Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 20th,
2014 what's going on? How
are you? How was your week?
Did you enjoy yourself?
Did you survive the weekend and all
the big football games and all this
screaming and yelling
there? Um, I had a fucking,
I had a great weekend. I have to tell
you that first of all before, uh,
before we get going just in case
there's any concern. I am. Okay.
All right. And I'm not talking about
the Patriots lose in. Oh Geez. You year,
I'm talking about the fuck
in fires in California.
You know,
it's fucking hilarious.
One of the greatest things that can
ever happen to you is far as you. Uh,
did I spell douche wrong for my little
notes here? Douche on southwest.
I spelled the deal. Uch. Let's
see, French spelling. Um,
I'll get to that story later.
I'm one of the greatest things you can
do as far as like understanding the news
a little better is when the big news
story is happening where you live and you
just watch how it's
fucking reported. Um, I,
I had a Gig this weekend
in, uh, in Albuquerque, New
Mexico, and, uh, you know,
this time of year,
the hills catch on fire.
It happens every fucking year. This
year there's a drought. So what's worse?
All right,
but this happens every fucking year.
And the way they report this shit,
they never just say that
this is completely natural,
that this is the natural cycle of a,
of nature out here.
Basically what happens to recap, because
I think I went through this before.
Basically what happens is,
um,
here in southern California,
what happens is, uh,
for like a month,
every year we get rain,
it rains like a motherfucker
that is him rain.
Like it pours a few days and everybody
freaks out and they can't drive because
it hasn't rained in like 11 months.
So all the oil and transmission and
brake fluid gets mixed in with the water.
And it's, it's actually, it's,
I would say it's like a little
bit slicker than it is back east,
but everybody out here acts like
they're driving in two feet of snow.
It's fucking ridiculous. Um, but anyways,
what happens is all that water comes in,
then all the hills, all the mountains,
all that shit turns a beautiful
color green, you know,
and it's lush and it's
beautiful looking and all that.
And then basically the rain fucking
stops and occasionally you will get rain.
And then sometime around the summer,
the fucking,
um, I dunno, like August,
September, whenever the October,
somewhere around there that we get what's
known as the Santa Ana winds there and
they come in from the east and these
fucking things will like, you know,
if he had shutters, they blow
them shut and open. I mean,
they're really strong winds, especially
if we're in the hills a little bit. Um,
cause it's just flat land out here.
And what happens is it goes across
the Mojave desert, all right.
And it picks up all that hot air and
it's basically like a giant hairdryer and
it dries out the fucking hills.
And then inevitably a fire starts and
it burns out all the brush and then it
starts a new blush and beautiful
every year. But the problem is,
is we've out fucked the flatlands.
Yeah.
The problem is we don't
like living near one.
Another problem is we like to have status.
I want to look down on you.
I want to be away from you.
You're fucking music's too loud.
I don't like to smell your food. I don't
want my kids hanging out with your kids.
So we move up into the fucking hills.
And next thing you know,
rich people with fucking gold bracelets
start getting eaten by Bobcat's or have
a scratched up by them,
eaten by mountain lions and
they're fucking houses burned down.
But it is 100% natural.
And then what always ends up happening
is some fucking Douche on the east coast.
What it is,
and it's not their fault because when
they show this shit on the news, you know,
I was out here and I went to, I went for
a hike and I was able to see out, uh,
and I could see a fire out in way out
in Pasadena. And that's fucking amazing.
Giant fire in this type of
shit. But whatever. It's
just, but it's like fucking,
I don't know, 30 miles away or whatever,
20 miles away. It's not a problem, but I,
I landed in Albuquerque and
they were showing the fires.
Um,
and the way they were talking about them,
you would've thought the entire
state was engulfed in flames.
I had like five people call
me to make sure I was all
right. Hey, I'm seeing this,
I'm seeing this stuff on those.
I'm just making sure,
like the whole fucking state is on fire.
Like we're all out here
without fucking garden hoses.
Um,
and they just completely zoom in on the
fire and that's exactly what it looks
like.
It literally looks like hell on earth.
It reminds me of when I lived back
east and there would be a hurricane.
It actually was downgraded to a tropical
storm. Then it just kind of reigned.
Do you remember that news clip with
that woman was in the boat, you know,
acting like she was in four feet of
water and then those construction workers
came walking by and it was like,
it was like fucking ankle deep.
That's what they do. So, um,
I'm just letting you know,
California beautiful fucking
state. Uh, it's not on fire.
The fires are natural. Um,
as they are with all forests.
I don't, I know I'm not a fucking nature
guy. I don't know what to that level,
but I do.
It burns it all out and it causes it
to come back even more healthier every
fucking year. Now if you
want to be, you know,
a gambler and build a house in
the middle of the shit, you know,
there's a chance one day it might burn
down. All right. But, uh, actually,
you know what, I, I'm,
I'm fucking up here.
I should just roll with it and act like
the entire place is on fire and maybe
less people will move out here
and we can drive a little, uh,
we can drive a little more. But a
verse, he actually sent me a text,
he said he was watching the La fires
or whatever, the, the California fires.
And he was just saying like, uh, you
know, the usual, that's God's way as say,
and you should live up there, you know,
meanwhile, he lives in fucking New York.
You know what's fucked up about New York
and why people are way more polite or
than they give him credit for it.
When you're on the subway,
pretty much people are polite because,
um,
you're all mixed in together and you
have no idea who or what is next to you.
And what the fuck they
did in the last 24 hours.
Forget about the last 24 minutes.
They could have just stabbed somebody,
they could have somebody fucking locked
in the closet and they're fucking apart.
You have no fucking idea.
So generally speaking, uh,
you're on your best behavior when
you're on the subway, but um,
you know, I don't fucking know. You
know, the, they, they, they always,
they always just show all the worst.
It's a fucking great state and whatever
catches on fire. I mean, we have to,
we have something has to happen to pay
for the fact that it's 60 degrees out and
I don't have to shovel my cat
out of the fucking package spot.
Right. So I'll just let you
know. In case you were concerned,
case you would think and like, Hey, I
always wanted to move to California,
but of the entire state is engulfed in
flames once a year. That isn't true. Uh,
yes, we are having a drought. Um,
and I don't know if that has to do with
just the natural cycle or the fact that
there's over 7 billion people getting
up every day and they got to take a shit
and asked to go somewhere and maybe
eventually that leads to a drought.
I have no fucking idea,
but I'm just letting you know the whole
fucking state isn't on fire. All right,
so in the words of Martin Short,
relax your crack.
Um, okay. So anyways, this is the, uh,
the Monday morning podcast.
Oh. And I, I get it.
So I gotta I gotta talk about
the Douche on southwest. So, um,
I went to Albuquerque this weekend
and I had a fucking unbelievable time.
I have not been back there since,
uh,
all those wonderful episodes of
breaking bad that I got to be on.
And, um, you know, I was
going to go on a hike.
That's what I wanted to do. I wanted
to do that. But, uh, you know,
Nia had some friends out there.
We were going to go to lunch
and you know how that is,
it only take like an hour,
that's three hours,
you know, so I'm just like,
I'm too fucking old too.
Um,
I'm too old to fucking hike and have a
social event in one day and then actually
give any sort of a decent,
decent, uh, performance.
So I was like, all right, fuck it. I'm
not going to go on the hike. I'll go over.
And we met, um, I met his friends
and they were, they were awesome.
Fucking cooked up burgers the
middle of the day, you know,
those homemade burgers that are way
bigger than the ones that you get in a
restaurant and then you eat m and a,
you don't feel 60 Assam stomach
afterwards. Fucking phenomenal.
And, uh, the people's
house, we went over to,
they had all these beers and that
type of stuff and I stayed away.
I was a good boy, so I could have the
show, but I know myself at this point.
So I still that I see, I can't do
all of those activities in one day.
So I just decided like, uh, all right,
I'll just do the social
thing and I'll chill out.
Which was actually really cool because
I've been to Albuquerque a bunch of times
and I never got to ride around and,
uh,
see any of it and, uh, it's really,
really fucking cool placement.
Really, really cool. Um, so anyways,
so that night I was at the, uh,
the 66 casino,
meaning basically route 66 and,
uh, it's one of the coolest
looking casinos I've, I've seen,
I'll try to have some
images up for, I, you know,
you tried to take pictures of those casino
lights and it never comes out on your
cell phone. At least the one
that I have, the four S. Um,
but it was really cool, like the
hotel had like that, you know, uh,
the route 66 sign instead of the 66,
it just said hotel,
it was all lit up and then, you know, it's
native Americans own it. And then the,
the,
the arrows pointing in where to go.
We're literally like arrows
and they looked like they
were stuck into the ground.
They were all lit up. It was
fucking bad ass. It was bad ass.
And then I got to play in the name of
the theater was the legends theater.
I played a place called
the legends theater.
I remember I was doing some
press for it and they said,
what can people expect when they come down
to the legends theater? And it's like,
well they should expect to see a legend.
Okay.
It shouldn't expect to see me. Oh,
fresh out of the fucking horse stable.
Where do I go?
Is this the way to the grade road?
They're going to be allowed people. I'm
scared. Uh, fortunately it all went,
it went great and a fucking great
people out there, man. Once again,
and this was another place that was
supposed to be a stop on the uh,
Billy red state tour. And um, I dunno
for any comics who are listening to this,
don't buy into that horse shit
that these are fly over states.
They're beautiful places to go.
And the people are ridiculously
appreciative that you
showed up this site and
they always say the same shit. Can you
tell this person to tell this person?
You know,
they're always asking for Jim Norton
and all these guys that I know from the
opie and Anthony showed telling
them to come out there. You know,
we like comedy too,
so I pass the word on to them in a
lot of them have started coming out,
which is cool. Um, I just
hope that they don't become a,
an old jaded like when you play the
bigger cities and it just like whatever,
whatever man, you know, I got other
things to do, man. It was great.
And they actually bought a bunch of DVDs,
which is phenomenal because I got a
bunch of, I'm sitting in my garage,
I feel like in my garage is
filled with fucking laser discs.
I got to get those things
out of there. Um, anyways,
so, oh, the doe, Shawn southwest,
sorry, I'm all over the place today.
So we're flying back, um, quick
flight back. I don't want 45 minutes.
Fucking phenomenal. And, uh,
you know, the southwest people,
they always try to be funny, put a smile
on your face. Most Times they're not.
And this guy was actually kind of funny.
Then we go to land worth landing in Los
Angeles and this fucking asshole gets on
the fucking mic. It
starts going, you know,
he's like going welcome to Los Angeles,
which is a
okay,
interesting place.
Yeah.
Yes.
Very interesting.
He kept doing this weird laugh and
I'm looking at me at, first of all,
it was sounded creepy is fucking hell.
Um, I don't want to be homophobic,
but the guy sounded gay,
you know, the gay accent.
And so I used to do a joke on this,
like gay people come from all 50 states,
yet they kind of all have the same accent,
which isn't true.
But generally speaking there is a
gay accent, which makes no sense.
How did the joke, that's
how that joke, just to go
like if you were gay from
Alabama, we were like, hey bud,
add row lock to suck your Dick.
Like that's the way you should sound.
Just do a stereotypical redneck accent
with my stereotypical gay accent.
All right?
But they don't,
I grew up in Alabama and let's
just say I'm not going back there.
It's probably more valid. Go. You
know what the Fuck I'm saying?
That's what the guy sounded like. So I'm
just sitting there on the back and like,
did, uh, you know,
this guy get blown in west Hollywood
and somebody stole his wallet.
Did he want to be the next
Jim J uh, uh, buffets,
whatever the fuck the guy's name
is from too close for comfort.
I don't know what his fucking deal was,
but I'm just sitting there and my head
going yet another most fucked up thing
about living in Los Angeles.
I've never lived in a city
where everybody trashes it.
Everybody just shits on it. And
that kills me about that. Let's see.
This is the only fucking
city where you could do that.
I guess you can kind of
make like a gambling joke,
but you can actually land in Los Angeles.
Not give a fuck that everybody,
their lives on the plane for the most
part lives there and then just shit on it.
Um,
okay.
I can, I fucking drove me nuts. Drive
me fucking eyes was a interesting place.
That's just sick. Well,
what the fuck are you doing?
What makes you such a good person?
What happened? You here, Huh?
What Sit-com did you test for?
And you got to coked up the night
before and you fucking blew it. Ah,
what were we supposed to be on?
Will and grace.
I'm sorry.
In order this,
I'm defensive of La at this point because
I have to live out here because this
is the fucking business on it.
I don't have to, but you know,
it makes life a lot fucking easier
to be where everybody else is in this
business. You know, if I
was into fucking computers,
I go move up to watch the
fucking, ah, the valley up there.
The silicone valley, which for
the life of me, I don't know what,
why do they call it silicone?
Isn't it? What's in fake titties?
Is it? I don't know. Fuck it now. Anyways,
let's do a little bit of advertising here.
Um,
I'll thanks everybody who listened to the,
a very special
bonus podcast this week with Jay more.
If he didn't listen to it.
And you always wondered what Harvey
Keitel would sound like doing bad 80.
Stand up. It's a must
list. It really is a must.
Listen nothing but rave reviews.
Uh,
other than one one person,
one person shit on it was saying how lame,
uh,
Jay Moore was and he called him Jay snore.
So literally this person is telling me
that my guest is lame and then his joke
is a pun. You know, that Kinda
Kinda kills you. Credibility.
Uh, I think Jay is a fucking genius, man.
My face actually hurt from
smiling by the end of it.
This is fucking ridiculous impressions.
Um,
so please have a listen to that.
You know,
I'm going to kill a couple hours for you
this week. Weekend. You cubicle there.
All right. Dollar Shave Club. Everybody
tall is shave club. All right.
For a couple of bucks a month,
dollar shave club.com delivers amazing
quality razors right to your front door.
Not only does it save you a ton of cash,
it saves you from trudging your sorry ass
to the drug store for a pack of blades.
I always get stuck behind the low
paying with all or loose change from
the car ashtray with their blue wig. Uh,
it's like she thinks exact
changes a requirement. Um,
I can't, why do I always try to read that?
It says I'm a patient person, but heck,
I came in with scruff. Now I'm
leaving with a full beard. We get it.
I'm there for a long time.
We all know you go in there.
Drug stores are the absolute worst.
It's just a complete a cross pollination
of everybody from alcoholics and drug
addicts. I was in the cvs the
other day or the Dwayne Reed,
Dwayne aid,
whatever the fuck they have out here.
And this fucking dude came
in with just pants on.
That's it.
Just pants on.
He didn't have on any underwear because
I could see at least three quarters of
his ass crack hanging out of
the back of his fucking pants.
And he wasn't even that fat.
He had a beer belly,
but he's still at his see
still at his high school hips
or maybe he just pushed his fucking
quarter. Roy's down that far, you know.
So he walks out,
I walk up behind him,
he has a dollar in his hand and for some
reason he fucking bitch a glob has spit
on it and then sticks it to the
side of the, of the, uh, the cvs,
Duane aid read fucking thing there,
right.
And then walks away and within two
seconds of blue down in the ground.
And I was just like,
well,
I guess that's what I would do if I
didn't have a wallet. I have no idea,
but I don't want to look at that.
That's why dollar shave club, everybody
right now, dollar shave club
for a couple of bucks a month.
You can avoid that nightmare and you
can get amazing quality razor blades
delivered right to your door. The
can't make it any easier. That's right.
No more wasting time and no more
getting hit up for 20 bucks.
Every time you buy razors.
Everybody here meaning me is getting
the dollar shave club blades.
And you know what? You should
too. You don't have to,
but you should want to make your life
easier. And here's a genius idea.
Try replacing your old shaving
right [inaudible] with doctor
from dollar shave club.com. Trust
me, your face will thank you later.
Don't waste time at the drug store
behind a lady paying and penny's.
Go to dollar shave club.com forward slash
bar or go to [inaudible] dot com and
click on the dollar shave club banner.
Keep your stress level low and your bank
account high shave time, shave money.
Go to dollar shave club.com. Forward
Slash burr. Uh, there you go.
You know, it's funny every time
I say keep your uh, your, your,
your stress level low and
your bank account balance. Hi,
I point I point down and point up,
I don't know why desperately trying
to help myself have a good read.
It's part of my ritual. Okay.
Hulu plus Hulu plus everybody.
You've probably tried hulu.com
unless you're living under a rock.
Now with Hulu plus, you can watch
your favorite shows anytime, anywhere.
Hulu plus lets you watch thousands of
hit TV shows and a selection of a claim
movies on your television or on the go
with your smartphone or tablet and it all
streams in HD for the best
viewing experience with
Hulu plus you can watch your
favorite current TV shows like Saturday
night live community and family guy.
You can also check out exclusive content
including Hulu originals like the
awesomes,
starring Snl,
Seth Meyers and moon boy starting Chris
O'Dowd from bridesmaids bridesmaids.
Hulu plus also offers a great selection
of acclaimed films for only seven 99 a
month. You can stream as many TV shows
and movies as you want wherever you want.
Right now you can try Hulu
plus for free for two weeks.
When you go to Hulu plus.com/bill that's
a special offer from my listeners.
Make sure you use Hulu plus.com/bill so
you get an extended free trial and that
they know that we send you,
go to Hulu plus.com/bill now or click
the Hulu plus better on the podcast page
at [inaudible] dot com.
All right, there you go.
There's two two reads to now what do I got
to go? One, two. All right. Two and two.
Two and two this week people,
two and two. We got a fine.
I sales a new can of energy. All
right. What to talk about next?
Um, oh this week. Oh, Billy red,
fake sole alabaster chest.
All Milky legs himself.
It's going to be out in Hawaii on a
Lulu who I'm doing a show out there on
Friday night and it's just me,
myself and I um,
I don't have an opener,
a just going to be me and,
uh,
going to be doing a whole bunch of
material cause I'm getting ready to do a
special this year, baby.
Getting ready to do another one.
I gotta be honest with you. I don't
know what I'm going to put it out on.
I feel like I still have to make DVDs
for people my age and on up who liked to
have the hard copy, you know, did I
mention that Nia hooked up our stereo?
Um, I bought her this stereo
when we first started dating.
It was one of the,
I think our first Christmas together.
That's what I got her and I
was sitting there going like,
I don't know if she's going to like this,
but um,
she seemed like sort of an
artsy nerd like me and uh,
I'm not really artsy, but whatever. I'm
a fucking nerd. I get into shit and um,
I took a shot. She absolutely
fucking flipped out. She
loved it. So she was living,
you know,
it wasn't living with me at the time
and I hooked it up and I don't know what
happened. I forgot how to do it. The
wires got crossed through moving,
I don't know,
a few years ago when we were still living
in an apartment was the last time I
hooked it up properly and I
don't know what was going on.
I couldn't figure the fucking thing
out when we moved into our house.
So it's just been sitting there and
I figure it was a few years old.
I thought it was broken.
So I go on the road and uh,
when I come back she had the whole thing
set up and was playing like some pink
Floyd and all this type of,
it was fucking awesome and emasculating
all at the same time and I'm
kind of, fuck, did I get into that?
I was just going to Hawaii
to hell was my point there.
I fucking know. Oh, I know.
Yeah. I was talking about
what am I going to put out my,
uh, my new album on? I have no idea.
Well, maybe like, you know, people
were still like DVDs. I have no idea.
I'm still going to burn off some.
I can tell you right now,
I'm not going to make 5,000 of them and
have 4,500 of them sitting in my fucking
garage. Like I have a second car
that doesn't go anywhere. Ah, Jesus.
You don't, one of my goals in
life is to have a clean garage.
I don't want to be that guy that has the
fucking garage that you can't even put
the car in. Um, thank God I got
my old truck sitting in there,
so that takes up most of it. I got to pull
you guys want to hear about my garage.
We'll go around the garage.
I got my 68 f 103 on the tree
over there and then I got the,
uh, I get up, I got pull up dip
station and then on the ground.
This is thankful pushups if you want,
but I still have those perfect pushups
things. I Dunno if they're perfect,
but they're fucking hard. I
can tell you that. And um,
then what else do I have?
I have a 10 or a 12 speed bike that
I bought when I was like in either,
I think the ninth,
ninth grade.
I've had it forever and I still ride
the fucking thing every once in a while.
Um, can anybody explain to me why? If you
don't, if you ride a bicycle every day,
it doesn't really need air in the tires,
but if you just let it sit there,
the air goes out of him.
Can you guys answer some
just some day to day simple
science questions for me
that I don't understand.
How come I can lay on a couch
for four hours, catatonic,
barely moving and I'm fine.
But if I fall asleep for five minutes
on the couch at my, I wake up like, Ooh,
it's chilly and I need a blanket.
I mean it's just shifting my
weight every five minutes.
Is that enough to keep my body temperature
up that I don't need a blanket?
It could be the middle
of the fucking summer.
Okay.
I mean, unless there's a bunch of humidity
and you don't have ac or whatever,
I'm just saying he could be
just perfectly comfortable.
It can be like God damn 72 degrees.
Perfect weather in your God damn
living room. Any me anyways. And if I,
if I fall asleep for more than five,
seven minutes,
I wake up on my shoulders a cold
and I got to put a blanket on.
I have to grab a little blanky, like
a little twinkle toes there. Um,
why is that?
What else?
Okay,
what else is there?
I know I have a bunch of these little
ones that I just don't understand.
Those are two. If someone could
explain the same thing with the car.
If he leave it sitting there too long,
the air goes out of the tires.
They become flat after a while.
Does the air feel not needed?
Well through goose guys call me back.
It goes somewhere else. I don't
know. I know I sound like a moron.
I go fuck yourself. Um, so anyways,
I'm going to be in Hawaii this weekend,
which I'm really excited about and I'm,
I'm going to go to the pro bowl this year.
So look for me.
I'd be wearing a Robert
Williams Hawaiian shirt, um,
drinking some milk.
Okay.
And, uh, I think it's going
to be a fun game this year.
I liked that they choosing upsides.
I heard that they're not,
it's not gonna be enough seat versus AFC.
They're gonna choose up sides and then
they're not going to have kickoffs do I
think is good because it's such a weird,
like it's,
you can't play the game because
no one wants to get hurt.
I think they should
just play flag football.
They should just play flag football and
they should just make up the players
because you can play hockey and all
star game and hockey. You can just play,
you just play, you know,
basically non contact,
not going too hard and guys can still
entertain the crowd with the stick
handling the shots and all that type of
stuff. Same thing with basketball. Um,
you don't have to go that hard and you've,
everybody can watch a one 50 to one
45 game and baseball, the baseball,
all star games the best
because it actually something
and they actually come out
and play. Um, but you know,
it's a non contact sport.
What are you going to do?
You know,
unless somebody tries to beat you with
the ball or if you're talking about the
ball hitting the bat
there. Um, so anyways,
I want to be out there and,
uh,
going to be doing probably at least an
hour and a half on stage cause I got it.
Well, I got to blow it out and then
tighten it up right before. Um, my, uh,
my special comes out and then I'm
going to weed out the weak ones.
It's like making an NFL roster.
I probably got it, you know,
55 guys on it and I got to cut.
Was it like 10 of them? 12 of them?
I don't fucking know.
But a cup you guys been asking me,
still have been asking me about when
my Carnegie hall album is coming out.
Uh, we were in the final stages and
hopefully it's going to be out May, June.
It took forever. Um,
because I was dealing with,
uh, you know, Carnegie's
very prestigious place.
They got to make sure all the
i's dotted and the t's across,
whatever the fucking expression
is. So it's, it's been
very long and very tedious.
And, uh, but eventually it is
coming out and I'm going to psyched.
And it's only coming out on album only.
So get your Stereo's today.
And um, you know, and if some of
you are going to be like, well,
how come you won't pull
it out all over the stove?
Because there's too much overlap
in material between that.
And it's basically the hour I was doing
when I was leading up to recording my
last special. So I don't want to fuck
people over and put out, you know,
two d DVDs of the same fucking thing
or a CD that's the same as the DVD.
So I'm letting you know right
now it's like three quarters,
the same material.
I tell it differently every night.
But basically it's the same shit.
There's a couple of extra lines and maybe
some lines from the special ed isn't
in there.
And then there's a chunk of shit that
I didn't make this special for whatever
fucking reason.
And it's only coming out on vinyl there.
I've told you what the deal is,
so don't come crying to me afterwards.
Um, except the worst selling
job of a fucking album ever.
Um, all right. So what am
I talking about? All right,
let's get down to the pro football
this week. Everybody pro football. Oh,
Jesus. Um, let's see.
What are we going to say are that
first game? Like I kind of went the,
the Patriots Broncos kind of went,
went the way that I thought
it was going to go. Uh,
I didn't think that we
were going to win and, uh,
congratulations to the Broncos.
They definitely were the best team
in the AFC this year. And, um,
um, I, uh, I dunno, I still saw
some articles out there. I mean,
I'm surprised at how many people who
write and talk about sports that,
uh, talked about, you know,
the disappointing end to the Patriots
season and everything. I mean,
I just feel like, well,
what they were working with,
that was one of the best seasons
I've seen Bellacheck Brady have. Um,
I never would've thought in
September where the fuck we were at.
I will never would've thought that we
could have, uh, gotten as far as we did.
And, uh, you know, so I'm
looking at it like it's success.
I saw some great up and coming stars on
defense and I'm looking forward to next
year and uh, and I'm actually psyched
at the Broncos in a way. I'm psyched.
I never like seen my team lose, but I'm
psyched that they up because you know,
Peyton manning the fucking unbelievable
offense, they got a really solid defense.
They should be there.
I want to see a good super bowl and um,
I know Bella check was complaining
about a Welker and I'm going to use air
quotes hit until leap. I didn't
think that it was a, I mean,
I don't know the game the way he does,
but I didn't look dirty to me at all.
If anything looked like he got the worst
of the hit initially it looked like he
was trying to get out of the way. Um,
I've never known Welker to do anything.
He never did any of that dirty shit.
He's a little fell out there
with a giant football helmet.
Now was he wearing like an anti
concussion for the rest of my life helmet.
Did anybody else notice that his helmet
was like a third bigger than it usually
heads.
He looked like he looked like,
is it Kazoo in the Flintstones?
His head look,
look at his helmet was fucking eating
his head. It was like, oh look at,
look at, look at Wes Welker way
in there and that helmet. Um,
but anyways, the uh, oh the
Broncos look really, really,
really strong yesterday and I ain't know
this was a tough year for me to watch
football cause I got married and then
I also spent three weeks in Europe,
so I don't even know guys fucking name.
All I can tell you is that 88
net 80 fucking killed us. Uh,
especially at fucking 88
like, and I swear to God, like
guide for catches like a hundred
yards within like a quarter it seemed.
I just remember by the time
he caught that fourth one,
I'm literally sitting there on the
couch going, I think in a fucking cover.
That guy, is it? Is it still a
mystery? What the fuck is going on?
Ada?
Right.
I'm hanging in there rooting for the
team and all that type of shit. Oh,
you know what? You know, it's
funny was I was on the, uh,
the southwest flight with the dose
trash in La when the game started.
And I taped the game. I DDI
audit, I had my phone off,
I put my headphones on in the airport,
pulled my hat down, walk by all the bars,
didn't look at anything,
had the music cranked when I was sitting
at the little turnstile waiting for my
bag.
And I somehow I was able,
with all the technology
and all the streaming shit,
I was able to get home and having no idea
who was doing what, ran into the house,
sat down and I was able to put it on.
And um,
and it was great because I got to fast
forward through all the commercials.
I got to fast forward through halftime
and I got to watch this, this, you know,
this game. Everybody wasn't
a great game. I mean, uh,
the Broncos really dominated even
though we were in it somehow in the end,
I'll get back to that
later. Um, but anyways,
so congratulations to the Broncos and
all that shit and uh, good for pigment.
Cause you know, I read something
where he was, you know,
it was neck was all fucked up. He didn't
know if he was going to play again.
So He seems to really psyched, obviously
to be back. So good on him. Um,
and then onto, um, Seattle 49 is,
which I felt was the super bowl and
I'm kind of still feel that way.
I felt like whoever won that game
was going to be a, I just, you know,
it's just the ebb and
flow of the conferences.
There's always one conference
that is stronger and um,
I dunno, it was a fucking heavyweight
battle man. Just a great game.
And fortunately there was only
a couple of those soccer mom,
um, um, bullshit fucking
calls like that, that,
that one that they called in the first
quarter had me up off the couch. Um,
that unnecessary roughness where it was,
uh, it was against the 40 niners and me,
it was just a textbook
lead with your shoulder.
Wasn't helmet to helmet and Troy Aikman
goes, well he does launch himself.
It's like Troy, he has, how else
do you tackle? You supposed to eat,
you got to launch yourself at the target.
I that was one of the worst fucking
calls and I think eventually they said it
was a bad call. It was perfect. But the,
those are those fucking calls man,
that I think that's yet another reason
why all of Dan Marino's records are
falling because that should
have been the end of the drive.
Um, I think it was third down, I don't
remember. But, but generally speaking,
it ends a drive,
an incomplete pass and then they
call unnecessary reference roughness.
It keeps the drive going and then the
quarterback gets to continue throwing the
ball down the field, adding
more yards to their resume. Um,
in this era, when you can't really
cover receiver past five yards,
you can't even look at them or you
get a fucking flag. Fortunately,
there was only a couple of those calls.
Um,
and obviously there's going
to be a rule change with, um,
I really should know the names
of these guys. I just don't,
this year I've just been fucking
traveling so much. But, uh, uh,
the guy in the 40 niners this is so
disrespectful cause he gave up his goddamn
need to make the play.
He recovered the fumble he was,
he was touched by a Seattle player.
It should have been our turnover,
but fortunately it was justice where they,
uh,
Seattle turned over the
ball a couple of days later.
So what they really just got fucked out
of about 30 seconds on the clock. But, um,
I dunno, it was just an awesome,
awesome, awesome fucking game. And,
um, I dunno. I, I think
in the end I just think
Kaepernick is inexperience.
MMM.
Kind of caught up with them a little bit.
Just some of the decisions that he made,
but,
but that guy is the real deal and
he's not afraid of the moment.
So I just think that
unfortunately for 40 niners fans,
they're going to have to
wait at least another year.
But I think that that guy's got, he
definitely has what it takes, man. Um,
he's definitely a winner and that
type of thing. So it was just,
it was a great fucking game. And, um,
so now we're into the super bowl.
Now we're into the chauffeur bowl.
So now you have to wonder. You got
to wonder, right? If you like me,
um, all I want to do is see the fucking
game. I don't want to listen to the,
the pregame and postgame analysis.
You know,
there's always one person
that's going to make, you know,
all the quotes and all that type of
shit and Yadda, Yadda, Yadda, Yadda,
Yadda, Yadda. So this is what I do. This,
this is all you gotta do if you
just want to watch the fucking game.
MMM.
I would,
um,
just put it on the NHL Network for the
next two weeks is basically what you want
it to
get into NHL hockey.
You won't have to watch any of the
fucking analysis where they're going to go
the entire roller coaster.
MMM.
I don't know.
It's just lazy journalism and whoever
talks Shit and that type of thing,
they're going to get it 100% of the
fucking attention. And it's just gonna.
It's just, it's absolutely
fucking nauseatingly. Like,
um, yesterday, you know,
at the end of the game,
the Seattle, uh, 40 niners game,
I felt like a Tommy Lee
Jones and no country for old
men where it just sorta has
passed you by and you can't even
make sense of it anymore. Um,
I gotta tell you, I
talked about this on, um,
on forest Shaw's and Al Jackson's
podcasts. What the fuck is it called?
Jesus Christ. I'm so old. I
can't remember anything anymore.
MMM.
Whatever. Just Google that and you'll
find it. I talked about that. That shit.
Now everybody,
whether you catch a four yard pass or
you hit a layup and you get filed and it
goes in like all these athletes,
now they've got to do that stupid fucking,
they do that. Yell like they're in
300. Like they just slayed a dragon.
He had a fucking lay up ticky tack foul
and one even Paul was Saul does it now.
What is that?
Okay,
did it? It's fucking the stupidest.
Did Jerry Rice ever do that?
Did Jordan ever fucking do that?
You know,
it's fucking hilarious. I
saw, who was it yesterday?
Was it golden Tate is a great fucking
receiver. Critical moment in the game.
They need a first down and catches
the ball. He has first down yardage,
I dunno if he didn't know
where he was in the field,
but rather than just dropping to
the ground, he cuts back inside.
Now he's behind the first down line and
then as to fight like hell to get across.
So he basically makes the play,
fucks it up and is able to
recover and then he gets up, ah,
screaming like he's God's gift.
I gotta tell you this right now,
this is why Marshawn Lynch is,
might be my favorite player,
favorite athlete out there because the
fact that he's doing what he's doing
every week and I guess he, my
buddy was telling me, he just said,
I'm not talking to the media this year
and get fined 50 grand and he didn't give
a fuck you all he wants to do is when
the God damn game like that guy and that
guy just runs over people and gets up,
basically gets, I'm going to say
it doesn't celebrate a touchdown,
but he just gets up and walks back
to the huddle. I love that shit.
And as much as they're
going to talk about,
um Oh,
what's his face there for running is Yap.
I have to tell you,
a cornerback is not going to
win the Superbowl for you.
He can shut down that part of the field,
but what can I think what's going to
be the difference in the super bowl is
going to be,
I think it's going to be Marshawn lynch
because I think Seattle has a better
defense, but the Broncos have
also have a really strong defense.
So, um, I give the nod to Seattle there,
but it's not this such a giant gap
that the game is over. All right?
And then when you go to the
quarterback position, obviously, um,
you got Peyton Manning,
okay.
And Seattle's best weapon against
Peyton manning is not their defense.
It's actually Marshawn
lynch. Okay. Peyton Manning,
the way he's playing this year,
playing that guy. It's basically,
it would be like if you owned
a poisonous snake, all right?
And you got to take it out of the tank
to fucking clean the God damn tank.
And no matter how careful you are,
eventually you're going
to get bit by that fucker.
The only way not to get bit by that
fucker's to keep the son of a bitch in the
tank. And the best way to do that
is with a great running game. Okay.
And I've seen this before in past,
in,
in a championship games where you have
this unstoppable quarterback and the
guy's sitting on the fucking bench.
He's not even sweating.
He's been there so fucking long because
the other team is just running the ball.
And my big knock against the Broncos,
despite the fact that they are a great
team, is that they don't put people away.
They had both against San
Diego and the Patriots, they,
for the most part dominated the game.
But at the end of the fucking game,
they let, they let the chargers hang
around. They even let us hang around.
Like if we made that two point conversion,
that onside kick, if we get it,
we can actually drive down the
field and somehow could tie it.
Like that's the situation they were in
after absolutely dominating the game with
like four minutes to go, whatever.
They were still in that situation.
And I don't know, I think that
eventually bite you in the ass. So, um,
I dunno,
I just think that it's going to be a,
I think Marshawn lynch is going to be
the difference if they are going to,
and obviously their offensive line,
but they only need to open
this the smallest of hole.
And that guy is just,
I don't know, it's the,
he's like this devastating combination
of like Earl Campbell and like Walter
Payton. I mean, he's fucking
unbelievable. And um, and with that,
so what you're going to be now is you're
going to be inundated with people, uh,
you know, talking about,
uh, what's his face there?
Uh,
Shannon Sharpe Sharman they're going to
be talking about this guy up and down,
up and down, the brash, outspoken.
They'll go all the one once they've
exhausted that, and then there'll be like,
is it blood? Is it an inferiority complex?
Blue, blue, blue, blue, blue, blue, blue,
blue.
And then they'll get tired of doing that.
And then we'll talk about his upbringing
and they'll say whether his father was
there, whether it was father
wasn't there and Yada, Yada,
all that fucking horse shit.
So what I do for the two weeks in
between is I just watch hockey.
All right,
this is how you do it.
It just fucking watch you watch hockey
or whatever. Go work out for two weeks,
get yourself in great shape because
you know you're going to eat like shit
during the Superbowl and just
don't put it on sports center.
Just don't watch the shit unless
you're into it. I'm, I'm not into it.
I think if you're one of those people who
watches the game with the Jersey on at
home and you put eyeliner under your
eyes and you yell things like all day,
all day at your TV, I think you actually
want to watch the super bowl coverage.
But uh,
if you're a fucking regular fan,
which I actually came to a piece here
with Seattle fans because I was looking at
Seattle fans, the way people look at
like the fires out here in California,
it wasn't fair hours looking at them
because they weren't showing the diehards.
They were showing the jerk offs.
Like did you see that guy in the lime
green pimp suit? You know what I mean?
Where the fuck is that Guy
Ben, you know, come on.
Who does that?
What kind of a real fucking fan does that?
You just go to the Goddamn game.
You Watch the fucking game,
you put a little money on it, it
drinks a fucking beers, whatever,
crack jokes or whatever and you
watch the fucking game. So anyways,
um, so this is our wash
again. Basically I, I don't,
I watch NHL hockey and then this year
I'm not going to a Superbowl party.
I'm going to be at home.
And uh,
what I love doing,
I told you guys this last year is you
start the game like 90 minutes after it
started.
Just wait like an hour and a half.
I have a couple people over
who really liked football.
You have a couple of beers, you shoot
the shit, blah blah, blah, blah, blah.
He got the grill going and all that type
of thing and about an hour and a half
in, you fast forward through all
of the crap in the beginning,
which I think is going to be the chili
peppers. I actually liked the two music,
Bruno Mars and a music acts, a, a Bruno
Mars and the Chili peppers. But I, I'm,
I'm there to watch the game,
you know what I mean?
If I went to see either one of those
bands play in like halfway through it,
they played a little bit of touch
football in the middle of it,
that would also be annoying.
Um,
so you fast forward through all of that
crap and then the person, you know,
trying to make a record career artist,
a singing the national anthem,
you fast forward through all of that
fucking shit and now you're into the game
and you can fast forward through all the
stupid fucking commercials and he just
watched the game.
And then you get to fast forward through
all of the halftime and then basically
you catch up somewhere in
like the third quarter. Um,
at which point the game is really
starting to get tense because you know,
a championship is on the line.
That's basically how I do it. Um, if,
if you, uh, if you like me, if
you're the Tommy Lee Jones of,
uh,
of sports fans at this point and you can't
even remotely relate to what happened
at the end of the game yesterday,
like why you would do that and how it
was actually mildly depressing like is
that's going to be the new
thing that you have to do. Um,
I dunno. I don't fucking know.
I just hope that that uh,
I hope that that's just a
unique personality and that
everybody doesn't start
doing that because uh, I
dunno, you play sports,
you fucking try to kick the shit out of
the guy and in the end you just go, hey,
good game. That's what you do.
Nobody choked in that game yesterday.
That was a fucking great game and I just
felt like that whole, all of that crap,
it just took away from my era.
I watched a great game and how I got
to sit there and listen to all these
fucking lazy journalists who all gonna
like moths to a fucking light are all
going to go up to that
complete non fucking story.
Just a non fucking story
anyways. Um, what that,
what that let's get to more, uh, let's
get some more advertising. Oh, by the way,
Seattle, you know, you might
finally have some to chair about.
You guys are one fucking game away.
And if you guys win,
I hope you understand how ridiculous
that loudest crowd thing was. All right.
And retiring your jersey,
you're retiring, you're fucking
come on. Real football fans in.
Come on.
They retired your number.
I mean, are you guys all dying out
there and there was some sort of,
make a wish thing that they had
to do for you? I mean, I just,
I can't get past that. And the fact that
the team's never won a championship,
what do they say it? I don't, I don't,
I don't understand it. So hopefully,
you know, either way it's going to be a,
it's going to be a great thing to see. Um,
either see Peyton manning when,
one, when another one, uh, which,
you know, Ryan's me when John Elway,
he also played for the Broncos.
Maybe that's a little storyline
they could run with. And,
and then the other thing is
Seattle, finally Wednesday, uh,
filing wins the super bowl gets the
monkey off their back. Either way,
it's going to be a, it's going
to be a good thing. And a,
I will definitely have be fast forwarding
through commercials and I will not be
watching any post game or any of
that fucking crap mute button.
We'll be right at the fingertips.
Oh,
Billy Lee Jones. I'm
trying to, I'm trying to,
what I'm trying to do is through modern
technology still make it seem like what
it was like when I watched the
Superbowl in the late seventies,
early eighties where it was
just the fucking game. Uh,
you know, uh, I just sound like a grumpy
old man. You know what, I'm, you're right.
I am. I, yeah, but we're either
way, congratulations to a,
the Broncos in the Seahawks.
It's uh, you know, this is the,
I liked it. There's no real
underdog. You've got to, to,
to really kind of the best teams. Although
I really felt the 40 niners are also,
eh, they should have been there too. Um,
so I felt NFC was the Superbowl, but
whatever, it's still going to be.
Hopefully it's going to be an
awesome fucking game. And uh,
you know,
there'll be nobody wigging out either
at the end of the fucking game.
I literally thought that dude
was going to start crying.
Um,
it's fucking uncomfortable.
Uncomfortable is health.
That was like seeing the nerd
finally beat up the bully. You know,
when you're finally ball up your fist,
you punch and you win the fight. You,
you're almost crying. It
was just, I don't know.
I don't fucking know. I don't know
what, what has happened to sports?
Can we a ESPN, can we,
you know, 100% access?
Can you dial it back down
to like maybe 40% access?
Can you stop interviewing fucking coaches,
Fox and whatever.
NBC as a jogging off the field trying
to think of their halftime adjustments.
Can we just stop fucking doing
that? I don't give a fuck. Nhl.
Can we stop interviewing players
in between the fucking, uh,
periods?
Is this sitting there still out of breath
from their last shift and that fucking
drop a fucking sweat hanging
off their nose looking like,
not that they have to keep wiping
and then it comes back again.
Can we just enough? I don't give a fuck
what happened in that first period.
I just watched the first
period. I know. What happened.
What do you think you have to do in the
second period? Oh baby score. More goals.
Vinnie. Nhl players listening to this. Uh,
I'll give you a free podcast tee shirt
even though you're going to get fined
probably a hundred grand by the league.
Is there any way you could wipe your
nose and the blouse of the person who's
interviewing you in between periods?
Just reach out and grab that tie.
Just Dab your eyes. You know,
I got nothing to give you a,
you're a millionaire athlete,
but could you just do it for the,
just for the fucking ridiculousness of it?
Yeah.
Like they're not going to interview
you after the fucking game.
Like I have to have it.
They got that fucking guy who stands
down there and what it looks like the
penalty box in between
the fucking benches,
whatever the fuck his name is,
prince fielder, the hell's his name.
Prince Harry standing down there. Well
it's really that ate up down area ice.
Like why do I need to hear that guy?
Okay.
Poor bastards got to stand up for three
periods and his loafers probably got
hammer toes by the end of the year.
Less access.
Do you think you could do that?
Do you think he could actually start a
sports network that could compete with
ESPN and the whole thing is less access.
Yeah.
No miked up players. You just fucking, uh,
just trim the fat.
Can I just go back to watching Bob Lobell
at the end of the news and just seeing
five minutes of the shit?
Can I just see that as he sits
there in a fucking blazer?
You know, every once in a while it takes
a day off in me. Comes in. Bob Knew Maya.
I miss those days. I really miss
those fucking days. Um, all right.
Legal, zoom.com everybody. All right.
Some things like stat and a business
or protecting your family with a,
we'll aren't like your
other new year's resolution.
She can't afford to blow them off. Instead
of less snacking and more exercise,
put them at the top of your list.
Thank you to the listener who actually
let me know how to read that sentence.
Legal Zoom helps you incorporate or form
an LLC with their simple questionnaire
starting at just 99 bucks.
Over 1 million entrepreneurs
have done it in 90% of customers.
Recommend legal zoom
to friends and family.
You can also create a will starting at
just 69 bucks or even a living trust
quickly and easily and get peace of
mind and protection. No surprise fees,
no hassles and no headaches.
Legal zooms step by step process was
created by a team of experts in law and
technology.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm but can
connect you with the third party attorney
and provides you with Selpa self
help services from wills to business
formations, trademarks,
powers of attorney,
and go to legal zoom.com for even more
savings tight bur bur until the referral
box at checkout. Don't put, don't
put things off you need to do.
Go to legalzoom.com now and use the
discount code burpee. You are our,
that's legalzoom.com discount
code burr and finally,
finally lastly,
but not leastly eve voice.
You are a business owner,
but automated phone systems
and secretaries are not in
your budget just yet and
juggling incoming calls yourself makes
it hard to look like a professional.
Here's something that will
dramatically help you make more money.
In 2014 it's eve voice.
Everybody,
whether you're a business of one or 100
he voice will help you manage all of
your incoming calls with the
toll free number. Dial by name,
directory and call routing tools. Your
business will sound like 1 million bucks,
which is show can't take a call,
he voice,
we'll transcribe the
voicemail and email it to you.
Never be caught off guard again.
And with the voice you can try
it before you buy it right now.
Just for my listeners, you can get
a 60 day free trial to eve voice.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and enter
the Promo Code Bill B I l l for the
challenged out there at checkout.
Take charge of your business and make
more money in 2014 go to [inaudible] dot
com and enter bill at checkout
for your 60 day free trial.
That's [inaudible] dot
com Promo Code Bill. Okay.
I really upped my out
reading out loud game.
I don't give a fuck if you
guys still think I stink.
I'm not as bad as I used to be. How about
that? All right, where are we right now?
54 minutes and we haven't even added
so much to talk about this week.
We haven't even started
doing any of the reads. Um,
I did get a chance to watch a couple, uh,
about 10 minutes of the second period.
My flight yesterday was during the
Bruins Black Hawks game. And, uh,
I loved that the Black Hawks beat the
ducks and there's still the team to beat.
I really loved that franchise.
Did there,
they're doing it the right fucking
way. They really are. And um,
I don't know who's
going to knock them off,
but I gotta tell you if you
want to get into hockey,
I would definitely suggest watching the
playoffs when they come up out west with
Black Hawks, the ducks, the
Kings, the sharks, at some point,
are they going to push through?
I mean,
they just really got a lot of great teams
out there. Uh, they play great hockey.
Who'd ever thought that in
hockey going through Anaheim,
Los Angeles and San Jose would be a
brutal road trip. It's fucking unreal.
It's a great thing. Anyways,
um, enough with the movies, uh,
big bad bill is sweet William now. Okay.
Hiccups, some criticism for the week.
I like this.
I like having the occasional criticism
you guys can start sending in your
criticisms of the week. Uh,
just put that in the, uh,
the subject line like she is. Okay. Bill
of all your comedic and podcast talents,
of which there are many. Look what
he's doing. He sent me up, oh,
he's patting me on the head.
He goes of all your Yadda,
Yadda Yadda towns and all that shit.
Movie reviews is not one of them.
Do I do movie reviews? I don't think
I do. He goes to beat, to be blunt.
You suck at reviewing movies when
you say things like, you know,
the one guy who was in that other
one where they did that thing.
You sound like Tony Soprano talking on
a compromised phone line and one was the
last time when every movie
you saw wasn't great.
The only moderately intelligent thing I
heard you say regarding movies was last
summer when you went off on the
whole PG 13 Zombie movie trend,
which of course was spot on.
It's entirely ridiculous to have a
Zombie flick that isn't rated r at the
minimum. They should all probably be NC
17. Well, you know what's funny, sir,
Mr Criticism was I was actually wrong.
Yeah,
I already forget the name of the movie.
That movie Mars Volta
the fuck was it called
bread a world war z.
How the fuck did I get Mars
volt with bars? Is there it is.
That was the Z in there. I have a
learning disability. You asshole.
And I was wrong about that.
What was what actually made World War
z great was the fact that it was PG 13.
So then we're relying on Gore and
shock and three d and All that crap.
They couldn't,
they actually had to build suspense.
And that's what's missing out
of a lot of fucking up the, uh,
the big time summer movies say go.
How's that critique?
How does that grab you are
actually fucking wrong about
that world board sees a
great fucking movie. Great. I loved it.
Two thumbs up to freckled thumbs
right up your fucking ass. All right,
let's finish this critique.
Here he goes,
but when talking about individual movies,
you might want to consider not
doing that. Now, Jesus Christ,
you might want to consider having
some sort of original criticism.
Instead of speaking in sound bites,
you might want to consider not doing that.
Um, he goes or maybe get one of
your comedy in quotes and quotes,
friends to guest review movies for you.
Oh, you don't think my friends are funny?
You don't think that I know people who
are funny. Is that what you're saying?
So what do you do?
Who are you shitting on here with
your little hipster air quotes? Uh,
he then goes on to sake.
I'm sure you have one or 20 that would
desperately be grateful for the exposure.
Look at that. Look at that. See
that now he's making fun of a,
the desperation of being in show business.
This is all kinds of just left
some little, little pitter.
Pat Wright's, you know,
little flyweight here, work in the body.
He goes, just trying to be helpful.
Anyways,
you will probably continue to do this,
but I hope from now on you will have a
little voice in your head telling you
it's a bad idea. There's his ego
wanting to help that, you know,
he affects my reads in the future or
whatever the fuck it is that I'm doing.
He'd go, that would be enough for me.
Even if you don't this on the podcast,
ps Bella check in is cheaters are no
different than all those roid pumping home
run record holders. All right.
Sounds like a colts fan. Um,
anyways. Uh, sir. I don't review movies.
I don't review movies. And when I watched
them, I can't remember who's in him.
I can't remember the names of people. I
can't, it's, it's, you know what it is?
It's part of getting old and you have
other shit to do with your life. You know,
I'm sure you still have a fucking,
uh, Orson Welles poster on your wall.
Whoever's the young hottie
today, Ryan Gosling, right?
I'm sure you have one of those up on
your wall and this is like a big part of
your fucking life. But it isn't a big
part of my life. It isn't. All right.
I only have so much time. I have too many
fucking hobbies. I can't remember that.
I can't remember the names of restaurants,
all the restaurants that we have
out here, I just, they're just,
I just have nicknames for him.
I don't know why.
Okay.
You know, maybe I talk on a cell
phone too much, but, uh, you know,
it was funny,
one of my favorite movies of all time
is no country for old men that already,
I can't remember if I even said this
already. No country for old men.
I just watched it again last night and I,
I always forget if it's
old man or old man.
I think I already said that
in this podcast at night.
Okay.
Did I, I don't fucking know. Um,
anyways. Well, whatever's sir,
you will be in my head every time.
I say it now,
but it's going to be in a good way knowing
that I'm annoying the shit out of you.
Um, and in the future, um,
if you ever want a comedian
to stop doing something, uh,
one of the best things you could do is
not let them know that what they're doing
annoys you.
Because that's one of my favorite
things to do is to annoy the shit out of
people. So a, there you go.
My movie reviews will continue and
I will be thinking about you sir.
Every time I do them,
um,
you might want to think
about not doing that.
Ah, Jesus Christ. Hey guys, how
about more Chivonne tee shirts?
They're all hilarious.
So she's come to Greece.
A bill. If you ever come in, I can't
even, I didn't know what that is.
FESA long eeky Greece.
There will be a house waiting for
you. Huge Fan was, isn't that nice?
Isn't that nice? Well,
I hope someday I get to,
I would love to do standup and grace.
Go over there and make a
couple hundred bucks, you know,
go out there and look at some ruins and
some fucking Greek women. I'm up for it.
Um, all right. Do those,
those Chivonne t shirts or this
generation's I'm with stupid t shirts.
Jesus Christ.
Unfucking believable.
I think I've seen every Chivonne
okay.
What does it carry on?
Is that what it was relaxing
and that's what it is.
Relax in.
I don't even know what the fuck they say.
Okay.
I just keep seeing people
with them and I just,
it just always blows my mind like
how do you still think that's funny
or just a funny tee shirt in general.
I just love how it's like
the joke that doesn't leave.
Like somebody reads it and it's funny
and then they laugh and then then you
still standing there with
the joker and your tee shirt.
Do you guys remember how
they used to end that?
That show police squad or they used to
make fun of when they would do the free
for freeze frames like on chips.
Okay.
When ships used to,
and somebody would always make a joke
and then they'd start laughing and then
they'd freeze it and then they'd show
some credits and then they'd had the,
the footage move a little more than
somebody else would do something else that
would make everybody laugh
and then they'd freeze that.
They kind of made fun of that except
they weren't freezing the frame and they
were just standing there.
That's basically what those t shirts are.
It's the police squad ending version
of a tee shirt, right? Jesus.
That was a long way to go. I
need a glass of water. All right.
Response to college, kid
dealing with rumors. Hey Billy,
but fuck Jesus Christ.
Can we be nicer in 2014
he said, I'm having some,
I have some advice for the kid who was
dealing with the rumor of him getting a
younger girl drunk and fucking
her in the elevator. All right,
so obviously you're assuming
that this dude was innocent.
How can I get out of the abyss of
these sexual sex crime? Questions here,
but potential sex crimes.
Um, all right, here we go.
I'm a recent college Grad who had to
deal with tons of rumors being made about
me. I was in a fraternity. That's
a red flag. I partied a lot.
Red Flag number two throughout my college
career. Career key comes from money.
Red Flag number three. Um, and fuck,
you don't think I'm just some typical Frat
Douche bag. You don't know my life. Ah,
you busted me. You have busted the, yeah,
that was awesome. Ah, Shit. He goes,
I used to deal with the same thing.
I would go to introduce myself to girls
and once they found out who I was,
they would either walk away or get that
fuck off. Look on their faces. All right,
now what did you do?
What we will accused of here he goes,
this kid needs to stop being a
pussy and just fucking go with it.
He should be like, yeah, I fucked
that chick in the elevator. Yeah,
that doesn't sound like a Frat
guy here. Frat guy advice. Uh,
he gets some respect from dudes at
parties and if he walked around with
confidence and embrace it, girls will
eventually come around to, all right,
so this guy's taking the, uh,
just continue being a Dick,
which I actually, it is.
It is very, uh, it is effective,
I guess from personal experience as much
girls would want nothing to do with me.
The same amount of girls would actually
come onto me because all of the
outrageous things I've done or
have been rumored to have done.
None of what you're bringing up. He says
he's in college. There's tons of hot,
easy chicks who want to hook up with
wild guy. All right. This guy's gross.
All right. I'm moving on. Um,
article on comics being psychos.
Uh,
Billy straight jacket.
I was at the Wiltern theater Gig and it
was the best new years I've ever had.
Well, you know what, it was one
of the best. I've had two man.
You guys were a great crowd,
so thank you. Um, he says,
I hope you come back next year.
Even if there's an overlap in material,
people pay to see the stones trudge,
trudge through,
jumping jack flash every God damn year.
Yeah, but you can't dance to my jokes.
What's the fucking deal with Obama?
I can't, I can't sing them. It's just
no, dude. You know what it
is. You think that you want,
you don't mind if there's overlap.
Well, I guess you are saying overlap,
but you're still saying come
with some new shit. Believe me.
I would love to do the Wiltern every year.
That was such a thrill to work there,
so I'm glad you were there anyways. Um,
he says enough ass kick ass kissing.
I'm sure you've seen this article making
the rounds about comics being psychos.
What are your thoughts?
My girlfriend said you made a
comment about it on Twitter,
was hoping you could elaborate,
uh, go fuck yourself. And Nia,
we love her. Um, oh yeah. Yeah.
There was a study by scientists
were trying to figure out,
I guess why comedians are funny.
And then they just said that
because we're basically,
we share the same traits
or we are psychos. Um,
I started to read that and um,
it's ridiculous,
mmm.
To attributed to that. It's, first
of all, they're, they're making,
it's just a giant generalization.
There are comics who are psychos,
but there were also truck drivers
who are psychos. There's teachers,
there's mothers, there's
dentists, there's lawyers,
heads of corporations, politicians.
They're psychos exists.
Um,
I really don't feel that it,
yeah.
That, that article has basically
no credit on for me anyways,
as far as like, I'm not saying
that comedians aren't psychos.
MMM.
But I mean, this sounded like they
were saying literally psychos. I mean,
we're out of our fucking minds,
but I think a lot of people are.
MMM.
But my, the, the reason
why I don't buy into it,
it might be on defensive because I am
a comedian. I will entertain that. But
okay.
Nobody I know was interviewed
for that article and no comic,
I know who's worth his shit would
okay.
Would want to take time out of that
day. Cause that's a, that's like,
yeah.
At the very least,
the only people they got were
either struggling new or old,
desperate like comics who just needed 25
bucks to be part of this study and then
their comics.
There's no fucking way I would ever go
into a lab in somebody like asking me
questions.
There is no fucking way I could resist
giving misinformation and watching the
guy write it down and add it into
his lab book with fucking beakers and
graduated cylinders behind him.
I would have all I could do
to hold a straight face throughout
the entire process. So, um,
look, if you want to know why
people are funny, it's a gift.
You're just born with it
the same way somebody can,
a carpenter is born with the gift. You
just, you're just born with gifts. That's,
it's just a, it's a gift. It's not
like, oh, maybe if I'm more like this,
I'll be funnier.
You just either can do it or you can't.
And then like any gifts,
if you work at it,
if you appreciate the gift you've been
given, and then you try to develop it,
you can get better at it.
You could actually get funnier if you
push yourself. It's weird. I didn't think,
I thought you were kind of
born with your level of funny,
but it's like any other talent.
You just got to keep working.
But if you're not born with it, it's
like me. I can't, I mean I can't sing.
I'd love to be able to sync doesn't stop
me from singing on the fucking podcast,
but like you,
you gotta be born with that Geeky.
I could take as many singing lessons as
I wanted to when you could sit there and
try to break down the
psychology of a musician.
I'm not a musician as much
as I would love to be.
I still play drums as of as a fucking
hobby. I also cook a little bit,
but you wouldn't want to go
to my restaurant there. Right.
So that's what I think about.
I think it's ridiculous.
And I thought it was really funny that
some of the tweets I got where, um,
I love this one guy,
like just the fucking ego on
just the average everyday person.
Cause they always talking about how
people in the public eye are egomaniacs.
I don't think we're any different than
anybody in the fucking crowd to Same
Level Eagle. Some guy sends me
this fucking tweet and he goes,
this article proves what I've
always thought about comedians.
Oh really?
Your study that you never did with all
the comedians you never hung out with.
And this, this one fucking
article proves it. I don't know.
It's more like, aren't you just unhappy
with your own life on some level?
And it's great to see that they're
saying that these people, uh,
who do this admirable thing
or actually all psychopaths.
So it makes you feel better
about whatever your lot in life.
I don't fucking know. Um, whatever.
That's, that's what I feel about it.
I might be wrong. Maybe I'm a psycho
and I can't wrap my head around it.
All right. Imperial
Japanese hold, hold out.
Dies at 91 hey wild bill.
Read Cock.
Oh that's so childish. Shit.
They always make me laugh. Ah,
you'll like this article.
One of several Japanese soldiers who
continued to fight the war until the 1970s
deep in the jungles of the
Philippines recently died at 91 yeah,
I talked about a couple of these guys.
It was like three of them who didn't
know the war was ended and you know,
even when the, the, the, the leaflets
of the flyers were dropped from planes.
They thought it was a allied propaganda
and they just held the company line.
I think one of them,
one of them,
the first guy I think was the 1960s they
finally got him late sixties and then
they got two others in like
the early seventies I think.
One guy went all the way to 1974
basically the end of the Vietnam War.
He was still on some godforsaken island
out in the Pacific fight in World War II.
Anyway,
so he said it took his former commanding
officer to find them in the jungle,
in his jungle,
hide out and tell him it was a rap and
he needed to stop killing Filipinos for
him to finally come home.
The guy was convicted.
Guy was convinced seeing all the u s
military air traffic heading to Vietnam
that the war was still on despite hundreds
of leaflets and newspapers flown in
and dropped to his location.
Uh, the link is below.
Go Fuck yourself and up to see you
in Cleveland soon. Yeah, that's it.
It's a fascinating,
fascinating fucking story that that's
what was a major chunk of that man's life.
Uh,
Jesus Christ,
if I ever for some reason was chosen
to give a speech on sticktuitiveness,
that would probably be the a, the B beat.
That guy would be the lightning rod.
The crux of the speech. Um, anyways,
our long distance hiking is this, there's,
this led is the last one. Everybody,
this is it. And then that's all there
is for this week. Long distance hiking.
Hey Bill,
on January on the January 7th podcast,
you went off about getting stuck in the
woods alone in mauled by giant animals.
Last September,
me and two buddies height in height,
a portion of the hundred
mile wilderness in Maine,
which is the last leg of the
Appalachian trail, took four days.
They went 40 miles in five mountains
with 35 pound packs on our backs.
Dude, I'm getting scared. Just
fucking hearing about that.
I know there's a lot of people
who fucking pussy go out there,
go out there with you and a couple of
your fucking buddies when you can't hear,
see or anything other
than just fucking nature.
And you start seeing tracks of animals
that could mall you to death and it is no
fucking joke.
MMM.
He said on our fourth and final day in
the woods after getting rained on all
night,
we encountered a bull Moose on the trail.
If you've never seen a moose close up,
they're fucking huge. Jesus Christ. Dude,
I thought you were going to go a
little more in depth than that.
I was all excited. I've never seen
him most close up. Yeah, yeah,
they're fucking huge.
Oh, it goes on a little more like
a full size pickup truck. Huge.
At first it didn't see us,
which is always dangerous.
And then like a scene out of a movie,
my friends stepped on a twig
and it snapped under his foot.
What happened next was the most finked
sphincter that I say it tightening
experience of my life.
This thing lifted his head up,
looks me right in the eye and starts
charging down the trail at us. Oh my God.
All three of us dropped our packs and
ran as fast as we could off the trail.
Fortunately,
Moose have shitty eyesight,
so we were able to lose it.
You know what I was actually picturing
is I'm just picturing Zidane old Charisse
skating at me and just
hoping he can't turn.
Fortunately Moose have shitty eyesight.
I figure what those long skinny legs,
they can't, you know, if you do a
little Barry Sanders move, you know,
dodge it at the last second
you said they have shitty eyesight.
So we were able to lose it and he
continued on down the trail. No doubt,
uh,
to scare the shit out of some more hikers.
What we later learn is that September
starts the Rut from Moose mating season.
So not only was this thing pissed, we
were in his house, it wanted to fuck us.
Um, Jesus Christ, you
know, as scary as that is,
I would actually love to do
it just to see if I could, uh,
if I could hike that far,
just the physical test of it,
but I would have to go out there with,
uh, somebody really experienced too.
We had a fucking firearm
cocked and loaded in,
pointed in all directions
and I'm in the center of it.
And then I think I could actually
fucking do it. Whatever. I have respect,
respect for fucking, uh, the wilderness
and I'm, I'm terrified of the ocean.
I won't go in it. It's
fucking nuts. All right.
If you had a medium sized alligator in
a pool, I wouldn't go in that either.
Why would I go into the ocean?
We're all sharks other than
the ones in aquariums exists.
I don't want to fucking do that.
All right. And anyways. All right.
That's the podcast for
this week. Everybody. Um,
okay.
Yeah, that's it. I'm really excited about
the Superbowl and, uh, try it to share.
Try One year, not to just watch all
the fucking hype. Start the game.
An hour and a half late.
Drink a couple millers and put it on.
I'm telling you can actually maybe
get for the old guys out there.
Maybe you can get back to some
of the way it used to be. Um,
okay.
You know, back in the old
fucking days. All right.
That's the podcast for this week.
Uh, that's it. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you next weekend.
Next week I'll be telling you stories
about Hawaii and the pro bowl always in
that exciting. Well, it is to me.
Oh.