Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burn his time for the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
November 23rd, 2015 what's going on? How?
What's up? Oh Billy red
face. So Billy red cakes.
Oh fucking what are you doing?
Douchebag.
Freckles here is integrate Moody's on
is for dumb with his first week and not
doing shit.
I'm not doing shit for the last week.
I already did it already accomplished
a dream of not doing shit.
And this week I'm not doing shit right.
Greatest fucking holiday.
The year everybody talks about Christmas.
People talking about flag day,
fucking Easter.
I'm telling you this is the one you
don't have to buy shit. Oh you though.
You just show up. You show up
little corn, beef and cabbage,
whatever the whatever your little
family fucking dishes. You show up,
you smile, you do a couple
of air kisses, you know,
feed your fat fucking face and then
you just slip into the living room,
right?
And watch the game sitting on the sofa.
Then there's that other guy that's
socially fucking awkward guy who hides and
alcohol sitting in the lazy boy.
You know,
you guys are angled just enough that you
can see each other in your peripheral
but you never say anything.
You know,
a couple of times you go to start the
conversation and you see the lonely guy
being excited,
but then he fucks it up.
He seen withdraw again and you try to
act like it didn't happen and that's just
a second quarter. All right. Anyways,
um,
I find I did my official way in
today to see the damage I did.
I was about a buck 65 or something before
I left to go to way back in September.
Right.
I was trying to get down to one 62 I
got to one 65 and one day I just skipped
rope and just sweated it out.
I got to like one 62 point something
but that's bullshit. Right.
Got down on one 65 then I had a wedding
week long family event and then right
after that I went to Texas for a week
and then Toronto and it came back for a
few days and then I went to DC. Then I
came back for a few days, like a week,
and then I did that two
week fucking tour of, uh,
the Midwest came back for three days.
Then I did the Philly run,
then I went to New York and I did MSG.
So in that time I knew I
was putting on way, uh,
I knew I was doing, I knew
what I couldn't, I couldn't
stop, right? All right.
Now before I started this whole thing,
I was 187 pounds of getting down to
one 65. I lost 22 fucking pounds.
So the big question is, Bill, you dumb.
Fuck. After you did all that work,
you stupid cunt.
How much did you give back this morning
after weighing himself in September before
all the festivity of you see what I'm
talking about? 165 pounds. I weighed
myself this morning, right when I woke up,
the most accurate weight from
what I've read on the Internet.
So take that with a giant
grain of salt. And, uh,
one 76.8.
Ah,
Billy, what did you do? I just
remember my last night in New York,
fucking hammered eating
two slices of a sausage,
Pepperoni, and it wasn't even good. And
after the first one, I was like, Jesus,
this is so much shit on this.
This feels like Chicago pizza
where like nobody in there,
nobody in their right mind ever has more
than one slice of deep dish pizza he
had just fucking can't do it.
You're, you're out of your
fucking mind. So anyways,
um, yeah. So I'm pissed that
I fucking went that hard,
fucked it up that much, but I'm
not, I didn't see the dreaded,
the one that really depresses me is
when that second number is an eight.
So I'm going to try to do the impossible.
The other thinkable Cleo, we have
stopped licking yourself so damn loud.
Hey Cleo,
Cleo,
we get you knock it off over there.
I know you gotta do what you gotta do.
You need a bath?
Okay.
Anyways, the fuck was I talking about? Oh,
I'm gonna try to do the impossible.
The unthinkable. Now this, she goes,
look at herself again. Good
Lord. No shame whatsoever.
I'm going to try to lose weight
during the holiday months here.
I'm actually during the week of
Thanksgiving, I'm trying to get to,
my goal is to be a,
to do the three pounds that I was doing
back in the summer drop three weeks.
So that's one 73.8 is when I need to be
next Monday morning when I roll out of
bed. And um, so we'll see what
happens. But he has a fucked up thing.
I made three Pi's yesterday.
All right.
I'm not all for me obviously just people
come by the house and stuff like that.
So I made a cream pie or pumpkin pie and
an apple pie and I actually fucked with
the sacred family recipes.
Now I even had a slice of any of it yet,
but I up the cinnamon
in my apple pie and um,
and I use this, this different recipe
was a butter base crust. And um,
my wife sent me a fucking text message.
I thought the house was on fire.
It was just Omg, Omg, Omg, OMG.
I can't even say it that fast
to fucking say it slower.
Bill will be still on the stand. She wrote
Omg like 50 times in a row. So I was,
I had gone, I was driving. So I texted
while driving of course. And I said,
pie question mark,
question Mark House fire question mark.
And then she did a bunch of
Emoji Emoji Shit. And uh,
she wrote that pie is fucking delicious.
I said, how's the new cinnamon levels?
She said perfect. And then I said yes
with an exclamation point. How about that?
You got to hear my whole
private text message
now that's the best apple
pies. A motherfucker, you know,
I don't know how you guys do it.
I use it like three different types of
apples got appeal and then you quarter
and then you try to get like eight slices,
right? You slice them nice and thin.
The Way Paul,
he does the garlic and fucking good
fellas and you gotta you gotta have your
mics ready though. So they don't
turn Brown. You stick them in there,
you swish it around and all that.
You make sure it gets all over the
place and then, then the fucking,
the apples all intermingle, you know what
I mean? Like, like, like the higher ups.
Don't want us to, everybody getting
along. I'm fucking with you.
I guess why I went down to the
comedy store yesterday for the,
for my first set since,
uh,
my last show in New York and I went
down there, I had the best fucking time.
I try it out,
all this new material and I actually
walked into the comedy store and you know,
they have the original room and
then they have the main room.
The original room is the
part of the original club
when they just bought half of
it.
It used to be in a nightclub called
Ciro's and a with the original room sits I
think was the back of the main
room. So, um, and he's whatever,
come out to la, just walk
in, take a look at it.
So I got what's going on in the main room
and they go, Dick Gregory, I go white.
They go, Dick. Great. I go, Dick Gregory
is on stage right now. And they were like,
yeah. And I went in there and the guy was
fucking hilarious. Still funny as hell.
Still Edgy, talking about topical
stuff. He was talking about Paris,
he was talking about all this
just right up to date stuff. Um,
he was fucking amazing. So that gave me
a charge. So then I go into the, the uh,
the original room, they bring
me up, I start doing my thing,
everything's going great.
You know, I did my little one
wage gap, gift, a joke, and then
I get off stage, thanks a lot.
And uh,
all of a sudden there's lay,
she comes up to me and then she just
wants to present her case. She's like,
you know,
well actually I'm in my mid thirties,
and now I'm at an age now that when I
go out with a guy, he wants to go Dutch.
She expects me to pay for half and
then I just go, well yeah, you should,
you know,
it should.
No, this is asking too much.
You're in your thirties.
You've demonstrated that you're not a
first round draft pick at this point.
You know you fucked up like
me so I know I'm fucked up.
I know you're fucked up or maybe
too driven to commit to anything.
So you know, we got to keep each
other at arm's length here, right?
So I paid for my shit. You pay
for your shit. I couldn't be like,
I couldn't even listen to like that's
lets your big fucking complaint life that
for the first 30 years you got free
fucking food and drinks like as a guide.
You know how far back
into my life I got them.
They get to live like eight year olds.
When when you were a kid you just walked
around as a kid, you had no money.
You went out with your parents yet
all fucking day. Yay you had drinks,
you fucking on booze. But you know, cut
yourself a high c, whatever the you had,
you know,
went
to a ball game, whatever. You
never went in your pockets.
The life of a kid,
you know,
you essentially in that nightlight,
look,
I obviously know that women don't
just not pay for fucking anything,
but I'm just saying that
when they get courted,
you know,
you don't have to pay for Shit
generally speaking. Right.
So anyways, so she comes up to me and I
just didn't want to fucking hear it. And,
uh, I made the mistake, I treated her like
a guy and I feel bad. I just completely,
I just gave a shit and then she was like,
going how you're being mean and
everything I make, it's a comedy club,
but Canadians,
this is what we do.
Okay.
And then she wanted to make her
fucking point and I just, you know,
I just walked away and then of course
I made the mistake of asking another
comic. I goes, I just two main
there. And he's like, yeah, no, no.
Comedian will never say you're to me
felt like the, uh, the
right level of it. Um,
that's a pet peeve of mine.
I don't like when I'm standing on stage
and you could heckle me while I'm making
my point. Instead, you don't,
you wait until I get off stage and then
you want to have some fucking, you know,
Charlie rose conversation about
what the fuck you think of the jail.
I don't give a shit at
that point. I, you know,
I would much rather that
you yell out during my show.
Okay,
I'm in my thirties.
I got to pay for a date that we could
have had that hilarious conversation a
little back and forth.
But instead, you know,
I got to get off stage and then you come
up to me like I'm being debriefed after
my shift. You know what I
mean? See where I went. Right.
To see where I went wrong. Like,
I don't want to fucking hear that.
But you're more than welcome to heckle me.
I don't give a shit.
I don't care about that. You know, I'm
up there just me and the mic stand.
You know, I feel safe.
Uh, who's given you,
I was probably too much of
an asshole. What do, what
do, what do you want from me?
So anyways,
what the fuck happened to my Lsu Tigers?
Jesus Christ. I'm not even what
was on the road. A lot to shoe,
so I missed most of the season,
but I watched the end of the Alabama game.
They lost that game and the fucking
wheels fell off and they got their asses
kicked by Arkansas. Who even knew they
still had a football program out there?
I mean it's Arkansas. When was the
last time you even heard of that state?
Bill Clinton was in office and that
was only in the first term that former
governor, a little rock,
Arkansas. All right.
By the time he got to his second term,
they phased out Arkansas,
like the older brother on happy
days. Right? No more chuck.
Now he's at school now he doesn't exist.
Right.
I'd a fuck do you lose to them then?
Add in the Midwest and not in the south.
They're just there.
The name their capital.
Okay.
Little Rock. It's got little. How does he,
how does your capital have little in it?
Yeah. Unbelievable. We fucking lose to
them. What do you mean? What are you,
he goes on in Arkansas.
Yeah.
Some reason why I think
Arkansas, you know, I think of,
I think of like an
Oldsmobile four, four, two.
Yeah,
I guess 65 for some reason.
I know that riding around it,
but they're all driving around
old cars like Cuba, you know?
But that embargo hit them real hard to,
even though there's no embargo on them,
but to just Arkansas. How to
Fuck d lose to Arkansas. Um,
I'm just waiting for
those fucking Arkansas sc.
See if you were actually
in the conference.
I don't care.
Okay.
And then who the fuck did they play
this past week? Uh, all miss. No,
right down there on the goal line.
And one guy thinks it's a fake play.
The other guy's trying to hand it
off to him was fucking keystone cops.
Yeah.
Keystone cops.
This is what kills me.
They'll probably end up getting rid
of les miles. You know what I mean?
I love that one bad fucking year.
And then all of a sudden you don't
know how to coach anymore. He watched,
they'll run them right out, you
know? Well, show me, show me.
He's got to answer to this. Nobody
could just just be like, you know what?
We had a bad fucking year. It's gotta
be like, Oh, you know what? That's it.
You're done.
You don't know how to do this anymore.
Does that happen at your guys' jobs?
You know what I mean?
Say you're working at staples,
right, and you fucking a,
you're going down to the dial with the
three ring binders and you think they're
on the lefthand side. They were on
the right hand side. Then they go,
you know why you just can't do it anymore.
It's over.
You've been here for fucking four years.
I don't think you're not to work at
staples anymore. I know I'm, I'm, I'm,
I guess I'm belittling both people
belittling that job and I was a belittling
the job of working at staples.
I think the job at staples is a big thing
as you hide in the back room because
they have so little people on the floor.
If you walk out on the floor,
everybody's going to ask you a question.
Right?
You're going to walk out and ski with me.
Excuse me
sir, sir, sir? Yes.
Could you tell me where
my dad is? Age, birthdays coming up
and we had Devon Kelley paper. Yeah.
That's when you should legally be able
to just grab somebody by the back of the
head and steer them towards
where they need to be. You know,
this then like push their head down to
see where it is on the shelf and then as
you go to let go,
you give them that little push before
you do that causes them to do that half a
step and put their hands out like
a toddler about ready to fall. Um,
anyways, um, I barely watched
any football yesterday.
I got a couple of things done that,
uh,
we're hanging over my head that we're
going to cause me to not enjoy my fucking
holidays. Um, I am now at the age is,
it's somebody asked me to write
a letter of recommendation
for this fucking thing and I just kept
putting it off and putting it off and I
was like, you know, Bill, this person just
trying to get on with their life here.
So I just sat down and fucking
forced all my add away.
You know, I opened the email, but I
looked at a bunch of other emails first.
I gradually closed all the windows and a,
I missed all the one o'clock games.
I caught the tail end of the cowboys game.
I was psyched for the cowboys.
How fucking nuts is it that
they're undefeated with Tony Romo?
But the 10 games in,
it's just a fucking tragedy.
They were two and all Tony breaks
gets his fucking collarbone broken.
They lose seven in a row.
They go all four fucking seven
that totally comes back. Boom.
It's like he never left. You know,
like that old friend you don't see for
20 fucking years and you can see each
other. You just start laughing. You pick
up right where you left off. Tony Romo.
Tony Romo. I want to get a
cowboy. Feds bitch about them now.
Huh? Hey, you go. You got what you wanted.
You got Tony out of the fucking
line up and look what happened. Oh,
four fucking seven.
Okay,
so now he's back.
Anyone I love is the fucking NFC.
He sucks so bad that they could actually
go on a run and still win the division.
Okay.
You know, that's what's killing
me about the giants right now.
Cause I know I told you I never
want to see the giants can,
I don't give a fuck that we beat him
in the regular season and thought it
doesn't matter. Okay. I can't,
I, I can't handle another,
I can handle another Superbowl loss.
I can't handle another loss the way we
lose to the giants and just can't do it.
You know Tony Romm Rama Fades back.
That's a show comes up.
He does a show by accident.
Everybody goes after the show. A
tacky Friday. What? The football?
My Lane,
our touchdown.
Fuck that.
I can't,
I can't watch another one of
those John Brady back to pass.
He's got to throw in fucking
half a yard or Westworld.
Correct.
I can't, I can't, I don't even
want to fucking deal with that.
And this is what kills me.
The giants whose absolutely
have absolutely shit the
bed this year are in first
place. I think with like
a fucking, you know,
foreign six record or something.
You know,
I could just go on the Internet and I
could look this shit up or I could just
wing it. Um, no. Who's kidding? Who?
I would love to play the giants
again as long as we win, you know,
to try it. But I even know if it was like
going to be a 50 50 and be like, yeah,
you know, I don't need to go
through that emotionally anymore.
I really don't fucking kills me. How
much these stupid losses, you know,
I never get a ring.
They don't ask me to get on the
duck boats for the parade duty.
Why the fuck do I care?
Why am I absolutely elated that the
Bruins if on two games in a row right now,
Huh? I don't know. I have no idea. Second,
Wayne big winning against
the Toronto Maple leafs.
I've been at home getting caught up
with them being all they look all right.
Last couple games they look are right.
Definitely up and down season. Um,
so I don't know,
I won't pack it in until like February
and in February they still doing this
stuff. Then he stuck getting
those awful feelings.
Waikiki almost want your team to lose
so they get a better draft pick. Um,
but uh, I cannot, I can't
fucking do that. But anyways, oh,
did I miss it yesterday
to the islanders and uh,
Canadians play job bite
next from puck off.
Told me that there was going to be bad
blood is going to be some bad blood in
that game. I think I fucking
missed it. So anyways,
but the big game tonight is a Ulu
to do is a patriots first the bills.
So,
um,
I'm going to try to do my best to get in
front of a TV so I can listen to bills,
fans talking shit again, uh,
about what they're going to do,
what we should have done. Right.
They're going to get all like, fuck Gig,
you fucking there.
I already got a text from somebody.
So one of my friends out there,
I think the shred and Reagan show,
they texted me going,
the Patriots are going to get their
asses whipped and I just wrote back,
uh,
who were they playing?
He goes to play in the bills
this year is super bowl champion.
And I just wrote back, I said,
well it should be a great game.
You guys have a wonderful defense.
Good luck
just to fuses all this shit out.
Why is a, why you talking shit?
You know what I mean?
Dude,
the little fucking call me for good.
He's going to do it for getting one
if he does it. And what if he does?
What are you going to do?
Huh?
You going to sit there and
grow your man tits with me?
You don't want to fucking do it.
You know?
And I was watching a Bruins game and
I was so disgusted with myself. Um,
I had this workout for
like the last two periods.
Every five minutes of the
game I would do 25 push ups.
Um, it's an easy way to do
200. You know what I mean?
You get nice long rest depending on uh,
how many penalties are
called and commercial breaks.
Just every five minutes you bang out 25.
I've got to do something guys.
I made three fucking pies.
I'm in trouble here. Um,
but the key is I haven't had one yet so
I don't have the crack rolling around in
my fucking system. All right, here we go.
Let me do some reads here for
this fucking weekend course.
I got to type in my fucking podcast
and I park my password. Sorry.
See that I can't do two things at once.
Like with like the women can
like the ladies. Um, alright.
What the fuck is it? Oh, here
we go. The old favorites here.
We've got a couple this week. All
right. Trunk Club, everybody, you know,
last minute gifts, crowded airports. The
family who wants to deal with that shit.
You have enough to worry
about during the holidays.
Your outfits shouldn't be one of them.
Trunk Club has your back Trunk Club had
it takes the hassle man out of shopping
by shipping a trunk of
clothes that fit perfectly and make you
look like 1 million bucks with all the
new fall and winter styles@trunkclub.com
slash [inaudible] you answer simple
questions about your style,
your preferences and size,
and are assigned an expert stylist.
They cure rate close.
Oh, what a great word.
They cure rate clothes from the best
premium blend Brent brands and you approve
what you like.
I like to do is get rid of that and just
like that a trunk arrives on your step
filled with hand pick clothes that are
perfect for you right at right from the
venue. Migrant workers just picking
genes off of the genes tree.
Try them on.
Keep what you like an easy return,
what you don't in their prepaid trunk.
This is not a subscription.
You son of a bitch, you only pay for
the clothes you keep from your trunk.
No hidden charges, just great
clothes. Call to action offer.
It's the busiest,
most hectic time of the year.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But you can look still look fantastic.
Great.
Get started today and Trunk
Club will style you for free.
You free shipping both ways.
You only pay for the clothes that you
keep to take advantage of Trump cup.
Go to trunk club.com/burr one last time.
Hey,
trunk club.com/burr for a trunk filled
with clothes you'll love wearing.
Oh, and here we go. Oh, our favorite
here? Bodo boop, boop, me undies,
me on d no more drippy
balls. Go Dude, dude, dude,
me undies, me undies. Don't grab one.
Grab 'em all shaky and
nuts saw nice and dry.
You and you put on these underwear,
your balls will be high.
Like they ate a fucking pot cookie,
except it's your balls and not your brain.
Oh yeah, you probably got more hair
down there. All right, Mandy's,
let's talk about your underwear
and needs to be comfy.
It's gotta be snug and all the
right places. It's gotta look good.
It's got to feel good. Can't write up
your butt crack. You know what I mean?
But it can't lead you balls hanging
Jesus Christ.
It's no wonder they don't fucking just
measure your whole fucking pelvic area.
I'd like to thank all of our pelvises
are different, just like fingerprints,
but despite that it'd be nice if we
could still find a common ground.
Oh,
you don't just want your underwear comfy.
You want the world's most comfortable
underwear and you know what that is.
Sure you do. It's me undies. There
it is across the bar staring at you.
It just sent you a drink.
It's winking, invited over,
bite it over. Right up against
you. Fucking under carriage.
Please include all of the following
points during your week. Well,
I've got to read what you're
fucking roach. You assholes.
No modal is pronounced mode out.
Every pair of me undies is made
of Micro Matt Modal, Modal Fabric,
which doesn't sound sexy,
but once you feel you're Mandy,
she'll never back to regular old
underwear again.
You can't believe
how massage your balls are going to be
and let's not forget about the tape and
the tape can only lead one way
right into your asshole. Yup.
That all fucking hold of the center of
the Earth when it'd be nice if that had a
nice fucking velvet,
he fucking rubbed down to act.
Now we'll throw in me undies,
asshole bleach for just for free.
It's a bleach strip that goes right
up the cracky erass with me undies.
You'll feel more comfortable
than ever before me.
And he says a ton of different colors
to choose from. Jason's I suck.
It's the, it's the only
place what me. And he says,
a ton of different colors to choose from
is the only place to find styles for
both men and the fucking ladies and
a new signature design every month.
And with the holidays around the corner,
me undies makes the perfect gift.
Trust me, these are not your
parents stocking stuffer. Uh,
so go to [inaudible] dot com slash bar
right now. Get 20% off your first order,
plus all orders in the u s and Canada,
or we shipped for free.
Mandy's even has a money back guarantee.
All right?
And if you don't like how you balls
fill in these goddamn things, you know,
you can just,
I don't know,
you get to keep your first pair
for free and get a full refund.
You literally have nothing to lose.
Um,
order of before December 13th and your
Mandy's will arrive in time for Christmas
for 20% off your first order of the
world's most comfortable underwear.
Head to [inaudible] dot
com slash bird right now.
That's [inaudible] dot com slash
[inaudible] [inaudible] dot com slash bar
all right, I got a couple of,
a couple of things I need to,
uh, announce here. Uh, the fourth
annual Patrice O'neil comedy benefit.
I want to thank everybody that
bought tickets for this thing. It,
that tickets are selling a faster than
ever and that just reminded me what the
me undies thing, the stocking stuffer,
it makes a great stocking stuffer.
All right.
Um,
you get to see some of the top comics in
the country honoring the greatest comic
I ever saw live and a honoring his
memory and helping out as loved ones.
Uh, I'm just going to get to New York
City Center on Tuesday, January 26th.
You know,
it just go to the frigging website.
I'll retweet the link once again today.
I got the date up on my website,
the whole damn thing.
Um,
the great thing about this great gift to
get to for somebody in all you gotta do,
go on the Internet, click, click,
Click Bing, Bang, boom, you're done.
Stick it in the stocking and then he can
go right over to spike in your eggnog.
All right. And then also an old friend
of mine has a new album coming out.
If you guys like straight ahead blues,
someone that can absolutely fucking shred
on the guitar and has a fucking voice
to match.
Felicia Collins has a new album out
called Felicia Collins discovers the blues
straight ahead blues album. She sent me a
couple of the tracks. Me and Bart. Nick,
we'll listen to it. The other night we,
uh, nick was over here watching a Chicago,
Vancouver and I'm absolutely
blown away. Um, for those you,
David Letterman fans. Uh,
she played in the, uh,
CBS Orchestra and she was actually there
when they were way back when they were
on NBC. And um, so obviously the show's
over and now she's stretching out.
So check it out. Tuesday, Felicia
Collins new album, the Felicia,
Felicia Collins discovers the blues.
Um,
okay.
All right. And what else do
I got coming up? I have, um,
of course F is for family is
out on December 18th and uh,
oh and p Corey Ellie is going to be a
guest on the Thursday afternoon podcasts
just before Friday next week to promote.
Uh,
I believe it was new
standup special on showtime,
which I heard is getting rave reviews.
He's one of my favorite comics of all
time and he's a great guy to go and see
before he fucking blows up because
he's that level funny. Um, all right.
And with that,
but that babbling,
let's march on here with the podcast.
Um,
what was I going to
say? Yeah, so I got it.
I'm going to go to the fucking gym today.
At the second I do this.
So this is my game plan.
I'm going to do an hour
on the elliptical today,
Tuesday and Wednesday.
MMM.
I'm doing the Joe Joe
Rogan's podcast on Tuesday,
tomorrow. So, uh,
I might bring some of that
pie that I made over to them,
you know,
which should be a cool thing
to do for the holidays.
Plus then I don't have it around here,
so I'm not fucking eating it. Right.
And then all they do is eat one.
I think that could work, right?
You've got to give away some of it.
Um,
but I'm going to do that three
hours of that by thanksgiving.
Am I one bad day is going
to be Thanksgiving then
I'm just gonna try to, uh,
I gotta turn around guys.
If I go back up to the one 80 zone
would be so fucking depressed.
I just don't want to be that fucking
guy at the start of the year. Like, Oh,
good to fucking,
yeah.
Okay,
here we go. I'm going to
fucking get in shape. You know?
You know what that's like.
You know, it's like starting
your year as a fat fuck.
Who's got dropped like fucking 20,
30, 40, 50, a hundred fucking pounds.
It's the worst. Why not get started
now and not do the fucking damage?
You know what I mean? You know, that
awesome feeling you get, you know,
okay,
if before you go to work, you make the
bed and you come home and the bed's made,
you know,
that fucking feeling.
Or maybe the night before you did all
the dishes and you wake up to make
breakfast and there's no dishes
from the night before that, that,
that ahead of the game feeling,
you know, or at least I'm even,
you know what I mean?
Like,
I don't get to start my day
doing yesterday's bullshit
plus whatever the fuck
hits me today.
Um,
that's what it's like to be on
January 1st to actually be in shape.
And I don't think I've, I've
done that since my twenties, so,
um,
okay.
I'm really gonna try and,
uh,
it always helps me to announce it on the
podcast and I'm going to fucking do it
because I know you guys will fucking,
you guys are going to check in on me
and you're going to give me shit when I,
you know, if I'm not talking about it,
you know, I'm not doing well and God
knows you guys like to be mean,
but I probably deserve it after what
a cunt I was to that lady last night.
I wasn't even a cunt.
It's just the fact that she's a woman.
You need just supposed to,
you know, you're just supposed
to let him win. Be Like,
oh wow. Wow. Yeah. You,
you, you and you. Yeah,
that's exactly what the joke was
about was all about you. All of you.
Why not talk about all of you?
Your so interesting.
Please tell me another story about your
Damn Day and what you said and all my
God, what you were like. So I
said this and then she said that,
and then I was like,
okay
ladies, how do you not see the pain in
your man's face when you're doing that?
You know what I mean?
I see the pain in my wife's face when I
tried to talk to her about a game, man,
it was fucking two minutes left, right?
Patriots or getting killed on defense.
Right. We get the ball back.
Tom Brady throws the ball.
Giant guy grabbed any fucking lands on
his stomach, not just window. By then,
it's just fucking over. She just
starts making fun of me. Really?
Oh my God. That's amazing. Just
give a fuck. You know what?
If I don't listen to her fucking stories,
oh Jesus. Oh, forget about it. To be,
it's a big Goddamn, I don't
know what it is. Um, anyways,
let's get to some of the reads for
this week. Okay? Yeah. Bell, it's fine.
It's absolutely fine.
All I'm doing the comedy jam tonight
are right with the fucking,
yeah,
the fucking text message is there.
Um, let's read the text message.
I was that somebody else
who saw the F is for family.
Okay.
Yeah, I saw the trail. People are like
in the trailer. Thank Christ. All right.
Uh, venue dear Billy, big shot.
Okay.
Now that you've done the
mother of all venues with Msg,
what non traditional venue
would you like to play?
Like something like the Great Wall of
China. Congrats on your year ago. Fuck
yourself. Um, no, there's still a,
there's still a bunch
that I would love to play.
A Royal Albert Hall is on my bucket list.
Um, and, but then there's also,
there's a bunch of theaters that I would
still like to play or continue playing.
There's the one on out here
in California in Long Beach.
So Long Beach something or other
where Richard Pryor did his, uh,
live in concert.
Um,
I already did a show at the palladium.
That's where he did live on the
sunset strip. And I forget if the,
the one that he performed at when he did
his here and now, which I think was in,
uh, New Orleans. I got to see
if that one's still exists.
But I really,
uh,
I like doing those old theaters.
I like doing a man.
It's like going to old ballparks and
you hear all the people that were there
like last night when we were
down the, um, the comedy
store, this is just
characters just show up,
right? Dick Gregory's onstage.
And then this other guy comes
in cause he knew Dick Gregory.
He was the publicist for Ciro's. There
was this nightclub. I said it became a,
the comedy store. And uh,
you know, when Frank Dean,
Sammy and all of them were down there,
he was just naming all of these
fucking names. He said, hey, he goes,
I first came here in 1950 so immediately
doing the math going, Jesus Christ,
if this guy was like 20 in 1950,
that's 65 fucking years ago.
He's 85. He didn't look like it was in
his eighties. He actually looked great.
But, um, so let's see what
venue. You know, red rocks.
I performed there though, but I, I
did, I did red rocks when it was, uh,
there was some sort of animation
thing going on after it.
So when do you get the comic comedy works?
Uh,
got me the Gig and we went out there,
but it was cool to be at red rocks,
but uh, they weren't there for me.
They were there for the fucking film.
So there was a lot of chatter. But um,
okay.
A lot of the things on my
bucket list are venues that, um,
that either bands played in that I love
and had some live album there or as
comedians that did a, uh, special there.
So I told you when I was in hammer town,
they're up in fucking, uh, Toronto,
Ontario. I mean, I know
Ontario and it's Toronto. Um,
okay.
They just kept calling a hammer town.
I can't remember the name of the town,
but it's south of Toronto.
I didn't realize I performed
until after I was there.
I performed at the theater were bill
Cosby did bill Cosby himself. Um,
arguably the greatest special of all time,
you know, now what he did afterwards.
I don't want to get involved in that.
Um,
so that was cool.
okay.
I did a,
yeah, that's a great question. I
don't know. I just want to keep going.
I liked going to venues
that I'd never been to.
You know what I really enjoyed this
year was when I was doing the tour of
California going to Reno and Bakersfield
and Fresno and they were along the old
school highways where
people were site too,
like the highway went
right down main street.
So they would have some big fancy sign,
you know,
Reno biggest little's town and
uh, you know, the West Fresno,
you know, whatever the fuck
their slogan is. You know,
they would always have like town and then
some sort of slogan Bakersfield, like,
Hey, stop and stay awhile, you
know, some corny shit. But um,
okay,
I really liked that route.
66 type of stuff. And uh,
as far as Europe goes, that's to me is
all about world war two, World War One,
those, you know, those types of
places. But as far as performing,
I don't know enough about Europe and
that type of thing. Uh, I did look up,
you know, Ac DC where they recorded a,
if you want blood, their live album,
that was a place, I believe it
was in Glasgow or Edinburgh,
I want to say Glasgow,
but, uh, the venue
doesn't anymore. So, um,
yeah,
so that I would say that I get a big
charge out of a music place cause I'm a
total nerd when it comes to that shit.
And, uh, I remember when I was in England,
London a couple of years ago accidentally
coming upon that Ronnie Scott's and I
saw Jeff Beck have one of
the great fucking was him,
Vinny Coley Uda and that chicken base.
And they just will fucking unbelievable.
Like Jimmy page was in the
crowd, you know, sinking down
in his seat. Like, Oh yeah,
I stole that riff on, it was still on that
one from him and nick in it, I believe,
as they call it. So yeah, there's
still plenty left. And, um,
the MSG for me was not as much
as it was a high watermark.
It wasn't like this, you know, and
now I just slide down the back nine.
For me it was,
uh,
it just felt more like an honor to be
there and it was mine for an hour and a
half. And then, you know,
the second you leave somebody else's name
was on the marquee and it's like, wow,
I got to do that. Um, but I got to
tell you, I had just as much fun,
uh,
fucking around with the new stuff.
You know,
it's hard to describe unless
you're a comedian. The
excitement of new stuff. Like,
Oh,
I get to say new shit.
I have to keep saying this stuff and
trying to figure out how to make this
fucking new again tonight.
Um,
so anyways,
so yeah,
I would say I've Royal Albert Hall is
like the next one I'm really thinking
about,
but there's no way there was in something
in Ireland or something in Scotland or,
uh, Finland, Norway. I mean, I
think I'm doing a tour of the, uh,
the fucking, um, eastern Europe.
Be Crazy to play a venue that like fucking
like Hitler or Stalin or Mussolini,
one of those fascists.
When now I get stolen wasn't a fascist,
but one of those fucking maniacs gave his
speech and you know, it's still exists,
you know, fucking nuts, right?
I Dunno. Alright. Baking.
Hey, Bill. Uh, Bacon Bill.
I'm thinking about surprising
my girlfriend and her
family by bringing over a
homemade pie for thanksgiving.
All right, dude. I got you.
I'm going to make two pies
because one isn't enough.
I'm thinking about apple and
Pumpkin also because also,
please know that apple capitalizes apple
as if there's no such thing is fruit.
Oh, the apple company.
Anyways, I know, uh,
from previous years that you're
killing it in the kitchen.
I'll thank you before I called my mom
and her two s and get her 2 cents, uh,
from Youcan, I get some pointers,
some basic do's and don'ts, uh,
when getting into it, should I
avoid either apple, the fruit,
uh, or Pumpkin? Thanks. Um,
Pumpkin pies and an easy recipe.
Apple pies work as far as the filling,
but it's also fucking, now it's apples
and cinnamon. Man. I mean, come on. Um,
I'll give you the biggest, like the
filling is the, is easy. All right. The,
the thing that scares and
intimidates people is doing the, uh,
oh my God guys, do I have to make
a fucking pie crust making video?
I'll fucking do it.
I'll put on the apron.
I'll put on the apron and a silly hat.
You want the,
I'll do that for you for fucking
thanksgiving. How about that?
I will make a fucking pie video,
um,
pie crust video.
Uh,
but if you're going to do it right now,
because I won't get the video up in time,
I will show, I will show you. Uh, I'll
try to walk you through it. All right,
so the recipe that I use,
it's two cups of all purpose flour.
The kinds that people say, you know,
you're gonna die if you eat it.
That's what you want with the pie.
You don't want to go any low fat.
You don't want to go wheat. You don't want
to do any of that fucking stinky feet,
Seattle thing of with it.
All right? You want to go?
Midwest Chicago heart attack.
All right? You're making a pie.
You want to be healthy? Go have a fucking
salad. That's not what we're doing here.
That's not what stock you're crying,
right?
And it's funny.
There's roofers fixing something on my
fucking roof that's never going to be
fixed.
And they probably just heard me yelled at,
now stop your crying and get
out of my kitchen. You know,
that's how rumors start. I know that
guy. That guy tells jokes. Yeah,
he's fucking verbally abusive
to his wife. Um, anyway,
so what you want to do is you
add two cups of flour, okay?
And you get yourself a sifter,
right?
And there's always a little bit of salt.
Go easy on the salt,
like an eighth of a teaspoon. So what I
do is I take the cup of fucking flower,
I poured into the sifter.
The sifter is sitting in the bowl
that you're going to sift into.
Don't just pour it into the sifter and
it's going to end up on your counter.
You don't want that, right?
So you're pouring one cup,
then you put in your salt and you put
your next cup over it. Then you sit there,
right? It comes fucking out. Then a,
and then you add you shortening, right?
I use a stick of butter.
Sorry.
You want it to be cold so it's
not too fucking mushy. Uh,
take it out of the fridge. You
just cut it up and like, you know,
eighth of an inch slices,
you put it in there and then with your
little fucking thing that you hit. See,
this is why I'm gonna to do a video.
You just, you want to cover it, right?
And then you put your shortening
it and then cover that.
You want it to be all like, uh,
like you make an a fucking meatball.
You want to get the bread crumbs
all over except it's the flower.
And then when you do that,
you just lightly tap all the way around.
You know, he let in that
shortening sat kind of get into it.
Then you go a little harder,
a little harder,
gets a little mealy once it's a little
mealy, he started adding your water.
I got to make a video,
I got to make a video and I can also show
you how much you can fuck up acrossed
and still save it. And uh,
uh, you know what, I gotta
do it. I'll actually do that.
But as far, listen man,
pumpkin pie is great,
but if you want to knock people on
their ass, you got to make an apple pie.
And I'd get three different
types of apples. Uh,
throw a granny Smith in there so you got
a bitter thing and then something else
for a little sweeter taste.
You know,
little surf and turf
going on in there and a,
you just make sure you use enough
cinnamon. You know what I mean?
I use about a half a
healthy half a teaspoon.
What has happened to me? I'm literally
just sitting here talking about this shit.
Like I'm about right.
Like it's,
this is a fucking game plan to win
the fucking football game tonight.
Um, all right. So
anyways, holiday wedding,
uh, Billy bell's, my friend
from college is getting married,
uh, the Sunday after Christmas. Oh, Jesus.
What a stupid time to do that was because
everybody's in your hometown. He goes,
is there a worst time for a wedding now?
Can you believe that it's in
upstate New York? Of course I can.
If he's going to be a [inaudible],
he's got to go all the way with it.
I'm sure it'd be fun once I got there,
but I'm thinking about skipping the
circumstances are grounds for not going
right. Absolutely they are. Fuck
that.
Fuck that.
You know what I mean? I always think that
when people do shit like that anyways,
it means one of two things that kind of
hope and most people won't show up or
two, they don't have enough money
to throw a good wedding anyway,
so all that great food.
You're going to walk away from that to
go up there and fucking eat hamburger
helper, you know,
standing out on the stage,
eating the fucking dance
floor, eating a steak, um,
gray, good tags, Calla Bu
du, Du, Du, Du, Du, Du, Du,
and you don't want,
your friends is going to cancel last
second that agreed to go and you're going
to fucking show up day.
There's some shit food being served.
Ride here now.
Some fucking shitty food. It's going
to come out. Chairs. Yeah. Fuck that.
Yeah.
Fuck that.
And he can never give you shit.
All you gotta do for the rest of your
life when he gives you shit or she gives
you shit or whatever about
not going, just, you just,
you don't use you sitting at the bar
and they're fucking [inaudible] man,
you're fucking ear.
You don't,
you just keep looking straight ahead
and he just put throw your hands out and
you just go. You got married
on the Sunday after Christmas.
Yeah.
Who does that?
That's it.
Yeah.
And as they try to defend it.
You just talk over married
the Sunday after Chris,
when?
The Sunday after Christmas.
It's almost like he didn't want me
to be there. If you get divorced,
when are you going to get married
this time? Fucking New Year's Day.
The Fuck Outta here.
Okay.
What do you think you're better than Santa
Claus? You better than the baby Jesus.
Huh? You think you're better
than the prime rip my mother
makes on Christmas Day.
You mother fucker.
Where the fuck do you get
an upstate New York?
How dare you?
I want to be that fucking person
driving in his station wagon
fucking Sunday after critic.
Get to fight this.
This is like my time off. This
is my time. All this is my time.
Okay, I'm going to go to
a God damn wedding. Oh,
that just reeks of like my friend got
ordained as a fucking preacher and he's
going to go up there and his
fucking street clothes. Oh yeah.
I bet they get married and like the
basement of a fucking holiday inn and the
ceremony is going to be going in
the door to the function room,
still going to be open to people and
we randomly walking by looking at it,
you know,
they got to keep the door open because
there's no bathroom in the function room.
See, you gotta walk out. Oh, that's
a shit show. Jesus Christ. It was,
that's like a, it's like a sales
meeting. You don't want to go to, well,
you know what?
I've convinced myself that I wouldn't go.
I don't know what you're thinking,
but I wouldn't go.
That's totally grounds for skipping a
wedding alone is grounds for skipping.
Who the fuck wants to go to that?
Unless you're still in your 20s,
you know, then it's a good time. You
want to go to a wedding single, right?
Go there. Maybe bank, somebody's right.
Have a good time to go there.
You know?
If you're not married then eventually
she's going to look. Oh wait, wait.
Dad I did is,
uh,
when you think of it, just
fucking running, doing a running
jump right off the
balcony. All right. Sleep,
trouble sleeping trouble.
All right. I hate bell.
I just started traveling for work and
getting a good nights and getting a good
night's sleep is brutal.
Yes it is.
I'm not trying ambien or
increasing my alcohol intake.
How do you deal with all
the travel, uh, alcohol? Uh,
do you use a one of those
stupid neck pillows? Nope.
Hotel beds aren't bad if I do sleep well,
I end up waking up feeling comatose,
which leads me to being more tired
cause those beds are huge and soft and I
don't want to get out of bed.
You're also making up for the sleep
that you didn't get on other nights,
which you can't really do. You know,
there's that weird thing that a flake say,
you know, you got six hours one night
and then 10 hours the next night. So
you got, you know, it
averages out to eight hours.
It still doesn't work that way for some
reason. Um, you can't retroactively,
like when you miss out on whatever it
is you need. Some people only need six,
some people just need four. But if you
need like whatever the fuck you need,
I'm saying if you come up short,
you can't just sleep extra
one day and then even it off.
It usually takes like a week. Like I've
been fucking sleep in this whole week.
I'm falling asleep like an old person.
So, um, but anyways, let me continue.
Um,
and I don't want to get out of the
bed. It has, it hasn't happened yet,
but I can see it's slowly turning me
into a grouchy asshole. How do you do it?
Well, you are cheery fellow
before hitting the road.
Thanks for the free labs. Um,
how do I do it? I'm German.
Irish. That's how I do it. Um, we're
not in touch with our feelings,
so even if I am tired,
I'm just naturally trained to
block it out and I just get up and,
um, then I go. But however,
every once in a while when I do make a
conscious effort to think about slowing
down and relaxing and not having
something to achieve every fucking day,
be it picking up dry cleaning
or writing a new joke, um,
I suddenly become aware
of how tired I am. So, um,
what I would do is, yeah, it's not,
not, uh, not use any of the drugs.
And I also wouldn't fuck with alcohol.
I wouldn't do that either.
What I would do is workout in the
morning and then go to your job,
whatever it is that you do.
And then at night,
because you were working all day and you
worked out, you'll actually go to sleep.
If you just get into the good habits
out there, it's not that bad. But,
um, I dunno, biggest thing
that I found him, he sees food.
Food is difficult. And uh, if you're
doing like a bunch of one nighters,
if you like a traveling
salesman kind of fucking thing,
selling your widgets or whatever,
that's when it gets hard because you
spend your day traveling and then you
arrive at the hotel, you fucking
hungry. But you got to go to your Gig.
So you usually end up,
you know,
did you guys get to have anything healthy
way? We got an apple base. Oh yeah.
Do they deliver and you they, yeah,
he sure don't. They sure don't.
Yeah.
Nodding yes.
They sure dope.
Yeah.
You should shake your head.
No.
Okay.
Can I get what I need? You
sure can't. Not In this town.
So then you,
then they always have like fucking menus
and they're always going to give you
some Chinese food,
which is just,
is going to be unfucking believable
or absolutely horrific depending on,
uh,
you know,
it has nothing to do with where you're
at every fucking town in the United
States as Chinese food,
I believe.
And every town has a Chinese
family that moved there, right.
For the most part,
or at least within two towns,
is a Chinese family that moved there and
they will make that fucking food. Now,
whether or not they're people
from China that know how to cook,
that's the fucking rub.
Okay.
You know,
you never know.
Even set and get five and in
the middle of fucking Kansas.
And I got some of the best Sushi
I've ever had. Japanese family,
middle of fucking Kansas. It's
like, how did you end up out here?
Yeah.
Does unbelief. I, I, most of the white
people I know didn't end up out of here.
How did you,
uh,
from Japan end up in
a lazy fucking Kansas.
Oh, speaking of bucket
list, I have like a bunch
of college basketball games I want
to go to. I want to go to Kentucky.
I've always been a Kansas Fan. I
don't know why I want to go to their,
their facility.
I want to go to a Duke Carolina
game at Carolina and at Duke.
Um,
can I have been to UCLA?
Who else has a big basketball
program? Georgetown. Syracuse.
You know the red men,
Saint John's Redmen one of the
fuck they called now the red storm.
I grew up on big east basketball, but uh,
I used to love watching all that shit.
So I've been to Indiana. I told you
guys I went to Indiana University, uh,
university basketball game with Bobby
Knight was still on the team. I was,
I could not fucking believe the level
of which set guy was screaming at his
players was insane.
Come in all the way on his fucking head.
Just snapping is a point that they let
up an easy bucket in the point guard was
bringing it up the court and
the fucking guy, I swear to God,
he walked like 10 feet out into the court.
Everybody was just like intimidated
by him. I just say, just annoyed me.
I wanted to see like somebody
stand up to him, you know,
give the guy next verbal fucking
slap. But it never happened. That guy,
classic example, Eagle completely
out of fucking control. Um,
when he started buying into being Bobby
Knight and he started doing those,
I'm going to be Bobby Knight. You
know, what is, what is a game face.
I never understood that. And he starts
mugging to the camera or when he goes, uh,
you know, I, boy my credits bury me.
They bury me face down so they
can kiss my ass. I was like,
Oh God, shut up. I have another drink. Um,
I just make fun of Bobby Knight. What it,
what the fuck is wrong with me? Um, yeah.
So I'm doing the goddamn
comedy jam tonight at the, uh,
if leaves the lyric theater
on a [inaudible] and I'm
looking forward to doing
that. I got, yeah. You don't want to
tell you guys I've got nothing else.
I can't even do a fucking hour.
That's,
that's how little I've been doing this
week. I got caught up on peaky blinders,
peaky blinders. I don't know
nothing about no robbery, um,
peaky blinders with
subtitles, uh, um, up to the,
a first episode of season two. So I'm
going to blow through that this week.
And then my wife is watching bloodline, I
believe that's the name of it, with, uh,
Norbert Leo Butz, who I did a failed
pilot with a long time ago. And, uh,
he's a fucking great guy and I keep
walking in there and he's absolutely
crushing every scene. And, uh, so I,
I got to watch it out of
solidarity. Um, we actually,
a long time ago did a fucking pilot. Did
I ever tell you guys this fucking story?
We did a pilot and they wanted edgy.
All right.
I thought I told you guys this
one, whatever. Who gives a fuck?
They wanted edgy. Okay. It was, you know,
and they will let us go
really far. And the, uh,
the pilot name was playing chicken
was the name of this pilot.
And the premise was,
um,
me and Norbert were brothers,
he was Republican and I was Democrat and
Norbert's character was paralyzed from
the waist down and he was
paralyzed because he was
playing chicken on a fucking
jet ski and neither person
turned away and he got paralyzed.
So that's what's the name of it.
So that's already the fucking premise.
So he was like over the top fuck homeless
people and all that Shit. So anyway,
so we're doing, you know, whatever,
they write this edgy fucking pilot and um,
right as we're about ready to do the
fucking run through where all the fucking
major network guys come down. And
it's basically you do, it's basically,
it's like a live play. All right,
let me just give you a little packet.
Basically what happens
is if you're on a sitcom,
you have the table read on
Monday, right? If it kills,
you go upstairs and you do a bunch of
blocking in the fake living rooms and all
that, which is basically, I'm going
to stand over here when I do this.
You go through the whole fucking thing.
If it bombs and they know that they're
going to rewrite a lot of shit,
you have a quick fucking day like,
well we're going to get a new script
tonight and this'll be, you know,
a little bit different. So then Tuesday
comes around, you fucking rehearse it,
you still got your script in hand,
and then you do a run through and it's
just for the, uh, the production company,
like the, whoever's making the thing.
So it's, that's friendly fire there,
you know, those are like the executive
producers and the people that wrote it,
the writers and all that. So they
watch it and they see what's working,
what isn't, what needs to be
fixed, what can stay the same,
what they can add on to. And then
Wednesday is the network run through.
And that's when the people that can
cancel your fucking show show up and leave
their sense of humor. At
the fucking door. Right.
So that's always a nerve
wracking fucking day.
And you go out there and if you do a
couple lines, they don't get laughs.
You start getting in your head like
you're going to get fired. You know,
and as you're walking from one fake
living room to the fake bar or a coffee
house that you hang out,
the only sound you hear is the shoes of
the fucking executives walking over to
the next fucking the next scene.
So anyway,
so we're doing this fucking
pilot and the opening scene is,
we're sitting there at some ice cream
place eating ice cream and this homeless
guy,
whatever.
We're having a back and forth and this
homeless guy comes up and asks for money.
So I of course being the liberal go to
give some money and Norbert's character
being the conservative guy, you know,
basically tells the guy to fuck off.
So everybody's loving it. He actually,
I remember flicked ice cream at him.
Oh he decided he was going to do that
during the fucking run through cause we
weren't going to do it all day long.
Flick and ice cream.
And I'd be a fucking mess. So he just
kept miming flicking the ice cream.
That's what it was.
So anyways,
people are digging the pilot, you know,
the producers and all the writers,
they're all thinking it's funny,
they're laughing it up.
We do the regular run
through what's going great.
So now we've got the network
run through but the next day,
and it just so happens that
during that week or whatever,
Don Imus said the nappy
headed hoes fucking comment
and for whatever reason all
hell fucking breaks loose like you know,
Hitler's back and um,
it becomes this big fucking lightning
rod thing that allows a bunch of people
who don't,
you know,
want to increase the fines
with the FCC and all this shit.
All basically what this one guy said on
the radio trickles all the way down to
our pilot that has these fucking suits,
nervous,
you know, just in general about, we
better watch our step because Don Imus,
I dunno what loss,
some advertising money.
So they in that fucking headspace and
they come down to our show where we got to
half paralyzed guy, you
know, and the opening scene,
we're doing the scene,
it's getting zero laughs.
And I remember where the homeless guy
walked out and they even gasped at that
because they really made them
look homeless. He was really dirty
and Norbit goes all the jokes of bombing
and he goes and turns around and flips
this fucking Globa ice cream and
hits the actor right in the face.
And they gasped and no law.
I mean I thought it was going to kill.
We thought it was the funniest shit
ever. They, there wasn't a fucking,
they just gasped and then it ended right.
And then just the sound of their shoes
shuffling all the way down to the other
side of the set for the next
fucking scene. And it, dude,
it was the worst run through
I've ever been in. I'm talking,
there was zero laughs,
it was dead fucking silence.
And I just remember walking
by this one actress,
she delivered her line and it got nothing.
And she walked by looking at me like,
what the fuck is happening?
And I almost burst out laughing
because for actors it's like,
fuck, I'm going to get fired and I'm going
to be unemployed again. For a comedian,
I can still, I'm not, I'm not unemployed.
I can just go back to doing shows.
The fact that I'm on this thing is,
is gravy.
So the look on her face was just, I
mean, I don't want it to be out of work,
but it was just funny to me.
So the more it was bombing them,
the harder I committed to what I was doing
just because if you're going to bomb,
you might as well just
fucking do the triple Lindy.
So I was just going bigger and it
just was just dead fucking silence.
So the run through ends,
I mean,
you can hear a fucking pin drop and it
was to the point, he was like, dude,
I didn't think they gonna
shoot this fucking thing.
So me and Norbert went back to the hotel.
We go right to the bar and we just start
laughing, going, I'm getting fired.
He's going, no, I'm getting fired. And we
had like a bet who's going to get fired.
It's like somebody is going down
for that. It's like, you know,
like Lsu loses three in a row of
somebody's got to pay the price.
Somebody getting fucking fired. So, um,
day ended up showing up and they would
talk to both of us individually in the,
uh, in our hotel rooms. I remember
the guy that directed the thing,
he came walking into my room
and just sat down on my bed.
It started eating the peanuts,
my peanuts without asking.
And I was the most arrogant
thing I'd ever seen in my life.
And I was just sitting there going like,
okay,
it's still bugs me to this day. I
didn't say anything to that guy. Um,
but anyways, so they fucking, uh,
okay.
So they ended up towing this
whole fucking thing down.
Okay.
Right. They go, look, we're
not gonna, we're not going
to get rid of you guys. Uh,
was the wrong tone,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then what ended up happening was
they fucking dialed it back like 40%.
Really took all the balls out of it.
Um,
okay.
And then,
you know,
a few days later we shot the pilot in
front of a live studio audience and it
actually killed it went great, but it
didn't end up getting picked up and a,
and yeah,
that's my, uh, that's
my story about bombing.
Sorry guys. I had to, I had
to go in the weld air, man.
I ran out of fucking stories to
tell if you tell you for this week,
all I know is that the bills are playing.
The Patriots tonight in Gillette Stadium
can happen. Um, they just
don't have a quarterback.
They got a great defense though.
So we'll see what happens. Uh,
I don't think the Patriots losing
one game is the worst fucking thing.
I think it's actually better, man. Get it.
Makes people focus on somebody else. So,
uh, you know, worst case scenario when
nine in one, I'm on vacation, you know,
I'm having a good time
here. So, uh, that is it.
I'll talk to you guys on Thanksgiving.
Um,
I'll try and make up a pie crust video.
I'm going to do that shit. Why not?
I said I was going to do it.
Right.
That'll be me giving back,
giving thanks to you guys listening to
the podcast I'm doing to do I the Joe
Rogan podcast, Joe Rogan experience.
I'm going to be doing that tomorrow.
Um, and, uh, I think that's it.
Happy Thanksgiving to everybody.
If you're traveling,
you don't have time to listen to podcasts
and he'll get a chance to say it.
Happy thanksgiving. Thank you to everybody
that's coming out to my show, uh,
over the years from the bottom of my
heart. I really appreciate it. And, uh,
that's it. Go fuck yourselves. Okay.
And I'll check in on Thursday.