Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday morning podcast.
Monday,
uh,
January 8th,
2018 that's a lot of age stowed.
I should go get a fucking scratch
ticket and play nothing but aids
do. My number came in. He had it
for fucking seven and a quarter.
We're going to go down to fucking, what
the fuck are those casinos down there?
Jesus Christ I perform at,
I'm going to go down on Mahican Sun dote,
hit the fucking blackjack table,
split and aces kid, whatever.
I'm playing with house
money. Um, how are you,
how was your first weekend of the year
to Jill? Jill? Joy, there's only 51 left,
um,
or four left.
If he listened to people who are fucking
freaking out about global warming.
I mean, you know, not saying that
I, it doesn't concern me, but uh,
I just kind of take it day to
day. I look out the window, right?
There's no zombies I can turn on.
The Faucet is still water k right.
You know,
he's got to look for the zombies first.
I like the old zombies,
you know what I mean?
The ones that walked real slow,
he had a fucking chance as opposed
to now they're like running around.
I'll roid it up. Um, roid it up.
It's right there on the fucking juice.
All these zombies need to be tested.
They got to get it out of the
fucking league. All right?
All those kills that all
those other zombies have.
That's why like zombies are killing so
many people now. You know what I mean?
Of course you don't.
You don't know what the fuck I'm talking
about and neither do I. All right.
If you new to my podcast,
how are you?
Get ready to listen to some of the
dumbest shit you're going to hear for,
you know, for like another 58 minutes,
I think. Yeah. Good call. I mean,
52 52 into the podcast.
Um,
I'm going to fucking pat myself on
the back. That's the back of my head.
That's why he was fucking sounded like,
you know,
I'm fucking wedding reno
sucks all winter wedding ring.
You've got this little piece of metal on
your hand. You hit yourself, you know,
it's like a constant fucking why can't,
it's like a painful reminder. Oh,
that's right. I'm married. You
know, fly goes onto your face,
you're whack yourself right in the face.
You already slept yourself in the face
and then your wedding ring like catches
like your brow, you know, like half fuck.
And right after that happens.
Yeah,
it goes high.
I was just asking if you could do
me a favor. When did that come from?
I did the Smad is thing tonight.
Right?
Me and my wife, right. And my
wife, we had this, you know,
every once in a while you've got to clean
house, right? It'd be like, all right,
let's go with a kid.
Can Harris,
let's just down and we're going to talk
about what we've been doing over the
last whatever month, six months, decade,
depending on how long it's been
since you've had those talks, right.
Having a talk in,
in,
in a relationship is like fucking the
nd a year when you have to do your taxes
and you didn't organize anything and
you've got a year's worth of fucking
receipts all sticking out all over the
place and you just keep putting it off
and putting it off, you know what
I mean? The next thing you know,
the box is fucking another box
down the street, right? Um,
so we, we try to air it out.
So we went out, all right,
got some chicken wings
and we just fuck it.
I think we were just going to go out to
hand. We knew that we needed to hang out.
Like we got to hang out, right? The
kids taking a lot of our us time,
you need to go fucking hang us.
We'd go hang out and then just all this,
the shit came out.
All right.
And one of the things that I was doing
is I was ruining television for her.
Cause I, I, I uh, I don't
shut up. When I watch TV
imitate people, I make
fun of them. And, uh,
when the other person is in the room
and they want to watch the show,
evidently it's really annoying.
Of course it's annoying. So, um,
and if she's watching reality TV, like
I never shut up cause it's just, I mean,
I dunno.
So I've been trying not,
you know, if she's watching something
and that we both enjoy like, Oh Zach,
you know, or uh, the Black Mirror.
Oh they all got Boston. They got the RS
in there. Uh, all the shows that we like,
twilight zone, all of that shit. If
we're watching shit like that, I shut up.
All right. But if it's anything
else, I don't shut the fuck up.
So she's watching like reality shows.
So tonight she was watching
the Golden Globes. All right.
And I know right there,
I can't watch that show with her
cause she's gonna get mad at me.
So I just wanted to watch sets monologue.
I always watched the comic cause it's
such a, it's such a fucking crazy Gig,
right to come out there.
You do an all brand new shit in
like sitting right in the front row,
like two feet away is fucking
Oprah Winfrey and you know,
Samuel Jackson and willing to fall. These
fucking people are there. They just,
it's like the whole move to Holt.
Everything you watch in Oman TV,
the television shows,
movies,
all of a sudden it turns around and looks
at you while you go out there with the
new fucking 10 minutes. So
whatever the hell it is they do. So
I'm watching that Seth is
fucking killing. And I, and I,
the first time I talked was at some point
when I saw Oprah was sitting there and
I leaned up and go,
can you mentioned doing your jokes?
And Oprah is like right
there. She was like, and,
and I was like, oh fuck. All right.
It's like, I'm going to shut up.
MMM.
And then the award show started and
the smartest thing I did is I just, I,
I pretended I had to go do something and
I just sort of got up and I walked out.
So I wouldn't, I wouldn't do the
rest of it. I wouldn't do the rest.
I wouldn't ruin the fucking show for.
And you guess what?
We're not in a fight right now.
It's unbelievable. You know?
And she would just, I just stayed
in the kitchen. I made some waffles.
I'm one of those breakfast for dinner kind
of guys. You know? That's how I do it.
That's my swagger.
Yeah,
that's it. That's, that's the
marble man that I have in me.
MMM.
I just realized the second I said that,
that's like some shit you say when you're
trying to be interesting on a date or
if you're too dumb to know you're not
interesting. You would say something. I,
first of all, I want to thank everyone
who's still listening to this.
The fact that I said I'm
a breakfast for dinner
kind of guy.
All right.
What I should've said was I like
having breakfast for dinner sometimes,
but I sent him a breakfast for dinner
kind of guy. Why you say kind of guy?
You should be legally required to do
the double fucking pistol shot with you.
Okay.
With your fingers and that kind of guy,
Bang,
Bang side of fucking sausage.
Um,
so that was out there and
making waffles and, uh,
she yelled out, she goes,
Sammy wants, Sammy wants Sam
Rockwell one. So I, you know,
obviously love Sam and, uh, he did
something that's really hard to do.
We had a great speech and,
um,
yeah.
And then,
you know,
I was watching a little bit more and I
felt all these things that I was going to
say. So I just walked up. I walked up
before I said something stupid. You know,
if she talks, it's all black, you're not
a rapist. Welcome to the Golden Globes.
Like I would've been doing shit like that.
Okay.
Do you realize you could be an
absolute fucking monster? Okay.
But if you wore an all black Tuxedo,
like no,
everyone would be looking at you like you
were progressive. That's why, you know,
I understand why it's done because it's
a show of strength and everybody's like,
yes, this is obviously something that, you
know, it needs to stop, Yada, Yada, Yada,
and a bunch of other obvious shit.
But, um, it also creates a sing would,
you could just walk in and no one's
going to fuck with you because you're
wearing the right uniform.
That's why I don't like all of that
political correctness stuff is because you
create a roadmap
yeah.
For,
for people to just get across the
river because they know what to say,
what not to say when they're
in public and everything. Oh,
he said native American
Gaddy said Mum, Mum, Mum,
Mama obviously and he has an all black
Tuxedo. Hey, must be a good person.
All right.
Now all of this is just shit that no
one wants to fucking here when they're
trying to watch. So I ran in,
I saw Rockwell when I heard
Carol Burnett was there.
I ran and I saw that and when I heard
Roseanne Barr and John Goodman we're on,
I ran in and I watched that and I went
out and always have something else.
I saw Jennifer Anniston. Oh No, she
was there with, uh, uh, Carol Burnett.
How fucking great does
she look, Tony? Man,
she does not age at all her
and fucking how he lawn.
I said the exact same.
That's kind of weird, right?
I say the exact same thing when
I saw how he launched today,
when I was watching the playoffs was
like give, he fucking looks unbelievable
guide. Just as he has not lost
one hair on top of his head.
I'm an Ilab,
that hair cuts and so I was like 15.
Um, anyways, uh,
I fucking watched so much God
damn sports this weekend. Right.
I did do a little duo lingo trying
to get back into the hole, trying to,
I have to become bilingual and I have
to learn how to speak French because
that's such a snooty fucking
language and I'm such a dope.
How hilarious would it be?
That's what keeps me going.
All right. Not Respect for the
culture, not trying to improve myself.
Just how fucking funny it would be if I
was completely fluent in French and like
really good at it. I could
speak the slang. Yeah. But the,
I wouldn't have an accent,
you know?
Let me just take a how much dumb shit
I've said right now and you're all of a
sudden out of no way.
I could just start speaking perfect.
I could go to Paris and no one would
turn their fucking nose up at me.
Okay.
Oh,
the opportunity,
I'm telling you I want to do that cause
I want to go there and I want to act
like a fucking moron. I mean,
not even have to act. I'm just,
I'd ramp it up, you know, and then just
listen to hear what they would say.
And I would just,
I would say 10 days of just laughing my
fucking balls off and then ruining it
for all you guys who go over there, if
you're from here. Um, anyways, so I,
uh, I had the peach bowl taped, recorded,
saved in fucking digital space,
whatever the fuck you kids say.
And I was meaning to watch it because I
came home from the Rose Bowl and I saw,
I was like, Holy Shit.
Central Florida one. So, uh,
I actually put it on in, my wife
was six this weekend, you know,
everybody got the bug, everybody got the
stomach flu. I haven't got it yet. Okay.
I take these little chewables.
Alright.
And I, I take a men's, uh,
what the fuck do you call
it? Men's, uh, vitamin.
What do they call those things? Men's
daily or some shit. I never take them.
I take them when I start to feel sick
and I knew everybody was getting sick
around me, so I just started fucking
just chow when those things down. Right.
And I've been able to hold it off and
last night I actually slept in a different
room. You know what I mean?
I love my wife, but you know,
I'm not going to start puking and
shitting, you know what I mean?
Unnecessarily. I wouldn't put
her through that. Right. And he,
Jesus Christ for better, for worse. And
then there's, there's like common sense,
um, and my wife's cool as hell. So she
was just like, yeah, get Outta here.
Get outta here. So, uh, I left.
You know what's weird is if,
when you have a chance,
like when I sleep in a different room,
I sleep on the opposite side of the bed.
So when I wake up and I get a sense
that the edge of the bed is on the wrong
side and I'm not on the road,
you know,
it freaks me out. Like,
where the fuck am I?
Did I get arrested for a murder I didn't
commit? And then I opened my eyes.
I'm like, Oh fuck no, I'm just sleeping
in a different room in my own house.
That's cool. Um, so anyways,
I watched the fucking peach bowl
and I watch to central Florida, man,
what a fucking game. What a gay
men, central Florida hub. I, I,
this is long overdue. Congrats in that. I
hope it say his name is Sheena Queen. Uh,
Griffin, the linebacker on the
team. The guys got one hand,
he's got one hand and he was dominating,
dominating Auburn,
who I swear to God,
half of their guys looked like they
had like 40 pounds on whoever they were
lining up against. And I
love Auburn. I Love Auburn.
I love watching a beat, Alabama.
You know, I love seeing that shit.
It's just fun. It's fun to see, you know,
cause Alabama supposed to win. So Auburn
was supposed to win that one. So I mean,
how do you not root for Central
Florida? Central Florida? It,
I went to their campus, right?
Did I go to the central Florida?
I don't think I did. I went
to the other one. I the,
where are the game was at the war and the,
for the one that's in Orlando,
I went to that one and I just went in and
I looked at the campus and I was like,
yeah, I could've got accepted here. I
could've gone to this fucking school.
Like their campus is in the
middle of like a rotary,
like there's a big
roundabout and they just put,
it's like they had a big roundabout and
then they stuck a school right in the
middle of it.
Um,
so I had to root for him because
I love that game so much.
And I'll see you gotta love an underdog.
So congratulations to them. And, uh,
what else did I watched all of the playoff
games playoffs except, uh, yet, uh, no,
I can't even say that.
I watched two of the Games today and I
missed you don't put the Kansas City game
on right at the end.
And cause my brother texted me,
he said it was talking about, uh, Sean
Mcdonough's voice when it cracked.
I can't believe the level of shit the
guy got for that. That was a great call.
It just was,
it just wasn't a touchdown.
Then everybody who sues fucking miserable.
It's got to trash the guy.
I wish something as exciting is that
happened to every game just to hear him
lose his shit.
All I heard was a guy that loves
the game and loves his job.
Everybody's like, yeah. Did
you hear his voice? Crack is,
I've entered all my voice cracks
when I get excited, you know. Um,
anyways, so everybody's
jumping all over. Uh,
Andy Reid, you know, giving him
shit for fucking, I don't know.
I don't even know what the hell happened.
I have no idea.
I know that they're big fucking tight end.
The potato sack race guy.
I know we took a shot to the
head so he wasn't in the game.
Obviously that will change the bill.
You were literally going to break down
a game he didn't watch. Yeah, probably.
Probably. Um, you know, you know,
loves to say, you know what,
the guy can't get it done,
guy can't get it done.
Any radio at guy can't get done. You know,
people love to say that kind of Shit.
People can't get it done in their
own lives. You know what I mean?
Can I can't get it done? Nobody can
get it done in Kansas City. Okay.
Nobody's got it done in Kansas
City since fucking hang strap.
All right.
He's gone to a fucking franchise that
is a perennial fucking loser and he came
from another one, Philadelphia. That's
a perennial fucking loser. All right.
Kansas City won a Superbowl in 1970.
The fucking eagles won in 1960.
Hm.
Anybody could do the Phil Jackson thing
and fucking go jump on the Goddamn
Lakers when they got already
got Colby Bryan Shack.
Eddie raid likes a challenge.
I've go to the most miserable
fucking sports city in the world.
Philadelphia, the, yeah, he
went there before the fit.
The Phillies won. All right.
When it was a fucking drug where they'd
won 1980. But you know what I mean?
So in defense of that guy is
everybody shitting all over them?
Like they would have known how to run the
clock or whatever the fuck they giving
him shit about that guy. He's taken
out two huge fucking challenges.
The Philadelphia Eagles
and the Kansas City chiefs.
MMM.
All right. So there's my take on it.
Having not watched the game, you see that?
You see what happens when
you just give find an angle.
Did you just go off on it?
It actually sounded for half a second.
Like I knew what I was talking
about. Right. Actually,
you know why he didn't see the game?
The real reason I didn't see the game
but wasn't because my wife was sick.
The real reason why is because I
was busy looking at Game Phil Film.
I was busy looking at game field,
getting ready to, uh, you know,
I had to coach some kids out in the
buffalo against this team. The jag was,
if one more person sends
me a God damn photo going,
is it me or you've looked just
like this guy. It's like, dude,
that choke was made like a year ago.
Okay.
Like if you guys really want
to just fucking annoying me,
just keep sending me that like,
and g got gotta deliver it.
Like it's the first time,
you know, I should've done,
I should've started re
tweeting all of them.
And maybe that's why I need to do it.
I thought I already retweeted them to
be like, it's this joke has been made.
Let's can we build on it. I'm not saying
don't make the joke, but you got to
knock knock. Who's there?
Banana. Banana. Who knock knock.
Who's there? Banana. Banana.
Who I get.
MMM.
Where the hell am I? All right, Jack.
Speak the fucking bills. Oh, that's right.
I watched that.
That's the first game I watched.
I missed the Atlanta
Falcons playing the rams.
MMM.
And I think like a lot of people,
I forgot that Atlanta one,
the first 58 minutes of last year's
Superbowl and then what was great was they
completely fucked up their regular season
to the point nobody was talking about
them, but they made the playoffs.
So now it playoffs until, and I,
everybody's zero and zero to start.
And they got all that experience in the
last year. Last year, right? I Dunno.
Put the fuck do they play next week?
They go to Philly,
they go to Philly and Philly
was all lined up to go.
And what happens?
Huh?
Carson Wentz gets his fucking need fucked
up for the rest of the season because
it's Philly. Okay. And I'm
not shitting on Phil Yeti.
Eagle Fan will tell you this the
second you put that fucking helmet on.
Somebody who's got to
break that curse man.
Do you think it's going to be Nick
foals? Ah, this is his last name.
Sound too much like follies,
the nic, foals follies.
If he fucking blows this game,
I'm telling you right now he's going to
be started in one of those ice capades.
He'll be like the guy with the top hat
bringing out a bunch of old eagles on ice
skates that never won super bowls.
I'm trying to figure out who
I'm going to root for this year.
Obviously I'm rooting for the Patriots,
but who else do I like? You know,
I actually like the saints.
Uh, what a great game that was.
Now that game I saw against the
fucking path is a lot of drops,
some critical drops by the panthers or
the first time felt that about, you know,
what I think's going to happen.
I think drew Brees, drew Brees,
the underrated drew Brees,
he's like third all time passing.
Nobody talks about them.
You know what I mean?
You know why he's just a
regular looking guy. You know,
he's a little taller than Doug Flutie.
Okay.
He's a little shyer than fucking,
uh,
Brett Farve and he's not as
good looking as Tom Brady.
Okay.
You know, and he's down there in New
Orleans and nobody's paying attention.
Nobody is fucking paying attention. And
meanwhile, the guys out there killing it,
he's got a Superbowl ring.
Okay.
So now he's going to Minnesota.
Yeah.
To face some guy named case Keenan who
people will say it, he's in the running,
they'll be the athlete play in the league.
He is,
you think drew Brees is afraid
of that? I don't think he is. Um,
it is my prediction for next week knowing
nothing about the Minnesota Vikings.
Okay.
I say drew Brees goes into Minnesota.
Okay. And when he leaves is going to be
a bunch of people crying at the mall of
America.
I think the sates go in and
they fucking beat Minnesota.
You know, buddy of mine was going, uh,
I can't believe Minnesota built another
dome there, like a cold city team.
That's like a great advantage.
And now drew breeze is going
to go in and play in a dome.
He's going to be at home. And I was
just like, why did they make a dominant?
I was like,
that's what I was thinking.
But we're old guys and I
think that, uh, you know,
the NFL has done with us,
you know,
they're now trying to move on to the
millennials and you've got to build a dome
because millennials don't
like to go outside. Right?
So if he can just get them to an Uber,
they'll get to the game and they look,
you look you back inside again,
you back inside this big TV screens.
You can stare at those instead of watch
the game. But he can sit here and say,
you, you, you are at
what you watched on a TV.
Um, all right. And the Patriots
are playing the titans.
Uh, we'll see. We'll see how that
one goes. You never know. And, uh,
who did the steel has got the
Steelers get the fuck in a,
they got the jags right?
The Steelers got the jags
kind of happy.
Both those teams, one of them is
going to knock the other guy off.
Although I am not excited, you
know, if we get past the titans,
I am not excited to play the Steelers
again cause they already beat us once this
year. Um, but unfortunately,
uh, we were given the victory
over that whole bullshit.
Maybe it's a good thing cause he
ended up getting home field, but, um,
I always think the team that loses has
the advantage the second time around.
However, however, I just think bill
Belichick has such a superior coach,
by the way. You know, I'm like,
do I really have to address this
stupid shit about bill Belicheck
that he's going to leave the patriots
over a fucking personal trainer? I,
I sometimes I just think that the fucking
media just has it out for the fucking
patriots.
I just don't understand.
I've never seen such a big punch
of shit made out of nothing.
And here's the thing,
if he's fucking going bad,
it Bella check ever went back
to the giant who gives a fuck?
He's not ours. He started with
the giants. Okay. We didn't,
he started with like the
fucking lions or southern,
but he started with the giants. Okay.
That's where he got his first ring.
Then he went over to the Goddamn jets.
Right.
A man goes over to the
fucking jets and um,
no. He went to Cleveland before that and
they fired him. Typical Cleveland move.
He goes over to the jetty, was going to
be the jets coach. It was right there.
And then he just wanted to get off Monday,
bill Parcells and he left.
So I, it wouldn't be a defection out
of Boston. It would be a return home.
We fucking stole that guy in 1999
we've gone to seven Superbowls.
One five maybe. That's why we never beat
the giants. That was the football gods.
God Bill, you never shut a
left actually showed a left.
You know what I mean?
That was like when he stepped
out from bill Parcell shadow,
it became the fucking legend
that he is now. But anyway,
so the end of the fucking day,
I don't give a fuck about Tom Brady's
personal trainer. I don't give a shit.
Who the fuck would break up the
Goddamn band over that is beyond me.
Am I really supposed to think that that's
a real fucking thing that would shock
me? Not if he left. It would just
shock me. If it was over that.
Okay.
But you know, Bill Parcells
leftover Terry Glen, rest in peace.
You know,
I'll never quite forgive that guy for
telling the fucking team that he wasn't
coming back the next year before we
played the packers and the Superbowl.
And uh,
actually has that ever even
been confirmed? Somebody
just told me he did that.
All right,
I'd like to apologize to bill Parcells
with the fuck am I talking about here?
She listening to as a man who
did nothing but this weekend.
That's what you're doing.
Okay.
That's why you probably listening cause
you probably did it too. All right,
here's one of the Douchey is things.
I haven't done it yet,
but I'm going to do it and I feel like
I have to admit to it before I do it.
Okay.
Anybody in in Ireland,
we're not going to make sure that's the
right country. Who Makes Shepherd's Pie?
You know what I mean? There's,
there's like all these,
those fucking Pi's over there and I love
all of them cause I got all that blood
in me. English, Irish, Scottish, so at
any sort of Elena knows fucking meat pies.
I liked that shit.
All right.
Shepherd's Pie or Ridge in
shepherd's pie was invented by shame
is so shepherd shepherds pie or cottage
pie. He's a meat pie. Bababababa
[inaudible] place of origin.
The United Kingdom. Oh, all right.
Cause there's no sheep in Ireland. Is that
what it is? I always forget that then.
Then Ireland, they make it. They'd make
a different one. Right. Shepherd's Pie,
cottage pie, blah blah, blah, blah. That
just you get could get care history.
It's going to be boring as shit.
In early cookbooks,
the dish was a means of using leftover
roasted meat of any kind in the pie dish
was lined with mashed potatoes as well
as having a mashed potato crust on top.
Oh, say build a wall around it
back then. Where did it come from?
Okay.
I like that. I can't find it so I
can't, so I just yelled at my computer.
I don't give a fuck. You
know, that's it right there.
That's why I didn't do well in school.
I look it up and I have again, I got,
I got that clock in my head
like a quarterback. You know,
we've got the clock before I just throw
it out of bounce. I don't care. No, no.
I'm not going to learn it. I'll, I'll
fucking make it up on the next question.
And that's why I got like a three
90 combined on my sats. I did.
And I took a prep course and I actually,
I actually,
I studied, did I break it? I
don't think I break broke 400.
I know. Whatever you do is you look,
do they give you like three 50? I know,
I know.
Um,
anyways, I'm going to make a shepherd's
pie with cauliflower mashed potatoes.
I just have to pause here
as everybody's gone. Um,
yeah.
Cause this gluten free diet that I'm
doing that I'm kind of half ass doing it,
but just half ass doing it.
I don't have to work out.
It's fucking great telling you,
man.
If you lay off the gluten, I remember
thinking, what the fuck is glued?
And then they told me what it's
everything that it's in. And I'm like, oh,
so like all the good foods,
all the foods I love.
MMM.
I've just been laying off the
old glute there. Uh, gluten free.
If you ever saw my flat ass, she be
surprised on us. Sorry. Bad joke.
Yeah.
So I'm going to make it with a
cauliflower because I'm not allowed to eat
potatoes.
I'm sorry people,
I've been out here too long.
You know,
I've been 10 years out here,
out here in Hollywood,
and I become a gluten free Douche.
I'm not really,
because I got these Brioche buns that I
bought for the hot dogs at the Rose Bowl
and it was the only thing I fucked up.
I forgot to not only bring hot dogs,
I forgot to buy them.
So I have all of these brioche bonds and
it's like I'm not going to throw them
out.
So when I brought some hot dogs,
so I'm kind of full of sodium
and gluten at this point. Um,
anyways, so I'm going to
make shepherd's pie with, um,
mashed potato and I'm not putting,
well,
it's one recipe I saw they had corn in
it and I was like, oh, I want to fucking,
why would you do that?
It's all about the piece.
You had the lamb in there,
right?
You get a little bit of
onion and minced that up,
couple of other fucking salt and pepper,
whatever else you put in there. And then,
then,
then you get the piece fucking corn.
It's an imposter,
doesn't have the guts of a p.
That's what yellow.
It's a little yellow.
Fucking cowardly fucking sort
of vegetable. Then a fruit.
Is it not at all. So that's why I'm, I do,
I'll make a shepherd's pie
with fucking mashed potatoes.
Got Cauliflower mashed potatoes.
I actually really like cauliflower mashed
potatoes. I don't like cauliflower.
But if you're gonna throw a
bunch of butter on it, I mean,
how is it not going to taste good?
You know,
the only thing I really don't like is
that fucking, uh, what is that shit?
They were putting in
everything for awhile. Oh,
what the fuck it was it
being with at teed in it?
Truffle oil.
Okay.
I mean,
one time we went out and there was mashed
potatoes and they had truffle oil in
it. No, no, I'm sorry.
Head at a macaroni and cheese
and they put truffle oil.
Why would you do that? You don't need
to, it's pasta with cheese. Fuck off.
You know, truffle oil for a while it was
like the fucking Hari Krishna of herbal
ingredients, you know? Yeah.
Tell him he don't want any
fuck out of you. We need low.
Um,
okay.
And I,
and the waiter or the waitress or is,
is there an, is there, I can't believe
no one's been offended by that yet.
Wait around and wait. She said, and we're
all waiters is, is there a fucking, uh,
gender, gender neutral fucking
term we can come up with that, uh,
wait, attended, who that's going
to give someone a body image.
Um, the fucking person
who gives you your food,
who would rather be doing a
different job for better money there.
Is that a good description?
Was that genderless? Um,
told me that there was only a little
bit of trust. It's just a hint of it.
That's just a hint. That's just a
dash. And I was like, all right,
and I ordered it and it just,
it just sucked.
Truffle oil overpowers
every fucking thing.
It's like a comic that's on offstage,
like a fucking lamp shade over.
It's God damn head. I hate truffle
oil. I don't even know what it is.
Should I look that up and fucking,
is it from like a mushroom or something?
Truffle.
Okay.
Oil.
This is why the Internet mets makes
people less funny because back in the day
you just had no idea and he just guessed
and then there was always somebody in
the room with a big enough fucking ego
to just definitively give you an answer
even though they didn't know. Truffle
oil is a modern culinary ingredient.
Used to impart the flavor and
aroma of truffles to a dish.
All right,
now we're looking up truffles.
Truffle is a fruiting body of subterranean
has come set fungus. Oh
fuck. Is that all right?
Now I'm looking up a scum set.
A scum set is a division or a
phylum of the Kingdom of Fuji.
Fuji. All right. What's
a phylum in biology?
A phylum is a level of classification.
Alright.
Taxonomic rank.
Biological classification. A taxonomical
rank. See what I'm saying? It,
this is why I don't look up.
I'm too dumb to understand the fucking
definition. It just, it just keeps going.
It's like a humble.
Okay.
By the time you get down and you don't
even know what the fuck you were asking
the question. So keep it going.
Like, like, uh, I can't say that.
You know what I mean? Some of
these fleet streaming sites, right.
And you're fucking, oh, I want to watch
that. Oh, wait a watch that now watch.
It was another thing I was going
to watch. Um, all right. Anyways,
so what am I read a little about
advertising? Shelly shall lie.
Read a little bit of advertising.
Oh, look who's back in Doki. Oh,
Indochino talk about how every man
looks better in his suit. Yes, they do.
Especially if it's an all black
suit at the Golden Globes.
So we know that your progressive,
okay.
We know that you're a progressive person,
you're not wearing that suit to a
hopefully ward off any investigation on
yourself.
Alright?
Indochino is the largest
custom apparel company,
okay?
They make suits and shirts.
I know those words in French costs.
Dube shimmies made to your exact
measurements for a great fit.
Guys love the wide selection of high
quality fabrics and the option to
personalize all the details,
including the lapel jacket lining,
monogram, and much more. That's actually
cool. You can customize it. All right.
Here's how it works. Pick your
fabric, choose your customization,
submit your measurements,
place your order and wait for it
to arrive in three weeks or less.
Is it any wonder why people are
so fat now? This is incredible.
You can shoot back in the day if
you wanted to have something made,
you had to go down and talk to Jimmy, the
gent and he'd be like, yeah, keep going.
Should I did try dad's.
Okay,
you almost got whacked trying to get your
own personal fees. Fucking millennials,
they don't have to work for anything.
He can shop online and then don't cheat
or.com or visit any of their showrooms
across North America this week.
My listeners can get any premium indochine
oh suit for just $359 a custom suit
people,
but 359 bucks it indochino.com
when entering burr at the checkout,
that's I n d o c h.
I. N. O. Endo,
like Indonesia or in do go in that door.
What do you want to do?
I N D O.
I always assume people are just as dumb
as me and then United spelled China.
Okay,
take off the ain't put
on and then Dope Gino.
Fuck man,
that's over 50% off.
The regular price for a premium
made to measure suit plus is
absolutely fucking free.
That's indochino.com promo code per
for any premium suit for just $359 plus
shipping. Even if you're
the size of Andy Reid. Oh,
didn't he get enough shit going?
A big red suit.
You know what?
The gang clock on the lapel.
Alright. Zip crude. Oh
look who's back goes up.
Wrote up Zip recruiter.
Post your job to over 100 post your job
to over 100 of the web's leading job
boards with just one
click. Oh, that's awesome.
Then ZipRecruiter actually looks for the
most qualified candidates and invites
them to apply that doing everything.
They even review every application to
identify the top candidates so you never
miss a great match.
That's why zip
is different.
Unlike other hiring sites,
ZipRecruiter doesn't depend on the right
candidates finding you. It finds them.
No wonder 80% of employers who post on zip
get a quality candidate through the
site in just one day. Ziprecruiter,
it the smart way to hire.
Find out today why zip
has been used by businesses of all
sizes and industries to find the most
qualified job candidates
with immediate results.
And right now my listeners can post jobs
on Ziprecruiter for free. That's right.
Free. Just go to ziprecruiter.com/bird
that's ziprecruiter.com/pro one more time.
damn.com/ [inaudible] all right.
How many more fucking beats? Oh Jesus.
Chris. Two more dollar shave club, dude,
dude,
come on in and where you Bend Dollar Shave
Club at the store at this still Woah,
they're at go down to the fucking packy
gimme me a 12 a natty light at this
still wa there are too many options and
you can't tell the difference between
any of them. Dan, if you have
any questions, the clerk he is,
he doesn't know what the fuck
they're talking about either or.
You can't really help you since they're,
they're not experts on the product.
So usually,
you know,
there's just one person working the
register and there's somebody else running
around getting ice cream for old people.
There's nobody, there's nobody there.
You know what I mean?
I love when the old people go into the
fucking pharmacy to get their ice cream,
you know?
Okay.
That's how they live off social security.
Yeah.
You know,
you make tough decisions like that.
All of us running around going
to these gourmet fucking places,
they go to the pharmacy.
Ice Cream is ice cream.
It all gives you a headache
if you eat it fast enough.
Dollar Shave Club makes it easy.
And convenient for you to upgrade to
your shave upgrade your shave and your
bathroom, need to remodel
your bathroom. Jesus.
Now you don't have to set foot in the
store to get a high quality and grooming
products. Dollar Shave Club delivers
them right to your door. Once again,
making people fatter,
but God damn it,
you're going to look good being
have a nice smooth fucking face. Uh,
if you're sick of the
nonsense of the store,
now's the time to try out dollar
shave club for a limit of time.
Dollar Shave Club was basically
giving away their shit.
Shower shave starter kit to s to new
members for only $5 to start a set.
Features that are exclusive razor and
three trials size versions of their most
popular products that help you
stay so fresh and so clean.
And your first box you'll receive their
shave bodywash and one wipe cherry but
wipes.
You will also receive their executive
razor which includes their premium weighty
handle and a full casket of charges.
Cartridges,
sorry. After the first box replacement
cartridges are sent for only a few bucks a
month.
This offer is exclusively
available@dollarshaveclub.com
slash burr that's dollar
shave club.com/burr dollar shave
club's high quality products.
We'll have you covered from
face cheeks to butt cheeks.
There's no better time to try the club.
And lastly, but certainly not leastly.
They had liner always bringing up the
rear loyal. No matter what I've ever said,
they've always stuck with me.
God bless him. You know Yolanda,
you use stamps.com everybody.
Here's a new year's resolution.
You can actually keep
add stamps.com to your business and
save a ton of time and money this year.
Share your experience with how
stamps.com has helped you maximize.
I'm going to start
speaking in a different,
we know when they tried to tell me
what to do when these things. Bill,
if you could share your experience with
how stamps.com has helped you maximize
time and money. Ah, G Z amount of
time I used to waste. You know,
I used to walk backwards to the a uphill
to the, to the fucking post office,
you know,
with my wallet hanging out in the back
of my pants through a bad neighborhood,
you know. But now with stamps.com
they saved me time and money.
Almost everything you can do at the post
office you can do right from your desk.
Plus stamps.com has postage discount.
Yeah.
I'm trying to think what
else you couldn't do.
I guess she couldn't check out the
girl's ass in front of you at the post,
at your house.
But you know what?
If you stick your scale close enough to
the window, you can check out Shinay.
Not to mention it's a fraction of the
cost of those super expensive postage
meters,
stamps.com we'll send you a digital
scale that automatically calculates the
exact postage you will never overpay or
underpaid for postage again and right
now you too can enjoy stamps.com service
with a special offer that includes a
four week trial plus
postage and a digital scale.
Ready for a happy new year.
Go to stamps.com.
Click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbarthatstamps.com
enter
[inaudible] [inaudible] all right.
And went done.
We're done the reeds for the
week. Um, if you might notice you,
you have noticed that, uh, I am in
a little more of a perkier mood.
I am in a great move. Cause guess what?
Guess what? Guess what? Guess what?
Guess what?
Um,
I finally made a breakthrough in my
rehab of this fucking lingering a rotator
cuff injury. You're not sorry. I don't
even know if it's cup or cuff links. Cuff.
I always forget.
I think I said Cup for most of my life.
Let's go back to row a Wikipedia rotate
Brodie Tor. Oh, it's cuff.
It's not cup in anatomy.
The rotator cuff is a group of muscles
and their attendance, that act
to stabilize the shoulder. Yeah,
that's the problem because
when they fucking don't,
you show the kind of comes out of
the socket maybe, I don't know.
Okay.
Uh,
the four muscles of the rotator cuff are,
are over half of the seven
scapular meal muscles.
Scampi it for you.
And marbles are a group of seven
muscles that connect to the humorous,
humorous to the Scapula.
They are amongst the
muscles that act on the
Glio rule. Well Joe, what the fuck
is that? The shoulder joint. Oh,
that's his shoulder.
Joined the Glencoe Humber all join up.
It gives a fuck many ways.
My shoulder's been bugging
me so I didn't understand.
Um, I don't understand how to Rehab.
I like when I felt pain, I stopped.
I didn't understand that you had to
kind of go into it a little bit like you
skimming the frost enough, right?
We should making steel cut oats,
you know that awful Gluey Shit on top.
You just skim that off.
He kind of got to do that
with the pain. So, um,
yeah,
it's person told me this great
exercise we were, I just,
I laid down on my back
and then put my arm,
like if I was standing up,
I would be pointing straight ahead.
But when you lay down your back, you're
not pointing at the ceiling. Okay?
I'm not saying put your arm
up over your fucking head.
Just pointing straight up and
just start making little circles,
you know, a bunch clockwise,
a bunch counterclockwise.
And then you just gradually increase
slowly as shit the circumference of them.
And when you start to feel the
top layer of pain, you know,
that's where you stopped. But you,
but when you, when I was going, wow,
I've been doing it when I go around
into this circle is I kinda stay at an
acceptable level of confronting the pain.
And I swear to God,
I've been doing that for
like the legislature since
a Thursday and I've gotten
like 30% increase,
I would say in my range of motion.
And I feel like I can get this thing,
you know,
I'm not saying restrengthen it,
but I think I can get it all back by
the end of the fucking month. Oh, I,
I can't say that because I don't want to
fucking rush it because I don't mess it
up again.
Um,
yeah,
they're very excited about,
that's putting me in a better mood.
You know what they say?
You know,
hey, at least she got you health because
it puts you in a bad guy. Damn mood. Um,
all right. So somebody was asking
me, Dean del Ray's diet. Hi Bill.
Can you please talk about Dean
del Ray's diet details on,
on his next podcast?
I'd like to lose a little weight myself,
so I have to go into
Dean del Ray's podcasts.
Let there be talk from the all things
comedy network, network network.
Um, Dean can explain it. I
don't remember all of it.
I just kind of like,
I eat like for breakfast I have two eggs,
always g and then I have a one serving
of steel cut oats to take for fucking
ever to cook. Um, it's
another way to lose weight,
waiting for your food to be ready.
Um,
and then for like a snack,
I'll have a z bread,
which tastes like shit unless you put
butter. And I have almond, peanut butter,
almond butter is what it is.
And uh,
I have that and that's actually
fucking delicious. And it's filling.
And then for lunch I have a
keen awash with uh,
okay
with black beans.
And then I throw salsa on top to
give it some sort of fucking flavor.
Cause other than that, you know, I've
never eaten a shoe with, you know,
with a newspaper on top because
that's what it tastes like.
And I try to avoid throwing salt
and any of that shit in there. Um,
and then in the afternoon,
I dunno,
what the fuck do I have?
There's always that one meal
before you have the real meal.
Right around four o'clock.
I have like a fucking a
okay.
I Dunno what. Sometimes I'll
have a whatever the fuck I want.
And other times it's like this
pasta that's made out of chickpeas,
it tastes a little weird, but
it's not that bad, you know?
And then for dinner I just have a protein
with like a salad and I'm done and I
just drink waters and I stay away from
the booze and all of that bullshit.
And um,
it's just weird thing when
you eat like that where
I think what you mean when
you say God like, God, this
food is so boring and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. It's cause
you're used to the sugar assault.
It gets your system going like sugars or
salt does whatever the fuck salt does.
Like it's like you get your
fix so when you eat that,
what do eat stuff that doesn't
have any of that in it. Um,
okay.
You're just not hungry afterwards
and it's weird and then,
but you feel energized. But it's
a, it's a different kind of,
you got to adjust your brain to the
fueling your body rush as opposed to the,
the rollercoaster of sugar and salt.
Um,
so I that, that's as much as I know
about the Diet and I've been doing that.
And then, you know, I like
that most of the time,
probably 80% of the time I eat that way.
And then occasionally if I just
want to have a fucking pizza eat it.
But Dean does it, dangerous fucking
stays with it. And that fucking guy,
he'll every once in a while he just sends
me a picture of him when I first met
him. It doesn't, he doesn't
all get the same person.
Okay.
Cause not only did he
lose all this weight,
like he like his skin fucking cleared up.
You know,
they used to look like a fucking cop
with 20 years in is what it used to look
like. You know, now he looks
like a fucking rock star. Um,
so I would listen to him out his podcasts,
let there be talking. I'm sure he's,
he said a dietician or something.
He gets great guests over there. Um,
all right bill, you're not an
addict. Hey old ginger balls.
Uh, I'm a big fan of the
podcast and looking forward
to your next special and the
new season of F is for family.
Keep up the great work. Thank you.
I been listening to the podcast for the
last couple of weeks and I've heard you
going back and forth about abstaining,
but from booze and most recently
about a, yeah, I'm sorry. They fuck,
I said a lot of bad things about Aa.
If it fucking works for he works for you.
It's just, it's just fun to make fun
of that Shit. You know, it's funny,
I saw the other day in a
strip mall. It was, you know,
all these different
stores that one of the,
one of the stores there and
said alcoholics anonymous,
you know what I mean?
It's uh, it's kind of putting
it out there, isn't it?
You know,
it's bad enough.
These poor people had to sneak into porno
stores and that type of shit back when
they would drink at night. You know,
you're going to do that to him. Just,
yeah.
Shouldn't it say bill W's? Well,
I guess how that signed up,
a bunch of cats like me might be walking
in like, what are you guys selling?
And you guys would be like, hope
smoke filled room with donuts. Um,
I've been working in addiction
and back to the letter here,
I had been working in addiction and
the addiction field for over a decade,
teach and addiction course at a college
and work at one of the most highly
respected addiction programs
up here in Canada. Ah, dude.
You know, you had it all. You
had me until you said Canada.
Canada doesn't count.
Yeah.
Dude, you, you live in Canada. For me to
be considered an alcoholic and Canada.
I have to drink like
fucking two cases a Molson.
Okay.
You guys, animals up there have you
guys don't know you're alcoholic.
She just think you keeping
warm. All right, well let me,
let me not judge this guy.
Now that I've mentioned my credentials,
while at the same time sounding
like a pompous content are,
I love this guy called himself out on,
I can tell you that you are not an addict,
but it's like you are not the father,
you are not an addict,
but everything you have mentioned on the
podcast that I am a longtime listener.
Um, oh, so when you said we listened
to the last couple of weeks,
I guess you'd dip in and
dip up, right? All right.
The word addiction is thrown around a lot,
so as the word hero is thrown
around a lot and typically to
any behavior that is out of our control
a to put it as simply as possible.
People will often say things like they're
addicted to things like TV, shopping,
sex,
et cetera.
People will also use the word to
explain what draws system symptoms of a
substance or behavior.
I,
I must be addicted to coffee because I
get headaches in the morning if I don't
get a cup.
However,
experiencing enjoyment or withdrawal
symptoms does not mean that someone has an
addiction.
Can we just kind of stop here and say
this is one of the best written fucking
letters in a while. I apologize that
my level of intellect is reading it,
but I think you guys can hear that this
person seems to know what he's talking
about or she or it or
her who used to be him.
Did I cover everything? However, in
the edition, in the addiction field,
there is a way to tell if
someone has an addiction.
We call them the four C's of addiction,
cash,
cons,
cauliflower
and I dunno, I, I bring up in
the chargers la charges. Okay.
If you've persisted,
if you can,
if you have persistent cravings
for drugs, alcohol, slash, alcohol,
if you have lost control over how
much and how frequently you use,
if you continue to use despite
consequences. I he legal issues,
job loss,
children taken away.
And if you feel a compulsion to use I,
he always feeling like you need,
okay,
uh, a drug or alcohol is a
bunch of weed smokers going, um,
and alcohol is a drug.
Uh,
then you can begin to think
you have an addiction.
Knowing what I know about
from you, uh, on the podcast,
I'm not going to pretend
to know you personally.
I have never heard you
mentioned any significant
consequences around booze other
than your Dui when you were young
and you have control of booze.
Since you can have a full bar in the house
and not drink it and abstain for long
periods at a time from booze,
the bar in the home also means you
don't have a compulsion to drink.
People that struggle with significant
alcoholism cannot have booze just sitting
around their place drinking it. It's
fucking funny to me. I don't know why.
Like they're just sitting there seeing
it at the corner of the ride and they're
like sweating. It's
fucking looking at me, man.
He liked that black dude and predators
shaving your head. I see you over there,
that bar.
Um,
I don't believe you have an addiction
and you don't need to go to Aa for me.
He wrote it all in capitals.
Uh,
you're just some content likes to boos
whose job in lifestyle allows for it.
Dude, you're going to talk
me to drink it tonight. Um,
if you ever feel like you d
do need some serious help,
go see a professional instead of some,
sorry,
sat bleeding his heart in a church
basement in front of a group of strangers.
Having said that, I know Aa does work
for some people and if you're into that,
knock yourself out, you just like me,
you had to shit on it a little bit.
I hope this helps and can silence the
bill w listeners of the Monday morning
podcast. Best of luck in the new year and
all the best in the air and your lovely
daughter and go fuck yourself. Wow.
I might have to fucking download,
download that, whatever
printed out and frame it, uh,
at framers.net or whatever the fuck
those people are. Frame Bridge.
I got to use those guys for
that. Wow. That was awesome.
That made me feel better about myself.
Um,
am I going to drink now? No, I got to go
do a set tonight. Uh, all right, chef.
Not Making enough money.
That was really informative by the way.
MMM.
I definitely went through periods
where I was craving it, you know,
and didn't want to drink and I was
just like, this is what I did. And,
and he and I would just go
over it and I just, you know,
but I felt more like a diet thing,
like late at night,
just fucking eat.
Well,
don't go out and go make a fucking
grilled cheese sandwich your friend,
and then you just go out and do it.
But what that first fucking night when
you don't do it, then I could stop.
So yeah, I don't think I am.
Bill. Stop giving you examples.
The guy left you off the hook. All
right, chef. Not Making enough money.
All right,
dear Billy Betty Crocker,
I liked that one a way to go champ.
On your pie making skills.
I'm the chef of a new
restaurant this year.
The restaurant has made a hundred
grand more than a year before.
The restaurant is doing great,
but I'm making sad money.
I have a wife and a daughter.
My wife has always supported my cooking,
but I don't make the
money. I should. Recently,
my wife told me I could work with her
brother as an electrician for the water
district. I could be making three
times more than what I could as a chef.
I love cooking. It's the one
thing that makes me happy too.
I hang tight with the cooking and do
what I love or skip out and go with the
easy money. I have investors ready to
support my cooking, but I need money. Now.
Love to hear what your thoughts
are. Your thoughts. Oh Jesus, do.
This is a huge fucking decision.
How much do you love cooking? Is this
your dream? Is this what you want to do?
MMM,
I,
I can only equate to standup comedy.
There is not a job out there that
would have paid three times more
than what I could make as a
comedian that I would have ever,
ever even for a second,
considered
ever,
ever.
Not even for a fucking second.
Okay.
If you feel that way about cooking that
I would stay with the chef jump. However,
if you know,
if you don't feel that way,
I would talk to somebody else.
This is a major decision, dude.
I'm not making this decision
for you, but I can tell you, uh,
you know,
one of the great things about my dream
of being a comedian was I really had no
other options because I kind of sucked
at everything else and I was miserable
doing anything else.
And that was the only thing I ever
did where the second I did it,
I was just like, oh, I'm doing this for
fucking ever said I don't give a shit.
So, uh, but I also didn't have a
wife and a daughter at the time.
There's a lot of variables here.
MMM.
You have investors ready
to support your cooking,
but any money right now?
Uh,
I would say this, if, if you,
this is your decision buddy.
If you decide to keep cooking,
you gotta,
you gotta get your wife on the right page.
You guys got to give him extra to
say on the same page. You know,
if you really believe in yourself
and then you can run a restaurant,
you can be one of those guys,
right?
Walking around with the orange clogs,
fucking riding a vesper and all that shit.
You know,
like Mario Batali,
that was another guy,
foggy grabbed a couple people's asses.
Now I never get to see him again.
You know what I mean?
Kenny just fucking from
his self imposed exile.
He can't just make a fucking use the
well method and show me how to make
something, you know, you just
put them on a leash, right?
You put them on a fucking leash and he
can't go anywhere away from the island in
his kitchen. Uh, anyways. All
right. That's what I would do.
Okay, so I would ask, how much do you
want to be a fucking chef? All right.
And if you want to be a chef,
you gotta get your wife on the same page.
Other than that, uh, you know,
if it's not your fucking dream,
then you could just fucking become an
electrician who has the best fucking
cookouts ever. All right. Ex-Girlfriend
hooks up with stranger at party.
We both attended.
Okay.
Hey Billy, on the back.
Nine of life. That's true.
My girlfriend and I broke up about
four months ago after an 11 year
relationship. Wow. Sorry to hear that.
We share a lot of the same friends and
I knew we would see each other at a
friend's New Year's party.
Two days before the party,
my ex hit me up and asked to get a drink
and clear the air before seeing each
other for the first
time since the breakup.
We had an awesome time and
we ended up going out again
the next night and add
an even better time.
She then asked if I wanted to share a
cab to and from the New Year's party.
I agreed while at the party she met a
guy and they were all over each other the
entire night.
Oh God.
She ended up ditching me and going
home with him at the end of the night.
I have hooked up with a few people to
break up but never in front of my ex.
And after the previous two nights I was
absolutely devastated by what she did.
I would love any advice or insight.
Thanks and go fuck yourself.
Well that it really seemed like,
unless she was completely shit faced,
that really seem a little calculated.
And that right there sir.
Your story right there is why I avoided
staying in contact with ex-girlfriends.
I'm not saying they were all bad,
but I had a girlfriend like that,
an x and uh,
they have like this sixth sense is right
is you're starting to get past and over
them. They just feel it. They call
you up and they just fuck you.
Life your head up all over again.
Um,
here's one for you dude. What kind
of a person would do that? Huh?
The kind of person that you
don't want to put your seed in.
Just know that that could have been
the mother of your fucking children.
You dodged a bullet. Congratulations
sir. Congratulations.
Okay.
And I'm willing to bet that unless
she completely fucks up her life,
you will not hear from her again or
you will hear from her because she is a
sadistic person and wants
to hear your reaction.
She wants to hear the pain
and get off on it while she goes like,
well,
I didn't think there'd be a
problem because we were broken up.
So I don't know why you're putting this
on me. Okay. I thought we both had,
we have nice time.
We were adults and the whole time she's
just getting off on the fact that you
still give a fuck. So Ah, dude,
you dodged a major fucking bull. I mean
I, I would never do that to somebody.
I would never, I wouldn't
do that. Like if a,
you know, I, I wouldn't do that
now. I've been with Nia forever.
If I saw an x grove, I would never
fucking, I would just western hail,
let's get out of here.
It's gonna, you know,
let's go someplace a little more quieter.
I would never do that to somebody
that's just a fucking asshole,
male of female to do that to somebody
who's a really fucking asshole thing.
I'm sorry that happened to you, but you
know what? You know what's great too.
She's out of your life. She's
Outta your life. And you know,
you know what those people are,
but they like those.
What about Bob people you know, remember
the beginning of, what about Bob?
The therapist gets Bill
Murray's character away from it.
Dumps him in fucking Dreyfus.
His lap. That's what she's,
she's the fucking, the female
version. Those what about Bob People?
If you can ever dump them off on
other people's fucking tremendous.
And she did it to herself
and this is what you do.
Anytime you ever see her after that,
just big smile on your face.
Big Smile on your face. Hey, how are
you doing? Why are you mad? No, no,
we broken up.
Good for you. You know,
have the time of your life,
my senior leave.
All right.
And now's a great time dude to
fucking expand your horizon.
Find new friends and dull a fucking hobby.
Travel Gig itself in great shape.
Go to the gym.
It's time to you fucking work on you.
And that person is,
is in the rear view fucking mirror.
You know what all she did was give you a
great fucking story to tell the love of
your life. Cause that,
that chicane it. All right.
Enjoy your 2018 you're a free man. All
right. This girl is killing me man.
All right, dear Billy, big head.
Ah Shit. You guys are really accurate this
week. Uh, back nine, big head. I mean,
what are what? I'm fucking on the
ropes here so we throw in the towel a,
I am a sophomore in high school,
okay,
but I've been listening to your
podcast podcast for a year now.
I need some advice out. Jesus
Christ. This is fucking scary.
I hope you need some fucking
regular advice. All right,
I need some advice on how to handle
this. Girl. Hey Nia, you out there.
They are.
You want to,
you want to give this kid some advice?
Oh, that's right. You're
sick. Okay. Sorry.
Hang on. Let me hit pause here. Hang on.
Hang on. All right. I'm back. I'm back.
Jesus Christ. She's still
sick. She's still sick.
Sleeping upstairs again tonight.
Um,
all right.
A sophomore in high school and I need
some advice and he knows how to handle
this girl. I dated her for about nine
months last year. A lot of heartache this,
this week and learned a lot.
The problem is that this girl is
really immature and I cannot have a
conversation with her without her arguing.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Pick this up without arguing with me or
something over something not important.
Oh, tell you're a son who gives a
shit. Fucking move on to the next one.
For example,
towards the end of my relationship with
her and she gave me the silent treatment
for multiple days because I told
her I didn't like Australia.
She constantly insulted me,
called me dumb, and told me
I was a terrible brother.
The date and your sister when
she just observed your family.
What state
did this come from and did crazy things
like this throughout our relationship.
She's one of those girls who
thinks that she, she's always,
she thought that she always gets to be
right and I am not and I am not about
that life.
He says when she broke up with me,
it was this whole scene,
Walter,
that sounds like you dodged a bullet here.
What dating is all about is what you
don't want and then you figured that out
and then you finally fucking meet
the right person. You totally, yeah,
you're fucking youngest shit.
What's the problem here?
I got very close with
their family and while,
so you're a good guy and when we broke
up her seven year old sister's sobbed,
Jesus Christ,
her mom even went to the extent to call
me on the phone to tell me I was a great
boyfriend and wished me wish that me and
her could possibly work things out in
the future.
Her family adores me to this day due
to the fact that I really played up the
whole nice guy thing or what
are you really an asshole.
This is where things get even worse.
She constantly leads,
leads me on and I fall for it.
Yeah.
That's what being young is all about.
And at a town fair we have,
we have,
she hung out with me all weekend.
We were very flirty and she heavily
led me on, but when I asked her out,
she said she wasn't ready. All
right dude. This once again,
if you listen to the last,
so this is why you do not stay
in contact with ex girlfriends.
Okay.
She just doesn't,
she doesn't want you to meet someone else
until she's met somebody or, I don't.
I don't. I don't know what the fuck they
think. I just know. I just know you just,
you gotta, you gotta you gotta you
gotta walk, you gotta walk. All right.
The same thing happened
a few months later.
I have left her alone
for the past few months,
only talking to her once every three
weeks and every time she ends up being mad
at me for some dumb reason an hour ago
she was mad at me for not roasting her
and called me pathetic roasting her.
Hm.
I'm trying to figure out what the fuck
you live. You've got a little fair,
the town fair. And then you guys
also have roast. I don't really,
this is all right.
She apologize all the time for her action,
but continues to do the same thing.
Should I not even talk to her or
should I forgive her because she's just
immature and can handle our feelings?
Any advice would be appreciated.
Especially you get the, uh, the
lovely Nia to answer as well.
Hope the family's doing great and
go drink a beer. It's hilarious. Um,
yeah, I would just have a conversation.
I would just say, listen, uh,
I don't enjoy talking to you because
you always get mad at, you yell at me.
We are broken up and I don't think it's
healthy for us to continue talking to
one another. However, when I see
you, I don't want it to be weird.
So is there a way that you,
you want a nice way could just fuck
off and let me get on with my life.
But if I see you, you know, we
could just walk by, you know,
we could raise eyebrows, you know, and
acknowledging that we saw each other.
Maybe we get a high five and
not saying anything, you know?
And then if she flips out, it gives
a fuck. Think gives a fuck. I mean,
it's just doesn't, you
know, it doesn't sound like,
here's a question for you since you
broke up it, has it ever ended? Well,
any interaction, any interaction you've
had with them? Okay. If the answer is no,
then she got to stop
interacted with there.
But it seems like it's such a small town.
I'm judging you because you went
to a fair. Okay. So my world,
you brought your prize
pig down there or not.
I don't know what the
fuck happened after that.
All right.
Um,
I would say, yeah, I would
just, you know, this,
I imagine plenty of other women,
you know,
uh, what's the proper word at that
age? Chicks you fuck go to school with.
Okay.
It's really no middle world, right?
Girls, you know, girls that point,
you're a fucking teenager. I don't, I'm
not, I'm not going on Wikipedia again.
I don't know what the fuck word is.
Okay?
There's plenty of the fucking chicks
you could be hanging out with.
All right?
That's it. And here's the
thing. Here's a tip for you.
When you fucking hang out with them,
don't talk about your old relationship.
Okay?
What about some mother fucking woman?
They don't want they, they, well, yeah,
I don't want to hear it.
Okay.
She have a beer with one of
your buddies out in the woods.
How are the fuck you do it? And
just be like, yeah, you know, I,
I don't encourage underage drinking.
Whatever the fuck you did she give
you guys do, that's when you vent.
Uh, what do you are you will, you have to
do is every time it starts to scab over,
she calls up or you call her and
then you got an open wound again,
but you gotta do what you got it.
You got to heal like a fucking ex mat
and then the next time you see her and a
guarantee,
if you don't give a fuck,
she's going to fucking be all over you
and want to hook up and this is what she
have to do.
You got to not do it.
And then watch how quickly or that all
that flirty turns into fucking anger.
And then she's going to yell at you and
then just be, keep it cool and be like,
this is why I don't hang out with you
cause y'all fucking crazy a ballet.
Do something like that.
And I would also ask some more adults
who actually actually know the people
involved in this story,
including yourself. Okay.
All right. Good luck to you.
All right.
Sister is obese.
Sister is obese. Dear freckles.
Hoping you can offer some advice.
My sister is and has always
been on the heavy side.
Oh that's sucks.
But Shit has gotten out of hand.
If I had to guess or body
fat is easily 40 to 50%.
I love her and I'm struggling
to get through to her.
Okay.
Uh, you seem like you'd never
hold back or sugar coat reality.
Um,
should I do the same in this situation?
I don't want to send the poor girl into
a whirlwind of emotions and maybe that's
what,
okay.
But maybe that's what she needs. Thanks
for the help. Oh, that's a big one, dude.
Okay.
Um, I don't know how old she is. I
don't know. I don't know her. Um,
yeah. How do you get somebody's
daddy? Tell somebody, hey,
tell your sister she's fat.
Uh, let me see. Let's me just
Improv a couple of scenarios here.
Acs I doing, did I mention you're
overweight? That's too blunt.
What has four limbs and needs to lose
85?
Uh, it's not good to joke about. Um,
I don't know how you'd do it cause I
don't know how fragile she is and I
wouldn't want her to go more in that
direction cause nobody wants to.
Um,
is there a way that you could just start
cooking a little more healthy around
the house and your producers
or some stuff or maybe, uh,
get her to start working out with you
and maybe just go for a walk or something
like that.
MMM.
Maybe just sit down.
He had a great talk with her and find out
what's going on with her and you don't
bring up our weight.
Maybe you work on your relationship
with her and then she opens up and maybe
there's some sort of pain that's
causing her to eat like that. I mean,
that's like a psychological
thing sometimes. Uh,
from what I've heard on shows that I've
seen where people actually know what
they're talking about. So
maybe you need to get like, uh,
I don't know what your relationship is,
but maybe if she feels
comfortable opening up to you.
MMM.
Just ask her what's going on with her,
how's she doing, how's she feeling?
Blahblahblahblahblah and if she, you
know, there's something going on with her.
Maybe she lets that out and then baby,
she brings it up and I hate how I look.
And then you can be like, well, let's do
something about it. You know, maybe try.
I try that way, but I don't think
I would bring up that she's fat.
I wouldn't do that as much
as I made those jokes.
But this podcast is supposed to be
funny and it's supposed to be fucking
ridiculous. So I had, I had to do a cup.
All right, what do you want from me?
I'm bald with a big head and I'm on the
other side of the fucking golf course.
[inaudible] it's, it's, it's where I'm
at. All right? That's a podcast people,
if you enjoy this podcast,
you'd like to donate,
but not without spending a fucking dime.
Just go to my website,
[inaudible] dot com click on the podcast
page and just click on the Amazon link.
Go on Amazon and buy something
you don't really fucking need.
It's not going to cost you any money.
And I'll get a little bit of credit for
driving traffic their way and they'll be
like, ah, bill is a couple of bucks.
That's it. All right everybody,
I'm going to go drink my face
off cause I'm not an alcoholic.
I'm not going to go do a set.
I'm going to go do a set cause I'm
going to be at COBB's comedy club next
Saturday night after a, I do it, do
Kevin Pollock show. Um, he's going
to be interviewing me or whatever.
So it's going to be fun. Uh, I love
that guy. So I do anything for him,
including going up to San Francisco
to hang out with them doing a shelf.
All right, that's it.
Everybody belching here. Uh,
I'll check in on you on Thursday.
Go fuck yourselves and have
a wonderful couple of days.