Hey, what's going on is bill burr and it's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
April 1st,
2013 that's right everybody,
it's April fool's day. Holy Shit.
Is this podcast going to be wacky?
Is he going to pull a prank? Is He
pranking us right now? Is that his voice?
I would tell you guys how much I fucking
hate this day. You know what I mean?
Back when I was in the Matrix and I
actually had a day job and I was a
productive member of society,
you know,
and I actually used to sit there and I'd
go to fucking work every God damn day
and every once in a while at the end
of the day they'd say some shit like,
ah, you know, we'd appreciate
it. It's not mandatory,
but we would appreciate it if you guys
could hang around for a couple minutes
after five today we'd like to talk about
a summary of our productivity goals in
the upcoming quarter. And I would actually
hang out going, I got to do this. I,
I gotta I gotta I gotta put on, I,
uh, I got to put on a, you know,
I've gotta be a team player here and
I would sit there and listen to these
fucking suits, you know, talking about a,
you know, unloading trucks or whatever
the fuck they were talking about it. Oh,
that is interesting. All that's great. Oh,
are we going to upgrade to the
electronic fucking Pallet Jacks,
Pallet Jacks? And we said Palliate
Jackson is like fucking 25 years.
We were all excited. Wow. They really
give a shit about us now. They know.
They just worried they're going to get
sued because the fucking coke had just
blew out his God damn back. You
know? And then they're like, well,
what if everybody blows out their backs?
How do we avoid debt?
What is going to be cheaper paying their
workman's comp or actually getting them
the proper equipment? Um, so anyways,
this stupid fucking April fool's jokes,
right?
I say hate those fucking God damned.
You know,
what I hated about it was half
the people who would get you,
they weren't funny and they their,
this is their idea. You know,
it'd be like, they'd be like, you be like,
Hey, do you know where the pens are? Yeah,
they're in there. They're right in that
drawer. And then you opened, they're like,
hey bro,
ah,
actually this one over here, I just
got, um, I got him with an April fool,
Ya know? And You wonder why
officers get shot up, you know,
just what it is. It's not because a
sociopath's it's not because of, um,
um, um, relaxed gun control laws.
It's not because any of that shit,
it's because of some stupid April
fool's joke that someone won't let go.
And the talking shit about
it still in June, you know?
And then somebody just finally snaps and
they come in there and they mowed out a
bunch of people and it's
considered a tragedy. And it is,
unless you're into the environment
and you look at it a different way
and you're like, well, you know,
as tragic as everything that just
happened is day's going to be a whole lot,
a whole lot less people drop and doses
in that building that will end up in the
water supply. Do you know I went to the
grocery store the other day, people,
oh yeah, I'm not a vampire. I need food
and I fucking walk.
I'm walking in there and there's some
fucking green peace guy with a clipboard
and he's singing like R and B shit.
And
I didn't want to hit him.
I just had to get away from him.
Like it was literally effecting how
I was walking. He was just singing.
He was,
I dunno what,
like he was trying to audition and save
the environment all at the same fucking
time. He was singing some song and
at one point he went like, Whoa Dude,
that fucking that R and B,
you know,
let me hold this note
like I'm getting tickled.
I'm sorry folks.
I did a benefit in a fucking mind
this weekend and I'm a little fucking,
I'm a little,
okay.
Oh, I feel like fucking shit
people. I caught one of these,
one of these super Coles.
Did you guys have it?
Did you get a chance to listen to me?
Last week on the Joe Rogan experience,
I might've mentioned that
I was starting to get sick.
That was the day when I did Joe Rogan's
podcast and I forgot that the guy does
an 18 hour podcast. You know, I'm thinking
like, all right, I'll go over there.
They'll be done in about 90 minutes.
I'll come back here,
get myself a little bit of Robitussin,
chase it with a little bit of Nyquil,
do a line of blow, you know,
fucking stare down the cold,
wide awake and then that'll be it.
And no, that's not what happened.
I did a three and a half
hour podcasts with Rogan. Yo,
what's amazing about two Rogan's podcast
is three and a half fucking hours long
and it feels like 20 minutes,
you know,
until he gets to the last 20
minutes. Then he just like, dude,
I can't fucking talk anymore.
And he may just think about Rogen is if,
I think if you didn't bring it up that
you were three and a half hours in,
he would do another three
and a half hours. Um,
but I had a great time on that one and um,
I sounded extra dumb on that because
Rogan actually reads, you know,
I sound dumb enough
when I'm just by myself,
but when I'm actually on a podcast with
somebody who's actually a well read guy,
you know, my level of stupidity
really gets fucking exposed
to an even higher level. So, um,
okay.
Anyways. Yeah, I've been sick
for like four fucking days.
I didn't actually then take any and I
didn't take any cold medicine because
every fucking cold medicine I looked
at said may do permanent liver damage.
So it was like, all right,
well let's do the math here.
I either go fucking two,
three days of hell and then I'm fine
or I fucking pussy out of three days of
hell in the trade off is permanent
fucking liver damage. Right.
How fucking dumb would that be?
You know,
if you take cold medicine,
you're a fucking pussy is
basically what I'm saying.
Nah, that's not true. That's
not true. Cause you know what,
I don't have to fucking go to work.
You guys do.
And how many sick days can really use,
especially if you're a woman, you know,
if you get knocked up and you're already,
how many days did they give you for that?
It's so fucking pathetic in this
country that like you ever see,
I don't know other countries like how much
time you get off and then people like,
yeah, but they pay like fucking, you know,
nine 90% taxes in that country.
Yes. So what at least they get
something for their fucking taxes.
What the fuck are we
getting in this country? Oh,
I got my two by four out of
the angry voter. Everybody.
Um, despite the fact that I was as
sick as I was, I was sick as a dog man.
I,
uh,
I still got the windows tinted on my car.
I got a couple of things done.
You know what's funny was, ah, the lovely,
beautiful and talented Nia was actually
leaving town on Wednesday and came back
yesterday and I got sick literally
Tuesday night and I was sick the whole
fucking time. I was so fucking
excited that, you know,
that like excited she was going to be
leaving and I was just excited that,
you know,
she wasn't going to be here,
you know, match madness, you know,
watch the fucking basketball
and have the fellas over, right.
Fucking barbecue, drink some beers, right?
I was going to have a great time,
great fucking time.
And then I got this God damn tsunami
of a fucking cold and a dude.
It really wiped me out.
Okay.
Two days. I was just laying on the couch.
It's going, really, are you fucking key?
This is a cold. This is what, this
is what a cold is in 2013, dude,
my fucking hair hurt.
I thought it was because I was dehydrated.
Just started sucking down water and
all it did was make me gag. You know,
it hurts to move my eyes.
I can't move my eyes, man.
Um,
was it was fucking brutal.
So I toughed it out and I still got,
I got the windows tinted. Oh, my car.
And uh, that was hilarious.
And went down there,
I went to this fucking
place where it's like,
do you guys like tint windows and also
torture people in the back room? You know,
one of those really shady,
I didn't go down to the dealership because
I knew they were going to charge me
like fucking 500 bucks to have the
official Toyota of tint on the windows.
I'm like, fuck this, let me just get this
guy to do it for a buck and a quarter.
Um,
okay.
So I go in there,
right.
And then obviously English as a second
language for this guy, you know,
and um,
okay.
I'm sure I could've had
my pick of women to,
if I actually went into that back room.
It just seemed like one of those things,
I just felt like I was in the
second season of the wire, you know,
like there was going to be some big cargo
tin with a bunch of dead hookers in it
in the back. But anyways,
that's none of my business.
I'm just here to get my windows
tinted on my fucking hybrid. So, uh,
I say to the guy,
a guide,
I want the back windows as dark
as I can possibly get them,
cause my dog rides back there and she's
always pen to beat the fucking band.
I'd like her to be cooler. And then up
front, you know, the darker side can get.
And then I was like, wait a minute,
wait, we're waiting. Might Go, you know,
my girl Kinda stinks it drive.
And so I don't want it so dark that she
can't see other cars. And he laughs,
you know, this fucking eastern
European black market fucking laugh.
And he goes, all right, we'll do the 35%
and then we'll do the UV rays up front.
And I'm like, great. So yeah, Yada a,
he does them enough. They, they,
they look fucking phenomenal.
Okay.
So I'm recovering the next fucking
two more days of this bullshit, right?
I finally come around yesterday and a,
I'm feeling good and I know knee is
on the way home. So what do I do?
I fucking clean up the Goddamn House.
Yeah.
That's a big thing you have to do
when you fucking woman leaves town.
When she comes back,
the place has to look even fucking better.
It has to look fucking great. And there's
got to be food in the fridge. Okay.
Why? Because out of
respect, no out of love.
No.
Okay.
The why would you do it, bill? I'll
tell you why. Because you can't fucking,
okay.
You can't give them that fucking power
that they feel like you're an absolute
fucking moron.
Okay.
If they're not there, you know, they
stuck feeling that after a while,
because you know, when you fucking
live with somebody, like a woman,
they basically decide
where everything goes.
That's like shit that you both use and
you're a guy and you don't give a fuck.
Right? So every fucking time you gotta
be like, yeah, where's the salad spool?
Where the fuck is this?
Where the fuck is that?
And then they get to be like the fucking
chick on a, on a sitcom. Right? Well,
my husband, he's a fucking moron, right?
So I didn't want to have her that I didn't
want her to have that fucking victory.
I vacuumed. I did have the, took
the trash out at everything.
Just looking fucking spotless.
Okay.
You going to come home?
Look at me like I'm a fucking moron.
Okay.
Well honey, the place looks great.
Yeah, I met you when I was 36.
I know how to make toast.
All right. Get over yourself.
I was actually cleaning
up so well was like,
she's gonna think I cheated on
her or something. This is like,
this is getting fucking ridiculous.
What'd you vacuum for you getting rid
of the fucking straight pubis is, uh,
this is the Monday morning
podcast. Everybody. Um,
now that would have been, that would
have said if I actually cheated on her,
what a fucking piece of shit, first of
all. And then second of all, like, um,
I would have a sex addiction if I actually
did that because of how fucking sick,
sick I was.
You know,
if I should bagged one of those fucking
eastern European horrors that I know
we're locked in the back of that
tinted out fucking place. Um, you know,
it's funny. It was, we, she gets
home. All right? And within,
within an hour we get where we were in
a fight because I told the story about
getting the windows
tinted like an asshole.
I wasn't even thinking and I mentioned
to the fact that I said she wasn't the
greatest driver and I heard her feelings.
Okay,
you said that you don't
think I'm a good driver.
Okay.
Oh Jesus Christ. And that's one of those
ones where you just got to be like, okay,
ah, Bill, you're an idiot. Why
did you say that? You know,
I'm still pissed that she
got pissed about that.
Okay.
You know,
that would be like if she told one of
her friends that I'm not a good dancer,
and then I was like, you told
her go to. Yeah, Bill, you suck.
Suck it dancing.
You know
Jesus fucking Christ.
Okay.
I was fucking kills me about
fucking women. It's like they, they,
even when they know they
stink at something, if you
say they stick at something,
they get,
they get all fucking offended.
You said the truth.
Well why?
Why would you say what's
actually happening? You know?
Okay.
Terrible fucking dancer.
I think maybe I could in another
life I could have been a good dancer,
but all like happy emotions were beaten
out of me by the time I was fucking four
years old. So, you know,
just dancing. I mean,
okay.
I can't, I don't, it's not even in me.
Okay.
That whole fucking whatever that
gift is, when, whenever that is,
whenever the dancing does
just fucking sprinkled on you.
That was not sprinkled on me in any
way, shape or fucking for, you know,
even the music lessons to angry music
except for Bruno Mars. Every once in a
while I got it. I got a little, I don't,
that's not true. Wait a minute bill.
Come on. Who else she got in there?
Night Ranger. Hey, did
you see these fucking, uh,
these guys want to blow us up. Now.
You know what? Before I get into that,
I bought a little advertising. Everybody
let's, let's do something. A voice.
Everybody their back
that back on the podcast.
He voice is the reason you're going to
make money in 2013 let me repeat that.
He voiced
is the reason you're going
to make money in 2013 hey,
why are you going to make money in 2013
because he he voice when your customers
call, you'll have your own toll
free number, professional greeting,
dial by name directory and more.
All this is basically if you want to
start your own business and you want to
make it seem like you actually
own your own skyscraper,
but you actually, you know are
still living in your parents' attic.
He voices the way to go to make yourself
sound unbelievably professional.
You'll sound like a fortune 500 company
and you'll blow away your competitors
simply by sounding that professional
and that's what it all is people.
It's not about your product.
It's about what it sounds like when
they call your company. All right.
He voiced lets you give out one number
that rings wherever you are, the beach,
the bar doesn't matter.
You'll sound like you're at your office.
You got to go to he voice.com
and use Promo Code Bill,
ie voice even takes all your voicemails,
transcribes them and sends them
instantly as a texture. Emily, uh, email.
That's great. So then you can
be at your other job. You know,
you don't have to be on the phone.
You can act like you're typing as you're
sitting there looking at your, uh, your,
your, uh, your voicemails. Um,
she can check voicemails before
the meeting ends and not look rude.
Eve Voice is only 10 bucks a month,
but right now,
listeners to my podcast can try
he voice for free for six months.
That's right. A six months
free trial. Support my podcast.
Stop what you are doing.
Hit Pause,
set up your eve voice free trial and
see what I'm talking about. Go to eve,
voice.com and use Promo Code Bill.
That's he voiced.com. Promo Code Bill.
One more time.
Eva [inaudible] Dot Com Promo Code Bill.
I don't think,
I think slipped that in there.
Stopped what you're doing it and hit
pause. See what they just did there.
Ah, that was kind of sneaky.
My dumb ass read it. Um,
anyways,
you see these North Korean cons are
allegedly going to try and blow us up.
This is fucking amazing.
They get this video.
It's fucking Jesus Christ built team kit.
Can you,
can you just have anything ready to go?
This is,
why am I eventually actually
going to have like a whole, Nah,
I'm not going to do that.
Actually have like a, like a,
an official radio set up. You
know, I'm not going to do that.
Cause then you know what,
then I have in this somewhere.
I have to be this people I have to answer
to in all that fucking horse shit I'm
not doing,
I was watching this whole thing on um,
uh,
North Korea and how they made make this
promo video and it's basically about
them launching their own space. Shuttles
is North Korea and dude, I'm assuming,
right? And he's sitting there dreaming
and they had the instrumental of,
we are the world in the
background, right? We owe the womb.
We are the children.
This fucking North Korean
space shuttle is flying around,
you know, fried around the
globe. Korea is unified.
And,
um,
okay.
You know, and it ends with a
city that looks like New York,
which is on fire after some sort
of missile attack, you know?
But I guess they say, and it looks
like the evil doers did themselves in,
they don't take responsibility for doing
it, but I guess, you know, I don't know.
Evidently that was caused for big concern.
Not In my world though,
even though la I guess is one of
the first ones they want to attack.
I don't give a fuck.
Okay.
Is that going to make you happy?
They have fucking all fucking
fat face their fat face part too.
You know,
I could see why were annoying.
Okay.
I mean, we got in the middle of their
fight over there way back in the day.
Should a minded our own business,
let them Duke it out,
whoever wins wins.
But we didn't leave stuck a fucking noses
in over there and now they don't like
us old. What will we do
during the fucking, uh,
civil war if all of a sudden a
Korea came over here and was like,
Hey,
we side with these guys other side.
Why don't you settle down
after a while. Be like, hey,
why don't you guys get
the fuck out of here.
Let us solve our own fucking
problems. I get it. You know,
I just don't want her to
stand what North Korea has,
what their fascination is with
having a fat dictator. They, oh,
they like a real pudgy fucking,
uh,
like on medication, like bloated
face kind of fucking dictator.
That's their thing. I don't,
I'm not worried about it.
I would be more worried if they were
going to try and blow up San Francisco
because I'm in Los Angeles.
Okay.
If you're going to fucking shoot a
goddamn nuclear weapon at this country,
by all means do it at the city that I'm
in because I don't want to survive it.
All right? Best way you
want to be, by the way,
all these fucking people trying to come
up with these underground places to go,
that's not what you want to be.
You want to be right with a
fucking Kona that missile hits.
That's what you want to be. Just
get vaporized. You have no idea.
You don't even know what's coming.
Sitting there watching sports in a bad,
bad at it.
It over.
You know you don't want to
be on the outskirts like in
Scottsdale fucking Arizona
with one side of your fucking face melted
off and then walking around for four
days
for wheat thins.
You want to do that. You have some
fucking agonizing like 18 day death.
Fuck that.
I want to be vaporized.
You know?
Why did you ever see a bunch of
bugs and he hit him with some raid.
That fucker one that takes the direct hit.
That thing is done in two seconds.
But the other ones that do when that
little fucking Angus young running on the
ground during a guitar solo fucking move.
Those are the ones you don't want to be
right.
I Dunno, I don't give a fuck about North
Korea and that worried about those guys.
All right. You want to fucking start
some shit? Go ahead. All right.
Start some fucking shit.
What are they going to do?
Like what, what exactly is that?
They're, they're fucking game plan.
You can update it. It's so like not even
a throw. Okay, you're going to, what?
You're going to take out two cities.
We have enough shit to fucking blow up
the entire world like 9 million times.
So you're going to take out Los Angeles,
right? And then, then you know what?
You're not going to have any movies
to watch. You ever think about that?
North Korea, God knows your dad loved
watching all our fucking movies.
You're going to have none of that shit,
right?
You're going to have half the
fucking divas that you're going to,
that you're going to hire to perform
at your fucking New Year's party.
Like Beyonce.
They're not going to be there.
Isn't Beyonce one of the ones that
perform for some fucking mass murdering
psychopath? Was it her? I had a fuck
enough. I'll throw her name out. You know,
I'll take her name off and
I'll say it was, uh, uh,
boost face there from the voice.
The one that likes to get dirty.
What's her name? Christina
Applegate gag. Yulara.
Yeah, you go. Was it
her? She's another one.
She does that R and B singing
[inaudible] and fucking point everywhere.
Fucking voice is going.
Seems like she's sitting
on a giant vibrator. Um,
she's just said,
fuck it.
Okay.
You know what? I sat with her and
she just said to hell with it.
I don't give a fuck.
You know,
I'm just going to be almost in shape
and you guys can just fucking do.
I had a kid, I like having a glass
of wine around four in the afternoon.
Go Fuck Yourself. I'm an I like, I
really respect that she doesn't care.
You know?
Like if she was a dude,
she'd be one of those guys who couldn't
wear a tie because it, it just fucking,
she can't breathe at that point.
Okay.
She would she dress like
Dana White? Um, all right.
I didn't know what the fuck I'm talking
about here. Have you guys see that?
They get to have these
new smell of visions,
real smellovision TV
unveiled by Japanese team,
and it's not an April fool,
is what it says.
Tokyo team advent as
smelling screen that makes,
smells emanate from the spot on the
screen showing their corresponding object.
It works by feeding odors from
sublimating gel pallets
appellate's into air strikes.
It's sublimating.
That doesn't sound right.
Like I don't think I
pronounced that correctly.
Whatever gel pellets into air streams
that can be directed to specific spots on
the screen.
So what are you going to have?
Like a bunch of pellets.
Okay.
For every state that just, it's
not going to work. You know what?
The sad thing about this
stupid fucking thing is,
is this at the development promises to
make advertisement for fried chicken or
fresh coffee even more appealing. You know
who's going to get this fucking thing?
I swear to God,
Bobby Kelly [inaudible]
good. I got the new
smell of Asian kid, dude.
I'm watching the food network.
I was fucking drilling.
Did the guy's making a
fucking lobster souffle?
I could fucking smell
the fucking beach dude.
You know it.
He'll buy it right when it comes out.
So we can be the first guy
and is blocked the habit.
It'll cost him 15 grand and
then in like fucking four years,
they're going to be
selling for like 600 bucks.
Yeah,
that's,
that's the one of the things about being
at the forefront of technology when you
just have to be the first Douche
bag on your block. You know,
I gotta I have to have him on
this podcast because I really,
I really want to talk to him about
that. Like what, what is that?
Okay.
Cause I see it it like,
it like fills him up.
When I used to be in New York City
and he would get some new gadget,
he couldn't fucking wait
to come down to the cellar.
It stick of some phony reason
to pull out his new shiny thing.
Just dying for somebody to be like,
oh is that the new fucking shiny
fucking fuzzy 1000 and then either
they need a big N. Oh,
why? Yes. Yes it is.
Go check it. It charges my iPhone
bum. You opened this over here.
Flap.
I got all my dates Zoe.
That motherfucker has had
everything fucking everything.
I like 15 years ago when he's
still at his noodle hair,
he fucking had anything that
had a stylist at palm pilot.
He had everything he had that I lived
with them, he had that and he had bags.
He, those were the two things
that he was fucking into.
And you know what I was into eating
bland food and staring at the wall.
So who fucking one who wanted that one?
I would say Bobby.
Um, all right, let's
get to some fucking, uh,
some God damn questions for this
fucking week here. By the way,
I dunno if I brought this up yet cause
I've had it start this podcast a couple
of times because I had
a coughing fit. Uh, um,
obviously the fastest,
most Speedy's recovery possible
for Kevin Ware of the, uh,
of Louisville. Jesus
Christ. That was one of the,
that's one of the worst
things I've ever seen. And um,
okay.
Yeah.
And if you haven't seen it,
you know what just it's killing me is
I know there's going to be a bunch of
people upload that fucking
video and then Douche,
we'll have to make jokes
in that type of thing.
But what a tough mother fucker
Skype basically he broke,
I don't know if it was a
compound fracture. If it was,
if it was both bones or whatever,
but I know at least one of them,
you know,
was coming through the fucking skin
and he's still laying in there telling
everybody to win the fucking game.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
That wouldn't have been me.
I would've been crying like a fucking
girl and saying, you know, games,
I would have used up all our time out.
Right.
Yeah.
And I could give a fuck about the game
at that point. I would be screaming.
I would've been like,
Nancy Kerrigan.
Why?
Oh, that's one of my favorite clips of
all time. Because you know what I love?
I love that she acted exactly
how I would have acted.
Everybody wants to act like they're going
to be the hey win one for the gipper.
And you know what?
Most of us got that Nancy Kerrigan gene,
you know, we're just going to
start crying and be like, why me?
MMM.
That really was, that was right
up there as far as like, you know,
she'd obviously never gotten
her ass kicked in her life.
The fact that she couldn't even
wrap her fucking head around,
you know, if she had gotten her ass
kicked a couple of times, she, at least,
what is she, why me would have been
downgraded to dude. What the fuck?
Oh my God.
Right?
Why?
Um, I don't even know where
the fuck I was going with that.
Oh, sorry guys. This fucking podcast
sucks this week. I, I'm, I'm,
I'm all right. I admit it. It this
week. I'm fucking, I'm still sick.
But you know,
yesterday's yesterday's fucking
last week's was a great one. Okay.
So give me a little bit of slack here.
Company a little slide for quite shit.
Can you do that? Um, right. Oh, by
the way, you know something, um,
a couple of weeks ago I mentioned to the
fact that, um, I don't get the, you know,
the Premiere League as far as their,
their soccer over there where
their jerseys can be just
so the colors is so dry,
a dramatically different.
Like you'll be watching a team and
they're red and white and then next week
they're wearing black and yellow. And
it's like, what the fuck? And, uh,
this guy wrote and he said, uh, in
the premier league colors Shange
uh,
for example, Arsenal play man
United, they both wear red and white.
So the way team changes colors. That's
why they changed the team cause I guess,
and it's kind of weird that they're in
the same league and guys can have the
same colors, you know, which is
starting to happen in American sports.
Like however,
the Toronto Maple leafs sued the Tampa
Bay lightning for their new fucking
jerseys, yet, you know,
they're slowly moving in on your fucking
territory and I don't know why you're
not saying anything. Um,
all right. Anyways, Bill,
your workout routine.
A bill,
I'd like 95% of Americans on your shows.
You look like what I think most people
would look like should look like in terms
of fitness. Uh, you see what he did there?
He gave me a nice big compliment as
he fucking trash. 95% of America.
It's not 95%.
It's a good fucking 65% of their kids.
Um, do you follow a specific
routine? Thanks. Um,
well, right now I'm fucking horrible
shape. I put them fucking 10 pounds.
But this is the thing, I never
let it get beyond this. You know,
I never let it get beyond
like a little bit of fucking
like 10 pounds and then I just take
it off. That's basically what I do.
I hike with my dog and um,
and I,
I use my own body weight.
I use my whole body weight because I
find that that that makes you more cut
rather than puffy.
If you fucking lift weights and Shit,
you get,
you just start over,
develop in like five different
groups of muscles and a,
you start walking around looking
like a midget bouncer. At least I do.
So I you a climbing rope.
I have a peg board and I have a,
a pull up and dip station.
Uh,
because I am a firm believer that you
need to be able to move your own body,
you know, and I used to do yoga
fucking years and years ago, but um,
I dunno, I just can't get
myself to go to the classes.
Those fucking mats are all dirty and shit.
Even if you bring your own mat,
that's just the level of and bare feet,
it's just fucking disgusting. And uh,
you know,
and then also the chicks and they're so
fucking ridiculous looking that at least
out here in la, um, you know,
the whole mental aspect of the thing
is out the fucking window cause he's
supposed to be like, you
know, also calming your mind
and I'm not calming my mind.
My mind is fucking going.
So, um, yeah, that's what it is.
And I try not to eat like an asshole and
now that I'm ever advanced age can be
45 years old.
I try to eat a fucking giant salad
every day and a is while fighting that,
what are you a fig fucking
voice in my head. But um,
as much as people sit there and they say
that that's bird food and that type of
thing, eat a giant salad every
day and I'm telling you, yeah,
you're going to be right as rain.
All right.
I'm telling you,
if you don't eat a salad every day and
you read and fucking a bunch of meat and
that type of thing,
I swear to God trying to take
his shit is like fucking,
it's not a fun experience. You have a
giant salad every day. It's not a problem.
That's, you know what? That was true
but disgusting. But I don't give a fuck.
There you go. So that's
what I do. Um, all right.
Cooking Billy boy our day.
What are some of your favorite
things to cook in the kitchen?
I was never much of a cook until
I realized it's super easy.
Um, well you must have a gift
then. What do you mean super easy?
What are you making eggs over easy?
Yeah, that's easy. But he immune,
you're actually, you know, doing
some of that food network stuff.
I don't think it's super easy.
Second, you've got to have like a,
an ice bath bath to like
blanche some shit, you know.
Anyways. Uh, or caramelizing shit.
You just got to experiment and think
the basics through the food network
mentioned a website called my fridge,
food.com that tells you what you can
make with the ingredients in your house.
I accidentally learned how to make
teriyaki sauce and Pumpkin pie because of
what I've had, what I had in my
place. That's actually an interesting,
you mentioned once you made ribs.
Have you mastered anything?
What's your go to?
Um,
if I mastered anything,
uh, the fuck can I do? Uh,
I don't know. I don't know. I, I'm
one of those people every once,
once every eight months I throw down and
I cook and I make a fucking great meal.
MMM.
Through it.
I'll make you a spaghetti sauce if you
like a sweeter one that has some molasses
in it and it will literally make you
punch your fucking wife in the face
repeatedly.
Just fucking,
just drawn back with each shoe,
just areas. You bite down,
you're letting it fuck you. Let your
hands go. You know, you're free.
That's how good.
This just spaghetti sauces.
I can make you little lasagna
meat based of course. Uh,
to do that.
I can do all of that shit.
I can make you some fucking short
ribs there. Yeah, I can fucking cook.
If I gave a fuck if I really wanted to,
I could get really good at cooking.
I'm actually, I'm really good at
baking. I think I tell a nice story.
I don't like this shit.
I don't like being,
I don't like these two fucking questions
here where I'm talking positively about
myself. You know why? Because there's
absolutely no humor in it. All right,
let's get back to the
fucking grip strength.
You know why you need grip strength in
case you're ever in a fucking house fire
and you need to climb
down the Goddamn gutters.
All you need to go up to the roof and
then take a running leap to the house next
to it and you're gonna come up short and
you're going to fucking grab something
over there or maybe a fucking tree branch.
That's what you need.
Grip Strength Four.
All right.
I guess if you lift weights and you
ever get sucked into a sinkhole,
you can fucking lift your house.
Safia I dunno what, all right.
As far as cooking, I don't
think cooking, senna,
cooking, the whole thing is, is you
got to have all these, you know,
if you really want to throw down,
it's that initial startup costs.
It's like when you first
learned how to fix a car,
it's not going to be cheaper than taking
it to somewhere else because you're
going to have to fucking,
not only by the parts,
you're gonna have to buy all the tools.
Um,
so I dunno, have I mastered anything?
Yeah, I can make a fucking pie.
I can make cakes. I get big. I can
grill. I'm not the greatest griller.
I got to admit,
I get very impatient with growing.
I know I'm supposed to have like the
caveman shit and want to be standing out
there over the fucking fire.
I'm, I'm really not a into that.
I used to work in a restaurant and I
worked in the ski grill and they had the
big fucking chef hat and all that type
of shit and I made great burgers and
shrimp Rochelle and chicken sandwiches
and that shit. I know how to do it.
I can mock up the meat, I can
fucking cook. I just don't, I'm just,
I have to be into it and I get into it
and I'm psycho into it for like three
weeks and then I'm just not, I
don't give a fuck after awhile. Um,
cause I have fucking add,
you know,
basically standup comedy is the
only thing I ever stuck with.
So hence it's the only thing I remember
I'm really good at. I can play drums,
okay. Can play a little guitar, they
can make a couple of dishes and uh,
I can shoot the shit about the weather
at a party. And then pretty much that,
other than that, I'm done.
Um, underrated the Bible,
the Bible. All right. Uh,
well, Jesus, here we go.
That's the risk of pissing you off.
I'm writing to say that the Bible is
underrated. That doesn't piss me off.
I mean, it's a hell of
a story, you know? Uh,
really all religious texts are
underrated and I can't blame anyone for
underrating religion since
religion is a lot of, uh,
speculative crap. Um, no,
I think the basis of all religions
are the way you should live life.
Like the 10 commandments is like
common sense, the seven deadly sins.
I love that shit. It's that. It's that
once you start being like, you know, he,
he loves us best and you don't
believe what we're saying. So, uh,
you're infidels and now we have to kill
you or we have to have a crusade or we
have to torture you until you're into
what the fuck were into or were making so
much money off this horse shit. We
have to look the other way. Well,
some of us are fucking children.
You know that, that's where I, I, I,
I make my departure,
you know,
or you're constantly telling me that,
that this thing is fucking mad at me
because of flawed despite that's the way
you fucking made me.
Like that's never made sense to me.
MMM.
Or like if there's a god that, you know,
he makes somebody like a sociopath.
Okay.
It's sociopath is basically
a broken human being.
Like they didn't get all the parts
and
it's like, not even, it's not
even their fault that, that, that,
that they're born that way,
that they don't feel anything.
All right.
That's not that that person's going to
hell because they were born fucked up,
you know? Now I'm not saying
I have sympathy for sociopath.
I think they should be hunted down and
fucking shot in the street like rabid
dogs. But I'm just saying as far as the,
uh, are you going to have an a hell?
I mean, isn't that like
on, on the manufacturer?
I've always equated it to that. Like,
you know, it'd be like if you built,
built a piece of shit car,
like you fucked up,
you fucked it up when you built it and
then you get mad at it because it doesn't
run right. You know? So that,
that's my thing. So you know,
if humor into the Bible, I
don't give a fuck. Anyway.
I want to bring up the book of job.
Huh? Look at that. I said it right.
I didn't say job job rich reads as a
tale of cruelty because God and the devil
got together to put job through
the wringer. Do you know bad?
I would love to read the book of Job and
actually be able to read more than two
paragraphs without sitting there going,
what the fuck are they talking about?
Uh,
I think most people religious
and otherwise miss an
important point throughout
the text.
Job's friends went half cocked
saying that Joe must have,
must have done something to
deserve what was happening to him.
Sounds like the type of
thing a lady would say,
not at sounds a type of thing like
a religious nut would say to me. Uh,
at the end God became angry with job's
friends from making this assumption and
made them do sacrifices just
for being smart as shit heads.
Um,
so the Bible has all kinds
of moral concepts that have
barely survived into the
modern era. Probably thanks to
all the linguistic mangling well,
thank God you're there
to figure it all out. Uh,
job demonstrates that the burden
of proof falls upon the accuser.
It's even part of our justice system,
but nobody gives it the importance
it deserves. Especially Christians.
If there's a god, he definitely
pissed. He's definitely pissed at,
you know who? No, I don't.
I don't know. I was totally with you
until you put it all on the Christians.
But now I think that which we jury
the Jewish or Muslim or fucking,
okay.
I Dunno.
Is there something else?
Okay.
Who are those people who pray to the
trees? Hippies. Is that a religion?
Huh?
Dirty hippies?
Yeah.
Et cetera.
Religion.
Okay.
Hindu, not Hindu. Hari Krishna.
Hari Krishna is just dirty
hippies who shaved their heads
or am I thinking of that Charles
Manson movie for the Manson family?
I'll shave their heads. I don't fucking
know. I don't know what your point was.
Surf. It made me want to read the book of
Joe, but I know what's going to happen.
I'll start to read it and then as B,
and then God said it thought to you with
the hallway and the the seventh son of
the fucking he BD Hamadie who? And
it's just like, all right. You know?
Okay.
Why don't they give a,
I'm sure there is.
I'm sure there's an updated version of it
where they actually write it in a more,
um,
modern English.
Yeah.
Like the band. All right. Bill wife left.
Okay,
Bill.
So I got a text from my wife a couple of
weeks ago saying she had taken her dog
and her things left and
we're getting a divorce.
Wow.
She gave you a text message,
you know,
that's kind of the way to do it.
Okay.
In a selfish way,
you know.
Do you know,
I know somebody who did that.
I knew somebody who was in a
fucking relationship forever.
Yeah.
And I guess they just didn't
know how to get out of it.
So here's an option for people out there,
men and women.
And so this has nothing to do with you.
This just reminded me of this.
So this fucking guy,
okay.
Is uh,
is woman went on a cruise,
I went on to some sort of wine
tasting thing or whatever and
he, I guess he knew that
she was going on this trip.
So before she left,
he already found another apartment,
signed a lease and all that type of shit.
So she leaves, I mean she was
leaving for like two, three days.
He had another buddy of
mine went over there.
They packed up all his shit and
fucking moved it out to this new place.
And then,
you know, he just lived in that place
until the day she was coming back.
He came back to the apartment,
she comes home and immediately
sees half the shit is gone.
And he just dropped the bomb
like that and said, listen,
you know, we need to talk.
I'm not fucking happy.
And what I tell you,
this fucking woman flip the fuck out.
Flipped the fuck out.
Like what?
Absolutely fucking ballistic.
And,
and I always wanted to ask her why,
what was it that made you flip out?
Would you,
would you have flipped out less?
Yeah,
cause she, she didn't even go
into the, the surprise of what,
Oh my God, crying, uh,
blood went immediately to anger and I
think it was because he was already out.
Yeah.
And there wasn't going to
be any sort of closure.
Slash I can torture you.
It'd be a total cunt to you.
Like he sidestepped all of that.
It just made this clean ass fucking break.
You know Dennis Miller, that's
the news. And I am out of here.
That's what I thought what he did it.
And
I dunno why. I always smile when I
think, cause that's the thing, you know,
if you're going to break up a woman,
you just know. I mean, I mean,
I never had a breakup with
a girl I was living with.
I can't imagine that fucking
hell and this person.
I mean that, that's one way to do it. Um,
so if you are stuck in a relationship and
you don't know how to fucking bring it
up, you just don't know how to
do it. That's one way to do it.
Because when they come home
and you're sitting there,
but you all your shit isn't there. Uh,
that's, that's the conversation has been
God.
Fuck. Anyways, so getting
back to this poor bastard,
he goes, harass Chanel was that,
she always hated me. Oh my God.
Forget the eight instances of cheating,
three posts, marriages that I,
three post-marriage that I tolerated just
because is as good of a reason for her
to leave as any,
wait a minute back up here.
Wait a minute, dude. She
cheated on you ate fucking times
five times before he got married.
I mean to what? Come on man.
You didn't see this coming. All right,
I'm going to save judgment here. Uh,
he said forget about the
aids instances of cheating,
three post marriages that I tolerated
the he price and quote just because is as
good of reason for her to leave as any,
uh,
here's where you pummel me,
but she was my mom's,
but she was at my mom's
bedside with my mom
and I when my mom died.
Okay. I didn't realize,
dude, you didn't write this well. I
didn't realize to her that nothing,
I didn't realize to her
that was nothing but
her way in.
I didn't realize that to her. I don't
know. What did she went to that, that,
that was her way into your life?
In my grief.
I didn't notice she went full Andy.
Okay.
Do frame just chipping away at my
sense of self so she would fuck around.
So when she would fuck around, I
thought, well no person in the world.
We'll hang on to me. So this is better
than being alone. Fuck it. I'll do.
Come on man. She and I had
been together for nine years,
married three.
My problem is that as a 26 year
old birthday was yesterday,
none of my friends can relate.
And my thousand yard stare,
oh can relate.
And my thousand yard stare at
the bar just seems to be harsh.
Seems to harsh there.
Hipster PBR buzz. Dude,
this is the most difficult fucking
thing I've ever tried to read. Um,
dude, you're like 26 years old. Get the
fuck out of this thing. Go to the gym.
Is that your problem?
Huh?
You got a little dull around the
fucking middle that said to read up on
nutrition gets get some
fucking self esteem, man.
This is ridiculous. Is fucking
cunt. You know why she hated you?
She's probably one of the reasons she
hates she's cause you're not sticking up
for yourself. This fucking
dude. Yeah. You know what?
I'm not gonna yell at,
you've already been through the
fucking ringer with this one.
I'm sorry you ran into
something like this. I'm sorry.
I don't know who the fuck you are.
Your male role model was when you were
growing up, didn't build you up more.
They obviously didn't fucking raise you.
Right? And now you've got to do it. Okay?
You got to build yourself
up, man. You can't fucking,
you can't fucking have
something like this going on.
You like William h Macy in
fucking a boogie nights.
You going eventually fucking
shoot her in the driveway,
fucking your friends and
then go blow your brains out.
You don't want to be that
guy. Fuck this woman. He goes,
I've tried to get back out there with
some people I know, but when they tried,
when they tell their stories from college,
all I think is,
I wonder if John McCain gets this mad
when people his age tells stories about
Woodstock.
Okay.
All right.
Now where do we make the leap there?
What their pussy stories and you're
pissed because you missed out on that.
Uh,
I'm lost.
I'm optimistic as for the most part,
my life is much better by friends think
I'm exaggerating because they saw us
together and my response is that people
saw Elizabeth smart out in public too
and she wasn't and she wasn't fine either.
What the hell do I do?
The last time I was single, texting
didn't exist. I couldn't drink legally.
I've lived with my parents.
I lived with my parents. Uh,
you got the 0.3 examples ago,
but I keep typing.
I thought maybe as a comic
when you started going into
the road and didn't know
people everywhere, it may have been a
similar vibe. Yeah, Dude. Like you're,
you're starting from ground zero.
You're totally beat down.
Okay.
You're 26 years old talking
about like you're 50, you know,
you're fine. All right. Oh wait. So you
went there for fucking, what'd you say?
Eight or nine years?
Let's do the math here.
Yeah.
Tastes my wife of Blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah. Eight instances.
I'll see you there for nine years.
So you got together with this girl when
he was 17. He was still, you were a baby.
All right. I get it, I get it.
And you stayed with this girl and you
never cheated on her. She cheated on you.
And all those years of college when
you should've got you game together,
how to talk to women, but blah
blah blah blah blah. Yeah,
dude, that's easy. You can,
you can make up ground real quickly
here. You're only 26 years old. Um,
you just gotta. You just gotta get
yourself out there now. I mean,
I wouldn't suggest just going out to
bars. Look, if you want to fuck a woman,
go out to a bar. Do that. If you want
to meet somebody nice, then I would,
I would be, I would definitely look
elsewhere. Uh, do you have any hobbies?
Do you like sports?
I would join some sort of a fucking,
what the fuck is the word?
What's the word?
When they lead guys and women
play together. You know,
I joined some shit like that.
Take a fucking cooking class.
It's just something, you know, something
where the, where the good girls go to,
you know, but you know, if you
just want to go out and get laid,
who gives a fuck? You, what you gotta
do is you got to get over being,
getting rejected. Just go out to a
bar, just talk some shit. You know,
don't go out and get plastered and
use that as your fucking courage.
Just go out there and just talk some shit,
you know,
and just go out there and just say, all
right, I'm going to die. I'm going to say,
what's up to 10 different women tonight?
All right? Or if that's too overwhelming,
make it five or four. All right?
No more, no less than four.
All right? All right. With no,
no pressure on the results.
Just go out there and just
fucking strike up a conversation.
See how long you can keep it going and,
and just,
you know, whatever, you're going to be
nervous, you're going to give a fuck.
But with each one, you're going to give a
shit less. And the less you give a fuck,
the more relaxed you are going to be.
The funny you're going to be,
the more you're going to attract them.
It's, it's literally when you give a fuck,
when you give a fuck, you
scaring them away. When you care,
you know you'll be fine,
all right? But it's,
you got to grow up and stop and brace
in this fucking this depressive shit
because it's also gonna make you an angry
cunt and you're going to fucking hate
women and you're gonna push your
friends away in the end up being alone.
All right?
Unfortunately you fucking,
you wasted nine years of your life with
some cunt and he got fucking married,
okay? But it wasn't a waste because now
you know what you don't want. All right?
So that's it.
But for the love of God,
do not get into another
goddamn relationship.
You got to make a pact with yourself.
You're not going to go from a nine year,
one, three year marriage to fucking
jump in into something else.
You gotta stay single and figuring
out what the fuck you want.
You might not want it.
You might want to like not even go out
to fucking bars for awhile. You know,
let's go to the gym.
Hit it like a fucking mad man.
You know it.
Fucking figure out what you will,
what you're looking for and then
where it should be and then go in that
direction. Do that. All right?
Not Everybody's going to be the guy who
goes out and bags of fucking a hundred
women who gives a fuck. All
right. At the end of it,
if you find fucking love and you find
the person he's supposed to be with you,
one. Okay, so, uh, whatever,
there's my fucking 2 cents. Did I
say the F word enough? Um, alright.
From fucking Croatia,
which is in fucking Europe.
Look at this guy breaking my balls from
the other side of the planet. All right,
I'll get right to it. Recently, my luck
with the ladies changed for the better.
Good for you sir.
I realized how different men are from
women and it started using that to my
advantage. Both sir. The last person.
Please listen to this guy. Uh,
I'm 23 and in college I started
college three years older.
So I am in class with 19 to 20 year olds.
Pretty much.
They are all ladies. Not a single
one of them is, Eh, is annoying.
I get along with all of them.
But there is this one,
Christina who acts like she's
the only one with problems. Okay,
well there's always going to
be a bad one in there. Uh,
we talked a couple of times,
even when out on a date she seemed
interested but very distant.
Uh,
the date was very tense.
Unlike all the other dates I can handle.
Oh,
Jesus. You guys really killed me this
week. Unlike all the other dates,
I can handle someone
manly. At least I am. Cool.
So everything goes relatively smoothly.
I'm going to cut you some slack circus.
This is a fucking second language.
This is amazing. Um, this date was as,
as stiff as Jay Leno. I hated it. Uh,
so we didn't talk for a couple of
days after the Hora date. Uh, my dad,
my bad for not knowing, not talking
to her. I know. No it isn't.
He had a bad day. Don't call her
back. You didn't have good time.
Why would you pursue it? Uh, anyways,
then we started talking again
and some vibes are going on,
but we only saw each other in class.
Then we started talking some deep shit
over Facebook as 20 year olds do and I
realize we don't get each other.
We just don't understand one another.
All right,
so walk away.
She has a little circle of friends
and a lot of guys come on to her,
but she's like very into ourself and shit.
Okay.
I know her self centered
feelings are natural or her age,
but I am a little bit older but she's
like, now no one understands me.
She's really a baby yet, dude, you
have this all figured out. He goes,
we don't understand each other at all.
It's like,
we mean the same thing but awkwardly
argue over the choice of the words we use.
Man, I really want a banger.
She smiled. I was going to say,
she has to be beautiful. He said
she's smoking hot. In the meantime,
I am all over the other ladies.
Uh,
but I'm really restless about this one.
I like her,
but she will break me if
I get too much into her.
Alica we started speaking like Ivan Drago.
Um,
so the gist of my pussy ass letter is
how do I bang her now after the shitty
date and awkward Facebook
arguments? Uh, God damn.
I just realized she's cutting my
balls off when I talked to her.
I must get my shit together
if I want to fuck her,
but I still don't really know
how to do it. Shit. Okay.
Uh, all right. What
are we going to do? Um,
yeah.
All right. How the fuck do we undo
what the fuck was already done?
What would I do? Uh, I would fucking,
you know what I would do?
I would just charm the shit out of her
and I would come in in a fucking great
mood. Even if you're not in a
great mood just coming to class,
you know,
is it,
I'm giving you the fucking demoed speech
from fast times at Ridgemont high get,
Oh, you just kept walking in
like, your fucking life is great.
You know,
she's going to be like, oh my God.
He's like, I'm not like talking to him.
And he's like having a good time. Does
that like mean I'm not pretty anymore?
Like that'll fuck with her fucking the
world revolves around me that you can
actually, now that you've
been sucked into her world,
you could still actually
have a great fucking day.
Okay.
Without needing her fucking,
uh, attention or anything.
Yeah. Just walk in there like your life's
to shit and when you see or be really
friendly, hey, why are you
giving her a nice big hug?
And that'd be fucking flirting with all
the other fucking women that'll make her
fucking jealous. I mean, he's basically,
you're going to have to play a fucking
gay with a fucking cunt like this,
which is really a lot of work.
MMM.
And it sounds like you,
you like,
you sound like you're kind of the
male version of her, you know,
she kinda didn't let you fucking hit it.
So now you're kind of getting
wrapped up in this fucking Twat.
You don't even want,
your ego wants it.
You want to fucking bag or you
know what you should do, sir.
It's just fucking walk away.
That's what you do.
Walk away and go bag something else.
And when she actually fucking cubs at,
you'd be like, why didn't
you call me anymore? Just be
like, Eh, no vibe between us.
There really isn't.
You know,
you're beautiful,
but the conversations too awkward and
I find that you're just really self
centered. You're really into
yourself. And uh, I find it annoying,
you know,
if you tell him that you've probably
going to be closer to the fucking pussy
than you are going the other way.
Why don't you call me? Oh sorry,
I've been busy. You just act like
a fucking loser. Don't do that.
All right.
Okay.
You get this one by walking away
from this one. That's, that's,
that's my gut feeling. All right, sir.
You know what you do, you just walk
in class, you'd take your Dick out,
you put it right on a fucking desk.
Could just go and, you know, really,
can we just stop already? And then
when the teacher's like, excuse me,
fucking the checklists, Avaya Ne,
whatever the fuck her name is.
All right, sick. I used to play
for the, uh, for the Lakers.
Who's fucking over there? Christ.
I'm sorry guys. This podcast stunk.
Just take your dick out and shake
it in her face. Cool. Listen,
I want to show you something. You go
ahead. Right? Flopped in. Yeah, right.
How would you do that there?
Can I tap out on that? Um,
this has been the Monday morning podcast.
Everybody.
Thank you for listening. Uh, if you'd
like to donate to this podcast, a click,
go to the, um, Jesus Christ.
Go to bill [inaudible] dot com.
Click on the podcast page.
You'll see the Amazon link.
Click on amazon.com go to Amazon.
If you would like to buy something,
buy something. If you do, it
doesn't cost you any more money.
But they kicked me a little bit of money.
And I take fucking 10% of that and I
kick it to the wounded warriors project.
So he support me and the troops. They,
you'd go, that's a podcast for this week.
Go Fuck yourself next week.
I will feel better. Uh,
I hope I will be funnier.
Okay. Oh, next week,
where the fuck will I be
now? I'll still be here.
I will still be here and it'll be right
before my whole dirty south fucking tour
salt be hyping that next week. All
right. That's it. Oh, by the way,
I also did an episode of Voc
Greg Fitzsimmons podcast.
If you want to listen to that one, uh,
yeah, that's great. Listen to Greg's,
then listen to Rogan's.
You'll listen to me gradually get sick
and this is the fucking fall out of it.
All right. Go fuck yourselves.
We'll talk to you next week.