Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcasts from Monday,
August 5th, 2013. How are you,
how are you doing this morning?
All of that.
She has fantastic,
this is going to be another subdued
William Burr here on the Monday morning
podcast.
As you can tell,
I wasn't able to find a
fucking cord from my mixer. So,
um, the lovely Nia is going
to send me mine. Uh, so next,
this will be the last week
of this kind of stuff.
So I've had difficulty trying to find
basically everything here in New Orleans.
For those of you just listening, I haven't
listened for the past couple of weeks.
I'm here in New Orleans.
I'm doing the, uh,
what do you call it?
The final episode of Glee for this season.
It's like some three hour extravaganza.
So I have to be out here forever.
And you know,
like I mentioned,
I am going to be shirtless
in the cafeteria scene,
so I've been trying to try
to get healthy food out here,
which is practically impossible.
I haven't been able to find it.
If there's any New Orleans people,
I guess they don't say knowledge,
by the way.
I was told that the other
night that they don't say that.
That's just some Hollywood
shit. And then, uh,
I taught that person how to
properly say Boston, B, a w Boston,
not Boston.
So we both had a laugh and then we
ate some fried fucking oysters because
everything's fried down here.
You know, I go into Verizon,
I need a new cell phone.
You know,
they didn't have the entire thing.
They just had the part you plug
into your fucking computer.
So unless I was going to walk around with
my computer and then bring that plug,
plugged that in and then plug the
fucking cell phone into my computer,
that was the only way for me to
charge it when I was on the road.
So I'm sitting there going like, you
know, I'm becoming a top of shit here.
And I have my big shirtless scene,
you know,
I'm singing a eight, six, seven,
five, three Oh nine, Jenny.
Uh, but the jazz it up
a little bit, but uh,
anyway, so I find someplace
to get a juice. And uh,
even then the way they do the juice,
you know, usually you use the apple,
you use the fruit to give it a little
zing so you can drink the fucking green
shit.
But they do it the opposite down here.
It's apple juice and then they'll add
like half a leaf of Kale in there.
And I just kind of hop and yourself
up on sugar. So, um, I actually,
I do have a game plan dot people,
um,
after your wonderful suggestions
where you like, Bill,
why don't you watch that documentary
fat sick and nearly dead?
And I'm like, well, yeah, I've
already watched those, you know,
Food Inc and I watched
uh,
Drylok [inaudible] fucking uh,
Morgan Spurlock try like [inaudible] yeah,
it's a famous percussionist from India.
MMM.
I fucking, uh, I mean that's
how you can say his name built.
Just get to the point on right.
The fuck was my point.
Oh, Morgan Spurlock.
Is that his name? I watched that. What?
He Ate Mcdonald's for 30 fucking
days in a row. And uh, I mean,
you know what's great about that?
You knew what you knew his
body was going to be junk,
but secretly haven't you always
wanted to do that? Just say fuck it.
Just blow your body out.
You know,
just deep I would,
how much weight you actually could
gain if you really put your mind to it.
You know,
this is what I do.
I would start with a grand slam breakfast
and then I have to take a nap cause I'm
old. When you get older, by the way,
when you eat really bad,
you know,
rather than just running outside
like you do as a youngster,
it takes a toll on you.
He actually have to go lay down
and try to sleep yourself back
into some sort of balance.
I don't know what put a, yeah,
I'd probably start with that.
Okay.
Lunchtime or would I do steak and cheese
so you know what it is?
That kind of food itself fucks me up now.
I can't even enjoy it anymore.
That's what happens as you get older.
It's like you fucking guts.
I like some engine that your entire life
you went down like two quarts of oil on
and it just doesn't run as
well as it used to. You know,
back when you were younger,
you could do fucking neutral drops and
fucking be driving 40 miles an hour and
just yanked the emergency brake.
It cut the wheel and almost tip over
your fucking Volkswagen Fox like my buddy
did back in the day. You can't do that
anymore as you get older, you know,
so if you are older
and every time you eat,
you then have to immediately fall
asleep. Uh, you're down a few courts.
It's time for a new, ain't want to put
a synthetic in there. So anyway, so,
um, I've been a, you know,
days, I'm not working.
I've been kind of bored.
I know a lot of you guys already
know what I'm working on here in la.
Do you guys always go, Bill, why do you
try to keep it such a big fucking secret?
What you're doing?
You can just go to your imdv page and
figure out what you're doing. Well,
do you ever think that that may be that
that's the fucking method to my madness.
See, if I just told you what I'm doing
down here in New Orleans, you'd be Oh,
humble brag or you'd give me
shit. You know, easy their care.
Don't forget where you came from,
Ra.
MMM.
So what I do is I deliberately
act vague and then people send me,
then they just got an IMD B and they
ended up knowing more about what the fuck
I'm doing. Then if I told you anyways,
and then people send me emails like bill,
in order to still be so vague, it's
so easy to find out what you're doing.
You're doing this, that blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. It's like, there you go.
You're dumb. Fuck. That's
exactly what I wanted.
I wanted you to have the
information. I tricked you. Okay.
You're coming at me like you
just solved the murder case.
Like you're fucking Colombo and you're
looking away with your crazy eye rubbing
your forehead and I'm standing
there flabbergasted here
in a heartbeat under the
floorboards. You got it ass
backwards. That's why I'm fig.
I want to give you
something to do at work.
Well, is she going to do sit there
and stare at your spreadsheets,
figuring out how much fucking grapes
costs in the next 20 minutes screaming by
myself. I've actually been
doing really well with my
weight here. Oh, so anyway, so,
uh, I finally give in and a, I'm like,
all right, I'm not working today.
I'm going to go, uh, I'm going to go, uh,
yeah, I'm going to watch this
fucking fat, sick and nearly dead.
And I gotta tell you, man, it was awesome.
I absolutely loved it. And, uh,
I felt bad for trash and fat
people on my podcast, my, my, uh,
Billy shade, Billy shame to get back
and get back into shape. You know,
where I just make fun of the Fed is,
um, I mean it was always done in jest,
but I don't know if there's one guy that
he runs it to that, uh, I don't know.
I felt bad for the dude, but anyway,
so he goes on this juice fast. So,
of course now I'm like obsessed with it,
you know,
just so I can get some of these
fried clams and all this stuff,
these po boy sandwiches.
Just try to get these out of my system
because I'm sick of having to take a nap
every time I eat out here.
Uh,
so I think I'm going to buy a mini juicer
and a bunch of Kale and that type of
shit. Nah, juice it up and then just
shove it down my fucking pie hole,
you know? And believe it or not,
it fills you up. It fills you up.
Do you get used to it?
Then you start craving that and uh,
and then the best part is you
don't have to go to the gym.
That's what it's really all about people.
That's the number one reason to eat.
Well, not so you live longer. It's
so you don't have to go to the gym,
you don't have to go to the gym and
you've, you've clothes still fit. Right.
You know,
I don't know. It was funny. Somebody you
ever, they actually sent me an email call.
Bill. Do you have any idea how
many times you say, you know,
during a podcast and it was, it's
just like, yes, of course I do.
You know,
how the fuck wouldn't I know that thick.
I don't listen back to these things as
I upload them to try to see if they're
funny or not. You know, I got admit
if I don't think they're funny,
I shut them off really quickly,
but they start going,
I like them.
But I do notice that I say
it that, that, that much.
But maybe can I have a catch phrase?
No,
that was actually not even a,
but when it wasn't even on you.
Now I'm in my own fucking head.
I don't want to do that anyways.
I'm still here at the hotel.
I'm going to buy a juicer and uh,
I just figured to two
out of three meals a day,
I'm going to drink that shit.
And uh,
yeah, when I come home I want
to have an even bigger head.
Yeah.
I guess that's the way you can,
I know you were,
if you come back off the road and
your head isn't three sizes bigger,
does your girlfriend thank you?
Cheated on her.
Like what are you in such good shape for?
But if you come back,
it's like a fed booze hound.
Oh, okay. He was faithful.
I don't know.
Anyway, so let's talk about, let's
talk about Major League baseball.
Something that I have not watched since
2010 when I just got sick of everybody,
you know, testing positive for stuff,
particularly people on my team.
And uh, it was just like, yeah. You
know, it just Kinda took all the, uh,
the glory out of those championships
and stuff that the red sox won.
It did not take any glory away from
beating the Yankees in 2004 though.
It did not at all because, you
know, they had just as many guys,
if not some of the worst offenders.
You know,
I think Andy Pettit woulda got more
shit if he wasn't into Jesus. Any,
any major league baseball players listing.
If you're listening to this and you're
doing, if you're on the juice there,
what I would do and you feel like
the hounds are nipping at your heels.
I would air quote find Jesus.
You know it.
Just start fucking write it on your glove.
When you wave to the,
when you wave to the camera.
Jesus's love.
Jesus saves Jesus is my homie.
Yeah, I know. Whatever. Whatever the
fuck else you say so that when you, uh,
okay,
you fuck up then you can just do like
that stuff like those televangelists we
just sit there crying. I
have sinned against you and
people seem to forgive you.
So let's get to Alex Rodrigues up
everybody buddy. Oh, by the way,
if you'd like to know who's in first
place in major league baseball,
I actually looked it up. I had no idea. I
mean, I knew the red sox were doing well.
Um,
the red sox,
the Tigers and the Oakland age earned
first place in the American league and
then see if I can remember this.
And National League, it's the A,
is it the Braves?
The Dodgers Dodgers are actually
doing well. Making me eat kraut.
Yeah. Cause I laughed at them last year
when they were like, we were like, hey,
we have $100 million worth the fucking
players who want doing shit for us.
And the Dodgers are like,
well shit, we'll tag them.
You don't like they're playing
a different game over there.
I don't know why you would do that but
thank you for doing it. And you know what,
thanks to you,
it works for all of us.
The Red Sox and Dodgers a buzzed
in first place. And my squad,
if I had been paid attention, the
Pittsburgh pirates. Yeah, but you
know how he found out the pirates were
in first place that was sitting in a bar.
Yeah. Eating fried corn flakes, whatever
the fuck they have down here. And um,
they had on a game and oh well the
pirates on pirates and cardinals,
I really loved the National
League for way back in the day.
I used to like it because so many
of the teams played on astro turf.
And when I was a little kid,
I thought that that was way
cooler than playing on grass.
Like now grass is way cooler than
astroturf. ASTROTURF looks cheesy.
But in the late seventies, early
eighties, astroturf was the shit.
You know, the whole infant field was
astroturf except around the bags. And uh,
it just seemed like a faster game.
They were playing, hit and run.
Guy Gets on first,
you bought them over to second stealing
bases and over in the American league it
was all about,
you know,
people just standing there trying to
smash the ball over the fence at back then
home run hitters would, would hit
like fucking two 78 if you hit to 80,
that was considered like a,
you know, you were a solid guy.
MMM.
I don't know,
maybe you are now,
but like they just didn't put
up the numbers the way they,
they did during the roid error action,
obviously I should say.
So anyways, I'm sitting there and
I'm in and I'm like, oh, pirates,
pirates and cardinals. This is
like the old days, you know,
and uh,
I'm looking in the crowd and it seems
like everybody's wearing a pirate ship.
And I'm just like, and the place looks
like it's sold out. And I'm like,
wait a minute, the pirates are
selling out a game and I'm like,
this must be a cardinals home game.
And I look at their jerseys.
What was weird was there, they're
away. Jersey said cardinals.
So then that made me feel like it was a
home game cause I thought unless I saw
it the wrong way,
right.
I misremembered it as politicians say,
but I was under the impression that uh,
uh,
way baseball teams,
when you're home you have the navy,
a team like the red sox and you go
on the way it says Boston, you know,
you ride home, it says the Indians,
you go on the road, it says Cleveland.
So I guess you know,
people who don't know shit about
baseball know what city you're from.
I have no idea. Uh, but anyways,
it turned out that it was a pirate told
game and it looked like it was sold out.
So, uh, oh, that makes me
excited. But haven't they,
they've been doing that the
last couple of years. You don't,
my fandom of the pirates is from fucking,
you know,
just watch a baseball
in the late seventies.
And that we are family team was
like one of my favorites at, uh,
I rooted against the Orioles because
the Orioles kicked the red sox ass in
[inaudible] 79 with their
unbelievable pitching staff.
MMM.
I would always root for the national
league teams I guess because it was
actually, it was really exciting to
see them play because they didn't have,
uh,
there was no MLB package is like if you
lived in Boston, you got was the red sox
game and then they would have
the, uh, the game of the week.
And uh,
if you miss that, then you watch
Mel Allen's this weekend baseball,
which was the shit you said.
Come on Saturday. Yeah, the
nudes and it was bent. Dun,
Dun,
Dun Bat,
Bat, Bat, bat.
If the gun, then he came,
you'd come on wherever the fuck
he would say. That was the,
that was supposed to be the exciting
theme song that started the show.
And then they ended the show
was something a little, uh,
not uptempo to just let you know it was
a beautiful game and they would just
show it in slow motion and the sun,
Duh,
Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh
Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh Duh.
[inaudible]
de de, De, De, De, De, De, De,
De, De, De, De, de, De, de.
Fucking people just do what all this
amazing shit and like slow motion.
And it was amazing about that song is,
that's probably a 40 person orchestra.
All right? There was no auto
tune. There was no drum machine.
There was no fucking one guy on a giant
keyboard that can make all those songs.
It was like 40 people getting
paid, um, all working together,
pointing it. Yeah. Other afterwards and
going out and having a couple of Schlitz.
Okay.
MMM.
So anyways, um, fuck am
I talking about here?
Yeah. So I started watching
baseball again. I haven't
started watching baseball.
Who's kidding who? But, um,
I was psyched to see that the pirates
server now first place and I'm actually
happy for the Dodgers.
Believe it or not,
I have a tough time with
the Dodgers because I was a
huge fan of them when I was
a kid because of the 77 and 78
world series when they played the,
uh,
the New York Yankees because I hated the
Yankees and we can never beat him back
then. Um, so I would root
for the, for the Dodgers.
And I remember feeling bad
for Tommy John Because, uh,
he lost in [inaudible] 77 or 78
with the Dodgers and then an 81,
he went to the Yankees,
which was unforgivable to me.
And then the Yankees played the Dodgers
again in the world series and then the
Dodgers finally won. The guy went,
oh, for fucking three poor bastard.
And he had an operation named after him.
MMM.
Him had Lou Gehrig. No one
was an operation. Yellen
was a disease. They Bell,
why don't you shut the fuck
up? All right, I will let,
let me read you a little bit of
advertising here. And then we'll get back.
When I come back.
I'm going to tease you a little here,
people you gotta to talk about
that whole a rod situation.
Uh,
here we go. All right. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody been talking about this for the
last couple of weeks and I got to tell
you a lot time ago,
I used to do a bit about this in my
act about why do they act like those
disposable razors or some sort of gold
bullion? Why are they locked behind that?
The, the, the, that plastic glass.
Why do they act like it's,
it's this amazing thing.
It's a little hunk of crap that
shouldn't cost more than a buck,
right? Say we go, I did that, right?
But like seven, eight years ago, see what
I did was, I just did a joke about it.
These geniuses actually
did something about it.
Started a company here and they're
probably making a zillion dollars.
And you know what I say? I say
good for them. I say good for them.
Dollar Shave club, everybody. Um,
it's a cool brand and they send you
these quality razors right to your door
every month. You don't have to think
about it. You don't have to wait in line.
Get someone to unlock them from a cage
and pay way too much money for a bunch of
features that don't even fit your old
handle. Shaving has become such a mess.
But now with dollar shave
club, all right, saves me time.
It saves me money and the
raises are fantastic and I can,
I can guarantee you that they've been
sending those things right to my house.
I don't have to deal with it anymore.
I have an awful cvs right
down the street with,
it's always like a 20 minute line
cause they only have opened, you know,
one register. Um, give
it a shot. You know,
I want you to try it.
Go to dollar shave club,
forward slash bar support this show.
Go to dollar shave club.com forward
slash bar or click the dollar shave club
banner on the podcast page at [inaudible]
dot com that's dollar shave club.com.
Forward slash. Bar. You don't have to
think about it anymore. What's above?
They send you a bunch of new blades.
Do you have a new blade
every damn week?
Okay.
The ladies like giving you
more kiss on the cheek there.
He voice everybody.
Your screening calls,
closing deals and making money all while
lounging poolside in the summer sun.
Thanks to who he voice.
The voice is a better way to connect
with the people that drive your business.
He voice will forward
business calls to your home,
mobile or any number you choose.
Wherever you are.
He voiceful find you don't have
time to take a call. No worries.
It's routed to your voicemail and you
can read it at your convenience as a text
message. Message, sorry. He voice not only
gives you an edge over your competitors,
it takes away the edge. The big companies,
half of you right now with the voice,
you can create the appearance of a
whole office building of departments.
When customers call you a
sales department, customer
support, tech support,
you name it. It sounds like you got
it and it works with daddy phone.
Even yourself. Hey, it's summer.
Don't be stuck at the office all day.
Get Jackass free yourself for a free 30
day trial of the voice so you can see
what I'm talking about.
All the go to [inaudible] dot com and
enter the Promo code bill for your 30 day
free trial. That's [inaudible]
dot com promo code bill,
or go to the podcast page on [inaudible]
dot com and click on the voice banner.
All right. That was painless. I only had
one screw up there. You liked that people?
I think I finally got my game
together with reading these, uh,
these advertisements. You know,
you don't, I am. I'm like a,
a number one draft pick bust when it
comes to that shit. I'm not quite a bus,
but no, about five, six years in
the original team I was on, uh,
drop me down to number three on the
depth chat and now I got traded and I'm
pulling back up over and
fucking in Minnesota.
But the first two went down and now
getting in. All right, is this, this?
Now skip Bayless.
He's yelling about me saying that he
doesn't think that I can actually read
these fucking things without screwing it
up. While Steven A. Smith Goes, blasphemy.
Blasphemy. Uh, alright.
Hey Rod, everybody.
It's my thing about this son of a bitch.
This guy gets a lifetime ban and
that somehow voids his contract.
The Yankees are somehow able to get out
of that contract. I swear to fucking God.
You might as well just have the
commissioner of baseball minus, well,
just be Steinbrenner's son.
Okay.
How much shit can the Yankees fucking
get away with? Do you remember?
The red sox wanted to get a rug.
We had the deal in place.
It baseball came in and was like, no,
we had the deal was done at baseball,
came in and said, no,
that's bad for baseball.
It's bad for baseball to have
yet another big time free agent.
Go to the red sox because that's what
we were becoming the Yankees. Right.
And then
a rod goes to the Yankees,
some health that wasn't bad for
baseball to have two of the three best
shortstops in the league at
the time on the same team.
One of them never to play shortstop again,
to have to learn a new position
at third base. If you remember,
this is pre steroids and all that.
So some of these names don't hold
the weight they did back in the day,
but they're infield was
[inaudible] Jeter and a rod.
And then there was talks that
maybe they were going to sign,
no mar to play second place, second
base. I remember Jambi be like, dude,
he was like, dude, that would be
awesome. I just remember thinking like,
how would that be awesome? What, where's
the fucking fun in that? So what, anyways,
we try to get a Rod.
It's bad for baseball.
The Yankees do it and they already had
like fucking every goddamn free agent in
the league at every position other than
they are for fucking five core guys from
their own, uh, uh, a farm team.
And somehow that was okay.
All right.
And that was just a,
an ongoing story in baseball.
It was the red sox just never just,
we couldn't win.
No matter what we did,
it blew up in our face.
And even when we made
moves and got a big guy,
it was considered bad for baseball.
You go back to the 70s we had rollie
fingers signed him bad for baseball,
you know, Yank that out.
Reggie Jackson, can you,
can we can the fucking Yankee
sign him apps a fucking Luke Lee.
I don't know what, I don't
know what, what, what our
pens look. But for some reason
they were bad for baseball.
So anyways,
for once after 86 years of flailing,
you know the deal,
somehow it worked in our favor.
So I have thoroughly enjoyed,
okay.
Watching a rod flame out and in and
watching the Yankees trying to get out of
that contract and just not being able
to get this $200 million albatross off
from around their neck.
I thoroughly fucking enjoyed it.
They try to humiliate them.
They've tea,
they benched him during crucial moments
and like the playoffs and a rod doesn't
give a fuck. He just sits there like
a fucking robot going, well you know,
whatever's good for with tape, I
don't go to shit. You know, just,
just keep paying me. I don't give a
fuck. And I completely enjoyed it. Ed,
they still have another five years
of this nightmare. Five
years, like $114 million.
They got to give this,
this matinee idol look in bust.
And I have completely
enjoyed every second of it.
And um, in my world is like,
I got another five years.
So just sorta, you know, I like,
I watch a ton of baseball anymore,
which is kind of sad. Uh, I gotta get
back into it. Everybody, but I can't,
I can't get back into it at
the, the, the upper levels.
I just can't, I can't watch
these fucking, you know,
juggernaut teams. I, I gotta, I gotta I
gotta be watching Kansas City, you know,
the Padres, the pirates, even though
the pirates in the first place,
but I don't think they have
any major leaks. Science.
I'm in major free agent signing.
But anyways,
so I thought I had another five
years of this show to watch
and now all of a sudden I'm worried
that it's going to get canceled.
I'll tell you right now, if,
because of this suspension,
the Yankees are somehow able to get out
of this contract and saved themselves
$114 million, which you sit down,
but it's just a drop in the bucket.
The way they ass rape their fans.
Every home game,
they way they take every one of those
poor Yankee fans with their pin stripe
shirts and they're classic Yankee hats
and they just bend them over the hot dog
stand and just stick that pin stripe
Dick Right up their ass. No loop.
You know,
I really feel bad for the total
fucking ass raping that every,
every Yankee fan takes when
you go to the ballpark. I mean,
if I was a Yankee Fan, I would
not go to that new fucking, uh,
beautiful baseball stadium
slash growing up gaudy house.
It's such a weird stadium. If you haven't
been to it, you should definitely go.
Uh,
but I,
I suggest eating a Thanksgiving dinner
before you go there or you know,
one of your kids will not
be going to college. Um,
but you go to that stadium is
such a weird stadium where like,
there's literally some breathtaking
views as you walk around that park
and every time you like, oh my God,
this is amazing. They really did it
right. Then they'll just have, you know,
some jackass like
just some,
some fucking look how much money we got.
Just you don't know it is it,
it's Kinda like this blend of,
um,
I dunno. Like what, what's a great
ballpark that they built that that's new,
but it's all, I guess maybe the
Jake when it first came out,
it's kind of the perfect,
it's a blend of, of uh,
the beautiful new ones.
They conjure up the old shit and like
Dallas Cowboys stadium where if you never
been to that,
you got to go to that one just once.
Just to see that absolutely fucking that
I saw of a television that they have
hanging up there. It's the dumbest
thing I've ever seen in my life.
I swear to God when I go to that stadium,
I always think if Bobby Kelly
designed a football stadium,
this is exactly what it looked like.
Yeah. Look, I think the TV is,
I don't have to go anyway, dude.
I just sit here and watch it.
MMM.
Dallas Cowboy stadium is an
absolute fucking abomination.
And uh,
and it's just because of that TV.
Everything else is actually,
it's beautiful.
If you could just get that fucking TV,
that TV,
it's like a drunk at a holiday. Family
gatherings, you know what I mean?
No matter how good the food is,
not how great it is to see everybody,
all conversation, everything is
drowned out by the fucking, the,
that guy over there, you know, your
uncle who keeps dabbling in the oxy,
he's telling you that he's
clean, but he is it, you know,
that's what that fucking TV's like.
So anyways,
the hell am I saying here
as a fan of sports and my
hatred of the New York Yankees,
I'm really hoping
that the Yankees feel like,
oh, maybe we can get out of it.
Maybe we can get out of it.
And then they still can't.
Knowing full well that in the long run
it's not going to mean shit to them.
$100 million doesn't mean shit to them.
It's just annoying and that's basically
all I can really hope for at this point.
So, um, maybe I'll write some letters,
I'll write some letters to
the commissioner of baseball,
tell them that I'm dying or something
and that my bucket like bucket list or
something. So something has to do with
a rod. I just really want that, that
I just want to be able to talk to him
sometime while he's on the field. That's,
that's my make a wish thing. I want to
look into those Zombie robotic guys.
Uh,
I like how he's actually pissed now says
that he's being singled out. It's like,
well you kind of made yourself a target
with the steroids for the second time.
You fucking jerk off.
He really
is like a,
he has an inability to,
to step outside of self and see how
he's coming off and absolute jackass.
And I can't think of a
better person to beat,
to be wearing the pin stripes
and represent what that
organization is all about.
They're clean shaven,
steroid abusers,
unlike the Red Sox who,
uh,
I don't know what we look like.
We,
we look like we'll go into an
Allman brothers concert. Uh,
I'm just trying to get Yankee
fans all day. Use Boyd too.
All right, let's, let's plow
ahead here. Have you buddy? Um,
they held it out. You've got to
talk about something. Yeah, I was,
I going to bring up the, Oh, let's move
on to this. Let's just keep the, uh,
the sport thing going here. Oh, no,
no, no. I remember what it is I owe.
I owe an apology.
This wasn't my fault,
but I have to apologize on behalf of
the theater that El Paso show got a
rescheduled,
as I mentioned,
because of the active work I
got down here in New Orleans,
I was only able to do the first two
dates of the red state tour. Um,
none of the shows are canceled.
They've all been rescheduled.
I know it's a pain in the ass. I know
people make plans. I apologize. Um,
I announced it here on,
on
MMM.
On the podcast. I, di I, you know,
I dunno what the fuck else I could have
done to let people know, go to hell.
I guess the theater out there in El Paso,
I don't know what happened,
but some people didn't get the word that
the show was canceled and I guess, uh,
there was some people that
showed up. So, uh, I apologize.
I hope you're listening to this.
I will try to tweet about it
and maybe you'll be able to get,
I don't know if you follow
me on Twitter or not,
but to let you know the,
uh,
the new date of the El Paso
date is September 13th.
All right. I'm sorry. September
12th. September 12th is the new date.
And uh,
I apologize to anybody who showed up.
I can't believe what a pain in the
ass that is. I hope nobody drove.
Yeah,
Jesus, someone's going to be like,
dude, I drove four fucking hours,
or I had a plane ticket or something
like that. So I feel horrible about it.
So because of that, I'm just going to
announce my dates right here. Right now.
I'm just going to read through a bunch
of these as quickly as I can. So,
uh, there's no more confusion. All right?
And then somehow there's still will be
confusion and then somehow someone's
going to get mad at me and I'll get
a fucking angry email or whatever.
I apologize for the clicking here people
see if I can bring this up with this
horrific internet here. Come on. You
could do it. You can do it. All right,
here we go. These are the
shows I have coming up. Uh,
and I'm going to read the ones that
don't even have ticket links. All right.
All right. This is the deal.
August 23rd I'm at the MGM grand
and a Mesh and then
top pocket Connecticut.
August 24th University of Cincinnati.
August 27th cobb's comedy
club with Brian Regan.
All proceeds are going to charity.
We do with a co headliner.
That one's actually already sold up.
All right.
Red State tour of rescheduled
dates for those of you in Colorado.
September 4th September 6th boulder,
Colorado pikes peak. All right.
Tickets are all on sale for these.
Uh, September 7th, I mean Coachella,
California at the spotlight
29 casino once again,
rescheduled a red state
tours September 12th El Paso,
Texas.
And because of that rescheduled,
I'm also now doing a San Antonio,
Texas first time.
I've never been there at
the Lilla rail theater.
September 13th and I know
what you think it bill,
you're doing a show on
September 14th. No, I am not,
but I'm not leaving Texas.
And what does Saturday in September
in Texas mean to anybody in Texas?
Huh? College football motherfucker.
I'm going to Texas a and M,
Alabama and I am rooting for the Yankees
and I will be drunk and I will still be
screaming Alabama.
The dream ends tonight.
So look for me out in the parking lot
with my sunburn. Giant head, eh, uh,
I'll see you when the stadium.
Um,
all right. Continuing on September
19th. I'm in West Virginia,
West Virginia University,
Morgan Town, West Virginia. Uh,
then I got Pittsburgh on September 20th.
All these,
all these shows are on sale people
up in Canada, Toronto, Ontario.
September 21st the Queen
Elizabeth Theater. September 28th,
not one, but two shows at the famous
Chicago theater. First one is sold out,
I believe.
A second show.
10 30 has been added a.
Now here's some that aren't on sale
but are coming up October 3rd, fourth,
fifth,
seventh and eighth.
No, no, I'm sorry. Strike that.
October 3rd, fourth and fifth.
I'll be in San Jose, Seattle,
Washington in Phoenix,
Arizona.
Those tickets are not on sale yet,
but I'm just letting you know where I'm
going to be and I'll announce them as
soon as they're available on Twitter.
So follow me on Twitter if you're not
on Twitter or Facebook or whatever. Uh,
November 7th, this is not on
sale. And over November 8th,
this is in ninth, seventh,
eighth and ninth. Sorry,
these are not on sale yet either.
Uh, I'll be in Washington DC,
New York City in Upper Darby,
Pennsylvania.
There'll be constitution hall, the Beacon
Theater and tower theater. All right.
November 15th rescheduled Red State tour,
deadwood,
South Dakota.
November 16th,
rescheduled red state tour,
Brady Theater in Tulsa,
Oklahoma and another red state. The
Orpheum theater, Wichita, Kansas.
November 17th. All right, and that
will conclude the red state tour.
I apologize for having to reschedule,
but uh,
I'm still coming. I could have been
a cunt and just canceled, you know,
sat out here and fucking New
Orleans with my shirt off,
getting ready for my big number.
Um,
what else? Southern Connecticut State
University on the 23rd. All right.
Now here's the big European tour.
People from Europe were asking me about
this shit and I apologize for this being
really long,
but I have to get this information out
here cause I do not want people showing
up when I'm not going to be somewhere.
All right,
December 5th I'm an Amsterdam.
Tickets are on sale.
December 7th I'm in London.
Show sold out.
They added another show.
MMM.
December 9th I'm in Dublin
at the vicar theater.
December 10th I'm at the savvy
theater in Helsinki, Finland.
December 11th I'm at the uh,
Cope Copenhagen. I'm in Bremen
theater in Copenhagen, Denmark.
Okay.
December 12th them in Oslo,
Norway.
December 13th I'm in Stockholm,
Sweden.
And here's two shows that
people don't know about.
December 5th eighth I'm going to be at,
at Harper Silverberg Hall in Reykjavik,
Iceland. Hope I'm saying that right. Never
been to Iceland. I'm really excited. Ed.
The biggest teaser of a mall.
You know,
I don't work new years cause I
go to the rose bowl every year.
When I finally decided this year,
well, I live in Los Angeles.
Why don't I do a big show in Los Angeles?
And why don't I put my buddies,
the Rosebowl legends,
uh,
fucking Joe bought nick and Jason Law had,
we're all do a show the
night before New Year's Eve.
If you don't have New Year's Eve
plans and you live in Los Angeles,
we're going to be at the Wiltern
theater right down there. Ron.
Now we'll chef Wilshire and western.
So tickets are not on sale for
that one yet. So there you go. Now,
you know as much as I do about my schedule
and once against sincerest apologies
to anybody,
any of the poor bastards that
showed up for my shelf and El Paso.
That was not to be, I don't
know how that happened. Uh,
so there you go. All right, back to the
effect of the, uh, the podcast here.
Everybody. So as mentioned,
I'm down here in New Orleans.
I've been making fun of the food, but, uh,
I've been having the best time
in New Orleans as they say,
if you can't have a good time down here,
there's something wrong with you. And, uh,
I went out the other night,
I guess they shoot a lot of movies
down here because it's really cheap.
He gave him a great deal or whatever.
And I had a buddy of mine who was
shooting something else and he had just
wrapped and he called me out.
We went off,
met up at this hotel
and uh,
just so you know what I, I'll
actually, I usually don't name a name,
but this will hype is movie.
It was Craig Robinson who still,
when they just wrapped on a hot
tub time machine part too. And uh,
Craig, just one, just one of
those guys who's just, I dunno,
unbelievably charismatic. Like I
watched, I was watching that guy,
that guy was having more goddamn fun in
one night that I think I've ever had in
my life. You know, just ease.
There was a live band playing. He
went up, he played piano, you know,
singing and making everybody laugh.
And then he fucking called
me up to go do some standup.
I of course was defensive, turned the
crowd off and then I got offstage.
But later on that night
when the band had left, uh,
he went back up,
started playing piano and I went up
there and played some drums full of,
I swear to go for like 45
minutes or like an hour and a,
it's probably the most fun I think
I've had in a long, long time.
And I was stone sober, didn't
have a drop alcohol, you know,
whenever I have an acting Gig,
I tried to lay off the booze and Mike
fucking giant head doesn't seem even
bigger. No one wants to see that on the
screen. So, um, I've been doing that,
walking around, checking out the
city, avoiding, what do you call it?
At Bourbon Street, you know, I that just,
I just don't like the date rapey
sort of vibe on that street. So, uh,
there is a laundromat that is on that,
so it's kind of funny.
I've been doing my laundry down that way.
It just walking on that street
like in broad day light after,
you know, show your tits or whatever
the fuck happened the night before.
It's just a,
if you ever walk by a
strip club during the day,
it's just really just, it's
just not a good look. It's just,
I dunno what about it is at nighttime
when you see those purple neon light bulbs
and you're half in the bag or something,
it actually looks like
something appealing,
but when you just see it in broad
daylight, it's fucking brutal.
So anyways,
uh,
I've actually been getting into like,
you know,
they've been talking about Lsu
football down here in the saints,
like every single day they're getting
so fucking amped up for football. Um,
I'm actually caught up in this
excitement down here and uh,
I saw that the saints have a preseason
game Friday night and if you think I'm
not going well,
if I have
to work that night, obviously I'm
not going, but if I don't have to,
there's no fuck away.
I'm not going because the super
dome now that they redid it,
it was already iconic. It's your OT is
self to come down here and go to a game.
It's, it's uh, it's beautiful. Which
brings me to their basketball team.
I don't know if you guys know this,
but the New Orleans Hornets or
no more than now called the,
uh,
New Orleans Pelicans.
Okay.
Just going to pause and let you take
that in for a second. It's called,
they're called the Pelicans,
which is arguably the worst fucking
name of any God damn sports team.
I, I'm going to motion, I'm
going to make a suggestion here.
Any new team at this point,
do not name your team after an animal
because evidently there's no good ones
left.
There's 122 fucking teams and
I think just all the good,
ferocious ones are taken unless you
just want to go obscure and just start
picking like names of like
poisonous snakes and fucked
up animals from different
countries, which I dunno, why would
you, why would you do that? You know,
the New Orleans tie pants, you know,
you wouldn't do that shift the Pelicans.
So I looked up their logo and I'm like,
if they made like a basketball net out
of that bird's fucking double chin,
uh,
I dunno what I was going to do,
but I looked it up.
And you know what they did conveniently
as they got rid of its double chin?
Like it had like a facelift.
So what I think they should do now,
if they're going to go like that,
if they're gonna sell horribly
misrepresent that Bert not have it's giant
fucking double Chin and somehow
have this streamline chin, you know,
uh, I, I think they should just, they
should just put those fucking, you know,
those lips, those plastic surgery
lips that you GAF fuck. I am,
I might even be remotely fucking
funny on this Goddamn podcasts.
Such a fucking handicap.
I can't hear myself right now.
I don't have my microphone. It's
like my Kryptonite. Whatever.
Make the fucking thing looked like
a Kardashian. Kardashians, mom.
I'm actually, you know
what? It's such a fucking,
you know what I don't like about it?
Date, they tried to make it look cool.
It's like if you're going to be
the Pelicans, just embrace it.
And what you have to have is do,
do the cartoony version of the Pelican
right where it's got a cigar in his mouth
and it's giving you the thumbs up
with it's fucking wing. You know,
he's got a fucking beer in one hand
or something. That's the guards.
It's just a Hawaiian shirt.
If you're going to be the Pelicans,
she got to do that. Stop trying to make
that bird look cool. It's not cool.
Is this iron been fucking rock
and like death the entire time?
It's not fucking cool.
There's two logos that really fucked up
the New Orleans Pelicans and then, uh,
the fucking Miami Dolphins
who never should have changed.
They shouldn't have changed their logo.
It had been,
it was always a kind of a Douchey logo,
but had been around long enough and
they'd done so many legendary things that
you kind of like, you respected
it. I mean, when I saw that logo,
I thought about Don Shula. I thought
about Larry's Onca, Jim kick,
Bob Greasy, that whole era, Gary, oh,
your premium or the fuck,
his name is and I'm
Gary at Premiere and that's why
people used to go bald. You know,
like fucking Lou grant was a dump of
these chemicals on your head and having
that whisper of grass on top of your head
or I thought about Dan Marino.
Okay.
Mock duper Mark Clayton, all of that
shit. That's what I thought about.
And uh, for some fucking reason
they decided to change it,
which I think is a desperate
move at this point.
They're trying to make more money because
now everybody has to go out and buy
the new logo is never better.
Look at the New England patriots.
I think we have to like the ugliest
fucking uniforms in the league,
that awful silver with that,
you know, whatever they call it.
The Flying Elvis on
the side. I hate it. I,
I've never bought.
Okay.
Wow. I just realized that I've never
bought anything with that logo on it.
Never bought a jersey or anything.
I've hated it from way back when
drew Bledsoe first came and it was,
it was more sky blue as opposed to
the darker blue with that silver.
I always just thought it was
horrifically fucking ugly. Um,
but the dolphins new logo, you know
what the logo basically looks like.
Do you know like when a
corporation accidentally
spills like nuclear waste into
the water supply.
So then they changed their name and
they try to come up with like a,
like a logo that makes it seem like
they give a shit about the environment.
Like BP did,
you know BP went from this
logo that looked like they drilled
oil out of the fucking ground,
like what they did and then sprayed
it on baby birds and fucking sweatshop
children. Now they got that
one. It's all green and yellow.
Like you don't know if they plant corn
or it just looks like grass and sunshine.
That's what I feel like
the new dolphins have done.
Is that what you feel like bill,
Bill,
considering you're not
that funny this week,
why don't you just read
some of the letters,
said a continuing to just
flail as you're riffing. Um,
all right, I'll get onto it.
All right. Here's the first one.
Facial scare bill, a few notes. Uh,
you know what?
I'm just fucking up this week.
I got to read these
last two advertisements.
I can't read them to link to the podcast
because for some reason they think he
think that you guys just shut these things
off. Uh, all right, Hulu plus everybody.
I'm sure you've tried hulu.com
if you haven't you. But
uh, but if you've already tried hulu.com
I want to tell you about Hulu Plus Hulu
plus lets you watch thousands
of hit shows anytime,
anywhere streaming on your TV or on
the go with your smartphone or tablet.
Why stand in line or ride a train
and just stare at your feet.
You could be watching your favorite
shows on Hulu plus who the pluses,
a great way to binge
watch your favorite shows.
I'm going to use Hulu plus to catch up
on all the old family guy episodes I
missed when I was on the road.
I guess I'm always supposed to put it in
the show that I really want to watch a
person of interest. I
think I'll do that. Um,
didn't see my episode of new girl that's
on Hulu plus two and if I ever decide
to watch lost,
which I won't,
Hulu plus is the place for all that
Hulu plus. It's only seven 99 a month.
That's seven 99 for all the
shows and movies you can watch.
Catch up on current shows, binge on your
old favorite or catch a great movie.
You can do it all on Hulu
plus everybody right now.
You can try Hulu plus for a couple of
weeks frame on me when you go to the
podcast page, [inaudible]
dot com and click on the Hulu
plus banner or go to Hulu
plus.com/bill please make sure you
use the Hulu plus.com/bills you get an
extended free trial and so that you know,
so that they know we sent you.
It helps us to keep the lights
on and gives you a better deal.
One more time for the extended free trial.
Hulu plus.com/bill.
All right,
I'm reading very well this week everybody.
I'm going to pat myself on the back,
uh, and put a little pressure here.
I Bet I can go through this whole one
without screwing up once. All right,
here we go. Legal Zoom. Most
Americans don't have a will,
but why?
You don't want government rules dictating
what happens to your property and
minor children.
So why procrastinate?
Most people say it's too expensive
or too time consuming. My answer
it is legal zoom.com too expensive.
You're going to love legal zooms,
reasonable prices, too. Time consuming.
Most people finish the online process
and just 20 minutes and we're not talking
some fill in the blank form.
Your will is state specific and
personalized based on your information.
Best of all,
legal zoom has 12 years of experience
helping people with important legal
matters. It's national.
Make a weld month everybody,
even though we're in August,
so don't wait any longer.
Go to legalzoom.com today and
get 15% off your last will.
Ah dammit. I was going to do it. Get 15%
off your, yeah, it is off your last will.
A last will and testament is that
short for that? I don't know,
but this offer ends soon or get a living
trust and you receive a pour over will
absolutely free to get your
spouse your special discount.
Be sure to enter [inaudible] in the
referral box at checkout for wills,
powers of attorney trust and more.
Go to legalzoom.com legalzoom can provide
self help services at your specific
direction or connect you with an attorney,
but they're not a law firm.
There you go.
Dammit.
I went 14 and two in the regular season
and I just blew the first playoff game.
That's what I just did there.
I pulled the Peyton manning.
Um,
okay.
All right.
Where the hell am I here?
Facial skin.
Where the fuck is it?
All right,
Bill,
this past weekend I went to Vegas to
visit my brother and his buddy who
currently reside there.
They actually caught your most recent
show in Vegas and had a phenomenal time.
Oh, that's awesome. Thank you.
Said I left last Thursday from Tampa
and I soon I touched down in Vegas.
I just received an out of nowhere
texts from the girl that got away.
I was shook this broad, used to live in
Tampa about two and a half years ago,
but she moved out to La to
pursue her careers and actress.
The two of us attended the University
of Tampa a few years ago and had an on
again off again relationship.
Long story short,
I was in a relationship with another girl.
We went on break and I met this
girl and was hooked. So anyways,
her tech said, hey, where
are you going to Vegas with?
Because I'm going to be
there this weekend to uh,
my guess is that she had seen
my social media. She had been,
my guess is that she had seen on my social
media that I was going to be in Vegas.
What I read the text.
I was very surprised and pretty pumped
because we hadn't talked in a long time
and like I said,
she was the one that got away.
She's absolutely gorgeous and she also
happens to be a really good person as
well. Jesus Christ. People
what could go wrong here?
We hooked up in Vegas and it was
amazing to see her. We all went out,
did our thing and had one of the
best weekends I've had in my life.
I give you more details, but you know
what happens in Vegas stays in Vegas.
All right.
You gave her the old Meat Hammer.
Wait, it be subtle. Anyways,
the reason why I'm writing to you
though is because on the plane,
right back to Tampa,
I was thinking about mine and this girl's
relationship and all of our history
and a pretty comical slash genius
story came to mind about her.
I know this is getting long,
but I hope it's not as long and boring
as that guide running to explain the
fucking origins of Jimmy's a couple of
weeks ago. Jesus Christ. Uh, but anyways,
like I said,
when I first met her,
I was immediately attracted to her natural
beauty, beauty, and her personality.
She's one of these ladies who didn't have
to wear makeup or do anything special
to look sexy. However, one of
the first weekends we spend vent
together,
I wake up with her in bed.
One morning I go to give
her a kiss and I am,
I am immediately troubled the way the
morning sun was shining into the window on
her face, expose something. I wasn't
ready for that. Early in the morning,
this broad has dark hair and for the first
time I noticed she had some dark hair
above her lip.
I was really surprised.
I didn't catch it before, but it
wasn't a thick mustache or anything.
It was just like the peach fuzz. A 12
year old boy has before he starts shaving.
Regardless,
I was taking,
I was taken back and from that morning
and from that point on that morning,
it was all I could notice.
Jesus,
isn't it crazy how visual guys are?
That's it.
Take the most beautiful woman
in the world. You put it,
give a mustache. We can't.
That's all we can say. It's like I'm
kissing fucking Burt Reynolds here.
All right, so when I went home,
I had to devise a master plan,
operation mustache removal.
I liked this girl way too much and
she was still very hot with the,
even with the stash,
but I needed a way to get rid of it
because I wanted to help her out.
Also helping myself. All right. Now
this is why I picked this one here.
Listen to this guy.
He's got a gorgeous fucking woman.
Everything about her is perfect except
she has a fucking mustache. Now.
How the hell do you bring it up
to somebody that you care about,
that they have a mustache and
his fucking turning you off.
There's no way to do that without
sabotaging the relationship or are really
hurting the other person.
The only way to do that is if you just
completely don't give a shit about the
other person. It just say, hey, you
know, if there's any way you could, uh,
you know,
I don't even know how to fucking say,
well,
this is what he did and this
was changes. He said, uh,
since we just started seeing each other,
I didn't want to come out and say, babe,
Babe, you shaved today. Seemed
a little self conscious.
Edit is so I didn't want to tell her
and embarrassed or anything like that.
I needed a way to remove this
stash without being involved.
Hence,
I did what needed to be done.
Listen to this fucking
brilliant conspiracy.
I call it my trustworthy buddy who was
playing hockey in Canada at the time and
told him I needed him
to do me a solid dude.
I filled him in on the situation and he
was willing to help me out since he had
a weird random Canadian
number at the time.
I gave him my chick's number and
told him to text her and simply say,
you have a mustache.
I ordered him to say nothing else and
not to respond under any circumstances.
He texted me back about 20 minutes
later and said, mission complete,
so this fucking lady,
just to get you caught up in case
you confused here with my reading,
she gets a random texts from a Canadian
number out of nowhere that just says,
you have a mustache.
I can't imagine your fucking
stomach must've dropped.
It's when he goes. Anyways,
he goes.
Later that night I met her at the bar
and she was looking extraordinarily sexy.
She seemed that she seemed to
have a little pep in her step.
I walked up to give her a kiss and I
looked above her lip and the peach fuzz
mustache was gone clean and
soft as a baby's bottom.
I was very happy how it played out.
I helped myself up because that would
have bothered me and I helped her become
even sexier, best part being. She had no
idea that I orchestrated that mission.
I didn't have to talk about it,
bring it to her attention and hurt
her feelings or anything like that.
I just had a broad with the cleanup or
lip thought I'd share, go fuck yourself,
dude. That is absolute genius. And
now I just got paranoid cause I said,
what's fucking school you
went to and all that shit.
I hope you don't get in trouble,
but if you,
somehow your woman is listening to this,
a guy does something like that.
Not because he's being a dick.
It's because he cares for you.
And uh,
we don't know how to,
we, we, we don't have those skills.
Okay.
How do you tell somebody that
there's no way to do it?
I think what he did was genius.
Nobody got fucking hurt.
You felt great about yourself.
He cared about you enough
sweetheart in case you're listening.
Then he came up with the plan that,
you know, if he put it in another area,
he could have like whacked JFK.
So there you go.
He came up with an enigma
wrapped up in a rental,
however that fuck that goes and uh,
and you look even better.
I would hope somebody would
do that for me. All right,
girlfriend and fantasy league. Hey Belle,
love the podcast I'll put up. Thank you.
I've been in a fantasy
football league for 10 years.
It was started by one of my best friends
and has been the same 12 guys for a
decade. I don't even know
how bands have put, uh,
I don't even know bands that
have been together that long.
So this year my buddy who started the
league decided to boot out to lifelong
members in favor of his girlfriend and
the girlfriend of a friend of ours.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait
a minute. Wait a minute. Wait.
Did those other two guys who got booted,
did they do anything?
I mean,
if he was going to add the ladies,
why did those other
two guys have to leave?
Wow. All right. Okay, well I'm
sucked into this story. He said,
I immediately called bullshit and said
point blank to his face is she wasn't
sucking your Dick then she wouldn't
be in the league. Uh, dude,
that right there is a game changer. You
can't say what if he marries this woman?
Always. There's a, for you guys,
always be careful what you say
about the woman you're guy is with.
Cause you never fucking know.
You never know.
And I'm sure there's some listeners
that have stories and if you'd like to
contribute them to the
podcast where, uh, you know,
it's even fucking worse is when
your buddy,
he says fucked up shit about the girl.
You know about what a horse she is in bed
and she's fucking brains out, but blah,
blah, blah, blah, Blah
and tells you all these,
these details and then the jackass ends
up falling forward and then he has to
fucking break up with you because he's
not going to break up with her because
every time he looks at you,
he thinks out. You know,
he knows how this girl, my,
my future wife Sucks my Dick.
You know anyways,
plowing ahead.
Okay.
He's trying to defend this decision by
saying she at least knows a little about
sports,
so this is awful.
This guy wasn't raised right, man.
This is just, this is fucking terrible.
You said the fact of the matter is that
she is from New York and knows who the
jets are. That's the extent
of her football knowledge.
He thinks I'm overreacting,
not overreacting.
He didn't ask anybody else.
You've had 12 for the last 10 years and
he just removed two of the original band
members
do.
This isn't even funny. This is,
this is really upsetting to me.
He thinks I'm overreacting, but I think
of it the same scenario. If you had,
if you have one night a year to have a
guy's night with your buddies and then
you get to the bar,
you see that your friend has invited
his girlfriend to guys night. Exactly.
Even told me that she,
she's the one who asked if she could join,
which obviously to me means he
had no intentions of inviting her,
but when he was backed into the corner,
his ball shot up into his throat
and he couldn't say no exactly.
It's not just a fantasy league,
but a clear indication that she's
going to slowly start chipping away at
everything else in the rest of his life.
Exactly. In summation, is girlfriend
wanted in and he crumbled and said,
yes. Am I reading too much into this?
Am I overreacting?
I'd like to know because he's getting
pissed at me for being pissed at him.
Absolutely not, sir. Everything
that I was going to tell you,
you already know and you wrote in this
email. Okay? You ran down the mats,
you went off the little
fucking springy board.
Do you hit the fucking hobby horse?
You dead.
Your little fucking Mary Lou lit
and flip and you stuck the landing.
You get a perfect 10 on that one, sir. You
are 100% right. You know what you want.
My move would be, I would start
my own fantasy league. All right?
And I would invite everybody else
in that fucking league. Well,
I wouldn't do that cause that's, that's
a chick move. Make people decide,
okay,
oh, this is what I, I wouldn't be as
harsh with him and just be like, no,
do what you did was absolute bullshit.
And I guarantee you,
I would tell him that she's going
to start chipping away at your life.
You balls are up in your throat.
Um,
but that's going to end your friendship
with them. But here's the deal, dude.
There are other fantasy
football leagues to join.
All right? And that, that's
one of those ugly things about
that chapter of guys lives after college.
You know,
when you went to grade school together
or you met them and call up guys and
college or whatever,
but you guys have this unbelievable bond,
like you went to fucking war together.
Um,
if one of your
friends is a policy,
you know,
he has a,
he has a chance of meeting somebody who's
going to splinter that group. You know,
and this isn't an anti woman thing,
this is more like an anti pussy
guy kind of thing where raw,
you know there are controlling,
suffocating people on
both sides. Men and women.
And I know that this women
listening and they've,
one of their best girlfriend started
dating some fucking overbearing,
insecure Douche bag guy and the first
thing they do is they cut them off from
their friends and then it's the coworkers,
then the friends and then their family,
they stick them under a fucking
little glass or something. So, uh, yeah,
you know what dude?
Get up divorced.
The sad thing is is you're going to
lose a couple of friends sometimes that
happens and a,
you just have to be content about it and
you know,
and I think it's really important for
men and women to have men only and women
only social events that they can go to
once a week or a couple times a month and
just hang out with the fellows or hang
out with the ladies. It just, whatever.
I think it's really, really healthy. It's
gives you something to look forward to.
It gives you a place where you
could just vent about your,
anything you fucking want in,
in a group of people,
that 100% is going to understand and
you don't have to worry about hurting
anybody's feelings or offending on
anybody. I think it's true. It's really,
really fucking healthy.
And this guy's fucking with that.
And uh, and he didn't put it to a vote.
What does he, the Grand Poobah this shit.
Okay.
I Dunno. There's so many ways you
can go with that. The spending,
depending on how much you
want to stir up the pot,
you guys should put it to the vault.
This would be great. Put it to a vote.
Do we have this be like
you're Arab spring,
but with a fantasy football league and
just felt that cunt out and then you
become the dictator and you move into the
palace. How about debt? Whatever. Dude,
you're 100% right. I would just, I would
choose my words a little more carefully.
Um, don't say that he didn't
have the balls. Just say, listen,
this was something that we did
together for 12 years and uh,
I'm really disappointed and shocked that
you made this big a move and remove two
other members and didn't
include anybody else in it.
I don't think that it was done right and
I think we should put this to a vote.
That's what we should do.
And if he gets mad and he starts yelling,
don't lose your cool.
Just keep stating your
opinion calmly and you know,
if he's going to be a bitch about it,
let it be a bitch about it.
And I would actually,
for your own health,
does she all the things she knows
is the jet. She's going to be like,
wait a minute. Who is that? I have, I
got, I got, I don't know anything I had,
she still tried to do that.
You know that thing where women try to
act like they're dumb because they think
it's cute. You know what I would do, sir?
I would just put your losses
just fucking with, I don't know.
The more you think about it,
the more noisy I'm getting in.
Just ruined my fucking day
and I'm not even in it.
I didn't like fantasy football.
All right. Bank or cuts. All right,
Billy boy. Uh, so have you heard about
these greedy cunts at Goldman Sachs?
That was kind of a national story.
What do they do? Something else?
You said they cornered a large share of
the market in aluminum and then bet it
on the futures of a lumen with the
price going up. Sounds illegal. It is.
But of course those stupid fucking
cuts found a loophole in the law.
The loophole is that 25 tons of aluminum
is supposed to leave the warehouse
every day. However, the law does
it specify where it had to go.
So they would just send it to another
warehouse of, there isn't technically,
it didn't leave the warehouse
and the New York Times article,
they interviewed people who
previously worked at these warehouses.
They would jokingly send each other
messages and say, Hey, get hey,
get the shipment of aluminum.
But really they were just transferring
it to an adjacent warehouse.
Uh, I, I, this is, I don't even
get what the fuck's going on here.
Of course Goldman Sachs has recently
posted it's largest quarter profit of over
2 billion.
When can we take these bankers out into
the street and just shoot them all?
Joking aside, this shit is insider
trading and they should be prosecuted,
but we know that won't happen. A
PS, no, you're busy for a while.
But when are you coming back to
Atlanta? Uh, I actually don't know.
I don't know when I'm coming
back to Atlanta. You know what?
That's one of those things I should have
read that 20 times in a row and learned
what exactly is going on.
I think this is basically how they get
away with it is that there's too many
people like myself that don't even
understand what was going on there.
All that stuff,
betting on futures.
I don't even understand
what any of that means.
I was just in the stock market
long enough to realize like, hey,
I don't know what the
fuck's going. I'm, I'm S.
I basically felt like I was
standing at a crap table. Uh,
I put my money on a crap table in
it and I wasn't even in the casino.
You know,
I was in a different state and then I
was calling somebody else up going, hey,
how's the game going?
You know,
I saw a couple of stats at the bottom with
the screen and I can't even read them.
I don't even know if the
games even being played.
That's what I can't get past about
everybody listening to this podcast. You
don't, you don't have any of the money
that you earn every week.
You don't have any of it.
You ever think about that?
It's a number on a piece of paper.
You take it to the bag and then they
stick that number in your ATM that
occasionally you go to the ATM and they
give you a piece of paper that is only
worth something because everybody
says it's worth something,
but you really have nothing of value.
What you have is the piece of
paper that's a part of the life
so that that is the genius of all of
this shit and into penalties and fees and
taxes and all that crap.
They get you even further
removed or you have to invest it.
You know? Why do I have to fucking
invest? You can't, I don't know.
You don't get anything.
You don't get anything of fucking value.
The only thing that has value is the lie.
And as long as the lie continues,
I mean,
isn't this the month?
Where are we going to raise the
debt ceiling every fucking year?
Eventually that wave's going to crash.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I hope when the wave crashes that all
races and all economic levels somehow put
down their differences and they all
come together and we just start walking
towards gated communities.
All right.
There you go.
How much are you stealing that you have
to live behind a gated community there.
They're sitting there acting like they're,
they're afraid that we're
going to steal their shit.
It's like you got your shit by
stealing from us. All right.
And our k sorry. All right.
What am I going here?
The next one.
Low Libido girlfriend.
Okay.
Uh, all right. Hey Bill.
I've been with my current girlfriend
for two years and we've had our ups and
downs,
ups and downs relationship wise,
but even at the lowest points we
still get back together. Okay.
Is there a reason you get back together?
Is it because you actually love this girl
or he just lonely and don't want to go
through the pain of a breakup?
A,
the problem is at this
point and the relationship,
it seems like I'm the only
one interested in sex.
Maybe it's just a man thing
or how long we've been dating,
but she's in her 20s and I'm 31 and
we have the sex life of a middle aged,
married couple once a month or
once every three weeks at best.
She generally responds to my advances
with this interest or at worst annoyance.
Do you think there is any ways to
change this or we just not sexually
compatible? Go Fuck Yourself? Well,
my gut tells me the relationship
is over and it's been over. Um,
oh, you said ups and downs. You didn't say
that you broke up. I ran into that. Um,
okay.
Yeah. You need to sit down and
talk to her and just say, listen,
I just want to talk about her sex life.
I feel like it's almost nonexistent and
when I try to get something going with
you,
I feel like you're a,
like I just completely turn you off.
You know?
Did I do something?
And if in general you
just not into me anymore,
just let me know cause I'm 31 at,
uh,
I should probably try and find someone
who finds me remotely attractive when you
think so. It was kind of
what I'm looking for in life.
Somebody who actually gives a flying fuck
then of shaking my dick in their face.
Huh?
See like right there.
I look at you just look down.
Just a mere mention of me shaking
my cock and your feet. No, sorry.
Yeah,
that's what I would do.
Okay.
You think there's any change of this? Are
we just not sexually compatible? Yeah,
this is all like all relationship shit.
His communication.
He kept a sit down for what you
want to communicate. Relationship.
What I've learned, the best thing to
do is sit down with yourself first.
All right. Driving in the car, get all
the yelling out. Scream at the windshield.
Yeah. Well what the fuck? I'm sitting
there, I went over to your broad,
he talked to you.
Yeah.
You don't just scream and get it all up
and then when you get all of that out,
then you just do some self analysis and
he, you try to break down the anger.
It'd be like,
what am I really upset about?
Okay.
You know, what do I feel right now? I feel
like I'm not being heard. I feel this.
I feel that. And then she, then
he had to have this game plan.
Okay.
Even if you've got to make like a setlist,
like a fucking comedian and you just
write down what you feeling and the points
that you want to get out.
Draw a smiley face at the end of it to
remind yourself to not get angry because
you're going to start the conversation.
This works for both men and women.
You're going to start the conversation.
So the other person is caught off guard,
so they didn't get a chance
to scream at the windshield.
So they might start screaming at you.
So your point,
your main thing is not to join in
and have the whole thing escalate.
You just want to be heard. All
right? So if you in an adult way,
just tell them what you're
feeling without insulting them.
It's always good for the relationship.
Even if the relationship
fucking comes to an end,
uh,
you're just pressing fast forward
through a bunch of pain. So there you go.
So I would just sit down
with them and just say, yeah,
I just feel like I repulse
you to the point that I'm
okay.
You know, I feel hesitant to even
even trying to make a move on you.
What's the deal? You know? See
how that works out. All right.
Road, head accident. Hey Bill,
I took my lady out to a nice
steakhouse for our anniversary.
We had an awesome night. The food
was expensive, but fucking great.
We pigged out and after it was all over,
we left.
We then went and seen a movie.
I don't know if that's a Typo, sir,
but I fucking, I know guys like you.
We went out, we had all this meal
and we went out. We seen a movie
and at two hours to let
our stomachs settle.
I'm surprised you didn't fall asleep.
I would have felt if I had a giant steak
dinner, I woulda got the itis. Anyways.
Then after we left the theater,
we locked eyes in the car and we
immediately wanted to fuck Jesus. Dude,
you're killing it. Steak, dinner,
movies. Now you're going to, you know,
you've got a woman who wants to jump on
your deck. God bless you, America. Uh,
so I threw the neon into
tribe in Florida towards home.
However, she had the amazing idea to give
me some road head before we got home.
Being in Dota. I had my dick out before
she even got situated. Of course,
after a while of her doing
this, she started to gag
being a dude. I was thinking,
oh yeah, she can't even handle this dick.
Jesus Christ. This guy's spare no detail.
Sorry ladies. Uh, despite the fact that
she had never gagged before, oh, sorry,
I missed the, the self
deprecating tag there. He said,
I was thinking she can't handle this dick,
despite the fact she had never
gagged before. Before I knew it.
Oh No.
Okay.
All right. If you're squeamish,
people just shut it off now. He goes,
I felt a wet sensation on my balls.
As I looked down,
I noticed that she had thrown up all over
my dick balls and general crotch area.
Sorry.
Wow.
Here's the bullshit.
She was mad at me.
What the fuck? She was so
upset and embarrassed. That's
what it is right there,
sir. About about it that she
hasn't come over in two weeks.
Why is she pissed? She isn't the one
that had the cleanest stake dad. Right.
All right.
Tell me what to do.
MMM.
I gotta tell you this. She's being
really immature. She's embarrassed.
She's embarrassed,
and
she's not being mature
about this. Where, I mean,
it was a mutual thing.
It's not like you grabbed
her by the back of the head,
just slammed her head down there. You
know, she was all about it. In fact, if I,
if I remember before, I can get that
nightmare visual out of my head.
It was her idea. Right?
We wanted to fuck whoever.
She had the amazing idea to get
me some head, oh, she's a trooper.
You know, this is what I would
do. Send her a card in the mail.
All right.
And just, just tell it that,
you know, you miss her. I,
you don't viewer any differently
or anything and just, just,
just write something nice and
yeah, I'd really like to, uh,
take you out for an ice cream.
Maybe if you do throw it up
all of my Dick and balls later.
I think it'd be kind of a soothing,
you know,
this is summertime months and that
criteria can get a little hot.
So I wouldn't mind a little mint chocolate
chip around the pubes there. Right. We
leave out the last part,
but
I have just sent her a nice car.
I wouldn't even bring up the incident.
Just send her a nice car.
Something cute.
Nothing silly, nothing fucking overly
loving. Just something in the middle.
You know what sir? I think we actually
found a new niche for hallmark.
They got to have one where there was
something sexually weird happened and the
other person is embarrassed
at the other person.
Doesn't judge him and wants him back.
You could have those cards.
Let's see if I can come up with
one here that actually bribes.
Uh,
dare lay you got a little shady.
I still love you. Uh, I dunno.
You puked at my Dick and balls.
I don't know how to fuck again.
Somewhere in there. Uh, wrap ups. Okay.
That's a podcast for this week. Everybody,
uh, once again, I feel absolutely horrible
that people actually came out yeah.
To that,
uh,
to the fucking El Paso show.
I don't know what happened.
I don't know if you
missed an email or what,
but it seemed like there are enough
people showed up at the ball.
Got dropped somewhere.
I announced it here on the podcast.
MMM.
I Dunno. Anyways, my apologies. Wrap
ups. Okay. Now that the show's over,
don't forget to support our sponsors.
This is really important is how I make
money on this thing and I don't have to
charge anybody shit. Uh, once again,
get started with a free 30 day trial of
he voicey voice gives you a toll free
number.
Don't free a local number,
so you can make business calls from
anywhere and always sounds like you're at
the office. Uh, right now,
go to [inaudible] dot com enter the Promo
code bill for your 30 day free trial.
That's he voice.com Promo Code Bill,
or go to the podcast page bill bird.com
and click on the voice banner, uh,
support this podcast,
an extended free trial of Hulu plus
when you go to the podcast page,
[inaudible] Dot Com and
click the Hulu plus banner.
I'll go to Hulu plus.com/bill.
That's Hulu plus.com/bill
that's podcast for this week.
Uh,
once again,
my apologies to everybody went
down to the show in El Paso.
I feel horrible about it. Everybody else
go fuck yourselves. Have a great week.
That's it. I'll talk a later.
Where's the Stop Button?
There it is.