Hey,
what's going on is bill burn is time for
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
April 18th, 2016 what's
going on, dude? Hawaii.
Um, I don't know. I don't even know why.
I don't even know where to
start on this fucker one. Um,
how do you begin? This one is
still be sensitive, sensitive.
There's so many sensitive
stories out there.
Everyone there is when there's feelings,
they're uninformed
or you tried to approach this,
um,
this fucking lay down at the
zoo in Palm Beach, Florida.
Rest his soul got attacked and killed,
got mauled a by a fucking tiger,
sometimes referred to as
the tiger whisper, Yadda,
Yadda, Yadda, Yadda, Yadda,
Yadda, Yadda, and all that fucking
shit. These, I don't know what it is
about people who fall in
love with wild animals.
There's nothing you can do to cure it.
It's fucking,
it doesn't give a fuck about you.
It's not a dog,
you know,
fallen in love with a wild animal.
It's like falling in love with a stripper.
Yeah. It's just not gonna end.
Well, it's not gonna end well,
fucking unbelievable. Then there's
another story. This fucking scout leader,
it takes a bunch of boy scouts, takes a
bunch of children into the fucking woods.
He goes into a cave and there's
a fucking bear in there,
fill the whole story's always an amazing
that the boy scouts kept their fucking
cool.
That guy knew.
The scout leader knew that he pulled his
shirt up over his face and then curled
up into the fetal position, which I guess
is the international bear signal like,
hey man,
I don't want any part of this man.
And then the bear loss
interest in walked away.
But at no point during all
of this does anybody say,
hey,
the fuck are you bringing a bunch of
kids around with his bears just walking
around. It's bad enough if you
take your kids to the fucking zoo,
the amount of times these God damn
things get loose. Or at the very least,
some fatty is going to walk
up to some polar bear cage.
Go over the fucking thing and stand there,
you know,
and then get fucking snatched by
this thing. And what is she saying?
What for you to fucking blow
your brains out. You Dope. Right.
So I'm not saying the lady who died in
Florida was a dope. I'm just saying that,
um,
I don't know.
You Insert yourself into this situation
and there's no good way to insert
yourself into a mauling to death by
tiger cause you knew what that means.
There was also, they always just say
malt. You know, like it came up like,
like some prisons shit and just
stuck you with the shank. It didn't,
it fucking crushed your neck and then
it started feeding on your energy.
That's fucking brutal.
Okay.
Hang on a second. Nia. Yeah. Okay.
What are you doing? You coming in?
No. All right. Did you lock me in?
No.
Okay. Sorry. She just goes, she
freaking me out. They're like,
well I got these new locks on the door.
I thought she was locking the door.
It's still early here and I just woke
her up so she's going to be a little
grumpy. Nia, you want to come
in on the podcast? Let me know.
Oh, that's silence spoke volumes.
You know, I'll tell you right now,
getting married is kind of like a
falling in love with a wild animal.
Yeah.
You know as much as you love them, don't
get too close to the fucking end. Close.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um, yeah. Let me get back to it.
Why the fuck would you take
a bunch of kids out like no.
At no point does anybody addressed at
this guy took a bunch of fucking children
out to where there's bears and then they
watched him get fucking mauled for half
a second before he took his Izod
Aggie and yanked it over his head.
That's what you're supposed to do.
How have I been on the earth this long
and not known that that's what you do
when you run into the bear?
Is it because I'm not in scouting or is
it because most people are smart enough
to not be around bears?
To not reenact the fucking scene
from the Leonardo Dicaprio movie?
What was it called, the ray content?
I don't even, what the fuck it is.
The revelent, the irrelevant,
whatever the fuck it was called.
I hate when they take some big word that
already exist and just makes you feel
like it's like, did they make
that word up? And it's like,
no, that word is existed.
The revenant,
right.
That word is existed your entire life.
Just you and everybody you know is too
dumb to walk around and use it on a daily
basis and yeah, that's, it's a sad
feeling. Just sad fucking feeling. Um,
I forget what I was looking.
Oh yeah.
What to do if a bear attack shoe,
I can tell you right now,
this is going to be 99.9% white
people looking the shit up.
Yes.
Where the dubs that go out there,
I hate to do def jam material,
but it's fucking true.
Okay.
Jesus fucking Christ 2016 and
he get mauled by a grizzly bear.
There's no excuse for that. And
you know how, you know, hallmark,
does it make a card?
Fourth Day you go,
you can go through all of
that whole sympathy section.
Sorry for your loss. Sorry.
You got this disease. Sorry, I was
a Douche yesterday. There's no, wow.
Fucking sorry. You got mauled by a
bear. They don't because it happens so,
so little. So few times.
There's no reason for it.
They should really make one of
those and make it even better.
It should like rhyme.
I hate to look,
I hate to stay on your face.
Got Mauled by a bear.
I'm really fucking sorry.
Uh,
I know something about a trolley. Go
Fuck Yourself. I hope you feel better.
Tension all zookeepers out there.
Uh, those are not your friends. Uh,
and they don't want to be there. And I
think a lot of them realize the situation.
They're not just sitting there fucking
waiting for you to give him another
fucking pile of Cube steaks.
They're sitting there,
even if they were born in captivity,
I guaran fucking tee you that they are
sitting there with this strange feeling
that there has to be more than
this. Look at me to look. I mean,
if you're a fucking tiger, even you're
a tiger born into captivity, right?
You're rolling around with somebody
dressed in a safari outfit. Okay.
And you bond with that person like
it's your fucking mother. Right.
It's some fucking point.
Okay.
It's some point,
you know,
just your ego alone with all those people
showing up just to look at you taking
your picture. This no weed, no. There's no
way to keep you four feet on the ground,
you know, and not be like, dude, uh,
why am I in a cage right now when
everybody's coming up? You know,
all I do is lay around every day and these
people can't get enough looking at me.
I mean, man, I, I'm the fucking
Shit, you know? And you just start,
you ego just goes fucking crate lane.
Then you start looking like, you know,
I don't know, you'd start testing.
They come in a little bit,
you give him a little growl,
you see it in their face and they get
some broom handle and get back and back,
right? You just Sorta, you know,
first time with your park
test the strength of that.
Okay.
Fucking little broom handle. Like,
dude, I could snap that thing.
This guy's fucking shoulders, guys, a
pussy, what? They're doing, tiger pushup.
And then one day you just like,
you know what?
As much as I'm enjoying
this fucking raw meat.
I have it every day and I need to
switch up the Diet, you know? Oh,
but I mall you and a usually
a belt is some dental floss.
I know, I know what you're thinking
right now. You probably think it build.
This is really fucking insensitive.
Well you know what,
this is how I deal with sad shit.
I joke around about it cause I don't
feel like they get about everybody that
loved that woman that now
can never see her again.
So I mean what am I supposed to do?
And then also I like to feel that I'm
being responsible by giving you some tips
on how not to a, yeah. You know, you
don't get good mauled to death by a bear.
I just don't understand that.
Like what's so fucking funny
about these goddamn scouts,
it's like why didn't he
just go in the woods?
You don't have to go into
the Goddamn wilderness. No,
fuck brings a bunch of kids out there.
I'll tell you,
it brings a bunch of kids out there,
kind of guy that goes on,
just walks into a fucking cave,
gets mauled by a fucking bitch.
Who the fuck walks into a cave in the
middle of the forest? What kind of it?
I mean, I'm not in scouting. I never was.
I can't start a fire without a match.
But I can tell you right now,
my general instincts say
is that says that you know,
okay,
there's no apartment buildings out in the
fucking forest. Okay, so a cave is like,
that's like a townhouse in Brooklyn.
You know?
Definitely people have to fucking
digging holes in the Goddamn ground,
curling up to hibernate and that.
Here's a fucking cave. All right,
so you think everybody who lives
out there, that's like fucking,
that's like Beverly hills level property.
So who's going to get it?
The strongest sick is craziest
motherfucker out there and that's a bear.
You know,
you're not going to walk in there and
there's going to be a little fox in there
like it isn't.
It's going to be some fucking,
it's going to be the king of the forest.
Which is a bear as far as I know.
Although I did see a mountain lion
give it a couple of fucking, you know,
Pernell Whitaker is, you
know, memo fast. That guy was,
they would just fucking right on top of
his head and the bear just sat there and
taking,
you know,
he had like the head movement of light
of late Mike Tyson rather than early and
he just took a few and then he just
sorta started running away was a sad day,
you know? Um, anyways,
just imagine if you ran into a
badger or a fucking wolverine.
Those lunatics.
Okay.
Badges and Wolverine still like the Irish
and the Scottish of the fuck at forest.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
Those things don't even quit.
Even, even if they're losing it,
they just got that. I don't give a
fuck, you know, blood all over the face.
They're not stopping.
They're going to keep coming.
Just like the Irish and the
Scottish fucking loaded ticks.
You don't want any part, any
part of that? Well, you know,
I don't know oil.
You know what?
I never even look to say Kate
impairing counters and back country.
If you encounter a bear on the
trail or in your campsite. Yeah.
Cause you're cooking food basically
the dinner bell of anything.
But then fucking,
yeah.
Oh my God. Look at this size
of this fucking bear. Oh,
there's a lady fucking walk in and
there's a bear in the background.
Guess what color she is. All
right. Be Safe and bear habitat.
Oh God. This is the first sentence.
The level, I mean, as dumb as I, uh,
the level of dopes that have to become
to this website. Listen to this.
Just the first sentence.
It's normal. It's normal to,
I said normal. It's normal to be
frightened when you encounter a bear.
That's how this, this is,
this is the jump off point.
The reality is that most
encounters with bears rarely,
rarely lead to aggressive behavior.
And attacks are even rarer. Yeah.
They go sucking into the forest.
I mean it happens,
but generally is,
here's a great lie.
They're actually more afraid of
you then you are of them. Yeah.
And what do they do when they get,
when they're afraid.
Okay.
They either take off running
or they fucking mall you to
death. I think though, a,
you know, here's a bonus. The threat
is gone and now I have a midday snack.
A remember it? Most bears preferred
to avoid contact with humans.
That's hilarious. They're
like the champion that doesn't
want to fight. You know,
just trying to hold on to the belt back
pedal in the entire time until your
corner.
The fucking thing in any bear you do see
is probably just as frightened as you
are there.
It is every fucking,
yeah.
You know what it is that bears
don't have access to a mirror.
They're living in their heads. You know,
they're out there by themselves, you know,
talking to themselves account man.
You know,
I'd love to find a cave or some shit,
man. Right? And all of a sudden,
so they finally find it. Nobody else
is in here. You can fucking chill out,
put an l shaped couch over here,
get a flat screen.
And all of a sudden this fucking guy
comes walking in and his God damn shorts.
You know what he's thinking?
He's thinking to catch a predator.
He's probably seen that show too.
He comes as fucking pedophile.
The bear thinks he's going
to get fucked in the ass.
And next thing you know he's on top of
this guy or I and a fucking dude stodge
Yank and his shirt over his head. And
then the bears like, what the fuck?
Sky's a bottom. You know, I thought
this guy was trying to rape me.
Now all of a sudden he's acting
like we'll make it love here.
And he's been all submissive.
This is fucking weird in me out.
What if he tells his friends the bears
all homophobic and then he kills him and
why? You know what? And there's a bunch
of little kids watching it. All right?
And that's what camping is.
And I think, you know what?
I have to haven't worked
that out right there.
I think scouring should be illegal. You
know what I mean? We want to get there.
Well first of all,
you know,
dressed in those little boys up
like little French maid's, you know,
the will scarfs running around.
I mean it's just a, yeah.
Wonder why he got all
the sexual predators, sex
predators, sexual predators.
I don't. A sexual chocolate, um, anyways,
remained as composed as possible
and follow these simple guidelines.
Whenever you're in bear country,
soon you will,
you two will have more composure when
citing a bear because you know what to do
a scream bloody murder and
running the other direction.
And actually it's the exact
opposite of what you want to do.
You want to remain calm and take a step
towards the beer that shows a level of
confidence.
Okay.
Fucking dope. All right. First
one, avoid. Avoid, avoid.
Yeah.
Light by staying in civilization,
the best way to prevent an unpleasant
and unpleasant bear encounter is to avoid
them all together.
Bears usually avoid people and most
people don't even know when they,
they've come close to a bear.
Exactly.
To ensure a surprise or an to ensure a
surprise or unpleasant encounter with the
bear doesn't occur.
Avoid moving through bear habitats
silently and alone traveling groups.
The larger the better.
And make lots of noise by talking or
singing and put the iPod and pay attention
to your surroundings. Ah, Jesus Christ.
I don't know about that.
What if the bears having a slow fucking
couple of days and is hungry and you
start seeing, oh, I'm saying I get it.
The ranger school Beto Beto Zip,
Betty Doe,
Dad, Zip, Ada, you know, in the
bear starts sticking you like,
you know what? I think it's worth
the risk. Even though I'm scared.
I think I could take that fucking
hundred 40 pounds. Dope. All right.
When it happens, she how
they wrote down. Instead it,
when you're getting mauled by the bear
and you feel its breadth in his fucking
incisors ripping at your
neck when it happens. That's
another way of saying that,
uh,
remain calm and ready.
Your bear spray or other deterrent,
what is it?
Your underarm hair, uh, stay
together. If you're in a group,
you will appear larger and more
intimidating. If you stick together,
try to figure out whether the bear
is a grizzly or a black bear. Hey,
that thing running that
is 40 miles an hour.
If you had a dog that's over fucking over
trying to figure out whether the bears,
uh,
grizzly or a black bear.
As you will see below grizzly bears and
black bears tend to behave differently
in a given situation.
So it helps to know which species
you're dealing with as it's running.
After you give me a fucking break,
I just click here to see the difference.
Okay.
Bears at a distance,
dude. It's a fucking bear.
Yeah.
Look at these fucking things.
Okay
Dude.
The fact that one of these things could
pick up Lawrence Taylor at the height of
his fucking career and throw
him through the uprights. You
okay?
Get bear smart societies.
These fucking people like I don't get it.
I mean there has to be, why can't
you just go out in your backyard?
Just set up a tent. I mean
you, you are still outside.
As long as you don't go inside,
you are camping.
Okay?
It's not the same thing, man. I got
to get out there with his bears.
I know what to do. Right? If
it's a black bear, black bear,
they usually lead with the left.
You know what I mean?
The traditional put a grizzlies,
a south park,
so it's going to be a little bit weird.
They definitely have a reach advantage
considering when they stand up.
They're about eight feet tall.
So what you want to do is you want
to stay outside his wheelhouse. Okay.
And you want, you want to circle
away from his power pantry.
You want to circle to your left,
staying away.
The grizzlies want to load up that
left that go for the big shot.
They try to steal around.
I don't know. Sorry.
My am I beating this to death here?
I'm just, there's no fucking reason.
There's no reason to get killed by a
tiger in the United States of America.
They don't live here.
They're only one place there
at the fucking zoo at uh,
you know they're in cages self.
At some point you went into
the fucking thing. You did.
You just see, I don't know.
Oh my God. What is the fucking thought
when you get yanked in the second Uga?
Oh No, it's got to be it. Oh No.
Make it quick. I mean, just shit that
would go through your head. I'm sorry.
This is getting fucking morbid. Um,
so anyways, my condolences to the,
uh,
friends of families or the lady down there
in Florida and my condolences to the,
uh, the guy with the members only jacket
that he yanked up over his fucking head.
Uh, you know, good on
you, sir. I hope you,
I wish you more luck as you bring
children into the fucking woods.
Fucking idiot.
What is it about putting on a fucking
uniform that all of a sudden you think you
know something? I just don't
get it. Oh, I am. You know,
I have all my badges on my shirt.
I had been trained
for, he's a jolly good, fair.
That's where they should be singly.
This the thing that, you know,
we're never going to see you again.
Music right before you go into the woods,
just to fucking reminds you of what
you're walking into. Um, anyways,
so, hey, um, the official,
finally the official Lau,
um,
I'm allowed to finally say it.
F is for family has been
picked up for a second season.
Um, I actually got the news back in
January, but for whatever reason,
the way Netflix promote stuff,
which I would never question considering
they're dominating the universe.
They wanted to wait until last
Friday. So it is now official. Uh,
we are working right now. That's the
stuff I've been alluding to that, uh,
I've been working on. And
um, uh, what was I gonna say?
Uh,
actually this weekend I was writing
an episode so I missed all the fucking
hockey I saw.
The series that I'm watching is
Saint Louis first, the Black Hawks.
And when I saw game too,
I threw in the fucking
towel. I was like, that's it.
He gave a game to the Black Hawk. She
cannot give a game to the hawks. You know,
you had your foot on their fucking neck.
He had the gall,
the goal was fucking
called back or whatever.
I can't remember what happened to gold
got called back, right. Or terrorists,
ankles goal got called back
and then it's just like,
that coach should have gone down the
bench. No, let down. No let down.
Right.
What do they do?
They go out there that pissed terrorist
Sanko takes a stupid fucking penalty.
The Blackhawks score the goal and they
steal the fucking game and I was just
like, and I was texting
my buddy. I was like,
that right there is why the Blackhawks
win every fucking year in St Louis loses
every fucking year.
Whatever.
The Blackhawks have that ability to
remain calm when they're down Saint Louis
for my whole fucking life
has never had that right.
The right after I said all of that shit.
What are they doing?
Game three I didn't see the game.
I just looked at the highlights.
You know they fucking took three
quick penalties in the first period.
Chicago scored on the first, on the
first one. If I was watching that game,
I'd be like, here we go, here we go.
Chicago is going to win like the next
for the next four to five and they didn't
give him digging. Even Saint Louis Seal
right there. Fred St Louis came back,
tied it up one one. Chicago scores a
goal in the second period, two to one.
They're going into the third period
in Chicago. This is always said,
you know,
it's over for the blues.
It's always been that way since I don't
know how long it's been going on forever
now. Like the Blackhawks will
give my whole life to mean shit.
They went through a nice drug to,
but like the new black hawks,
like this series is over and
fucking Saint Louis came back,
tied it up to two and
then went ahead three,
two with like six minutes left and a so
a big congratulations to a the St Louis
Blues,
that huge fucking victory.
And I can't wait to see the next game
cause I know the Blackhawks and act in it
and I just got to go out like that. Right.
You know, they're going to tie it up.
They're going to go into St Louis. This
might go a, I don't know, may go seven.
I'm hoping for seven. You know,
I don't give a shit, but I'm,
I'm pulling for Saint Louis. I think
they're my team over Dallas. Just because,
you know, Dallas was
the north stars, right?
They've only been Dallas stars for
like, what, like 20 years. Eh. You know,
I mean those people down there, but they
have a bunch of cowboys who's kid too,
you know,
they getting plastic surgery yet.
How they got their oil welding
whites wearing too much makeup.
I mean the different Dallas, the big D,
it's a football town to football state.
I love the fucking stars.
I love the people on the stars.
But like I also like their
fucking college. They got
Celtic colors. I like to,
I still like to stars,
but you know, I think,
I don't think it's time for the blues.
They've been around since 67.
They never won shit.
So that's the team I'm pulling for GPL.
How you not for the Boston Bruins
because we didn't make the playlists.
Um,
but who would've thought a Blackhawks sit
down two games to one to the blues and
the Kings are down o two
to the San Jose sharks.
Um,
and actually a buddy of mine who writes
onF is for family before this all
started. He goes, I don't
give a fuck. He goes,
the Stanley Cup goes through Chicago or
la. And that's what everybody was saying.
Now,
granted we're only a couple of games in
here and granted the kings are playing
the sharks and,
and you know,
the sharks are like the San Diego
chargers if they were skates, you know,
every year coming out having
this wonderful fucking
regular season and then they
go in the playoffs and they just
shit the bed. So we'll seek,
they were up two games to none.
Um,
I think game for if you haven't
been watching as Tuesday night, uh,
the Black Hawks first, the blue. So I
would definitely be checking that out.
And um, I think that's it. I think
that's all I had on hockey. Right?
My Celtics, I watched them lose
game one, but I'm just so psyched.
They're in the fucking playoffs
and now they're a young team.
They should have won the game. They
should have been able to close it out,
but they didn't, but they hung in there.
They got high that just a little young.
Okay.
They just got to learn how to fucking
a filler that hopefully, you know what,
what I'm getting, I'm hoping, I'm
hoping that we get Kevin Durant.
He would be a great fucking Celtic. Uh,
whether he does that or not, I mean,
there's always someplace,
uh, you know, what's this?
This is the most crucial time
and I,
since I can remember for the Los Angeles
Lakers with Colby just fucking retired.
Okay. Their owner fucking
died to now they got the sun.
Okay.
Fuck head that he is sorry that it
had nothing to do with the Lakers.
I was just quoting.
What movie was that?
And then your son Fuck head that is left.
Is drivers less true romance.
Um,
okay.
Yeah.
They have to make something happen.
They got to throw their fucking
money around. I don't know.
They don't have the coach. They don't
have it. This could be for the first time.
You realize that the Lakers have one more
fucking championships since 1970 than
any other team in any other major sports.
MMM.
So I got to respect what they've done
more so than what anybody else has done
prior to that. Because prior to
that was the 23 skidoo years.
Where did the shit was in fucking
basically black and white, you know,
segregated leagues. The Stanley Cup
was the size of a shot glass, you know,
the Celtics used to when that would be
like fucking five white guys against five
white guys or maybe five
against four white guys.
And then Bill Russell was out there.
You know what I mean? It's just,
it's just a completely
different time, you know? Um,
okay.
I Dunno. We'll see. So anyways, let me do
a little bit of advertising here. Sorry,
my brain's all over the place and I just
still can't get over how fucking people
get mauled 20 1620 fucking 16 I mean to
get mauled to death by a fucking tiger
in 2016 it's,
it's like,
okay,
I don't I to take a,
I think the probability of getting
run over by a stage coach is,
is just as probable like helping
people gain on, I got to look that up.
Death by stage coach is, you know,
this can be somebody, some wow.
Which show in Oklahoma fell off
the chuck wagon. Okay. You know,
what's going to be a guy too,
man killed under stage coach.
Let's see if we get to see we're getting
did you mean man killed under stage?
Coach? One word. I guess
I did. Unsettling events.
Stagecoach robberies,
police id man killed in Stowe crash.
Okay.
Fatal crash on stagecoach road,
72 year old man was killed Sunday morning
after a crash in West Lake township.
I know,
authority said.
Okay.
A vehicle traveling
northbound on coach Rowe job,
I guess it doesn't happen and whatever.
Somebody get kicked by a
horse or something stupid.
Something that should be
happening during this time,
but why can't you just admit that you
are wrong? All right, I was wrong.
It's more probable to get mauled to
death by a tiger. All right, let's uh,
let's do read some of the advertising
here. I do always shave club, everybody.
Dollar Shave club.com as a special
offer to new members who join today.
You get a free month of the executive
razor when you buy a tube of doctor
cabbies.
Easy shape.
This is the first time they've
ever done something like this.
And once you try dollar shave club.com,
you'll be,
you'll become a proud member like millions
of others just puffing your chest out.
As you walk down the street.
I get cheap razors.
What are you doing with your life?
One reason is because they deliver amazing
razors right to your door for third
of the price of what the greedy
razor corporations charge.
That means when you join it DSC,
you can afford to shave with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
You feel like you're running a bank right?
Um, you get a first class shave when use
the executive blade without hurting your
wallet.
Another reason is Dr Carver's shave
butter can't believe it's not Garvey's.
Um,
using it with the executive makes the
blade glide gently for the smoothest shave
ever.
Dr Carver's shave butter.
If doctor [inaudible] isn't
your average shave cream,
it's a unique conditioning formula
with high quality natural ingredients,
leaving your skin feeling unbelievably
smooth and soft. And right now,
new members who buy a tube of the shave
butter, get the executive razor for free.
Uh,
they've never done this before.
Take advantage of it and it's only
available by going to dollar shave
club.com/bird that's dollar shave
club.com/burr that Jesus Christ,
how many have I got this
week? Alright, trunk club,
Trunk Club Trunk Club was started
to solve a simple problem.
Shopping for clothes in stores
is overwhelming and inconvenient.
It's not overwhelming. It's
sucks. Who wants to do that?
At least I don't. I don't want to fucking
do that. So if I don't want to do that,
then I assume everybody else does it.
Thank God for Trunk Club.
Cause with trunk club you'll discover
great clothes that are perfect for you.
Oh if you look at this shirt
without ever having to go shopping,
we combine top brands,
experts,
service and unparalleled convenience
to deliver a highly personalized
personalized experience
that helps you look.
Your best trunk club is
not a subscription service.
We send you clothes only when you
ask zero sign up or monthly fees.
He can't, he can't ask for anything
more than that. Look at that. You know,
they'll send you a
shirt whenever you want.
We sent trucks refrained
from saying boxes,
alludes to subscription service. I
didn't. I said, what the fuck you wrote?
Why would you put that sentence in the
copy? You know, I'm going to read it. Uh,
don't talk about price.
Talk about quality. Hey,
don't tell me what the fuck to do.
I'm reading. Why don't you just write?
What the fuck you want me to read?
You assholes.
How did this go from copy to
them wagging their finger at me?
I'll talk about what the fuck
I want to talk about. You know,
if you want to go to the fucking mall,
this is a great thing. Okay. They got it.
I mean, I can paraphrase all of this day
of an expert stylist. In other words,
someone who eventually we'll actually
get paid a decent amount of money to pick
up these clothes,
but right now they're new to the business,
so take advantage of their talents while
they still work for trunk club. Okay.
You tell them your basic styles.
I like concert tee shirts and flip flops,
whatever your fucking deal is,
and then they'll get somebody go
out and they pull a bunch of shit.
They stick it in the trunk, they sent
it to you. You keep what you want.
You take everything else you don't want.
You throw it back in the fucking trunk
and you send it back to them and that's
it,
and they don't send you any more shit
until you ask them to because it's not a
subscription service. All right. If
you'd like to take advantage of this,
go to fucking whatever the hell it is.
Trunk Club
please. No mention of competitors. I
don't even understand this. There's,
this is like a,
yeah,
this was more a letter giving me
shit for what I've been doing.
All right.
I'm going to say it's trunk club.com/birth
that's what I would go with a MVMT
watches.
You know,
it's been a few weeks now since I
cracked open these sharp looking, ah,
Jesus Christ.
Why do they keep doing this to me?
Why do they keep pumping?
Probably sent this copy out
to every person with the
podcast and everybody goes,
you know,
it's been a few weeks since I cracked
open these sharp looking movement watch
boxes. I did. I saw him the fucking great.
They looked like expensive
watches and you know,
but I am a fucking 48 year old man,
so I have an expensive watch and
I'm going to continue wearing that.
If I was in my twenties or early
thirties if I'd gone through a divorce,
these are the fucking watch for you.
Okay?
So you can still attract some
expensive tail. All right. Without,
you know you're still have money to
buy her a drink. That's basically it.
All right.
If you haven't had a chance to experience
how movement watched fits around your
wrist,
this is the chance movement watches start
at just $95 seat when movement cut out
the middle man with the
huge big bank brand markups,
the price of a stylish watch,
finally got affordable.
Imagine that exclamation point.
A watch with the department store quality
for a fraction of the price. Okay?
So if you want one of those
things, go to MVMT. Um,
MVMT watches.com/bar and they'll give
you 15% off your entire purchase.
MVMT watches.com/bar. All
right, stamps.com everybody
stamp a lamp has dotcom. This
is the last one. All right,
stamps.com everybody trips to the
post office are never convenient,
so why not get postage right from your
desk with stamps.com stamps.com even
gives you special postage discounts
you can't get at the post office,
including FirstClass priority mail
express international in Muah.
You'll never pay full price for postage
again. Here's how stamps.com works.
Using your own computer and printer.
Buy and print official US postage
for any letter or package.
Then handed to your mail Daniel Mail to
the mail man or drop it in a mailbox.
It's that easy. No wonder over
600,000 small businesses already used.
stamps.com I use Dan. Stop calm
anytime. I have my posters.
When I'm whoring myself out.
After my shows, I sent him out.
I'm a moron if I can figure out how
to use his shit. So can you right now,
sign up for stamps.com using my last
name [inaudible] for this special offer,
four week trial plus $110 bonus
offer that includes a postit,
including postage and a digital scale.
Don't wait.
Get started with stamps.com today. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbirthburthatstamps.com
calm
enter burr. All righty. That had add that.
But then at dad, that'll take care of
that fucking mall to death by a tiger.
You know, fucking, you know,
attacked by a bear in the wilderness
as you're walking around with fucking
20 children that aren't yours.
I mean,
that sounds like an episode of law and
order. Boop, boop, boop, boop. Ooh.
Like what the fuck were you doing out with
the, with all of those kids? I found a,
um,
all right.
My gym got delayed by some bullshit,
you know,
not some bullshit, just some shit. And I'm
just like, now do it. Right. They're like,
we can do it this way or we can do it the
right way. I might do it the right way.
So,
um,
I have not been working out and I've been
eating like shit because I'm just like,
well, the second the gyms there, I'm going
to fucking go like a madman. But, uh,
Jim is taking longer than I
thought and uh, you know, oh,
Billy started it looked
like some overcooked mashed
potatoes and I'm not liking,
I'm not liking it one bit. Um, all
right, let's, let's do some reads here.
Let's do some reads. Oh, you know what,
I didn't talk about any of the
other playoff series. Did I?
I think you of the other NHL once the,
uh,
the filthy flyers it down to Oh to the
Washington capitals and uh, they are,
they are the perennial favorites to
the, uh, the eastern conference. Uh,
c real quick.
Tampa Bay lightning leads Detroit
to one Detroit one the last one.
They fucking red backs up against
the ropes. Big victory there.
Islanders over Florida,
two games to one.
Nashville's up two games to none of a
fucking Anaheim. Oh, this sucks. Bad.
Fucking the kings and the ducks
are going to get knocked out.
No playoff hockey for oh
fucking freckles out here.
Dallas is up two games to none.
Um,
I'm completely in the dark with all of
this bullshit cause I'm going to be in a
writer's room. I'm in, in the
writer's room for the next olds,
18 weeks total to write the uh, the
second season. And uh, believe it or not,
I'm actually finding that I
love being in the writer's room.
I thought it was something that I was
not going to enjoy because of the freedom
that it has as a comedian,
but it turns out I really like writing
scripts and I like writing dialogue and
all of that Shit and uh,
we're having a great time and I think
you guys hopefully are going to enjoy it.
So now your next question should be built.
How many episodes did they give you?
A 10 10 episodes for season two.
And when is it going to be at?
When is it going to come out?
Probably this time next year. It's
animation. That's how long it takes.
Um, I think they're saying may of next
year is when it comes out, unfortunately.
But uh, that's how it works. But
it's going to be worth the wait.
But I hope that now that we're kind
of going, that once we do this,
when we can immediately go into season
three, I don't know how it fucking works.
I guess that wouldn't make sense.
They got to see how many
people watch season two.
I Dunno.
I think by the time we finished
season five, I'll be 60.
That's what I'm guessing.
All right, let's do some questions
here for the week. Uh, come to Prague,
come to Prague. Um, I'd like to go cry.
Hey Billy wing nut. Just so you know,
we started using your
songs at circle time.
Circle time is every morning
at nine 15 after yoga.
Is it his songs and words
and learning English.
All the kids singing our check
kids please come to Prague.
The fuck is circle time
sounds oddly filthy.
Uh,
circle time.
Prague,
Prague, link, linguistics circle homepage,
the fuck. And I didn't know what
that means. I can't tell you this.
So I've stuck with the French have 51
fucking days and now it's starting to just
be in my head. I still can't speak it.
Well, if somebody is speaking it, I,
I pick out a few words, but like reading
it, I'm crushing it. Reading, I read,
I transcribed this whole fucking article
about the pope saying that, you know,
as much as the Catholic church
has been against condoms,
there are certain instances,
you know, that they don't
think it's bad to use them.
Um, you know, especially preventing, um,
the spread of HIV, aids,
whatever, you know, and they
said something about, you know,
unprotected sex with male prostitutes.
I think that that's what it said.
I couldn't tell if it was that
or men going to prostitutes.
I couldn't quite get the translation.
So, uh, I'm sticking with it. And, um,
cause on dual lingo to a fee,
if you do a hundred days in a row,
they give you a couple of trinkets,
whatever the fuck that means. So I'm,
I'm over the hump of Brian
Downhill now. And, um,
I dunno,
I just think I'm really doing it.
Not only did I want to learn how to do it,
but I just think it's funny.
If someone is dumb as me
becomes completely fluent in
French and then that gives
me the opportunity to go to France or
go to Montreal and act like the dumb
American and then listen to what they're
saying about me and then just fucking
hit him over the head with some fucking,
I can't say perfect French,
but like fluent French
just watched their fucking,
the little fucking pocket squares
get all fucking in a bunch.
That's why I'm doing it. I'm
doing it. I was going to take,
I don't know how long
it's going to take me,
just I want to have that moment just
once in my life or I could just sit there
and have somebody trashing
me in a different language
and they don't know that I
can hear everything.
I understand everything that they're
saying just so I can look at him and then
fucking come back and I'm like, dude,
DVD. But did they basically saying like,
I know exactly what the fuck did you
said? Right. I'm all right. Sorry.
Most people want to learn it so they
can communicate. Not me, not me.
I want to do it so I can have an
argument on the other side of the world.
What does that say about me?
All right. A cooking question.
Do your Billy the butter basting bitch.
Ah,
that was
a good, oh, say there you go.
There you go. Something original.
I liked that. Made fun of my cooking.
You kept the alliteration going.
You called me a bitch in
the it. I give that one four
stars. Four stars. All right.
Uh, anyways, uh, I am a huge
fan and I blah, blah, blah,
Blah Blah and Yada, Yada, Yada.
My question is, thank you for blowing
through all that. My question is,
you used to talk about
cooking all of the time,
but now you're rarely do what gives.
Did you stop cooking? Uh, if not,
what have you made lately?
Please make more cooking videos.
Like the pie crust one you made. I need
something new to choke off too. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Um, yeah,
I haven't been cooking. I've, um,
when I,
uh,
when we write these episodes for Apis
for family, I'm so fucking relieved.
I can finally talk about this shit. Um,
it consumes my life. I mean, I basically,
I go in at 10 30 every morning. There's
usually some other bullshit I have to do.
So I'm usually there by 10 in the morning
and then we fucking write all day till
about seven. And by the end
of it, I just come home.
I Pour Scotch, I stare at
the wall, I fall asleep,
my dog wakes me up at seven.
I take her for a walk,
I come home,
I have breakfast,
I try to bang out a podcast and
maybe do a little bit of French,
and then I go right back to
work. So I don't have time
to fucking do anything. Um,
you know, I should do, I should start
using blue apron. You know, Michelle,
Mark Marin, he actually
cooked a meal on it. It looked
fucking delicious. Um, but I,
uh, I should really start doing
something like that because I have,
I been eating like a sort of in
a good way and sort of bad way.
I had the best mother fucking Burger
I've ever had in Los Angeles and that is
saying something and if you'd like to
know where to go the next time you see me
when you're in Los Angeles, if you ask
me, I will tell you where the places,
but I'm not saying it on a podcast because
I hate when Anthony Bordain does that
and this is cool fucking spot. And
then he makes it, he makes it fucking,
you know,
every Tom,
Dick and Harry's got to go out there
and then it comes under new management.
The whole thing gets fucked up.
So,
or even if I'm out on the
road from on the road,
just yell it out during my shelf. You,
Hey, Barb is flawed. You are now like,
you know, you bought a
ticket, I'll tell you.
Then he listened to this podcast for free.
You don't get the information.
Oh, is it delicious? The fries
were okay. The soda was, you know,
they had the Mexican fucking coke and
the fan to orange with the real sugar and
credible, credible tasting that's
west where this country is right now,
Coca Cola is made better in Mexico
than it is in the United States.
What does that say about us?
You know, and as Donald Trump,
Hillary Clinton or fucking Bernie Sanders
even approach that at any point during
the this, this campaign they might
have. Lord knows I'm not watching.
All right?
So I'm no where I last left.
I was trying to learn how to make
Gnocchi and I failed miserably.
And my own wife, the woman who's
supposed to love me unconditionally,
sickness and health and good times
and in bad. And when I made Gnocchi,
it was a bad time. And what did
she do? Did she stick by me?
Did she say it's okay and rub my
head? Nope. You know what she said?
She leaned over and she goes,
hey. And I was like, what?
She got right mayor and she goes,
you should make pasta anymore.
She said, you shouldn't make
pasta anymore. You know,
maybe she knows me well enough to know
that when somebody says something like
that to me, that just
makes me go, all right,
I'm going to fucking master this shit.
You know? I mean, it's not like, you know,
somebody says you shouldn't sing anymore.
Well, you should dance anymore. I mean,
I understand that. I mean, I fucking,
there's just certain things, but I mean,
cooking, it's just one of those things.
So you just do it. You'll learn.
He can learn how to do it. Like all
these fucking people on the food network,
they don't have any, they don't have any
talent. It's just, they just, you know,
they didn't have any friends
and they just fucking, you know,
they started off making cereal and then
they just kept progressing. I'm kidding.
I know it's an art form,
right? To fucking relax. Okay.
Put your apron back on and go fucking
make a souffle. All right. So, um, yeah,
so I'm kind of stuck on that. But the next
time I go to New York, I met somebody,
um, and met somebody. It's very special.
I met somebody in New York,
uh,
a chef at this Italian restaurant.
He told me, he's like the real deal,
like right off the boats and anytime
you come to New York he goes,
I'll show you how to make pasta
from scratch, blah blah blah blah,
because I took a pasta
making class and uh, uh,
they were supposed to then email a bunch
of shit to help you out and they never
had any follow through. And then I waited
too long to try it again. And I finally,
I kind of forgot some
of the tricks. So, um,
that's where I met with the cooking thing.
And,
and as far as making
like the cooking videos,
I did the pie crusting cause
that was another thing. I
just thought it was funny.
Someone like me knows how
to do something like that,
but like I can't cook better than
most of the people out there,
so I don't understand the
point of it. Um, maybe if I,
if I learn how to make Gnocchi,
I'll teach you guys how to do it,
but I'll have to do it for a long time
before I feel like confident enough to
make a video. Maybe if I fuck it up,
it'll be funny. I have no idea. All right,
let's, let's keep reading here,
shall we? Okay. All right. Garden.
Do we topsoil,
one of my favorite things you use to
talk about was your garden and your steps
towards getting off the grid.
My question is do you still have a garden
and are you still taking steps to get
off yourself off the grid?
Um,
I mean I have a lemon and a lime
tree so I'll never get scurvy.
MMM,
no,
I just,
the level of like commitment that that
takes and you have to have like a fucking
hen house and shit. You know, I don't,
I don't have time to become Mr. Green
jeans and then what do I have to have a
hen house guy?
I have to have the chicken guy.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
It's like as you accumulate shit,
then you have to get the something guy,
right.
Okay.
Yeah. You buy a fucking house. She
immediately, you'd have a plumber,
you got to have a fucking electrician,
you know, you've got to have a,
basically a handyman. Okay. Then what?
Then you have a garden and you got to
have a fucking landscape or gardening guy
because you're too busy doing whatever
you do for a fucking crook, a living.
You get a pool, you need the pool
guy, you know, you get a dog,
you got the fucking dog guy,
the vet guy, all of that shit.
It's just more money flying out
of your fucking wallet. And, um,
I am very envious of people that have
their own gardens and that type of shit.
But, uh, I, you know, I have
my little piece of fucking
La out here, which is not much.
We all live on top of each.
I'm literally looking out my window right
now and I see the roof of the person's
house next to me and that's just
basically how it works, you know?
And I look out the back,
I look out my back window and
I see the apartment buildings,
the back of the apartment
buildings from the street over.
It's really not a place to plant some
turnips, although I wish there was.
And I don't think that could really get
away with like having fucking chickens
and shit. Some rooster crowing
every morning cause uh,
the noise ordinance is noise is not
supposed to leave your property.
Although most people the second
they turn on their stereo,
they break that fucking thing.
But um, I would love to do it.
I'd love to get solar panels and be
off the grid, but she really can't be,
still have to give them a
little bit of money. I forget.
I don't know how it works, but they
have some, so I know how it works.
The president makes 400 grand a year,
so he, they go, yeah listen, fuck,
oh he want the second term, make this
a law. We should make it a lot. Right.
Next thing you know,
it's a lot cause there's people
live in the middle of nowhere.
The electric company finds
him and then they like,
they show him and like you have to
give us money every month, which is,
I just don't understand how that is legal
that goes around so many things that
this country is allegedly about.
Someone would force you.
I understand taxes. So like,
yeah dude, you want to live here?
You've got to kick in for the puddles.
I get that.
But you have to buy power from
this fucking noise. Don't fuck off.
But that's not how it works. It's not how
it works. If you guys know how to do it,
if you how to get off the grid,
by all mean not because I
want to be off the grid. No,
cause I give a fuck that I give
money to the power companies. I just,
you know when the shit hits the fan,
I would like to be that beacon of light
that all the zombies run too. Right?
He's still got a flat screen.
Um, alright. Girlfriends. Wait.
Oh Jesus. Here we go. Dear Bill,
I'm a 21 year old guy and my
girlfriend is 20 we've been taped.
We've been talking for about six months
now and we just recently decided to make
it official. Now here's the part where
I need your expert advice. Oh Jesus.
How should I go about telling her?
I think she needs to lose weight.
She's not a fat ass by no means, but
she could lose a few pounds. Now.
I sound now I sound like an ass.
I know. I sound like an Asshole,
I think is what he's supposed to say.
Okay.
Yeah,
I know I sound like an asshole,
but I care about her and want to see her
be more confident. Thanks for the help.
I enjoyed the show in Long Beach.
Um,
okay.
How do you say she could lose
it there? There is no way. Uh,
what I would do is I would
get yourself in great shape.
Okay.
And start getting her into hiking
with you and like, uh, you know,
but you can't make somebody work out.
You can't make somebody get in shape.
They either want to do it or they don't.
And um,
you know, that's like a
major, major, major fucking
okay.
You know, you tell telling
a woman she needs to lose a
few pounds, just like that.
That's, that's the female equivalent
of them saying to you like, you know,
your Dick could be a little bit
beggar.
It's devastating.
Um,
yeah,
I wouldn't say it to her, but uh, you
know, you also got to think, you know,
at 20 if they could lose,
if they're already getting out of
shape at 20 years of age, you know,
okay,
then what? Then they have a couple of
kids that going to be a fucking house.
I mean,
that's just something you get,
you gotta be honest about if someone
doesn't take care of themselves,
you know,
and this works both ways too late ladies.
Like if you're with some guy and he's in
his twenties and he's sitting there and
he's already getting Mantech,
it's, it's not going to get better.
And you got to sit there in,
in and really just be like,
how much do I love this person?
Because I'm going to watch them
slowly eat themselves to death.
Cause that's what you're
doing. And unfortunately, um,
you chicken start coming home
to roost in your forties,
whatever the fuck you did,
whenever you will start to go off the
rails at 16 or 17 with drinking, drugging,
eating or whatever,
right around when you get to your
forties is when the first like,
like God damn that happened to him.
I thought that was some old man shit.
And you're like,
oh wait,
we're in our forties because you'll
still feel like you're in your 20 self.
MMM.
I Dunno. I would go a positive route. I
would just tell her how I would tell her,
uh, oh, we tell her how good she looked
at me. That's just fucking, I don't,
there's no way to do it that that is,
there's no,
that's a fortress in, there's no
door in. You know what I mean?
There's no door in on that one. You just
have to just, if you're going to say it,
if he just fucking say it,
then you're really risking
hurting her really bad.
You know what I mean? Um, any
who wants to do you don't,
you don't want to fucking do that.
You know?
I wonder if women ever
feel that way about guys.
Like if there's anything like
this, like, you know what?
You just can't say that to a guy
because that will hurt them too much.
Do they ever think shit like that?
I think shit like that with women.
There's just certain things you just,
you just don't fucking say like,
what does it all I'm going to do is hurt
her in ruiner for the next person when
she fucking eventually comes
to her senses and dumps me. Um,
and then you'll be that, you know
what this guy said to me one time,
yeah,
we were going into a weapon
and I ordered a double cheeseburger.
Any interrupted? He said, no, no, no.
She wants to single,
you know,
being that guy.
Um, no, I don't know. I don't know what
to tell you. I can't tell you this though.
I feel like when you are,
you know,
aside from just all wanting it to
yourself to try to stay in shape,
when you were in a
relationship with someone,
did just fucking let yourself
go and just become a fat fuck.
And you know,
do you just not have the consideration
that somebody is sort of obligated to
have sex with you to just try and remotely
keep yourself looking halfway decent?
It's really a selfish fucking thing,
you know?
But we live in the age of,
um,
a lot of times the victim is,
is the,
is not as is considered
like the antagonizer. Yeah.
You know what I mean?
I would never do that to me.
I wouldn't ever just fucking
put on a hundred fucking pounds,
just come waddling into the
fucking bedroom, you know,
rollover on top of her since she
would be completely grossed out.
And every woman listening to this probably
just went picture that me a hundred
pounds heavier, naked,
sweating on my upper lip.
Crawling into fucking bed. Yeah, exactly.
Isn't that disgusting? Well, that,
that's a two way street sweetheart.
You know,
we don't want to see you come fucking
waddling in under the room. You know,
your hips taken out the fucking door
jam. You know what I mean? It's just,
it's not a, it's not
fair to you, the person,
you know,
when you really look at it and nobody
understands that more than gay guys.
I would say that gay guys have the most
respect for the fact that someone's
going to hook up with them.
You know what I mean?
I wonder if that pound for pound in the
best fucking shape than anybody else or
is it because they're trying to
attract guys and they know guys are,
I can't even say that shallow cause they
always say that guy's a shallow when it
comes to that. We are, but like you
fucking hold up something shiny.
A woman's like, I didn't want that.
You know, they're just as bad. Right.
Oh Christ. I'm all over the map. All
right. On trial for a joke. All right,
Bill,
did you hear about the entertainer who
might get prosecuted for his poem that
trashed ahead of State?
Oh, what country? Uh,
they're calling him a comic, but I
think maybe Europe's version of a comic,
not the traditional standup ball. Depends
on where you go in Europe. Europe is a,
uh, you know, it's not the
biggest continent, but that's all.
It's a long fucking trip
from Paris over to Moscow.
I think Moscow was technically
still in Europe, isn't,
I know the west coast of Russia is now,
he sucked getting into the eastern
Europe and you know, I mean they,
they still had vampires out there.
So you can only imagine how that would
affect the artist standup comedy.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
All right.
And Angela Merkel gave the go ahead to
the Turkish prime minister to make an
inquiry,
which basically means put on trial
all because of a stupid poem.
Thoughts. I hate when people
do that. Thoughts. Hmm.
Talk about that. Um, yeah,
it lists a bunch of countries that are
just getting their first taste of standup
comic. It's comedy and they are going
through their Lenny Bruce years.
Um, which is what happens that happened.
Lenny Bruce, he was put on trial,
he was arrested for obscenity
and all of that type of stuff.
This is what happens.
And once the government realizes that
it's just jokes and that a standup comic
doing an hour on jokes is not going to
cause a revolution and that they can
relax and continue to fuck over their
own countrymen and sleep well at night
doing it, then they usually
ease up on it. And, uh,
people are allowed to, you
know, do stand up comedy.
Like what's funny now is what's happening
is there's this new, you know, sort of,
I dunno what you would call it,
Lenny Bruce time,
but it's just more through
people in the crowd. Dope.
But it's not the government anymore,
so it's really no big deal. It's just,
you know, people with agendas and
websites and shit like that, you know,
clickbait, clickbait
people. Right. All right.
Boyfriend wants to have
sex with other girls. Um,
I wonder if there's a way to basically
support that person. Angela Merkel,
can I help pay for the lawyer kick in,
you know, all the comics around the world.
Take fucking throw 20 bucks at it and uh,
they could tie it up in the
Turkish courts. Can that
happen? I don't fucking know.
Oh, you know what, I'm
going to look that up.
I'm glad you brought that to my attention.
I know that there was some
somebody in in Canada,
the same thing happen and it's one of
those things where it's like you want to
talk about it,
but you also don't want to feed
that fucking beast and give all,
all types of a notoriety.
But then you're also going,
well that's a fellow comic
going through that Shit.
There's gotta be a way in a stealth
way to hopefully put that fire up.
Um, you know, when I was in India, the
podcast I did, the guys over there,
they were going through some
shit because they had a row,
they did a roast and everything was fine.
Everybody laughed and then they
put it up on youtube and you know,
there's like 40 million
different religions there
and somebody complained and
you know,
they were in a, definitely a, a, what's
the word I should use? They were in a,
they weren't a situation over there
when I, you know, which is hilarious.
Then a pluck of walking down
the street with them. Yeah.
Yeah.
Like, how am I going to get fucking
arrested because I'm with you guys.
You know what's fucked up? I only spent
24 hours in India and I already miss it.
I really want to go back.
I had such a good time in the 24 hours
despite the fact I had to get a piece of
paper to leave, which was
really fucking creepy. But um,
okay.
And that was weird and I,
I didn't,
I didn't know what I was thought I
was going to think when I went there,
but I felt an odd connection
when I went there. Um,
which is one of the coolest things
when you travel. Like when you,
you go every place you go to,
it's going to be great when
you actually go to a place.
Like why is this fucking place
feeling like, uh, like feeling like,
oh like a home.
Like I relate to these people more so
than a lot of countries I've been to.
I was over there going like,
God,
that guy reminds me of rich foss maybe
cause I hung out with a bunch of comics.
I had no idea. Anyways, boyfriend
wants to have sex with other girls.
Hi Bill. Hi Bill. Um,
my boyfriend and I had been
together for over two years.
Recently we had broken up for
a little less than a month,
but we started talking again.
We broke up because of though he
loves me and wants to be with me.
[inaudible] he still wants
to have sex with other girls.
Our sex life isn't a problem
because we fuck on a daily basis.
Most of the twice a day she
was supposed to write time.
She was supposed to write time
most of the time, twice a day.
And he always says on the best
people ever slash we'll have,
he also believes that there is a very
slim possibility that there might be
something better for him and then he
wants to experience other people before
possibly spending the rest of his
life with me. He's 25 years old,
so he is pretty scared about staying
with one person for the rest of his life.
We are both not ready for marriage
or that type of relationship,
but I feel that ending a two and a half
year relationship over his urges isn't
the right thing. Especially since he
still loves me and wants to be with me.
He's pretty unhappy,
but he knows that being with other people
won't help because he will feel the
exact same way as he does.
Now. He tells me that they,
I am amazing and beautiful and he
wants to have a perfect relationship,
so I don't understand why he wants to
leave that for something that is most
likely going to be shittier.
I can't go through another breakup
with him because it was horrible. Uh,
while we were broken up, he did have sex
with one girl and talk multiple girls,
but he didn't feel any better and he was
still unhappy without me, please help.
I don't know what to do and maybe this
can help them as well. Thanks a bunch.
Ah, well first of all, I'm not a fucking
relationship expert, but a, first of all,
I've got to give him Kudos
for just being honest,
saying that this is what I want to do.
Um,
well I'll talk to you cause he, you, he
didn't write it. So I would just say that,
um,
unfortunately this is
where he is at 25 and um,
you are not.
So if he wants to fucking go out and
do whatever the fuck he wants to do,
you know, let them and then I think
you should get on with your life.
But I don't think it's healthy
for you to have him keep,
keep calling you during this time when
he's out there fucking other people but
still fucking with your emotions.
So I think you let them go and let them
go do whatever the fuck he wants to do
and, but there's, you don't
have any contact with them. Um,
that might be a guy thing where you,
you need some sort of closure,
Assam Shit and gradually talk and then
talk less and less and less. I don't know.
I'm a fucking psycho when it comes to
that shit. So that's what I would do.
Um,
I would say at this point,
what he's doing is he's trying
to do what's right for him.
So you have to do what's right for you.
Um,
he's putting himself
first and his wants first,
so you should do the same
thing and there's nothing
wrong with what he's doing.
Um,
he could have fucking lied and said that
he didn't have urges and then gone and
fucked around and you know,
I don't,
no matter what, he was going to end up
hurting yet, but he did it. He did it.
He did it the right way.
He told you he broke up with you and um,
okay.
Yeah,
he's got to go figure some shit out.
But I don't think he needs to be calling
you up and talking to you after a month
and getting your heart going
again and giving you hope.
But I don't know where they want
to do, but I do love you. But
yeah, go fuck yourself with your
wishy washy shit. All right. You know.
Okay.
You're beautiful. You're young. You got
your whole life ahead of Ya. You know,
fuck them. Just fucking, I dunno.
Why don't you have a little you time
over the next two to three months,
see where you're at. Make a little list,
figuring out what you want out of life.
You know, who knows, who
knows? Maybe he'll come back
to you and be like, you know,
and it sucked and you want to take
them back. Maybe you won't, but a,
I think you need to focus on
yourself and not him. That's a,
that's what I would do. Um, cause
you didn't pull the trigger. He did.
So there's no guilt on your end,
but um,
it's a shitty thing to do to do that to
somebody and then come back like a month
later and can drag you through
that hell all over again,
but then not get back with you and make
some sort of a commitment to just go
back and be like,
Ooh, you know, hooked up with
one person. I still miss you.
You know, cause then you're going to
be like, yeah. So what does that mean?
Does that mean he loves me? And you got
to sit there playing that mental tennis,
fuck all that. Fuck all that. Yeah.
Right. They're wishy washy. We'll see ya.
Just tell him what you need. You need,
yeah, 100% commitment. That's it.
You're either in it or you're out of it.
I respect you.
The fact that you're honest,
but you know,
I know I don't need you fucking hemming
and hawing every fucking four weeks
dragging me back down to that emotional
pit. I'm done. Get on with your life.
That's what I would do, you
know, as fucking jackass.
And then the second you're
getting on with your life,
he won't want to lose you and then he'll
come back and just so we won't lose one
of those fucking guys.
That's what I'm thinking. Um,
okay.
Yeah, I would, I would get on with
your life. That's what I would do.
I hope that's good advice.
I had no idea. All right,
that's the podcast for this week.
Thank you guys for listening and thank
you to everybody from the bottom of my
hat who watched the first
season of f is for family. Uh,
we're really going to try to outdo what
we did in the first season and, uh,
try and make them as funny as possible.
All right. That's it. Go fuck yourselves.
And I'll check an audio on Thursday.
See Him.