Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
August 20th, 2012. How's it going out?
I can't fucking hear myself. I don't
know what the fuck happened to my, uh,
my other, my regular,
my regular headphones,
which suck by the way because
they flake all over my ears.
What does that mean bill? I don't know.
A little pieces of plastic. You know,
like they don't have the
space age technology.
Whenever somebody uses that expression,
you know,
they have no idea what they're talking.
This is just coming from the gut.
Like they don't have the fucking
space age technology to make a set of
headphones that, that will
just last forever. You know,
can't do that canyon. Well we
might get lasts forever. Oh,
they're never going to come
back and buy another one. Dan,
what are we going to do? I don't know.
Go plant some beats. You fucking cunt.
Do you feel how fucking hot the
sun is lately? Have you felt it?
You know, do you remember it ever being
is fucking hot as it is now? Like,
literally God has a magnifying glass right
up on the crown of your head. Granted,
part of it could be because
my hair's done and out,
but I choose not to
address that this week.
You know the God damn
hole in the ozone layer.
Can you make fucking headphones
last a little bit longer? You know,
so now what I'm supposed to
throw out these other ones,
these flaky ones that I can't
even fucking fine. Right? I love,
I yo put it in the trash,
put it in the fucking trash like,
like it's still not going to end up
outside somewhere. It is outside.
We just have it over here in this
contained area. You know what?
I'm not going to be able to tell whether
any of this is funny cause I can't hear
myself. I'm like a singer right
now. You know, turn up the monitors.
Oops,
I did it again as shaped my pathy.
Um, yeah, so I got to go
out and go buy another,
another fucking pair of headphones.
I'm one of those crabby old fucking
people who I, when I buy something,
I use it until it's fucking,
it becomes literally on a different
matter, you know what I mean?
Starts dissolving into a, a
powder. Is that a different matter?
All you egg heads out there, we'll
technically a powder is still a solid,
it's just did a more granulated form.
Thank you.
Never fucking got your Dick sucked.
Why don't you go back with the lab coat
and have a nice fucking hand job with
yourself and a pipe in it again
later when I say something stupid.
Um, I'm a little wound up
this morning. I'm excited.
An older, wiser bill burr, wiser than
he was last week. I'm finally back, uh,
back here in Los Angeles, Los Angeles,
you know, which is always, you know,
kind of a creepy place to come to once
you've been on the east coast and you sit
in there looking at all the green trees
and all the ponds and all the lush land
back there. And then I fly across
the fucking country, as I always say,
watching the country slowly die,
right? Slowly getting fucking,
you know, geographical chemotherapy. Um,
it's usually to be a big Bandanna tied
right over fucking Arizona in southern
California. Oh, that's good. Beth.
A little cancer joke in there with your
fucking musings about our topography,
topography. Um, but I got to admit,
I'm actually excited to be
on this side of the country.
I think I have a better
chance of surviving whatever
the fuck is going to happen
to this planet.
Believe it or not,
in this overpopulated city that
technically has no water supply.
I have a better fucking chance.
Why you ask? I'll tell you why.
Because I read a fucking article. I
didn't read it. Who's kidding? Who?
I glazed over it and it
was so fucking depressing.
It scared the fucking shit out of me.
But as far as I can tell,
New York City is going to look
like Venice and about three years.
That's what I'm guessing. You
know, it's going underwater.
That's what I think.
So if you're on the third floor or lower,
you might want to consider
selling your apartment now. Um,
they've just do an all this shit
talking about how, you know,
the glaciers are melting
at a much quicker rate.
Len scientists first feared,
look at this picture from July.
Now look at this one.
You know, I have no idea.
You know what's funny is I have no
idea if the pictures are fucking real.
You know, they're like these, uh, these
pictures that show like, you know,
red and white,
white obviously being the glacier red
being now like fucking the sunburn,
shoulders of a red head or some shit.
Right?
So it's basically scaring
the shit out of me.
And then I actually found
comfort in something. Well,
they were saying that scientists,
you know,
not so much shit has melted in Antarctica.
They're actually saying that,
um, this is even being recorded.
I can't even fucking hear myself.
Uh,
what's the solution bill?
Should you turn it up a little bit?
Maybe a little bit halfway through
it. Why not now? Look at it now.
It just went through the fucking roof
and I still can't hear myself anyways.
Scientists or the writer who wrote the
article, maybe they just made it up.
I have no fucking idea.
Basically said that,
uh, they discovered, you
know that back in the day,
aunt Artica was aunt Artica
bill at Arctica, aunt Artica,
who gives a fuck,
you know,
God damn place with all this fucking
penguins sitting there pushing their
fucking, except who fucking went
and saw that march of the penguins.
Why don't you just call it, I want to
cry for the final half hour. You know,
that's what every nature show is.
Let's show you how fucking cute they are.
And now we're going to show
you what we're doing to them.
And now you sit there with this
hopeless, sad fucking feeling, right?
And then what if you'd like to donate,
give the flak and save the penguins feet,
right? Dotcom. And then what do you do?
You go over to your checkbook, you know,
and you pull out another check
and you write, you write it out,
and then you grab a fucking
envelope and you grabbed a stamp.
You do all that bullshit. Or you print
out a stamp if fuse and stamps.com oh,
what a whore. Um, right. And you mail
it off thinking you did a good thing,
but what did you do? He just used a
whole bunch of paper. Yeah. You know?
Right.
Because you do that enough people do that.
They got to cut down another tree,
right?
Next thing you know that little
fucking penguins got nothing to center
underneath.
You don't want to,
Jax is a little fucking penguin dick to
make another egg. And then how it works.
Aren't they like asexual that they fucking
Jack often with their little flipper
into the other flipper.
And then do like a pap smear fucking uh,
sort of a George Gervin lay up
to their own fucking crotch area.
George Gervin the iceman that actually
made sense. Penguins ice, right?
I go fuck yourself.
Anyways,
so, um, this part is it made
up, they actually said that,
that the fucking and article that
the fucking Antarctica, okay.
You people who are, uh,
scientists out there, Jesus
belt. Just say what they said.
Just say what? The Guy said that they
said that you now believe. Um, he said,
uh,
oh Geez,
I can stop talking to her
cell phone than Antarctica.
People punching the dashboard right now.
Spit it out.
And Arnica used to be a tropical
forest. All right. Nine. Oh,
a lot of rednecks went.
How
born to the fucking
swamps running over vapor.
Well, I think their tails is so
flat. They used me round to me.
My truck went in that
crick. Hey, no, not likely.
And driving over some hairy little
fucker. I love it. Raccoons.
These just something about him.
Raccoons, possums, all of them.
They just got this look on their face
that just says, shoot me. You know,
I'm just going with my instincts. I'm
out in nature and I'm just going with it.
I'm seeing these little fuckers to staring
at me. I got my headlights out them.
They just keep fucking
looking at you don't get shot
stuff fucking looking at me.
That's how I look at it.
Um,
this is what I believe with
that information that that
guy said that the other
guy said that know what
they're talking about. So I,
I think that the global war,
I can't believe I'm actually trying
to attempt to discuss this subject.
I think global warming is actually
natural, but we are hastening it.
We're just making it way fucking quicker.
We have it on forward. You're like,
you fast forward through commercials.
That's what we're doing.
And we're doing that towards
our, uh, our own fucking demise,
which I think is going to be tremendous.
You know, and then we'll die.
And then maybe all this shit that,
you know,
when they put a microscope
up to your skin,
all that little shit there that's
crawling all over you. Maybe.
Maybe that's the next thing that's
going to build a skyscraper.
Name it after themselves and have people
write a whole fucking nice version of
their life because they're afraid that
there actually is some old man in the sky
that's going to fucking judge
them when they die. You know,
if you could write your own little thing,
your own little ditty about your life,
how would you sum yourself up?
I love people that kind of know
they were a Douche, you know,
although he didn't always right
there, you know, like, okay,
I know I'm kind of going to hell in a way.
Speaking of which, I started
reading this book, sins of the,
it's a book I wanted to read for a long
time. It was about not Joe Kennedy.
And I figured what better time to start
reading that book while I was taking an
ultra white vacation on
the island of Nantucket,
considering you get on the high speed
ferry, run over a couple of seals,
um, right out of Hyannis port,
home of the Kennedy compound,
you know, and for so
long, what did they say?
They call it Camelot there the first
fucking Royal Lee family and all that
bullshit. Right. But I always heard,
you know that what's his face?
Joe Kennedy was, you know, Goddamn rum
runner, you know, he made all this money,
insider trading and all this
fucking bullshit. Right?
So I wanna I want to read about
it. I want to, I want to see,
I want to hear the other side.
Now that I've read the fluff about all
the sacrifices he made for this country
and all his kids die in,
you know,
in war and in public servants getting
assassinated and fucking going skiing
while trying to play
football. Right. I was like,
I got to check this shit out and I
read it. You know, I've got the book.
I thought it was going to be a great book.
That book is,
it's like a fucking,
I feel like some soccer mom reading
some juicy like summer novel.
Like I should be digging my toes in the
sand with my knees up to my chest as I
read it.
It's just such a one sided and it's so,
so much fucking hearsay. Oh, did he?
Did he do this for this reason?
Or maybe he did it because he was a cunt.
First of all, the guy made a fuck
load of money. All right, let's,
let's get down to brass tacks to guy is
one of the weirdest looking human beings
I've ever seen in my life.
I used to think all the Kennedys had
that same look about them cause they sort
of did a Rothchild thing
where they kind of,
they kind of fucked real close
to the farm, so to speak.
So they kind of had that [inaudible]
here comes my big fucking head over here.
Right?
He's a fucking weird looking dude.
I will definitely give you that.
But when he did his insider trading,
it wasn't illegal.
You know, the guy actually says in
the book that it wasn't illegal,
so he didn't do anything wrong.
You know, it was looked down upon,
it was considered a shady thing to do.
But the guy goes and then he has some
sort of quote of Joe Kennedy go cabal,
let's do this quick before they
make a law against it. It's like,
where did you get that fucking quote from?
I don't know.
So all I do is I'm just
skipping around the book.
I want to see how he reacted
when when Jack got whacked,
I wanted to see what happened
to their kid that you know,
they said was a mentally
challenged but maybe wasn't,
was just a pain in the ass and
they gave her a fucking love.
Bottomy it's really
just a sad fucking read.
I just jumped around it and now I'm
going to use it as a fucking paper weight
and I can't tell you how long
I wanted to read that book.
I know what you're thinking right now.
Bill,
where the fuck are you going with this?
I don't know.
I don't know where I'm going.
I can't fucking hear myself.
All right. For those of you who
did listen to my podcast last week,
I have a new stand up special called you.
People are all the same and
it's airing exclusively.
It's streaming,
whatever you could say on a Netflix
and I know what you're thinking.
Is it only on Netflix in
America or the United States?
No sir, ma'am. Transgendered person.
It's a hermaphrodites. It's
also on Canada. Netflix.
It's also on Ireland,
Netflix and Great Britain.
Netflix, which I'm really excited
about because I think I got,
I think I have a very, uh,
very, uh, user friendly,
special [inaudible] got a
little choked up there. Um,
I think people are gonna like it. When
you think about that. I'm actually,
I'm feeling good you guys. You guys wrote
so many nice things to be on Twitter,
which is a rarity to just get
a whole nice sea of niceness.
And I know a couple of cuts right now
just for the fuck of it going to write a
bad one, but I know what you're up to. Um,
so people ask me, they said,
hey, how can I regular guy,
regular old gal,
just salt of the earth person.
How can I get a hard copy version of that
hour of filth that you just put out on
Netflix? Um, this is the deal. Um,
the hard copy version,
the digital version,
whatever the fuck you want
to download it to your Ipod,
you're fucking a iPad. What? I don't
know what, whatever you people use,
I don't, I don't fucking
know anymore. Okay.
However you want or you want to go fucking
old school, I'll put it out on VHS.
You keep running your gaps.
Now I'm not doing that.
I'll put it out on DVD and all that stuff
and you will be able to get it at my
website. And my website only
build bird.com. That's it.
We've got a whole page set
up, but I just, you know,
it will be coming out in September.
Going to let it marinate for good six.
Let people go. Oh, I like it.
Where could I bucket by it? Right.
And then Bam, it's going
to be available. And uh,
the wonderful thing about this is,
uh,
I'm eliminating the middle man and
that way it can be fucking cheaper.
You know, I'm basically, I'm doing
what Radiohead did 10 years ago.
I'm doing what prince did. I'm
going to do that thing, you know,
and now it's gone into the whole
fucking comedy world with uh,
Louis C k Aziz and all those guys and
I being the hack that I am and I am
following right in line. Okay. Seems to
be working for everybody else. Why not me?
Um, so there you go. That's how
you're going to be able to get it.
You're just going to go
to my website and um,
as that day approaches when you can do it,
uh,
I will let you know and um,
I don't know what the prices are going
to be. It seems like it's going to be $5.
I want to be,
I want to have it be $5 and 1 cent
just to fucking piss people off,
you know,
sacrificing some sales just for people.
But this got to think he's 1 cent better
than everybody else. Um, so that's,
that's the answer to your questions.
People have been asking me. Um, all right.
And that is it. Back to the podcast.
If this podcast is even being recorded,
God knows I can't fucking hear myself.
Um,
speaking of stamps.com everybody,
come on.
Don't do this to me. Oh, I
hate this computer. I fucking,
what is the problem?
What is the fucking problem?
I did it right. Oh, what now?
You're going to freeze up on me?
You're going to freeze up on
when I need you most, right.
Right in the middle of the podcast.
So now what do I have to do?
I have to force fucking quit. I don't like
foursquare. That's a little too rapey,
isn't it? In a computer sense.
Forced quit. There you go.
I'm forcing you to quit.
Yeah, like an overbearing
father. Hey. You know,
one thing that I noticed
about myself asides, you know,
the obvious that I'm an extreme douchebag
is when I was down in Nantucket,
I really had to work on not hating rich
people just because they were rich,
you know? Oh, let me get this stupid
commercial out of the way here real quick.
Not a stupid commercial.
A a very important information.
Let me get this to you here.
I stamps.com everybody, um,
are you sick of going to the post office?
You know,
do you not like going to the post office?
Are you busy? Do you got stuff to do?
Do you want to get caught up on
your favorite show? But, oh snap,
I have to go to the post office.
Would it be great if you didn't
have to go to the post office yet.
You could get everything that you
could possibly want at the post office,
minus the attitudes right in your
own home or apartment Gazebo,
wherever you live.
Well,
with stamps.com it's easy to use to
do all of that and it's convenient.
You can buy and print official US postage
using your own computer and printer.
Get exact for any letter or
package whenever you need it.
24 seven you can stand there
naked with an English muffin,
just printing out stamps like a
counterfeiter if it was legal currency,
and then just hand your mail
to the mailman and he had done,
when I say you'll never have to go to
the post office again, I really mean it.
I use stamps.com that's how I send
out all my DVDs to all my shows.
I love it. They give you a little
scale. You feel like you're in business,
you feel successful.
You know all that gives you the scale.
I think they should give you a little
hat. So right now, use my last name.
[inaudible], B U R, r
for this special offer,
no risk trial plus $110 bonus offer that
includes the digital scale and up to
$55 in free postage. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the radio microphone at the
top of the homepage and type in burpee.
You are that stamps.com enter B U. R. R.
I endorse it. I approve of
this message. So anyways,
I'm down in, uh, I'm
down in Nantucket and uh,
with all family friends, extended family
and all that type of stuff. Nieces,
nephews, the whole nine
yards, drinking again.
Oh baby, I'm drinking again. You
know, I'm down there, boozing it up,
drinking some of that Cisco
Brewery, whale tail, Pale Ale,
whatever they got down there.
You know,
I got my little Nantucket Red Fuckin um,
I'm friends with the bankers shorts on.
I'm living the dream.
All right.
And I'm just sitting there walking
around and I'm looking at all these rich
fucking people and I just
find myself, I fucking
the level with which I was judging them,
which of course no one would give a shit.
You know what I mean? If I was judging,
uh, you know, a Ey,
ey with the fuck am I doing?
If I was judging like some
poor group of people like that,
I would be considered the
biggest douche ever. All right?
You don't all these poor people. Why?
Why are you judging in that way? Right?
But you, you, you did
he, why am I stuttering?
You're fucking judge rich people that way.
Everybody laughs. They all
think it's funny. You know,
I had to work the whole week.
It's like, why do I hate that guy?
How do I know he didn't get his money?
Legitimately?
Why am I immediately assuming that this
guy was a complete piece of fucking shit?
You know, you know what it is. I don't
like how rich people carry themselves.
People born into wealth.
They just have this,
like that time when I was in DC and that
little fucking six year old kid got up,
walked right up to the bark,
a client up on the stool and started
calling out to this adult behind the bar,
sir, sir, excuse me
sir, like the co I can,
I'll never be able to do the proper
read of that. The way this kid said it,
there was such a comfort in, in,
in summarizing this person over to come
and talk to them to do whatever the fuck
he needed them to do at six years old.
Um,
if fucking the shit, I mean, I was
just looking at in these,
these fucking which people they have
the creepiest looking God damn kids you
ever seen in your life.
Just creepy little fucking future bankers,
CEO looking kids, you
know, little blonde hair.
They already got those, those
Chubby fucking, you know,
all kids have chubby cheeks, but just
the way they look, that waspy pedigree.
Right.
Which is another thing I can get
away with. You know what I mean?
The waspy pedigree, everybody will laugh.
We can only gives a fuck about that.
You can trash waspy people up and down.
I can't be always with this, this,
this Jewish
blah blah. That's it. I
got to fucking apology.
Waspy totally gets a fucking open lane.
So anyways,
waspy fucking look upon them,
right with their fucking,
you know,
they look like little Winston Churchill's
like they still talk like little kids,
but they should be walking around and
right here Troy Howard was numbers number
rider. How did, it just did just look
like they're going to fucking get,
they're going to get some
great fucking job and they,
and they're going to steal from the
company and when they get caught,
they're not going to
get fucking prosecutor.
Just like these God bankers
just like all these rich cuts,
they just not gonna cause they're going
to have connections and Pete and he's
going to got to know shit about
people, whatever. And they just,
they just hook each other up the same way
at the level that I grew up.
You didn't rat out your friends.
They're doing the same
thing at their level,
except what they can do affects the
entire population as opposed to the level
that I came up with where,
you know,
maybe somebody's car that used to be
there isn't there anymore yet off.
That's insurance fraud, I guess that
hopes that hurts the group after a while,
doesn't it? I Dunno. So
that was basically, uh,
what I had to work at,
you know,
and they had this place down the
street called the summer house.
I was staying out in Wisconsin and uh,
it's absolutely fucking beautiful and uh,
I just couldn't get myself to go in there.
I want it to go in there.
I wanted to sit down and
have a fucking drink,
but every time I saw another person
going in with their fucking boat shoes
without any socks on,
like I felt like this,
this hatred coming up in me and I
justified it for like two, three days.
And I was just like, what the fuck is
wrong with me? You know, I bet you know
those people that they're probably just
like me or the people I hang out with in
that,
as I always say,
most of them are douchebags but there's
going to be like four or five people in
that are going to be really interesting.
I've totally time I flew on the plane,
right?
And I sat next to that guy who made a
ton of fucking money starting his own
credit credit card.
And then he parlayed that money
into buying cell phone towers.
The guy was fucking hilarious. He had
it lost it, had it all again, lost it.
And then now he was on top again. He had
this a, what the fuck are you gonna do?
Vibe self made man.
So I'm sitting there going,
they're not all like that,
but they all had that saved.
I def with their fucking feet. I
can't stand them. I really got issues.
Okay.
Cause here I am, I'm down there,
I'm vacation and to act and like,
oh but I'm the down to Earth Douche
bag with my salmon colored shorts on.
Fucking hypocrite. I Dunno. So anyways,
I ended up going out
fishing, uh, with my family.
We had a great time, didn't
catch shit, just catch blue
fish, didn't even catch us.
Striper did catch anything,
but you know,
it was still cool and we didn't take
more than that then we were going to eat.
So, uh, I didn't feel too
bad about that, but, uh,
I think I kind of got talked into
doing something really stupid.
The guy who had the boat actually had
a fucking shark cage and he's like,
you know, it's totally safe.
We take you about 15 miles out.
We chummed the water and you get in
this fucking cage and you know what,
Ah,
you have to all these years of doing bits
about how fucking stupid it is to swim
in the ocean and all that type of shit.
I'm going to do it next year.
I'm going to do it.
I almost said it costs an arm and a
leg as your fucking pun right there.
You're awful joke. But uh, it
does. It's really expensive,
but I want to see a fucking shark.
Okay.
You know, and I got that
white thing in me where I, uh,
that white person think where I
want to see the shark being a shark.
You know,
the same way.
I don't want to see a bear just
walking through the forest.
I want to throw something at it so it
gets up on its hind leg Ra and starts
doing that shit. Like it's about ready
to step into the squared circle. Right.
I think that that is uniquely
a white thing that we, we just,
we just want to see it animal looking
like it's going to kill us or we don't
feel like we, that we got the
full experience now. Okay.
Now can I not only not hear myself getting
hot as fuck in here and I don't even
know why. Oh bill private. Cause
you don't have the windows open. Um,
anyways,
what else do I have here?
What else do I have here on the dock
at a shit that I want to talk about?
Oh, as you can tell, I read rolling stone.
Here's another article I saw, by the way,
they have Rick Ross on
the, uh, on, on the cover.
I don't know much about the guy other
than he's the most confident fat person
I've ever seen in my
life for half a second.
I thought it was little Wayne and he just
went to like Wendy's for 20 days in a
row.
How much does the tattoo artists not
want to tattoo the underneath part of
fucking Rick Ross's man tits.
You know,
cause at some point you sitting there
with the surgical gloves and you got to
hold it up and actually feel the
fucking weight of it. Is Your fucking,
I wonder if he giggles. Um, I actually,
I started to read that article, but I,
I cannot,
I can't read articles about rappers at
that fuck who come with that vibe of look
of, Oh look at all the shit
that I have. It's the most,
you feel like you're
reading like a fucking,
I dunno what Jordan Marsh catalog.
That's all they are.
He said something.
He was standing on Jewish marble.
Is there a such thing as Jewish marble?
I have no fucking idea.
Is that somehow like a GM? I said kosher
if like some fucking Borshbelt joke.
Um, at one point and he goes
out to a fucking steakhouse.
They list everything that he
orders and how much it costs.
Okay.
Uh, it's unreal if you illiterate, if you,
honestly, if you have problems sleeping,
read that. And I'm not trashing
the writer. I just, I, I,
I'm on a fucking plane.
I'm trying to kill time and I couldn't
get through the fucking article. Oh,
do you smoke weed the whole time? Do
you have 50,000 fucking cars? I got it.
Yeah.
You know what they call that Nantucket?
They call that new money.
I never used to know what that
expression is. He's new money.
You know what old money does old
money acts like they don't have money.
You know what I mean?
They'd walk around and Salmon,
fucking colored pants and they call up
their financial advisor and then they
manipulate the market and
they make more fucking money.
And then all of a sudden they,
a prohibition comes along and they got to
hook up for Scotch. So what do they do?
They fucking do it. I really don't
have a prop while you know something,
I didn't get into how we,
uh,
I don't know who the fuck knows if
anything that they're saying about Joe
Kennedy's the truth. I want
it to be the truth. You know,
cause it makes you feel better
about yourself. That's what it is.
That's why you look at
rich people like that.
You have to look at them like they
did something fucking crooked.
Because if you don't,
it makes you feel like a loser.
His fucking yacht is bigger
than all the houses on my block,
you know?
Now if you give him the
benefit of the doubt,
then you just have to stand
there and just take that shit.
Or you can just say he's a crooked
son of a bitch. He's going to hell.
God loves me best.
Right.
And you could walk around with
your fucking nose in the air,
like you're better with your slightly
cheaper salmon colored fucking pants.
Okay.
I ain't know what the fuck
I'm talking about. So anyways,
so I'm not an operating that
whole fucking Rick Ross thing.
You know,
I don't know. I'm sure he's got good
music. I don't give a fuck. Okay.
How many different ways can you
say I have more shit than you do?
You know,
like he was bragging about eating
lobster bisque for breakfast.
That's what,
that's what new money does.
New money gets like fucking DVD.
Those DVD players in the head rest
when you drive in like a two seater.
Remember that Shit,
I got those best for the people behind me.
That's how much money I have.
I can actually waste it.
Rather than taking that money and,
and adding to my portfolio and be,
and,
and truly getting out of my
fucked up neighborhood. I'm
going to do that instead.
That's what new money does straight across
the board. Straight across the board.
You get a redneck, a bunch of money.
You know what's he going to do? Huh?
So you going to buy some gold?
Is he going to, you know,
try to invest it and
seeking to start a business.
Now he's gonna put another
three inches on that truck.
He's going to get some big fuck and motors
and he's going to fucking drive down
the fucking street. He's gonna
make us fucking engine waterproof,
have that goddamn chimney coming up the
side of it so you can go into the swamp
and right back and never
have to fucking stop.
That's my Apocalypto fucking truck
out there and he shit happens.
I'll drive over everybody. I'll just
keep going to, I get up North Pole,
make myself fucks.
NOCO that's what new money does,
right? Is that what they do?
I don't know what they do.
You know what I do with my money?
I just sit and stare at it.
I Dunno what to do with the
money that I have. I don't,
I have no fucking idea what to do with it.
Cause you know what would
wherever you invested,
this is the funny thing
about investing your money.
All of it involves you taking your money
and giving it to somebody else and then
going, all right, call you in a month.
It's the dumbest Shit I ever did, you
know, and the fucking stock market.
That's like getting in the mob. Once
you're in, you can't get out. Oh,
you can get out, you know?
But it's going to cost.
You got to cut your fucking Dick off.
Get your fucking shit back out again.
All right.
I think it's time for some more
advertising. This is great.
Hey, do you want to start your own
business? Do you want to make a will?
You want to do all of that stuff and
I have to pay a zillion dollars Bullis
before I get going.
You've probably already heard about
legal zoom.com but now I am telling you
about them so you got to check them out
because these guys are great. All right.
This is a way, this is legal,
zoom and eve voice. These,
these are my two things to get you
out of your cubicle. All right,
so pay attention,
coffee points
if you've got, if you've been
waiting for the perfect time,
start your dream business.
It's right now.
You can incorporate your business or form
an llc@legalzoom.com starting at just
$99 I paid 1500 you can do it for $99.
Why do I need to incorporate that way?
No one can sue you when,
whenever you did blows up in somebody's
face, you actually pay less taxes.
It's what smart people do.
Okay?
And I'm not smart so I can't explain it
beyond that. Um, and if you have a family,
uh, guess what? You need to make sure that
protected. I don't like that. Guess what?
Like I'm talking down to you
and if you have a family,
I'm sure you already realize you need
to make sure that they need to be
protected and you can protect your family
and assets with a legal zoom.com will
for just 69 bucks.
And the past 12 years,
over 2 million Americans have used legal
zoom for Llcs, wills, trust, trademarks,
and morph a,
they've saved hundreds,
even thousands of dollars versus
going to a traditional lawyers.
And I know what you
thinking. Well, I don't,
I need a traditional lawyer to help me
through all that stuff. Don't worry,
they even have attorney to
help you through. Um, all
the legal Mumbo jungle jumbo,
sorry,
legal zoom as online process guide,
you step by steps and you
get total customer support.
It couldn't be much easier.
Uh, Start Your Business and
protect your family@legalzoom.com.
You also get a special discount
from listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter bur bur are in the
referral box and check at checkout for
more savings.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm and self
help services are provided at your
direction. In other words, if you need
help, ask for it. Okay, so good luck.
I want to see who the first Monday
morning podcast listener is.
Who's going to use legal zoom because
they advertised here and now you're out of
your cubicle and that'd be a great,
that would be a great segment.
You know,
people talking about how they got
inspired by this filthy podcast and they
somehow got themselves out
of that fucking cubicle.
Um, anyways, so I know I'm
drinking water here. All right.
What else can I talk about here?
34 fucking minutes.
And you guys watching any preseason
football? Why not? What are you watching?
Baseball and the six teams that are
competitive. Um, well, speaking of which,
I was back in Boston and uh,
I try really hard to listen to that
sports talk radio. It's just fuck,
it's impossible.
Who listens to actually feel bad for the
on air personalities that they have to
sit there for four fucking hours.
Like,
like those legitimate sports talk
radio guys, not the smart ones who go,
all right, it's a sports talk radio
show. But we're going to talk,
we're going to bitch about our wives.
Uh,
we're going to fucking talk about how
we went golfing and we gambled and
so-and-so sucked. And I want all
that guy shit and smoke cigars.
And then if something interesting is going
on in sports, we'll bring it up, right?
Like Roger Clemens gets
acquitted, you know, by the way,
just cause he got acquitted, he got
acquitted, uh, of uh, lying under oath,
which is one of the most difficult
things to proof. Okay. So,
but if you think that that guy didn't
take a fucking something and stick at,
you know, where and all of a sudden
he's winning those shiny things,
you're out of your fucking mind. See how
he did that? So couldn't get sued. Uh,
that's just my opinion.
All right.
I actually have a number of people
that I'm watching as a sports fan.
You know,
I'm telling you what's his face?
Milky Cabrera.
I almost called Paul Versey
and gave him shit like, Hey,
you should've got rid of this guy.
All of a sudden he's coming on.
That is the telltale fucking,
I think now of, of of PDS.
It's, it's one, it's one of the,
it's basically as simple as this because
you don't get fucking gigantic anymore.
I think they got it down with
that little cream that'll solve.
They have like steroid lip, Bob, you
know, you just put it on your bottom.
Let me go [inaudible] and next thing,
next thing you know,
you're fucking running over people.
You turn in the corner and
you're hitting home runs, right.
Just pay attention to
people who were okay.
And then they started to taper off and
all of a sudden they're fucking great up
telling you,
okay,
that never happened when I was a kid.
Once you started tapering off, you have,
you were fucking done. I Dunno, maybe,
I'm sure there's always a couple
of examples. Oh, by the way,
one little fucking editor, a note
last week when I brought up the, um,
the spurs and the Houston Rockets,
I talk so fast,
it sounded like I was saying that those
were pile on teams. I wasn't saying that,
I wasn't saying that. I
realized that, you know,
you know that what's his face Olijahwaun
and they drafted and I obviously real,
if I certainly realize that Tim Duncan
was from their system because the Celtics
were in the lottery that year and
Tim Duncan would have been know,
he would have been great anyway,
but he was such a perfect Celtic
yet out fun of Bell Basketball,
boring as hell, kissing the ball off the
glass. Jesus Christ. Fucking Tommy Heisen.
Um, and David Robinson, I realized
that those were your guys.
So I w I was trying to say
that those teams I respect,
they weren't pile on teams, but
uh, you know, the NBA is a silver,
silver
bunch of little dream teams.
Um, what the fuck was,
okay. So I actually, I am,
and I'm not going to
say the person's name,
but it is a running back in the NFL
and his last name is the name of a bear.
And it also talks about
maybe a lady's muff. Um,
they go,
it's just somebody who I saw was,
you know, was the man in
college, was not the man in NFL.
And all of a sudden last year I'm watching
him. He's fucking running over people.
Rarely you learn how to run over people.
Four years into it, I'm not buying,
I'm not buying it. And the last sentence
he plays on the Seattle Seahawks,
that's just a misdirection.
Um,
you'd have to be a two year old enough
to figure it out. Um, all right.
And that's the deal.
I want to start taking fucking roids.
They make it up for us now. I'm,
I got a whole new bid on it too,
so I can't burn too much of this.
But it's about that synergetics
those fucking old roid it up.
Those guys they're on,
they're on.
That's human growth hormone that
those guys are on. You know,
they show him all sad but there
man ticks, tits ticks, man,
tits on this stomach and then the stomach
hanging on their fucking old man ball
bag. And then all of a sudden, like a
month later, that did look like an Adonis.
You know the ball bag looks
like a fucking speed bag again.
They'd read their bay, their wife
is over in the corner, right?
Just fucking squatting on a
tub of fucking, uh, Ben Gay.
Cause he just tore it up
like it was 1926 again,
I want to know why those fucking people
aren't going to get brought before a
grand jury for cheating.
Okay.
You're going to bring Clemons out there.
Clemens in his big old butt,
right?
You're going to bring him out there and
question all of the 87 cy young award.
See One past the age of 50.
What about these fucking old guys?
All of a sudden they're old fucking heads
in a young body is going to go down to
the Goddamn a fucking, uh,
whatever the clam shack, right?
And just start banging
out fucking 20 year olds.
There's gotta be a price that
you're going to pay for that.
Is God going to allow that?
That can't be a god,
okay?
How is God allowing them?
That goes against all the laws of nature.
There's going to be fucking 80 year
old guys with knocked up 25 year olds,
okay?
My girlfriend's pregnant,
right?
They're going to be sitting there with
their fucking dentures and they'll write
it up. Bodies trying to talk to
these girls and to get an abortion.
You know that I'm telling you,
that's what's going to happen to this
fucking generation. All these guys,
these guys who invented the fucking,
uh, youtubes, the, my spaces,
the Facebook's, all of them, by the time,
you know, once they figure this shit out,
by the time they get in their [inaudible],
they're all going to
be fucking write it up.
They're going to be fucking knock it up.
Fucking 22 year olds and then they're
going to have them like there's somehow
happen CAFTA hadn't whacked.
Can you imagine that? Would you,
would you guys, uh, I dunno.
Would you do it? Cause they're
going to figure it out. Look it,
I'm 44.
I figured by the time I got to start
doing roids I figured right around 65.
So that's another 21 years. If
you go back 21 years, what is it?
2012 21 years.
That's 1991 it doesn't
seem that long ago to me.
Yeah. Shit. I'm fucking, you know
what the next guys, you guys,
you guys in your twenties, by the
time you guys get to, you know.
Okay.
Cause if you go back another 20 years,
that'd be 1971.
And when you took roids back then,
like literally your balls,
they turned to dust.
You had like c Cup titties and uh,
you know,
you turned into a fucking Werewolf.
Okay.
Women did.
Women turned in a wherefore Werewolf and
guys became like these fucking psychos.
Like women had like
those Merlin Olsen beards
and then guys just became these Adonises
who look like, you know, had like,
they had no balls anymore
and they had tits. They,
they look like if,
uh,
who's that guy in the
fucking Chicago bears?
Like if Mike Ditka became
like a transgendered person,
that's what she ended up fucking
look alike. And now you know,
you can't even tell,
look at Milky Cabrera.
That guy didn't look
like he was on anything.
So I figured by the time the people
in their twenties you guys get there,
it's going to be fucking over.
Like how good you guys are going to look.
It's going to be another 60 years
of them practicing facelifts.
All right, the probably cure
baldness, they're not even gonna know.
You probably going to
get carded at fucking 68.
And that's going to be like
the new thing with like checks,
like the new lie guys are gonna tell.
They gonna tell chicks that there,
I'm legitimately 28 years old and then
one day you're going to forget to die
your pubes and she's going to see a
couple of fucking silver ones down there.
Or even worse white ones when she's down
there grabbing your fucking prohibition
era.
Fucking Dick.
She's kind of flipped the fuck out.
Yeah.
Calling up cry. Mandy, what's right.
I found out he's 80.
Well that's okay.
He still has another 70 years left.
Right. I remember reading
one time, this guy that said,
these other guys said that the
scientists said that the fucking, uh,
that the body is actually the body.
My Boston accent coming back
bawd wide body is designed
to live 150 years. You know? That's how,
that's how difficult life is.
They had to have it designed to live
that long because the way nature of beat
the shit out of you when
you lived in a cave,
you could only get fucking
30 years out of it, you know?
Oh by the fucking way,
not by the way people,
this is by the fucking way,
which you know that I'm about ready to
tell you some shit that I believe in baby.
Uh, I'm at, I'm at Logan Airport,
Edward Lawrence Logan Airport.
I finally learned that.
But Logan Airport is a,
as named after Eddie Lawrence Logan,
who was some sort of fucking a military
person who fought in the Spanish
American war and that they used to have
a statue of him before they had to make
the airport even bigger because
people are fucked it, you know,
so why go there?
Okay.
And I go through security and they
got the giant fucking microwave.
They want me to stand in with my
legs spread doing the Jay z symbol.
Right.
Well the Sammy Hagar from the 51 50 tour,
depending on what generation you are,
a business,
depending on what side of the tracks you
from. All right. This podcast is for,
um, I'm sure someone in the
village people did it there.
You see that reached out to
the gay community swell guy.
Pat Myself on the back here. So
anyways, I say I'm not fucking,
you know, I'm opting out. All right,
sir. Can you go stand over there?
I didn't even like standing over there.
I used to work in a fucking dental
office when I would take an x ray,
somebody's tooth,
one little fucking thing.
And we put that camera right
up to the side of the jaw.
We've put a led vest over all their
vitals right down to their dick or who ha.
And then I left the fucking room,
stood behind a wall that had lead in
it and I pressed the fucking button.
Now I'm supposed to stand there.
You know,
like I'm just going into prison.
They do everything,
but you have your bend over and spread
your fucking ass cheeks. I'm like,
I'm not fucking doing it. And I know
what people are saying. Well Bill,
you talk on his cell phone,
right? That's fucking radiation.
You fly in an airplane, right?
That's fucking radiation.
I understand that.
I am getting radiated throughout the
course of the day in the way I live my
life. I understand that. Okay.
But I don't need to get extra radiated.
So if there's a way to opt out,
believe me, if there was a way to opt
out of flying on a fucking airplane,
a viable way,
aside from just saying,
fuck this business,
I'm going to buy an old bus and just
drive around and that'll be my miserable
life,
I would do it.
But the fact that I can just
stand there for an extra five, 10,
15 fucking minutes,
you know,
and rather than stand in that microwave,
I could just go over and just have some,
you know,
sort of cute male person,
pat down my ass with
the back of his pants,
the sensitive areas. Uh, I would much
rather do that. Okay. And then, you know,
people giving me shit about it,
saying it's stupid,
it's fucking pointless and
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Well, so anyway, anyways,
I met Eddie Lawrence, Logan
Airport, Edward Lawrence, and um,
I'm standing and I'm waiting,
you know,
and whenever you want to get fucking
padded down, they wait for fucking ever.
They'd make it take extra long.
I'm convinced that they do it
just so you just say, fuck it.
I'm going to go into the toaster.
All right. But I don't give a shit.
I was get to the airport early because I
know the game that they're running over
there. Oh, the lovely Nia.
Everybody. Oh, are you?
Come over here and talking to
the microphone. How you been?
We couldn't hear you last week. Oh,
I've been great. Thanks for asking.
Great to be back. Are you reading
from a script? Oh, who just woke up?
I am. Great. Thank you for
asking. Where's the Real Nia?
Who is a sexy robot that was replaced?
Listen to this shit.
I'm telling you this story about,
you know,
I always opt out of doing the Jay z thing
where they radiate everything but you
fucking taint at
the airport, Jay Z. Yeah. You
know what? You're fucking,
you have your hands like the
whole aside. Oh, isn't, isn't
that what it is? Yeah. So,
um, I'm standing there waiting, right? And
I'm staring down some baldheaded Douche.
Who knows? First of all, they always
have some chick there and she just goes,
you know, what are they, what are
they, what do they say? A male.
What does what they say? Male pat down
or whatever they say male support.
I'll five. Whatever the fuck they say.
And it's typical chick voice where it,
it can, it can only carry
what? What is, what is that?
You guys are good at yelling.
Yes, we are like, no one hears it.
No one hears it. All right, go ahead.
You know I've got the microphone away.
Yell male support aisle for yell at. I
want to hear it. I want to hear it. So
that's good. That has a sense of
fucking her. Just say all right then.
You know what?
They don't put their fucking Hartnett.
They just go a mail pack down.
He's screaming like there's something
going down or whatever. Yeah,
but you got to communicate.
You've got to communicate to those
bald fatties guys down there.
We're gonna put the back of their hands
on my ash there. Well they, they don't,
they don't get it.
They have a whole little system that
they're talking to each other that you use
fucking side. Do you want here?
Not Yours obviously. All right,
well listen to this shit. Listen
to the shit. Wait a sec, let me,
let me get to the point. Timeout.
Timeout. Get another microphone.
Get another microphone.
Hang on a second.
We're actually going to pause the podcast,
the podcast.
All right, so the magic of hitting pause
or something I never do on this thing.
Actually hit pause there. Uh,
so anyways, this is the deal.
So I'm going through security.
Yeah. After all these people
[inaudible] you already getting
rid of each gene anyways man.
So why not stand there and have literally
have your entire body budget tank lit
up,
right?
So fucking standing there and this
lady is going to nail supportive,
you know, and I'm like,
they're not hearing you.
They're not here. I know that.
She goes, sir, could you stand over?
There I go. I'm going to stand right.
And you'd watch my wallet. Okay. You can
stand right there. All right. So anyways,
this fucking, this Asian
kid comes up. Fat Asian Kid.
One of the rare ones. Why? Why? Like
like, like, like, like a white elephant.
Why is that relevant? Because Asian
people in great shape, they eat great.
I don't know what it is.
There were fucking awesome shape.
There's every once in awhile you see one,
you see a fat age and you're like,
Holy Shit.
Right?
I don't mean like he's a fucking
did it on purpose to sumo wrestle.
This is just a fact. Sumo, sumo,
Samoan, whatever the fuck it is.
This fat Asian kid comes up and relevant
to the story, but it is for the comedy.
It is. Oh, I see. Alright,
sorry. Come on. Listen,
I trashed waspy fucking white
people on this. Oh, you did?
You're talk about Nantucket. Yes I did. Oh
boy. Oh boy. Yeah. See you just hate him.
Hate anybody. I don't have hate in
my heart. All right, shut up. Listen,
so this, this, this, this person.
This fat comes up.
All right.
And The lady in lady, she goes, hi. He
couldn't even here. He goes, he's like,
what does it, hey. He's like, what?
And I want to be like, how old are you?
That's what the fuck she's trying to say.
And he goes,
13 and she goes, all
right, come over here.
And she had them go through
the old school one. Yeah.
So basically you want me to stand in
something that could kill a 13 year old.
That's what the fuck I'm supposed to do.
You know why the white way on the way
out on the way back twice. Two Times,
two times that four times a month I'm
going to stand in this thing that can kill
a 13 year old. I'm sure I can't kill
it. Maybe like can affect his like um,
puberty or his growth or something.
I think women that is Dick.
I have a dick to what?
Cause my Dick's old now
you're taking old 30 grown.
Your shoulder are like down
between your knees cubes.
No one cares about it anymore. Like
it's just kinda like out of commission.
I think women can avoid that full body
thing by saying that they're pregnant and
they won't let you go.
They won't make you go in there
if you say that you're pregnant.
Women always have the,
I'm just a girl excuse that's not get out
of this a girl twins that guys have to
do. But stick with the thing
here. If that fucking thing.
How old are you?
13 get over here at him from getting like
chest hair or something. But you, yeah,
you're old.
Like they don't care about you.
It's the youth of tomorrow that we're
concerned about or there you go.
I sat there and I, I I man, I almost,
I'm not even, it's, this isn't about
me whether I feel like I'm older, not,
I know I'm old, I'm talking about bed. Um,
I almost high five myself. I
actually, I burst out laughing,
extra laughed cause I wanted fucking
marry mumbles to be like, eh.
It Mary Mama. Yeah. What
are you laughing at?
I'm laughing cause I'm
doing the right thing.
If that fucking thing isn't
safe for a God damn 30,
I could see if it was a bit and making
some little baby crawls through there.
It's a fucking kid. Probably knows more
about computers than I do and they like,
yeah, no, don't think so. Come over
here. All Right Nia, you know what?
It's time for.
It's time for some questions up
bu then we can wrap this up. Oh,
first of all,
GI bill.
I enjoyed your standup special
on Netflix Canada so much.
Are you coming up there? Actually I'm
not. I still updates in the states.
Don't you ever go to Canada?
Oh No.
You've got to Montreal a couple of times
when I go to Canada because I didn't
like the way they were portrayed in all
those Michael Moore movies like they are
just so god damn perfect up there.
Despite the fact that they can't even
handle losing a fucking hockey game. Oh,
that's down every Starbucks or,
that was a kind of a,
is that something that
Canadians do often though?
Is that a normal thing in Canada
for the the riots to happen?
I never pretend to think that I know
what a Canadian person is thinking. Oh,
you wouldn't?
I wouldn't.
Okay.
That's an arrogant thing to do and you
want to be ashamed of yourself and you
should apologize. I love Canada.
I have only been to Manchuria.
I've only been to Montreal.
I've been there twice. It
was amazing. It was lovely.
The people were awesome. And the
last strip clubs. I went to England.
I only went to London and they'd be
like, Oh, I love England. All right,
well then get out there and muck it
up. Get out there in the sticks. Fine.
I love people who are too dumb to live
in London, living light to go to Toronto,
sit next to one of them was some fish and
chips hanging out of his mouth and you
tell me how much you like it.
You get to the ugly seedier side,
the CD and r really seedy
underbelly like we're going to,
Australia coming up are going to be to
and sick suddenly the shiniest of all
shiny cities over there and that's how
you're going to judge us. Oiliness Sydney.
Yeah.
Rather than going out to the fucking
outback with all those toothless people
playing that long horn. That doesn't sound
good. Right? Digital. He did you redo?
All right. I'm going to be in
Orlando, home of Disney world,
September 7th eighth and ninth
then I'm going to be in Charlotte,
the comedy zone,
September 13th 14th and 15th it's now,
these are all the comedy clubs. What
date was that again for Charlotte? 13th.
14th and 15th of
September. Oh, okay, great.
Um, people that want to go
to that. Cool. And then, uh,
I'll be at Carolina in New York City,
the one I had to make up. That's right.
I had to reschedule that because I had
that, I booked the pilot of the news,
the reboot of zoom, zoom, zoom,
zoom, zoom. That's a
Caroline's is September,
2021 22 and I believe 23.
It's a Thursday through Sunday.
There's only $3 and be gone a lot.
Awesome. Yeah, we've had enough.
We've had enough of
which a lot of time lot.
It's a lot to say it like that when you
go out of La and it's a high amount of
time. It's been great. It's
been good by Nini. Fine.
All right. Uh, funeral music.
Uh, I seen him, you know,
relative passed away how she
picked out her, her, her, her, uh,
our best funerals ever. Rather than
just being sad. It was like, Oh,
you've got to feel more of a personality.
Who's awesome anyways?
Hey bill funeral music shirt. You can
have some ac DC. Hey, it's your funeral,
right. Um, I did the music for my dad's
funeral three years ago. Weird. Huh?
I was 25 at the time. Dude. You
manned up. Yeah, you did. You end up,
cause that's what happens when the older
generation dies is the younger one has
to step up is always,
there's always a person who steps up and
then there's the people who just can't
deal. Then there's the selfish people like
I can, I have a rock throwing festival.
I'm going to you handle the pain.
Um,
approximately um, anyways,
he came into black Betty.
Betty Bam. A black mini.
That's awesome. Right there.
You feel like you're at a
concert? Yeah. Also played a,
he says pronounce Gow D'été Gow date.
I don't have know how to say it.
And a couple more.
It's spelled G. A. U. D. E. T. E. I'm
sure I've heard it. Gow Dare Tech. No,
I don't know what the updates,
I don't even know what that is.
And a couple more rock ones that I
can't remember and no religious shit in
between. That's fucking,
that's how I'm going out.
Yeah. You know what? I'm
going to go to that damn a,
what the hell was it that I just told
you to go to legal zoom.com write up my
own damn will and that's going to be part
of it. You're going, whoa. Black minute.
Bamba lamb. Whoa. One more thing
I got to, I got to read here.
He voice and then we're done.
I think with the advertising stuff for
two quickies in the end he voice, oh hey,
if this is another a great way to start
a business where you know you still,
you know you don't have an office but
you want to make it sound like you do.
You don't have money for 58 cell phones,
but you could have,
you know a bunch of different cell phone.
Oh yes.
He was showing me the website
to, yeah, that's very cool.
I keep saying viral phone numbers. It's
not that viral, not viral. What is,
what is the proper kid terminology?
Tell me what do you have the
proper terminology for what now?
For phone numbers letter.
Then you're in the air. Man,
but they're not there and they go into
your phone, man, I don't know what it is.
Virtual virtual phone numbers.
You could literally have like
fucking 15 phone numbers.
They all ring to your phone.
They got these professional voice actors.
They will act like they're
your, you're sexy. You know,
double o six vixen have
a secretary devil's six,
whatever the hell it is. He's double o
seven. He's on top. Oh, I see. Right.
You get it.
He voice your mobile phone at work.
One of the great eve voice
features his music on hold.
Make your business seem more
professional as the voice.
We'll treat your clients and
customers to music on hold. Hey,
get somebody could kick your calling,
some giant building.
As you're sitting there sneaking around
and you can paint and your cubicle,
right. You go to legal zoom,
you get yourself incorporated.
You're on your way out.
Yeah. It's like the greatest scape you'd
digging the tunnel. Tremendous. Um,
you can even set up a voice to run
promotional advertisement for your company
while people are on or are on hold
instead of music. Yeah, that's good.
Like coming up at Joe Blow's Frisbee
fest. You can, I have your toes painted.
Sorry.
He voice also has call recording features,
which is perfect for doctors,
lawyers, real estate agents,
hiring managers in any other
professional discussing contracts. Um,
easy to use.
You just press star two to
start and tars start to to stop.
It's easier than me reading this copy.
Perfect.
If you're driving and you can't write
something important down eve voice makes
your life easier and seem more
professional for free, for free.
Six month trial for six months.
That's pretty good.
Do it. Yeah. They have a cat on it.
You can do like a conference call.
You can have up to 90 people on hold if
when you have your massive drug dealing,
uh, international thing there from
the phone ideas, oh please meet this.
This whole thing is set up.
You can use this for good or evil.
Just like the Internet.
You can learn about turtles
or watch something you
shouldn't have seen. You know,
this is same thing with the voice.
They are giving you the option to start
your business and get out of I get out
of your cubicle and start living your
dream. Or you can use it for evil.
You know,
I don't think that's probably a start
a whole nother family or whatever.
And he got six months to do it
with a free six month trial,
go to www dot [inaudible] dot com slash
bill burr or go to the banner on my
podcast page at [inaudible]
Dot Com and, uh, get out from
under it. Everybody. Yeah.
You know what, that's, that's
good even for so that way.
Is this a thing where you can
give somebody your actual, no,
it's not, you're not giving me a number
and they don't have your real numbers,
but they don't have your reality,
but it brings kind of phone and you
have the option of turning it on,
turn it off.
It's like it's some star trek stuff
and it gets you out of your cubicle.
So you can avoid situations like this.
Look at this right back to the podcast.
That right? There was a
professional segue, um,
office rumor and Mary, uh, Hey, bill,
a great show and all that Bs.
Anyways,
I came in to the office where I work on
Friday and my boss came up to me very
angrily and said,
you up to something staring in his face.
See he voice, legal zoom. You get
off from under this. Um, he goes,
I didn't know what the hell he,
I don't know what.
I didn't know what the hell he meant. So
I said, no. He said he'd been watching me.
That's what he basically that you walk in
on a Friday, you site for your weekend.
This guy comes up and goes, you up to
something. You say no, and he's like,
I'm watching you and walks away.
You just have to sit
there and take it right.
Slink back into your God damn cubicle.
He goes,
I found out later that everyone in the
office thinks I fucked the secretary.
Mary. I didn't, Ooh. He
goes, I didn't, I asked,
I asked Mary about it and
she said that she made it up.
Don't guys usually do that? He
goes, I thought it was sexy.
Oh Geez. Jumping right into this one
and then they really fucked. Yeah.
I had always admired Mary from afar and
thought she was a good match for me.
I really want to date her,
but I fee you want to date this girl.
Just put her on the desk and Banger.
You're already getting fucked over for it.
You might as well this isn't the mother
your kids do. This trick is a psycho.
Stop it already.
What? You are such an asshole when
it comes to let me finish. Let me,
let me let me show or asserting her
sexuality and you're such a fucking
hypocrite about it because
he'll love that shit. Okay,
so don't sit there on like
some sort of moral high horse.
This is the mother of your children.
This is how women should act.
Madonna and whore like
you know what I'm saying?
I had done, yeah. Just say bitch,
please bitch please. There we go.
All right. Coming soon to a podcast.
That's right. When are you going
to start the bitch, please? I'm going to
start and I got a lot of shit going on.
Yes, it's coming soon. The
bitch please podcast. Yeah,
my own and my own podcast and you should.
You should. Now that I've said the name,
you should definitely go out and start
the website or anything. Anyways,
he goes, he goes, I really want to
date her, but I fear that if I do,
my boss will fire me or otherwise hurt
my career because he is strongly against
office relationships. What should I do?
All right. First of all, right there.
That's why you need to get
out from underneath this dick,
because he's literally saying,
who can fuck who this guy is on a total
power trip? That's a normal policy.
And workplaces, they frown on
interpersonal relations up to something.
I'm watching you. That's a total. Now
j Edgar Hoover Shit. That's like, oh,
go to HR and talk.
You know what he should have done?
He should have kicked him in the
balls from behind when he walked away.
Get that nice sound. Yeah, that
nice sign of a foot hitting the,
the MC hammer part of
the selects. So Mary, Oh,
you just tore me a new fucking asshole.
This is what I'm talking about Mia. What?
That chick is fucked in the head.
Why she made,
she made a joke of inappropriate joke
that got around absolutely asserting
yourself sexually is that she just comes
up to him and asks him out or whatever.
I don't have a fucking problem
with that to walk around.
You know what you want to
talk about fucking hypocrite.
You're a fucking hypocrite.
Why?
Cause if he sat there and he
said that he fucked somebody,
he didn't fucking the office. How
would you look at that? Uh, exactly.
Okay. This chick is doing, she has
some sort of, she has some sort of,
this chick is a fucking psycho.
You don't have to go that far
to be like they're a psycho.
But I gave you did you do me?
It's a major red flag.
It's a decent point because
the Afa man said, oh,
I could down to me it's a decent point.
Stuff.
Pat me on the fucking head to break
Goddamn head and I gave you a fucking
example and you, you, you actually
shut you off for half a second.
Which is not an easy thing to do.
I am saying that it was a good point.
Put your eyebrows down. All right.
Now your eyes. See what you did.
That's classic female shit there. See
what you did. No, no, no. Your behavior.
Why do, why am I said what happened
for your classic overreaction and like,
you know, because you assumed
that me saying that this
chick is a fucking psycho.
You immediately assumed that I was,
I was saying that women can
assert themselves sexually. Okay.
And then I turned it around and I gave you
an example. I am pointing, you're away.
You better put it away.
I'll do the Bill Clinton fist out of
not have sex in proper relations. Um,
because bill about, let
me finish. All right.
Then I gave you the example.
What if some guy said he fucked
you and he didn't fuck you.
What would you think about that guy?
Always just asserting himself sexually.
Is he hot? What's the, what's
the stuff you suck? Suck on
with the joke. All right.
All right. All right. Yes,
I get your point. I get your
point. Yes it would. No, no,
that's not good enough. What do you
want me to say? Cause you're going,
I get your point. That's a decent
point. You Pat me on the fucking head.
I made a great God damn coin point.
After you sat there and you flipped out
on me calling me a hypocrite and all
this bullshit. You want your new
little bitch please fucking rant.
And I came back.
Now you actually understand where I'm
coming from because you fucking leaped off
the got you just took a little thing
and you ran with it because you watch,
we tell some jokes for fucking 10 years.
Um,
I mean you're right. I am right.
It would not be and it's killing me to
say, okay, if we're got to do that Fellas,
that's how you do it. You don't
let them warm or the way out of it.
That's what she did.
She tried like three different
techniques of patting me on the head.
It's decent point.
And then you did the other thing
when you knew that I was right.
Then you put your eyebrows
up like, yes, you're right.
Like I'm being an
overbearing asshole because I
know when one of these things, because
I said, I said it was a good point,
so I don't know what more
you want from me, but yeah.
Do you remember you don't remember your
Newt Rockne speech she gave fucking 90
seconds ago about an asshole.
I was screaming and yelling and all that,
and then when you find out I'm right,
you go, okay, that's a decent point.
You don't think that
that's, you know? Yeah.
I think it's me giving me be like if I
took my barefoot right now and I just
know she right in the face with it and
then you went over the side of the bed,
hit your head, started to cry. This,
you said that I was wrong. And I said,
all right, you're right. Maybe I pushed
it too hard. This rights. You're right.
That should not kicked you.
All of this is besides the point.
The point is he actually likes this woman.
No,
he's trying to figure out what he not,
no. See once again the last second,
she tried to warm her way out
to just see that. Anything,
I'm just trying to get back
to the top aside. The point,
it is a beside the point.
You just read me the riot act
and you will fucking wrong.
I don't know that I was completely wrong.
I don't know.
Why aren't you making eye contact anymore?
I don't think that I was completely wrong.
I just think that you brought up a good
point that I hadn't considered passing
hatred. Of course. What else do I have
to judge you on paths, Beth course.
I judge you. I'm not
saying that's wrong. You.
My entire life is judging
people on past behavior. Okay,
but when you find out you're wrong, you
just say, yeah, you know what I was wrong,
which I do and you never give
me fucking credit for when?
When do you ever say I was
wrong? Whatever. You do
something where I didn't know.
You come in and you snuggle up beside me
and you make a little joke or you like
to try to get me wrong and
I'm going to work on it. No,
that's not what happens at all.
You'd try to cute your way out of it and
like charm and do a little funny dance
and hey everybody, I'm Billy. Okay. You
know what is? You know what? And that's
some of the times I do that. I do admit
that when I'm seriously fucking wrong,
what I'm saying, I see wrong. You do
apologize. That's true. And I say, Oh,
we'll work on it. Right? What'd
he go? Jesus Christ. It's
like police fucking teeth.
All right. Female question about anal.
There's, there's a nice segue. Wait,
did we even give that guy advice though?
Or do we just go off on our own
relationship? Here's the advice.
Uh,
don't date this girl.
If you're going to banger.
I mean you're rolling the dice because
then she's going to be a, okay, lastly,
go with a joke. Right now. I
really am. Oh, that's true.
She might blow up your
spot cause she's already
talking out of school.
Yeah, that's a good point.
This and this guy has the problem that
I have is that when he makes a fucking
loony bird who's fucking all about it, you
just fucking, you. You can't, you can't,
you know, you just, yeah, that's
like a, that's literally uh,
that's like a second degree like Dick
Black belt to be able to walk away from
pre pussy like that.
And I sorry that I'm being crass.
I've just one running out of time here.
I'm just trying to get to the point here.
Followup was a virgin,
not a virgin anymore. This is before the
female question about anal. I wrote, okay,
this guy got fucking late.
Hey you broke your cherry.
I wrote in a few months back elaborating
on my situation. Remember this 20,
I got a lot of versions calling in uh,
writing, uh, as a 21 year old virgin,
uh Oh, I was going to make
a really bad joke there. La.
I've got a lot of virgin typing
in on a semen stain, keyboards.
I know it was gross. I, it is funny
to me in my head. All right, sorry.
I wrote it a few months ago.
I helped this person a few months back
elaborating on my situation as a 21 year
old virgin conservative girlfriend where
the furthest we went was oral sex as
well as subsequent hookups with
other girls only stopping there.
Um, so you kind of get blown. I
don't really consider that a virgin.
I just can see you like how I was
going to say you like it, Dah, Dah,
Dah. You're not out in the field.
You know, you just come, you,
you go to bed every couple of innings.
I don't know though,
but is that guys deliver like not a
virgin if he gets blown, but a girl,
is it still a virgin if she just
gets EFA guidance goes down in our,
because then her hymen isn't
broken. No, no, no. As a guy,
you're still a virgin
until you banged a girl.
You've got to in there and a woman,
you're still a virgin slash kind
of Horry if the other way around,
I don't have time to get involved
in the debate anyways. Um,
as well as subsequent hookups
or the Gobbler Blah, blah.
This was when I asked you whether
telling a girl that I was still a virgin
before slash during, during, during,
quite as, I don't know what that means.
Fornicating was a good idea during,
does this jolt your memory?
Absolutely it does.
I actually lost my virginity 30 minutes
before my actual birthday with a girl
I'm currently dating go.
So yeah,
it's not like I was a
fucking whore. Anything, uh,
you will write about telling a girl about
my sexual experience or lack thereof.
She was actually totally fine with it.
Of course I'm not a bad guy.
Gave this guy some advice that
worked and we shouldn't Fry's that.
I was a virgin, which I guess I should
take as a compliment. Absolutely.
It means you probably kissing
a nice rubbing it tidies
the way she liked it over
there. Um, anyways, I'd like to
thank you for that as a small part.
Uh,
it
may, uh, as small of a part as it may have
been, it still helps. Well, there you go.
So what is good now, if I could follow
this up with another short question out,
me and this girl been hooking
up pretty frequently in,
I'm going to have some dirt question
here. All right, here we go.
Now he's going to get technical.
Not, I'm just fucking on.
How do I improve on that?
Um, is that disgusting? Um,
and the one issue I have is that I used,
I have to use a rubber.
You did say safe sex is like boxing,
keep yourself protected at all times.
Uh,
unfortunately when I do put one on I
can't feel shit and therefore tend to lose
my erection erection after awhile.
And it's not like she is in hot
or anything. Uh, cute Asian.
That's number two with the Asians.
I know one fat Asian, one Q one.
Now number one, what is wrong
with saying she's a cute Asian?
Nothing. She's a hot chick.
How dare you say that?
She's good looking and
describe her. There you go. Um,
stop talking for condoms were number one.
Have you ever encountered
issues like this? Yes.
And how would you go about solving it? Uh,
is it actually my fault? No. Cause what?
You know what it is,
dude,
you're used to fucking mouth on Dick
contact and now all of a sudden you put in
the Dick. Oh yeah. Your, your, your
condom on and it feels like you're,
you're in the abyss.
This is what you're going to get used to.
It jerk off with the condom bond.
This stuff that you could do
don't jerk off for a while.
You have to get used to the
sensation again. It sucks.
But I'm telling you he could
get those thin ones though.
The real thin lambskin or whatever.
And I could run through that x ray
machine at the fucking airport to no,
I'm telling you this is the greatest
thing you can do now that you're fucking,
but I don't really get this kid some
advice. Get some different kind of car.
I'd like to experiment with different
condoms. No. Trojans are super thick. No,
there's other ones that are, oh, this
is what you want to do. Okay. Okay.
Well in this day and age with Greenland
fucking melting and the water rising in
New York. Okay. You, you cannot, you have
to where you got to fucking go all out.
No,
I'm saying he should wear a condom.
You don't get the one that does the
fucking thin one. This thing too,
you can wear condoms. Still get herpes. I
still don't understand all that happens.
Is it on your ball?
Big Oral.
If you shaved your nuts that day
and then you fucking against it,
I have no idea. It's a risk of getting
something. That's just how it goes down.
So this is the thing, dude,
uh, right out of the gate,
get used to fucking wearing condoms.
I can't even fucking tell you how
psyched you are going to be. You know,
if this doesn't work out, you have a one
night stand. As much as it sucks, there's,
there's no fucking better feeling.
The end when you walk out
knowing that you wore one and oh,
this is what you always do after you have
sex, you go, okay, you know, you act like,
oh, I got to go throw
this thing out. Right?
And then you go and you put your Dick in
her sink in flux and you scrubbed that
fucker and then you walk out that need
to put, use her face towel. Oh Man.
Get the fuck out of there.
Or you know what else it could do and
you don't fuck whores, which is hard.
You know what else you could do if
he's in a relationship with his girl,
he's a virgin.
I don't know what her sexual history is.
They could both go to the clinic together,
get tested for everything wrong,
everything across the board and then
still wear a condom because you have no
idea what the other person's going to do.
You can be with a sociopath.
You don't have time for this.
Don't fuck that. Fuck all of that.
But if they're in like a committed
thing, you know the 21, the 21,
she's going to run into one of these,
write it up.
80 year old guys that's has fucking
70 [inaudible] 70 years again,
he's going to fucking talk him into
going down on his fucking grows.
Babe Ruth Dick. Uh, female question
about anal. This is the last one.
I got to see this. I
gotta get Outta here. Um,
my husband keeps jokingly bringing up
the subject of anal sex. The funnies.
I fucked in the ass.
Did you have him call me in and asked how
we should go about asking you for anal?
Um, there's no, there's no ask you
with anal. You just do it. Wow.
Wow. Now what it is, you have to,
you have to do a survey during,
during doggy style. That's what
she, that's how you figure it out.
It's done with the thumb. It's sort
of a rubbing circular motion. William.
It's finished reading. I just
finished reading it. Okay.
Just stop and just read please.
For the love of God. Oh,
this guy just joking around.
I love these pancakes so much that I
love to fuck you in the ass. Just kid.
Just because kids sweetheart.
Oh, this poor guy.
He wants to fuck you in the ass.
He doesn't know how to bring
it up after corn flakes.
This is the funniest thing ever.
In the past,
he always acted as though
he thinks it's gross.
Maybe he did and he's just watched so
much porn that he's now graduated to it,
which is the danger.
Uh,
my sister told me that a few of her
girlfriends said they actually enjoy it.
Oh, that means your
sister likes it. You know,
I have this friend. Yeah, she
loves it. Says that it enhances,
um, he's very well endowed and I
weigh only all of 95 pounds. Yeah.
It ain't happening. It ain't happening.
I think my concern is well founded.
Yes it is. But wait a minute,
those porno girls can take it.
You can take it to come on, be a trooper.
Uh, what is your opinion about it?
Should I let him? What would need
to say? You just heard what he,
what she has to say. He, he
listens. He listens to this.
Say No, please. You want female
listeners. Punk helped me out. Thanks.
Lock Yourself. Ah, feed.
Really don't want to do it
then you shouldn't do it.
You know, there's no reason.
Yeah. It'd be one thing if you didn't
have a viable option somewhere else. Yeah.
That was actually, you know what I
mean? It's basically you have any Nikes,
you have a nice probably
mid size, uh, shit.
Dan going on there and this guy
for some reason, despite its size,
is going with the mini Cooper.
Look, they do, I gotta be honest workshops
and it's not something you don't want.
You don't want to do that with your wife.
You just don't,
okay. I thought that's the one person
you would want to do it. Well, no,
you do it with it.
With that fucking dig back that says
she's already banging you at work. Okay.
That's who you do it to write on a desk.
You fucker in the ass musher face into
the card catalog and then you know what
the card catalog,
whatever the fuck they got nowadays.
That that's how you do it with, that's it.
Okay. That's the podcast for this week.
Um, oh, I got it real quick. One
from, well if I'm a lady, uh yeah. So,
okay.
I Dunno. I Dunno what to tell you.
It's like, you know, get 95 pounds.
He has a giant Dick. What, what do
you, what are you going to do there?
I have no idea.
You know what I would do?
I would call in doctor drew
show and have them, uh,
I would say I'm going to
pass up. You throw? Yeah,
I'm gonna I'm to send that one up.
The up the up the, what'd they say?
What'd they say in the precinct? Send
that went up the up the ranks. They uh,
you know what? We don't have time.
No, no, no, no. Really quickly if you,
I don't know what city you live in,
but if there is a sex shop near you,
they normally have like
these anal sex workshops,
like taught by women or
whatever and a couple can go in,
you pay a little bit of money and
they like, they talk you like,
they tell you how to do it so that
it's gentle and it's not freaking out.
How do you see you could do that? How do
you start that? Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I understand that.
If she wants to get it when you go into
a sex store and they're fucking in there,
but how did you get there? Where are
the anal sex shop? Like open mics,
like where do you start?
Like you're sitting in a cubicle and like
you know where I think I would make my
millions in New York City people how
to take their big Dixon and that little
white sand city.
There was a place called toys and babe
land and they gave all kinds of workshops
how to give blow jobs, but how do
whatever what's you're missing?
Introduce SNM into your relationship.
They all have these things but
you're missing the point here.
What is the point is is how do you
become that fucking person? I don't know.
That's what I'm saying. Where
are the open mics? I Dunno.
You probably see a good gig. You want
to sit there and talking about Amy,
you're acting like a bunch of hotties
I going to cry in or you work in a sex
shop, you learn about things and
then you just become an expert.
You study it or whatever.
You talk to people and I know you don't
even know what you're talking about.
You literally were
looking up at the ceiling,
sort of shaking your head like idea or
out of this guy. Probably just, yeah,
it just have a parachute and you
land on the store and they say, Hey,
you want to talk about dicks?
Humble, female breadwinner. Hi Bill.
I'm, I'm one of those ladies who
usually takes too long to tell a story.
So I tried really hard to make this quick.
This is actually than most of the guys,
so
I appreciate it.
Uh,
I make three times more money than my
boyfriend of 15 of one and a half years.
Sorry, 1.5 years. Jesus Christ.
How career-driven is her 1.5 years?
Let me sure that she's making more money.
Um,
I have zero problem with this because
money is not a big issue with me.
It's a tough economy and he's
very hardworking. Lately.
This seems to be more of an issue for him.
Of course it is.
He makes a bigger deal about going out
to eat and took a weekend job so we could
see each other less.
Um,
he has told me that he is ring shopping
and even though I've told them many
times that I don't want
anything fancy or expensive,
he counters saying when I show my friends
I'll be embarrassed and he wants to
give him some really nice yeah.
Any advice on how to convince them?
I'm not a material girl now what you got
to do is support the guy cause there's,
you got to understand
that as a [inaudible]
guy, like going out and earning a living,
that's, that's what we're there for.
And when we're not doing it,
not only we can't do it at that time
because we don't have a job and your
fucking doing it, no matter how cool you
are, it's totally fucking emasculating.
It'd be like if I could all of a
sudden have a fucking kid and you
get pregnant and I was over there,
fucking nursing a baby is
creepy as that example.
I'm just saying,
you know what I men,
men want to be the provider that's
like in their nature. So no,
that's our job.
It's our job.
It's our fucking job. It's the same way
that women like when you're with a woman,
if you get in too good a shape,
they get fucking insecure.
Like they don't like a lot of women.
As much as they liked those shredded guys,
they don't want to be with a guy that's
in that go to fucking shape cause then
they're like,
fuck,
now I have to be in that good of shape
and I can't go to those cheese fondue,
lava fucking things.
You don't stick my tongue in it with a
glass of wine and pontificate about sex
in the city or whatever the fuck it is.
You brought stu. Listen, you want to,
oh my God. You want to like, uh,
those are absolutely disgusting by
the way that she's come on. They sit,
they stick in the, she's calm.
That's gross. It smells awful.
Terrific. Yeah, I don't,
I don't like fondue. You only
fondue? No, that's weird. All right.
I went to a fondue restaurant. It's my
like feed. I would just say, listen,
you got to support this guy. Just
say to the guy, just say, listen,
I get it. I get it. You don't have a job
right now and it's fucking hard for you.
And,
uh,
I have 100% faith that yet
you're going to find another job.
We're going to have a great life.
And you know,
you don't have to buy a ring right now,
but when you get your job and everything,
you want to go out by me.
If I totally respect the fact that you're
thinking about me being embarrassed or
on my friends, just support
the guy, that'll be fine.
Yeah. That's all you gotta do.
Just support the guy.
Yeah. Because right now,
no matter unless he hears that from you,
he's just going to automatically think
that you're thinking that, you know,
he's not a provider and he's not a
good guy. He needs to hear it from you.
The same way that when Yell Lady,
maybe put on a few,
you got to tell us she's
still looking good. Right? Why
are you looking at me like that?
Because lately I've been slipping.
That's the podcast. Oh my God.
No, I was actually thinking like,
I'm given a good advice. Maybe she'll
play, she'll pleasure me later. Um,
all right. Just left it at
the good advice. You know,
you could have not asked the question.
You could have not shown up.
Come down here. You know, I
didn't ask you on the podcast.
You're fucking bashed in.
I did ask you last time.
I said he had been here in
awhile and we missed you.
We missed you here on the podcast.
All right, last two things.
amazon.com which she likes to
support the troops and this podcast.
Next time you're going to go to
amazon.com to buy some silly straw,
go to build bird.com first
click on the podcast page.
Click on the amazon.com link.
It'll take you right there.
You don't have to do anything else.
Once you get there, go buy something.
Buy An old baseball card. Uh,
Amazon will give me some money.
I kicked 10% of it actually kind of been
kicking 10% of all advertising to the
wounded warriors project. It's a great
thing. It was what should be done.
You know what I mean?
It's what should be done.
So they could go and gain fly.com hey,
do you want to sit on the couch,
smoked some weed and I eat some cheese.
It's well going into a different world.
Um, anyways. gamefly.com is
awesome. If you're into video games,
they got 8,000 gains for you to choose
from. You got a two week free trial.
You get them direct to your
PC or delivered right to
your damn apartment, Gazebo,
tent city, wherever the hell you live.
You can play all these games. Uh,
8,000 games for a two week trial.
Take two weeks vacation and sit there
and play 8,000 different games right game
fly.com go to the go to game,
fly.com/burr now gamefly.com/burr or
the banner ad on my podcast page for the
free trial. Joy, all the video
games you can play. That's it.
That's the podcast for this week. Go fuck
yourselves. Hey, thanks for all the odd,
nice compliments about, uh, my
guest star on breaking bad. And, uh,
all the wonderful things you guys
said about my special, you know,
I really means a lot to me. I
appreciate it. All right. Thank you.