Hey, what's going on? Is Bill Burn?
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday, April 11th,
April 11th,
2016 what's going on?
I worry. Yeah, it's a,
it's Sunday night to Sunday evening.
I'm in the house all by myself.
Uh,
the lovely Nia had some business
meeting or some shit she had to go to.
Um, it's show business. I
know what you're saying.
You guys all live in the normal
world. You're thinking like, wait,
my wife says she's got a business meeting
on a Sunday night at fucking yeah.
Surpass a certain hour. That means
she's out there banging somebody.
I know.
That's what you think.
But I'm in show business so it's totally
normal for them to go out that way.
What the fuck happened to
the high hat over here?
I told you I got my little fucking
practice set up there. What the fuck is
maybe Cleo was playing it
when I wasn't here anyways.
Any she um, yeah, so she's out.
So I'm going to try to
knock this out cause uh,
I gotta be at work on Monday
for something. For some reason,
I still can't say whether
what it is or what's going on.
Hopefully. Uh, so yeah, you know
what it is. You know what it is.
Maybe you don't know what it is.
Maybe you don't listen to every week,
but you know what it is. So I gotta
be at work on Monday and uh, oh,
Billy fucking,
uh,
clean living ever since
I got back from Canada.
Oh, Canada, you punch a freeze and cuts.
I got just got back from there. And, uh,
I kind of realized that when I
go on the road with the fellows,
we act like we're on some sort of
bachelor party. I don't know what it is,
minus the fucking who is everything
else. Uh, we basically, uh,
you know, we booze and we smoked cigars
and that thing and it's just, yeah,
it takes a lot out of me
and I got a bunch of shit I gotta do.
So I kind of need to be clearheaded
as opposed to the usual, you know,
usually when I got nothing going on
in my life. I mean I can fucking,
you are going to have a few.
Right.
And I can wake up the next morning
like fucking eggs or something. Right.
I can be in that mindset, but
uh, as of right now, I can't, so,
um, I have not done anything. Haven't
touch shit. I haven't fucking,
I haven't drank,
I haven't smoked a meeting pretty good.
Uh,
even laying off the internet porn,
I mean it's just fucking over actually
got this time magazine that was about
Internet porn and how it's like
fucking people up, you know,
especially like kids, you know,
when they first like just the shit,
the Schmooze kitten home, this shit
you can see on the fucking Internet.
I can't believe nobody's stepped in. I'm
not saying somebody should step in, but,
um, you know, I gotta tell you if, if,
if they knew what the fuck the
Internet was going to be when it was,
whenever Al Gore was inventing
it back the eighties.
Um, I'll never said that.
I said that I was at,
I was involved in the email
chain, whatever the fuck
he said. That fucking guy.
Remember when his campaign was over,
man,
when he was dancing around and all
sweaty and all that shit and how he just
looked like he was so fucking
relieved that it was over. Um,
what a thing to go through running
for president. I just saw a clip,
a Hillary Clinton. I have not been paying
attention at all, but Jesus Christ,
what the fuck happened to her?
She looks like Earl fucking weaver.
She's like Earl weaver.
She was doing something right.
She was standing in some black
church, right? Baptist church.
I'm going to assume you know, I don't
think it was a Jewish synagogue there.
Whatever the fuck they could temple
she's or there's green shoots.
You just like yelling the
shit she was going to do.
That's the only time a politician goes
near the black community is when they're
running. They fucking,
they swing by the church.
They make a whole bunch of promises and
then they get in the fucking limo and
they go, let's get the fuck
outta here. Fuck out of dodge.
Then they go over, they do a town meeting,
talk to all the lunch pail Louise.
Right. Then if they, if there's even
those people left in this country,
if you fucking make anything,
they get over there and they
say roll up their sleeves.
That's when you know they're
talking to the working man.
They take off their sport coat and
they roll up the sleeves, you know,
like they going to build something
rather than just go out there and say the
exact same bullshit.
They just said the Baptist church with
more of a fucking lunch pail swing do it
right. And the whole fucking
thing. It's just gross.
I don't know anybody sits there
and watch that shit, but um,
okay.
The latest thing that I become fascinated
with is I completely leave whatever
the fuck I was just talking about. I'll
come back to it. The clean living thing,
who wants to listen about clean living?
It's the most boring shit ever, you know?
Anyways.
Um,
okay.
I become fascinated with
how super rich people,
okay.
Avoid paying taxes.
Just fucking fascinating.
It's one of those things,
you know,
it's like you got to respect
it on just certain level.
It's just the brilliance of it.
And then there's a certain level of balls
that that takes because you're fucking
with your freedom anytime you fucking
with taxes, you know what I mean?
Fucking what the government, anytime
you get doing that, I mean, you know,
why is it that, I don't know. What
the fuck is that a federal thing?
I guess if you're not paying your
federal income tax yet, Bill,
that would probably be a federal crime.
I Dunno.
I always hear you got
to cross state borders.
Do you get to like not pay taxes and
then leave your state before it becomes
federal? I don't know. I don't
know these things. But anyways, um,
just the balls in it takes and the,
uh,
I dunno, I don't like people physically,
other people, that type of crime.
But when there's something
like robbing banks
or tax evasion or even a good
old fashioned fucking scam,
if there's like a,
like an amazing level of thought behind
it on some level, you got to respect it.
I think,
you know what I mean?
Like I remember a long time
ago there was some fucking guy,
he figured out how to rob parking meters.
Yeah, they were allegedly,
it was impossible to do.
So this guy figured out how to
fucking do it. It's amazing.
And he did this shit.
This is back in like the 80s or some shit.
This guy figured out how to
do it. So it was way, way,
way easier to not have everybody
breathing down your fucking throat.
You know,
people will be having eggs watching
you fucking robbing a parking meter.
They didn't have a fucking
smart phone on them.
They just be sitting there going,
it's fucking got guy.
Just is that Guy Robin and parking meter.
Oh his shit. The fuck. See that?
Everybody see that?
That was it.
That's all in fucking happened
rather than some dope shit.
And they're filming you and you were
arrested before you even get home.
All right.
And then the fucking local newscasters,
they always got to do some sort of
fucking bad pun. You know what I mean?
I'll tell you, this guy's life is
freedom is now going to change. You know,
they do that. Some are, they get away
with that and I'm like fucking newspapers.
Like they can have the
biggest fucking puns ever.
And everybody thinks it's great.
You know? I don't know. I,
I can't even think of one right now.
Yeah. But uh, whatever, you know,
you sit at home and you think about it,
you said you're a fucking cubicle
instead of doing your goddamn work,
you think of one. So anyways, this fucking
guy figured out how to do this shit. Um,
and of course the parking meter
gods were beside themselves.
You know what I mean?
It was like one of those Scifi movies.
We're like the titanic movie land.
Not even God can sick it.
That's so they will like,
not even God could get the
fucking quarters out of
this meter. This may, right.
That's,
they were talking all kinds of shit to
this fucking guy figured out how to do it
and you'd think you'd like a high
whatever, man. You too. Well,
what the fuck are you
going to do with that?
We'll do this fucking meters
all over the city. So this guy,
anytime you wanted a drink, if you
wanted a fucking sandwich, he, his guy,
he had it perfect.
It was like his own ATM machine before
ATM machines, he just walk up, bank bank,
boom. He had a sack of fucking quarters.
You go down to the bank, you go here,
can I get one? Some of the rolly
fucking things there, right? Yeah, sure.
They don't give a shit. Nobody gave a fuck
back then. Nobody was paying attention.
They were trying to pay attention
but not not to that type of shit.
So this guy would roll the fucking
quarters, you know, roles enough quarters.
Next thing you know,
he gets himself out of how the fuck you
get all those quarters down to a car
dealership.
I have no fucking idea.
Although I talked to some drug
dealers about how they fucking, um,
or a guy of new drug dealers.
Let's be honest at bill,
let's not act like that news guy saying
that you were in the war and then you
were in a chopper,
Assam Shit next to the chopper and you
didn't really fucking see it. Okay.
You took a fucking helicopter tour
one time. You weren't even in Iraq.
Whatever the fuck he said, I don't
pay attention to shit. So anyways,
I was talking to this guy and basically
how back in the day when drug dealers
was still driving around and flashy cars,
cause when I heard nowadays they,
they don't even want to track
that level of attention. Um,
how it used to be was anything,
any cash deal that was over 10 grand
grant had to be fucking reported.
So what these drug dealers would do was
they would go out and they buy a car
worth nine grand for cash and then they
drive it around for like a fucking week.
And then they traded in
for a car was 16 grant,
maybe get seven for theirs and then
they throw another fucking night at the
other car. Now they got a $16,000
car. I drive around for a little bit.
You fucking trade it in or $23,000 car.
They give you a fifth whatever and so on
and so forth til you trade your way all
the way up to whatever fucking
car you want it. Um, it just,
I just look at that shit. It's like, I
mean, that's not the, the deepest thing,
but that's the way my brain would work.
I'd be like, well, it goes so good.
I drive a piece of shit.
Then what's the point of dealing drugs?
Right? Or I just say, fuck it.
I'm buying a Ferrari and I'm want to
drive it until they catch me fucking three
weeks later. Um, by the way,
the Ferrari I like is the Ferrari
California. That's the old man.
Once the fucking gt, the grand
touring one, right. I don't know.
You ride around in some Batmobile,
just gimme one that's shaped like a
fucking Jaguar from back in the day,
you know,
or maybe a Toyota supra,
those fucking things from the 80s. I
remember this sky loaned me his, well,
he used my truck to move and I,
Brandon,
I'd beat the shit out of his car and
he'd beat the fuck out of my truck and we
both got a cars back and he's smelling
rubber and I'm seeing all kinds of
scratches all over my truck. And we just,
Eh, it's kind of a fair deal, right?
And then we both got arrested for
drinking and drive it months later.
But that's a completely different
story. I know. I'm all over the map.
I'm doing this late night and I
don't want to be doing it right now,
but I got shit to do in the morning.
So anyways, it's fucking guy.
You know,
if he had half a fucking brain,
what you do is you keep your day job,
right? Keep your fucking day job,
and then, you know, for
anything miscellaneous,
she gets to go to the parking meters,
right?
And what you do is you start
storing up on the quarters.
Then every once in a while,
right? You just start,
you start washing the money
with you fucking cat. I know
what you do. You fucking,
you go into stores and stuff,
who gives a fuck? Right?
You just use it to get yourself a
better TV. But what is this dope do?
He gets fucking greedy.
I didn't even buy a fucking story goes.
All I know is he just started hitting
every fucking God damn parking meter
around.
And next thing you know he's sitting on
like a fucking $2 million in quarters
and he ended up getting busted. But
there was a part of it. I liked the guy,
you know.
So anyways,
this gets me to the super rich on how
you know all that shit about the Panama
papers and all that type of stuff.
I was talking to another friend of mine
who's a fucking lawyer and I was like,
how does that work? Like how do you
get your money out of the country?
And then once it's out of the country,
how do you make sure nobody steals it?
Like what happened to Johnny
Depp's character and blow?
And then once you have
it out of the country,
how do you get it back in without
just getting taxed all over again?
A busted and he said,
basically this is it.
And he broke the whole fucking thing
down. All right. Or as far as I know,
he broken aspect of it down. I know all
you guys are sitting in right now going,
Oh gee,
she's going to try to explain to him,
I'm going to try to explain some shit
that was just explained to me and I don't
really know what the
fuck I'm talking about.
So let's get rid of one myth right out
of the gate. I remember a long time ago,
a friend of mine had a fucking landscaping
business and he already had a truck
and he went out and he bought
this giant fucking, you know,
one of those things with the dual wheels
on the back and this fucking giant
Bedley you put cattle in it, right?
And I was like, holy fuck man,
how much is that thing costs?
And you know,
it was like the 80s it cost like 25 grand,
which was a lot of fucking money back
then. Right? Um, for a truck, you know,
it's like 10 grand more than you pay
the 25 30 grand or some shit. Right?
I was like, Holy Shit Man, you can
afford that. And he was like, yeah,
it's a write off. That's what a
lot of dope safe. And they, they,
it is a write off,
but what they think is,
is that they can write
$30,000 off of their taxes,
which you can't.
What you can do is you can write off,
it's a write off as far as that 30 grand
that you just spent in that truck is
untakeable all right,
it's sitting in whatever you made
that money you made 30 grand.
If it's just sitting there and you
don't put it back into play as far as
reinvesting into your business,
the government will tax you at the end
of the year. You know, on that 30 grand.
And let's say you're in
like a fucking a whatever,
20% tax bracket that you'd,
you'd have to give the government
fucking six grant. Right?
That's it. So the people
more on steak, oh,
I get to write 33 in the end of the year.
If I owed 40 grand in taxes
and I bought a $30,000 truck,
I get to take $30,000 off on my taxes.
You wouldn't,
you just be able to knock off six grand,
right? You're not even knocking it off.
You just not getting taxed on that.
Does that make sense?
Probably doesn't cause I explained it.
So anyways,
when you have your own business,
what you're trying to do is you're
trying to come up with as many fucking
writeoffs as you possibly can't.
Many expenses,
everything you possibly can to
lower your, your basic, your,
uh, whatever your income as far
as what is going to be taxable.
So say you made fucking a hundred grand.
All right?
Your gross to a hundred grand.
The net is what you're left
with after your expenses,
you try to fucking come up with as many
God expenses as you can to get that
hundred grand is far
down as zero as possible.
Ideally you wouldn't want to pay any
fucking taxes as far as these people look.
But the bottom line is you can only do
it so much and if you write off too much,
the IRS is going to show up and be
like, what's this fucking, you know,
60 grand for fucking cheeseburgers,
blah, blah, blah. You tried to write off,
you need going to get busted.
All right?
So what these fucking
super rich people do is,
the first thing they do is they get the
fucking money out of the, out of the,
out of the country
because the IRS has jurisdiction
doesn't go beyond the borders.
So what they do is they just create a
company that doesn't exist. It just,
it's just on paper, right?
So say you make $100 million,
right?
What you do is you go to a country that
doesn't give a shit about America and
let you use it as a tax shelter. You just
come up with some incorporated thing,
like who gives a fuck ink,
right?
And then you just have that company bill,
your company,
a consulting fee for
$100 million or whatever,
the whatever of the hundred billion,
30 40 50 whatever.
You don't want to pay taxes
on whatever you, whatever.
And then you write a check to
that company that doesn't exist.
That's really you.
And then you send it out.
So now it's out of the fucking country.
Okay.
And then what they do is
they open up like 10 other,
these fucking shell companies and they
have those other companies build the
first company. And then the
third one bills, the second
one, the fourth 1 billion.
It's just got the monies fucking gone.
Now the IRS could come in and you'll be
like, what the fuck did you pay somebody?
$100 million consulting fee.
And then you're telling me,
okay,
you paid somebody
$100 million as a consulting fee.
And then you just look at him and go,
yes.
And evidently there's nothing they can
fucking do about it. So then I was out.
I go, all right, so now it's out
of the country and then this,
it's in this other country. How the fuck
do you protect it? And they, and he goes,
well you those countries where these
tax shelters are there in on the scab.
So you just kicked them
10% of the hundred million,
you give him 10 his fucking whatever you
can negotiate. We'll just make it easy.
Here's 10 million bucks.
So what I, you know,
I'll give you 10 million rather than the,
given the government fucking 50
55 60 million at a 100 million,
I'm still fucking up 45 million.
All right.
So then I was like, all right, so
now how do you get the money back?
Because if you know you bring
the money back is to the bank,
they're going to consider
that earned income. Like
where the fuck did you get it?
And this guy was like,
they,
they bring it back into the
country in the form of a loan.
Okay.
Loans aren't taxable, right? Like,
if you get a fucking loan
cause you already paying
interest on it and everything,
they don't tax you. So they just
bring it back in the form of a loan,
whatever the fuck you want to do.
I want to buy a $10 million house.
You have this Shell company that's 10
times removed from the one that you paid
for the consulting fee.
Right.
And they can't follow the
paper trail because it's in
a different country. Right.
You just bring it back into the
country in the form of a loan.
MMM.
And then you go buy a fucking
house. And I guess, I don't know,
you pretend to make payments on the
loan is forgiven by this shell company.
That's still you.
I know.
I just glossed over that and if
anybody has more information on it,
I find it absolutely fascinating.
There's all, there's other ones,
they just pretend that that's
their main business, um,
that shell companies.
So they just act like it's doing the,
I don't know that that's,
that's as far as I can remember that
what he told me and I found that shit
absolutely fucking fascinating
because at the end of the fucking day,
as far as what they're doing,
I know they're fucking over
you and me because you know,
the school systems go down the shitter
because they don't have enough money.
There's a lot of potholes
is all kinds of stuff.
You can't take care of
your homeless people.
You can't build another gleaming
structure for a fucking sports team.
Whatever the fuck it is.
Uh,
the end of the day is fucked up is that,
is these people who are criminals,
they're stealing from other
criminals. As far as my, uh,
conspiracy theory goes to the IRS. It's
just a bunch of fucking crux. Anyway,
so I made they,
it's kind of fascinating watching these
two giant powerful entities fuck with
each other, you know, meanwhile,
yeah.
When the cross hairs, you're
in the crosshairs and we're
all paying Elvis taxes
and that goes Hillary Clinton's
screaming and some Baptist church.
Is she talking about that shit?
Because she is it,
because when you bring
the fucking money back in,
you just don't bring it
in and go out by yourself.
You fucking Ferrari California. What
you do is, I mean, you do do that,
but what else should,
what you also do is you walk around with
nice water cash and you go, oh, hey,
chief of police. Oh, look
at that Birdie over there.
And as he looks over your stuff, a fucking
wad of cash in his pocket, you know,
and then I'll, oh, is it
an election year? Yeah.
Let me get a take 2 million on Trump.
Give me 2.5 on Hillary and a fuck it.
Give me 500 grand.
A Bernie Sanders. What do you mean he's
not taking any money from guys? Like make,
oh, is that right? Oh, well, you
know, whatever. He won't get it.
And if he does, uh, you know, I'll give
3 million to, well, you know, silence.
That's what the fuck they do. And that's,
and that's how they, they, you know,
I don't know.
I'm convinced of that.
I'm convinced as far as
like standup comedy goes,
you know why they're always giving a
shit is because a standup comedians just
organized.
Okay.
And we donated to the campaigns
of people running for two,
the democratic and the Republican parties.
Right.
And then we bought a little ad time on
CNN and on Fox News and all these major
networks.
If we did that,
you'd never see another comedian getting
in trouble for doing a fucking Caitlyn
Jenner joke
anyways.
If anybody has any more information
on that or they can talk about, I,
I don't like if it's really
dry, I just like, um,
I'm fascinated with people that do shit
like that. And then they go to bed,
no one what the fuck they're doing.
And they got to be thinking at some point,
like the wolves gotta be coming to the
door at some point. Hang on one second.
I got to answer this. All
right. So I'm back. Of course.
I completely forget what the
fuck out where I ended off. Um,
but what I really learned when I was,
you know,
listening to this lawyer telling
me all this shit, um, oh,
I know I seen the balls at that takes
to go to bed at night knowing one at any
point. Like, all of a sudden the fucking
feds are gonna kick in your fucking door.
But I think that these guys
are like the smarter ones.
And when you watch like American greed,
what I noticed when I watched them,
all of their fuckery was within
the borders of the United States,
which you just, I mean, if you, I
guess if you're too dumb to know,
you don't realize you're not going to get
away with it forever. But like, once I,
um,
after talking to this guy,
it just seems like anybody who just
tries to have their entire illegal entity
within the borders of one country
is, uh, you're just on borrowed time.
So I think when you watch American greed,
what you're really seeing is,
is the hacks of, uh, you know,
you always see these fucking idiots.
They buy a house,
they get all these fucking cars and
they have some strippers come over.
Oh my fucking laptop.
Oh,
that was a laptop hitting hardboard
floors. Come on. Come on baby.
Come on. Come around. You're all right.
Hang in there and help us on the way.
Fuck yeah.
Ah, you fucking motherfucker. Steve
Jobs is laughing somewhere right now.
He's laughing at me cause I got to give
him money and he also know this can be
another little kids. Get to
put it together. All right.
It's saved. It's saved. Um,
okay.
So anyways,
uh,
let's read a little bit of fucking Ad
Shit here before my screen goes dark.
Hang on a second. I find
that shit. I find it, um,
I find all that stuff fucking amazing.
It's really, really interesting.
If you just remove yourself from it,
the humanity of it or whatever, uh,
and all the people that it's affecting
and kids not getting better school books
and shit. If you just look at
the fucking game that's going on,
it's really fucking
interesting. All right. Oh Shit.
We got somebody new here. We got somebody
new. This is Joe Rogan's company,
the Great Joe Rogan, uh, from the, uh,
Joe Rogan experience podcast.
He might recognize him from a g,
I don't know,
the first 200 UFC paper views.
Um,
one of the best standup comics
I've ever seen. All right.
Here's this company on it.
On it is a health and wellness company
focused on inspiring peak performance
through unique products and actionable
information. I can already tell you,
this is written to smartly,
so I'm going to fuck this up with strategy
from leading professional athletes
and medical practitioners.
Practitioners on it has focused on
creating earth grown nutrient based
supplements and foods as well as
unconventional fitness equipment.
All based on the latest science
research on conventional fitness.
He got like the leg curl thing going the
other way. You break your fucking knees,
they're on.
It believes that supplementing your
diet with earth grown ingredients
challenging your body with innovative
fitness methods and supporting cognitive
functions of the brain are
all pieces to the complete,
to the complete approach to wellness.
They call total human
optimization optimization.
Please don't write that word again.
I'll fuck it up.
Find out more at [inaudible] dot com
slash bill o n n I t.com/bill alpha.
Brain instant is a delicious all natural
stimulant free drink mix that helps
support memory, focus and
processing speed. Joe,
you got anything here to
help somebody read out loud?
Better go to onnit.com/bill to get
a free trial of Alpha brain instant.
I know somebody using this shit is
actually saying it's the Shit Alpha brain.
Instant is a delicious,
I already said this right?
All natural stimulant free
drinks that helps support memory,
focus and processing speed.
I already said this,
I need this shit and he'd cases of this
stuff to double blind randomized placebo
controlled studies conducted by the
Boston Center for memory showed that
subjects taking alpha brain demonstrated
a significant improvement in areas of
executive function,
verbal memory and processing speed.
What are you waiting for?
A you got nothing to lose and a series
edge to gain ignites your brain with
Alpha instant.
Try it.
Try It for free on [inaudible] dot
com slash bill now that's o n n I
t.com/build.
Try It free today.
Jesus Christ, they had a fucking
brain cramp. Just trying to read that.
You know, I like shakes. I like a
delicious shake that comes from the earth.
You know, it helps me remember where I
put the fucking stirrer for it. All right,
blue apron. Everybody. You need to,
you need to know how to
cook unless you filthy rich,
unless you got a fucking
shell company, right? Uh,
not only do you need to feel like
you know your way around a kitchen,
but cooking at means eating healthier
and saving money instant instead of
ordering expensive takeout. Again,
it becoming a fat fuck whose kid? No,
but where do you start? Blue
Apron has you covered? Yeah.
You don't start with a peanut
butter and jelly sandwich.
You want to hit the ground running
for less than $10 per meal.
Blue Apron delivers all the fresh
ingredients you need to create home cooked
meals. Just follow the easy
step by step instructions.
Each meal can be prepared
in 40 minutes or less.
No overwhelming trips to the grocery
store where no more sad takeout nall no
matter your dietary preferences,
blue apron makes it a breeze to discover
and prepared dishes like steak and eggs
with Kimchi fried rice.
I would fuck the eat that right now.
Chicken Kay,
who's soy soup locked in?
Crispy wanton noodles.
I'd wait for on that one.
Spice Catfish with pay a lease style
rice and creamy Saffron Aeolian IOD debt,
cauliflower I that looks like manure.
Many Uri, m, e, U, N, I, e,
r e and it's underlined in red so it
wasn't spelled correctly or it's such a
brand new fucking word. I would need it
delicious and good for you right now.
It's made out of a rock they
got from fucking math right now.
You can get your first two meals
for free@blueapron.com slash bird.
That's blue apron.com/burr ha blue
apron.com a better way to cook.
All right. How many more of these
fucking things do I have? All right,
we're going to and to then.
All right. And you guy,
are you already listened to fucking two
of these? Let's get back to the podcast,
shall we? All right.
Um, oh Jesus. Oh Jesus.
I got to bring it up. My
Boston Bruins, unfortunately.
Um, after a big, big win
over the Detroit Red Wings,
uh, got beat down by
Ottawa, six to one and a,
we're out of it. You know, it's funny,
we'd beat Detroit the game before
and then because we lost Detroit,
get in and do you know,
there was actually a certain amount
of fucking red wing fence that we're
actually talking shit, the smart ones
were going, hey, thanks for losing.
And then the other ones look
good fucking 26 years in a row.
We've been in the playoffs.
Yeah, it's impressive.
But this year you backed in like
a bitch. You went in. As far as,
I don't know what you fuck.
I mean,
because it team that you couldn't even
beat when it counts two days before,
you know who fucking manhandled you.
I don't know what you're excited about.
You know, you like the fat chick who
got, you know, fucking ass to the Prob,
you know, you're all exceeded.
She just wanted to be there.
Who's getting know you're there for the
fucking buffet and then you go and home
crying.
That's what I'm predicting for Detroit.
Your makeup's going to be running
by game three of the first series.
I'm fucking with you.
I have no hate for anybody that's
in the playoffs this year. Uh,
I think I'm going to one. And
I've always liked Detroit. Um,
cause when I was growing up
they never won shit. Yeah.
Big thing is they had one it since
1955 with Gordie Howe and um,
they weren't in the middle
of a 40 year drought. Um,
before they got a team
around Eisenman and Nah, man,
that was what great times watching hockey,
that fucking avalanche Redwings
fucking rivalry. That was the best.
It was the first time when I lived in
La and the games came home at five and I
totally got back into hockey and
you get all this original six oh,
is to burst up. Sorry.
Buchard Yada here. So, um,
so this year I think in the
east, uh, I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna root for two fucking teams this
year in the east and the West. Uh, the,
I'm rooting for the capitals to push
through to get to the finals and a,
as much as I liked the kings and the
black hawks, just to switch it up,
I'd love to see the Dallas stars or a,
the St Louis Blues,
you know, somebody different, you know,
Saint Louis Blues who's kidnapped fans
have been waiting for fucking ever.
They have been in the league.
They're part of the expansion
six that came in 1967.
All right.
The NHL was a 16 league.
Um, before that, right
after the depression,
there was a lot of people that I didn't
realize this either. There was a,
there was a bunch of other teams,
not a bunch,
but there was like fleece
for other fucking teams are
something that all folded
after the, the, uh,
the depression and the six that survived
and became known as the original six.
Um, so in 1967 sixteenths
came in. Can you name
off the top of my head? Let's
see. There was the flyers.
The penguins.
Okay.
The North Stars. Oh, Jesus.
The California golden seals.
Ah Man. I used to know this
off the top of my head. Wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Capital's didn't come
in until the early seventies. Fuck.
Make St Louis Blues. Jesus Christ. It
just brought them up. One more. One more.
Was it a Seattle team?
Cleveland Barons.
It's with the fucking golden seals became,
didn't they?
All the fucking La kinks.
Yeah, the La Kings way.
The fuck out there. And that was
funny when for the Golden Seals,
like folded or to Cleveland,
they went to Cleveland.
Just like the dreams of all the
sports fans there. They did.
They just fucking died. A slow,
miserable death. And I'm like,
that franchise just died out.
Nobody bought it and went nowhere.
It just went to Cleveland and fucking
died. So for the longest time,
the only game in town I'll fucking west
was the king's every fucking road trip
they had was like at least a three, four
hour fucking Denver didn't have a team.
Vancouver didn't have a team.
Edmonton, Calgary, they had nothing.
They were just out there by themselves,
you know,
basically fucking whatever
actresses couldn't bang.
A Los Angeles dodger are an la ramp.
That's basically, they got sloppy thirds.
That's what was going on. So
anyways, yeah, we lost. So, uh,
graduations to the flyers and the fucking
red wings. There was two spots left,
t three teams vying for it.
And uh,
we didn't get in and like clockwork,
the day after,
we don't get in.
What Boston sports writer who doesn't
watch hockey do you think piled on
immediately? And I as always calls
for the wrong head to be chopped off.
Good old Dan Shaughnessy the
noodle headed [inaudible] himself.
Who doesn't watch hockey,
doesn't like hockey chimes in,
something's gotta be done.
It's time
based on what Dan, all the hockey.
You never fucking watch. Hello Julian.
This was actually one of his
finest coaching performances
of the year of, I mean,
of his career.
They traded the entire fucking team away.
Basically they treat it was what they
got rid of over the last few years.
Tyler's Sagan,
um,
Johnny Boyd Shuck Doggie fucking fresh.
They're fucking Milan. Lou
Cheecha was just, I was like,
we got nothing. We got nothing
left. I now know looking Marshawn,
we got Bergie was still had
shower shower's older now,
but basically coos can do
anybody fucking watches hockey.
Looked at the Bruins who was like,
you know what,
this is a rebuilding year and
all the way up to like mid March.
Clo Julian had this, this rebuilding
year team was the third seat.
Everybody was bunched together.
We hit a bad patch, you know,
went out West tough fucking run. We
lost some games and next thing you know,
we were fighting for the playoff lives
as they say. And we didn't win. I mean,
I mean, I don't know if
you get, I would get,
if anybody's heads going
to get chopped off,
you chop the head off whoever
made all those fucking trades.
But you know the bottom line is the guy
who made the first half of those already
got his head chopped off and then you got,
was it Michael O'connell?
You've got to give this guy a chance,
right?
You can't just go one and
done a fucked up with deputy.
They just cave Clo Julian of fucking
watch. We're having the most Vic,
the most wins ever have any Bruins coach.
He got us our first fucking
Stanley Cup in like, what was it?
Almost 40 years and then what? A
couple of years later, he doesn't,
not a coach hockey anymore.
Okay.
Why is it time Dan Shaughnessy
why is it time?
Cause it's too early
in the baseball season.
He got nothing to write about his guys
forever calling for somebodies head.
You know what Dan, you don't want
to take, it's time for you to do.
It's time for you to stop writing about
hockey or maybe watching maybe fucking
five games at a goddamn season.
Unfuckable fuck that guy.
I swear to God at the end of the day,
I think he's from New York City.
The way he just tries to pull apart
fucking teams. It's unbelievable.
You know what I mean?
He's like somebody with some
mob guys Goumarre that they
ended up having a whack,
cause she can't keep her
fucking mouth shut. Oh Jesus.
Pillco wheezy on the guy's just
trying to sell. So fuckin pay bus. Um,
I don't really hate Dan Shaughnessy.
I don't know the guy,
but I can tell you right now,
uh,
he's one of the few people that
looks less athletic than me
anyways.
Any who as I as I was
talking about earlier, um,
I've been doing the whole fucking clean
living thing since I got back from a yet
another lost bachelor party.
Weekend Slash standup dates run with,
uh, with my buddies. Yeah.
MMM.
First he and Bart. Nick and a,
so this whole week, no booze,
no porn, no cigars, nothing. I got the
cigar. I think I got that thing on,
on fucking lockdown.
MMM.
I don't have them in my house.
I think about do,
I don't think about doing it as much and
I only had one cigar in March and I'm
gonna try to just have one
this month, although, um,
okay.
Yeah.
Look,
I'm thinking about only having one and
then I'm also thinking about having a
fucking cigar night over here.
I might do that because
I have like fucking,
okay.
I Dunno about 10 cigar friends.
Unless you smoke cigars,
you don't know what that means.
But it's just people that call a,
I'm going to smoke. You
want to come by, right.
So all of a sudden I have 10 opportunities
a month. People call me a, come on man,
come by and smoke and smoke. And next
thing you know you smoked in like seven,
eight, nine, 10 of them.
So I'm going to invite all of them over
to my house the same fucking night and
I'll smoke one cigar with all 10 of them
rather than smoking one each with 10
individuals. How does that math work?
Right? Then I'll create a shell company.
Um,
okay.
So anyways,
so I bought this time magazine on watch
an Internet porn and how it's fucking up
kids like the,
you know,
the amount of shit that they see before
they even get their first fucking hand
job. It turns them into light,
these fucking sociopath.
And I got to admit reading
some of the articles,
like I could relate to a lot
of the shit that was going on.
So I'm really just going to fucking
going to try to stop that cold Turkey.
You know,
I got to stop looking at that shit.
Fuck, I'm sorry. See this clean lists.
What clean live does
free at 10 30 at night.
I'm fucking Yani all ready
to go to bed right now.
Get my fucking jam jams and here and here.
I am supposed to be there for you.
You guys are sitting there at work.
The last fucking thing you need.
You probably already had a doughnut.
You're going to sick a sugar crash
here in a minute. And here I am,
young in a on Ya.
Um,
so
what else can I talk about
here? Oh yeah, clean living.
If you try and have some clean living,
do not watch the Lemmy documentary,
which I just watched for the second time.
Um,
makes you want to have a couple
of drinks cause you like,
look how long that guy fucking lift
all this shit that he did. You know.
Fuck you're good. All
right, 39 minutes in.
I could do the last 21 minutes here
without yachting. Here we go. Here we go.
All right. Um, by the way,
I don't for a people
out there, uh, you know,
I mentioned some of the
helicopter shit. I did. I did.
I tell you I finally did that,
that Solo flight that I wanted
to do from long beach and I,
I went through the Bravo airspace with
the plane's taking off over you. You know,
at lax, came right around,
looked at the house,
flew over the fucking house that they,
uh,
the horses head from Godfather right down
sunset over to El Monte and then back
to, um, oh,
I did tell you that because that's when
I saw the old guy fall off the fucking
scooter. I'm sorry. I thought, I
didn't think that I told you that one.
I was just thinking about
that shit the other day.
Of course my fucking headphones go
out and what they would have fucking,
I knew it. I fucking knew it. I
knew that was gonna happen. Um,
so anyways,
I was at the comedy store on Saturday
night and I was trying out this, uh,
this new chunk that I've been fucking
with for the last couple of months.
And I finally got it down. I said
it, it's perfect as I could say it.
Of course I didn't, I didn't fucking know
I didn't tape. Of course I didn't tape.
Why would I take that would've
been the smart thing to do,
but whatever I said it, so I'll
get it, I'll get it back. And, um,
I felt fucking great about it.
And then today I got text messages from
two different comedians telling me that
they love the new shit that I was doing.
It, it just, I just made my fucking day.
So I'm really excited about,
uh,
getting that shit together because I want
to do another special this year. And,
um, I got some stuff on
my act. That's funny,
but I just feel like the topics have
been done before so much try to like,
you know, you know, push that shit to the
wayside. Maybe that'll just be on the,
some of those topics. We'll
just be on like the, uh,
when I released the vinyl of
the Madison Square Garden Show,
I'll just keep them on that one.
There'll be some extra jokes that won't
be the same material. I don't know.
I'm just excited about the,
uh, the next few months,
how that Shit's going
to turn out. But, uh,
before we get into the
questions this week, everybody,
I have to give a shout
out to rogue fitness,
whoever dental was listening
to the podcast. I was
breaking that balls. You know,
I'm making a gym. I'm paying somebody
to build a gym for me out my garage,
a little gym there in the back. And I
got all my shit through rogue fitness.
They just had the best shit out there.
And I was just joking with them that, uh,
you know, how dare you not send me Free
Shit. I didn't even ask him for it.
He just immediately came to the podcast
breaking the fucking balls and they
listened to the one where
there was me and Nia,
Nia told me to get the
regular looking weights,
just the ones that look like iron
or whatever. And I wanted the,
I wanted the color for once and
she thought that they were corny.
So all of a sudden I just
got this shipment of these
colorful weights and I was
laughing going, Oh man, I must have
fucked it up. I got the colorful ones.
So I wrote them trying to ask how
to send it back and they said no,
we listened to the podcast and they sent
me some free weight and they sent me a
tee shirts. I, you know, rogue
fitness. I was fucking around.
You didn't have to do that. You
guys are solid man. And I'm,
I can't wait to uh, you know, use your,
your equipment cause it's, you know,
it's great. Made in the USA. All good
stuff. Oh look who's here. The busy body.
The lovely Nia. Did you
get some Thai food? Yes.
Did you grab a mic or do you want to eat?
Do you want to eat?
I got another, uh, 17 minutes here.
17 minutes to Mike's were in
the closet. Oh, why don't you,
why don't you sit down and help
me through with the questions.
Why do I hook it up? Cause I am, I am a,
I'm actively doing the podcast
right now actively. Oh,
Jesus. You know, if he going to
be in a mood like that. Oh Geez.
Is
What's that?
You just walked out on
me anyways. All right,
well I'm going to start
reading the first one then.
You don't care. All right. Oh,
by the way, you know something,
I was taking my dog out for a walk today.
You know,
we were walking up into the park there
and this is before she puked and I
decided to turn around and come home.
She started nowhere. She started yakking.
Uh, made me feel bad. I was like,
Jesus, I hope it wasn't something I did.
It wasn't hot out or anything.
Um,
another Yale has a very sensitive stomach.
Well,
another fucking group of people come up
the second they get to the end of the
park,
they just fucking don't say what park.
They go to the fucking park and they
fucking take the leashes off the fucking
dogs come right up to my dog. And they're
like, yeah, no worries. Don't worry.
She's friendly, she's friendly.
It's like, my dog isn't my dog.
My dog is ignores other dogs.
It chills and then we're like, when
you are bugging my dog, it doesn't go.
It never has the, hey, can you do
me a favor? Can you knock it off?
It immediately just grabs you.
Like,
remember Friday the 13th when Jason was
under the Cot and grabbed that dude's
head and reached up, I guess it
was the chicken, the first one.
I met a dog tonight who just
didn't like anybody and I've,
but I realized quickly what it was his
owner was holding him and anytime anyone
came towards the honor, like,
oh, hey, oh, what a cute dog.
The dog was stark rally and I,
and it's so funny because he said to one
of the people, oh, pet him. And I'm like,
no, your dog isn't,
doesn't want to be pet.
It growls at everybody.
And I think the dog was protecting the
owner. So anytime, you know, like I said,
anyone that came towards him,
he started growling, but right.
He was so clueless that he was like, oh
he's fine, just pet him. And I'm like no,
no, you can't pet the dog. If it's ground
at people. I cannot judge him. Our dogs,
a psycho dog went to bite me like it
actually kind of like put, it's the,
its walked across the fucking Bro.
I went over and it put its,
it's put my finger in between its teeth
and didn't chomp down. But it was,
I was yes, but it was a biting behavior.
So a little dog man with
little dogs with people.
They'd be riding around in convertibles,
you know, like a corvette or some shit.
All right, let's, let's leave
in 11 minutes. All right.
So can you want to do one,
one question? Yeah, let's do it.
All right, job. Hey
Billy. Baret um, I, we're,
I'm working part time
job and I have a problem.
Let me see if there's a
relationship one here.
Why can't old boyfriend, can I not
be involved in the the job one? Well,
I just feel like I always
give the guy advice.
Well, maybe it's time to shake it up a
little bit less. So it's trying to do,
have you given some lady advice
on some relationship? Huh?
Oh God. Are you going to
go on a feminist rant here?
You know women can answer other fucking
questions too, you know? Yeah. All right,
let's get another question that doesn't
have to do with relationships. Hey,
you know,
I'm trying to give you a nice softball
here in front of the lob it over the
fucking place. A fucking
softball. Anything Person
Rolling your head? Here we go.
When all reality show me there.
All right.
I'm working a part time job and I have
a problem related to it. All right.
The job is I work at a fucking ice cream.
It's at an ice cream place in my town and
the second time I worked there a while
back,
I had a godawful shift.
I didn't have all the kinks of the job
worked yet and I was working with someone
I didn't know, which made me more
nervous. The night quickly became, uh,
you know this word Koffka esque
parade. Who's calm? Who's that?
Oh No, he's a writer. Is he a philosopher?
I'm going to have a
particular political view.
I think he died in a boating accident.
Whatever. Mommy, Inez. Kafkaesque.
Joseph Kafka. I think he's a one
of those. He's like a philosopher.
J Lo no, four. She goes on tour.
I'm not going to lie and say I know
exactly. Who can we Google it though?
I really feel like it's a Joseph Kafka.
We just read the fucking
question. Oh, right. Okay.
The night quickly became a Kafka
as parade of a horrific errors.
I screwed up, orders, stock things wrong,
et Cetera, and by the end of the night,
my coworker was audibly and visibly
disgusted with me and she should have been
John's Kafka. Okay. Sorry. Chairman.
Language writer of novels
and short stories. Who is?
Oh my God.
He died the day after my birthday
and therein lies the tragedy.
All right. Here we go. All
right. Put down your phone.
Try to align what car I was going to
say. It's surreal. I was right. Yes.
I'm not entertaining.
Sorry.
Entertaining for people.
Kafka ask elements often
appear in existential works,
but the term has transcended the
literary realm to apply to real life
occurrences in situations that
are in comprehensively complex,
bizarre or a logical where
we go Franz Kafka. All right.
Okay.
All right. So the ladies or the lady
is, was upset with him and he's saying,
you know, audibly and visibly disgusted
with me and she should have been okay.
She's in college and I'm in high school
so luckily I never had to work with her
again after the summer was over
and she went back to her classes.
But even as recently as spring break,
I've heard she's still
talking shit about me.
Yeah. Oh, you heard this all the
way back. She's at some college.
How did you hear that? Yeah, they
were all on the Facebook. Um,
oh Grandpa,
I love saying the Huh?
You guys taking the Molly
those? No, you wouldn't.
You wouldn't know Molly, if you are the
grampy like Molly ecstasy, whatever.
It just an old guy thing.
Yeah,
that was my dad when he used
to get mad at my sister Christ.
Is she on that Internet Internet?
Um,
it's almost summer again and I'm almost
definitely going to have to face her if
I work regularly. If I do, I know for
a fact I'll fuck things up immediately.
Purely from England
anxiety. Hmm. Dude, you should
be like to fucking older,
wiser guy crushing it and then you fucking
banger confidence and my friend, wait,
what? What do you mean banger? It's
all there. Why didn't you what?
What does it all there? You can make
her a mall. She'd get two straws.
You know why? Cause she's
the older woman. Right.
And she has to be tamed by getting
that deck. Is that what it is?
I didn't say that you did.
No,
really go after the competence and then
get banger because your life is like a
fucking movie from the 19 20th Bill
where the guy is slapping a woman around.
I was like, get it together.
See? And she says, oh,
he completely fucked up cosmetic.
This is like one of those
coming of age movies.
Warn the begin beginning the
nerds like, Yo, walk away from me.
The nerd is looking at the cheerleader
and she's dating the impossible Dick with
the blonde, wavy hair. Somebody
does a fucking triple Lindy.
Okay,
Jesus Christ. I went sideways,
Huh? The fuck just happened there?
I said,
cause I'm not going to be able to get
awarded and defense of what I was saying,
right? He makes an ass out of himself
in front of this. You know the soul,
the fucking broad. All right.
See, this isn't sexist.
Now you come back, you're a little
older, a little wiser, right?
You're a year older, you still growing,
you filled out a little bit, right?
All of a sudden you're crushing it.
He make it a fucking couple banana splits
in a smoothie all at the same time and
she's just like, wow, this is it. The
man that I left the year, you know,
the year before, all of a sudden you
guys are working closely. You know,
ice cream is always romantic.
What kind of fucked of advisor
you get given anything and fun.
I'm telling this kid
can shake it off he goes.
If I don't work often,
I could lose my job as we've got more
employees than we need and I really have a
great setup. Now that I've
learned it, the work is easy.
I basically pick my own hours and
my bosses by far the sweetest,
racist homophobe I've ever met in my life.
Any ideas besides the obvious murder?
He said your standup is killer.
I hope I can see perform
sometime. Yeah, dude, you got to,
you got to grow a Dick here,
man. You're the fucking man.
You've been there for a year. You know
what's going on. Just be like a, I dunno.
Just, I don't know. What do you
do? You have a crush on this woman.
If she's not going to fuck you,
then what?
Do you care what she
thinks is that bad now?
Yes.
What is spiking has to do with it.
Does have confidence in yourself
and do the job. Also, this is,
this is a high school
person that's writing in.
This is somebody who's making ice cream
cones and he's scared out of his mind
about some woman who is not
easy and he's not even fucking,
he doesn't want to ask her out.
What is the problem?
She's going to yell at you about
the way you put the fucking
cherries or something because
as a job and he's in, you know,
worried about how he's
going to perceive you.
Remember what it was like to be at that
age where you know every little thing
you know means disaster and the
bigger picture. Oh, so is he,
cause it's just a job a little bit.
Yeah.
I think you're worried a little too
much about nothing. Just do your job,
do your thing,
don't even worry about it.
And there's plenty of other
jobs out there by the way,
and he should just be totally,
yeah.
Cocky.
Which she comes in.
What up bitch? Yeah, I'm sure
that'll go over real well.
Float. Do [inaudible] kiss
with the little piece side? No,
no honey. Yeah. Ice Cream had to decide
we pussy or nothing.
Jesus Christ pushing all the chips.
And this is the world series of poker.
All right. Hey there, Billy boy. I'm on.
I'm a new listener to your podcast,
but a long time fan of you stand up.
I was wondering if you could help me
out with it. A dilemma I'm facing.
So my weed dealer put the moves on me.
My last time I was at her place.
Uh,
nothing came of it,
but I could tell she was trying
to get me to fucker until now.
I thought it was weird that she began to
me pot for practically. Yeah, nothing.
Wow.
She's cool.
And I've hung out with her at her
place many times to just smoke weed,
just, just as well. I'm single,
so I have no problem getting some
strange pussy that falls into my lap.
The problem is that she's a very heavy,
broad,
and completely unattractive. Oh, Gigi Age.
But she sells the best weed in
the area. Dude, this is fucking,
this has all the makings of the
great first 10 pages of a script.
We've established who the characters are.
Oh yeah.
Now we've got the Rabo
super far with this premise.
Yeah.
Oh God. You know what? You know what
I love. You know what I love to do?
You know that guy can help it.
You know that guys just want to fuck you.
Women know that you use it to
your advantage to get shit.
And then when we admit that that's what
we want to do. You look though, oh my God,
I really,
someone would tell a story about a guy
who was getting thrown pussy left and
right and doesn't know what to do with it.
And it's like a coming of age and I'm
sure he's also fighting with his friends a
little bit about like,
what dorm are you going to stay in?
And it's just hilarious.
Yeah.
He's got this heavy broad
that he's not attracted to.
Who's this fucking weed dealer?
Yeah. She's got the best
weed. Yeah. Knows he wants,
she wants to fuck them. What was the
rest of the story? Does he want it?
This is a fuck. Come on.
Seth Rogan would crush this.
Hmm.
Ah, you are in it. You know what?
You're hungry. You're like him.
When that snickers commercial,
I don't know who you are,
where Seth Rogan would write a phenomenal
transcendent script that Jonah Hill
would act out and it would just be
like, wow, is this what it's like?
What is wrong with you?
Huh?
I like all of those people and I like
those movies. You don't like hot tub,
Chubby and awkward and not know what
to do with your life. Oh, what are you?
Why are you being a jerk? I don't
know. You're being a jerk, right? Yeah.
You're hungry. I am being a little bit
of a generic, apologized to Seth Rogan.
I'm also okay. Yeah, you are.
You're a little out of
sorts here. Okay. All right.
You let you burn burning bridges in this
town, Sweetie. Let me tell you something.
Those bridges don't come back,
but she sells the best weed in
the area I don't want. All right?
I don't want to not fucker
and then ever cut me off,
but at the same time I feel that I,
if I do fucker then I'm no better than
an addicted crack whore doing a line off
some fat guy's Dick.
Maybe. Uh, so guess what,
when it comes down to what do
I fuck my ugly drug dealer for?
[inaudible] oh my God.
What do I just question or do I just
find a new dealer was super urban.
Pay More money. Thanks. Hope all
is well with you ginger. Fuck.
Cause she had ginger. Fuck. Um,
okay.
Have you ever heard the expression
don't shit where you eat?
Yeah.
Don't fuck your weed dealer.
Yeah. Don't just don't fucker.
This is a business relationship.
Keep it business like lie and started
talking about how we as a girlfriend.
No, just buy weed from her and
like just let it be business. Yes.
Stop Smoking with them.
And also like,
I mean maybe she's
desperate for your cock,
but maybe you're like reading into it.
She might be trying to fuck you
and the next dude, so she's, she's,
she's a drug dealer. She's hustling.
She's hustling for like customers.
She's hustling for Dick.
Like don't get excited.
You know you're not the only one bra.
So you think, yeah, but she's given
away for next to nothing. If she does
that, she's not gonna make any money.
True. She's making it
another way is, I dunno,
I feel like just don't
fuck your weed dealer.
That just sounds like a disaster written
all over it or get yourself a really
good connect.
Now have that in your back pocket.
So if you do decide that the only reason
why you would fuck your weed dealer is
if you actually want to fuck her.
Not because you're so desperate
for the best we'd ever have.
You really had the best weed
and like your entire city.
Probably not so calm down.
Don't matter dealer. Uh Huh.
I mean, you know, you kind of enter
the habit. You're not just going, hey,
can I get a hit off that when you fucking
go in there week after week to the
point that the [inaudible]
weed dealers are a dime a dozen though,
there's, it's not like a specialty,
but just say this fucking chick is
the vcs buying so much weed off.
If she's developing feelings for,
she's not,
he might be cute. Jesus, you might have
a little crush, but like it's not that.
It's,
my point is it's not that serious.
Don't fuck your weed dealer unless you
want to have a problem with your weed
dealer and you didn't want to cheat. You
don't want to have a problem. Trust me.
We dealer wants to fuck one
of her customers. Course.
I completely believe it.
I'm just saying just don't, don't
go there. It's not worth it.
That's my bottom line. She's usually
not this grumpy. You guys all right.
The grumpy old boyfriend,
texts wife.
Oh, Billy cheese balls. Where'd
that come from? I don't know.
It just fucking make up names
for me. Oh, okay. All right.
Very happily married for 25 years to
the hottest wife and mother of our three
sons.
She's in spectacular shape and beautiful
while on vacation in palm springs.
Bang. Right. Just scape herself in shape.
Yeah. We're visual animals.
We're visual animals.
I know
there's a reason why all those gay
guys are walking around with six packs
because they know what
they're trying to attract.
Yeah.
Don't bring the gaze into this.
Do you think all those gay guys wanting
to go to the gym that much? They have to.
If they don't, that's the end of the Dick
Train and they know it. They know it.
All right. So anyways, uh,
while on vacation in Palm Springs,
I caught a glimpse of her phone
screen and saw a text from PB.
Pb was asking,
how's the weather?
So I asked her who PB is after a
little persuasion. She replied,
it's Dave.
Dave is a boyfriend from her high
school years and he is a former fiance.
This is awful.
She promised it was nothing.
I asked if they had seen each other
underneath a different name though. Yeah.
That's pretty suspect when you have
the presence name saved under an alias.
The B was PB mean. Wait, there's a penis.
Brilliant. Brilliant
Penis. She's dyslexic.
Penis, Babe. Penis,
Pussy Banger.
Maybe.
I'm sure it's something between the three.
It was a capital p and then a lowercase
B. I don't know why he did it. All right.
If you guys have any suggestions
what PB would stand for? Come on.
What social media is
all about? It goes, uh,
she promised it was nothing.
I asked if,
if they had seen each other or
slept together. She said, no,
I believe her. Okay. Oh, Jesus.
It's a pharmacy up fiance. Does
he mean now? I guess now or maybe.
I just want to believe her. She is
otherwise a very honest person. Well,
I sent Dave a text and here's what I said.
Oh,
beautiful.
I'm only going to say this once.
You're nothing but a sleazy cock sucker.
You've crossed the line of decency.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Or better yet go choke
to death on some poor.
Something that he's Dick. Wait,
what? So it's a, it's a homophobic.
He was upset. Okay. Never
communicate with my wife,
capital letters ever.
If you pursuer in any way,
I'll cut your dick off with a rusty saw
blade and shove it down your throat.
I hope you're getting the message here.
His reply understood.
This is the less text
name and numbered deleted.
My question to you is,
was I harsh enough with team
and I'm not sure what to do with Bob.
My wife,
she deleted him from our context
and she said she has no need to ever
communicate with him again.
What are your thoughts?
Wow,
I think you need to let it be then.
I mean I that was,
I have to say that was masterful.
All that text that he sent to PB,
Aka Dave. I think he got the
message with that one now.
What do you think?
Uh,
so do you think she banged him? No,
she was probably sending, flirting,
borderline inappropriate text messages.
No ebay years. Those beautiful the day I
took you to prom. Like that type of shit.
Why are you, why we went on the left
side than that? I don't fucking know. I,
the recent
Bill Barr?
Probably what it said some like that's
what you're making because you know how
you are. You probably would've said
some inappropriate shit over text.
I mean that's what, yeah.
Is that what texting is?
It's what is, how do I, how do I,
how do I get to the texting to us?
Well, lose weight. How texting works.
All right. Advice from a, for
a fellow ginger. Oh, moving
right. Moving right along.
Right along fellow ginger from Finland
here.
I have a decision to make and would
appreciate some advice from a wise and
experienced man like you.
Ever since I was a kid. Oh,
you've just every fucking thing.
Ever since I was a kid,
I've wanted to be an airline pilot.
I'm 19 years old and I'm graduating
from high school in December. Yes.
Here we finish high school later.
I was just going to say, is that when they
graduate from high school and Finland?
Yeah.
Then you
guys in Mirka. Alright. I've,
I have till the end of the year
to decide what I want to study.
I've always had a plan after
high school. I would want to, uh,
go to a flight academy and become a pilot.
But now I've started to question if that's
what I really want to do for a living
living. I mean an airline
pilot is an incredible job,
absolutely love flying and we get to
travel a bunch of seal kinds of amazing
places,
et Cetera.
Plus I would get to the sun every day
without burning my Nordic ultra pasty,
pasty skin. Um, the
captain makes six figures,
which is plenty enough for
me since I'm not into money.
My only problem with being a pilot is
that I would never be completely free,
meaning that for the rest of my life
working for some other douchebag, uh,
would, would decide for me when I
can come to work and where I can fly.
The idea of being tied up to a company
and having some con making all the
decisions for me scares the
shit out of me when I'm older.
I want to be able to do
things on an impulse without
asking permission from, uh,
some capital letters,
other men also pilots.
But you're just over there taking
pictures of shit. And you, um,
also pilots spent a lot of time away from
home and someday when I start a family
and have kids, I want to spend as
much time as possible with them.
So that could be a problem as well.
Flying planes for living
would be a dream job,
but we'd get in the way of my other
dream of being completely my own man and
free. What do you think? Should
I go study something else? No.
What you should do is still
be into the aviation thing.
You just figure out a way to do
what you want to do within aviation.
Okay. I will equate it to the job
that I have. I am a standup comedian,
which opens up all these doors
into the entertainment world,
which a lot of them you think you want
to run through until you get to the other
side. And then you realize what you're
talking about is like, holy fuck,
I thought I had the world by the balls.
If I got this,
I thought I would be the pimp.
And then you realize that you're
actually the whore. So you have to,
um,
what I would do if I was you is I
would still go to flight school.
I would learn how to fly.
And then what I would do is rather
than going flying for some commercial
airline, there's gotta be some
other cool shit that you can do,
like flying for site, seeing tours.
You're not into money, right?
Maybe you do that.
Maybe you ended up having that business
and other people fly for you and you get
to fly around. Um, what
other jobs are they?
There's fighting forest
fires and you know,
you do that and like helicopters and
planes and that type of shit. Yeah.
Um,
listen,
just by being a pilot already,
you got some sort of
renegade spirit in your,
so I'm sure there's plenty of fucking
jobs that you can get in aviation.
I think it pretty much any job there's,
there's a way to be in the matrix and
then there's a way to be outside. Like,
you know, he's a renegade, that one, you
know, don't get tied down with that guy.
You can definitely do it.
Right. What do you think? Yeah.
So he should still be a pilot to do you
love to fly. It's what you want to do. Um,
but you know, there's, there's all kinds
of shit you can fly for fucking airline.
Make your money and then leave
and then go do something else.
Like start your own business. I Dunno,
you're laughing at me right now.
He's 19.
He's got the whole worry he's got,
he's got the world by the fucking short
hairs and all. Sounds it all sounds good.
I was listening to a
podcast from wild back then.
You were shitting on the
NFL having games in London.
He said those games a huge things for us.
European football fans.
And believe it or not, there are tons
of football fans here in Europe. Uh,
the Games always sell out and I fell.
Football sells out there. Who knows?
All right, here's new. Who, whose,
here's the last one. I'm stuttering here.
Okay. Guess what? I just
time traveled in the podcast.
Let me give you a second to just wrap
your head around this because I know it's
always weird when this happens.
I actually finished out the podcast
with the lovely Nia with my fucking
batteries wore out and I didn't
even notice we had a nice debate.
She fucking trashed me. Ah,
what are you going to do?
Um, so let me, I don't even
know where to pick up here.
I got two more reads to do and I think
I have another question. I'm not sure.
So let me, uh, all right.
Dollar Shave Club. Everybody.
I know this is fucking weird.
Sorry to just slam your fucking brain
against the inside of your skull there.
Um, all right. Dollar Shave Club.
It's Monday morning. Not by the way.
That's why I sound a little more fresh.
No Yon and for all freckles.
All right.
Do I always Shave Club
dollar shave club.com has a
special offer for new members
who today you'll get a free month of the
executive razor when you buy a tube of
Doc Dick calvers I got to still,
I'm going to say Carvey for
the doctor cabbies easy shape.
Whenever I hear that executive razor, I
just picture, he's like, you know, you,
you have the dress shirt on with boxers
and then you'd dress socks with sock.
Garters just shaving with it.
I'll go to a fire so much time.
All right,
this is the first time they've ever done
something like this and once you tried
dollar shave club.com,
you'll be,
you will become a proud member
like millions of others.
One reason is because they deliver amazing
razors right to your door for a third,
the price of what?
Greedy razor corporations charge.
That means when you join DSC dall sheep.
Um,
you can afford to shave with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
You'll get a first class shave when you
use the executive blade without hurting
your wallet. What Martin
Sheen, you're looking at manor.
Didn't judge another man by
the size of it. I mean that,
that fucking Michael Douglas greed
is good movie Wall Street. All right?
Another reason is Dr Covey's easy shave
butter using it with the executive makes
the blade glide gently for the
smoothest shave ever. Dr Carver's.
Shave butter isn't your
average shave cream.
It's a unique conditioning formula
with high quality natural ingredients,
leaving your skin unbelievably soft
and smooth. Jesus Christ. We got it.
How many times you can see how
smooth it is, like a baby's ass. Uh,
call to call to action.
And right now,
new members who buy a
tube of shave butter,
get the executive razor razor for free.
They've never done this before.
Take advantage of and it's only available
by going to dollar shave club.com/
[inaudible] that's dollar
shave club.com/bar dollar
shave club.com/burp um,
MVMT watches.
All right,
it's been a few weeks since I cracked
open these sharp looking movement.
Watch and I'll spend a couple of months
stop putting words in my mouth. Uh,
all right.
As promised,
the quality's watches are there for an
awesome price in the style department.
The compliments I get on this thing are
really unbelievable considering I don't
wear it now I'm wearing it.
Describe your watch. Well,
I'm wearing the fucking watch.
I always had,
cause I'm a grownup and I can afford a
watch because I spent 24 fucking years in
strip malls. I can actually
afford one. But back in the day,
I'm going to Redo this copy. All
right. When I couldn't afford a watch,
when I stayed in that broken bed,
net fucked up,
cabin up and chill coot
Charlie's and Alaska,
I would have worn a watch like this and
they would've been like, God damn it,
this guy's a pro. I hope
they gave him a good bed. Um,
if you hadn't had the chance to
experience how movement will, uh,
how a movement watch fits
around your risks, this is
your chance movement. Watch,
watch his start at just 95 bucks.
It looks like a $700 watch.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
See,
when movement cut out the middle
man with the huge big brand markups,
the price of a stylus watch
finally got affordable.
Imagine that a watch with
a d with department store
quality for fraction of the
price movement has grown organically
purely by supporters. Like you said,
join there more than 1 million social
media followers and get a movement watch
today I'm going to MVMT watches.com/burn
they'll give you 15% off your entire
purchase. That's an the empty
Michael Victor Michael Tango,
watches.com/ [inaudible] and
there is one quick mode. Last one,
stamps.com mailing and shipping are a
routine part of running your business and
important keeps your operations going.
But if you're making constant
trips to the post office,
that's a routine you need to change.
There's much more convenient way and
that stamps.com stamps stock, uh,
brings all the services of the
post office right to your desk.
Buy and print official US postage
using your own computer and printer.
You'll never waste valuable time going
to the God damn post office again so you
can focus on what really matters.
Trying to bang the chicken,
the cubicle next to you
and growing your business.
I use stamps.com anytime I
sent her name of my posters,
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now,
sign up for stamps.com and use my last
name, birth for this special offer,
four week trial plus $110 bonus offers
that includes postage and a digital scale
scale. Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburbburthatstamps.com
and to
Berge Jesus Christ. All right. Um, okay.
The last question that I actually did
with the lovely Nia and now we're fucking
wage gap myth.
Uh Oh,
did this spark a debate a deal?
Dear Billy Baru,
I was one of the fortunate and
audience members of your epic terrorist
performance. You crushed it. My
opinion. Thank you very much.
He said the wage gap statistic.
Um,
he said I wanted to bunk a myth for
you. The wage gap statistic. You know,
this is thing right now that they say
that a woman gets paid less 79 cents less
to do the exact same job is a guy which,
you know, my opinion is fucked up.
The job should pay what should pay.
Right?
So this guy says the wage gap statistic
that you hear about all the time is
simply the average earnings of
men and women working full time.
It does not take into account
different job positions, hours worked,
or different jobs.
It has nothing to do with the same work.
It has nothing to do with discrimination.
In 1963,
the supreme court passed
the equal pay act,
which makes it illegal to pay
different wages for the same job.
If you still don't buy that,
then consider this.
If a company could legally
play pay women less money,
do you think those greedy
Kuntz would ever hire a man?
Some decent points there. Uh, once I
pulled this wage gap threat thread,
a whole bunch of other feminists
myths started to unravel,
but I just wanted to shine a light on
this topic. Well, okay, lets you know,
I'll have to look all of that up. I never
looked up the equal pay act, but um,
if they're still able to make the
numbers work then wouldn't that say,
did guys get the better high paying
jobs then done then does it become that?
I'm just asking. All right. Um, that's
what I would guess. So why don't know.
Evidently, I have some readings to do
and I think a lot of feminists do too,
that just jump on the bandwagon
and I'll look up the equal pay act.
MMM.
I don't know who the fuck knows.
I mean,
one of the dumbest fucking ways to
get somebody to listen to your goddamn
opinion is to just sit there and be like,
you got it better than us.
You're life is fucking easy.
That immediately puts the
other side going, like,
you know, an f fuck you. Fuck you and your
procedure. You know, my fucking life. Cz,
I just dealt with this, this,
this, and this. You know,
it just puts people into that mindset.
MMM.
I Dunno if that whole fucking yelling
and screaming and shit. You know,
believe me as a yeller and Screamer, I
know it doesn't make people listen to you.
It just makes you, people just go, oh my
God, I want to get away from this person,
or that person's a fucking lunatic.
That's been my experience
trying to convey ideas
since I was a little orange,
had a child.
MMM.
I don't know what's going on. Okay.
At the end of the day, people should,
the job should pay what the job pays
and the best person should get it,
but sadly that is never going to happen
because there's always going to be the
boss's son.
There's always going to be the hot chick.
There's always going to be the racist,
the homophobe,
the person who comes in with a southern
accent, you're up north or vice versa,
and somebody mentally still fighting the
war. I think southern people are stupid.
You can't. The only way to take the
human element out of it is to gradually,
slowly but surely dumbed down,
human beings make everything automated
and you slowly replaced them with free
thinking robots, which is basically
what's going to happen. By free thinking.
I mean they agree with the upper 1% and
not even the upper 1% the upper 1% of
the 1% that doesn't even show up,
you know?
Okay.
There's a lot of,
remember all the blue blood money and
everybody kind of knew how much money they
had and now they all say that, oh
they gave away a lot. You know,
the rocker fellows or you know, they're,
they're fortunate is, and what it's worth,
they use to be the Vanderbilts that are
only worth like $75 million. Now. I mean,
that's,
I don't know,
there's all these stories out there that
there's families that are so fucking
big and powerful. They are above any sort
of borders and they fucking, you know,
when they traveled by yacht,
it's only like,
it's like their little navy and they just,
I love conspiracy theory
and they just float around.
They pull up to the dock and the comp
countries just come out and give them bags
of gold and then they just disappear.
It's like waterworld except you know,
without the, uh, you know,
I don't know if they still have all the
amenities cause the world hasn't flooded
over yet. Does that make
any sense? You know,
I think that's as good
a spot to stop sending.
Uh, my apologies for a fucking
up the podcast this week. Um,
you guys have a nice couple of fucking
days and can I end on some more drum nerd
shit. I told you my, uh, drum
teachers taking me through, um,
that sting album,
10 summers tales of,
of that has the great Vinnie call Uda on
it and how they played in all these odd
times,
but they wanted to imply for four time
and he finally taught me on that seven
days, which is in five, which I love. Uh,
he finally wrote out what he
was doing on the high hat,
which is basically he's playing
that it's four, four against five.
He's playing five underneath,
but he's implying four in the high yet
and a off to all these fucking years of
trying to figure out how to do it.
He finally,
he just wrote out one line of it
and now it makes sense. Um, to me,
and it's basically on the high hat.
I just still count and five,
but you just count,
you know, underneath it. If
you listen to what you're
counting. One, two, three, four,
five, one, two, three, four, five.
[inaudible]. One Dent that fucking shit.
But on top,
how it works for me is you just,
you just,
I still counted five. I
just, you're thrown in. He
counted is like eighth notes.
So one and two and three and four and
five and one and two and three and four
and five.
And the first time through Ux sent one,
three and five and the second time
through you accent too in four.
Try that. That's the way I've
been doing it. Now granted,
this is massively filtered down
from a professional drummer to a standup
comedian who cannot read out loud.
Um, all right, that's it. Go fuck
yourselves. I'll talk to you on Thursday.
L check yet.