Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday.
I don't know. A fucking day. And it was a
July 20th is that what it's going to be?
Is that what it's Gunna be? Pow. Yeah,
that's what it's going
to be at Sunday night.
July 19th one I'm doing this.
I am an Ottawa.
I'm in my hotel room. I am stone
sober. They have Cuban cigars here.
I have not smoked one.
And I'm sitting in bed right now with a
plate full of raw vegetables that were
supposed to come with hummus but
came with ranch dressing instead.
So I'm trying to avoid that so I can hum
somehow make my goal of being down to a
buck 80 this week, which I
think I am. I think I am,
but I don't have access to a fucking
scale here. Uh, that's what it is.
That's where I'm at.
This is what Busan and eating pizza and
bear and all this other fucking horse
shit. This is where it
gets you. At some point,
you got to pay the Piper and sit here
with a bunch of vegetables eating.
There's fucking crap.
Oh,
or a punch or rabbit right now. I don't
even know why. It's not their fault.
It's not their fault that I ate the
way I have a like a fucking rabbit.
Then you know.
Oh fucking no.
I don't know. I was so excited
like a minute ago. Now I'm
just fucking, you know,
I'm just so,
what's the point of living
if you're not killing yourself slowly,
what is the point of live?
What is the point of living? It's,
think about it. All this shit that,
you know what that's going to kill you
someday. That's the best fucking time,
right? Smoking, drinking, eating.
Fucking some whore. Raw. No, sorry.
I need to watch my mouth here because
I'm in a nice hotel. I just don't want,
I don't want to disturb
the people around us.
So anyways,
there's just one of these deals. This
sucks right now, but in the morning I'm,
I'm going to be psyched. You
know? Oh, I wanted a burger.
Oh Billy fucking pasty.
Flabby tits. Wanted a burger.
No Burger for you. There will be no burger
for you. I'm not going to eat or drink.
The entire podcast, but I
just had some salary. Right?
Which salary?
I think this chemical makeup is like
air and water as far as I know with some
green dye number five.
But I got one of those salary hairs in
the back of my throat right now. Ah,
you fucking Veggie cons. How do you guys
do it? You know, like a true vegetarian?
Well, they don't sit around eating this
shit. They actually have better meals. Um,
you know, I love when you
meet like a fat vegetarian.
It's just like you're fucking
yourself over on two levels right now.
You know what I mean?
It's like you're not eating meat and that
sucks and then you're not even eating
good food. You just sitting
there eating like Doritos.
It's actually good. Don't tell them
you know, it's too many fucking people.
Let them die.
That's what I say.
Okay.
Is that what you say? Oh, that's what
I say on my podcast. That's what I say.
Let the fat vegetarians who don't
know how to eat right, let them die.
I implore the next leader of our great
nation of the United States of America,
of the Americas of America,
please just let him die.
Okay.
I don't mean people, diseases,
let's try to help that shit.
But if you just shove and she,
well wait a minute,
maybe that's how you got the disease.
Cause he kept shoving shit. Okay.
Down your fucking throat.
Let them die.
That's what I've always running for
president. That would be my campaign,
a message.
And I would,
I would contact hootie and the
blowfish and I would get those.
Ask him if I could have the rights
to uh, let her cry. And I would just,
uh, I would just have it, let,
let them die and said, and I,
I'd contact the black dude who's name
is not hoodie. Was it Frank Gifford?
I don't know his fucking name is what?
I think Frank Gifford,
Dustin something or other,
uh, what is this fucking name?
I have it. Darrius Rucker, right? I did,
I'm go and if Mary Parker and Shit,
Oh,
you did a lot of fucking wine in the raw.
What a fucking genius that guy was.
He saw the writing on the wall and
he was just like, you know what,
we made our money. I'm fucking out and
I'm African American and I am going,
I am steering my creative ship into
the overt heart of white racism and I'm
going to put out a country album. The
God damn it, I'm going to be successful.
And he did it.
The fucking guy did it.
They did.
The white version of that is if you
played a Ukulele and one of those fucking,
you know those,
those bands were chicks with dirty feet,
sit there and watch them after they
take off their boots and you fucking,
you just put out like a,
a rap album and crushed it,
you know? And all you did
was said he like he just put,
he put on like a trucker cap.
Like that was his big thing.
So you'd still dressed the way you dressed
and you just put on like a do rag or
something, you know, and you went from
singing about the Appalachian trail
to wrap it up. [inaudible] what
would you rap about dope? Yeah.
Ukuleles.
You face airbrushed on the back of
it, you know, and just come out,
you know,
I want to see so many do that.
Go down on one of those eight mile open
mikes and I want you to come down with a
custom Ukulele. A do rag.
Why does health you gotta be,
I was going to say at least as wide as me,
but I mean at that point
going into albinos border.
You've gotta be super white and I want
to see you go to and just how long you
can fuck in La, which is all they're
going to do is Bo. Come on man.
You can take a good boy and right.
Go down there and fucking
have one of your buddies.
Airbrushed yourself in an arm,
the shit pose and just come walking out
what you do rag and you fucking Ukulele
and just have it flipped over so they
can see your face and just have a dead
serious look on your face like you are
about to blow everybody's fucking minds
and then wrap over the Ukulele. It
just see how long you can go. Why not?
Okay.
Why the fuck not, oh, I'm
babbling. I'm babbling. And Ottawa.
Is that a Meg Ryan movie?
He's Tom Hanks. Is he lonely?
Is he going to come up and bang
her out there on the canal?
They never show the bagging and
those Tom Hanks. Meg Ryan movies.
That's why they never rang true for me.
It's like I get it.
You're finding love and all that,
but at some point you do got to fuck.
And I'm not seeing it,
so I'm calling bullshit.
You know more reducible.
Oh yeah. Kim Coleman,
I call bullshit.
I don't think,
I don't think that's sleepless
in Seattle story ever happened?
No.
Why am I eating vegetables
on fucking pocket?
Okay.
Do you know a lot of the train
conductors say eat while they do the
announcements?
That's why you can't hear him.
Can you just shove a bunch of
food in the mouth like no. No,
no.
Wow.
Is there anything worse
than no fucking tomato?
Maybe they were in season up here. I
don't fucking fuck fucking tomatoes, man.
Unless you pull them out of your
yard. What are you getting? All right,
don't worry.
I'm gonna
take it away from the microphone.
If you're still listening to this,
I want you to call suicide hotlines.
Oh fuck.
Am I sober and awake?
Jesus Christ. You don't want you,
first of all, I had, I had a lunch.
I had a rough one coming in here.
Um,
I left lax.
Oh my God.
I went down to lax to get on Air Canada.
We have a leaf on the tail that represents
what a nation's about throw when some
syrup and some mild racism and a couple
of terrorists trying to cross the
border.
We play hockey.
And that ice shovel board that
I can't remember the name of.
Who is our president.
No one fucking cares.
Keep heading north and your mates
Santa Claus or good mauled by a fork.
A polar bear, that fog
to grizzly bear. Great.
That's everything I know about Canada
next year. Polar bears and grizzly bears,
they have fucked at this point.
Like Tom Hanks and Meg Ryan never
did in sleepless in Seattle.
And they had a, they had a
goal of bear or a, uh, uh,
a fucking pissy. You gotta
go, go, go. They're busy.
That's a bad one.
That Kit's going to get that little cubs
going to get the shit kicked out of him
at school. All right. Hey, you
fucking different man. Right? Um,
anyway, what am I talking
about? So I want to fly in,
right or ride in?
Pilot flies.
I just sit in the back riding in and uh,
we got out onto the tarmac.
That's the word you never want
to hear during your flight.
The second they used the word tarmac,
you're going to be delayed
at least two hours. Um,
this, you may have noticed the pilot
is pulled over onto the tarmac.
We're going to be sitting.
What do you mean shutting the
engines down here on the tarmac?
I don't even know what the fucking tarmac
is. I have no idea what the fuck it is.
All I know is that means you're going
to sit there for two hours. But, um,
there was all this crazy what?
This crazy fucking
all this thunder and lightening
and all that shit. So I'm like,
absolutely Paul over to the side.
I'd rather sit here.
So, um, I sat there and I don't
even know what the fuck I did,
but basically I was supposed to connect
to Toronto to get here to Ottawa and I
miss that connection. And, uh, I was
supposed to be in Ottawa by eight o'clock,
and when I missed my connection so bad
that where they hooked me up on the
flight, the next flight I
left at 10 35 out of Toronto.
Um, so it was brutal, but I didn't die,
so it's fine. You know what I mean?
And at the end of the day,
as long as it was,
I still went from La to
Toronto to Ottawa in one day,
which was impossible up until
a couple of decades ago,
right in the 70s. You couldn't do that.
They were, they had to pull over and stop,
you know,
fight off some of indigenous people as
they tried to refuel in some God forsaken
place,
like nonstop flights from La to Toronto.
I don't think that started
until the early 90.
[inaudible] as far as my Wikipedia
page says, obviously I know that. Well,
when was the last time that you,
what did they first be able to go from
like New York to La without stopping?
I don't know. Bill, why don't you look
it up? Like I said, I don't give a fuck.
I'm just talking filling up fucking time.
I'm filling up your little ride to work
right now. Huh? How's your car doing?
Is it sputtering along? Is it
running good? What is it doing?
Why did you buy that?
Cool. Um, so anyways,
on the flight out there,
uh, I watched, uh,
the Maltese Falcon whenever they have
that on there. I loved Humphrey Bogart.
And if you're a,
a big Frank Sinatra fan,
frank was a huge fan of Humphrey.
And when you watch Humphrey Bogart,
you see a lot of, uh,
elements of his swagger, uh,
in s Sinatra's style.
And I have to tell you right now,
if you're trying to quit
smoking and drinking,
do not repeat.
Do not watch the Maltese Falcon.
Do Not Watch that movie.
Humphrey Bogart makes smoking and
drinking look like the greatest thing ever
before you like, Oh, you sure you
know that guy died of lung cancer?
I know he smoked camels
unfiltered like a fucking chimney.
Do you know what else he did? He became
one of the biggest stars in Hollywood.
Has ever known any fucking,
was he hooked up with the,
was it bogeying Bacall Lauren Bacall
when she was like 19, she was like,
that is a fucking stellar human being.
He was in his forties
and they will fuck it.
Inseparable.
They loved each other and he never
wanted to go out. She always,
there's two couples that I fucking,
I that I love.
Bogeying Bacall and a Paul
Newman and Joanne Woodward.
They somehow they fucking made it.
Now obviously Bogart died.
So that really helps to marriage,
but fucking Newman and
Woodward fucking made it. Um,
put anyways, this fucking guy is
just rolling his own cigarettes,
which wasn't bad.
But at one point in the movie when
he sits down with the fat man there,
he and he hands him a fucking torpedo
cigar. And if you look at the master,
the master shot,
which is basically a,
how do I describe it? Jesus Christ, I've
been in a couple of movies I should know.
This is the master shot is
like whatever the scene is.
That's the wide shot where you see the,
where they are.
Everybody that's basically in the shot.
That is the master shot.
They usually shoot that first
and then they go, all right,
coming around to your point of view,
his point of view we're
going to do is to show,
we'll do a three quarter of
dual fucking close up and all,
it's all up to the director,
but the master shot,
if you look at the other shots that,
not smoking but in the master shot,
they're actually smoking cigars,
well acting and make it one of the
great movies of all fucking time.
It's one of the,
I just,
that's all I think of when I see that I
want an acting gig where I just get that
on the master. I get to smoke a fucking
great cigar that so that they, ah,
it's so fucking phenomenal movie.
And I think one of the most
underrated actors of all time,
even always a considered a legend.
I think he's one of the best actors of
all time is a, I hope we say his name.
Peter Lawford I think is awesome.
And,
and the guy who plays the fat man in the,
I should know all these people's names.
He's fucking amazing. Just the sound
of his voice, the way he plays it,
the way he's just such an even keeled
emotional person with everybody else's
kind of erratic and a,
it's a fucking awesome movie.
But if you stopped smoking and drinking,
I mean it's fucking brutal.
That's back in the day.
Can you imagine back in the day,
like if you just walked in to get car
insurance and the guy sitting to cry,
you want to drink? Yeah, let's
fuck. That's fucking Dylan.
I just gives you a shot.
There's no drinking and driving.
There's no laws against it. There's
no breathalyzer. There's nothing.
There's no airbags.
Fucking water's fine.
The fucking food hasn't been genetically
altered. You just walk in places, hey,
you want something to speed?
Was doing smoker drank back then?
You weren't an addict,
you would just consider it an adult if
you couldn't get your shit together.
[inaudible] he's a drunk. He's the
town drunk. It's a fucking wine.
I'll get your shit together right now.
Everybody's a fucking addict in
it isn't their fault. I Dunno.
I guess I understand that. Um, with drugs,
I certainly understand that
with drugs and alcohol.
I've lost some friends to that shit,
but I got to say what the food stuff,
you know, I don't, I
don't know about that one.
It's just kinda like,
okay,
just eat a salad. My
oversimplify. It really is,
I guess that's say who an
alcoholic just don't drink.
But you really just got like,
I'm trying to say this in an empowering
way to like tonight I wanted a burger.
I wanted to fucking ribs.
I wanted all of that shit.
And you just got to get past
that dumb thought and think like,
do I really want to have to do,
do I like going to the gym now?
Do I want to go on the elliptical
for the rest of my life? No.
Just throw a couple of celery sticks
down your fucking pie hole and then that,
that craving will be good. Like right
now, I'm not even thinking about a steak.
All I'm thinking right now is how awful
vegetables taste. But you know what?
That'll be fine. What I'm looking at my
options call a, if I was a vegetable,
I'd be called a flower. Isn't that sad?
Like the ugliest vegetable there is?
I had a green one the other day. You
know something? If I wasn't so stoic,
I'd start fucking crying right now.
Just the last couple of days of eating
has been fucking brutal. However, um,
that's not what I came here to talk about
everybody. I came here to talk about,
um,
okay,
how I was in Ottawa tonight.
And it's hilarious. My agent
goes to me, he goes, hey,
before you do the Montreal comedy
festival on Monday, there's this Gig,
um,
there's Blues Festival in Ottawa.
Deep Purple's going to be there, Yada
yell at type of Shit. So I go, yeah man,
fuck it. I'll do that. When I was
in Reno, there was a blues festival.
All of a sudden, I don't know about
a week, it was like months ago,
about a week out.
I,
the fucking word comes in that a dead.
It's actually, it's outside and I'm
going to be going on in between bands.
I'm like, what the fuck was, I call
it my age and I was just like, dude,
I'm not trying to be a diva here, but
uh, then we already pay these dues.
I thought I already,
I already did these.
I did these gigs to not have to do
them again. Right. He's like, no, no,
it's going to be great. It's going
to be great. Saget did it last year.
He had a great fucking time. And I'm
like, this thing is outside. Yes,
it's outside. I go on
in between bands. Yes.
You go on in between bands and I'm
like, and it's good. And he's like, yes,
it's good. Trust me. It's good.
Now I assume most of you guys will
listen to this or not stand up comedians,
but any standup comic who is listening
to this right now is like going either
laughing or going, no, don't take
the Gig. So I fucking show up.
Okay.
And, um, you know,
weird Al Yankovic had gone on like at
like five in the afternoon when it was hot
as shit. He's putting on all
these fucking costumes and stuff.
So he's laughing about it and we're
having to fight and I'm standing there
looking out in the crowd and uh,
Bachman Turner overdrives
play it on the other side.
It's one of those things where they got
two stages going when they finished,
then I go up and then the next band,
so they are out there and I'm just
looking at a bunch of, there's no chairs.
It's the summer, so it's
still fucking, you know,
broad day light and it's
fucking McGee as shit, you know.
And Bob Bachman,
I guess Bachman's the only guy left and
he's on the other side of the fucking
parking lot
from alarm clocks border.
Well, I'm just sitting there
taking this all in and going,
I am going to eat my fucking ball.
I'm going to bomb.
This is going to be a fucking nightmare.
And I was gone out of that. Good.
They're good. So, uh, anyways,
they ended up bringing me up. This radio
guy brings me up fucking amazing voice.
What I want to fly. I'm like,
guys, sounds like amazing, right?
Brings me up.
And I come walking out there and uh,
the whole crowd cheered and it was ended
up being this fucking amazing show.
And I was really kind of waiting for two,
uh,
in the first eight minutes I was waiting
for it to go bad and it was fucking
amazing. And then I was outside and I
started thinking about Robin Williams.
Uh, all those shows, he did perform
for the troops. Those were outside.
And uh, I don't know, I'm middle of
it. I got like about 10 minutes in,
I got inspired to like really quit
being a fucking baby about this thing.
Um, cause you know, you get out there, you
know, if you think somebody's coming at,
you want to start fucking lashing
out of people before they get you and
everything. And uh, reminds
me this, this faith,
there's this famous story about
Robin Williams. Um, Joe Barton.
Nick told me it and um, you
know, he was royalty. Um,
Robin Williams in San Francisco.
So I guess there was some sort of
concert that was supposed to happen,
some huge band and everyone's
standing outside, you know,
some giant fucking venue
waiting to see this band.
But it started raining and lightening
and all this shit's of the band couldn't
go on and everybody was getting upset.
But I guess Robin Williams was in the
crowd was there for the show and he just
said fuck it.
And went on stage for like an hour or an
hour and a half and just did a off the,
you know,
the top,
his head comedy show fucking destroyed.
And in the end of his show,
the sun started coming out,
the crowd went fucking nuts.
And then he brought the band on and um,
I don't know,
he told me that says that that's one
of the coolest fucking things ever.
You know, somewhere in the middle of it.
And I started thinking about this, that,
that story. But anyways, I want to
thank everybody from Ottawa and in,
in and around Ottawa who came out
to the show. You guys had no chairs.
You stood up for an hour. I had
a fucking great time. And uh,
while I was doing it, the sun was
going down in the sky was amazing.
I kept making fun of that. Like I'd be in
the middle of a joke. Right? Tell a joke.
Yeah. It's my fucking wife of Blah Blah.
To Go, Oh God, how great was that breeze?
I was saying all this shit I'd
never said in 23 years on stage.
How great was that?
How great is the breeze
a look at those clouds?
Somebody take a picture and shy. That was,
it was unreal. It was a phenomenal gig.
And to make it even even better was a,
believe it or not, the, uh, um,
the company that we hired
to animate F is for family,
which is coming out in December,
is actually in Ottawa.
So I went over there today and I met
everybody and they were all cool as hell
and young and they thought the
show was fucking hilarious.
And it wasn't like anything they had
ever seen. So, and I, and I met this,
this one woman who was, I'm not,
I'm not giving away any of the show,
but was animating this
really fucked up scene.
And I was laughing that she got to see
just because of what the scene was about
and her being a woman. And
she said, and I was like,
how did you end up getting this?
She said, I actually requested it.
I wanted to animate this scene.
And I got to tell you guys,
I don't talk to any shit. I'm not as
well, who's kidding, who I fuck around?
But I'd like when I talk about my career,
I don't talk about any ship,
but I will just say this,
I was very,
very excited when I left those studio,
that studio today. And I think,
I think this show's going to be,
I think this is the one is far as I found
the right thing where I can be funny
the way I'm funny and standup
and funny on the fucking podcast.
I can be that kind of funny on TV.
Um,
so I don't even feel like I'm jinxing it.
I'm one of those fucking old ladies,
like don't say that. Then you're going
to fucking jinx it. I think it's fucking,
it's really coming out.
Well,
I'm trying to fucking not be
too fucking excited, but uh,
just do me do me a solid you guys.
When that fucking thing comes out,
just watch it on Netflix.
Just fucking watch it so we
get good numbers because,
uh, and then if you like it,
please tell some other people.
I don't think I'm going to have to
ask you to do that. Ft. Watch it.
I'm just saying that right now. Oh,
Billy is talking a little shit here.
Talking a little bit of Shit then
that's all I fucking need, right?
I do stand up and then I do this
fucking off the wall cartoon.
I call it a day.
Call it a day,
do a good five seasons of that.
And then I fucking happy trails.
I go by my fucking ranch in Alabama.
I'll see you get the NHL package,
the MLB package, the fucking,
uh, the fucking, one of the basketball
one is, I'll get the college one too.
I'll get the fucking end league pass,
NFL pass, whatever the fuck it is.
I'm getting all of those. All right.
And then I'm getting me a case.
A fucking bear. That's it.
Get me a case of fucking beer
and then I'm going to fucking,
I'm going to join the Klan when I'm
down there and I'm going to see,
I'm going to be like,
see if I can like talk people out of it.
Just show up to meetings and sort of nod
as people are talking and just sorta be
like, damn, I ain't know me. I'm just
doing it. Then that, that back of mine,
you know, just, I'm just saying, I'm
just saying and you know, it's funny.
That's what every group needs.
Even if you have a good cause,
you need somebody in there that does not
share your point of view because if you
don't, you go off the fucking
rails. That's what the Klan needs.
The Klan needs some members that don't
hate black people just to fucking spin
them back into reality.
Yeah.
When should think like these feminists
groups, that's what the fuck they need.
They need some fucking jerk off guy
like me in there just to fucking,
you know the kid. You can't be in a group
where everybody thinks the same way.
You spin off down the fucking wheel.
It's like when conspiracy theorists get
together a fucking eyebrows shoot up to
the ceiling. Next thing
you know, we're, we're,
we're talking about ad
everything was an inside job.
You need somebody there to
be like, guys, guys, guys.
Do you realize how many people would
have to be involved to pull that off?
And everybody keeps their fucking
mouth shut and then you can be all,
you know what? You're right. You're
right. We got a little out of hand there.
We got a little out of hand.
Maybe I'll drive by heckling
clan meetings in the south.
Just drive by it. Not that bad.
If you get to know some paypal,
I wouldn't agree with that.
I have experiences that are like that
anyways. Um, I don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about.
Let's do some reads this week.
Um,
fucking draft kings has
been breaking my balls.
Just breaking my fucking balls.
I love draft kings.
I don't know what they're fucking play.
Don't like that.
I make a joke that they're a fucking
gambling website. They don't like it.
I keep getting the, like I got a text they
said earlier this week, just, you know,
we love the reads. Just don't say
that we're a gambling website.
Just say that we're, it's more of a
skill based thing. It's just like what?
What are you talking about? It's
like you're, you're gambling.
You've combined a fantasy
fantasy football with,
with the Vegas sports book.
We're all adults.
I don't have a problem with it. Why can't
you just be who you are? Draft Kings.
This is the fucking letter I
got here. Where is it? Here.
All right. Uh, okay. Just,
just sent saying the advertising. Did
you see the email regarding draft kings?
Please remind bill not capital,
not to compare draft kings to gambling.
Well Dad, I don't, I don't fucking
get people that, first of all,
gambling is legal. It's legal.
What you're doing is fucking legal.
Why are you a shit that's like saying,
you know,
we're not having sex with just seeing
how our bodies fit together. Right.
That's probably a bad example.
I gamble.
You don't the Pete Rose Joke. Not only
is it funny, it's fucking make sense.
So I'm going to continue to read it the
way I always fucking read it and then
you know, if you don't like it then I
guess you know, go to another podcast.
I don't know what the fuck to tell you.
This isn't like radio.
I can't get fired from
my own fucking show.
Fucking skill based thing.
Yes.
What kills me that you're sitting there
is fucking adults and you could just sit
there and say that lie. Unless you sat
there in the meeting and you went like,
listen guys,
this is just bad for business to
say that this is a gambling website,
so let's hope bill is dumb
enough to go along with.
It's more of a skill based fucking thing.
Well,
I'm going to keep reading
it the way I read it.
What about the Howard Cosell thing
that I do? You don't like that.
If I don't make these things fucking
entertaining advertising people,
people just going to fucking fast forward
through said if me undies can roll
with sweaty balls and no sweaty clam,
I think he can handle a Pete rose joke.
We're all adults here.
We know what they are.
It's more of a skill based fucking thing.
That's what they used to say in the
football card when I was in high school,
when they'd had known that the bookie
give you that on the back it says not to
be used for gambling. It's just a skill
based game. We all know what's going on.
All right,
there we go.
That's like the two people at the office
who were fucking and they think nobody
knows. Everybody knows that, right? Just
fucking drop your pants and go at it.
All right. Dollar Shave club,
everybody. I got to tell you,
shaving the old way sucks a lot.
It hurts.
You lather up with cheap foam wincing.
His hair is scraped from your face.
With those old worn out razors,
you won't throw away because
they cost so much goddamn money.
Not Any more dollar shave
club sends amazing razors
for a few bucks and when you
use them with their, with their
members, only Dr Covey's easy shave,
it's completely changes the game. Forget
foam. This stuff is the real deal. Yeah.
You can't be shaving with foam
mat. You can't do that. It's magic.
Something happens when you put it on. It's
hard to describe, but it feels amazing.
It's the most gentle,
peaceful shave imaginable.
Jesus Christ. I want to do this
naked while watching a sunset.
You barely know you shaving other shaving
products can leave your face feeling
dry and tight. It's awful. It
is awful. But Dr Covey's easy,
Shea, it's high quality
stuff. Just like their razors.
It's got organic.
All natural ingredients like pear
cactus and black willow bark.
So your skin feels fresh,
smooth and moisturized after every shave.
It's funny if you rubbed any one of
those things up against your face,
you wouldn't like it.
Pear cactus and black willow bark,
but you put them together.
It's like a Reese's peanut butter
cup except it's for your face. Um,
it's great if you have sensitive skin.
Let's get a thought stunted.
If doctor cabbies easy shave butter
from dollar shave club is like nothing,
nothing you've ever tried. Call to
Action Dr Carver's easy shave butter.
Just one more reason to try
dollar shave club today.
Do it today@dollarshaveclub.com slash
burr that's dollar shave club.com/burn
mathy and me my coffee. All
right, here they are. Draft Kings,
the always sensitive draft
kings.cam baseballs in full
swing and you can be part
of the action right all
seasonLong@draftkings.com
the official daily fantasy
part partner of major league baseball.
Daily fantasy means no season long
commitments, just instant cash,
instant gratification.
Why wait until the end of the season to
get paid when you can win huge prizes
everyDay@draftkings.com it's like a
brand new season. Every time you play,
just pick two pictures,
pick eight position players and pick up
your cash unless you're fucking lows.
That's it.
After ask Peter from Colorado,
he doesn't have a last name,
but evidently he won last year.
He won $1 million in one day.
Simply playing fantasy baseball at
draft kings. That's what he was doing.
I think he was gambling on it.
Hundreds. They enjoy the final read.
Hundreds of thousands
of fantasy sports fans,
just like you have already
cashed in@draftkings.com
even more have lost or this
thing would not be in business.
Now it's your turn. Call to action.
New Co new contest.
Start daily.
So hurry to draft kings.com right now and
use the Promo code defense to play for
free and tense and today's
$10,000 fantasy baseball contest.
draftkings.com official partner
of major league baseball.
Pete rose. Can't gamble but
fuck the people in the stance.
They can lose their houses for
all we care. Obviously Gamble,
responsible and draft kings.
All right,
whoever the person is in the conference
room, right playing this thing.
Lighten the fuck up.
All right,
I'm singing about sweaty balls with
me undies in this selling like fucking
hotcakes, okay? Everybody's
always going to love sports.
Everybody's always going to love gambling.
You came up with a unique way to gamble.
I think this is cool.
You get to be your own GM.
Why don't you just be who you are.
If Bruce Jenner can be Caitlyn Jenner,
I think you guys can be a gambling
fucking website and our defense for free
entry now@draftkings.com that's draft
kings.com. That's draft kings.com right?
All right. Trunk Club Trunk
Club. It's so hard to say.
Trunk Club. Um, that's like
Trump tower trunk club.
Say 10 Times at Trunk Club Trunk Club
come comp summer has officially arrived.
Jesus Christ.
Guys,
it's almost fucking August and that
means you're too busy firing up the grill
and sunning in the sand to even think
about s setting foot in a mall. Artisans.
Does that sound great? If I went to
a barbecue right now, I'd have to,
can I get the grilled
veggies? No sauce. Um,
the problem is you still need
to look fresh. Oh, Jesus.
Trunk Club gets trunk club gets it.
That's why they've taken
the hassle of shopping out.
It's shipping out of shopping by
shipping you a trunk of clothes that fit
perfectly and make you look like 1
million bucks at Trunk Club. Slash bar.
You answer simple questions about your
style preferences inside this and then
you're assigned and expert
stylist who handpicks closed,
curated from the best premium blends,
blends brands that are perfect for you.
You basically you pick what you like
and just that a trunk full of clothes
handpicked comes ready yet god Damn door,
you pay only for the clothes you want
and then you send the other crap back.
No Art, no ongoing
subscriptions, no hidden charges,
just great closes and right now
their services completely free.
Get static at Trunk Club. Slash. Bird.
That's trunk club slash birth
starts summer off right?
Or the middle of summer from with Trunk
Club. One more time. Trunk club slash.
Birth.
That's right.
Get yourself some clothes that make you
know that will enhance your opening line
when you're fucking drinking.
And one of those tents that they set up
during the summer. All right, last one.
Everybody.
Legal Zone.
Do you want the government to decide
what happens to your property and your
minor children?
Well Doja if not,
make the commitment to protect your
family with a last will or living trust
today.
It's national.
Make a will month every
month@legalzoom.com. You might
as well call it national.
Make a will year and doing the
right thing has never been easier.
You really should do this shit.
Uh,
they've created a better way for you
and your spouse to take control of your
family's future. I know a lot
of guys don't like making wills.
That fucking freaks us
up and I'm telling you,
it's a fucking load off your
mind knowing that if you die,
everybody's going to be fine and
they're all going to be sitting there.
You know what? He Sinead, all those
donuts, but you know, he took care of us.
Check out legal zoom is new last
will and living trust bundles.
The more you plan ahead with wills,
trusts, and powers of attorney,
and the more you save, even if you've,
you're confused about all the options,
don't let that hold you back.
You can use their online resources and
estate planning tool to help you figure
out what you need or get more specific
guidance from legalzoom's network of
independent attorneys in most
states since they're not a law firm.
Um, don't procrastinate when it comes to
protecting your family. Get legal help.
You can count on@legalzoom.com today.
Don't forget to enter Burr in the referral
box at checkout to save even more.
That's legalzoom.com, Promo Code
burr legal zoom.com. All right,
mercifully the reads are rover.
I helped draft kings has
a fucking sense of humor.
That would be a goddamn shame if they
just walked away. I'll fucking upset.
Now I'm going to eat a carrot
or shop. What? Shop Deck?
I almost had a bad joke. Gay Bugs
Bunny man. What's up? Cock. Ah,
that was one of the worst ones ever.
That was one of the worst ones. Deborah.
Um, anyways, you know,
it's funny as I'll probably get
complaints from a gay rabbit group.
Did you mean that? Will
you being theory? Um,
what am I doing right?
Dollar Shave Club.
I got to get to the fucking questions
for this week. Where are we anyways?
37 minutes in.
I'll tell you a time flies when you
just stone sober eaten vegetables at 10
fucking 52 at night.
Jesus Christ.
Oh my God. What am I, I'm a two weeks in,
two weeks in. It's just hard at night.
If you notice when I do the podcast
in the morning or in the afternoon,
then in that damn bendable bull,
I'm going a good fucking mood.
This is when it's the hardest.
You know,
your body starting to shut down and the
devil starting to wake up like, Hey,
what are we doing?
What are we doing?
You're born in your goals.
[inaudible] um, all right,
let's read,
let's get to some of the reeds here.
Have I talked about everything
I wanted to talk about here?
The fuck else did I
want to mention? Um, Oh,
oh, Jesus Christ. I almost forgot, uh,
one of the guys that basically taught
me how to be a comedian unfortunately
passed away a 73 years
of age. Bob Cybele. Um,
it was laid to rest today and,
uh,
I just wanted to make sure that
I took time to mention, uh,
what a fucking great guy.
He was meant to such a great guy.
He was always cool to me when I
started out and just such a, um,
I mean, I didn't even know all this
shit about, I'm going to read this,
this link here when they talked about,
um,
Bob Site Bell,
uh,
he started in 1979.
That was the start of a 36 year career
in standup comedy from a guy whom his
good friend and fellow comedian,
Mike McDonald,
who is another fucking hilarious comic
called the fantastic maniac on stage.
Bob made you laugh offstage. He was
gen, he genuinely cared about people.
And uh,
this,
this is what I found amazing about this
guy and actually I kind of relate it to
it where he was into a bunch of
different shit. Um, let's see.
Where the fuck is it Christ bill,
why don't you given a tribute to the gain?
You're going to fuck this whole
thing up. Well, you know what?
You're going to have to deal with
me reading out loud here. Uh,
those are new Cybele are aware that his
life was lived in two distinct parts
with January 5th,
1977 serving as the,
as the line of demarcation.
I hope I said that right.
That's the day he gave up drinking,
driving into an occupied parked car
on market street was the final Straw.
And while his post drinking life was
not much longer in years, 38 versus 35,
he was determined to live every day like
it was like he was trying to make up
for lost time. Uh, they've see the,
basically the gay and that
does sec is commercial.
The most interesting man in the world
doesn't have anything on Bob. Say Belt.
Now you know what you're thinking. What
the fuck does that mean? Here you go.
Where do you start?
Cybele ran more than 30 marathons.
This is a monster headline comic.
He also ran more than 30 marathons,
including the Boston marathon 17 times.
He was a certified scuba diver who
dived, you know, he did cruises. He did.
She fucking dove all over the
world. An artist, a musician,
an airplane pilot. He hiked the
Appalachian trail several times,
climbed mount, kill him, kill him.
Agero he went on transatlantic cruises,
uh,
though,
not in the traditional manner,
he would travel on cargo in steam ships
and was often the only one on the ship
not working. It was his economical
way to see the world. Uh,
that was far from the only traveling he
did in the last 11 years since he and
his loving companion reconnected.
They dated in high school
and lost touch for 44 years.
The pair of traveled to
China, Italy, Morocco, Greece,
Turkey, Ukraine, France, Spain,
England, Ireland, Iceland,
The Bahamas, and Canada. Let
me tell you something to do.
That's the way to be a fucking comedian
is once you're a headliner comic and
you're telling fucking jokes and
people are coming out to see you,
why you would ever get yourself sucked
into the industry when you can do all of
this shit.
How fucking amazing is that?
He fucked around for the first 35 years
of his life and was still able to do
that. And I gotta tell you, man, he was
one of the greatest fucking guys. And, uh,
when I started out, I know
I've mentioned this before, um,
I started out in March in 1992 and the
big eighties common comedy boom was
crashing hard. And there was a lot
of guys that worked in the 80s.
They basically,
they had more,
more rooms than actual bonafide comedians.
So what happened was I came in
during the trimming the fat years.
So obviously I did not start off from
the greatest rooms and I ran into some of
these bigger guys that were coming
back down and had to get day jobs.
And they were,
some of them were some of the worst
fucking people you'd ever want to meet.
I forgive them because they were
fucking dealing with, you know,
what they were going through.
But some of them, I mean,
I know guys who would be like, hey,
you know, look at this, look at this.
It's Wednesday night.
You know,
fucking three years ago there'd
be a line around the block.
There's barely anybody here. And I had
a guy one time say that to me and say,
you know what a file if I was
starting out, Nah, I quit, man,
I get into something else.
It was literally trying to discourage me.
That's how desperate this person was.
And um, Cybele was not one of those guys,
man, he was just a great guy.
Really was interested in,
in who you were and what you did and all
that. And uh, he lived a hell of a life.
Uh, that's another great thing.
I'll post the, the uh, this article,
one of the coolest things
anybody could ever say about you.
They said Bob side bells
bucket list was empty. So, um,
I dunno, I definitely just wanted
you guys to know who that guy was.
He was a fucking great dude,
man. All right. So anyways,
let's get onto your questions here for
the week, for the week, for the week,
for the week. Where the hell do
I go here? Sorry, I'm on my iPad.
I'm on my mini iPad. It's like, it's big,
but it's small. You know what I mean?
All right. Um, okay. Once again, people.
Um, if you want to email
me and ask me questions,
the email is bill@themmpodcast.com.
Um,
Boston posters are still on sale
as of now. There's 175 left.
I know I had a lot of problems with the
website, but you know me with technology.
I'm also, I'm supposed to remind
you guys about be the match.org.
Be The match.org. It's the bone
marrow registry. You give bone marrow,
you can save somebody's life.
Uh,
we've had a few listeners that
respond that joined the registry, uh,
at the [inaudible] match in tweeted
us at what a great experience it was.
All right, there you go. That's, that's,
that's good Karma to whatever
horrific thing you do this weekend.
You want to balance it out. You can
go do that. All right, galaxy search.
As I mentioned,
I was looking for a Ford Galaxy.
My wife has kinda making me being a
little more smart about it, but uh,
I already have one fucking old vehicle
that I got to get fixed all the time.
She's right. But you know, maybe
it needs a friend. Anyways,
this guy said, hey bill,
if you want to search craigslist
nationwide for that galaxy,
try search tempest. So there
you go. That's for you guys.
Whatever the fuck you [inaudible]
looking for a www.searchtempest.com.
All right, here we go. Let's get
into the questions for the week here.
A new fan from Norway.
J UPP jump. That's right. New
Fan. It's possible. Great podcast.
Great shows. Well thank
you sir. Or ma'am, uh,
I've seen all your clips on youtube
and the last couple of days now,
summer holidays at the cabins
raining. So thank you. You saved it.
A pardon my English. But how's your
new Norwegian? Right? You know what?
You got me there.
You're way better than I am.
I don't know anything other than
Tuck, which means thank you. Um,
so somebody could be like, hey, can I
shoot you in the head? I'll be like,
thank you. Yes, absolutely. Keep on
doing whatever you're doing at works.
And when you come back, when
are you coming back to Oslow?
Uh, because I know you,
I see you've been here. I've been there
twice. My friend next time call me,
he gives the phone number and he goes, not
gay. I love when guys do that. Not Gay.
Like what if you were that they like,
I like whatever move you made, I
would. Hey Dude, I'm not gay. Yes,
sorry man. But you know, I'm flattered.
Then it would be over. Let me go
cross country skiing or whatever.
I can handle it. If he gay, no big deal.
A promise. He said, I promise I can.
I can take you on a local to a local
soccer game. Anyways, best regards,
blah, blah blah, blah blah. Uh Oh,
his name is Glenn named after Glen
Anderson from the Gretzky line from his
Edmonton Oilers years.
True. My, uh, my dad's work.
What? Valerie go red sox
rangers, New York giants,
l Beckham Jr. We'll own
2015, 16. You know what dude,
you went off the rails with your, your
English. I don't know what happened there,
but you know, what most important thing,
when am I going back over there? Uh,
probably next year.
Um,
I think the last time I was there was
the end of 2013 so I am more than overdue
cause I could go there right now and give
you guys all brand new hours worth of
jokes. So, uh, and I think this
team, this time when I go over there,
I'm going to add some eastern
European countries and uh,
I don't know. I'm looking forward to
it. Definitely looking forward to it.
Last time I went to Oslo, met this
fucking Badass dude who was shredded.
It was this little guy who had
the most sickest fucking beard.
He just did not shave. And his
beard went from just under his eyes.
Downton met his chest hair.
This guy was a fucking animal and uh,
he had just come back from Thailand.
We're two months out of every year.
This guy goes over there and it just
gets taught by these masters and gets the
shit kicked out of them and comes back
here like a fucking cause back to Norway,
just absolutely shredded and even more
of a deadly weapon than he was when he
left. Um, those are the
kinds of people that I like.
Those are the kinds of people that you
should meet because that's the kind of
shit like you listen to
like, dude, you can do that.
You can just leave what you
live for two fucking months,
go to the other side of the planet in
fight for two months. And it's like, yeah,
if you set your life up,
always working towards that,
your life ends up going around that shit.
So if you're young right now,
you know when you're sitting there,
you're getting ready to get out of college
and the whole cubicle life is scaring
you. You could set it up
however you want to set it up,
just doing the shit that you want to
do and then you'll life sort of builds
around it. All right. So
anyways. All right. Weight loss,
challenge a,
they have freckles.
I love the podcast and I've been trying
to get motivated to at least not be that
fat.
I'm from Wisconsin,
so beer and cheese curds are like
appetizers before more beer and meets with
fried cheeses. Ah God dude, you know
hard. That is the read right now.
And you know how fucking
great that sounds. Oh my God,
I'd kill for any of that right now.
He goes, I'm five, nine 218 pounds.
Big Boy.
Okay
Dude, you are, you're, you're
like fourth and goal weight.
Give it to you. You'll get it
in there, man. Five, nine to 18.
That's pretty fucking solid, my
friend. And he said, I bet I've, oh,
how many fucking hoodies do you want?
He goes,
I've always been active
in play sports they ago.
So there's muscle underneath there.
You,
you're going to fucking destroy somebody
if you start playing rugby. Um, you said,
I've always been active and play sports.
After your last Monday morning podcast,
I was asked by some coworker if I wanted
to be there fourth in a relay marathon
because of your recent fat motivation
towards yourself and challenge.
I am doing it. All right,
good for you. Said this.
Chubby John Stockton Pot paps beer loving
bastard is already ran 13 miles this
week already and it's cut down on the PBR.
Switching to PBR light.
Ha ha ha. Thanks for the encouragement.
All right. Good field. Yeah, dude,
that's the one thing I have noticed since
trying to lose weight is a runners are
fucking,
they're all fucking skinny.
You don't see a lot of fat runners unless
somebody is fat and they decided to
run. Other than that, it just
sort of melts off of you.
My only thing is I don't know how their
feet and knees can take it and their
back and everything like that.
Um,
I got this weird thing where I could
sort of run on a treadmill a little bit,
but if I run outside,
if I run on a sidewalk,
like I'll go half a block on my knees
are like, hey, hey, hey. Easy, easy.
What are we doing here? What
are we doing? All right,
get on the grass and start walking.
So my biggest thing that I'm doing
is I'm just changing the way I eat.
Um, whose kid? No, I'm taking
a break from the way I eat.
I'm always going to have steaks
and shit like that. But uh,
God dammit. Look at this. I have
three pieces of cauliflower.
I get like
two carrots,
three little those round fucking tomatoes
and a couple pieces of Broccoli is,
there's nothing.
I love Broccoli if it's steamed,
but if it's completely fucking raw,
it is practically impossible to eat.
And you know what's even harder is
to eat it. And actually do you know,
do a podcast.
I bet this has never been done.
Has anybody ever just taken a big fucking
thing at shoved it in their mouth and
tried to read an email on a podcast?
Podcasting is so young, you know,
I don't think it's been done.
This is like eating a fucking raw
broccoli with nothing on it. This is like,
you know that cinnamon challenge and
like a vegetarian way. Here we go.
This is so gross. Look at the
top of Broccoli. It's like,
you know those people with gross tongues,
all those little bumps on the
fucking tongue. It's just,
this is fucking nasty. Ah,
all of our golf,
I don't know,
an eight an ironing board, but I think
this is what it would fucking tastes like.
This wasn't even full.
This is a fucking gross and think,
oh my God.
Oh,
it's fucking horrible.
Broccoli. Two thumbs down. You know what?
Broccoli is like part of a comedy team.
Like I live in comedy.
They'd had to be part of a team.
There's no fucking way this thing could
go on stage by herself and hold a crop.
Holy Shit.
I tools that never fucking,
then you will chew Broccoli
for like four fucking hours.
Oh God.
All right.
Jesus Christ. Um, anyways,
why don't I do this? I still have
to fucking cheek smaller. The ship
will be a ballplayer in the fucking
seventies and eighties said, it's tobacco,
it's Broccoli. That'd be great
if you joined a baseball team.
They're all putting my fucking dip in
back in the day and just sticking like
Broccoli. And they're like, why are
you doing? Oh yeah, I still broccoli.
It's good fiber. It's good for
your prostate, keeps things moving.
He's a good for your prostate. I don't
know. It's not good for your mouth,
I can tell you that.
Wow.
Correct.
I never make noises like this one. I'm
eating steak. That's all I'm saying.
You know,
you eat steak yet. Ah, you fucking
drop the fork. Unless it's a shit one.
You know what I mean?
Here's a good,
is a good rule of thumb.
If you walk into a steakhouse and
they have steak sauce on the table,
you turn around and you walk the fuck out.
All right,
good steak. Just not, it's a
fucking month ended already.
How long does this take?
Come on.
All right.
There we go.
You know, it's funny that man versus
food. I never saw him eat broccoli.
I know why. I know it sucked
towards the end of the challenge,
but he always enjoyed the beginning.
All right. Sorry about that guy.
So that was a bad fucking idea.
Holy Shit.
Oh, the only thing worse than that
would be eating like a mouthful of hair.
All right. Bad Ass Russian pilot.
Oh, you guys got to see this video.
You guys see this video?
Um, I actually got her name.
She's um,
her name is Svetlana.
How great is that named Svetlana Nina.
Svetlana Kappa Nina, right. Um, dear bill,
the red bar on, oh, like the red
baron. I get it now. It's not bad.
Since you're a pilot now I thought
you might find this video interesting.
Even though I had my license, I do not
consider myself. I am a novice dude.
I'm still fucking learning here obviously.
Okay. The Russian pilot is considered,
uh, the pilot of the century. Um, oh,
she's considered the pilot of the century.
According to our t news,
she is one of the world's most honored
aeronauts. Check out the video below.
It's a cockpit view of her flying
acrobatics around the Black Sea.
Um, look wise, she is a Russian seven,
but when you factor in her pilot
skills, she becomes a perfect 10. Um,
more Russian seven is a fucking at
least an eight and a half or a nine.
Anywhere else in the world.
They're gorgeous.
I'm seriously though this video
shows that the Soviets were,
we're on to something when they used
women as combat pilots in World War Two.
I didn't know that by the way.
The Germans didn't have a chance
against the night witches.
I got to look some shit up on that.
Hope my internet came back.
He's fucking dickheads. I paid for
it here. Let's see here. Night,
which is, I got to read about
this, but I watched the video,
we'll post it and I'm,
the shit that this person is
doing is like just the level of,
Jeez,
I give us the,
those guys like when they just auditioning
to see if they can be a jet pilot and
you know, they, they sent him around
that fucking whatever. It's like that,
that carnival ride that you
always go on except dates.
It's way faster and they end
up like passing out and shit.
How she doesn't pass out and um,
and knows where the hell she's going. I
actually got dizzy watching it. She's,
she's fucking unbelievable. All
right. Night witches, everybody, um,
name,
which is the English translation of um,
some fucking German word that I can't
fucking pronounce or World War Two German
nickname. Um, for the female mill, uh,
female military aviators of the 588th
night bomber regimen known as the 46th Tom
and guy, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
How can they ever made a movie about this?
Cause it's the Russians and the Cold War.
Jesus Christ.
This has Meryl Streep written all over it.
You know,
they wanted to do it and instead they
did a league of their own because the
fucking wall hadn't come down in
Germany yet. It's a fucking amazing.
This amazing, uh, should be a movie.
They must have made one already.
The regiment flew, harass, harassment,
bombing and precision missions against
the German military from 1942 to the end
of the war. All right. This is creepy.
How do the Germans know that
it was a guy or a woman?
You know what happened
is they shot one down.
They ran over to see if they was
still alive and if they were,
they killed him and then in the
end they realized it was a woman.
Okay.
How the fuck did they know?
I never understood that.
How he got to know your enemy that well.
Like you knew,
you knew that that was the,
like when they're dropping bombs on you,
you're sticking your head out.
Yeah.
It looks like the five 88th
night balm or regiment.
So sassy pitches.
All right.
The night regimen or I
blahblahblahblahblah they
threw over foreign 800
admissions by the end of the war in
23 having been awarded 23 of them were
awarded the hero of the Soviet Union.
Title 30 members died in combat.
Um,
the regiment flew in wood
and canvas by plants.
All that's why, ah, Jesus, they fucked him
over. They didn't give him a nice planes.
A 19,
28 design intended for use as training
aircraft and for crop dusting.
And to this day, the most produced
by playing in, in all of aviation.
Oh my God though Joseph style,
he didn't give a fuck.
Okay.
Teach sacrifice at 200,000 fucking of
his own God damn people to get another
hundred yards.
You didn't give a shit him put the broads
up in those old fucking plates do it
or I'll fucking have you
killed. It worked. All right.
It worked. He'd beat their fucking ass.
It's couldn't beat the people in Finland.
Now Cuddy,
I still have those fucking Broccoli Shit.
My mouth.
I'm gonna read more about that,
man. That's very interesting.
Thank you for that email. All right.
What are we up to? 58 minutes. All right,
let's get in the last fucking thing here.
Let's get the last fucking read in here.
Um,
[inaudible] all right,
girlfriend with too many guy friends.
Jesus Christ.
I'm sorry.
I'm still doing what the Broccoli here
girlfriend with too many guy friends. Hey,
old doctor bill.
I'm a 21 year old Kyle College student
and I started dating this girl at my
school five months ago.
Things seem to be going great,
but unfortunately we've been away from
each other this summer because we're from
different states.
We talk almost every day,
but there are some days when
I never hear from her at all.
I just see her posting different things
she does with their friends on social
media.
I would have a problem with,
I wouldn't have a problem with
it except hang on a second.
What the fuck? Broccoli.
It's just never done.
Okay.
I'm sorry guys. I promise I won't eat
again on the podcast. It's really rude. I,
I know, I know. It's horrible.
Sorry. Uh, we talk about Bubba.
I wouldn't have a problem with except the
majority of the time it's with a group
of dudes.
She's always hanging out with five of
her friends who were all guys and then a
handful of times there's
other girls there.
Every time I see her post
something about them,
I feel jealous and angry that she's
spending all his time with the other guys.
Not only that,
but her most recent posts was on a boat
with all these guys wearing prob wearing
probably her most revealing bikini.
I haven't met any of these guys,
so I definitely don't trust any of them.
And whenever she's with
them and I text her,
she takes hours to respond or
even weights to the next day.
I want to bring it up
how I feel about that,
but I don't want to make it feel like
I'm telling her who she can and can hang
out with. So what do you think
I should do? Bring it up? Um,
that I don't like how she
hangs out with other guys.
It just shut the fuck up and trust
that she's not up to anything. Uh,
it would be great to hear from
Nir. Thanks. Uh, what, Nia,
thanks to get a female perspective too. I
wish she was here right now because, uh,
you're going to get my perspective.
Um, anyways, sorry for the long email.
Hopefully it didn't, I didn't use too
many big words for Yag. Go Fuck Yourself.
Um, what do I think about that? Uh, yeah,
that's kind of weird.
I mean,
what would she think if you were fucking
hanging out with like five other broads
and you awareness speedo when he got,
didn't get back to her the next day,
she probably thinks that you were
fucking around, right? So I would just,
I would just say to us, hey, listen, I'm
not trying to be a jerk here, but, uh,
you know, when you post, you
know, when you're hanging out,
you seem to only be hanging out
with other guys. You were on boats,
you were in skimpy bikinis. It's, it's
making me feel uncomfortable here.
All right. She's like, you
know, try it. Just go, look,
I'm just communicating that it,
it kind of makes me uncomfortable.
Um, yeah, this is real difficult.
Without, you seem like you're fucking
checking in on her and being like a jerk,
but just, just ask her just so let me
ask you this. If you know, if I didn't,
if I text you and I didn't get back,
if you text me and I didn't get back to
you for a whole full fucking 24 hours,
all right.
And then you see a picture on Facebook
and I'm standing there with my ball bag
all in a bunch,
you know,
all watered up like a
fucking pack parachutes
hanging out with like five chicks on a
boat. I mean, when you kind of be like,
you know, dude, what the fuck? Just
ask her, am I out of line here?
Then also tell it to, and
please tell me, you know,
if you're not feeling it anymore and
you want to hook up with other guys,
just let me know early on. So you
know, the heartache is way less.
Just let me know. All
right? But, uh, I, dude,
I don't think that it's weird that
you're uncomfortable with that.
That is fucking weird.
MMM.
You know,
hanging out with five guys and you're
most revealing fucking Bikini gimme it.
You know what the fuck you're doing.
No, those are just my guy friends.
All right. Now I'm getting annoyed. How?
What are you a fucking attention whore?
What's, I'm going to say all the
shit that you can't say to her.
This is all the shit you're thinking and
you're totally justified to think of it
and don't listen to any fucking brides
would tell you anything different because
if you were doing it, they give you
the exact same fucking shit. All right,
I got my foot nine. This
one. All right. Just ask her.
Just ask her what is, what's,
you know, don't stone at a time
tone than I'm doing a bigger,
you've got to ask what the fuck's
going on here? You know, honey,
with all due respect,
yeah, me, you fucking,
it looks like you're in a
sausage factory there. You know,
wearing your little skimpy fucking
outfit. What's going on? Be One thing.
If you were there with one of your
girlfriends and even then I'm thinking a
little five on to action, right? What's
going on? I don't know what to tell you,
dude. That's, that's a
fucked up situation. Uh, it
might be just how she likes.
She may be honest.
I don't like other girls that
don't get along with another girl.
She may be one of those
fucking people all really,
you're like hanging out with guys or one
of your door with some fucking clothes
on. How about that? You know, how about
this, can we, can we make a rule that a,
you know,
you gotta put on some fucking clothes
when you hang out with these guys.
How about that?
Cause you know,
you're just going to get pissed and
then you're gonna start hanging out with
some checks and just to piss her off.
You're going to start taking fucking
pictures and now return her fucking texts
for a day and you start doing
that childish shit rather
than just getting right
to the fucking media. The
heart of the matter there.
Right. The meat of the matter.
I'm looking at it. That's
how much, instead of saying
the hardest said the meet,
that's how much I'm fucking hate. And
these vegetables, no know Gigi here. Um,
anyways, people, if you enjoy
this podcast, all right,
and you'd like to donate
without having to donate.
Next time you're going to
buy something on amazon.com.
Go to [inaudible] dot com click on the
merchandise page, click on the Amazon, uh,
fucking link and it just
takes you right there.
And I get credit for driving traffic to
their site. They kicked me a little doe.
It doesn't cost you any extra fucking
money if you don't want to do it.
I completely understand. Um, so anyways,
that is the podcast for this week. Um,
I'm happy to be fucking stone
sober and getting in shape. Uh,
the today was a bad one and I probably
should have been more uplifting for
people who are trying to do it.
You're going to have these fucking nights,
but I will tell you this.
I'm going to finish this fucking plead
a fucking Broccoli and cauliflower and
all that horseshit. If tomorrow morning,
you know what? As much as this sucks,
I'm going to feel like 1 million bucks
and my stomach's going to be a little
flatter, right? You gotta
be willing to sacrifice
Jesus Christ. I, you know what,
I'm so fucking bummed out. Rain.
Oh Kitty even fucking, uh, I actually,
you know, it's funny, once you,
the English people told me that bummed
out means you got fucked in the ass.
I can't even say that anymore.
Well what, what's, what,
what is the real word that I'm trying to
say? I'm a little melancholy right now.
A melancholy with the cauliflower.
Um, anyway, sorry about that. Uh,
that's a podcast for this week.
As always.
Thanks for listening everybody in
order, whether it showed up, man,
that was fucking cool as shit,
man, to actually perform outside.
I have a whole new um,
perspective on it.
It made me think of that cool
fucking story. Joe Barton,
Nick told me about Robin
Williams and it actually, uh,
and I know, kind of reminded
me like, Hey, you know, yep,
you were put here to do this,
so quit your fucking whining.
Okay.
You know, what's a matter of,
it's not a perfect situation.
Your fucking baby get out there and
give him a God show and then you have a
great fucking time. It was
awesome. It was fucking awesome.
So thank you to everybody in Ottawa
and a now it's onto Montreal,
the Montreal comedy festival.
And I'm doing three goddamn comedy
jams and I'm doing three standup shows.
Um,
and uh,
we going to be up there with the lovely
Nia and we're going to be enjoying
Montreal. I'm doing three songs,
playing drums for three fucking songs.
And I was actually putting my support
and pressure on myself for that,
like fucking practicing and all that shit.
And then I finally remembered like,
Hey, he's in playing drums. Just
something you do for fun, Bill.
Why don't you work a little more on the
standup act to k instead of the fucking,
so whatever.
So I'm probably going to fuck up.
I know I'm going to fuck up the
songs, uh, in some way, shape or form,
but I'm going to have a good
time. So, uh, that is it a,
that's a podcast for this week. Go fuck
yourselves. I'll talk to you next week.
Draft Kings fucking grow up. Don't be a
bunch of God damn babies. If you're smart,
you'll continue advertising
here and you'll make some
money. If not, uh, you know,
thanks for being here for the time.
You were all right. Go fuck yourselves.
Everyone.