Okay.
Hey,
what's going on is bill burn.
It's the Monday morning
podcast and before I get stuck,
I forgot to read one of the ads,
so I got to read this one right here at
the top and then splice the thing in.
You don't need to know the technicalities.
Here we go. You're ready. Sit down, pull,
fold your fucking hands and face
forward legal zoom.com every one.
Look, you got to plan for your
future. You do financial planning,
you get insurance,
but to get real peace of mind,
you got to make sure your
family is legally protected.
So where do you turn to for
affordable legal protection,
you can trust one place
and one place only.
Legal zoom.com for over 12 years they've
been helping Americans get personalized
wills, powers of attorney, living
trust, real estate documents,
and more legal zoom also helps start and
maintain businesses with incorporations
in LLC filings,
trademarks and copyrights.
There are time saving service
was developed by a team
of experienced attorneys
and legal zoom takes care
of you from start to finish.
Legal Zoom documents have been accepted
by courts and government agencies in all
50 states.
Legal Zoom is not a law firm,
but they can connect you with an attorney
to help provide self help services at
your specific direction for even more
savings and to B u r in the referral box
at checkout. If you are a parent or an
entrepreneur, entrepreneur, excuse me,
don't wait any longer.
Call or visit legal zoom.com
and protect what is yours.
And now the beginning of the podcast.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
April 22nd, 2013 how? Why?
Okay,
I know. Well that's good. Um,
what a week. It's amazing how much
the world can change in a week.
This weekend. Everything. Sadness, fear,
triumph and conspiracy theory.
When else do you need?
And by conspiracy theory,
I'm of course talking about
how the fucking Los Angeles
Lakers made it into the
NBA playoffs.
Dude,
the NBA is the most manipulated. I, I,
it's just, it's almost like they're trying
to get caught. You know what I mean?
I'm going to sound like this fucking guy
who made this conspiracy theory about
the bombings in Boston, but you
know, to steal his fucking line,
how much more proof do you need?
Oh,
you got to look at is fucking,
who would you rather see in the playoffs?
Who's going to make it more fucking money?
Huh?
The fucking Utah Jazz or
the Los Angeles Lakers.
Okay.
Jesus Christ. I mean it was,
it was fucking ridiculous.
And now they're in the playoffs and they,
but people are gonna Watch
cause they hate them.
Just to watch them suck and watch them
get pounded it jazz. Just fucking,
I don't know. I, it's, it's the worst.
It's the easiest fucking league to fix.
All right? Nobody has more power
than a fucking NBA official.
I could fix a game.
I don't even understand the game.
No.
All I gotta do is just fucking,
I've said this before,
all you have to do as a fucking NBA Ref,
who's the best player?
Give them two quick ones
and then another, right? That
is, he's sitting at turnaround,
looking over his shoulder with his
fucking eyebrows down. You know,
some guys worth 300 million fucking more
than I am and my stupid athlete's foot
shirt. I just look at him like, yeah, keep
looking. I'll give you a tee the tee up.
All right, so now he's out of the fucking
game. He comes back into the game.
The second quarter.
I give him another one that's straight
saying the third quarter buddy.
There's no other fucking sport.
You can't do that. An NFL football,
you know,
I can't call intentional grounding fucking
two times on Tom Brady and get them
out of the game until the second quarter.
I can't call three strikes on it. Fuck.
You know what I'm saying?
It is the most manipulate
Avi and obviously brutally,
obviously manipulated game.
This is what kills me.
What fucking kills me about the mouth
breathing fucking morons that you walk
into that you bump it to. She walked
into, I'm a fucking mouth. Three more on.
I can't even express my views. Um,
I'm actually taking a class on that.
How do you express your views or to call
other people done without sounding dumb
yourself. Have you found yourself
on your podcast with no guests?
No.
Um,
yeah.
This is what kills me about these
fucking mouth breathing morons.
If you to start telling that the NBA
is fixed or it's fucking manipulated,
they roll their eyes at
you like you're a moron.
And what fucking kills me
is they had a mocked up ref.
They had a fucking mopped up ref.
Then they do that shit.
I was just what
was just one? Yeah, just
one bad seat in the NBA.
It's boxing. It's basically boxing.
What? It's, it's just as fucking corrupt.
I loved that Shit. How it was just one
how there was a mobbed up ref and no,
none of the other referees
on the officiating crew
could figure it out that this
guy was throwing games, a shaving
points to me. What are they doing?
They don't notice.
Give me a fucking break cause
all I'm saying. All right.
And then another thing is I,
I,
there's no other fucking
sport with the star players.
Get the level of preferential,
I didn't want to hear it from you
fucking NFL fence with how they protect
quarterbacks. Okay. They do that
straight across the fucking,
they do that straight across the fucking
league because those guys are the
breadwinners and obviously a Peyton
manning a Brady is going to get one of the
star plays. Always get more preferential
treatment. Okay. In all sports.
I'll throw that out there,
but none,
none like the fucking NBA.
All right.
If you go near Coby Brian, you're getting
a fucking file. If it doesn't go in,
he looks at the ref like it didn't go in.
Obviously I was filed and he gets
to fucking call. It's annoying.
Having said all that,
as much as I hate the Lakers,
that was the fucking worst thing I've
seen is sports and a long time other than
that kid's leg fallen off for
Louisville was uh, uh, uh,
Colby, uh, snap, snap,
snapping his fucking Achilles.
But luckily they were in a,
in an age now where they,
the,
he's going to be back there the way
that they can operate on that. Like,
what am I trying to say?
The level of technology that they had,
like back in the day,
you were fucked.
It was over by my buddy
Jason [inaudible] had,
who's got a great podcast himself,
um,
was saying Dominique Wilkins came,
took a year off after an
injury and actually came
back and became NBA player of
the year. But he was never the same guy.
But, but it's different now. You know,
what's your course? They won't take into
consideration. So when he does come back,
they going to be the most I
believable and probable, you know,
isn't it ridiculous? My, my level
of fucking, it's not even a Lakers,
it's their fucking fence.
Their lack of knowledge on the game.
Well,
they have one of the most selfish self
centered fucking players of all time and
how the team actually plays as a tape
when he's not on the fucking court and
they still chant MVP. When that fucking
cancer comes back out on the court,
it just blows my fucking mind.
You know why?
Because everybody's in a fantasy
league and it's all about, well,
he had fucking 38 and Scholia
2,240 16 points better. All right,
let me take my tampon out here in la.
Let's get on with the podcast.
You're listening to the Monday morning
podcast and it's not brought to you by
anybody this week.
It's brought to you by me and my fuck.
Um, all right, so I started off with
something silly and over the top. Uh,
I don't, I don't like talking about
heaviest shit on this podcast,
but obviously I've got to acknowledge
what happened at the Boston Marathon. Um,
you know, I'm not gonna say anything
that everybody else hasn't already said.
I just don't know how somebody can,
hi, how do you fucking do that?
Just walk up and you setting it down
and you're looking at people's legs and
kids and Shit and you just walking away
knowing that in whatever, seven minutes,
eight minutes, whatever
the fuck it is. I mean,
just how do you do something like that?
You know,
fucking unbelievable.
It's got damn nerds, man.
I gotta tell you something.
Nerds are some of the most fucking
people on the planet. Okay?
Those two were a couple of nerds,
nerds,
fucking MIT fucking nerds.
You send me in a Goddamn hobby store
to cannibalize some fucking toys.
You think I'm coming out with a bomb?
I'm not,
I'm coming up with the fucking ugliest
toy you've ever seen in your life.
I'll fucking tape together with duct tape.
I didn't know what,
what is in a fucking hobby store?
What is in there?
What did they, what did they, some
glue. I don't know what they took. Um,
and is another thing that's
fucking annoys me. You know,
and then everything's nerds.
They,
they make all these fucking movies like
they're these great God damn people.
They aren't,
they aren't all the weaponry that you
see across the fucking globe for as much
as some sociopath thinks of this shit.
It takes a nerd to make that
psycho thought of fucking reality.
Fucking God damn nerds.
You teach them,
you know the secrets of the world and
this is what they do with it. You know?
Or they come up with something and then
somebody else uses it for fucking evil.
I don't know what the fucking thing is,
but here's my thing. Fucking cutting.
Get any terrorists listening
to this podcast. Are you,
I in a fucking cave right now.
You know,
jerking off to your fucking 72 virgins
or whatever the hell they're promising
you. All right? First of all,
they're not there. When you die,
you're going the ground.
Okay? That's where you go.
And so what you want to do is you
want to try and stay alive. You know,
meet yourself. Acute
fucking lady, you know,
have a cookout,
okay?
Ride a bicycle. Fill the wind in
your fucking hair or in your beard.
You know,
what are you doing?
When is your district manager going
to go fucking do something instead of
sending all you can sit over
here is another thing too.
How about you switch it up every once in
a while and you go to a gated community?
You know,
does it always have to be regular people?
Why don't you actually fucking go after
the country that are making your life
miserable and you know
who I'm talking about.
I'm talking about the fucking bank,
you know, let me tell you
something about these banker cons.
They fucking own everything.
You understand me? They own
everything. And if they don't own it,
it's just temporary because somebody's
going to fucking die or need a kidney and
then they're going to lose
whatever the fuck that they own.
Yeah.
You know,
every fucking house,
every fucking building,
every fucking piece of property,
every fucking blade of grass,
these fucking banker conch own.
And they look at it that
way. That's our stuff. Okay.
And then you go on it, you, you air quote,
buy it from us and then we bend you over
that fence and fuck you in the ass for
30 years.
By the time you come out the other side,
you're too fucking old to take care
of whatever you bought. All right.
Can I go up the stairs or
the wrong through walls and
then you sell it and then
they get another 30 35 year old cut in
there and they fucking bend them over.
Fucking have add if the 30 goddamn years,
that's what they do.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I dunno what those people
were trying to fucking achieve.
All they did was just, you know,
make a bunch of regular people.
There's no way to hear whatever you have,
whatever your fucking causes.
I don't give a fuck.
You could actually have agree with me
on everything that I think about the
fucking world this second.
You walk into a crowd and just
fucking do something like that. It's,
I don't know anyone we want to hear it.
MMM.
But you know, it was, it was, well,
it was fucking amazing was how they
just shut the whole fucking city down.
I mean,
that's just unbelievable.
Nobody just stay inside and then you
just got the only person running up the
street is the guy you're looking for
a couple of crackheads, you know,
crickets don't have radios
and plus they live outside it.
What the fuck am I supposed
to go in my box? You know,
get your feet up on that park bench.
Your fucking feet come off the park bench.
You were officially considered outside.
It gets to the shoot too.
And your fucking neck deck kid.
How funny was the news coverage?
Listened to all those
fucking Boston accents?
Yeah.
Yeah, we actually obtained yet there's
no suspects of Marcy Boulevard.
Um,
yeah,
I actually didn't watch most of it
once the bullshit was going. It's like,
I'm not going to sit here for eight hours
in watch a goddamn standoff watching
these fucking news reporters grabbing
anything with a mouth to start talking to
them, you know? Well, we got a, Ah,
we got a gentlemen hair or works,
uh,
he works at adamants bakery.
Uh, you, you said that, uh, you,
you, you actually knew one of the, uh,
suspects or should we know about
both of them had brown hair and,
uh, my mother's got brown hair,
so there's like, you know,
it's like eerie,
you know.
Then one time they actually got a guy
who were,
were one of the suspects,
dropped off the car, you know,
and he had all this fucking unbelievable
information and he's just spewing it
out on television and I,
and they're also filming the cops
where they're at and their location.
I just wanted something like
fucking 20 year vet to come up to,
what are these reporters?
Stick a pistol right underneath
his fucking Chin and just be like,
who's fucking side of you are
this, shouldn't this show? And
what they're doing. I Dunno.
But anyways,
I was really amazed at how quickly
and efficiently that whole thing went
down and how quickly they got those guys.
Uh,
okay.
It W it was unreal.
Um,
and then I was happy that when I found
out I'm sitting there going, please,
please don't be from North Korea.
Please don't be from the
middle of fucking east.
Please don't be from one of those fucking
places because these fucking assholes
are gonna beat us because
if we keep bombing every
fucking and going to war with
every country that they're from, I mean
we're going to go bankrupt. I mean,
we just spent like fucking out of how
many billions of dollars did we just spend
to catch like 35 people?
I don't know why we just don't
send the drones over there.
What are they going to do?
Worst thing to do is they shoot,
went down and gives a fuck. He just
make another one. Have a fucking nerd.
Make another one.
Okay.
You just fly around over
there, right? Damn. I know.
I'm over overly simplifying it,
but, um, then I found out they were
from Chechnya and I Chet. Yeah.
How the fuck you say it and
how many people will like,
like me who said that if from
Chet, yes. You can't even say it,
let alone even know where it is.
I thought that was near like
Yugoslavia or like a, uh,
checklist Slovakia.
And today when I went to look
it up before the podcast,
so I wouldn't even sound dumb or,
um,
I just wrote in Chetan yet, and
I spelled it so bad. Oh my God,
I spelled it so bad that,
um, I don't, I have you say,
I still can't fucking say it right.
And I've heard them say it like
9 million times in the news.
Like that computer didn't even
know what I was, was typing in.
So I had to take my shot at spelling
[inaudible] and then I've wouldn't Russia
after it. And then I was
like, oh, you made this. Um,
evidently it's just north of Georgia
and Armenia and as [inaudible],
um, it's basically to the right and
to the north of Turkey. You know,
I don't fucking know.
And you know what the worst thing about
the bombing other than the tragic loss
of life, you know, and there's so many,
so much other stuff like just I would
imagine people with hearing loss lost,
you know, vision or partial loss
of vision and just, I don't,
just a psychological, all of
that damage that was done, um,
right up there.
Not right up there,
but a distant third to death and injury
in psychological put it forth is the
fact that I really felt that I
was then in my own little way,
I was starting to turn the tide and I
was starting to turn red sox fans against
that fucking Neil diamond song.
But now,
now it's over because now
everybody's all patriotic.
You know about Boston,
they played the fucking song,
they played it at Yankee stadium.
I'm getting Deuce chills just talking
about it. And then Neil diamond himself,
the devil himself comes to fucking Fenway
and everybody region out touching me,
touching the fucking joy in these people's
faces as they sing along with this
man who wrote a song about
an eight year old girl.
I don't understand it, but
it's over now. I give up,
I'm thrown in the fucking towel. It's,
it's over. Cause now it now it is.
It's,
it's now associated with the triumphant
feeling of getting the two counts that
uh, you know, it started the whole fucking
art, whatever. Anyway, I'm fucking,
this is why I'm not a news correspondent.
I can't even explain it without saying
Kuntz who will responsible for the
bombings of Boston. There we go.
That's what I'm trying to say.
And now it's associated
with that. So it, it's,
it's fucking over fucking over. And, um,
anyways,
bright side of all of this is
that they got the two guys, um,
and the two guys who are trained in,
in a fucking country that's too fucking
big for us to attack at this point.
They've got too many, too much shit
themselves. So maybe we won't go.
We won't have to spend $1 billion,
you know,
have more loss of life on our side and
have like kill a million civilians over
there trying to find
fucking 35 assholes. So, um,
so I guess that part of it is good then.
I love that we got them and I think
it's fucking hilarious that people,
if there's already conspiracy
theories that, that,
that these aren't the two guys and
it's the youtube video of the week.
You got to hear this fucking guy.
He basically,
he pieces to gather a bunch of video
and cell phone pictures and he finds
another guy with a backpack and,
and then that's,
it completely ignores,
you know,
they say innocent men don't run yet.
They also don't kidnap people and throw
grenades and shoot guns at fucking
police. You know, that's not what you do.
Like I being accused of something I
didn't do and then he just grab a grenade
Outta your fucking back pocket,
you know?
But this guy is absolutely
convinced that from his computer,
he doesn't need to go down to the sea.
He doesn't need to interview anybody.
He doesn't need to be
anywhere near the evidence.
He just needs to be on his
computer looking at cell
phone pictures and video and
so he finds another guy with a backpack
that he says matches the one that was
exploded afterwards and then he goes,
there it is folks.
He goes, how much more proof do you
need? Then when he goes, he goes,
smoked it folks. Game over.
Just talking shit like version.
I love the guy. When I have time
I'm going to go back to his channel.
I'm going to watch all of his fucking
videos because if he's going to end every
half as half-baked fucking idea was
smoked it folks game over. I mean,
I don't know about you guys,
but that's easily four hours of
entertainment in my world, you know?
Anyways, so here we go. Let's get,
this is the Monday morning podcast and
I am your ignorant fucking host and I'll
make you feel better over the next 60
minutes about your level of intellect
because no matter how
dumb you think you are,
there's no way you're going to
come off as it stupider than I am.
What are we up to?
Huh?
How many fucking minutes is it time to
do the one and only read this week? What?
20 minutes in reaching out,
touching me pat up file,
fuck and creepy.
All do.
Get away from our damn kids.
Fuck you. Fuck you. All right,
here we go. I just hate when everybody
goes. Bump, bump, bump. You know.
Oh,
do the world a favor and kill yourself.
Kill that song. Um, wait a minute.
Okay.
Where the fuck is, where the fuck is
the a, the ads for this week, everybody.
I did my little due diligence here.
Downloads.
There it is.
stamps.com everybody
stamps.com you know the drill.
Small businesses know from experience to
going to the post office is a waste of
time,
but at least,
but leasing an expensive postage
meter is out of the question.
I know a better way and I've been
telling you about this for over a year.
stamps.com stamps.com we'll
save you valuable time.
You get 24 seven access to all services
of the post office right from your desk.
Whether you're sending
envelopes or packages first
class or priority domestic or
in an international,
however you want to send it.
Get the postage you need using your
own computer, printer and stamps.com.
You standing there and you're running to
where at two in the morning and you can
get all your mailing done.
You can get a jump on your day.
You never have to leave your house. It's
fantastic. It's the Howard Hughes, um,
style post. You can sit there and
grow your nails and your hair.
He can have a great time.
It's quick,
it's easy and it's really convenient
and you'll never have to go to the post
office again. I use stamps.com to send out
all my DVDs. I don't have any problems.
It's tremendous and I'm a moron and I
can figure out how to use it right now.
Use My last name burpee.
You rr for this special offer.
No risk trial plus a $110 bonus offer
includes a digital scale and up to $55 in
free postage. Uh, don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
enter
burr. There you go. That right there,
ladies and gentlemen is all
the advertising for this week,
so you whiny concern out there who want
your free shit and I love how they whiny
cunt,
want free shit and they want no
advertising worked for me for nothing.
I'm all right.
Before I get onto some of the other
shift that I want to talk about,
I'm going to read this first email that
I got from somebody and it's titled
Anger, not hitting. It said, dear bill,
I watched two of your specials
recently on Netflix while you,
you are a very funny guy.
Now this is when you know some
criticism is coming your way.
Anytime something now, you know? Yeah.
I'm not saying you're not a good guy.
While you are a very funny guy and
most of most of the stuff is great,
I really need to point out your bit
about violence against women has a major
flaw though.
Thank you person who never did stand up.
Please by all means help me fix my jokes.
Uh,
there's no doubt.
There are plenty of reasons a man
could be angry with the woman,
so there is a reason for that,
but there really is no reason
and no excuse for hitting.
My ex nearly murdered me because I didn't
want him to be with him anymore and
told him he needed to
move out of my house.
I paid for entirely mine alone.
I never laid a hand on him,
never even thought of it.
I spent a week in intensive care so you
can see how I might think that you could
amend that bit to say there are
reasons for anger not hitting.
All right. Now for those of you
who aren't standup Comedians,
this right here is a reoccurring email
that will go on throughout your entire
fucking career and this is what I find.
First of all, at no point did I
say anybody should hit a woman.
I never said that. I said, when they
say there's no reasons to hit a woman,
I presented the scenario. I just said,
look, there's plenty of reasons to do it.
You just don't do it.
That was the joke.
Repeat the joke.
Capital j Dash O k joke.
And this is what I find about people
who get offended and she was cool or
whatever. Obviously, you know, um,
this is what I find
about people who send me emails like this.
All right?
Obese people get offended
by jokes about obesity.
You know, women who've been fucking
beaten by some piece of shit.
Guy Get offended about the
hidden women joke. All right,
fuck it.
I Dunno.
People flight pilots get offended by my
shit about talking shit about pilots.
But this is what I find. Pilots never
get offended by the obese material.
Obese people never get offended
by the hitting women thing.
The dog lovers who get
offended by the dog,
they got adopted dog rescue dog bit.
Never get offended by the starving
child jokes. See what I'm saying?
Well, I understand. If you don't, I'll
let me try to explain it a little bit.
I'm just saying this
fucking lay sat through
two of my specials. So the first
special, okay. She watches,
I don't fucking talk about hitting women.
So that's an hour right there.
She sat through laughter,
fucking tits off at a great time.
And then she sits through about 40,
45 minutes to the next one
and everything's fucking fine.
And everything's funny and everything's
just a joke is I'm just going through
one topic after another that's offending
the fuck out of everybody who's in that
group.
And then it comes around to some shit
that's in her neighborhood and then all of
a sudden I have to start
making like a men's
okay
to bits.
I need to tweak it a little bit because
of her fucking personal experience.
I have to tweak it because
of her personal experience.
And then all of a sudden what
I'm saying is not a joke anymore.
It's more of a statement. And
I'm more, more like, you know,
I mean,
earlier in this podcast I advocated
these terrorists go into a fucking gated
community. Do you think I really want him
to do that? Yeah. No I don't. I don't.
But uh, just maybe light some
firecrackers off underneath that limo.
Just something,
some sort of small payback.
Okay.
How easy would it be for them to get
the fucking, those gated communities,
they're already driving town cars.
Yeah.
Dude, if I was a banker and
I was a piece of Shit Bagger,
I would be so fucking paranoid that
someone was going to whack me for all the
misery and suffering.
Okay.
That I fucking, you know,
that I've been caused.
Yeah.
The fact that I turned a fucking
pond into my own Jacuzzi, right.
I can park my yacht and my fucking
Jacuzzi and I just sit there,
you know, eating fucking crab
legs and caviar every fucking day,
standing on fucking dead babies heads.
There's no fucking way I would ever get
nick fucking town car. There's no way.
There's no way
I would have whoever my
Fredo of my litter of kids,
whoever the Frito was. That was the
be the guy that I had driven the car.
Although in the godfather he was looking
out for Marlin Brando and then I,
he got shot. Right. So, I
don't know. Fucking dumb.
Anyways. Oh, you know, I read some,
actually some really interesting shit
about how Iceland beat the bankers when
Iceland went bankrupt and in the, banker's
tried to pull this shit where, yeah,
we were greedy cuts and now we're putting
the dead on you when your taxpayers,
they said, you know what? Fuck you.
This is an our debt. This is our mess.
It's yours.
And then all these fucking sellout costs
like fucking Amsterdam and Britain put
all this pressure on fucking Iceland
because they pussied out with the bankers.
They've been on their knees sucking
that banker cock for fucking ever.
They tried to fucking
get them to come along.
They've tried to pressure them and I,
you know,
or else we'll turn you into the Cuba
of the north. And they said, fuck you,
we're not doing it. And you know what,
that's what this country should have done.
This country should have told
us bank or fucking cunts.
I just emphasized myself that
it isn't brought up more.
You know, it's the whole thing.
Like I had water damage to my house,
my insurance company sends a check
that's made out to me. Uh, Nia and,
and then my mortgage company
and I have to sweep up the sign,
the check over to them. So they keep
the money. And you know why that is?
Because they fucked so many
people so fucking hard in the ass.
So many people are upside down in
houses because of the bullshit that they
created by making people who aren't
qualified for loans qualified.
So instead of having five
people bid on a house,
she got 10 people bidding on it and it
goes up like super bowl tickets, right?
And all of a sudden a house that's
really worth a buck 80 sells for two 70.
So he got these concerts. Everybody's
fucking upside down on the house.
They're like, well fuck
it, I'm keeping this money.
And then when they foreclosed on it, they
fucking come in and they're like, fuck,
they never fixed the roof. So now I
have to sign over. My God, their money.
It's my money. It's my insurance.
That's my insurance money.
I have to send it into them. You know
why? Because people, it's not my house.
It's their fucking house.
It's theirs. All right.
And if I ever paid this fucker off,
what, you know I'm Gunna, I drive off.
I dropped her six year old hybrid.
All right. I don't give a fuck.
I fucking,
I dress like Malcolm young cause I'm
getting these cuts on in my life and this
is what's going to happen.
I'm going to pay off this fucking
house and you think when I die I can,
I can just give it to somebody
else. It's my house. Right?
Okay.
If I can fucking give
away all my other shit,
why can't I give the house the house is
going to have all taxes and all these
penalties and all this bullshit,
whoever I fucking leave it to
is gonna make you know what?
It's just going to be easier to sell it
and then they sell it and whatever money
they make,
they get the shit tax started them.
They get half a dick in their ass and
then somebody else buys this thing and
then the, that the bank goes deep in
them for another fucking 30 years.
You don't want halfway
through that I realized,
am I sounding crazy or am I making sense?
I Dunno,
I talked to a banker and a titty bar.
He agreed with everything I said.
All right, special thanks this week to
a everybody, I did a at the Tampa it,
who came out to the Tampa Improv,
who came out to Florida State University
in Tallahassee. I'd never been there.
And, uh, came out to Miami, the
Fillmore, Jackie Gleason theater, um,
had a great time in all cities.
That was the end of the bus tour
when it was just me and Versie, uh,
Jason Law had,
and his dad had gone home at that point.
So it was just us on the
bus. Um, I got gotta,
I have a fucking unbelievable
video of being on the bus and, uh,
this fucking RV is,
is just completely engulfed in flames.
So that'll be a video that I'll be sending
out to you guys this week if you want
to check it out. Tallahassee,
Florida. He played Florida state.
We went over to their Ra, Bobby Bowden.
We went over to the, uh, the stadium.
Did I tell you that last week?
I can't remember.
Okay.
No, I wouldn't because that
would have been on a Tuesday.
Yeah. So we fucking, we,
it was one of these great stadiums where
it,
they just leave it open and
then the students can go
in there and run the stairs
and just, you know, it's Kinda
how like it used to be stadiums,
even pro stadiums used to be like that. I
remember a long time ago, my family was,
was a vacation down to
Florida and we, we, uh,
we're in Tampa and somehow we ended
up the original Tampa Bay Buccaneers
stadiums, like the John
McKay one. Right. And I just,
I wanted to see it,
so I got out of the car with my mother
and we just walked right into the stadium
and I stood on the corner of one of the
end zones was just, it was wide open.
I mean, what do you, what are
you going to steal grass chairs?
It's just a big fucking circle
with, with uh, with chairs.
But now I guess because they got all
this other crap and there was the luxury
box. People think you're gonna, I
dunno. Steel what a fucking recliner.
I Dunno, whatever. So Florida State
University, we went there. I mean for,
as he actually,
we ran up the stairs once one time and um,
it was one of the great workouts
I've ever had. Just doing it once.
And of course me I have fucking
OCD is like, oh, you know what,
I do one for three days in a row.
Then I do too when I,
if I could work my way up like that,
but that,
but that was just my brain just starts
fucking going. But, um, great crowds.
They're great crowds and Tampa smoked
some amazing fucking cigars and Tampa.
And then we went down to
the Fillmore. Um, Miami,
south beach. It's south beach is
so fucking beautiful with the,
they have all these, like I'm a big fan
of art deco and they have all these, uh,
art deco style and the theater itself,
um,
was that art deco style crowd was amazing.
Um,
I'm not gonna lie to you dude. That tour
I just went through through the south.
I was on my fucking game. I had some
of the best shows I've ever had. And,
um, I think it was because it took me so
long to sell tickets down in the south.
Like,
um,
like the first place I sold
tickets obviously was east coast.
It's where I'm from.
MMM.
You know,
I,
my HBO special came out and then I got
on the opiate Anthony show at the same
time cause Norton was doing,
I'm lucky Louie.
So those two things kind of hit at
the same time. And once they hit,
I kind of was able to sell tickets
from Boston down to like DC,
which is a big O and a market.
And um,
then maybe to about Cleveland,
but I didn't have Pittsburgh though.
MMM.
And then I think I had like San Francisco,
that's what I had.
And then gradually I got the middle of
the country and the last one to fall was
the south.
I just couldn't get in down there from
fucking Nashville all the way down.
Even a like Miami, Miami, and Miami's do
the Improv. It was like, yeah, you know,
white comics don't sell well down here.
It's a really big Latino community. And,
and they weren't lying. And I
showed up, there was nobody there.
So I think I was fucking excited and
felt like I had something to prove.
I don't know what, but it was kind of
like the first show went well and uh,
it was like you hit your first jump
shot, you know, and then it just,
it just was fucking
amazing, man. Just amazing.
So I really want to thank everybody
who came out to all those shows. One,
one thing that did bump me out though was,
you know,
I'm a huge Jackie Gleason
fan. I used to watch is, uh,
obviously watched all the
honeymoon winners episode
and then I used to watch is
a, is a variety show, which I also loved.
You know, Joe the
bartender. Um, what was it?
Crazy crazy. I can't
remember. It's been so long.
I forget it. This isn't, when I say
Lou Holtz sounds like, hey yo, hey,
you meet the gunny. He that guy, he
sounds just like Lou Holtz. Shay,
you praised freaking to you coach.
Um,
excuse me. Um, oh fuck me.
God dammit.
I swear to fucking Christ.
Are you guys like me? Ah, fuck.
I spill a fucking glass of water.
Every god Damn Day
went right on my rolling stone,
which I have a subscription to fucking
Louis CK is on the cover. You know,
this is one I'm obviously going
to say knock it off fucking wet.
Now you gotta go down to the new standard
by another one. But you know what,
that'll be good for him
because they'll think,
well everybody's buying it
cause he's on the cover.
They won't realize it's a bunch of morons
spill of glasses of water on it. Uh,
by the way,
if you get a chance,
fucking unreal article on Louie
Ck fucking killer article,
killer article. Um, so anyways,
going back to, uh, the
Jackie Gleason theater.
So I performed there and then
I leave and after I left,
somebody goes like, yeah, how amazing
is that theater? You know, I was insane.
He's like, yeah, Jackie Gleason performed
there and blah blah. Like I know, I know.
And they go, did you see his
dressing room? And I was like, what?
They go yap stairs.
They have his dressing room.
They'd kept it pretty much like the way
he had it after he was finally here.
I mean, it's amazing. It's like walking
back in time. And I was like, it's like,
what the fuck?
Why didn't you tell me?
How do I know I'll ever
be back there again?
That was the only bad part.
But then it was quickly made up because
Versie at the end of the show is a,
he met this chef under New
Hampshire, uh, Tim, Andrew Yola,
and he had this, he was like, uh, I guess
he has three restaurants down there,
celebrity chef. Long story
short, he invites us out,
keeps the restaurant open, and we
basically, to use firsties expression,
we dined like gods. It was
insane. Now forgive me, Tim,
because I don't fucking remember the
name of the restaurant. I and, and,
and so you don't think I'm being
disrespectful? I don't know.
Remember the names of any
restaurants. All right. Like I have,
I just have nicknames for all
the ones that we go to out here.
One of them's called pancake circus.
That's cause I walked into
the first time I saw it,
his giant like manholes size pancake with
a bunch of fucking whipped cream on it
and all I could think of was like, that
looks like clown food. So I don't know.
I'm a moron, but I think it's
Timo. But this is the thing.
The first thing we go there, the first
thing they bring out is crab legs.
I fucking hate crab legs. I've never
been into them. It's so much God.
Their work to get a mouthful of fucking
meat and then it just tastes like the
God damn ocean.
All right.
I have been converted
these fucking crab legs.
Not only with the best crab legs
I ever ate. They would some,
it was some of the best
food I've ever had.
Even the melted butter tasted better
than anybody else's melted butter.
I was sitting there,
I look like a fucking,
I look like a toddler eating birthday
cake, seven cake all over my face.
It was just fucking crab legs and butter.
I musta ate like fucking
three or four of those legs.
Then he brought over pizzas.
Who does pizza well in fuck outside of
New York and the fucking east coast.
This Guy Tim, Andrew Yola fucking
pizzas. Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
And then, uh, we had, uh, severe Jay.
Is that how you fucking Chetan yeah.
I don't know how to fucking say it.
Um,
on fucking believable food and the
restaurant. It's spelled t I m.
O.
I know I'm saying it wrong cause there's
a little fancy accent thing over the o
team. I don't know how to say it, but
it's right on the beach. All right.
If you ever go down to south breach
and you bring your fucking lady,
then I can't say at t I
m m o with the fucking,
it's not the motley Crue two dots. It's
one of those little accent things. Um,
so thank you to Tim. His
whole staff, everybody was,
was insane. And we came over,
they was like, it was
like eight of us. Um,
and you know, I swear to God, he, they,
they would've still bring it bullpen,
bringing out food if we didn't,
if we didn't, if we didn't leave,
it was one of the greatest I've ever been.
Uh,
treated on the road and uh,
you know, yeah. I don't know.
It was, it was fucking insane. Um, so,
okay.
What else?
What else am I going to talk about it
that I don't have any smooth transition
from that to the next thing here.
I've been watching a bunch of shit on,
uh, on Netflix. I'm big on the, uh,
I like documentaries,
you know,
and I watched one and a half
last night before I fell asleep.
I watched this thing called the
queen of Versailles was she have to,
you have to see, and it's basically
about this guy, 75 years old,
75 years old. He married Miss Florida,
1993. So he's fucking balling.
Has seven kids with her.
Right. And he's got this,
he sells time shares,
you know, which you know,
is really a shady fucking
business, you know. Hey, you what?
I mean, I don't, I don't know. What
is it fucking time share? It's,
it's, it's a, it's a fucking
overpriced hotel room, isn't it?
I mean,
I don't know.
What am I buying if I
spend all that money?
I don't want to be laying in a bed
that somebody else has been fucking in.
I want a brand new bed. Okay. That's,
that's deal number one
because other than that,
I can go lay in a bed that everybody
else fucked in all year long.
It's called the hotel. Right. But
this guy hit, we had basically had,
was the biggest time share company,
um,
in the world according to him.
And uh,
and he was in the middle of building the
biggest house in America and it had 10
kitchens. This fucking nine people in
their family. They have one more kitchen.
Then they have people in their family.
All right.
You have to watch just to see them.
I mean,
it's not finished yet because in 2008,
they got caught up on all
the bankers shit. And um,
but you just have to see when his wife
walks in with their friend and when they
walk up these stairs, I'm telling
you, these fucking stairs are,
are wider than the stairs at
grand central in New York City.
They go upstairs and they'll
fucking friend of miss.
Miss 1993 Florida goes is like,
you know,
cause they haven't like put the walls
up. It's just the uh, the framing of it.
She goes, oh my God. She goes, is
that your bedroom? And she goes, no,
it's my closet.
It's fine.
But if you really want us,
okay,
now a lot of people will watch the queen
of Versailles and go look at these two
selfish fucking people in all
the waste and all that apps.
A fucking loofy lutely that's on the
fucking surface bond underneath all of it.
You,
you see a guy who doesn't want to declare
bankruptcy and put that money on the
American people and wants
to fight his way out of it.
And the bankers won't do it. Like he
had a building out in fucking Vegas.
He put 350 million of his own fucking
money in and now we can't make the
payments. So he wants to
bankers to try and, you know,
give him some of the bailout money and
they kept all of it because this is the
thing, if he fucking, if they
get him to default on that,
they get to keep his 350 million and
sell the fucking building all over again.
MMM.
You know, and obviously this
guy, he got over extended,
he made the mistake of not realizing,
you know,
what bankers are and what it is that
they do. They're not your friends.
They're not trying to help you
grow your fucking business.
They're trying to make every
fucking dime off you is they can.
And when it's over,
you're bus the joint out.
I just started thinking
about the, the fucking, uh,
good fellas when they
start burning it down,
but rather than burning the place down,
they fucking did you that Ray Liotta
and fucking Joe Pesci a fucking tie in
those little candle things to you.
Trying to bang his fucking Jew brought
over here. You can't help me out.
So well coming to, um, and then you
burn to the ground and that's it.
But the building's still standing and
then they get some other group to go in
there and then they fucked them
in the ass. I'm telling you.
Yeah,
we should all as civilians,
you remember the ending of Scarface
when they were coming over the wall.
That's what we should be doing right now
in gated communities, going to bankers,
fucking houses.
We should be dragging him,
dragging them out by the tassels
of their fucking wing tips. Um,
all right.
Anyways,
so I watched that phenomenal.
And it was sad.
It was also sad because you saw a guy
that was really into his business.
But granted, I think also, you know,
you have to find a through line
when you're filming something.
Cause I think they initially
started the documentary, Eh,
I think it was an issue was going to be,
look how successful this guy is.
And then that shit happened and
then it turned into something else.
So I heard he sued the
makers of the documentary.
But a phenomenal and the
music is, is incredible. Um,
all right. And then I watched
another one about the serial killer,
Carl Pans, Ram, the spirit
of hatred and vengeance.
You got to fucking see this.
MMM.
He,
he writes this guard befriends him
and he writes a fucking book in jail.
And, uh, I forget how off I fuck it. I
Ha I had it in my head. How he said it.
They have the voiceover actor.
Good.
My name is Carl pay his rent and they've
killed over 22 people and committed
over a thousand acts of sodomy.
How his book starts.
I got to buy the fucking book.
Um, let me, let me look this up.
I'll read,
I'll read you a little bit about this
guy and Wikipedia for some reason, like,
you know, a bunch of other people. Ted
Bundy, speaking of Florida state, Dude,
you know what? Florida state where Ted
Bundy killed those three sorority girls.
Um,
they still use that house is a sorority
house that should fucking blew me away.
Fucking blew me away. Like
how, how, how in God's name.
Now I'm not into ghosts. I don't
believe in that shit. But, uh, I,
I do draw a line.
I don't think that I,
I could sleep in that fucking house
knowing that all that shit like happened.
All right, here we go. Let's
just re Carl Pants rim here. Um,
it wasn't American serial killer,
rapists, arsonists and burglar.
MMM.
Here we go. He's known for his confession.
So who was only friend? Prison Guard,
Henry Lesser. Let's get
to this killing spree, uh,
put up a, the total, you know. Hmm.
What the fuck is he basically,
he used to have,
he had a boat and he would get sailors
drunk and he would bring these guys back
to the boat.
He'd fucking sodomized them and then
shoot him in the head and throw him
overboard. One of those evil
fucking things. That was basically,
that happened when he was a kid. He got
fucking raped. And then he was like,
all right, well, I'm fucking
rape. And everybody else. I mean,
the guy was just fucking, yeah.
Let me look up some quotes.
I don't want a creepy guys out. This
would be turned into a creepy podcast,
but I just never heard of this guy.
MMM.
Calm around.
Where the fuck is it?
All right. There's some website, the
11 most bad ass words ever uttered.
I hate when I do this. Do Guys want
to just start surfing the fucking net?
All right.
Hurry up. You. Who's your bastard? I could
kill 10 men while you're fooling around.
I Dunno. You know, it kind of
helps if you have the context. Oh,
I was that when they went to kill him.
Everyone hopes to leave a legacy to be
remembered after our passing did have up
it up.
Put it there.
Some people try to pull off in mortality
with the lifetime of achievement and
noble acts,
but why piss away all that energy when
you can simply spout one badass quote
before you take a dirt nap
and live on through eternity
known as a guy who needed a
second casket for his balls.
The last words of Carl
Pans Ram when they will.
He said, hurry up. You,
who's your bastard?
I could kill 10 men while
you're fooling around. Um,
who is your summary From Indiana?
Uh, but, uh, put up a Duh
Carl pans ramp did make an interesting
point about the mire of bureaucracy
versus individual enterprise
if you guys are executing.
Okay.
Elbit yeah. Basically thought
they were taking too long.
Okay.
Wow. This is great man. This
is all people's last words.
Last words of chief sitting bull.
I'm not going do with me.
What you like.
I'm not going.
Okay
then. Exclamation point. Come on.
Come on and take action. Let's go.
I guess that was back. Uh, you want to
fucking do this? Let's do this. That was,
that's how they said it
in the 18 hundreds. Um,
and he's also speaking a second language.
That's how much balls he had.
He still sounded tough
in another language.
MMM.
No. The guy before he got hanged,
the last words of George Angle,
union activist and founder of the
Socialist Labor Party be standard with the
fucking rope around his neck.
He said, hooray for anarchy.
This is the happiest moment of my life.
All right,
I got to read them all now.
Just when you thought you
had a fucking pair, it,
we go Gil's Corey.
Last words of a farmer accused of being
a witch, wellbeing crushed with stones.
He said more weight.
Uh, James French convicted
word murderer, putting a death,
um,
in the electric chair.
Oh, his name is James
French. He goes, hey fellas,
how about this for a headline for
tomorrow's paper? French fries.
Okay.
Oops, sorry. I'm a joy in
this. I hope you are too.
Uh,
last words of the hipster hero.
How do you say his name?
Che Guevara and the one that
everybody has on the tee shirt.
I don't know what he did.
He was friends with fucking the beer
to bastard down there and then all of a
sudden he went down. He was going to
play baseball. All those Cuban rebels,
at some point they were going to play
baseball. They fucking love the game,
I believe. What's his face? Uh,
Castro pitched in the farm
league and the Colt 45.
Uh,
all right.
Okay.
This is what this was it Che Guevara.
His last words were,
I know you're going to kill. Shoot,
you're only going to kill a man.
Jesus.
Okay.
I hope that they don't have,
if I'm going out like that,
they better not have my last words cause
I'm going to sound like the biggest
pussy ever,
you know, just thinking of
it was what's his face? Uh,
I can't remember anybody's fucking names.
I got to get this one right.
I gotta get this name right
off. I can't, I can't do this
a fucking, uh, I, I'm a moron.
This goes to go back to the podcast. I
was thinking of the, who's the guy plays?
Macgruber we'll uh, it's too many wills.
Will Ferrell will our net. It's not that.
It's fucking,
I'm the worst.
How he would always do that thing.
What do you would get into a jam and
just be like, I will suck your Dick.
I would have some awful fucking
quote like that. I would,
I don't want to die. Don't kill me. Please
do not kill me. All right, here we go.
Some fucking, um, I got to look. I'm
going to look up his fucking name.
Okay. Addicted to who was, hey,
bill loved the podcast.
I could use a bit of advice.
I'm a 30 year old man and have a bit
of a problem over the past few years,
I've become addicted to horse,
not just typical bar sluts,
but full blown professionals.
So GJ um,
it's gotten so bad that I researched the
girls that I see in the majority of my
time consists of going through message
boards and underground communities filled
with other pervs like myself
who review working girls.
All right, dude, you're going
down a dark fucking hole.
I fortunately never went down.
Uh,
I'm already in over my head here,
but you know, whatever you wrote it.
So I'm going to fucking try and answer
it knowing full well that I am not a
professional sir. Um, he says,
my problem is that I have
become so addicted to this
lifestyle that I cannot see
myself having a traditional relationship
with the woman. Yeah, absolutely.
Absolutely. You Open
Pandora's box. You know, dude,
you're,
you have a woman who will do whatever
you want and you don't have to be
emotionally there for, you don't have
to wipe your feet off. You could just,
you know, talk to wherever you want.
Give her some money and then she leaves.
You don't even have to cuddle.
You have zero emotional responsibility.
You know,
that's like somebody rich who's been
fucking flying around in their own jet and
then all of a sudden, you know,
this shit goes down like, and that,
that queen of Versailles and all of a
sudden they have to get on a commercial
flight and that kids are looking around.
God, why are all these people on a plane?
You're in the same place. Your Dick
is like a billionaire, you know,
and if you get door fucking relationship,
but that this point,
that's like the 2008 collapse,
you know?
Does that make any sense?
All right.
After experiencing this
lifestyle for so long,
I just cannot force myself to sit at a
bar trying to convince some chick who's
best years are behind her to
give me a halfhearted. Bj,
um,
I consider myself a decent looking guy.
I think you consider yourself
a lot more than that, sir.
I think you stand in front of the
mirror with your hands on your sides.
Like Superman, not hands on your hips,
hands on your hips, that's a feminine.
But if you stand there with
your two fists like that,
then all of a sudden you look like you
should have a Cape flapping behind Ya. Um,
I think you do that, you stand
there and you're naked, you know,
with like the same distance between your
feet that a state trooper has when it
comes up going dude,
how fast you were going,
and then you look to the
side with your Dick flap,
but it in the wing because
of the oscillating fan. Yeah.
Then you'd every morning,
God,
I am not sure.
Uh, that's how I think you feel about
yourself. That I would just guess.
Um,
anyways,
I think I'm a decent looking guy and
I do get attention from the women,
but I often find that they are not
worth the effort because I get bored so
quickly. Yeah. I know actually having to
converse rather than just being like, hey,
how much for you to suck my Dick?
Oh yeah,
I'll give you a half that good. My work
with me meet. I'll meet you in the middle.
I'll give you an extra five cause it's
cold out. All right, get in the car. Um,
my problem is that I get bored with women
immediately after I sleep with them.
I do not fear diseases as I
always use condoms though.
That's not 100% by the way.
I don't know why, but it is.
I don't know how you can have a raincoat
on your Dick and still get herpes I
think cause your balls are fucking
hanging out of the back of the chopper,
you know,
and safety.
I always use condoms and safety
and safety wise,
I love when you guys like rewrite your,
your fucking emails and then you delete
half a sentence and then you fucking
don't notice and then you put it in here
and you make me look even dumber than I
am anyway.
So I guess he uses condoms.
He said it would be Doobie
just as dangerous sleeping
with a random bar slut who
doesn't force their partners to
use condoms? Uh, no it wasn't sir.
No it wouldn't because it's
a numbers thing. Alright.
Some bar slut who doesn't
use condoms versus some woman
who fucks professionally.
Okay.
That's like you throwing the football
around in the back yard saying you just
like Tom Brady. Okay. Did,
it's not the same thing,
but I know you're saying
that to make yourself feel
better, feel better. He said,
I fear never being able to have a normal
relationship with a woman down the road.
I feel like my internal wiring got crossed
somewhere and I need a wide variety
of women to keep me sane.
I really want to fuck every woman I see.
But unfortunately I can cannot a
golf club, so I got to pay for it
anyway. Out of this love the podcast.
Yeah. I you need to go to therapy.
Um,
okay.
I gotta tell you though, once you,
once you, I dunno. Yeah. You, you need,
you need to go seek professional
help, sir. I would, I would.
I would say that because,
uh,
you've gone down a road for so long and
you keep coming around the track the
same way you've worn this grooving and
it's very hard to get out of. And, uh,
you have to sit down and
want to do the work and you,
you have to work with professional and
figure out if you have a sex addiction
addiction or whatever. One
of the doctor drew, you know,
if they can't afford it, I would
call doctor drew. But even then,
he's only going to talk to you for a
minute to have him guide you in the right
direction though. Uh, because that guy is,
is he kind of keep gets right to it.
I've done a show a couple of times,
he's fucking unreal. Um, so
that would be my suggestion.
I would say at first and foremost,
stop fucking prostitutes because you
are going to catch something and every,
and not only that, every, every one that
you bang or have blow you or whatever,
it's just another step further down
a direction you don't want to go.
And then also, it's a terrible
thing to do, you know,
to solicit a prostitute.
You're basically, you know,
something horrible happened to her
and then you take an advantage of it.
It's fucking horrific.
Um, so they, you go,
I hope I helped you. I know I gave
you a lot of shit throughout that,
but I hope it helps you out because
that is a serious problem. Okay.
House Derris Billy boy,
keeping it short and sweet duty.
Your undying hatred for reading out
loud. I actually don't mind it. I just,
I hate sounding stupid.
Uh,
my fiance and I are moving
into our first house on Friday.
Any last minute advice?
Yes.
Um, well, it's too late. You
already bought a fucking house.
My first thing would be drive
less of a car, wear less clothes,
everything less and start
knocking out the principal.
All right. You got to start
knocking that fucking thing down.
MMM.
And when they, then once you
knock it down to a certain point,
then they're going to come at you and
be like, Hey, do you want to refinance?
You want to refinance?
Look,
your mortgage payment will go
from 1500 down to 1200 dental.
Save you 300 bucks a month.
That's all a fucking scam.
Okay.
You really think there's somebody who
works at the bank and his job and he's
sitting there going, how can this bank
make less money? Oh, I know what I mean.
How long would that guy worked
there before we get fired?
It's a scam because what happens is if
you like four or five years into your
mortgage,
they're going to refinance it and your
payment doesn't go down 300 bucks and
you're still five years in, it
starts back at zero. All right?
Now you have that payment for 30 years
and you're starting all fucking over
again. So the 300 bucks that
you're saving each month,
they make it more in the fucking interest
in the long run because they sent you
back to square one.
It's all a fucking scam of telling you,
go to the gate communities and
go over the fucking wall. Um,
don't really do that. All right? I don't
want to be held responsible for that. Um,
these are all jokes. Wink, wink,
nudge, nudge. Um, all right.
Any other advice?
Yeah,
yeah.
Don't let you fucking lady.
Let,
let your woman have the
fucking dining room.
Let her have the fucking,
uh, living room. All right?
But you, you have to stake
your fucking claim in there.
Okay?
Don't let her turn it into a fucking
doll house the same way she wouldn't want
to be living right in some fucking,
you know,
House that looks like a sports bar,
and you got some fucking deer head
in a keg on tap and all that shit.
You know what I mean?
But just like I would say steak,
you're fucking claim in the
house and just say, listen,
I want this house to be a representative
represent presentation of both of us.
All right?
Okay.
And uh,
if it goes too far one way or the other,
I don't think the other person is
going to be happy and just say, listen,
I don't care what you do with this.
I don't care what you do with this room.
Just pick yourself a rumor to cause this
sort of unwritten rule is that the guy
gets one room and it's the
darkest kv just fucking place.
It's the basement. It's the fucking
garage and a, it's bullshit.
It's bullshit. Okay. So
that's what I would say.
Make sure that when people walk in,
they can immediately see
that you live there too.
That's something with a set of balls
is actually in that fucking house.
All right. And that's it. Good luck
with your marriage then. Your new house.
Congratulations. Pay Down the fucking
principal, sir. Get the shackles off Ya.
All right. Crazy ass
mom. Hey Bill. What's up?
My name is Hector. I'm from,
I'm a full time college student.
My life is fairly well. I get good
grades and shit. Big family. One,
a seven boy refinance with some new put.
Uh,
start it back to square one. Uh,
when was that? When I was little,
she was basically trying to steal me from
my father and taking all of his money
in the process. Hell
hath no fury, sir. Also,
she used to beat me like a red headed
stepchild. I find that offensive.
Okay.
All right. You want my
advice? Stone itself. Me?
Yeah.
All right,
Hector,
you don't what? I always
got childish. It made, uh,
made some joke about your change steering
wheel because you name is Hector.
But then I realized that that would
insult other Mexicans and I'm not like you
sir. I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
I'm take the high road here.
It just say that I wish you would've
chosen your words a little more carefully.
All right. And, uh, tell me. Okay.
Bb like a redheaded stepchild
and tell him, tell me.
My Dad did not love me, so I
would stop asking for him. Wow.
Yeah. That's, um,
that's something that parents do during
divorce on both sides. They use the kids.
That's, I'm so glad that never happened
to me and I got fucked up in other ways.
Uh,
this fucker left.
My father was so little money that he
had no money to pay the light bill and
other shit.
My Mom's stupid ass brother held a gun
up to my father's head and said he would
blow his head off because he
got my mom pregnant with me.
My Mother's dad was also,
um,
an ultra can't. Yeah. So he was familiar
with, constantly went out and married it.
Hopefully he fucking corrected
the problem. Cheeses.
You giving me the whole
family tree here, sir. Um,
since then she had gotten remarried
and then divorced a fucking gun.
He says the problem is after all that
shit, I can't stand even look at my mom.
How do I tell her to basically fuck
off this fucking podcast is the fucking
shit. Don't stop you redheaded
maniac. All right. There.
He made it up with something
positive towards redheads.
Thanks for your important. No.
Yeah, go fuck yourself. Um,
no,
this is very touchy because you know,
as much as you consider your biological
mother, your mother, this is your mother.
So, um, I don't know how that works
because I've never been in this situation,
so I wouldn't tell you.
Okay.
Your first mother to fuck off.
Yeah.
What I would do is I would have,
um,
yeah,
she is your mom. So I
would, I would have a,
just a very controlled
relationship with her.
Like I would meet her at restaurants,
I'd meet her in public and
have lunch with, be okay.
Got To get on with my week and that
way, you know, that way itself,
when she dies some day, you don't
have this regret that, uh, you know,
I hated my own mother.
What does it mean? Um,
and then I would just do happy mom shit
with, with your non biological mother,
you know, just smile and wave, go
through the motions with there. But, um,
I dunno,
I'd say I'd say maybe therapy call you
call your mom a cunt in therapy rather
than to her face. Cause it's, it's
not going to get you anywhere.
And as you get older and she gets older,
it's just,
it's not going to be a good fucking thing.
But I totally have empathy for
the situation that you're in.
I would just treat my biological mother
as my real mother and I would have a
respectful relationship with
my, uh, my original mother.
And, uh, when she started talking crazy
and everything, just be like, listen,
you know, you said that
stuff to me when I was a kid.
It caused a lot damage to me and,
um, I don't want to hear your trash,
my dad anymore. Uh, I respect
how you feel about him,
but I don't want to hear about it because
you have to understand that that's my
father. All right? And if
she has a problem with that,
you just go check please.
Yeah.
Now you go, she wants to make a scene
and throw some bread or route, then a,
then you got to be like, listen, you
know I can't, I can't hang out with you.
You're crazy. Trashing my dad. You're
throwing appetizers around the road.
Okay.
I will have dinner with you again when
you can show to me that you can act like
an adult.
Maybe you can just lay the ground rules.
This is how it's going to be.
We are meeting at restaurants and you
going to behave like an adult and you are
not going to trash my father.
Okay? We're going to sit here.
We're going to talk about the weather and
what's going on in our lives right now.
We're not talking about the past anymore.
That's, that's what I need from you.
If you can't give me that,
then I'm not going to the olive garden.
Okay?
There you go. Sir. I hope that works
for you. All right, relationship advice?
I'm pregnant. Oh, okay. Hey,
Mister Bill. I'm a 21 year old pregnant
girl who lives in Shit town, Illinois.
I moved here a little over a year ago
to be with my boyfriend who I met on
match.com
this is your prints. You meet him on
match.match.com led you to shit town,
Illinois.
There's a fucking one for everybody.
Do not go on match.com those stupid
commercials. They show everybody happy.
Everybody playing Frisbee
women jumping into guys arms.
Zani you see some 20 year old girl got
knocked up by some cut and fucking Shit
Town Illinois? I don't think so.
Hey Sweetheart, you know what?
You're already a great person because
you'll let us know what happens@match.com.
Um, everything was great at first that
I realized how much I fucking hate this
place. This town is such a cunt
and that includes the people in it.
I've been telling him that and I'm
unhappy for at least six months,
but he doesn't seem to care. Oh, see,
you don't really have a problem with him.
Yeah. Great. Now I have a slander
case with fucking match.com he said,
now I'm pregnant with his child and have
the opportunity to move to Arizona to
be with my parents.
I told them that I'm going to go,
but he said that he would absolutely,
absolutely would not follow me there.
He said he loves this place because it
has a lot of outdoor activities and he
loves his job.
This is not as hometown.
He makes $9 an hour
being a bicycle mechanic.
I told them there are bike shops all
around the country and he can find another
fucking job, especially since he is
former military. He doesn't care.
He's a stubborn ass.
What the fuck do I do?
This place has turned me into a depressed
bitch and I hate myself for it and I
don't want to bring the baby
into that kind of whirl.
Hopefully you can shed some wisdom on
this for me. I Dunno. This is a rough one.
So you're basically going to move to
where you want to live and then he's going
to become you. That's
what worried about, um,
do you have some sort of job
opportunities in Arizona?
MMM.
Cause you know, along with having
bike shops all around the country,
they also have outdoors.
Yeah.
You can go outdoors
anywhere in the country.
That's one of the greatest things
about the United States and Russia.
They can't go outdoors wherever they go.
You know,
you could send to Siberia and shit.
You are a fucking indoors.
All right?
Getting fucking raped in the ass and
all you can feel is somebody mittens on
your hips.
Oh,
that's one of the fucking most
evil jokes I've ever made.
MMM.
All right. What am I talking about? What
do you do? A sweetheart? I don't know.
Okay.
If the guy's fucking
that level of stubborn,
I, I honestly, you know
what I, you stumped me.
I know you're fucking punching
your fucking iPod right now.
What have you listened to the
song? What do you what? All right,
what would I do if I was a pregnant lady?
MMM.
Well, here's the question. How do you
feel about this guy? Do you love this guy?
He's just the guy you're going to marry.
MMM.
If that's the deal,
then I don't know you.
You got to try and work something out
because you guys are together and you got
to do, you've got to try and
do what's best for the kid.
But if this guy isn't the guy that I
don't know what to tell you that I read,
I think he's some great advice.
Don't get fucking pregnant by your
boyfriend at 21 I mean, I don't,
I don't want to tell you here you really,
you know what?
You really painted yourself into a corner.
I think what you have
to do is you have to,
you gotta man up and make a decision here.
Okay?
You have to make a decision what's best
for your baby because now you're in this
situation.
I know a baby needs a mom and a dad,
but if you guys don't really love each
other, whether you live in Arizona,
he live in Illinois,
it's eventually gonna fucking blow up.
Okay.
So I would just at this
point you're having a baby.
So your needs are out the window.
It's gotta be about the kid.
But you did mention in there,
so I guess took me a second
to try to figure this one out.
I guess if I was in your situation I
would do what was best for the baby.
Okay.
So whatever that answer is, I
would go with that. All right.
But I don't think that that's
just a, uh, a one sided talk.
Like you really have to sit down with,
uh,
with your boyfriend there and try and
together figure out what's best for the
kid.
Okay.
And then I would do that. Alrighty. I
hope that helped you out. All right,
this is a long podcast today. Um, is this
the last? This is the one. All right.
Hang in there everybody advice
for a big presentation. I bill,
I saw your special on Netflix and I
left my face off a few days later.
I started a new job at the sort of place
where my coworkers don't really speak
to each other during work hours.
You can hear the wiring,
the gear of the worrying of the fan
overhead and desk drawers being open and
shut Jesus Christ. So thank Christ
for your podcast. What a relief.
Thank you for making my day. All right.
I'm presenting at Ted at a Ted x event.
Is that like ted.com or all those eggheads
talk about robots and scuba diving in
like a wheelchair.
Um,
and I'm wondering what sort of tips you
might have for speaking to large crowds.
Try to make them laugh off the top or
save it until I'm further into the speech
or,
or what you've poked fun about bringing
a joke full circle at the end of the
set.
Is that lame?
I do this where whenever I write something
I can't read it once it's published
because it all sounds so cheesy to me.
Oh,
if you write it down because you're in
your head. Okay, I see what you mean.
He says like, I ended up hating
what I just put out there.
I just want to cringe every time
I think about my speech, you know?
What do you think? Ah, I think you have
the classic mentality of the performer.
You want to be in front of everybody,
you have self hatred and you want
the crowd to clap and be like, no,
but seriously,
you're a good guy.
MMM.
I would say this.
Um,
just talk to them like you're
talking to your buddies in a bar.
That's what I would do. I would just, if,
if you don't like what you wrote down,
what I would do is I would have talking
points in front of me like I'm starting
with this point and then talk off the
top of your head. If you're good at this,
by the way, all right. Now this is
one of your first times doing this.
You're going to be a little nervous.
It might be good to have
something a little more
prepared, but if you're good at,
you know, talking in front of people, I
would just have bullet points. You know,
like I'm going to talk about
how I ended up in a wheelchair.
I'm going to talk about how I used to
love the ocean and then I'm going to talk
about having all of
that taken away from me.
And then I'm going to talk about the
apparatus and then I'm in the ocean.
Then I'm going to show him the pictures
and then going to get all teared up.
And then I'm going to wheel myself
off while with one hand while waving.
But then I'll be in a circle and then
realize that I'm doing a circular waving
thing in my chair and then I'll just
sort of back up off the stage. You know,
that's just one example.
But um,
I think you know what the good thing
is your competition isn't that stiff.
There's going to be a bunch of monotone
jackasses. I'm just sitting there going,
Bruker,
Naren,
Cary Sherburne duty for fuel
and Yorkton injury or injury.
You're going to, you know, you're
gonna have to go on after that.
So it might not be that difficult.
So that's basically what I would do.
All right people, that's the podcasts this
week. Thank you for listening. Please.
All of you.
If you're going to buy something on
amazon.com if you'd like to donate to this
podcast and the wounded warriors project,
please for the love of God,
go to [inaudible].
Com,
click on the podcast page and
then click on the Amazon link.
It'll take you right to
Amazon. Not Nothing's going
to cost you any more money.
It's just Amazon kicks me a little bit
of money for sending traffic their way.
And then I take 10% of that and I throw
it to the wounded warriors project.
And I'm also, if you'd like to download
my special you people are all the same,
you can do it digitally, you know, $5.
Or you can buy the hard copy
version that has some extras on it,
some tours of cities,
um,
in both of those are available on
the merchant page. Um, that is it.
Go fuck yourselves. Have a
wonderful week and I'll, uh,
I'll talk to you next
Monday. Okay. Buhbye.