Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
June 23rd, 2014. How's it going?
How I yeah,
what's up and all of that shit.
Um, I don't know. What do I start?
I don't even know where to begin.
Um,
I taped my special Friday night in Atlanta
at the Tabernacle and I want to thank
everybody who came out. I had
a wonderful time. As always,
there were a couple of glitches as always.
A couple people screamed out and as
always, what the fuck are you going to do?
I had a great time and I'm,
I'm really looking forward to putting
that special out and coming up with my new
hour of material.
And right now I'm trying not to freak
out because essentially when this thing
comes out in a couple of months, I
have no APP. I mean I have an act,
but it will be an act that potentially
people in the crowd have seen.
So I have to try some. Uh, I don't
know what the fuck I'm going to do.
Well, you know what I normally do when
I try to build the new hour. No bill,
we don't know. Nor do we give a
shit. Well fuck you. It's my podcast.
I'm going to talk about it. Um,
when I like to do basically I,
I basically I take off all
rules of like hack deed shit.
I don't give a fuck. I will,
I will talk about anything.
So I am now just looking what's go,
what's,
what's going on in the news.
A little ageist thing here.
It's like Jay Leno was bit
right. We, it takes like the uh,
the headlines except he actually has
a staff of writers combing through to
actually find funny ones. I on the other
hand, we'll be going down to the clubs,
just throwing anything I
can up against the wall.
Why the fuck is it so hot in here?
Jesus Christ and I can't open the fucking
windows because my neighbors are going
to freak out. I'm taping this Sunday
nights. Everybody's home right now.
God dammit
Jesus.
It's not one fucking thing.
It's another, you know what?
I was going to do it in the bedroom,
being over.
My wife wants to go take a bath and relax,
which you know,
is that wrong? No, it's not wrong.
You don't know is it, is it,
is it pathetic that I can't do a podcast
and then in the next room without
disturbing her because I scream and yell
and rant and rave and all that shit.
I had to put that in. I guess
that is pathetic. So I am,
I'm out here in the living room.
I can't open the fucking windows and
I tell you that heat's getting to me
already. Oh, it's getting to me.
Um, what would you rather do?
Would you rather freeze to death?
I'll get myself a dilemma here.
We'd rather freeze to death or a, I'm
not going to say burned to death. Every,
everybody's going to
choose freezing to death.
Although there'll be a couple of dishes.
Woo. Boozing, good at be painful.
So it would to get the pain over with.
Okay.
You know, hit me with some sort
of scientific facts or whatever.
He'll just say some science shit.
They don't even have to be faxed when
it comes to my scientific background of
which I have none. You know,
I took two goddamn classes.
No, I didn't even do that one was
chemistry and I was just like,
I'm not fucking looking at bugs,
you know?
I know it's not bugs,
but I had to follow through with that
sentence cause that's the first thing I
thought of when I was looking, looking in
the petri dish. What are you looking at?
Huh? Oh that's biology. So I
was still wrong. Chemistry.
You know what I love about this fucking
podcast is how dumb you guys think.
I am not how dumb you think I am,
but like how much smarter like this shit
that you guys, right? I swear to God, Yo,
Yo, Yo, you fuck it. Animals just
like make all right, but whatever.
Maybe that's my job. My job's to
make you feel better. I don't know.
I have no idea. Um, but
anyways, yeah, my science,
my science backgrounds,
horrific. I took a,
I just didn't give a
fuck when I was younger.
They shouldn't try to teach you
that shit when you're young.
You know you're too busy staring at
the fucking hot chicks and class.
You sitting there with the fucking Rod,
you know,
trying to memorize a periodical chart.
You can't do that. And if you can,
you know what?
I don't even know what the fuck you are.
You're not even a human being.
How are you not looking at the check
that develop the quickest, you know,
with the tits over there or Jordache
jeans would have a Sass on whatever the
fuck they had back when I
was a kid. That's what you're
looking at. Or even worse,
you had some Hadi for a fucking teacher
that you wanted to bang, you know,
that'd be tell you about that time. I got
trouble. I got in trouble long time ago.
I was taking this French class
and the teacher I had was beautiful and
she had a habit of wearing dresses where
she had a slit halfway up the
side of her fucking leg. You know,
I'm in the eighth grade. What am I
supposed to do? Well. Long Story Short,
one day she came and she had a slit up
bolt on both sides of the dress, right?
So she would be writing on the board
and in when she would step back.
And did I ever tell a story came out when
she would step back so you could see,
you know,
she'd step one leg back and then somehow
you could basically see halfway up her
leg on her inner thigh on the leg closest
to the blackboard and like the fuck
egg. It was over. All
right. No blood in my brain.
I'm just going. All I'm doing is
thinking how to say in French,
please step back again.
See me play.
I have no idea. I don't. I'm not even
fucking listening. And to this day,
I don't know, I never had just one of the
worst. I've had a teacher yelled at me,
she called on me,
all right,
and I'm trying to fucking answer her and
I'm trying to bullshit my way through
and she realizes that I haven't
been fucking paying attention.
And she flipped out calling me a liar.
It's screen. To this day, I swear to God,
something was going on in our home
life because it's like, yeah, I mean,
you should just called me a fucking
liar and moved on. She just fucking,
she berated me for like the
last 20 minutes of the class.
MMM.
I remember Jesus.
I'm rubbing my head now thinking about it.
I was just sitting at,
you know,
you know any times I've thought
about that fucking moment, my life,
and I just wished that I had the
emotional maturity to be like, you know,
you weren't paying attention to where
are you? And I'd be like, no, I wasn't.
I wasn't. Why don't you, you know,
not come to class. All right.
We're with two slits up both sides.
You're dress obese.
You know what your inner thigh is way
more interesting than watching you. Uh,
go g, suite two A and all
that. I fucking crap. Okay.
Send me down to the office. What do
you want? What do you want from me?
I'll give a f. Yeah, whatever. I'm not
passing this class anyways. Am I, am I,
I, you know what, fuck this.
I want to thank you for dressing the
way that you do because that shit you're
writing on the board is not interesting.
It's not nearly as interesting
as a what's going on downstairs?
There.
Okay.
And quit acting like you don't know what
you're doing and you're yelling at me,
you're getting on me. You're having
a bad time with your fucking husband.
That's what it is. What's a matter?
He doesn't want to touch anymore.
So now you've got to come in here all
gussied up. Get us all hot and bothered.
Right. And then fucking scream and yell
at me cause I'm not paying the, yeah,
you're not even going to be yelling at me.
You're yelling at your fucking husband.
Can you imagine?
I actually have probably when and got
half of that up. I don't fucking know.
You know, I have to mention I had paid
off. I guess I had really bad add.
Okay.
Yeah, I can't, you don't,
you only time I can focus is if
I give a fuck about something.
All my life is in jeopardy.
You know,
like I went on a motorcycle ride today
with a buddy of mine and we drove all the
way down sunset all the way down and
all the way back. And I got to tell you,
uh, I don't see the enjoyment
and riding a motorcycle.
I don't get it. It, it always looks
awesome. But once you're on there,
all you're thinking is I'm going to die.
That's a fucking range rover.
Jesus Christ. Get the fuck
away from me. You know,
the whole fucking,
you can't look at anything.
All you're doing is making
you driving down the street.
You're making sure that
nobody's pulling out somewhere.
No one's going to open a door up.
You get up to a fucking stop light.
You got to look in your rear view mirror
to make sure it's nobody rear ends you
and pushes you out into traffic.
Fucking horrific.
You're going around a turn.
You got to look your way through the God
damn term and they make sure the other
ass hole across the street, you
know, come on the other way.
Is it going to wipe you out? But I
gotta tell you my focus is incredible.
I guess that's the only way I can focus.
Okay.
Or if there's like something,
something is on, uh, on the line.
Other than that, I just started staring
at bugs on the ceiling or whatever.
I don't know what it is I do. I'm out
of my fucking mind. So anyways, uh,
what was I talking about? Oh yeah. So
I take my special this weekend and um,
you know,
that's the fun part though.
The horrific part now is I have
to go back and I got to uh,
go in during the editing
process and that's not
something I liked doing. I said,
I got this weird thing where if
I videotape myself with a club,
I could sit there and I can watch it
and I can laugh and I can enjoy it.
But the second I know you
guys are going to see it too.
I get all in my head and everything I'm
doing, I think, Jay, why did I do that?
What am I doing? Blah, blah.
Why did I say this? You know,
why is my weight on my right leg
right now instead of my left?
Like it's fucking torture. So I got
to push my way through it because, uh,
you know, I, I'm trying to make sure,
you know, with each special, you know,
you want to be a little bit better
than you were the last time.
You want it to look a little bit
better than the last one. So, uh,
I didn't realize with that also
become, comes to pressure of, of uh,
I dunno, trying to, trying to keep
going up. I don't fucking know.
I don't know, whatever.
It's behind me. Okay.
So now basically what I'm doing
is I'm looking over these, uh,
I'm trying to watch the news, which I
can't do because I don't know about,
I don't know where you
guys live in the world,
but we don't really have news over here.
We have a little bit of it,
but for the most part it's basically,
uh,
the Democrat news and the Republican News.
It's really fucking sad.
Um, I used, I liked the
way they used to lie to us.
I liked it back in the day, you
know, when they just had that person,
that fucking older white guy who had
that sound in his voice that just sounded
like he fucking, you know, was giving
you the straight deal, you know,
as opposed to now we got
all these personalities that
are like bigger than the
news, you know, all those silly concent,
Fox News and all those dip shits on CNN.
Who's that guy with the
fucking silver hair on CNN?
What does he, what does he call
his show? Ah, Jesus Christ. I,
I can't remember when he got the, he got
the one calls it the, the situation room,
which you remember opie and Opie and
Anthony is to always make fun of the
situation room.
Okay.
And you got what's his face going?
Yeah.
This is the no spin zone
that bill O'Reilly jerk off.
This is the no spin zone.
It's like, dude, the your and your
entire fucking show was you spin in it.
There's no such thing as a no spin zone.
Right now I'm spinning.
How I think news is that this country,
so you guys agree with what the fuck I
say there's no such thing like I'm going
to give you a strike dark.
Even if you wanted to.
You couldn't cause you getting it off
that fucking whatever the fuck it is.
That ticker thing that you get
it. Yeah. You weren't there.
You don't know what happened. It even
if your were there, I'm going to get it.
It's going to be what happened.
Cut with your childhood.
That's what's going to happen.
Cause it goes into your brain and then
it's fucking in there and it's stepped on
like drugs. It's not the pure shit
that just happened so I can't watch it.
What the fuck does that guy called
his shell? That's silver haired guy.
It's something arrogant.
Something arrogant like he's giving you,
do you know what the fuck
is supposed to be happening?
Anderson Cooper three 60 is that what
it is? I thought it was worse than that.
Three 60 is not bad. Right? He's spinning
around is he tells the news today.
Hey Jeff. Uh, sorry. Terrible
joke and, but you know what?
I'll put that in my act. I
need jokes. Anderson Cooper,
three six look at net worth. Who
the fuck would look up his? Oh No,
it's just guys make a year or two. I did
good. Well what did you do? The shoot?
Any read teleprompters?
I could do that.
Yeah.
I thought he had something. I thought
it was called something worse than that.
Anderson Cooper, three 60
sounds like one of them.
My ex game tricks. You get a backside
fakey followed by Anderson Cooper.
Three 60
okay.
Jesus Christ. Insert homophobic
joke. They're like, what would,
what would an Anderson Cooper,
three sixties that's skateboard look like?
Oh that's, you know what? That's too easy.
Full coverage from Anderson live
in Baghdad. I got to tell, oh,
I know what annoys me is when he
goes out and he tells us stories.
Got a fucking helmet on.
You know what I mean?
Jesus Christ. A helmet won't even help
you on a motorcycle. Okay, you're out.
You're in a fucking war zone.
Take it off and show your great hair.
You son of a bitch,
Anderson Cooper,
three 60 spinning around
live here in Baghdad.
Republicans do everything wrong. Um, oh.
Keeping them honest.
Is that, is that what,
is that what he does?
Why am I asking you guys,
why didn't I do my fucking research
on this thing? Keeping them honest,
gay conversion therapy.
Oh,
Jesus Christ. I can't imagine
the tension there, dude.
How fucking retarded are you that you
actually think that you can stop somebody
from being attracted to what they're
attracted to and then also thinking that
it's unnatural. You know,
I don't understand that.
Okay.
Unless you're talking about pedophiles,
but even them,
it's the way they're wired is something
happened to them and then they try to
undo that wiring. That's noble work. But
I mean, at the end of the day, I mean,
we all know what needs to happen.
You got to take them out behind the barn
and give him the old fucking old yellow
treatment. All right?
So you can't help it.
I know it's not your fault. You want
to help. You want to fuck a kid?
We can't have that. Okay. Maybe
someday in the future. I
don't know when, but not now.
When would you, I don't know when
you would, but it's, it's, it's,
it's not gonna happen. So you
get done. It's over. Quit.
You cry and be a God damn man.
Right. And then that's it. So
keeping them honest, gay conversion
therapy, look at this fucking Weirdo.
How do they try to convert
you from not being gay?
I bet they just have you sitting
there, right? If it's a gay,
a gay man and they'd be
like, all right, okay,
we're going to do something
different here. Okay. And want you,
I want you to do is, uh, think
about having sex with a man.
Okay. And Are you doing it?
Yeah, yeah, I'm doing it.
I just keep thinking about that.
You haven't sacks, you know,
he smells like old spice, you know,
whatever you're into, blah, blah, blah.
And it gets the fucking due to Ra aroused
and then he just has some naked woman
come in and do like a flying scissor
kick and put her snatch rightness face.
Right. Gets that stank or on him.
While he's still has an erection
thinking that maybe that would take,
you know, other than that, I don't,
I don't know how you'd do it,
but what's funny about that was then if
they wanted to convert me to be engaged,
they would do the exact same thing
except the flying scissor kick would be
somebody package coming flying at my face.
I mean,
I want to go on a limb and say that,
that that's not going to work.
Okay,
dude.
How isolated are you as a fucking human
being that you're actually part of a
group that's trying to do
some shit like this? I mean,
I guess people looked at Orville
and Wilbur Wright like, yeah,
you out of your fucking mind.
You're trying to fly.
That's crazy.
So maybe they think that they're doing
that except with like sexuality. You know,
funny about the early planes is when
the people didn't understand that the
flapping of the wings was to gain speed.
So they tried to have like the
like, well I get, I don't know.
Isn't that what they thought?
Okay.
Isn't that something else that I haven't
read about that they thought that the,
it's got something to do with
the flapping of the wings
before they realize like, no, we just
need the somehow gained some speed.
We got to build something that somebody
can run with. Oh, Jesus. I look,
fuck you guys. I already told you I
didn't take any science classes. Okay, go.
You know. Anyways, Jesus is fucking
podcast is all over the place.
Uh, let, let's, let's do a little
advertising here. All right.
Um,
convert your kid back to being
straight kit. No kidding. All right.
A dollar shave club.
Everybody,
the big companies think we're stupid.
Every year they roll out some ridiculous
shave technology gimmick and expect us
to shell out big bucks for it. Yeah,
they got that new, uh, ball thing.
Oh, they got it. They're vibrating.
Handle roller pivot, ball,
back scratcher, ag timer, laser
pointer, corkscrew, all of that crop.
Um, do we really need that people
personally, I know that I don't,
I know that I don't, I know that I
was fine with two fucking blades.
One sucked unless she had a
straight blade. Uh, what do
you call a straight razor?
Or if you had one of those,
what do they call a safety raises?
Those things are fine, but if you just
talking about Gillette style razor,
which is what these people are selling,
okay, I need to fucking plates personally.
That's what I'm thinking anyways.
He said we were shaving just fine before
any of that junk and I definitely don't
need to spend my hard earned cash on it.
If you're sick of being treated like a
full join the hundreds of thousands of
smarter people who joined Dollar Shave
club.com dollar shave club delivers the
best blades in grooming supplies
for just a few bucks a month.
Even if this shit was the same,
the fact that they're going to bring
it to your door, this is a no brainer.
Their blades are better than the big shape
companies for a fraction of the price.
All right,
my listeners can get started
now@dollarshaveclub.com
slash burr and hey,
if you're already a member,
you got to check out their new
doctor cabbies post shave lotion.
It's the perfect way to make peace with
your face after the disruptive act of
shaving. And you know something. Nobody
ever teaches us how to shave. Okay?
Nobody ever tells you about
putting something on your
face before you lather it
up. He gets dragged that razor
across and nobody has it.
Talks about any sort of a after
shave. So good for doctor cabby. Uh,
anyway, stop getting ripped
off by the big shave companies.
Joined Dollar Shave club.com/burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/ [inaudible]
all right, another one here. Legal Zoom.
Everybody. America was built
by innovators and dreamers.
People like Thomas Edison and Henry Ford
laid the foundation for our country.
After they removed,
we'll after the native Americans were
removed who were kind of living off the
land. And uh, I got to, it
looked pretty good. Anyways,
these days it's the
inventors and entrepreneurs,
entrepreneurs all around us like you
that keep our country running by fueling
the job, market and eat and
the economy. This month,
legal zoom celebrates innovation
by helping you launch your dream,
apply for a patent to secure your
invention. Basically everybody,
they're going to help you.
They can't help you with your invention,
but what they can do is give you a foot
to stand on when some fat cat comes in
and tries to steal it from you.
Okay.
Register your trademark to protect
your products and services.
Incorporate or form an LLC and
launch your business the right way.
Visit Legal zoom.com and use the discount
code bur bur are they'll provide the,
the personal attention you need and
help take care of all the details.
They've helped over a million
businesses get started right.
And they received an a plus
from the better business bureau.
Celebrate innovation and zoom,
um, today and get a
special price on trademark,
copyright or provincial
patent of applications by
using the discount code bur
bur at the checkout.
Legal Zoom provides legal help through
independent attorneys and self help,
but they are not a lot from
legalzoom.com discount code burpee.
You are all right.
Back to the podcast.
MMM.
All right, so what am I going
to talk about now? Oh, so
today, so I came back, uh
Oh, by the way, you know,
it was awesome. After I,
after I did the taping at the
beautiful tavern, Ecker theater tavern,
Tabernacle theater in Atlanta.
Um,
Jason Law head, he, uh,
was looking for a place where you could
go out and smoke some cigars and it
turned out right in part
of the same building,
part of the Tabernacle is a new
cigar place called a Winston cigars.
And a,
I went in there and I had a great cigar.
They kept the place open late for us. I
want to thank everybody over there for a,
for letting us hang around and all of
that shape. We had a great time and uh,
definitely gonna stop there
again next time I come back.
And if you live in Atlanta
and you like cigars,
you want a cool place to hang out that
put on any kind of music you want the put
the game on for you.
It was absolutely perfect.
Got To hang out with a couple in there
from Worcester. So, uh, it was a,
it was a great time. It was
definitely a great time. So anyways.
MMM.
So now that I'm back here
in town, uh, you know,
I stayed up till like five in the morning.
Did Not drink though. Did Not drink.
I am, I am. I am saving myself. For those
of you listen to my podcast every week,
you know that, uh, ever since I came back
from France, I have not drank. I am up to,
I don't know how many fucking days.
By the time he listened to this,
I'll be on my 67th day and a,
I'm going to Vegas and I'm going, I
decided I'm going off the wagon and Vegas.
I got two shows a Friday and Saturday
night and at the Mirage casino.
And it just so happens that the tour,
that the Monday morning podcast has
been sponsoring the tour that has been
crushing it in the clubs all
around the country. The Tor,
that includes Paul Dude,
I called it Versie Joe Bart,
Nick Rosebowl tailgate legend and a rolls
volt tailgate legend and Grill Cook.
Extraordinary Jason Law head
will be at Harris at the Improv.
Uh, this Sunday I'm at the
Mirage Friday, Saturday,
and then my buddies are there Sunday.
So what am I going to do? Not Hang out?
Of course I'm going to hang out.
I'm going to go and I'm going to check
out this show over at Harris and you know
what's, so should you,
it'll be a great time.
Fun For all fun for all.
And who knows?
Maybe even a couple of special
guests when we're in Vegas.
You never know who drops in. Um, so,
so anyways, I haven't been
drinking. So today, uh, I was
like, all right, you know,
I've been on the road and Shit and
getting ready for this, a taping.
I'm going to take my wife up. She
wanted to go to the beach, right?
So I got my little motorcycle
riding in the morning.
I didn't die and uh,
came back and I took her out to
the beach and I went over to a,
Oh, I did my workout over there,
right over there on muscle beach.
I stood there and a little banana hammock
showing off my fucking pasty body.
Now they got a,
they got pull up bars and they got
rings and they got the rope over there.
I hate the fucking new rope now.
They used to have like a real rope.
Now this one's made like, I don't know
if they put some protective thing on.
It felt like I was almost
made out of plastic. Um,
okay.
I guess for the weather
or something like that.
So it wouldn't disintegrate like the
last one did. But I did all right.
I did all right on it,
man.
I was able to go almost all the way
up to the top without using my legs.
Then I got to tell you for 46
and a bed and a fucking bed.
So after that we drive up to Malibu and
I'm thinking malleable. This is fucking,
you know, with all these rich people are
and everything, this is going to be nice.
We go to the beach and I tell you,
I can't even begin to
describe the fucking animals,
the absolute fucking animals
that were at the beach.
I made. It is fucking
horrific. Fuck Dude. You know,
it's fucking hilarious is seeing people
from my generation and the generation
before, like the tattoos
that were in, you know
like dude, I saw this
guy in the beach, right?
And now that everybody's older and out
of shape and has kids and shit, this guy,
you know those fucking
stars that everybody had.
Everybody got him in the early 2000 they
were like red and then they had like
some sort of darker shading in him. I
mean I have a friend that has two of them,
I think one on each elbow.
So there's some fucking guy,
roughly the same age as my buddy.
He's got one just to the
inside of both shoulders,
which was sort of a weird place for him.
But if he had more tattoos that look fine,
but he had no other tattoos in that
area. It was just weird. It's like,
what are you, are you like a
general in your own life? White?
Why do you have those fucking stars
there? Right? So we sit in there,
you could tell he used to be in shape.
You know,
they used to have the packs,
but now that kind of looking down,
staring at the floor,
big stupid pot belly and he's sitting
there as his kids are running around and
these eaten these digging into this bag
of chips and then not ships, you know,
all those things that look like the
onion rings but then not onion rings.
It's like if you had a potato chip,
but it was a fucking shaped like an
onion ring that he's just sitting there
eating those things.
So this other dude come by.
Okay.
I know,
Dude.
I am obsessed with trying to stay
in shape and not become what I see.
Okay. At the fucking beach. This
guy comes by, or Latino Guy, right?
Fucking big giant belly and
tattooed on his stomach.
You know, like Tupac had thug life.
This guy for some reason had Pasadena.
Oh, it was awful. It was fucking awful.
There were two hobbies on the
beach other than my wife. Uh,
there was like the fucking model couple
guy in woman in front of us who look
like they were,
they were shooting up fucking guests
ad and then all the way down the way,
there was some chicken,
a fucking pink bikini who was
working out on the beach total like
exhibitionists. It was great.
It was great. I kept saying,
I need to go and look what she's
doing now. Look what she's doing now.
She's doing,
she's doing a leg lifts with the weights
on her ankles and she kept looking over
going like, Oh God, no.
I love when women get mad at other
women who were fucking prancing around
showing that clam. It's
fucking hilarious. Yeah.
I'm trying to think of
the guy version of that.
Okay.
What,
what would a guy be doing?
I guess I'm trying to think of something
that a guy would be doing in that
version that would, that same scenario
that wouldn't make me laugh my ass off.
Do we think guys would do that?
Would ever bug me is, is uh,
I guess walk up and just start hitting
on your girlfriend or your wife or
whatever. Right in front of you. I
guess that would be the only thing.
Other than that, if they walking
around peacock and I don't give a fuck,
I think it's hilarious. You know, and
plus you're young. Go ahead. Exactly.
Go fuck around the surf.
What? You still can.
So anyways, we're sitting there, Alan,
the families do what kind of people
go to the beach as you can tell.
I'm not a beach person, so I
never went. Just fucking animals.
These fucking people brought a table down.
They've got a large cheese pizza.
They just sitting on the beach
getting fatter. You know,
it's like you're going to take
your shirt off in a second.
You're going to slam you gonna fucking
down four slices of Pepperoni mushroom,
Jesus Christ. You know? And I
would love to, I don't know.
I would love to act like, you
know, people try to act like it.
It's only in America where
everybody's all fat. Uh, we are,
we are pretty God damn fat because
that food is such fucking poison.
MMM.
But it's, it's still a shit
show everywhere else, I
dunno. And in its own way. Oh,
speaking of that, do
you know what I was, uh,
I was in Utah last week and I took this
picture and I put it up on Twitter and I
was in the gym,
right?
The hotel gym and they had a couple
of ellipticals and then they had a big
window when you looked outside.
And right across the street was a,
this fast food place. So I took a
picture of it and just Hashtag like,
come on man,
you know,
like I'm trying to lose weight here
in the attempt me with this shit.
So the fast food place sod and then
tried to write a joke about it,
like trying to draw me until the horse
shit the fucking poison that they're
serving.
They always say,
why don't you come over here afterwards
and do some fucking Hamburger Charles?
Get it. That's what they
hashtag you get it. You know,
acting like they're the cool,
okay
fucking
dailer of poison. Right. And I just wrote
him back. I was like, no, I don't get it.
Why would I work out and then go over
New York restaurant and eat that poison
kind of defeats the purpose of working
out. No, and they never wrote back
stop back then. Like,
you're cool. You know,
it'd be cool if they just
came out and said, listen,
what we're serving you is
absolutely fucking horrific.
There's barely an ounce of nutrition
in this shit, but God dammit,
it is fucking delicious.
So I don't have it all the time.
Just every once in awhile,
if they just came out and said that,
you know, I don't fucking know. I'm,
you know what I'm talking about here.
I'm just trying, you know, I'm just, I'm
just trying to get to another podcast.
That's all I'm trying to do. Um, you know,
I really thought I was going to have a
big feeling of relief when I finished my,
my special I could get on with my
life here and, uh, I don't know,
kind of feel love.
I feel a little melancholy.
I'm really going to miss those jokes.
I really am, man. I fucking, I, I,
that was my favorite hour and a half
a shit I've ever written and uh,
I dunno,
I might have to pull out those couple
of those every once in awhile somebody
requests one or something,
I might have to do that.
Okay.
I got this helicopter
joke, man. Wait, wait DC.
It's one of my favorite
jokes I've ever gotten to.
There's just so much fun to
fucking do it. You know, it's a,
that Steve jobs bit than I did.
I did that one on night and
too many stars that was up.
That was a sad one to let go.
I just loved when I was walking around
acting like he was eating a pair that was
so much fucking fun.
Just acting like an arrogant ass trashing
somebody that's accomplished way more
than I'll ever accomplish. You know,
those are the funniest moments.
And uh,
and stand up
is when you get to do shit like that
and just act like a fucking idiot.
And people actually laugh and that's a
God damn it making fun of Oprah's fun.
How was it?
How was it not fun to make fun of somebody
as successful as her who has like 50
fucking houses and her own TV network?
It's just fun. Do you guys know?
I had at one time I had a meeting.
Right?
Okay.
And uh,
I was meeting with the casting
director of, uh, of uh,
what does it dreamworks. Right. And
I know this sounds like a big deal,
but this shit happens all the time.
All the time when you're out
here from the day you get out,
you get a meeting with like
fucking back in the day,
like castle rock was doing all
the sick contract. Oh my God,
I got to meet it with castle rock.
They have like nine sitcoms on and they
just meet with you and you think you're
going to get on a Sitcom and you're lucky
if you get an audition within the year
that just always meet new people.
Right? So this is all is, it's a,
it's just a meeting,
right?
So I go over there and I'm sitting
in the waiting room waiting to meet,
uh, with this big time
casting director. Right?
And all of a sudden I hear a,
okay,
this woman sing,
and goes,
I hear this woman go and Spielberg
like that and I'm thinking like,
Holy Shit.
Yeah,
am I going to see Steven Spielberg? He's,
he's at the top of his fucking chain,
but you never see the top guy. So I'm
like, rubber neck and, and all this shit.
And I look,
and he's not there,
but the person who sang that,
it was Oprah Winfrey
and she walked by and I'm sitting
on the couch going, oh my God,
I have made fun of you on
like 50 fucking podcast. It's,
she walked by with her entourage
and a for half a second. We both,
I was looking at her,
she actually looked over at me and
she just kept going for half a second.
I was so arrogant. I thought she
was going to stop and be like,
you're that punk ass who did that
fucking bit about me. You know,
it was going to start yelling at me.
And she didn't,
she just looked at me like I was a lamp
and she just kept walking and I was like,
oh yeah, that's right. She
has other things to do.
Evidently she was just saying
goodbye to Steven Spielberg.
How funny is it that she
doesn't just do that on a show?
That she actually really
sings stuff that she's saying
in real life does,
did you ever see that hilarious impression
that Maya Rudolph used to do of Oprah
and she used to do that thing where
she would sing to like the crowd. Okay.
And everybody gets a new co would do like
that thing that she actually does that
in real life.
You know?
Isn't that nice as a little
Hollywood story for your people?
I dropped two names in there
without you even noticing. Um,
all right. I don't know what to
talk about because hockey's over.
Basketball's over. I'm trying to get
into baseball. Oh, I will tell you this.
I'm actually thinking about getting
the baseball package and um,
as a red sox fan,
you know what I really missed doing?
Watching Yankee Games,
believe it or not.
I absolutely love watching the Yankee
telecast more so than I like watching the
red sox won.
I don't even know why.
I think because I lived in New York
for so long and I would just want,
and this is both,
this is when I lived during the height
of the curse of curse of the bay when I
was there.
So I fucking hated the Yankees.
So I went to Yankee
stadium a zillion times.
I watched all of their fucking games just
sitting there rooting against him and
must have saw Clemons pitch like
50 fucking times. I saw them.
I saw the 98 Yankees. Um,
which is legendary now. I mean,
I don't think there's been
a team like that sense. Um,
but I got to be on it. Like, I don't
know, there's something about it.
Like I did it for so fucking long.
I think I've actually watched wire to
wire more Yankee regular season games.
Then I have red sox games because I mean,
I was in New York for like,
I don't like 12 years.
And you know,
when I was a kid growing up, I mean,
the first 10 years of your life,
I mean you just run around
throwing sticks and mud and shit.
You're not really paying attention.
And then from 10 to 20,
I dunno, I would watch him, but you know,
you'd getting drunk for the first time,
you're trying to get up some girl's shirt,
you're busy.
So then I just basically had from
like 20 to 27 and then I moved.
Um, but I stayed in New York for like,
you know, fucking 12 years. So I, uh,
but I got to tell you,
I love watching them now because they're,
they're announcing team is,
it's the shit.
All Right, it's Michael
K, he's steering the ship.
And then I love when
there's nothing better.
When you have former players that are
actually really good broadcast is,
and they have Paul O'Neill,
the former Yankee. Great.
And they have al Leiter.
So you have one, uh,
one of the great hitters of the
last 20 years and champions.
And then you have al Leiter a pitcher.
So you got a picture in here and just
the combination of the two of them. Man,
it's Al Leiter is hilarious.
Fucking hilarious.
And I,
and this is a thing I always
loved Paul O'Neil and uh,
every my money and my family actually
fucking love the guy because he was so
hilarious to us cause we all have tempers.
And the funniest thing about Paulownia
was the amount of times I saw that guy
come up to bat,
hit a fly ball to right field
and the second he hits it,
you'd see him put his head down and go
fuck and throw the bat down and it would
be a home run intellect
the third row. But he, he,
he was such a perfectionist. Like the
fact that he didn't get all of it.
He was mad.
I guess what the,
he didn't drive it 30 rows in
and then in every fucking time,
whether he got a hit or whether he didn't
get a hit when he ran out to the field
and he would go out to right field,
he would immediately,
I guess he'd throw the ball around,
but once that was over,
he would be out the in between like
batters, it's in between pitches and shit.
He'd be out there practicing his swing.
I don't know. There's just certain guys,
even though they play on the team that
you hate, you can't fucking hate the guy.
The guy was great. So I was watching on
one of their telecasts recently and um,
they actually,
they cut to some footage of Al Leiter
facing Paul O'Neil and was hilarious and
of Paul and Neil gets a hit.
And then the last two that they showed,
Al Leiter struck him out and
he's like, oh, I struck yard.
I didn't even know that.
And then he looked over at
Michael and he goes, yeah.
And Paul didn't get that mad.
Was fucking great.
So I'm actually thinking about
getting the, uh, the baseball package,
cause I actually have a package where
I get the nes and network and I get the
yes network thinking that I'd get
the fucking games and I don't,
they blocked the whole thing out because
they say force you to buy, you know,
so I get the Milwaukee brewer home games.
It's such con
there's such fucking cunt.
Why can't they just,
you know, you know, I guess
it's my fault for moving away.
Do you understand what I'm
really bitching about here?
That basically for a hundred
something bucks that no, Boo Hoo.
Now I have to watch all the baseball
games you want to strike all of that.
God bless whoever came up
with that package. Um, uh,
what am I going here? All
right. World Cup soccer.
If you guys been watching,
I hate to say this man,
I haven't watched one second of it.
And I actually,
for as much as I make fun of a
[inaudible] football, the real football,
uh, I, you know, I, I totally respect
it. I think it's a beautiful game.
I just wish I had and I'm driving by the
bars and I'm seeing all the flags out
in the hearing. People
screaming and yelling. I wish
I had the time to watch it.
I know that there's some games tomorrow.
I think Brazil, please somebody.
I'm actually going to try at
least maybe to tape a game.
I got to get into this shit's once.
It'd be four years.
The whole fucking world's going
nuts. Uh, but hey, you know what?
I said that the United States
is going to win it. I said,
the fix is fucking in and we are one o
one one. I haven't watched a second of it.
I know that we tied Portugal today,
which to me seems pathetic.
All right.
Portugal's barely in Europe.
It's like Spain felt bad for him to like,
all right,
here's a little landing strip. You
guys can fucking live over here. Okay.
You can have your little football team.
He once every four years we'll let you
run around and sing you songs and where
you scarves. But other than that,
your pipe the fuck down. All right.
Now if all you Portuguese people were
going to get mad at me, um, right,
all the mean shit you want.
And then also tell me where I can do a
show in your country and I'll fucking do
it.
All right?
You guys can go there and you can fucking
heckle me by singing your soccer songs.
He football songs right in the
middle of it and I'll give you shit.
And in the end, you know,
we'll trade jerseys,
you'll give me a soccer jersey and
I'll take off one of my button downs.
What the fuck was with that
guy who scored the goal today?
And he started sucking his thumb.
Can anybody explain that to me?
I don't understand soccer.
Every time you start to love it,
somebody does some shit like that. And
then you just, you just got to walk away.
So anyways,
we are one all in one.
Okay.
So we're gonna play Germany
next and basically if we tie,
if us in Germany tie, uh, we
move, we automatically advance.
We're one on one,
one Germany's one on one.
And in Portugal and in Ghana
I think is in our, in our, uh,
whatever division, whatever the fuck
you call it, quadrant. They both are,
have yet to win a fucking game. So, um,
I dunno, I, I, I'm,
I want us to win the World Cup so bad
just because I love what I was talking
about last week. Just how much world would
fucking heinous, but I gotta tell you,
man, I think we're going to win and
one, eventually we are going to win one.
And I don't mean that
like, well shit, you know,
they're going to play it
every four years forever.
Eventually everybody's going
to win one. I mean, I think,
yeah,
we're on our way to winning one.
Okay.
As in I think we'll win one by 2030.
All right.
Which is saying something, considering
how far behind we were. And in 2030,
if you want to know,
I will be 62 years old.
That's how fast it goes.
You know,
Jesus and I'll be working on
another fucking special. Um,
hopefully, maybe it'd be my year off.
All right, let's plow ahead here.
Um, anything else here?
Did the all in tour.
Oh, youtube fucking video of the
week. I was watching this, uh,
the dead weather concert.
I don't know how to private p.
R. I. V. E. I started watching
this thing. I was trying to,
I don't know what the fuck I was doing.
I was doing something and all of a
sudden I just started watching Jack White
videos and I got to this,
I can't believe I didn't see the dead
weather live because I got to tell you the
lead singer that, or at least what
I've been watching, that woman,
I hope I say her name
right, Alison Mosshart, uh,
is a fucking rock star. I'm going
to go see that band. What is it?
The kill that she's in. Very rarely do
you see a legitimate fucking rockstar.
And she's definitely one without a doubt.
So that's one of the youtube videos
of the week. Just fucking watch it.
And what's cool also is Jack
White's set up, uh, his drum set up,
how he has everything all level,
kind of like the way buddy rich did.
But he's is a wonder why actually buddy,
which is symbols will level.
That's right. This is some drum kick
shit. You can fast forward through this,
but he has like,
it looks like he has a rack,
Tom and then two different snare
drums all at the exact same lab,
all at the same level that you
would have your snare drum. Um,
and then on the A to his right side,
he's got three floor toms.
The Way Tony Williams used to have him.
Right. You guys all know it, right?
When he had that yellow yellow kit,
do you know I saw him at the regata bar.
I saw Tony Williams and
I knew he was awesome,
but I of course didn't understand
everything he was doing.
And in between the break I walked
right up and stood next to his drums.
That classic Yellow Kid.
I saw him,
I saw Louie Bellson shook his
hand and I saw a Roy Haynes.
I saw all these great jazz drums.
And of course,
Tony Williams like died a couple of years
later, unfortunately from a heart. But,
uh,
anyways, what the fuck? Why am I talking
to you guys about old jazz drummers?
Jesus Christ. Uh, let's, let's
get to some questions here.
Um, oh, by the way too, if you
want to, if you want to, um,
send in some questions or whatever, uh,
which you want to follow us on Twitter,
it's at the [inaudible]
podcast on Twitter. All right.
And all the videos that I recommend
and all the shit that I talk about,
I'll definitely, uh,
have the links up there.
It's way more organized than it ever
used to be. All right. There you go. Ah,
Bill, bunch of emails from people who
were at the taping, couple emails,
calling out Douche bags at the
first show for being loud. You know,
I didn't mind that, you
know, the first show,
they told everybody to stay in their
seats and we realized that that was wrong
because I was doing well over an hour
and people were drinking. They had it,
they had to go to the bathroom.
It wasn't fair. So, um,
so on the second show I was, I
just said to the people, you know,
who was shooting and things like, look,
people walk around all the fucking time.
I still have a good set.
I don't give a shit.
Just let them do what they
want to do. I don't, you know,
let's just make it more like a show.
And that's what we did in the second
show when even better. So anyways.
All right bill, in response to
male whore verse a female whore.
Um, all right, dear Billy Buffalo, uh,
I am a proud woman who loves other women.
Nice,
Nice.
[inaudible] I found your handling of
the whore gay son verse a whore for a
daughter.
Question to be spot on.
I also agree with the gay
man who wrote in last week,
if I was sitting around a table and this
question was posed, you know, it's funny,
I don't even remember what I said.
I'd feel it was addressing current
issues that are generally ignored, uh,
discussions that are usually
avoided in fear of discrimination,
but in actuality depriving important
dialogue. Yeah, absolutely.
You should be allowed to be
ignorant. Is Long, you know,
as long as you're not like acting on it
and like trying to hurt somebody should
be allowed to say the
things that you feel.
And if they end up being, um, you know,
I ignorant not mean dumb,
just ignorant.
Like you just want to expose
to some other information.
You got to have people get them out and
then that's how you move on to the next
level. Like, no, actually
it's like this. Oh, I didn't
know that. And then, you know,
hopefully you change for
the better. Um, so anyways,
discussions that are usually avoid
it, blah, blah, blah, blah. She says,
I never knew my father, but I would hope
he would answer that question honestly.
Frankly,
I don't like labeling either as whores,
but it's the easiest way to sum it up.
I agree with you wholeheartedly. Uh,
caused somebody a whore that's really bad,
a hose kind of funny whore to
actually say it has really bad.
Um,
she continues to say,
I'd be remiss not to mention that Nia
spoke emotionally as a straight woman,
but did not consider why the question
is important to gate children.
Oftentimes gay teens experiment
prematurely after having
repressed feelings for
their early,
for their ear,
early adolescents or from their
early adolescence. I don't know.
The truth is though,
emotional,
emotional changes and repercussions of
early sexual encounters affect the female
much more severely. This is not to say
that boys can't suffer the effects,
but as you and Nia have both
pointed out in the past,
women are more sensitive to certain
things that men are not. Um,
I was with you all the
way until, till, um,
why you say that the,
uh,
the sexual encounters affect the
female much more severely? Um,
I don't think that that's something
you could ever prove or disprove.
Like that's something that I always
go round and round with my wife with
somebody says, you know, it's
easier for guys to lose weight.
You know, I, it's like, well,
you would have to be a guy,
okay and then be a woman and then live
the exact same life and eat the exact
same food.
To really sit there and try and guess if,
if whatever is easier and whatever.
I mean,
I think it all kind of balances itself
out is far as easy and difficult.
It's like,
you know,
I dunno that just that whole fucking
reoccurring thing that this is a bad
experience but it's worse for women.
Um,
or this is this experience.
It's easier for guys.
It's just always like there has to be
something out there where it's even,
or there has to be something out there
where it's worse or aren't they both?
It's just kind of a big shit sandwich
out there. And the big game is, you know,
trying to block that out isn't it?
I would actually say that,
uh,
the guy's pain is that we are not
allowed to talk about our pain
at all.
Where you guys can have painful shit
happened to you and it's okay for you
literally to break down
sobbing and weeping,
which is so healthy for you to get it out,
to get it out of you. I mean, it
doesn't get it all out of you,
but it gets that the buildup,
the, the like, you know,
you have a cook oatmeal and you'll walk
away and you'll leave it too high and it
fucking boils over. Yeah. That
shit. You can get that off.
I think through crime,
like the funny thing about crying is it
is a natural emotion for both men and
women. But we're told that
we can't do it. And I, it,
it's a fucking horrible thing.
MMM,
okay.
It's a horrible thing.
So I'm now,
I'm not saying that that makes you guys
have it easier, but I'm just saying that
that is, that is something
that I don't think that, uh,
is taken into consideration. And I just
feel like, you know, every time I see,
you know, I, that's a
reoccurring thing, but I,
I agree with everything
else that you're saying.
I guess she probably thinking I'm a
dick now, but I'm just just saying that,
you know, like, um,
okay.
I Dunno if you're a guy and you know,
you got to cry,
but you don't want to embarrass yourself.
Just go take a shower.
Nobody's going to notice.
No one's going to hear you.
And if somebody would have ripped
back the fucking thing, the, the, the,
the shower curtain,
like in psycho,
you could just act like you
got shampoo in your ride.
Just don't start talking or I'll
still realize it, but you know,
just have your head under the water and
just sort of look at it. I'm like, wow,
I'm showering. Get away from
me. You weirdo. Um, yeah,
you can cry out. A lot of childhood
pain is a guy in, in the, uh,
in the shower without anybody
knowing. All right, dear Billy,
ginger nuts.
Jesus Christ.
Can you fucking, you know, can you come
at me from a different God damn angle?
Everything's red hair red.
Pubes fucking pasty. I got it.
You think I haven't heard this my whole
fucking life? Jesus fucking Christ.
I gotta hand it to you guys.
You know,
you have found 700 different
fucking ways to attack me.
I'm referring to the question raised,
uh,
whether it would be better to
have a daughter who Jesus Christ.
This fucking question really has been
living on whether it'd be better to have a
daughter who were a whore or a
gay son who was also a whore.
The best analogy I've ever
heard with respect to the whole,
why is it dean bad for a female to
be a whore but not a male is this?
If you own a key that opens,
opens lots of locks,
then that that is pretty cool,
but if you have a lock that
is opened by a lot of keys,
then that is a shitty luck. You know?
It would've helped if I read it better.
She owned a key that opens lots of locks.
That's pretty cool,
but if you have a lock that
is opened by a lot of keys,
then that is a shitty luck. I
actually, I don't like that one.
I like my analogy because
I'm a self centered cunt.
I just think it doesn't take
any fucking skill. The love,
the skill level for a woman
to get late is just like,
what do you have to do? Lay on your
back, spread your legs. Who wants it?
I'm not saying you're going to
get somebody desirable, you know,
but the fucking work we,
this is something to try this one time
I told you I did this with my wife where
you just turn the tables one
night, have her hit on, you,
have her come up with an opening line.
You Watch,
you watch how much they bomb. He watched
the flop sweat. They got nothing.
You think you have nothing. They when
it comes to that shit, most of them are,
are like their game is where your
game was. You were like 12, 13.
The first few times you were trying
to talk to some girl in your grade,
you got nothing cause you
never tried it before.
That's where they're at
at like 35. Um, anyways,
free Billy. They they a golden
little play on the movie title. Uh,
Billy four times. Congrats on the
completion of your fourth special.
I can't wait to watch it with my friends.
We will all crowd around the tree TV like
one of the Roosevelt's fireside chats.
Okay.
This person,
a free willy reference and then hit me
with a little bit of a depression era
ship. Uh, my question to you is
how will you celebrate beers,
burgers. Uh, what did the coming
weeks have in store for you?
Please don't say working on your next
hour because no one likes a goody two
shoes. Yeah. You know why? Cause you're
still fucking up in your life aren't,
you know, it's funny, as I opened
this podcast talking about this, um,
okay,
I am going to drink,
but I also,
I don't want to put on the weight that
I took off for this special, you know,
I'm looking good for
me. All right? And, uh,
I actually have started this new
workout. I found this dude on, on,
uh, Youtube. I fuck, I think I told you
guys about them last week. This guy,
uh,
frank [inaudible],
frank Madrano fitness,
this guy,
he's a Vegan and all he does is,
uh,
his own body weight and he's
absolutely fucking shredded, shredded.
So, um, I'm going to try to, you know,
I've been eating a lot more vegetarian,
but I still, you know, I'm one of those
guys, I mean there's no fucking way,
you know, I'm still going to
have a couple of steaks a month,
but I'd like to try to
eliminate a lot of that other,
I dunno a lot of that.
You know what I,
this is what I liked about
eating vegetarian for two to,
I would try to go two days
a week and it was hard, man.
At first you don't know what to eat,
you don't know where to go.
You don't know how to make
anything of sucks. But uh,
the cool thing about eating vegetarian,
I would go back to back days,
Jesse eaten all Veggie.
What was great was it affected my
eating the other five days because it,
it really, it like reset your
cravings and I'm telling you man,
like when I get into that fucking sugar
salt thing, like back in the day, man,
I would go on like,
I don't know,
I would go on like a two and a half
month bender of just eating poorly.
I would still, you know, take
my dog on hikes and stuff. So,
and I never really let it get too bad,
but in that two and a half months
I put on like fucking 10 pounds,
15 pounds or something like that.
And then I'm just, ah, fuck,
I got to tell you to get this shit off.
And um,
that great thing about,
okay,
or even just one meal a day,
if he's just do it all Veggie,
it fucking balances you out and
you stop riding that rollercoaster.
Sugar, salt, sugar, salt, sugar, salt. And
I fucking hate going to the gym. I fuck,
I don't like working out. I
mean, I like it, but I don't,
I don't like having to do it
because I'm a tub of shit. And,
um,
I can't recommend it enough if
you just start eating that way,
dude. If you go veggie two days
a week and you go for a walk,
ride a bike or do something like that,
the fats got nowhere to hide.
He's got nowhere to go. It has
to fucking leave, you know,
and then if you just sort of
decent the rest of the week,
you know, and I tell you, you
know, I saw I'll, I'll fucking,
I'll crush a pizza,
I'll order a fucking,
I'll order a pizza and a fucking
slam that I'll make cupcakes,
like the twinkle toes that I am.
And I lead a bunch of
those in that type of ship.
But then I do the two veggie
days in a row and all of that,
it gets settles down again. Like
the, it's almost like a fire.
It doesn't get out of control. So
that has been working for me. And, uh,
I've been doing the pullups climbing
the rope and the dips in the pushups.
And, uh, I just liked that type.
I at this point in my life,
I just liked doing that better
than a throwing the weights around,
but I'll always still like doing that
because I came of age in the eighties and
that was always fun, you know,
benching. So what am I going to do? Um,
I going to, I'm going to fucking party
with the all guys, smoke some cigars,
but uh, I am, I'm not a goody two shoes.
What I am is I'm somebody who fucking,
I already lived the life, dude.
I did all of that. Okay. And uh,
I'm too fucking old to keep,
to keep putting on 1520 pounds
and try and take them off.
I don't want to look like the fucking
horse shell that I saw at the beach today.
I don't want to be those people.
All right?
I don't want to be sitting here with
my fucking shirt off with my tits,
staring at my fucking toes, you
know, eating a bag of crisps.
I don't, I don't want to
fucking be that guy. All right?
You can do that in your 20s have at it,
and you can wake up the next day
and still fucking be in shape.
But I can't do it at my age.
So, uh, there you go. Um,
I dunno.
I rode a motorcycle today.
That's about the dumbest
fucking thing you could ever do.
So is that enough for you? Um, okay. Bill.
We'll the military hurt my comedy career.
Um,
hi bill. I'm an 18 year old standup
comedian in Atlanta, Georgia.
I started when I was 17 and so far I
enjoy it while it can be shitty at times.
Um,
however,
I've always wanted to join the military
when I was young and still do to this
day,
I've been considering joining the army
and trying to become a green baret for a
long time now after I finished college a,
this isn't a decision I made because I
played a couple games of call of duty and
thought it was cool.
I've just always wanted to do
something exciting and adventurous.
I realized that it's very hard
to become one. Uh, oh yeah.
I watched that thing on
Netflix and that was a,
that wasn't to be a green baret that was
to be like an army ranger or something
like that. I forget what it was
like, called like 11 days a health.
It was fucking brutal.
Um, anyways, he said, I
realize it's very hard to become one and
there's a chance I might not make it,
but I am pretty much training every
day and still have another four years.
However,
if I were to pursue this goal,
it would also mean I will not be able
to do stand up until I'm about 28 or 30.
I would like to continue with
stand up comedy once I get back,
but I am worried that I might be
a little too old to start by then.
Any suggestions? Jesus Christ?
Uh, well first of all, um,
being a comedian is also an exciting
life and an adventurous life and
mmm.
I guess it all depends on what type
of adventure that you want to have.
MMM.
I mean, becoming a green baret is pretty
fucking bad ass. And that is a very, very,
very small,
uh,
I guess club to be a member of.
MMM.
You know, so I wouldn't have
a say don't do that. I mean
it was fucking guy. I mean,
if they're unbelievable,
they're fucking unreal. I mean,
I was still stupid action movies,
these actors flipping
over cards and everything.
I mean like the true like actions, like
those navy seals, the green berets,
the army rangers. I mean those guys are,
are there are fucking unbelievable. So,
I mean that's a,
okay.
Um, I gotta be honest with
you. I don't, you know,
I don't see any regret on either one
of those, cause I would just, whatever,
whatever one you want to do more,
I would look,
the great thing is you got four years to
get through college before you have to
make this decision.
So I would continue doing standup.
I continue doing your workout and uh,
yeah,
you know, in four years,
just figure out, you know,
you got four years to figure
out which one you want to do,
but I can't give you advice
like that as far as a,
you're 28 or 30.
Um,
okay.
Yeah,
I mean that's later than most of you,
but you're already doing it now and
you can also do it all the way through
college and there's nothing stopping
you from doing it while you're in the
military on your, your, your
weekends off or some shit like that.
Um,
okay.
All right.
Let's just say if you actually got into
the military and you didn't get out
until you were 28 or 30,
I would say,
uh,
if that's the situation you were in,
what I would do is I would just look at
comedians that started late and made it,
and that's who I would focus
on. Um, I've always done that.
I didn't always do that. I learned
to do that, so I stayed positive,
you know what I mean?
MMM.
And it really is like, did
I, the business that I'm in,
the worst thing that you can do was give,
okay.
You know, the other people, the
power mentally to just be like, well,
I'm too old. They don't want me. You
start thinking that way, then they don't.
You just fucking, you go
out, you do your shit.
And it's, it's really, uh, yeah,
like even the way you're looking at this
and the way I just realized this now,
like it's not what the fuck can you not
walk on a stage and take a mic out of a
mic stand at 28 or 30,
you're going to be a goddamn green.
Baret Jesus Christ should
probably repelling from a
fucking helicopter and come
through the ceiling.
Um,
course you can.
Course you can, you can fucking
do it. Because what it really is,
is it's what you're doing then
is you're becoming an artist. Um,
and then all that is,
is that's just your own personal journey
and you're just trying to keep becoming
a better artist and all
that other fucking crap,
um, comes, you know, and if you
just keep working on yourself
and try and get better and
better and better and better,
eventually you become undeniable
and they got to let you in.
That's basically what it is.
Or You just go out and you make
your own shit and who gives a fuck?
And then they'll come over to you.
Hey, what do you make an over there?
I'm making this stuff. Okay. We'd like to
be involved. All right. What's the deal?
Well, we're going to own it.
Hey, go fuck yourself. Oh, okay.
Um, it's been my experience. Yeah. Dude.
So you've got four years.
So I would,
I would continue working out and
keep doing the standup in four years.
Four years is a long time when
you're only 18 years old. So, uh,
see what you think in the end. But,
uh, those are two very noble, um,
you know, uh, uh, goals to try to achieve,
I'm not gonna lie to you. I watched
that 11 days of hell and just, I mean,
I was just wondering if, if, you know,
just to see if I can make it through it.
If gotta be mentally tough enough,
forget about physically the mental where
down to those fucking guys yelling at
you and the impossible situations that
they put you in both as an individual and
then in the group dynamic.
It's just, it's unbelievable.
11 straight fucking days of that.
Um, I would love to do that, but I,
I don't, I dunno. I'm
enough of a fucking psycho.
I wouldn't need to, to,
uh, to be in the military,
if you know what I mean. You know,
especially when we're at war.
The last fucking thing I need to do is
break one of the only commandments I
haven't broken yet.
I guess I don't know
that I would come back.
I don't know that I'm mentally strong
enough that if I went to that fucking
place that I could somehow
come back. Uh, I dunno. Um,
I'm out of my fucking mind.
So I have a tremendous amount of respect
for anybody who successfully becomes a
soldier and can handle the demands
that are put on you. All right. Okay,
here we go. Catholic
girlfriend. Hey Aaron burr.
Sorry if that history of reference
was a little too high. Brow. Oh,
he full. Do you mean high brow? Like you'd
be like, I don't know who that is. Why?
Hi Bro.
You know what?
I'm not even going to take that person
cause you give me making fun of the
listeners and making fun of
yourself. I have no fucking idea. Um,
I love Aaron burr and he was right.
Okay. In a Hamilton's a cunt.
He knew what he was getting
himself involved in.
Any fucking lost fucking crybaby. Now
he's on the $10 bill. Where's Aaron Burr?
Everybody hates him because he won.
You know, he's like the original Colby.
I'm sorry if that history reference
was a little too high brow,
but Aaron Burr was essentially the
biggest client in the early United States
history. Small world. Right.
Okay.
I would love to hear you justify that
he was, he was one of the biggest cons.
How about the people out there who
are committing genocide on the native
Americans? What do you need though?
He was a Dick at dinner parties.
Agreed to have a dual and had it
the fucking balls to walk out there.
Any wins because Hamilton was cheating.
He fucking quick,
whatever they did the quick cocked his
fucking gun. So when he brought it up,
it was already, he did. Some do.
Tried to do some little shady
fucking move before he brought it up.
Stripe it should it fired.
So fuck him.
Unfucking real.
I'm fucking real.
Do you realize if Aaron Berg fucking lost,
he would be on the $10 bill and then
you would have said that Hamilton's a
biggest content.
Who the fuck would you be?
Do you be talking to that guy
in the rangers? Um, anyways,
I've been seeing this girl for around
six months now and I'm seriously nuts
about her.
I love spending time with her and can
see this relationship even leading to a
ring in a few years. Oh, congratulations.
But the big problem for me
is we're not having sex.
She's very religious,
which
now all the age,
she's very religious,
which does not bother me because she
doesn't care that I'm not extensively.
I don't know what the fuck that means.
Um,
okay.
You know what,
why don't I look that word up you guys,
when you want me to take a guess here,
even though I'm not ostensibly
I, you know, I can't even guess what the
fuck that means. What does that mean?
You go twice a year.
Can I even spell it? Uh, stents.
Well, there it is. It figured it out.
Thank you computer apparently or
purportedly, but perhaps not actually.
You know what God says, why? Why,
why do you try to become smart
when that's the fucking answer.
Um, you know that that's a
great line to give a cop.
Okay.
You've been drinking tonight apparently
or purportedly, but perhaps not actually
fucking flashlight to they head.
Um, to all outward appearances.
Okay.
So I guess that's a fancy way of saying
apparently is this guy a hipster and
he's sick of all the hipsters
saying, apparently, apparently.
Um, where am I? Cause she does not,
wait, let me read this now. Now that I,
I just learned what ostensively means,
which, okay. But the big problem
for me is we're not having sex.
She's very religious, which doesn't
bother me because she doesn't,
it doesn't care that I'm not extensively.
Yeah.
I have to go back and look it up again.
I don't understand what this means
to all outward appearances.
You're not religious.
Is this like some fancy way of
saying that your mysterious anyways,
it's her choice and it
didn't bother me for a while,
but I guess my fucking hormones are
starting to get the better of me.
We're both in college right now and
come from different backgrounds.
She does community service
and I'm a Frat shithead.
I break it off if I didn't feel
as strongly about her as I do,
but I'm not sure how much longer I can
put up with my most intimate partner
being porn hub and a bottle of lotion.
Should I tell her how I feel or
just quit being a selfish bastard,
a selfish bastard? Are My concerns normal
or am I being a con? Um, first of all,
you're not a Frat shithead if you actually
have empathy as far as the stereotype
goes,
you're actually a very mature person.
You seem like you know what you
have and you don't want to lose it.
MMM.
Oh,
how do you say I respect your,
okay,
your religious views,
but
how does the bearded baby Phil
about the occasional hand job,
does she know the, you're
watching? I tell you,
it's not a good thing to only be watching
porn and not having sex with somebody.
Uh,
okay.
I Dunno. Are you starting to become
more of a serial killer? I have no idea.
Hey Nia.
You know what I, I gotta I gotta
Bring Nia and for this one,
yeah,
I got to bring her right for this
one. Hang on one second. Let me,
let me hit pause here.
I don't want to hit pause.
All right, the lovely near everybody.
Hello. All right, here we go. Um,
here is the question. So
this kid, he's basically,
I'm going to paraphrase here so listeners
don't have to listen to it again.
He's got a Catholic girlfriend.
Um,
she's very religious.
Just to pull the microphone back.
You're breathing into it
there. Sorry. Sorry. I think
I had turned up too much. Um,
anyways, uh, you know,
Catholic girl, very religious,
does not want to have sex before marriage.
And he's saying,
you know, they've been
together for awhile. He loves
or spending time with her,
can see actually given her a ring in a
couple of years, but the big problem is,
and not having sex, she's very
religious. Um, he's not religious,
but she doesn't care. He said it's her
choice and you know, to not have sex.
And it didn't bother me for awhile,
but I guess my hormones are starting
to get the better than me.
We're both in college right now and
I come from different backgrounds.
She does community service and I'm
a frat boy, shithead Frat Shit.
Eddie said I break it off if I didn't
feel as strongly about or as I do,
but I'm not sure how much longer I can
put up with my most intimate partner
being porn hub and a bottle of lotion.
Should I tell her how I feel?
But just quit being a selfish
bastard on my concerns. Normal.
Or Am I being a cunt? No,
you're not being a cunt.
I think he's actually being really great.
That's what I thought. Yeah. I mean,
you should definitely tell
your girlfriend, but be
prepared but don't play.
How does he do it? Because what I would,
what I would, if I was in that situation,
I would try to say, you know, it's,
you know, it's just a hand job.
It's just a handy, just a handyman. No, I
think you should tell her I was feeling,
but I would just walk out with my day.
You gonna keep interrupting me.
Can you help me out all week?
That sounds like something you would
do actually. Uh, she'd laugh. Uh, no.
I mean, you tell her how you feel, but
don't frame it in the context. Like,
I'm fucking dying over here. What
are you doing to me? Oh my God.
Don't make it like a guilt trip. Just
say, just, just so you know, I'm,
I'm really having a hard time with this
because I love you so much and I really
want to have sex with you,
but I know you don't want to,
I don't want to pressure you. They
make love I'd rather than sex. Well,
however you want to it. Love is
gross. No, it's not. It's gross.
Make love. Yeah. I mean, I don't
know. It's gross. It's just,
it's very like old fashion.
It's like what you say when you're trying
to like be nice about it or something,
you know? Yeah. Fuck. You
don't want to say that.
That's my favorite line in the movie.
What? Tom Robinson Bull Durham.
We don't fuck a word. Oh yeah.
Um, but yeah, just, just
tell her and the thing is,
she's probably feels the same way.
She might be frustrated.
He has been looking at Becky,
she's been listening to this southern Rep,
white and black people in the south.
They pronounced in certain words,
they just pronounced the beginning
with the first couple of letters. Yeah.
Yeah. You drop off.
Like, if it, if a word,
it has like two like syllables.
You got to just do the
first one to start on a new,
uh, but anyway, yeah, just, just,
just be honest with her about it. But,
but just,
you know,
make it clear that she knows how much
you love and respect her and that's,
that's all you can do. But how does
he do it without her feeling pressure?
She might feel pressure.
She probably already feels pressure
from society or whatever. So, you know,
she's already feeling the pressure,
but he just said
Tara and be like, listen, I'm not
trying to put any pressure on,
I'm just telling you where I'm at.
Because if he keeps going to porn hub,
what happens is with porn is you have
to keep going further and further and
further down the fucking hall.
Well when they finally have sex,
she's going to be like, what?
What do you want me to do?
You know she's going to be freaked out.
Cause that's the other thing,
you watch too much porn and like porn
becomes like your reality about what
everyday relationship sex. And so there's
all kinds of like, I, it's, I don't know.
I mean obviously kill me,
but it's like,
be careful what that porn
shit cause it's awesome,
but it will really like put you on another
planet if you're not careful about it.
And you just start thinking like people
should be performing like porn stars and
you should be performing like porn stars
and you should be able to do all these
crazy shit. These people are paid
to have sex. That's their job.
That's not your job. So just, I
dunno, just be careful with that.
I just feel it was like, well what
the fuck is he supposed to do though?
This is the thing you masturbating.
Yeah, I know. Thank [inaudible] wasn't
around when I was fucking that age.
Jesus Christ.
How did you watch porn at that age?
You would like sneak old VCR
tapes from your older brother. Um,
no. Like how did you do it with
nobody had a porno in my house.
No fucking way.
We had one VCR in the family room.
Fucking watch it. It was impossible.
I used to sneak and watch.
Do you remember a Emmanuelle?
It was like the soft core,
like Cinemax show.
It was like from Europe,
it was from Europe and it was all like
soft lighting and it was all about this
girl and manual who would have
these like sexy adventures.
Like she's going on a train to Paris and
then like she looks over and you know,
she the a guy like bang in
the fucking, I dunno, could
literally and figuratively,
no. Uh, the first time
I saw a porno, uh, uh,
a buddy of mine had it,
buddy of mine got one and we were all
on our way out and like five of us just
sat there and watched it
and then just got up and went out like 17.
I watched a porn at a sleep over, but we
were like in eighth grade or something.
Like she stole it from her dad
and it was like a seventies porn.
It's always just like everyone's
a hairy and it was just this guy.
Like it wasn't the ones, the one
that I saw I, where'd it go? Me Out?
The one that I saw, I swear to God,
I swear to God this happened. Okay.
The dude who was he,
he was working at a restaurant and
he was getting laid and he's fucking
everybody. And they had this fucking old
ugly lady comes in, was giving him shit,
you know, make the chicken sandwich
and I want extra mayo on it. Yeah.
Oh God. Oh No, this is even worse.
Can instead of just having
a guy jerk off onto the fuck
sandwich, I swear to God, you know,
or Twista re chicken, you know,
you can just buy one that's already
made. Yeah, he fucked it. Oh my God,
this was an a porno.
See nowadays that that would
have been considered BCL no,
it was considered like they
were trying to be funny.
I was and they were trying to be like
funny cause they play like there's weren't
wink apparently this wacky music when
he was doing it right. And I was like,
you gotta understand.
I had never seen a fucking porno.
And it went like the
first time you saw a need,
especially back then where as like,
uh,
like the most overtly like sexual thing.
Like when I was a kid was Brooke shields
the one button on a shirt and you know,
went from that to watch
people actually fucking,
and then there's dude's stuck his
dick in a chicken that's discussing,
remember when we went to go see that?
Um, what's that? Quintin Tarantino.
It was grind house.
It was like the two movies and then in
between they had the fake trailers and
one of them was Thanksgiving and they
show that quick little like two second
thing at the end of it of a guy like
fucking a Turkey remembering and everyone
in the movie theater went
through it in like fabric.
Like I would not be surprised if they
got that idea from that very porno that
you watched.
Yeah,
because back cause I think Eli
Roth directed that like trailer,
that fake trailer or something.
But yeah, that's discussing. Yeah.
Like no we're not lacking in.
And I remember like the videos.
Then after that the video store
came out and then the video store,
it had the back room with ours.
It had those so funny they
had these saloon doors.
He had to walk through end to get into
the back room and there wasn't me being
like a beaded curtain in some areas
like that was like the sexy area.
It was whether it be the
current one and I have to,
it was so early on I don't
think that there was categories.
They just had porno. It was
all straight porn. Yeah.
Growing up in a suburb,
right.
It was just all straight porn.
There was no,
there was no like categories like uh,
you know,
whatever fucking doggy style
ones or it's more like,
I feel like it's like
race or racial identity,
like Asian boy agent Paul or have an
evil bondage, blah, blah, blah, blah.
There wasn't just Debbie,
it was just people fucking on camera.
That's all it was.
It was a man and a woman fucking or
man and two women fucking are two guys.
Fuck it.
A woman and that within the occasional,
and then the chicken thing was a bit like
it was supposed to be this funny thing
and that I had and it was funny because
it was the first one I have a solid,
I was sitting like what
the fuck? Right. Um,
but then I was also site
cause I actually saw some,
I is actually saw porno a we getting
bagged and shit and it wasn't until years
later, wait a minute, I
think I was hanging out,
I was still living with Bobby Kelly and
we were talking about the first, yeah,
the first pornos that we saw. I remember
telling that and he was just going,
what? And I go, dude, I swear to
God. He goes, what was the name?
Like I don't know what the name of it was.
My buddy just had it. I, but you know,
you know
who would know, you know, who would know
the answer to it is David's [inaudible].
He would know. I bet if you asked
them or if we tweeted him and said,
do you remember ever seeing a porno from
circa whatever year that is. And a guy.
If I bet he would know, you realize
you just blew up his Twitter account.
All right,
we're going to end with this dilemma.
Oh wait, you know, I got to read some Ma.
I got to read the rest of the advertising
real quick. Uh, Hulu plus everybody,
come on, let me read it here. Hulu plus
she probably tried Hulu on your computer.
Hulu plus is so much more Hulu with
Hulu plus you can watch current season
episodes of your favorite
shows like modern family,
the daily show and scandal and watch
every episode of shows like Nashville lost
and doctor who,
um,
you get ad free movies and kid
shows to now more than ever,
there is so much to watch.
Take total control with Hulu plus to
stream these shows and thousands more,
as much as you want, whenever
you want. This is the best part.
Hulu plus works on your computer,
your smart TV, Roku, apple TV,
Xbox, playstation. Pretty much any
streaming device you already own.
You can apply Hulu plus two.
You can even watch on your eye,
on your phone or iPad while on the
train at work at the dentist or in the
bathroom,
you can even block off a day to binge.
You also get access to originals that
you can get anywhere that you can't get
anywhere else.
Check out the new show dead.
Beat a comedy about a pot
smoking guy who talks to ghosts.
Binge on all 10 episodes starting
April 9th for only seven 99 a month.
Get uh, get your shows anytime, anywhere.
That's like a quarter a day right now.
Sign up for Hulu plus.com/norm for some
reason they keep giving me this one.
Yeah, let's get norm. Let's,
let's give norm macdonald
the fucking money this week.
hulu.com/norm and get two weeks
full access completely free.
That's a whole week,
whole extra week more with your
special offer when you sign up at Hulu
plus.com/norm so get with it and start
screaming TV now with Hulu plus and
lastly,
but not leastly stamps.com everyone summer
is finally here and you want as much
free time as possible.
Don't let go into the post office
cutting to that free time, everybody.
Just use stamps.com instead
with stamps.com you can
print postage right from
your desk. You won't ever have to
go to the office post office again.
Find Parking, wait your turn.
All of that stuff that you hate.
stamps.com turns your PC or your Mac
country, your own personal post office.
What can you do with it?
Well,
you can buy and print official us
postage using your computer and printer.
You can print everything from
stamps to shipping labels,
shipping labels whenever you need it.
Then just hand your mail to the mailman.
Boom you'd done. stamps.com is
so convenient and easy to use.
Even a moron like me can use it.
You'll never waste time going
to the post office again.
I use this to send out all my DVDs,
all my posters,
whatever crap of selling at the end.
I've never had a problem.
I'm an idiot if I can figure it out.
So can you,
there's no reason to go to the post
office anymore and right now use my last
name bur bur for this special offer,
no risk trial plus a $110 bonus offer
includes a digital scale and up to $55
free postage. So don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top
of the homepage and type in Burb,
B u r r that stamps.com and to birth
it was a pretty good read, Huh?
Yeah. You're getting better
at getting better at them.
I'm still fucking up and I'm
getting better. Uh, dilemma.
Hey Bill,
would you rather be morbidly obese to
the point where just walking around is
exhausting?
I'm talking over 350 pounds and you
weren't allowed to lose the weight.
I love that.
You already answered or would you rather
be stuck in prison for the rest of your
life?
Oh, God. Stuck president. Rarely.
It's a shallow way.
Um, I feel like though, hey, easy, easy.
If you're 350 pounds or whatever,
that's my fault. By the way.
I'm not good with the mixture. Oh, okay.
Uh, it's like you're already in prison.
You're in prison, in your own body. I
think they're both prisons, aren't they?
I mean they are, but I mean it's
like, oh, I see what you mean.
No, no, I'm agreeing with you. Yeah.
You just had a nice little
metaphor there and I ruined it. Um,
but I rather be obese. It'd be in prison
for the rest. No brainer. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
But I can't just make it a fun.
You'd have getting that fat.
That's the thing.
It would be really fun to just be like
eating all the good shit that you can't
have in prison. They don't have good food
there. So maybe I would rather be obese.
I don't know.
Jesus Christ,
you might just, somebody's obese listening
to this right now. They're basically,
you are basically saying, Gee,
I would rather be in prison
for the rest of my life to be you.
I definitely rather be
silly like objective thing that's
new for you to get on a plane,
talk about it and people
shouldn't get offended by it.
Get on a plane with your two seats and
your giant seatbelt and you can fly
anywhere in the fucking world
and go get even fatter. Right.
Do you have to buy two seats if
you're like over a certain weight?
What's the weight requirement now?
Whenever it is like the Kevin
Smith is over it. Right?
Cause that's how why he got,
he had that whole problem with JetBlue
or southwest because they thought
southwest. Cause they were
like, yeah, you need to buy.
I don't think he was that big
though. Like two seats big. I Dunno.
I've never met him. I met him. He wasn't
two seats big when I saw him. Yeah,
I dunno. Maybe they're just
being decks. Look the only time
southwest is a great airline,
but I don't like, uh,
I don't like all the jokes that they tell.
I get it that they're trying to make it
lighten it up and with a cool company,
but it's like my life
is in hands right now.
I would, I would. I thought you meant
the stewards and this, even that.
I don't like being sad. I don't
like it either. I've kind of,
what I find,
I find when you're going someplace,
if the person at the top
is doing their job right,
everybody beneath is also in line and
they come off like the rod a line.
It seems like the,
the vibe on a southwest flight is
that this is substitute teacher.
I don't like that. You
know what I mean? I like,
I liked feeling like shit is in order,
you know?
Have you seen on Virgin Airlines that
there's safety video is like this full
scale music,
video production fucking thing.
It's like a little kid that wraps into,
there's like a little Asian girl
that wraps a little black kid.
That's awareness suit. I was like in those
break dancers you can't get away from,
it's a whole can't get away.
I was actually like,
I was actually finding myself happy for
the people that were in the view that
they were got work and exposure on
this level and I was, I was like,
how much money does Richard Branson have?
He really made,
I hate the mood light behind the music
behind the scenes video of how they made
the thing on it.
So when Williams or where are you
saying you hate the mood lighting?
Where on Virgin?
Why?
What do you mean you walk on and you
just going to get an STD on the fucking
thing. I Love Virgin Airlines. I love it.
That all mine like origins.
Cool. I I don't, I jet blue's
cool. Jet Blue is good.
You get to watching ESPN the whole
way across the country. I liked that.
I liked being able to watch all my
stupid like Bravo, real housewives.
I the only airline I really don't
fucking like other than the,
just the crazy ones that I used to fly
when I was starting out. Like that was it.
Ata or some shit. Oh, I don't know. All,
all trans something.
Try and err. Yeah. Yeah.
You know the airlines I've flown that
don't even fucking exist anymore at this
point. We just got swallowed up. Uh,
I flew people's express in
the age. What is that? Oh,
it was like the precursor to value
jet man. It was fucking shady.
I remember values yet. Um,
they had that fire. Um,
unfortunately,
uh,
I need to go back. Um,
I would rather be obese
eastern airline
my, but yeah, my mom has to work for
eastern choose to fly. She was a PE
anyway. And northwest, none
of these exist anymore.
None of them are you. They'll get bought
out or they went out of business. Uh,
wait, can we go back? So got
a flight. Franks airline.
Can we go back to that? Sounds like like
a corner store. Like a place like a deli.
Frank's like a deli. Sell
hotdogs. I made that up.
Rather be obese and free than in a,
in exactly apologize to
people who were overweight,
apologizing. We're in the age of apologize
and take a fucking joke. Fatty. But
you and your fat shaming. But you
know what? The fat, shame, shame,
shame,
American in the Frat people.
Shame is such such a fucked up
industry that I would not want it off.
You have no, I wouldn't get off
your, I wouldn't want to be,
I wouldn't want to be in prison. That
was, that was a stupid answer. Said that,
that was my main answer. We got it.
But I admit that, hey, I want to,
I'm going to start a new segment on here
where I felt shame somebody every week.
Cause I know cause I'd make it work.
Why don't you shame other people too.
Can you shame just shame. Can I finish
across the board and I'd finished here?
Sure.
So the jingles,
consider that chain of fools where they
go chain chain chain. I'm gonna Shame,
shame, shame, boop, boop,
boop, boop and other songs.
Shame on you. I don't know that I'll
have somebody sing the high pod. Yeah,
add those cupcakes. You really are
just going to go with this idea. No.
Your nods. Yeah. Yeah. I'll wait.
I'm going to show that it
works through that on news.
They used to do this shaver,
remember?
And they'd have this like graphic of a
finger pointing and it was the reporters.
I'd be like, they would go up to
like slum lords that he used to. No,
they had their own,
they had their own little like jingle.
But I'm telling you is that they, yeah,
they were like burst into places and say,
I hear, you know, we hear that you're
charging, customers were bup, bup, bup,
and don't you think that's wrong?
And they'd have to like get the owners
to try to like fess up. I, yeah,
it was a finger wagging and that was it.
That was it.
I don't know if there's a religious nuts
out there that can try to like make gay
people straight and they're trying to
show like that they think that that works.
Right. Oh, and I kind of liked
those people where I think shaming,
I've actually had iPad,
that's what they do on the biggest loser.
And I thought when they scream at them
and make them cry, make them puke.
I can't believe somebody just
hasn't dropped of a heart attack.
I know they've been writing articles
about that show and how it's really fucked
up. You know, I wa I used to watch it
all the time cause I was like, I found a,
and you'd sit there and cry with them,
laugh and you did a bit about it.
I remember because that's,
that's what you were talking about
how like they had so much fun.
Like they're living the life,
they're the,
they're the real rock stars because while
you're sitting there like, you know,
eating salads and having to work out,
they're just like doing whatever they
want and living the life. Oh my God.
That was a, wow. That was a
while ago when you did that bad.
But I used to love that show after
awhile I was like, all right, I get it.
I get it. I'm over it. But no,
I really, I really liked it,
but people will have a serious problem.
The woman left the show
cause she was sick.
She was sick of them sweating all over
him. She made her money. She's back.
I think that last season she's been back.
She left for a little, everybody's back.
This business is shrinking by the day.
There was a homeless on there.
All the, all the movie stars
are doing TV shows now.
I know I want to watch that Halle Berry
TV show that I need to want the pilot.
Just emotional people are grabbing every
dime they can get before my business
turns into what the music industry did.
You realize how fucking lucky
I am that I can, I actually
have a live show that I can go
on the road. How lucky I am.
Thanks fucking Christ.
I think like live shows are going to be
something of the past because it's like
they've been going on forever.
No, no, no. I think people will always
want to do that. I mean maybe they'll uh,
you know,
be funny is if
is if somehow like what
do they call those things?
They did that creepy thing
with Tupac and Michael Jackson.
Oh, the Hologram shit that they're doing
like at Coachella and like award shows
where like,
yeah,
all of a sudden two POCs shows up
and does like his entire discography.
Spencer people tripping their
balls off. I know, right? I know.
And people, you could hear people when you
see footage on youtube, you'll be like,
and then they're like,
oh wait, it's a hawk.
Well I would never say
that that wouldn't happen,
but I would think at some point you're
going to want to leave the house.
You're going to want to have to
leave the fucking house. But I,
I gotta be honest with you,
like live shows,
if people look live shows would stop. I
will tell you this. So I love that movie.
I did walk her shame. How at this
it's simultaneously released on
yeah,
I fucking like,
I would see more movies if I could just
sit on my ass here and pop in God's
Zillow or some shit like that.
I definitely would.
And Godzilla is something that I didn't
go see. But if I was sitting at home,
I was fucking watched that shit.
We still need to go see him.
Maleficent is it still in
the movie theater? I want to
see that movie. Yeah, I did.
And now I don't.
I was glad cause they stopped showing
commercials and I stopped giving a shit.
Like I was into it. They got me,
they had me rest and all that.
I go see that Alison Wonderland
looking evil. Which shit,
I'll go see that snow white and the
seven dwarfs.
All right. It's about the evil
queen, but yeah, yeah, exactly.
Oh it's hurts perspective. When
we had Juliana is the, uh, she's,
she's the queen and we had
a wrong the whole time.
Well we get to understand what happened
to her and the whole bit and why she's
that way. And can I say something
about that evil witch she childhood.
Tell me about it. Cause her
childhood was a long time ago. Okay.
At some point it happens in your thirties.
You have to stop taking your childhood on,
on people and you've got a fucking man up.
Okay.
So that's what I would
say to that, which, okay,
can we please go see this movie
so we can talk about it then?
Is she standing there stirring
her fucking steal fucking pot.
Whatever the hell she's doing with bat
heads in it. Coldron all right. Listen,
this podcast is going on and on and on
and on. We gotta, we gotta wrap it up.
We've got to wrap it up.
All right, this, this,
this has been the Monday morning podcast.
Thanks.
Thanks for everybody a for
listening. Um, thanks everybody.
Seriously who came out, um,
to my a standup specials.
You can tell I'm pretty fucking
burned out from the whole weekend. Uh,
I really appreciate it.
I had a great going down
that Atlanta is such a great
comedy city and uh, yeah,
I had a great fucking time. So that's
it. I'm going to work on the new hour.
Hopefully I'll have enough of that shit
together by the time the special comes
out. I'll let you guys know when that
comes out. Um, until then, oh by the way,
as always,
if you're going to buy something on
amazon.com you want to contributor to the
podcast, just go to the, uh,
Monday morning podcast page
on billboard.com and click
on the Amazon banner and
it'll take you right to Amazon and they'll
kick me a fee for sending you there.
It doesn't cost you any money
through it if you want to,
if you don't go right to Amazon. All
right, that's it. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you next week.