Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the Monday
morning podcast from Monday.
Fuck in my day.
Uh,
September 23rd, 2030. What's going on?
What's going on dog? What's up?
See The fucking patch. You know,
you didn't think they were that good.
You're fucking three and oh now,
now what do you think?
So mmm,
more on that later. I am a back
in the continental United States.
I just did a two wonderful
shows up in Toronto, Ontario.
It's the first time I've been up to
Canada in a while. Had a great time.
And uh, right before that I was in
Pittsburgh. Had a lovely time there.
Thanks to all the guys that uh,
DVE Randy Bauman,
uh, Bill Crawford, opening it
up, killing, killing, killing it,
the kick the Hines hall. And then
before that I was down there. But uh,
in West Virginia,
another beautiful state did
everybody shits all over.
I'm telling you I'm going to retire
and one of those fucking states,
that is my game plan.
The game plan is I'm going to somehow
get these fucking banker counts off of me
going to pay off this God
damn house and then, you know,
when I'm too fucking old hill,
my hair's all white or yellow,
whatever it happens to fucking red hair.
And on top I got those freckles
old age spots and my bald head,
I'm just gonna fuck.
Oh yeah.
And I'm going to sell this
place and I will move to like,
I dunno, West Virginia.
Uh, I'd moved to Iowa,
but like what the fuck? No, no,
that was good. That was great.
I really understand that topography now
of Iowa with that vivid description.
Thank you. I'm over
here in Wales, England.
Now I understand exactly what Iowa
looks like. I'm sorry. I maybe will the,
the Dakotas something along those lines.
Um,
I just going to move to the middle of
fucking nowhere and by then maybe I'll
have a pilot's license and I can go out
like John Denver and I had just picked
it. That would be a, a
B, a w a lovely life.
It would be a lovely life. Um,
no, I have actually, you know,
just been driving around seeing all the
different parts of the country here. Man.
I, I'm getting back into drive and
does stuff. In fact, by the way,
last week I got a brutal email from
somebody telling me what a piece of shit I
am and all this type of stuff cause I
had to cancel my Gig and El Paso and it's
like I didn't cancel the fucking thing.
It rained.
And that's not my fault that you guys
don't have a sewer system or whatever the
fuck it is out there in El Paso.
And I told you that I would
rescore I fucking flew out there.
I was sitting there, I had my show
shirt, all iron. I was ready to go.
But as promised I said we will reschedule
the El Paso date as soon as possible.
And I am a man of my fucking word.
The El Paso date,
the new date is
October 2nd. All right. And
instead of dude, I call it Versie.
Uh, I'm actually bringing Rosebowl
legend tailgate legend, Mr. Joe Barton.
Nick, everybody. Okay.
A man who honed his skills in the
San Francisco San Francisco scene,
man. And uh, that's, that's a
Wednesday. That's a great run.
Wednesday is a,
is El Paso.
Thursday the third is a San Jose.
Friday the fourth to Seattle.
And then the 5th of October is a,
I'm back down in Phoenix.
And uh, so anyways,
so if you,
if you bought tickets already for El Paso,
those things are totally honored.
If you can't make October 2nd, your,
your money will be refunded
any more than that. I,
there's nothing else I can, I can't
control the fucking weather. So, um,
anyways, I've been getting a
have against slammed lately.
There was some people in Seattle did not
take kindly to my fucking by song that
I sang Lexi. I get called like a faggot
like 58 times on Twitter this week.
Um, yeah, people did not
appreciate that song,
although they did not refute it.
No one ever said they didn't go out of
their way to architecturally in awake,
architecturally designed. How
else would you do with bill? Huh?
I also need to do it.
I'm trying to think of another big word,
but I don't have what I know I was gonna
say geometrically what you probably
need geometry and geometry for that
shit. That's not a good one. Uh,
peanut butter and Jelly Ectera
t way and a fucking, anyways,
you know what I love about then a couple,
I guess a couple of people just wrote
some of the blurb that I wrote to piss off
all the Seahawk fans. Um, and uh,
they left out the whole part where I
set all the complimentary stuff and how
they got a great team and how when I
watched the Patriots play and then I see,
you know, Seattle of Frisco Colts
or whatever, watch those games.
How it just looks like football on a
whole other level and how Seattle has a
great chance at winning the Superbowl and
how I don't blame fucking Pete Carroll
for what the fuck he did at USC because
everybody does it yet all of that shit
gets left out.
Only thing that they had in
there was we was me going, we
someday people of Seattle fans of the
Seattle Seahawks as mad as you are,
that you have to use those homophobic
slurs in your advanced city man.
MMM.
You'll, you'll, you'll, you'll
understand it one of these days,
one of these days when you actually
have something shiny and Yep.
Cupboard until now, you're just
screaming. That's all you're doing.
And you know,
that's another reason why you guys are
so loud because of how empty your trophy
cases,
it causes an x
go.
You guys came into the League in 1977
along with the Tampa Bay Buccaneers.
And even those sad conch figured out a
fucking way to win one by now. All right?
So even if you have finally when one
this year, I got two words for you.
It's about fucking time. All right? And
if you can't do the math on that, yeah,
I'm just fucking around. All
right. You Shit. Birds Relax.
I'll be up there on the fourth. Do
whatever the fuck you want. Boomi.
I don't give a shit. They give
me the check already. All right.
It's actually not true, but I'm
gonna act like it is. So anyways,
plowing ahead here. Um,
yeah, I was up in Toronto.
One of the great things about going up
to Canada aside from the fact that hockey
is the first story,
you know when it comes to sports,
that's the big thing that's going on.
I watched like hockey night in Canada.
I came home and I watched the replay,
the shown preseason hockey up there.
Like it's fucking march.
Okay.
And they're trying to figure out
who's going to make the playoffs.
Playoffs and a somebody actually uh,
I watched a little bit of
the Toronto Buffalo Games.
Some of the a replay. No, no,
I watched Edmonton. Vancouver.
That's what I was watching.
Somebody just sent me a link.
Did this great broth.
Um, I'll, I'll give you
guys a video of it and,
and all you guys who don't like hockey,
just spare me your stupid great
sport. What are they? Let him fight.
This is a sport. This, I gotta be honest
with you guys. That's music to my ears.
I liked the people don't understand
hockey that you can't see the puck for
whatever fucking reason. I
love it. I love it. Keep,
keep pilot on and watching football and
go down to your sports bar with your man
tits and you're fucking football
jersey. I'm all about it. By all means.
I'll sit over in the quiet part
of the bar watching a hockey game.
Same without you and your fucking Cheetos
breath invading my shoulder area near
my notes. You know, you shoulders, knee.
And that was right. I was thinking,
looking over my shoulder out, whatever.
I don't need to explain my body parts.
Do you people? All right. Um, so anyways,
whatever. Two guys on the, one
guy on Toronto, one Guy Buffalo,
they get into a fight and the guy at
Buffalo, his helmet comes off and uh,
he fucking ended up whacking
his head on the ice.
And I guess buffalo took an exception
to that. So this fucking big goof,
Scott is big goof.
That could beat the living shit out of me,
but I'm safe here in the podcast.
So I'll call him a goof
knowing nothing about him.
I'm sure he's a wonderful
well spoken human being,
but he looked like a big goof cause
he's standing next to Phil Kessel.
Phil Kessel comes up to like, I dunno,
maybe his hockey pants is a little short.
Shorts is little sat in booty shorts,
cities wherein Edd,
I decided to take it out on him.
He takes a swing at little folk castle.
Little felt ever heard anybody
just trying to score a goal.
Some assess doesn't even go on the corner.
He's not hurting anybody and I don't. I
did. Phil Kessel lost his fucking Shit.
I have a whole new found
respect for that guy.
This big dude punched him.
So one of the other fucking maple
leaf guys immediately grabbed Scott.
If Phil castled takes a two hander,
not once but twice to the back of
Scott's like nine old lot of you guys go,
well what the fuck? He's
tied up with somebody else.
That's a cheap shot. Fuck you.
All right.
When you're two feet taller than a guy,
when you have to punch down at the
top of somebody's head at that point,
you might want to pick a different
dance partner. Right. But he didn't,
so he fucking whacks him twice and then
squares off with another guy in the
sabers and actually wins the fight.
Bloodies the guy up.
They stop and then kessels he's
going to skate off the ice.
That big dude Scott is still tied up
with somebody went over and he fucking
spirit of trying to take out the guy's
spleen. I was like, good for him.
There you go. That's, that's good. Phil.
You don't take no shit off. Nobody.
He went all spider on. Why don't you
go fuck yourself Tommy. It was great.
It was great to see. And um,
I think the leafs, hopefully,
I think they're going to be good
this year. I like the leafs.
I've always liked him. Um,
and speaking of that, oh yeah,
we're going to talk hockey
here in September. And somebody
sent me an, an article,
uh, that said, um, you
know, the, you know,
you always got to have some sort of
controversial title just to get people to
read it. It says Montreal Canadians, the
most overrated franchise in Nhl history.
And they basically touched on some
shit that I had brought it up,
brightened that I had brought up, um,
you know, through, of course not reading,
just overhearing shit that saying that,
you know,
the Canadians dominated as 16 league and
that they had first pick at all French
born Canadian players, Yada,
Yada, Yada. All of that.
This is a really cool article because
it actually explains that more
and it makes me understand,
but it makes me understand Montreal,
Toronto better. Um, so this is the
points the guy's making. I don't,
I don't agree with all of this stuff,
but it says the original six teams, uh,
carries an aura with them. Uh, the
Montreal Canadian Baba, you know,
the 60s all did battle each other.
Um,
so basically you had a 16.6,
7% chance of winning.
So of course everybody's gonna
argue. Well, so did the Bruins.
So did the Black Hawks or the Redwings.
So did everybody else. But here,
here's the thing that's
really interesting about this,
unless you're not into a hockey then I,
I don't know what to tell you is um,
ah Christ,
I don't even have it here with a fuck. Is
it basically this, this is how it work.
Work Do, you couldn't like
sign anybody back in the day.
So the Canadians did not have first chance
at all French born Canadian players.
What they had back there was
something I guess called the c form,
which if you went out, you scouted people
they had to sign if they signed it,
that was an Iou that they were
going to go and play for you.
So Montreal was smart enough
to go all over Canada.
I try and sign these people like right
before they turned 18 or right as they
turned 18.
But the big thing was was you had first
chance at all players within basically a
50 mile radius of your city. This is
really interesting. I never knew this.
You had first chance at that. So, um,
okay.
Basically why that kind of tipped the
scales was Montreal and Toronto had first
chance at everybody and basically,
you know,
Quebec and Ontario where everybody's
hockey crazy and comes out of the womb
skating.
And then you look at like the Bruins and
we had first chance at trying to find a
rocket Rashard in like New
Hampshire or the, as they say here,
the rangers trying to find the next
best goalie in Newark, new or Hoboken,
New Jersey.
And it's really interesting because what
he fails to bring up in this article
was that Montreal didn't
dominate a 16 league,
um,
both Montreal and Toronto up until 1967.
The year of expansion.
At that point,
Montreal had 14 cups and uh,
and,
and the, the, uh, the maple
leafs had 13. So the two of them,
just by being up in Canada,
I'm being around all of that talent and
the fact that you only get to 16 fucking
league, they bill, they were
able to go on a run. But, um,
you know, and I wonder if that
helped Detroit too because Detroit,
they're 50 mile radius would actually get
them into a Ontario a little bit where
people gave a shit and love talky.
But it was a really interesting article
and I'm not sure here to shit on the
Canadians,
God knows I do that enough.
But that very clarified misinformation
that I was putting out there that that,
I mean I was, I was looking at it like
everything east of Montreal, they owned,
you had to go play for the
Canadians that I was like,
what the fuck that be like if he had a
whole all of new England or whatever to
draft for a particular sport or
something like that. So my apologies,
you won't hear this often to the
Montreal Canadiens franchise.
I was wrong about that.
And now I now understand
why Montreal and Toronto,
what kind of going tit for tat with
that 50 mile radius thing was really
interesting.
At the end of the day though,
that thing that Montreal was going
around trying to find all of this town,
they did do the work.
So you kinda got to give it up from
on a on that level. So there you go.
Look at that apologizing to the Canadians.
But I'll have a link to
that if you want to read it.
If you're a sports nerd like me.
Um,
it's a great article all the way through.
I wouldn't say that Montreal is overrated,
but I was disappointed that the uh,
that the writer of the article did not
bring up the Toronto Maple leafs in why
they were able to kind of go,
you know,
strive for strive there with the Canadians
up till 67 it was basically in the
70s I think. Right.
That's when the Canadians,
they one six and they also want what
they want and 68 and 69 I can't remember
now. Yeah, I think they want 68 69
then broadens one's 70 than Montreal.
[inaudible] 71 [inaudible] 72
then Montreal flyers, flyers,
and then Montreal for the rest of the
decade. That's how it went. All right.
Jesus Christ is there one woman left
listening to this podcast and with that,
let's do some advertising.
Great timing bill. Great timing.
I get the fucking calendar out
of the way here. Um, either way,
hockey's coming back. I'm really
excited about it. Oh, you know,
when I was in Pittsburgh,
um,
what the fuck was I just going to tell
you? I was hanging out with uh, uh,
Randy from DV and a bill
Crawford and you know,
they know Paula Steigerwald to help him
saying his name right. Stagger walls.
I always fuck up the pronunciations of
anybody's last name if it has more than
two syllables, but it was just so
insane. They brought him along and uh,
we kind of, you know,
talked right after the,
after the show and I've watched so much
center rice just to hear his voice was
insane. It just kept saying
that till going like, dude,
like this.
It was be hilarious.
He would start talking to me
just talking about regular stuff.
Paul Wood and I,
everything I did could do to not start
looking around for the hockey game on TV.
Cause I felt like I was listening to
like, Oh shit, there's a hockey game on.
I've just, I've, I basically,
I've watched a ton of penguins games
is what I'm trying to say. So, uh,
that was a big thrill getting to
hang out with him. But, um, anyway,
so let's get to the, uh,
let's get to the Goddamn, uh,
where is it here? Let's get
to the advertising for this
week. All right, everybody.
Dollar Shave Club, dollar
shave club, everyone.
There is so many things in
this world that irritate me.
Having to go to Canada to
smoke a Cuban cigar, you know,
that really irritates me. Is that the
only thing that irritates me? This, oh,
this fucking letter somebody
wrote me that'll read later,
that also irritate whatever. You know,
there's a lot of things that irritate me.
Um, when so many things can irritate
you. Why add razors to this list?
It's time to stop milking
your razor blades.
Everybody I know with brand name razors,
you used to paying outrageous prices
and exhausting those razors until they
start to look like a rusty soda can.
And it's time to move on.
Dollar Shave Club delivers amazing
quality blades to your door for just a few
bucks a month, month.
Never think about it again.
They send a pack every month so you
can change your blades every week.
I love these guys and your
face will love them too. Yeah.
I don't know why nobody ever came
up with this before. These guys,
I'm telling you in their commercials
are hilarious for the one wipe Charlies.
I'm going to put up a link for that.
It's hilarious.
Now they have these offensive linemen
are going to be the spokesman for the one
wipe Charlies, which is salt. It's
so brilliant. Everything that this,
this company is doing, uh, from
what they're coming up with,
two to how they're marketing it is, it's
awesome. It's entertaining. You need it.
It fills a void. God bless them.
All right. Back to the copy. Yeah.
They've got a new product
called one wipe Charlies.
It's a buttwipe for men and it's classy.
You can put a top hat on and use this
and no one's going to question you.
Check out the video for that and
sign up for your razors today. Uh,
I got a dollar shave club.com, forward
slash burr. That's dollar shave club.com.
Forward slash PIR or go
to the billboard.com and
click the dollar shave club
banner. All right, Hulu plus everyone.
You probably tried hulu.com
now with Hulu plus,
you can watch your favorite shows anytime,
anywhere.
Hulu plus lets you watch thousands of
hitched to TV shows and a selection of a
claim. Movies on your television or on
the go with your smartphone or tablet.
And it all streams in HD for the
vest. Best viewing experience, uh,
with Hulu plus you can watch your favorite
current TV shows like Saturday night
live community, family,
family guy, sorry, uh,
breaking bad, you know,
uh, the walking dead,
the shows that I like
where people get killed.
And you can also check out exclusive
content including Hulu originals,
like the awesomes starring Snl,
Seth Meyers in moon boy starring
Chris Chris O'Dowd from bridesmaids,
Hulu plus with the original programming
who plus also offers a great selection
of acclaimed films for
only 787 99 a month.
You can stream as many shows and
movies as you want whenever you want.
Right now you can try Hulu
plus for free for two weeks.
When you go to Hulu plus.com/bill
that's a special offer for my listeners.
All right.
Make sure you use Hulu plus.com/bill so
you get the extended free trial and they
will know that we sent you,
go to Hulu plus.com/bill now or click
on the Hulu plus banner on the podcast
page at [inaudible] dot com.
All right. Continuing on.
So this past week, everybody, um,
I actually rented a motorcycle
and live to tell about it.
Um,
I rented during a
weekday, right? And I, uh,
I just went to a party where I knew
there was going to be no cars or anything
like that and it was all these twists
and turns in that type of thing.
And it was, you know, it's just like
was fun, man. It was a lot of fun,
scraped the pegs a couple of times,
scared the shit out of me.
I didn't realize that they give,
you know, so you won't fall down.
That was definitely sent
a jolt through my head.
But um, it was awesome, man.
I gotta tell you, I really,
uh, I really enjoyed it. I
don't know. It's like I said,
it's still nothing compared to buy
a motorcycle or anything like that.
I just wanted to remember what I
learned in the, in the, in the class.
So I ride with a buddy of mine who's
been riding forever and everything went
great the entire fucking time.
I said I did a great job for the amount
of time that I've been riding. You know,
I drove stick shifts my whole life. So
it's the same concept of hardest things.
You have to switch it, you know, with
rather than shifting with your hand,
you know,
you're doing it with the afoot and
rather moving the clutch with your foot,
you do it with your hand.
It's all that type of shit.
But that motorcycle safety class
that I took, I highly, highly,
highly recommend taking
one of those because um,
they really, they help you
with turns. And I mean, like,
I like the shit you have to do on a
motorcycle. When you go into a turn.
It's not like a car, you know, you don't
have to worry about a car tipping over
and you being launched out of it.
Like what you have to do when a car,
you'd have to be basically gone,
I would think over 35 miles an hour,
40 miles an hour,
and then just cut the wheel as hard as
you could to the point you were skidding
sideways, even just to go it on its
side. But even then you're strapped in,
you got metal all around you and airbags.
Um,
so anyways, we wrote, I, I made
him go down and pick up the bike.
I did it as safely as
I could possibly do it,
and I had the time of my fucking life.
So,
and I got the confidence that I actually
rode the bike back to my house, uh,
before I went to bring it back.
And I lived, I live on a, uh,
I live on a hill that's on a turn.
So I came down and I was just like, oh
wait, well how the fuck do I do this?
And I went down and I brought
it up and I'm thinking like,
what do I do with the kickstand?
And then I kinda had it at the
wrong angle and I swear to God,
I tip the bike over at zero miles an hour.
Fucking
ass all do what I was writing for three
hours around turns a whole fucking thing
all the way up to fourth gear down
shift and looking through the turns,
the whole fucking thing did everything
right and then it's zero miles an hour.
I just was at the wrong angle
where if I put the kickstand down,
it was still going to tip over.
And then I tried to overcompensate and
the thing just tipped to the point of no
return and you don't really feel the
weight of the bike until it gets to that
tipping point. I mean, I didn't slam it
then I just basically dropped it down.
It was so fucking embarrassing.
And I bent the, uh, I bent the, uh,
the front brake and I put some
scratches on the fucking thing.
So it ended up being an expensive day
fucking asshole. I was so
embarrassed. It was a Harley too,
so I brought it back down to the place
and they're all, you know, they like, Nah,
it happens, it happens or whatever.
But I just, you know, I could not,
if I should have just gone down there a
little skirt with what's left of my hair
in pigtails, they'd be like, Oh God, I
tried to do is put the kickstand down.
I was really,
it's been a while since I've been that
fucking embarrassed. Like I was, uh,
I felt shame, but other than
that, it was a great time.
I was Billy bad ass for about a,
I don't know,
for a couple of hours
and then, uh, I dunno,
whatever the biggest pussy word you
can come up with. The begins with B
Billy blueberries and a fucking dumb.
Anyways, white blueberries are bad.
And if you stick them in a pie, I had
the urge to make a pumpkin pie this week.
I want to practice before the holidays.
Um,
and I want to smoke a fucking Turkey
this year. I'm throwing fucking down.
You know, that's one of the things
when the holidays come around,
you've got to have something
that you make, you know,
you gotta have your
staple and if you don't,
you got to have some sort of hooch that
you get from somewhere in the middle of
fucking nowhere that you got
to have something special.
You just can't hit be another client
that puts on some ugly sweater and just
shows up and stands there,
eat and everybody else's shit,
drinking all their fucking booze.
You know,
you got to bring something with you.
I think you know what they should,
you should do.
You should have like basically you should
have a pre Thanksgiving party in the
beginning of October,
like a preseason game and then you invite
like 30 people over knowing only 22
are going to make the fucking
roster on thanksgiving.
But don't tell anybody. No, that's
not fair for people. Trial for a team.
They know they're trying out for
a team to do that. There you go.
Then you fucking where one those bill
Bellacheck cutoff hoodies and you see what
people show up with. Just
a suggestion. No big deal.
Um, all right, let's
continue with the sports. Um,
people have been firing off
letters to me lately and uh,
I never sent letters to people.
I never do.
I never like I'll read something
and somebody annoys me.
And I guess the reason why I don't do
it is because I have the outlet of the
podcast or doing standup. So I
never really feel the need. Like,
you know, I gotta I dunno, send this
person like a fucking letter or something,
but I actually sent a letter,
an email,
and I'm not going to name the name cause
I don't, I don't want you guys to like,
I know most of you won't,
but some of you will find out who it is
and then go you stupid cunt age and you
know, the stupid, you know,
write something racist that hour,
whatever.
I just don't want to be a part of that.
But basically this person was writing
an article about this female goaltender,
uh, Briana Scurrey. I hope I said
her last name right. And, um,
yeah, it was really just
awful story. You know,
like she was top of her game playing
for the u s ladies soccer team,
the late nineties. And uh, she went
down to get to, to stop a routine,
a routine save one of those ones.
I think it's from the way it was described
as like kind of rolling fast along
the ground.
She dove down to get it,
scooped it up and had it and uh,
someone on the other team
went to basically try to
kick it out of her hand real
quick and then try to put it in the goal.
But as they will run an over to do that,
the other player's knee struck this woman
Brianna right on the side of her head.
And uh,
you know,
so she kind of gave herself a standing
eight count basically and stood up and
continued on like all athletes do.
She pushed through the pain. So,
unfortunately after a few minutes,
the back of our own player's jerseys,
when she was looking at the numbers
and the names started getting blurry,
started getting fuzzy,
then she started seeing more than one
soccer ball out there and the team could
tell that she was struggling.
And at,
and at the half they took a ride of
the game, sound like a familiar story.
She had, she had a brutal concussion
and ended her career. And now, you know,
she has to stay in like, you
know, a dark apartment. And um,
I don't know if she gets to bed,
spins are getting nauseous,
but the usual type of stuff. So I'm
reading this thing and I was like, Oh God,
another concussion stories.
It's just, I didn't, you know,
I haven't heard a lot of soccer players
having this happened to him, you know,
male or female. Um, so it was
really an interesting article.
And then all of a sudden, I don't know
where this person writes. You know,
it's one of the myths of the mainstream
sports media that concussions belong
only to men.
Most of them football players like,
okay,
I don't even, I can't even wrap my
head around that statement. It's like,
I want to just, let me just
continue reading this. In fact,
studies show that women and girls are
more likely than men and boys to suffer
concussions in sports.
They both play such as soccer,
basketball and baseball, slash, softball.
And in those cases they are also more
likely to suffer and private of far cry
from the attention NFL players command.
Can you fucking believe that that was
one of the most uninformed paragraphs I
think I've ever read on.
Like after I read that I was like,
I don't think this paper USA
Today, I don't think that
they have a sports editor.
I don't even know where to
begin with that. First of all,
to make concussions like a gender issue.
Like I'm not the smartest guy,
but don't we both just have
brains that sit in fluid
in your head.
A blow to the head is a blow to the head.
So I don't know what she's
trying to claim. And I, my,
one of my favorite statements of all time
studies show no footnote to the study
studies show researchers have said,
um,
oh my God. So I actually, I, I,
I'm not going to bore
you and maybe I will,
you want me to read the
letter that I sent her? I,
I wrote no disrespect because
I wanted her to read, you know,
get something to call their attention.
I basically said to suggest that female
athletes are more likely to suffer in
private,
a far cry from the attention NFL players
command when it comes to suffering.
Concussions is astoundingly uninformed.
The attention that NFL players command,
I kept putting that in quotes. She made
him sound like they would divas. Um,
the attention NFL players command has
everything to do with generations of
former NFL players suffering and private
after their careers were over in the
last five years alone.
Three NFL players have committed suicide
by single gunshot to the chest in order
to preserve their brains.
The scientists can figure out more about
the aftermath of playing professional
football.
The attention players command today
was the result of over two decades of
fighting tooth and nail with NFL owners.
In the end,
the only reason the owners gave in was
the irrefutable evidence gained through
examination of brains donated by dead NFL
players that's suffered in private and
then it brought up the class action
suit, but blah, blah blah, blah blah. Um,
Brian Scurry was taken out of that
ramp. Ryan, Briana Scurrey, sorry,
was taken out of the second half of
that soccer game because of all the
suffering and private than NFL players
have endured because of the knowledge
gained by all of those concussed football
players that were told to shake it off
and get back in the game.
This is a major issue in sport.
To see it glossed over and actually turned
into some gender issue is incredibly
irresponsible.
I'm not saying you're a bad person,
but to take such a serious subject and
not make it inclusive of all human beings
and then suggest that one side has it
worse than the other side and more like
fodder for the newlywed game rather than
a series metal. Does medical discussion.
See that? I can be eloquent. I
don't have to trash people. Well,
I can trash them, but I don't have
to write a all the curse words.
You see that at a very tuxedo
kind of vibe there, didn't I?
Unlike this person who wrote
to me. Oh, what a segue.
Ginger scumbag
bill. I've been a fan of
yours for 15 years. Okay,
so you guys got that. This guy has
been a fan of mine for 15 years,
so for 15 years this guy has been falling
me enjoying things that I'm doing.
All right?
This guy's locked in for 15 years.
The people that work hard every day
and spend their hard earned cash.
That's kind of redundant, sir. If you
work hard, then you have harder and cash.
All right? If you've got
an easy job, you know,
and then you'd be spending your
fucking teddy money right built.
Just read the fucking email. All
right? Just having fun. Bill,
I've been a fan of yours for 15 years.
The people that work hard every day and
spend their hard earned cash to see you
have been really disappointed.
This is one of the classic things.
When people complain rather than
just complaining for themselves,
they act like they're standing in front
of like a zillion people and they go
relax,
attention everyone.
I will send the email and we'll
convey all of your feelings.
Get on with your day.
Relax. I will handle it.
So evidently he has like, you know, all
of these people are disappointed in me.
He said, the people that follow
you and made you who you are,
they made me people.
I didn't work hard on stand up.
I was just standing there
and they all said, hey yo,
we have decided to make you and
who you are so sad it be said,
so set it be done.
He said,
you have made dates all around the
country and then cancelled them when
Hollywood calls you to do a part.
That's exactly what happened.
I picked up the phone, I said hello.
They said, this is Hollywood here.
We're calling you to do a part. Say, uh,
the people that go to
your shows and made you,
that made you aren't making a
10th of the money that you make,
but they paid to see you. Hey, ginger boy.
Without these fans, you're illiterate. Ass
would be working at Mcdonald's at best.
Now, I take offense to that, sir. Okay?
Without my fan base, I would not be
working at Mcdonald's. You son of a bitch,
I would be unloading trucks in
a warehouse. Get it straight.
He goes, you're a scumbag. Ba Gee,
you're a scum Baije and I hope every fan
realizes what you are and stops going
to your shows.
I will never listen to your shows or
podcasts again and we'll tell everyone to
do the same.
You are the typical sellout to
Hollywood fucking disappointment.
I know you won't have the balls to
read this on your podcast. Instead,
you will read a letter from a 20 year
old guy confused about his girlfriend's
sex and sexuality.
This is the best part here.
You're a real cunt.
Fuck you and everything you do
as one of the greatest Sendik's, one of
the greatest enemies to any email ever.
Gut. You're a real cunt in the real deal.
If you, if you tip over your country,
you see the stamp of approval from the
current factory and then it's just not
fuck you.
It's fuck you and everything you do.
Even when I go to the grocery
store. Yeah. That too.
Fuck you when you're out apples.
MMM.
Jesus Christ. Sir, you made me,
did I have anything to do?
Did I do anything? Did I work?
Did I not fucking go onstage and eat
my balls? Learning how to do this?
I guess you did I listen,
I just want to thank you for making me
without your hard work of going through.
I mean, I can't imagine
how many, uh, I mean,
how many people live in this country?
I just can't imagine when you're just
going through the macbook trying to figure
out who you've decided will become a
professional comedian. That just is.
And the fact that you also have a day
job during the time where I guess you're
grossly underpaid. I mean, that's
just incredible to me, sir.
What the fuck do you want from me?
Let me ask you this,
okay? If Hollywood called you
and asked you to be in a movie,
you're going to say no.
You're going to say no.
All right. And like, like you told
your mom, hey listen Ma, don't worry.
I'll come over and I'll clean up
your yard this Saturday. All right?
And then all of a sudden Hollywood
comes to Collins says, Hey,
do you want to pretend you're a lot
tougher than you are and getting to a
gunfight and get shot by, I don't
know, whoever your favorite actor is,
you're going to say, no, I have
to go. Uh, I got a stick. What?
You've never broken a fucking,
you know what? Fuck that.
Even like a playoff game comes along.
You've never fucking had to change a
schedule, sir. I had to cancel some dates.
I didn't cancel them. I rescheduled
the fuck. Do you want from me?
You want me to stay in the strip malls
for my entire career telling jokes I did
that. I'm trying to fucking,
you know, and all, all,
all these movies to do is make
more people know who I am.
So more people come out to my shows so
I can keep writing more hours and having
a good time. All right. I don't
even know why I'm talking to you.
You said you're never going to
listen to my shit again, right?
Are you a man of your word after you're
saying, I'm not a man of my word.
If you're actually listened to this, then
you're a fucking hypocrite. All right.
What's a matter?
Huh?
Jesus Christ.
You fucking pissed on your sweat pants
this week or I don't know what the fuck
that was all about.
You didn't even say what it was.
You may dates all around the
country and then cancelled them.
The fuck are you talking about?
I had one tour.
I had to move around and I
fucking did the first two dates.
Then I've made up a one to 3 cents then
and add an another one that wasn't even
on that original tour, so
go fuck yourself. All right.
All the tickets are honored and if he
can't make that date, you get it refunded
Jesus Christ. You know that that
tour that I was going to do,
I was just going to land in Boise,
you know,
jump on a bus and knock them all out
in 10 days now because that whole thing
blew up. Now I've got to get on it. You
know, it's like an extra 10 airplane ride.
You don't hear me bitching
though. Yeah, you fucking cunt.
You're a real cunt. Fuck you. And
everything to do that was worth it.
That was worth them getting mad. That's
fucking tremendous, sir. You know what?
As much as you do, you disappointed
me. You're a real disappointment.
You fucking jerk off.
You've liked me for 15 years.
One cancel fucking Gig and now you,
now you're saying fuck me and everything
I do. I make that Pumpkin pie this week.
You save fuck the pie too. That's a
part of it. You're saying fuck America.
If you're saying fuck punk,
punk a pie.
Okay,
but I got here I am a real cunt.
I, you know, I can't argue that.
Okay,
uh, hit us up to somebody.
Please put that on a tee shirt.
You're a real cunt.
Fuck you and everything you do.
Just to have that just
out there just written.
That's really tremendous. Oh, by the way,
if you guys want to read an unbelievable
book, I told you I was reading that,
uh,
that book data Al Jourgensen from
Ministry wrote, I just finished it, man.
I'm telling you some of the most insane
fucking stories you ever going to read.
I'll give you one line,
one descriptive line from one of the
stories was basically he was talking about
like these basically talking about three
of the craziest people he's ever met.
And he was talking about this one,
a tick guy who met this
lunar chick chick groupie.
And the line was he,
he brought her into the bathroom but
fucked her and then flushed your closed
down the toilet.
It was fucking insane thing
I've ever heard in my life.
So then she comes walking out of
the bathroom, she's like, oh my God.
Like what's with your friend?
What am I supposed to wear?
So they took a tablecloth of the table
and they cut a hole in it and they made a
dress out of it and then tied it off
around the middle and then she was just
went on tour with them, happy
as a clam. Um, all right,
that's me butchering that story.
Just imagine 200 and what was it,
273 pages of that phenomenal,
phenomenal fucking read.
And it also exposed me to all this
amazing music in the 80s that I completely
missed on because,
you know,
I was 12 in 1980 so right around,
I don't know,
you know,
you don't listen to good music when you're
in your teenage years unless you have
really well informed older siblings.
Like the youngest kid in the family
usually knows what to listen to.
You know, if he has older brothers
who were like eight, nine,
10 or sisters that are old,
like eight years old.
There was something that could usually
hip his friends to, hey, you know,
just some of the, the music
that ministry was making. Right.
And to think that I was arguing
with people about whether, uh,
you know, Motley Crue was better than
poison, not shitting on those bands,
but I'm just saying, cause I like
both those beds for what they are.
I like them, you know, I love Motley
Crue and poison. It took me a while.
I mean they came out with makeup and
all the chicks liked him and you know,
so it's, you, they were easily hateable
so it was bon Jovi and all that aluminum.
Oh my God, he's so dreamy. You know
who's going to consumed. Right.
They just stuck to you when that shit,
but if you just look at him,
what the fuck they were doing, you know,
it's all right. Right. But anyways,
I had no idea. I had no fucking idea.
And I still don't, if you guys actually,
you know,
you know a lot about that type of music
or you've got some punk bands because I
missed out on all of that shit.
And um,
I'd really like to go back and listen
and work my way through that. Um,
the road less traveled of eighties
music because I didn't know any better.
All right. Okay. Continuing on.
What the fuck is this?
Oh,
this is from last week and of course I
just reduced the damn thing and rather
than a, is that the right word? Reduced
it. And you're cooking here bill.
Um, oh by the way, all
things comedy has a,
was starting to do a
monthly show down at Largo,
Largo on La Cienega and we have a show,
um,
this Tuesday night. All things comedy.
Um, the podcast is all the network.
Me and Al Madrigal, we're going to be
down there and knocking out another show.
We had a great time.
Um,
last month show was one of the best
standup shows I've been on in a long time.
Just as far as not only the level of
comedy, standup comedy, just the diverse,
um, the d the, I don't know, just,
it was a really great mix of
comics that were on that one.
So we're hoping we can do it again.
And, uh, it's also a great, you know,
if you see our diversity comedians are,
so are the podcasts on all things comedy.
And I really appreciate everybody that's
already bought tickets to come on down.
It's going to be eight o'clock on Tuesday
night. Ra plowing ahead, plowing ahead.
What else do we got here? Oh, you
don't have to fucking bugs me.
I went to Toronto again, which is such a
great city. They're all Montreal, Toronto,
Vancouver.
I just have a great time when I'm up there
and I can't wait to run through that,
that country up there. And, uh,
March of next year is when
we were shooting to a tour
of that country. But, uh,
every time I go to Toronto,
I always go,
I gotta go to the El Mocambo cause
that's where Stevie Ray Vaughn, uh,
he recorded that,
uh,
I guess live at the El Mocambo
and I fucking still didn't
get to do at this time,
just didn't have enough God damn
times and knowing. So anyways,
let's plow ahead here. A Mother Teresa
is what? This next one is called. Bill,
you mentioned in your
youtube tour of Boston,
something to the effect of that someday
someone is going to write a tell all
about Mother Teresa. Yeah, I was just
joking around. He said someone did.
Here's the link.
Um,
here's the link to the documentary
based on the book. Quick summary.
She was a cunt,
had come on
a 100%.
She wasn't a,
she wasn't helped some people out.
Jesus Christ. Oh Way. You know what,
if Mother Teresa can be called at current,
I guess I should take the fact that
I'm a real cunt. You're a real,
can't you realize that? Um,
all right. College stadium.
Oh Hey. By the way, anybody,
uh, anybody ever been to Italy?
Um,
I'm going to go there to get acclimated
to the time before I do the European
tour. I'm just going to, I just
said fuck it. You know, why?
Just go over there and bang out a bunch
of shows. I never get to see anything. Um,
other than the backs of comedy clubs.
I want to go see some shit.
So I've decided that I'm going to
go over, you know, a couple, two,
three days over in Italy in a,
I'm leaning towards going in
Naples. Anybody, anybody at all,
if you've ever been there,
can you give me some places to go?
I want to go see a fucking opera
over there. Get all dressed up,
bring a little handkerchief, cry
like a little girl, you know,
take the whole fucking thing in.
You have some sketti and then I'm off.
I'm off on my run.
So if you guys have any suggestions
I would really appreciate it. Um,
Oh and speaking of which is really just
a lot of announcements this week, uh,
had a lot of shit happened.
Thank you to whoever brought me the uh,
Ken Burns the war on DVD.
That was ridiculously generous of you
did not have to do that and believe me,
I will be watching that once again.
The second I get through all of Ken
Burns is the rest of them because I've
already seen that one.
But I've done,
I definitely want to watch it again cause
it's like such a history lesson just
as far as you can just see. Oh first
we went here, then we went here.
This is where this island is.
This is where the battle of the
bulge was really fucking fascinating.
So thank you for that. Um, all
right. College Stadium Bill. I am
a group of my buddies and I,
uh,
want to take a trip somewhere random
and catch a good college football game.
Not necessarily just the game with a team,
but also a great stadium.
We're all in our mid
twenties and live in Florida.
Ben To plenty of gators and
seminals games. I was going to say,
Jesus Christ where you don't have to
travel. You've got it right there. Uh,
which colleagues called stadium would
you suggest we make our trip to somewhere
that serves beer during the game would
be a plus, but not a requirement. Um,
I don't know about, I don't
know that the NCAA, any of the,
the college stadium serve beer.
Um,
I never noticed that they didn't at the
rose bowl because I was so fucking shit
faced that I didn't need any more alcohol.
So I never tell,
I'm usually trying to buy something to
absorb all the booze that I've adjusted.
Um, but uh, I don't think that you can,
that's what my friends
had been telling me.
We were just in college station and um,
they didn't sell it there. They didn't
sell it at the Lsu game. So anyways,
in other words,
what's the Best College stadium atmosphere
that you've been to that you would
recommend visiting? Uh, love the podcast,
blah, blah, blah. Go Fuck Yourself. Okay.
Um, yeah, I liked it.
You phrased it that way cause I'm
only going by what I've done. Um,
I got to tell you,
Lsu,
Alabama in Baton Rouge was,
uh, even if you, you're
not a fan of the sport,
you realize that you're at
something legendary and special.
Just SCC football in general,
like the level that's being played at
there in another golden age of that
conference.
And I,
and I'm blown away by how well
behaved and polite the fans are.
Because you know, the stereotype of
southerners, you know, walk around.
Hello, what are you doing over here? Yeah.
We don't walk your cat around here. No,
it's nothing like that.
It's not the,
most of that shit is just from watching
Mississippi burning and Hollywood's
version. I'm not saying
that those guys don't exist.
All right.
It's kind of like a,
that Ray Donovan character,
like that character is
supposed to represent like
everybody on the east coast,
basically the northeast, that that's
how people are, you know, he come,
he come Numa family again
and I'll fucking kill you.
You know that bullshit all the time.
And like,
like everybody down south is
fucking playing a washboard.
It's not like that all at all. I
thought the two were raw, you know,
they throw down the level in
college station. They were amazing.
Um, this is what I would do. I would pick,
if you're a fan of any other team,
go into a home game against one of
their big rivals is awesome. It's, it's,
it's fun to go to a game where you
actually give a shit about the team. Um,
so you kind of have a dog in the
fight or if you're going to go, uh,
go see someone really special,
you know,
like some once in a generation kind of
play like Johnny football comes around
like,
you know,
like that guy is going to be a legend
regardless of what he does in the football
NFL,
whether he makes it a nod,
it's to be able to see and like I saw
that guy in his sophomore year play
against Alabama and a and a 49,
42 game. That's pretty cool.
So if I was you just to look in,
it's saving money and that type of shit,
you really don't need to go anywhere.
You're down there in SCC country anyways,
I would go see Alabama.
I go to the Alabama Auburn game even
though Auburn's non not as good as they
were. Uh, with Cam Newton,
I go to one of those ones.
For some reason the Florida Georgia game
in Jacksonville does not interest me
because that it's an away
game for everybody because
they were worried about the
behavior of people.
I want to see their behavior.
I like when does one
team going into a hostel,
a hostile environment.
So you know,
like I saw Texas,
Oklahoma at the cotton bowl and
that was awesome and it was great,
legendary steam to go to, but there
was definitely something missing.
There was no, you know, you're in
our house now. Vibe was not there.
Um, so I dunno, Jesus, am I fucking
meandering this week or what?
So I, if I was you, I would either go
to Tuscaloosa, I go to Baton Rouge,
um,
Tennessee for some reason it
looks fucking insane to me.
Tennessee I think would be insane just
because that's in Knoxville is just the
middle of fucking nowhere and
there's nothing else to do.
But to go absolutely ape shit at a
Tennessee volunteers game and just watched
them throwing down.
I'm telling you half the fucking show is
being outside the stadium and watching
how hardcore these people party,
um,
or and cook and all that. I mean, they
don't get drunk and belligerent like a,
at least I haven't seen that yet.
And it's probably a lot of people rolling
their fucking ice. But uh, you know,
it seems like the violent fans
are on the coasts. I Dunno.
Like if we're going to get stomped
or fucking stabbed or shot,
especially out here in
California, um, I don't know when,
if you Mosey on up to somebody smoker,
all you do,
throw them a couple of compliments.
Next thing you know,
you've got something smoked sitting on
a plate, they'll fucking hook you up.
That they're great,
they're great people south get the south
gets such a bad fucking reputation.
And I know there's the racism and
there's all that fucking shit,
but unfortunately, that
racism is everywhere, at least
as far as my travels. So,
uh,
the end of the day,
those fuckers cook better than they
do in the up north at a football game.
Anyways, so there you go. There's
my long winded fucking answer.
Alright. Hey, Billy bets.
Couple of weeks ago you said you don't
want to see the coliseum because it's too
touristy. I implore you to
change your mind. Oh, here it is.
Uh, you yourself, you
owe, you owe yourself.
You left out the o what? You, you, you,
yourself love to go to different
arenas and stadiums in America.
If I remember correctly,
you said you wanted to go to every
major sporting arena in the u u s yeah.
You know this argument.
I know what you mean.
As well as major college stadiums to
call a Siem is one of the oldest stadiums
in the world and the most famous in
history in the history of the world,
50,000 people could sit in it.
It had a retractable roof,
giant pieces of fabric that were
controlled by men to block the sun out.
Jesus correre and I'm sold.
I'm going.
And some historical texts claim that
it was even filled with water in naval
battles were reenacted for the public.
Jesus Christ.
You know what was,
was that the greatest empire of all time?
Wow. They put the gluttony
even in it even, you know,
I can only speak my country,
but even like the level of big
gulps and how fat people are now,
even with that, we don't have puking
rooms here. Like they had rooms.
The Romans had rooms just for like
after you've gorged yourself will,
you just went in and yakked you know,
and can you imagine the poor conquered
people that had to clean that fucking
thing out every couple of hours.
Okay.
And An air condition. Puke Room. Wow.
Jesus Christ. I'd fight a line in a
second not to fucking have to do this,
just get it over with. And he said yes,
it is very a very touristy place to go,
but it is the most famous arena
and the history of the world.
It was built nearly 2000 years
ago and still stands today.
I guarantee you that I saw in Dallas
won't be standing in 2000 years.
Ps, my girlfriend watched your episode of
new girl and said it was the first time
she ever saw you not yelling,
Jesus, I'm getting pounded this week,
but I can't. I can't argue any of it.
I am a real cut and I do scream a lot.
Um, all right, well maybe, maybe I, I'll,
I'll do that. Like, look, I
have, I have plans of, uh,
for the rest of my standup career of,
of continuing to expand
my tours through your,
through Europe and uh, wherever
else they'll have me, Australia and,
and I want to see it, man. I'm only
here once. I want to see it. And, uh,
Italy, I don't plan on just going to one
time, like there's all these different,
so all these years of watching a Mario
Batali who gets my vote is the coolest
fucking redhead on TV.
All right. Um, we just,
his knowledge and passion for a,
that country in their food and
all the different places to go.
Um, he's made me want to go to
so many different parts of Italy,
so I'm just starting with this one.
I guess I should start with Rome,
but it just seemed hacky to
go there. So, uh, I dunno,
I mean the game plan always was to tor
and make a little bit of money and Europe
and then blow all of it
in some awesome country.
So that's basically,
and it probably won't be making that
much money in Europe because people don't
really know me at, uh, but you
know how much this spaghetti costs.
Yeah. All right. How about
a little advertising here?
All right. He voice everyone.
If you're an entrepreneur
and a customer calls,
do you want it to seem like
you're in a high rise window view?
Fancy pants office.
Oh,
do you want them to know that you just
sitting there and your underwear and a
one bedroom apartment, you
know, all sweaty on a Futon,
that's not good for business. What do
you do if you can't afford the high rise?
Go to he voice with the voice.
You can create the appearance of an
entire building, sales, customer support,
tech support, you name it. It's
going to seem like you got it.
Give your customers the royal
treatment with the voice.
A voice will forward your business
calls to your home, mobile,
or any number you choose.
Wherever you are, he voice,
we'll find you don't have time to take
a call. No biggie. It's routed as, uh,
is relative to your voicemail.
And you can read it at your convenience
as an email he voiced not only gives you
an edge over your competition,
it will take away the edge of the big
companies have over you right now.
And now you can try he
voice for free for 30 days.
Go to [inaudible] dot com or just go to
the podcast page at [inaudible] dot com
and click on the voice banner. That's
the voice, everybody. And finally,
legal zone. A lot of pride comes along
with starting your dream business.
Doesn't it?
Heart swells up a little tear in your eye.
You push it back down because you're
a man, you're not allowed to cry.
And if you're a woman, you feel like
you're competing against men, right?
So you got to push it down or maybe
you don't. I don't know. But anyways,
either way, this works for both
people, both sexes, Male, female,
Hermaphrodite, legal, zoom, everyone.
Uh, let's get back to the copy, shall we?
But think about the stress you'll feel
if you don't take the right steps to
legally protect your business and
personal assets from the beginning.
That's why I me Billy red face.
Recommend legal zoom.com
during the past 12 years,
over a million business owners of trusted
legal zoom to help start their own
businesses.
Legal Zoom will save you a lot of time
and a pile of money on startup costs.
Plus they'll provide solutions to
help you run a successful business.
Legal Zoom can provide self help services
at your specific direction or connect
you with an attorney,
but they are not a law firm.
Just go to legalzoom.com today to see
what's right for you. Form an LLC,
get a Dba,
incorporate or form a nonprofit
all starting at just $99 plus.
You'll save even more when you enter
bur bur are in the referral box at chuck
checkout. That's legalzoom.com Promo
Code [inaudible]. One more time. Legal,
zoom.com Promo Code Bar.
There we go.
Bill, here's the dilemma. You're hanging
out at your house wanting a snack.
Your lady says she's going to bake
you some cookies. What a sweetheart.
Absolutely. What a champ. Uh,
she brings the cookies out. And to your
surprise, they are dick shaped cookies.
Think Bachelorette party complete
with sprinkles for pubes, et Cetera.
You're hungry and the
cookies are sure to be tasty,
but they are shaped like dicks. Do
you eat all the cookies? Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Uh, you
know what we have here, sir?
That right there is a classic
example of some Code Lotion.
That right there is some fucking
cold lotion. You said you're hungry,
you want a snack, and your woman goes,
oh, go make you some cookies. You're like,
Holy Shit. I've finally found
a woman that's still cooks.
It doesn't feel like you're
taken away her right to vote.
If she goes out and does that for you,
phenomenal. She brings the cookies in.
You're all excited and you look down
and you've got a bowl of Cox. Um,
do you eat the cookies? Um, well,
do you plan to run for
office? They sir, if you do,
while I probably wouldn't work,
I would say you should take a picture of
yourself eating the bowl of dicks that
way no one could ever say
that you're homophobic,
but somebody could run a smear campaign
and say that your marriage was a sham
and just have you get out and they picked
the worst picture you with your eyes
half closed and the most enjoyable
ecstasy. Look on your face.
Sugar rush as you stick in a dick in your
mouth. I know that could go either way.
Do you eat the cookies?
Um,
a listen man. A fucking cookie is a
cookie. I need them if they tasted good.
Um, hey, when those things get stale,
does that mean they're kinda that
he'd get like a wrecked? Sorry,
that was a stupid Dick Jokes.
Um,
do you eat the cookies? I don't
know about, you know what?
I'd have to know what your,
if your girlfriend did that
to be fucking hilarious.
Like, hey, you want some cookies?
And that comes out with a bullet.
Dicks Dick Cookies. That's
fucking hilarious. At which
point I'd eat all of them.
Okay.
But, uh, yeah, there's no way she wasn't
trying to be funny. You know what?
You should laugh when you should eat.
And with a big glass of milk,
which a metaphorically is just color.
If you get like the 0% fat, you
should just go all out with it. Ah,
that's fucking gross. I never liked sex
jokes with food. Isn't that disgusting?
That I grocery on? I apologize.
I apologize to you on this
wonderful Monday. Hey,
by the way, everybody, I bet you sitting
there going like, you know, fuck my life.
I want to know what bill's
doing this weekend. I know
you're not, but let's just,
just appease my ego.
Appease the ego of a real cunt here.
Um, I'm going to be at the Chicago,
the legendary Chicago theater. This, uh,
this Saturday night for not one, but
two shows. Who am I bringing along?
None other than master chef.
Slash Rosebowl tailgate
lesson legend Jason Law head.
Who's Cleveland browns one this
week. All right, so check out law,
head court, law heads court,
his, uh, his podcasts. Um,
you'll get to hear something that
you haven't heard in a long time,
which is probably a happy
Cleveland browns fan. Um,
I am a closet Cleveland browns fan
cause I think they have one of the best
fucking uniforms in the league.
And uh,
and they were great when I was a kid
and the 80s, I love those browns teams,
that fucking municipal stadium,
just that it just was on NFL films,
municipal stadium when it was overcast
and it was cold and it may be snowed a
little bit now. The field was
muddy. They had just with,
it was one of the last great
football stadiums out there.
Even though I know it was built for
baseball was probably a terrible place to
see a game and a lot of ways.
Um,
I was a fan of Brian Sipe and the
cardiac kids and all of that shit.
So I always root for those
fuckers. Um, so anyways, yeah,
I'll be at the uh, the Chicago
theater unfortunately, um,
coming in and coming right back out,
flying in the day of and then leaving.
I wanted to try and maybe take it
and I think Northwestern's at home,
I know Notre Dame is at home.
He's going to try to drive over there,
but I think it's too long a
fucking drive. But uh, anyways,
if you guys have any suggestions
on a great place to eat,
I don't want to get deep dish pizza.
I don't want to do that.
How about more like a steak place?
That deep dish pizza man.
Like you always order one. You
like, I got this, I got this.
And then it becomes like a man
versus food moment. Um, it is,
it is delicious. Do
you know what? Fuck it.
How about a steak place in a good
place to get a deep dish? Pizza.
You know what you guys should do?
You guys should try to see how fucking
fat you could make me just subtly,
just all get together.
Like that guy suggested like you're
all in communication with each other,
you know,
and now that I've canceled those dates,
why don't you guys try to get together
and try to make me a fet? Freckled fuck.
Alright, hater. Alright Billy tit. Rag.
I don't even know what it, what is
it? Tit Rec. Is that a worn out bra?
Um, I, I need some advice on a
hater. Alright, I'm 20 years old.
Hey, that guy called it check. That
guy who called me a ginger scumbag,
he called it.
That's at least he called
the age at somebody 20 years
old was going to write it.
I'm 20 years old and I've been pretty
shy and self conscious for my entire life
until recently. That's
understandable. Surf.
I was a well within the tortoise
shell until I was 23. Um,
he says,
I've started to just say fuck it.
It doesn't matter what anyone else thinks.
That's a great thing. Good for you.
You said it, it feels great, but
it's hard though. Uh, I'm no expert.
I got a lot.
I've got a lot more confidence and now
I ha I now have one of my first haters.
Well, that's good. You
know what most people hate?
Most people hate watching somebody
enjoy themselves or be successful.
So he must either he knew you or she
knew you before when you were shy and now
is seeing you start to come out,
come into your own,
and it's making that person
feel left behind or, uh,
they're just straight across the board.
Anybody having a good time and enjoying
themselves, they try to knock them down.
Um, anyways, he says this kid
goes to my college of 600 people.
We go out as a big group most
nights and he's always there.
Once in a while he'll throw a comment
my way and I just ignore it. Uh,
last night I was talking to a girl and
he comes up behind and puts my hood over
my head.
I turned around and stared at him for
10 seconds and he just looked away.
This kid's pathetic.
I've just been ignoring him and trying
not to give a fuck that doesn't work with
bullying, surf that doesn't. Um, he says,
I definitely don't want to fight
the kid and ruined my reputation,
but I also don't want to
look like a little bitch.
I figured you might know what to say,
seeing that you deal with hecklers all
the time. Thanks. Um, first of all, hey,
you don't have to hang out with this kid.
MMM.
You know this,
unfortunately,
this is not the first one of these kinds
of people that's going to be in your
life.
You have to,
mmm.
You got to pay attention,
especially when you're younger,
because you kind of wide open
because you just, you know,
you just started your parents' house,
you starting to learn shit on your own.
And a lot of times if you came
from a dysfunctional home,
you'll actually surround yourself with
the same, kind of, can't see exact cut.
Sweet.
When you yelled at your parents
and you walk out, you actually end up
rebuilding that exact same structure.
Now that's not my, that's obviously
I've heard that, you know,
from people who are intelligent and
I actually went out and did that.
So what you have to do, you've got
to cut the cancer out. All right?
You don't need to be around this guy.
You having a good time.
He coming into your own. You're talking
to the ladies, you having a good time.
So, uh, no. If he does something like
that to you again, yeah. You got to,
you have to, at some point you've got to
step to the kid and just be like, dude,
is there some sort of a problem here?
You know?
And considering you just stared
at him and he looked away, I,
I pretty much think he's going
to back down. But, uh, you know,
if you've got to do what you gotta do,
if you've got to have a fight,
you got to have a fight. It's
not a bad thing, you know,
it's just nowadays with lawsuits and
all these youtube videos and shit,
kids used to settle shit
amongst themselves, so, uh,
you might have to do that.
I hope you don't.
MMM.
But yeah, I, I would not ignore
him. I would not ignore him.
I would, uh, you know, if you don't
want to go to the physical route,
I would just pick out something, um,
that looks bad on him physically.
And I would bring that up. I would go,
I would go right for the fucking juggler
with that kid.
This is zillion different ways to do it
and I'm afraid to tell you which way to
do it because if it goes wrong,
then you know the way
everybody gets sued nowadays,
just know I'm a fucking moron. But, um,
I do know that if you're going to keep
running into the same person and they're,
they're,
they're overstepping a boundary with you,
ignoring them does not make them go away.
You know,
like that shit they say if
you run into a black bear,
just stand still and ignore it. It'll go
away. They don't, okay. So you have to,
uh, you got to address
it. He could say anything,
anything to whatever's
name is, hey, what's up?
You going to be in a country
mood again this night?
You know,
can you do me a favor and maybe rub one
out before you come over here with your
frustrated fucking energy?
Something like that. I don't know,
except don't start it. When you
say energy a energy. Um, I dunno.
I Dunno if you know how to fight. If
you know how to fight, uh, you know,
I'm not saying to do it,
but uh,
there is a reason God allowed
you to ball up your fist.
Hey, if God didn't want us
to punch anybody in the face,
what did he have blessed us with fish.
He's going amazing thing about your hand.
Now we can correct somebody or fucking
choke him to death.
Just the options. That's why I don't
think he's, he's going to judge it.
You could fucking really do
whatever you want. You know,
you're going to fucking just
give people that. The, the, the,
I've been doing a bit about this,
how you going to give people freedom
of choice and then you're going to get
upset when they make the wrong choices.
You're going to make them flawed
and then you're going to get mad.
I don't understand that. I
really don't. All right. Anyways,
that's the podcast for this week,
everybody. I hope you had a good time. Ah,
just to let you know this week,
once again,
I'm going to be in Chicago theater and
then I have a after that and I could,
I can tell you one guy
who's not going to be there,
that guy from earlier this
week, I lost one. Everybody.
He's not even listening to this right
now. Um, anyways, you know what?
I should get the email.
The guy from the past week,
you've got all pissed off
about the El Paso one.
I've got to get that from my guy,
uh, helps me with all his shit.
I should let them know
that it's been rescheduled,
that he'd get his money back and all that.
I still feel bad that he drove four hours.
I knew that was going to fucking
happen. Anyways, here we go.
Um, October 3rd, I'm
going to be October 2nd.
The reschedule show in El Paso
is going down. It's going down.
All right.
And I will try to do something extra
special to make up for the fact that all
these people drove out there
and then it fucking rained,
which was beyond my control. And,
uh, you know, it's fucked up.
I had such a good time driving from El
Paso to San Antonio that I think I'm
actually going to drive from La
to El Paso. It's a 12 hour drive,
which is a, that's nothing,
that's nothing to, uh,
I've been doing the road for a long time.
I already know how I'm going to break
it up, break it up, say break it up. Uh,
all right.
October 3rd,
I'll be at the San Jose Center
for the performing arts.
October 4th paramount theater in Seattle,
Washington.
We are not allowed is um,
October 5th, I'll be at the celebrity
theater in Phoenix, Arizona.
That is in the round. All of
those are going to be, uh,
just amazing venues and just
really going to be fun shows.
I got all this new shit that
I, I, I've been working on.
A bunch of stuff is coming together.
I'm excited to be doing my act,
so I'm thrilled that you
guys are coming out. Um,
despite the fact that I'm a real
cunt. All right, there you go.
And that's the podcast. Here's the wrap
up everybody. Now that the show is over.
Do me a favor. Don't forget to go to on
my podcast page. And if you could have,
go to Amazon and buy something.
If you'd like to help out this podcast
and the wounded warriors project,
just click on the Amazon banner.
It doesn't cost you any extra money.
They kicked me a little, a
little. Uh, thanks a lot.
Little How's your father there?
And uh, then I kicked part of that
over to the wounded warriors project.
Everybody fucking wins. Um, and that's it.
And the rumor has it that the podcast t
shirts are done and that I'm going to be
picking them up this week.
So get ready for those for next week.
And lastly, but not leastly, not leastly,
don't forget to sign up for your free
trial of Hulu Plus Hulu plus lets you
binge on thousands of tits
shows anytime, anywhere. Td, PC,
smartphone or tablet.
It's a, it's awesome man.
Support this podcast and get an
extended free trial of Hulu plus,
when you go to the podcast page at
[inaudible] dot com and click on the Hulu
plus banner or go to Hulu plus.com/bill
that's Hulu plus.com/bill once again,
thank you to everybody. Listen to
this podcast. Have a great week.
Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you next Monday.