Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
Monday,
uh,
February 3rd,
2014.
How the hell are you or how's it going?
I'm a little bit handicapped this week
because my internet isn't working.
I Dunno why. I Dunno what happened. I
hit the little reset button, you know,
you'd take out the little pin
and you stick it in the side.
You do a little fucking five count and
you sit there staring at the God damn
lights, Blinky, blinky,
blinky, and then what happens?
So it's supposed to all be good.
Well, not this week. I don't have any.
So if you think my reading is bad when
I'm reading it off a nice giant computer
screen, whether you're here this week,
when I'm reading off my fucking iPhone.
Oh wait till you hear it.
Um, all right, well let's get down to it.
How about that fucking Superbowl?
Was that awesome or what?
I'm speaking as a patriots fan by the way.
Um,
I gotta be honest.
Like if Peyton Manning,
he won his second super bowl and uh,
then he had to, and Brady had three,
then that's stupid ass debate
is going to start again,
which I have not heard
since Peyton, uh, lost,
or I should say the colts lost when they
played the saints and I didn't want to
fucking hear it. All right. And I love it.
So all you wa Peyton manning fans for
all these years who've been telling me
that fucking Peyton's better than Brady.
Look how many
fucking October. Um, you know,
it was a classic, a classic, uh,
Peyton manning stat yesterday is despite
the fact that they got the living shit
kicked out of him,
he still set the record for most
completions in a Superbowl game,
right?
He completed 33 passes,
33 passes. So you gotta be like Jesus
Christ. What he throw for 500 yards,
400. At least 33 you don't
need through for 280 yards.
That's less than nine yards a catch.
It was 8.7 yards a catch thinking it
Dunkin down the damn field and he got half
of those fucking yards in the,
uh,
the end of the third quarter when
Seattle went to like a fucking prevent,
just gave them the middle of the field
and gave him those six fucking points,
which pissed me off. I wanted
them to shut them out. Right.
It's embarrassing how much I
root against Peyton cause I,
it's like it has nothing
to do with the guy.
I think he's a great fucking
quarterback was just what I really,
I'm doing as I'm hating on Peyton is if
I can be a am I have two white to use
that expression as I dislike
Peyton manning is I am.
Um, um, it's,
it's really just all the sports fans that
I've run into over the years who just
with Peyton Manning,
it was always individual stats and
then blaming everybody around them.
The coaching, the defense to ready
engage, well, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Paula fucking crap. Give me a God
damn break. Give me a fucking break.
Did you see that?
Look on his face.
About three quarters of the way through
the first quarter in my family that is
known as Peyton face.
And that's when he starts pouting and
he gets frustrated and he gets upset and
he can't have your fucking
later looking like that.
Now nobody on ESPN is going to say it.
None of them are going to fucking say
that shit because they fucking dropped
down at the stats God and suck it's
Dick Everyday on fucking sports center.
They don't watch the game.
All right.
None of those people on ESPN or even human
beings, they walk in as human beings,
right?
And then something happens,
they drill into their head and they
stick a chip in there and then they just
become like these, you
know, like, I don't think,
I only think like their lip should move.
I think like their jaws should just
open and close like one of those wooden
puppets,
you know,
those ones that are dressed like
those guards there and the nutcrackers
okay.
Right. That's what, that's what the
one that ran credit rock got robbed.
They should just be doing that shit.
[inaudible].
Um,
I can't even tell you.
I had no idea how hard I was
rooting for Seattle until the game
fucking started because I thought,
you know,
as you guys all know how much I
hated that stupid 12th man and like,
you know what have been a great drinking
game was how many times Joe Buck said
it is really loud here,
right?
With the stupid sound,
a meter and all of that shit.
And I actually got a lot of
people on Twitter were given
me shit going. Yeah. How,
how dumb do you feel now?
I never shit on Seattle.
I never said they were bad team. If you
listened to my podcast, you've dumb cunt.
I said it was yours to lose.
I bet on you guys to win it.
But that doesn't change. And even your
championship does not change that.
That 12th man thing and everybody
dressing up like characters and bring in
fucking new year's whistles to the
Goddamn game is not the dumbest thing that
I've,
embarrassing embarrassing ball washing
thing I've ever seen in my fucking life.
The 12th man stinks.
You have nothing to do with the victory.
Despite what the players and
the owners are going to say.
They all make millions
because of your dumb ass.
That's why they say a nice shit to you.
All right.
Okay.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Jury think there's some running back and
the other huddle as he's listening to
the play going,
you know,
I'd really like to execute this play
the way we have all week in practice,
but golly, golly, is that crowd loud?
Um, but congratulations to the
true fans of the Seattle Seahawks.
The real ones, the real ones, the
ones who showed up when they suck too.
The ones who when they got better,
didn't go out and buy a bunch of shit and
start dressing up like fucking a green
Ben Franklin or whatever the fuck those
people were doing in the stance. Um,
I gotta ask you, be honest,
Seattle Seahawk fans,
now that you actually have something to
crow about, pun intended, you know, don't,
now that you actually have a Superbowl
trophy, you guys are actually champions.
You can actually sing champions.
Now.
Doesn't that loud things seem a
little fucking ridiculous? Didn't,
that just kind of seem like,
you know that mother that can admit that
our kids not talented so they got to
like somehow come up with everybody
gets a trophy, everybody gets a ribbon.
You know what you guys have
created up there I hope is over.
Not as far as like your
run on on championships.
I'd never wished that against you,
but as far as that loud horseshit, um,
if Kansas City next year tries
to break the record again,
if that whole fucking thing starts like
who is the loudest crowd and I guarantee
it it will. I can't say it guy. It
wouldn't surprise me if it what?
It is embarrassing.
You have your Superbowl trophy
for the love of fucking God.
Please stop looking each other
in the street going 12th man.
Okay.
Was that really even a congratulations?
Uh,
I was losing my fucking
mind watching that game.
I absolute lot of people, I guess
it didn't like the game or whatever.
Thought it was boring.
I fucking loved that game.
That game was the biggest
fucking beat down.
I'm trying to think if it was as bad.
This is bad for like Bronco fans.
I'm not rubbing this in be this really
has to disk goes back to the Patriots
cults like 10 fucking years ago when
Brady had three rings and Peyton had none
and will
monetary about, you know, [inaudible]
he's got the runes blow four,
I got its start team. I got to pills in
her own. Their stories got, Ooh, you bulls
right.
These fucking losing every year
and the first goddamn round.
Um, anyways, but last week I
hope you got an outpour. Um,
people who didn't give a fuck
about the game. I hope you, um,
you took my advice and you let
the game go for 90 minutes.
90 minutes is the magic number.
That is the magic number.
If you want to avoid everything and
actually watch the game and be on the edge
of your fucking seat,
provided if it's a good game is
you let it go for 90 minutes,
90 minutes you're hanging
outside, you'd drink it, bears,
you're doing whatever the fuck you doing,
hanging with like three,
four other people tops who
also into the game. All right.
We come in,
we sit down and we just
start when everybody shut
their phones off so we don't
know anything, right? Press play.
And then for the rest of the game,
we didn't watch one commercial.
We didn't have to sit through one
challenge flag. Anytime anybody got hurt.
We fast forward to it. We fast forward
through the entire fucking halftime show.
Didn't see any of it.
All we saw was the game.
And the second it ended and the coaches
were walking out and they'd go out.
All right, well let out a
little, we'll play catch shut.
We shut the fucking game off.
Didn't watch one second on ESPN.
Nothing.
I'm guaranteeing you.
Everybody there was going,
that's like one of the most enjoyable
Superbowl experiences I ever had.
It was fucking great. Anytime they cut
down to Pam Oliver, that other chick,
you just fast forward the whole fucking,
it was tremendous.
Absolutely tremendous. Um, but anyways,
let's talk about the fucking game.
So anyways,
the rest of the world is 90 minutes ahead
of us and we're still downstairs. Um,
you know,
out my back yard smoking
a pork shoulder right?
I made one of my famous apple pies. Law
heads. Fucking kill it in on my grill.
You want to talk about
losing your man card?
I had another man come over my house
and smoke a pork shoulder on my grill.
I couldn't believe I woke up this morning.
My wife was still next to me.
Do you realize like in the south like I
would legally be considered a homosexual
if I did something like that?
I know.
I fucking know and ever since
I'm telling you right now,
I ain't no man who locked himself.
The person foresee allows another
man come on fucking smoke on his grip
grilling. That's okay. Smoking.
That's a whole other thing.
You know what I'm saying?
I wouldn't be surprised if
not only if he's wanting them,
them a a a homeo tack.
Sexuals if fees also
one of them terrorist,
he's probably building a dirty bomb
shape like a dick. That's all I'm saying.
Yeah. I just, you know,
one of the keys to being successful in
life is knowing what you suck at and then
being able to find talent in that area
and then delegating. That's what you do.
But delegating, you have to be
like, you gotta be careful though.
You can't delegate so much of your job
that you're just sitting in your office
twiddling your thumbs,
cause then you're fucking useless.
There's a fine line between putting a
team together and then just sitting in in
a fucking room like a, uh,
like a fucking goddamn mop.
So I still made an apple pie.
I put on an apron,
took out some flour and some
sugar. I don't give a fuck. I am,
I'm good at making desserts.
All right? I don't know.
It's embarrassing. But I, I like sweets
and my mom always made great pies
and when I moved out, I missed them.
So I learned how to make
a fucking show me. Um,
oh Geez. I can't even look myself in
the mirror after this fucking podcast.
What do you want from me people?
I'm flying blind here. All right.
I don't have the Internet.
I'm doing a podcast without the Internet.
This is like a pilot flying at
night without his instrument panel.
Am I in a spin and my uh,
my level with the horizon,
I don't know my going up my going down,
God,
I wish I had a beverage so I could
actually look at it to try to figure out
which way I'm going.
Isn't that what you do?
You just put like a glass of water on the,
on the airplanes dashboard
and then you just,
you just use that as your fucking horizon.
Come on man.
That's pretty ingenious for a comedian
who has zero hours up in the air.
Um, anyways, so let's
get back to the game.
So the entire world is like 90 minutes
ahead of us and there's something cool
about that,
right?
Like they all got on the spaceship and
they went to a better planet and we all
sat back like, gag, go fuck
yourself with toughing it out here.
Non on cigars and shit pretending
we know how to fight. Right?
So we go upstairs and they finally like,
you guys want to watch the game? Yeah,
let's fucking watch it. All right,
so we go upstairs, we put it on.
I fast forward like, you
know, get right to where it,
right before the kicker is going
to kick the ball. And I hit pause.
You guys ready? Everybody, Jake?
Yeah, we're ready. Let's go.
Bomb fucking kicks the ball off.
My Broncos get the ball and the
very first play from scrimmage.
All right.
Peyton calls an audible
the fucking Manny Ramirez,
who I thought, you know, when
you get kicked out of baseball,
I didn't think that you could then just
go play football. But once again, Jesus,
what a fucking talent this man is Manny
being Manny hikes the ball over Peytons
fucking head ended up God damn end
zone, whatever the guy falls on it.
They get as safety,
very first play from scrimmage.
And I'm not going to lie to you.
I literally put my hand over
my mouth and I was stunned,
absolutely stunned because uh, you know,
I'm not gonna lie to him. You know,
you guys know what my
prediction was last week.
I thought that game was going
to be a classic. I'm, I'm,
I knew the AFC was weaker. I definitely
kind of felt that Seattle 49 is,
might've been the super bowl,
but it's fucking Peyton manning.
And I knew [inaudible] had a
great defense and all that.
I just thought it was
going to be back and forth,
um, through the first half.
This is what I thought.
And I thought it would maybe one one team
where the yellow was going to be up by
like two, three points,
maybe four at the half.
And then in the second half I thought
that the Broncos' defense was going to
cave in, that Marshawn lynch was
going to fucking run all over them.
That obviously did not happen.
I think the Broncos went in there
are obviously we'll like, alright,
we gotta stop, we gotta Stop Marshawn
Lynch. And they did. They did.
And they were like,
well that Wilson guy is not playing well.
If we're going to get beat by,
our offense is going to be
with that guys fuck it up.
And other than a couple
overly excited throws,
you know where he overthrew that
guy right out there and the flat.
Other than that, that kid fucking settled
down and had the game of his life.
I thought he, he, he made
some great fucking throws,
had no picks, no fumbles, no
nothing. He did not hurt the team.
All he did was moving forward. He
played a great fucking game, dude.
It was total 100% fucking domination.
Let me think about that. They had
two field goals. They had a safety.
They had a touchdown or
offensive touchdown. I think
it was a run, right? Yeah.
Marshawn Lynch.
That was a run.
That's 22 field goals at six fucking
annoys me going through the whole game.
That's 20 points now that it isn't,
oh is oh here it is.
A comedy be trying to add this up,
right?
Three and three is six plus seven is 13
plus two is 15 they had a kiss special
teams kickoff return.
That was fucking 22
what else did they,
I don't fucking room.
They had a pick six that's 29 points.
Then they scored another 14 I don't even
fucking remember now telling you I'm,
I mean, I might be wrong, but
they could have shot them out.
They went into the prevent and the
at the end of the third quarter,
which was fucking brilliant,
just give up the middle of the field,
let them burn out the rest of
this fucking quarter and we're up.
Even if they score a touchdown,
we're still up by almost 30 points.
There's no fucking way this scoring
30 and the fourth quarter it was over.
I've never seen the starting quarterback
get taken out of the game. Like, well,
there's no sense risking you getting
injured in a fucking Superbowl. I can't,
I'm trying to think. Did they take
Troy Aikman out that year when they,
uh, they won like 50 something to whatever
against buffalo or did they take Joe
Montana out?
MMM.
And that 55 to 10 game,
I don't think Jim Mcmahon came out when
they beat the shit out of the Patriots,
that 46 to 10 game.
So this is what I'm doing during the game.
This is how much of a psycho I am.
Every time Seattle scored points,
I stood up and I high fived each
person I was watching the game with.
Every time I'd go, Tom
Brady, Tom Brady, Tom Brady,
Tom Brady is,
I was going around in the fucking room.
I just look,
I'm too dumb to follow politics.
I'm not good at math.
I don't understand science.
So sports is all I have.
So when I put on ESPN,
it has been an absolute dream for me
since 2010 to not listen to the who is
better Payton or Tom Brady.
And if he won yesterday,
I was going to have to
fucking listen to that again.
So this is completely just selfish,
totally selfish because I didn't give
a fuck about Seattle either and there
would've been nothing funnier then
after all that screaming and yelling,
if they didn't win it, the whole fucking
thing. I mean, I didn't give a fuck.
It would have been hilarious.
But the second the game started,
like when Seattle started playing,
well first I saw Peyton, right?
And then there was the safety.
And I was like,
I was literally nervous at the
beginning of the game going, Oh my God,
is he going to just carve up this
fucking unbelievable defense?
And then this argument's
gonna start again.
I'm making this whole Superbowl about
me. I realized this, this was all,
this is all I gave a
shit about. And then, um,
and then Seattle started doing well and
I started seeing, you know, Pete Carroll,
very surprisingly, I don't think I
saw him went, Woo, the whole game.
I don't think I saw him
do that once. But, uh,
I got out and then I was looking at
him like, ah, fucking Pete Carroll.
I don't want to see this guy win.
Like I was just fucking,
I was like this little gargoyle in
the corner just sitting there. Like,
is there any way both teams could lose
so I could be satisfied as a sports fan?
I was just like one of the biggest clients
that ever watched a fucking game. Um,
and then I just realized that it was more,
it was more about a,
Oh yeah.
And not only that,
first he picked the Broncos and I picked
Seattle and that's a back to back years
were Paul Versey has been
dead fucking wrong. And uh,
this is the thing about Paul and this is
why you should never ever, and you can,
you can call in Diversey
effect if he has callers.
And you could tell him I said this,
don't ever,
ever take gambling advice from that man.
I'm not saying he's a good guy.
I'm not saying he's not a standup guy.
I'm not saying he's good on
a great husband and father,
not saying he's not a great comedian.
I'm just talking about the gambling part
of Paul versus New Jersey brain via New
York. All right. That fucking guy
he's never going to learn.
He is,
that guy loves offense.
It's a cliche at this point.
The say defense wins championships.
Paul just, he can't hear it.
Paul's like that guy that's
head fucking 19 beers and he's,
and you're trying to go gimme your keys
and he just will always think that he
can drive.
That's what he is.
I hope he listens to this when
it comes to be in a gambler.
That fucking guy loves.
He's flesh.
He likes the Flash, he
likes pinky rings. Offense,
throw the bomb.
That's his big thing.
Aaron out scare the defense. He loves
it. Waste to play. Just throw it.
70 fucking yards.
He is,
he's a time square fucking kind of guy.
He likes the lights,
he loves the fucking off fence.
I on the other hand, am a
miserable, middle-aged Andy,
Andy Rooney cunt.
So I of course love defense.
I love it. 10 to seven game. I love it.
I love it when people sit those so
fucking boring. I absolutely love it.
I love a pitcher's duel.
I Dunno why.
Okay.
I know why.
Because I'm a Kinda guy that will watch
the Superbowl and root for both teams,
the loose. Um, so
anyways, congratulations.
In all seriousness, congratulations
to the fans of Seattle lie.
That's gotta be fits. Great guys.
Haven't fucking won a championship.
So when was it? Let's
see. 77 was the bullets.
No, 77 was Portland. 78 was the
bullet. 79 I believe was, uh,
the supersonics.
Um,
okay.
The loudest fans, they are the loudest
fans. Hey, us, Seattle Seahawks fans.
Do you ever think if you cheered
that loud for the sonics,
they wouldn't have left?
Yeah.
Ah, it's just never going
to get old teasing them.
They don't give a fuck.
They have a championship parade.
So now they're actually talking
because they're so young. I mean, dude,
that was fucking, that
was seriously, I know.
I'm still breaking it balls
just because it's fun. Um,
that was seriously one of, I
knew the afcs week, but I mean,
there are only so weak.
That was still Peyton manning with one
of the most prolific offices in the
history of the modern era.
Fuck the whole game because the game
has changed so much. But like, um,
Jesus Christ, I mean, that game was over,
over in like
even I who never,
I always say it's never over. It's never
over. It's never over even, I mean,
it was just,
it was fucking over.
Yeah.
The fucking game was over.
Joe Barton.
Nick was sitting on my couch,
just La. He started the laughing
in the,
uh,
when the guy was ran the fucking
ball back to start the second half,
cause he's sitting there going like,
what did he say? He said, Bill, he goes,
I'm glad you have money on this game
because if you didn't I would be back
outside drinking and I start laughing and
then, you know, and as we're doing that,
we're fast forward through
all the fucking, you know, um,
halftime show and as he's saying
that, I'm laughing, we hit pause,
everybody, you know, bathroom
break and then we hit play.
They kicked the ball off and the
dude starts running back and,
and partner has this high pitched
laugh. I just, Sam, go ahead.
Once the fucking thing back,
dude,
it was an absolute beat.
I have to think that
everybody in Washington,
the state of Washington has to
have laryngitis like for fuck eat.
Especially if you watched the game and
you didn't miss any commercials, you,
you just watched it like,
like a nerd and just sat there like
a good little fucking TV viewer.
And you watched the whole halftime show.
I mean,
everybody in the state of Washington has
to have laryngitis. I'm trying to think.
The only disappointment you had
was that you didn't shut them out.
And even then it was just like that was,
they did that on purpose.
They just gave up the middle
of the field. Jesus, Bill,
how many fucking times are
you going this week? Got It.
They gave up the middle of
the field. You can't, uh,
you know, who would've thought I'd be so
fucking elated to see Pete Carroll Win a
championship?
I just ate just he party.
There was a couple of fucking
things this week. I didn't hear it,
but I guess on Bill Simmons Podcast,
he interviewed Larry Byrd and Larry Bird.
They asked him who he would want to
play with the most in today's NBA,
and he said, Coby Bryant,
Kobe Bryant. He just said, no,
the guy plays hurt.
He just fucking just went on and
on about how awesome the guy was.
So I have to retire trashing Coby Bryant.
It took Larry Bird to let
me know that I was wrong.
But isn't that why you
listened to the podcast?
Doesn't it make you feel
better about yourself? You
know what's funny by himself?
Fucking arrogant. I still don't
think I'm wrong about that guy. Um,
I can't get past my blind hatred of
the fuck. Its not even the Lakers.
That's their fucking stupid
ass fans. God, they're dumb.
They're so dumb.
He just gives us this like 8% of them
even remotely could even explain a pick
and roll. I gotta tell you,
if you're not from out here,
you gotta come down here and go to a
Laker game and just sit amongst them just
to see how fucking dumb they
are. God, they had dumped,
I mean I'm talking like not summer school.
Dumb.
I'm just talking about
fucking learn a trade.
Drive a truck. Dumb. Right.
And I know there's people out there
learning a trade right now and I know what
you're thinking.
What I just said was insulting and I
don't care that you think that because I
know you're too dumb to
figure out where I where,
where you can fucking find me doing
stand up even though it's on my website.
Get just too fucking stupid.
I really shouldn't say shit like that
cause there's always one dumb fuck who
takes me seriously.
Do you remember last week when I was
saying how Hawaii part of this country,
even though it is, I'm just
saying it just nobody, nobody, um,
black or white looks right on that island.
You have to be Hawaiian or,
or Asian and you look fine.
But we,
we,
the rest of us do not look right
on an island. We just don't.
And then the joke was, when I
fucking come here, you know, well,
I lean up against the tree.
I looked like an American.
Like you can't tell me that.
And I said,
I'm so sick of these native Americans
complain and f I have to argue with one
more Apache. It was completely ridiculous
and over the top, and everybody,
one fucking moron on
Twitter, he said, Bill,
the reason why you look
normal as this country,
he's because capital letters you would,
you killed all the native Americans.
It's just like, dude arguing with
the Paches didn't give it away.
There's always going to be
that one fucking person.
It just has to fucking take it seriously
and ruin it for everybody else.
All right. Am I done whining?
What else did I do this week? Oh,
um,
what did I do this week?
I thought I did something. Oh,
you know what? I haven't drank.
I haven't drank in a seven days.
It's been a week.
And I realize now that it is, um, okay
that basically I have to go once I
go seven days and I go and I get past
something like going to a
Superbowl party and I don't drink,
then at that point I can go a year.
Like now I could, I could go a fucking,
it's that first week.
Well I haven't drank in two days.
I haven't drank in three
days and I just think,
well if I drink I can start over again.
I can easily go for days and
beat my streak once personally.
Once I get seven days in, now I got
to hit in the street going, you know,
I got the hot bat here.
I don't want to end the streak.
I don't want to start over again at one.
So I got through the Superbowl and it
was brutal trying to get through it.
Um, oh man, we had such a fucking
great time. And then in the end, right,
cause we smoking this pork shoulder
and the last time we had we had the
temperature too high. And
by we, I mean La head. Um,
this time we slashed Lawhead had
it lower and it took a lot longer,
which it was totally worth it.
But we watched the game and like two
fa there took us two hours to watch the
game,
just flew through the whole fucking thing.
And then by the end of the
game, the pork roast, uh,
the w was ready and the pork
shoulder I should say was ready.
And we just sat there and fucking Chow
down laughing that we missed all of the
bullshit. Um, and it was funny.
Nia comes home and she's like,
what'd you think of the game? We were
like, yeah, we just finished it and blah,
blah, blah. And then she starts talking
about Bruno Mars and all that. We like,
yeah, we didn't see it.
She's like, it is. Oh,
we didn't see it.
So then she goes and we recorded the game.
She goes and she rewinds it.
Okay.
Are Fast Forwards, whatever the
fuck she had to do to get to it.
I guess we want rewind. Yeah, cause
we watched it yet. I hit stop. Yeah.
So she had a rewind back there
and she goes to put it on in law,
had sitting in my living room and it
comes on and there's this creepy fucking
singing of children in like in there,
like all, they're backlit. So he sees
this silhouettes and they're singing like,
whoa, whoa, Whoa, that
fucking Grinch music.
Whatever the fuck they was singing,
sort of holy sort of
creepy pedophile music.
Oh, there's so innocent.
Let's let them sing innocent,
creepy fucking church music.
Right. And I look over
at La and I go, Hey Jay,
this is what me miss.
And Jay was over in the corner and he
just fucking look up and he just made this
face. He just goes, but
I've got to tell you, um,
I actually watched, I did, and I, then I
watched it. Now that the game was over,
I didn't give a fuck. And I
actually really like Bruno
Mars. I watched it. And uh,
oh, what a halftime show that
was, that was a tremendous show.
Came out with the DW green spot,
played a fucking drum solo. Oh, he was
tremendous. What an entertainer did.
The James Brown dance, Gillette
peppers came out their shirts off.
I fucking called that a call that I
called it on Conan. I did Colin this week.
I said flee was going to catch a cold
cause he wasn't gonna wear a shirt and he
should be the only one
complaining about the web. Um,
so anyway, so it was, it was
fucking absolutely phenomenal.
Superbowl some a Sunday and I did
not have one fucking drop of alcohol.
And uh, I feel great when I got to
be honest, you'd not drinking is, uh,
it's really hard right around
four o'clock in the afternoon
till about two in the morning.
Those 10 hours are hard. The other
14 are easy, you know, eight them,
I sleep, you know, and I just
got to get through six hours.
But those other 10 men, I got to
tell you, those are fucking brutal.
But I'm a nice little streak here,
so I'm going to try to go until my
Canadian tour. And then once, you know,
the Canadian tour starts, I mean, they
got Cuban cigars up there. They got,
it's just gonna be, uh,
it's going to be cold.
Who wants a Heda? So whatever.
So I'm to, you know, it's funny,
as I overheard somebody who
wasn't a doctor say that,
um, that basically, uh,
to cleanse your liver,
it takes 42 days to cleanse your liver.
So like an idiot,
I just don't drink for 40 days,
42 days thinking I'm cleansing my liver
as I'm putting in all these fucking,
you know,
I'll eat at Mcdonald's once or I'll
fucking just be eating processed fucking
food. I'm not cleansing my liver, but
at least I got the alcohol out of there.
Right? I'll drink a little
water with some lemon, you know,
I do what I tried to do, but
you know, um, anyway, let's, uh,
let's get to some advertising this
week, everybody. All right, this,
this next advertising is
going to be called a bill.
Tries to read on his fucking cell
phone here. All right, let's,
let's bring this up. All right.
Live reads. Oh, Jesus. Well,
you look who's back.
It's our old friends.
Sherry's berries. Uh,
Jesus, they came back.
They were good sports.
All right,
let's read this homo erotic
slash homophobic copy.
Let's see how it is this time.
Sherry's berries, everybody.
What's the worst Valentine's gift
you have ever been given or received?
Talk about how much trouble it got
you in being in the dog house. Oh,
is that what I'm supposed to do? I'm
supposed to make something up. Hey Sherry,
I give, I give great gifts. Okay.
I hate why didn't advertisers have talk
about how much trouble have got you, boy.
Oh boy. I remember one year I
got my girlfriend a lawn mower.
What was I thinking? Oh Geez. Um,
anyways, look. Who's kidding? Who?
You don't have a lot of money?
Just get him some fruit dumped
and chocolate. All right.
Don't make a mistake again.
Order Sherry's berries now for
guaranteed gift satisfaction. Giant,
freshly drips strawberries from Sherry's
berries starting at 1999 that's an over
40% savings.
Like anybody knows what the market is for.
Chocolate covered fruit juice,
dust down 40% or double the
berries for just $10 more.
You just need my code burpee.
You are are when you order dipped in
white milk and dark chocolaty goodness.
Talk to a chocolate chips. I don't
know why this is so funny. Me.
Deckerd degradative swizzle or nuts.
40% off from Sherry's berries.
Enormous fresh,
juicy mouth watering berries.
Um,
please use this time to tell your
listeners about the personal experience.
How did the berries taste?
How did they look?
How did your recipient recipients react?
What the fuck is a recipient
rest recipient?
What the F. R I. E. Fuck it. Now, have you
ordered berries for your sweetheart yet?
Here's the only way to get this
amazing Valentine's Day deal.
Giant freshly dipped
strawberries starting.
It's 1999 or double the
berries for just $10 more.
Visit berries.com please
spell out the word B e.
R. R. I. E. S. Dot Com.
Click on the microphone in the top
right hand corner and type in Burke,
go to [inaudible] dot com click on the
microphone and type in Burr or it today.
I love that. Like you're going to
get in trouble for some weird gift,
but then you just get them this. I
ain't got to stop doing this, man.
I'm going to lose everybody. God knows
nature box is not talking to me anymore.
A bunch of babies.
Uh,
proflowers proflowers everybody for
getting Valentine's Day is as bad as
forgetting her birthday. I debate
that. I mean, they're both bad,
but I would say for getting
her birthday's worth,
you don't remember when I was
brought to this work. Um, you,
you can't just do it.
Wait,
you just can't do it and you
can't wait until the last minute.
I'd rather blank then forget
Valentine's Day. Hey advertisers,
I'm not doing the work for you.
All right? Right out the copy.
Talk about how much you
like flowers. Oh, Jesus.
I always skip through them as a kid.
I'd rather raw see Peyton
manning when super Superbowl.
Then forget Valentine's Day. Or
even if it's not for, forget.
It's always wait till the last
minute and then be screwed. Listen,
you guys know the deal.
All right.
This is one of the great gifts
you can get Valentine's Day. Why?
Because it's easy and it shuts her up.
Get one dozen red roses with a free
glass vase for 30 bucks or upgrade to one
dozen red roses with a
premium ruby vase and again,
gourmet chocolates for just nine 99 more
classic romantic red roses with a box
of chocolates. There you go,
sweetheart. And you pat her on the ass.
Pro is quick, easy, and delivery
on Valentine's Day is guaranteed.
You can't beat the price or the
convenience. Then I backed that 100%.
It's about as easy as it can get.
Best value. Get it done early.
Choose the delivery date
and check it off the list.
Even if you already have
plans for Valentine's Day,
you still need flowers delivered,
which is you have to, it's a must.
The longer you wait, the harder it will
be to find any flowers at this price. Um,
here's the only way to get this deal.
Limited time, Valentine's Day deal. Sorry,
one dozen red roses,
including a free vase for 2,999 or you
can upgrade to the premium vase and for
just nine 99 more, 40 bucks,
40 bucks. You make the call,
you make the call from a sports bar
where you're drinking with your buddies,
ignoring her texts. Okay?
That's how convenient this is.
Go to profile proflowers.com.
Click on the blue microphone in the
top right hand corner and typing.
Berbee you are are,
that's proflowers.com.
Click on the microphone and type in
birth order. Now this deal expires soon.
All right, we got two more. We'll do
those a little bit later. All right.
Yeah. The people that nature's box
weren't happy. Why weren't you happy?
Cause I said the obvious. Just eat
a fucking banana. Um, all right,
let's get into the questions
for this week. How far are we?
I'm feeling 40 minutes. Oh, 39 19.
The internal clock of a
comedian. Um, all right.
Los Angeles water shortage.
Hey there, Billy water.
Well I heard Los Angeles is
going through a doubt drought.
Um,
but what are people doing about it?
Are People shutting off
sprinklers? No, they're not.
My friend says they
still run the sidewalks,
sprinklers in his neighborhood every
night unless it rains for a few nights
straight. How does this area come back
from something like this? How does a,
how's your doomsday bunker coming along?
Um,
all right, here we go. Um, yeah,
well basically people will run their
sprinklers until the government says, Hey,
don't run them anymore.
So we haven't gotten to that
point in the drought where it's,
you can't run your sprinklers. So that's
why people are still running them.
And uh, it rained yesterday, so, uh, I
think we're going to be all right. But,
uh, I would ask you the same question.
How was your doomsday bunker coming along?
Um,
personally I don't have one and I take
great comfort in knowing that I can only
die once and that, um, just without
water I'll be dead within three days.
So I've had an unbelievable life.
I have no desire to
survive the apocalypse,
you know,
just at the,
just at the very basic level,
the lack of toilet paper,
toothbrush and toothpaste,
that alone, you know,
watching my teeth, turning brown,
having a slowly yank them out,
you know what I mean?
The loss of electricity in
listening to you stereo, that alone,
it's, it's just, it's
not worth living anymore.
You gonna to go back to fucking live in,
in a clan,
some God damn cave or some shit.
I guess the garages will be
the new caves of the, uh,
I guess of the millennium here. Do you
know? Oh, you know what? After the, uh,
after the Superbowl was over,
we all sat around the dining room table.
I told you neo hooked up to because I
was too stupid to figure it out. And uh,
we put on dark side of the moon,
which I have not listened to wire
to wire in years. I would arguably,
that might be the greatest
album of all time. Um,
I don't think anything can touch
and you know something, I hope that you
got the, can somebody out there tell me,
and this is a vinyl question,
I want to know on album,
what is there a better album
to put the headphones on,
lay in there and the duck and
just listening to that album.
And if you're young right now and your
whole life has been digital downloads and
all that,
I highly urge that you get a stereo and
you buy that album and put the fucking
lights out and put the headphones on.
You got it. You have to experience it.
Like that's, that's, you know, we watch
it. It was a bunch of old people there,
you know, my age and a little
bit younger and older, whatever.
And we were talking about how fucking
great the album was because nobody had
heard it in a while. And uh, someone that
was just sitting there going like this,
that's what she did.
Like back in the day,
like your parents be like,
where you going? I'm going
upstairs to listen to music.
Like you just, you just listened to
music. You weren't on a fucking treadmill
doing night. He just, I don't,
I mean, I, it, you did listen
to the radio in the car,
whatever,
but it was different.
You didn't have like your whole fucking
playlist and Bluetooth and talking on
the phone. It was just like,
it would really was, it was
an activity like, hey man,
I got the new whatever record you
want to come over and listen to it.
And everyone would sit on the
floor and do some drugs, man.
And you'd put on the fucking album.
I miss that. I never had that level.
I never did the drug thing. Um, but,
uh, I know that I just made me think
of Philip Seymour Hoffman, man.
What a fucking tragedy that is.
Huh? Jesus Christ. You know what?
I actually saw him?
Um,
I was dating this wonderful girl
and I fucked it up of course,
because I'm an idiot.
Um,
okay.
And liked in late 1990s and
Phillip Seymour Hoffman and John C.
Reilly did a play called true west and
they would switch parks every other show.
And, uh, I went down with the, the
woman I was dating at the time,
she said, you gotta go, we gotta
go see this. And I was just like,
I don't want to go see so much. He play
right. I was too busy doing stand up.
And she's like, no, you got to fucking
see this thing. And uh, went down and um,
and got to see both. Both of them
of course were unbelievable. And uh,
it just, it's just a fucking
worst. It's the worst.
If I've learned anything in this
business as I've gained a respect for a
addiction
and just,
I dunno just how fucking
powerful that is.
Okay.
You know, I actually in a way like with
like, even like with the, with like booze.
Yeah.
Like I, I'm trying to think the
last time, maybe like a November,
I went longer than seven days,
but even then I fucked up after 10 days.
And uh,
I was talking to draw all man.
We went over to d Rose's house apartment
the other night. Me, Keith Robinson,
de rose. I'm naming a lot of names
here. I usually don't do this shit,
but we got into this fucking debate.
Okay,
I don't want to do this because you
guys are going to blow up Joe's fucking
Twitter. And he gets all fucking of
sensitive about that shit. But we, well,
me and Joe gonna going to be
doing an uninformed again.
We have to have the debate.
It was basically,
it's centered around a certain
artists or certain artists and his,
uh,
unbelievable young wife and whether
or not this person was a creeper,
not and, oh, did it get heated?
Joe Actually got so mad. You
know, like when you get so mad,
you're standing up and you imitate the
other person in the argument while you're
doing a dump dance. Like, I
know what you're going to say.
Woo. Started doing this dance. And
everyone started laughing at him.
It was fucking, I mean, it started
at 1:00 AM I finally had to leave.
I was like, I have a dog. I got to go
home. Okay. I gotta take my dog out.
I think I left a little bit after
too, and I guess it kept going. Um,
and of course the next day we fucking
laughed about it. But, uh, God dammit.
Nother fucking great guy.
What was the last time? Well,
I guess sometimes somebody who stinks.
Overdoses. That's it. You don't,
you don't wanna fucking wish
that on anybody, but uh,
okay.
Everybody's talking about Philip Seymour
Hoffman is amazing movies to talk about
how great he is.
How about how awesome he wasn't twister.
That guy was such a great actor. He
was even, he was even great in twister.
I remember the first time I saw him was
incentive a woman and I don't, I don't,
all I remember was like,
who to,
who is that actor when he was sitting at
that table and they had the one of the
council there for the school?
I can't,
I can never remember what the
fuck and movies are about.
It was all the shit that he was
doing when he wasn't speaking.
Okay.
Um, oh, like in Boogie nights when,
how subtly they let you on dead.
His character was gay when he was holding
on to that clipboard and he was biting
on that pen. The total fallot fucking,
you know, we came up with that shit.
Then I also loved the way he was
standing in one of those scenes.
He had like his right arm was down and
then his left arm was across his body
grabbing onto like his
right elbow or vice versa,
which I remember like how many kids who
are really insecure used to stand like,
you know, when you were a kid, we would
size kids up and I'm in one of our,
I saw a kid standing like
that. It'd be like, all right,
I don't have to worry about that kid
trying to fucking kick the shit out of me.
Anybody who stands like that is the guard.
I didn't know that it meant garden.
I just thought it meant like you
were a pussy or something like that.
But I never saw an act or make a choice.
Even though I,
I've seen a zillion human beings do that.
I saw him do that and like a boogie
nights of Grady wasn't big Lebowski,
just everything. I've
never even seen Kapolei I'm
embarrassed to say that, but uh,
it just sucks, man. He was on my favorite
stuff. Fucking blows that, right.
That isn't, that isn't funny, right? This
isn't what this is about, this podcast,
his podcast is supposed
to be making you laugh.
Get you a great start to your
day. Um, all right, let's,
let's continue on here. So in
answer to your question, sir,
I have no plans for,
uh, for the dooms day.
Um,
okay.
I'm going to get a bat.
That's what I'm going to do.
I get a gun, but you know, I'm
going to shoot it without earplugs.
My ears already ring from
playing drums and um,
I, I, you know, then what?
Then I win the battle and then my ears
ring even more and I'm walking around
with Tinnitus and there's
no fucking hope for a cure.
Forget tonight is I'm just praying
for toothpaste. I mean, fuck that.
I don't want to live. All right. Sochi,
is that how you say it? No. Yoshi,
uh,
Billy SSR.
Have you heard how much the
Olympics have costs so far?
5 billion. That's more than
the last 12 Olympics combined.
What do you think all
the extra money is going,
or where do you think all
the extra money's going? Um,
do you have any Olympic predictions?
MMM,
what I think all no extra money while
they got to make all that snow and that
extra snow in case it doesn't snow.
Okay.
I mean, just to cover a mountain and
snow when it hasn't snowed. I mean,
I figured that's got to cost
at least 2 billion. Right?
And you know, I know it
does. And how fucking now,
what do I think of when I think it's
an unbelievably corrupt country,
even more than one than
the one that I live in.
So I imagine all the scams that go on
here go on over there because they are
human beings just like us.
And I think it's probably even fucking
10 times worse over there because of
where their jump off point was.
We at least had a nice phony jump off
point in this country that all men are
equal and everybody has the freedom of
speech and everybody has the right to
protest and a no taxation without
representation. We had a great fuck.
We had a way better lie
than they had in Russia.
Okay.
You know,
Russia's was just say everybody
gets the same amount of Meatloaf,
man. Right. At least from day one,
we knew that there was going to be people
gorging off high on the hog and the
rest of us were getting pig feet.
We knew that shit,
but as long as someone else
was just getting the tail,
we were happy in the middle class and
that worked for a long fucking time.
And now it's over up.
Dude.
How about like these fucking hype about
how about these fucking three major
bankers have killed themselves and the
last week and if we can get past well,
bad things happen in threes.
Um,
that scares the shit out of me.
I'm not going to lie to you.
Those guys were probably all making seven
to eight figures I would think.
Okay.
And they fucking off themselves and
there's no sign that a woman was involved
that broke their hearts or you know,
I just,
that that is scary where they going to go
rogue and say what was really going on?
Are they just looking at that Ponzi
scheme and just thinking like, yeah,
there's just, there's no way to
fix it. The wolves are at the door.
I'm going to be the Oswald. I'm going to
be the fall guy. So they fucking get mad.
It's just insane. What are the
odds? What are the odds of that?
What was the last time like three major
oil people all killed themselves within
the same week for the love of God. Can I
get some conspiracy theory on this one?
I would love to hear your theories.
I'd love to hear him. You know,
because that's the kind of guy I
am. Um, all right, where are we?
Let's get onto the next thing here.
Long distance hiking followup.
All right, here we go. Hey Bill.
A few weeks ago you asked for advice
on how to deal with animals in the
wilderness. Most people that get mauled
either left food in there. Oh yeah.
That's why I this massive fear about
going into the woods and accident
accidentally stumbling upon a,
uh,
a mamma bear with her cubs
or a, a, a mountain line.
I'm always on a trail. And to the left
or the right of me is a higher like,
like cliff and the thing is
just sitting there. You don't,
you know when they sit there and they
put their head down and they're fucking
shoulder and back muscles go like
fucking like if they were in a muscle
competition, like that would be like
the Schwartzenegger like stance.
They put their head down. You know what
I'm saying? Just waiting to pounce on me.
And this is what the project says.
Most people get mauled either. Uh,
most people that get mauled either left
food in their tent or tried to pose for
a picture with the animal or did some
other dumb shit you would never do.
But yes,
on very rare occasions and animal will
attack somebody who did nothing wrong.
Here is my advice. If that happens,
first of all, you did do something wrong.
You've ventured out into the wilderness,
you left the tribe,
you put yourself at
risk. All right? I mean,
I guess if you're in your
backyard and there's a bear there,
but if there's a bear in your backyard,
you,
that's urban sprawl that when
he's not in your backyard,
you're in his front yard.
There's no fucking reason a bear
should be outside your house.
You need to move back down towards the
village. You're right, they're antisocial.
Get a hobby. Say hello to somebody
you know, have a couple of drinks.
Get some alcohol, courage,
India, and go walk up to the
pretty girl. Say Hello. Okay.
Stop trying to live with the
fucking house. All right? Bears.
If you're attacked by a bear,
you should leave your backpack on to
protect your back and use your hands to
cover your neck.
What about your face?
Usually the bear will leave after a while,
but if it starts to chew on you,
that's when you need to fight back. Oh,
really? What? What should I go with?
Should I set up the,
you know,
the overhand right with a couple of
jabs or should I try to kick him in his,
uh, bear balls? What if it's
a woman? What do I do? Do.
I try to stick my toe when it's badge.
Uh,
it's bare Vage it's badge. Um, mount wines
with mountain lions
playing dead will not work.
You need to fight back right away.
Your best chance is to
aim for the nose and eyes.
Dude, this is fucking hilarious.
I mean, I, I think I would have,
this is none of this shit work
wouldn't work against Mike Tyson.
Forget about a fucking
bear or a mountain line.
Wolves playing dead won't
work in a wolf attack either.
You can either climb a tree,
put it in a headlock,
or shove your fist down its
throat. I'm not joking. Look it up.
You know what? I always thought you
could do a, I don't know about it.
A Wolf I always thought
against this was my,
yeah.
Well,
you know,
when I'm laying in bed and I'm thinking
about getting attacked by a fucking,
you know, some rabid dog or
whatever, if somebody was sick,
that dog on me when I'm laying in bed,
totally relaxed and have my wits about
me and I don't have a urine running down,
my leg is, I run towards my
Prius, like I wouldn't real life.
I um,
my plan of attack was when the
fucking dog is coming at you,
you stick your forearm out
and you just feed it to them.
You just jam it right into his fucking
mouth and right as it climbs down and it
has you,
you then take your other fucking
forearm and you come up over the top,
smashed down on the
top of the things neck.
As you push your forum up and you
break its neck, do you go Bam,
which is the sound of a broken neck flap.
I'm sorry,
I don't want to make the snap noise.
I don't have a twig in here. That's,
that was my game plan. Either that or
just stick your arm in there and you just,
you just fucking start
stepping on the dog's feet
because dogs are kind of pussies,
man. They'll go after you,
but the second you fucking do something
back to you, do you know what it is?
They don't have any shame.
They don't mind going and then
getting hit and then going
like, they don't give a shit.
It's not like other dogs again.
They can literally do that and then go
on the other side of the block and get
laid. There's like, no,
and they don't even remember
what just happened and less,
there's still pain in their
little dog paws. So, um,
I don't fucking know. I don't even know
what I'm talking about here. These,
these are all like,
these are all creepy fucking questions.
I always felt if I was on a boat and I
saw an alligator swimming towards one of
my friends and it went
by the boat or a shark,
I would just try to time it where I jumped
down and I just fucking land right on
its head. And I just figured that
that alone would so freak it out.
They would leave or you know,
the shark or alligators would be,
uh, would be feasting on to people.
That's what I would be worried about
after the show, after the shock, you know,
when the sharks, like what the few
motherfucker, when it's coming back,
that's what I think. Like sharks,
I think just leave alligators. I,
they just seem fucking relentless
to me. Um, all right, killer bees.
Here we go with killer bees.
Africanized honey bees.
You're supposed to run away for at
least half a mile. Now this I know,
do not flail your arms
and do not kill one.
They will swarm you if you kill one.
But honestly they,
they look just like normal bs to me.
So I don't know how to tell when
you're in danger. Oh my God.
Run for a half a mile
for fucking half a mile.
What's the fastest,
fastest mile I ever ran was like a six,
18 like freshman year in high school
when I weighed about 140 something pounds
and now a buck 75.
So I think I could run maybe a
seven minute, even with the fear,
just the pain is going
to offset the adrenaline.
That's going to be a long 15 minutes.
People. Oh God. Can you imagine me?
Balding Stung up.
Fucking swollen redhead,
just coming over their health. Jesus
Christ. What a site. All right.
Spiders kill almost nobody.
Most can be very dangerous if
you catch them at the wrong time.
Some snake bites obviously
require immediate medical care,
but I would be more afraid of
lightening if I were you. So yes,
it can get gruesome, but these attacks
are very rare. Absolutely. I mean,
I know shark attacks a very rare, but it's
just like, I would love to try surfing,
but just, you know, just
the fact that, you know,
you got to stand that surfing is a
sport where you're risking getting eaten
alive. I mean, it's just fucking,
I mean, it's just not worth it.
Goddammit. It looks like
fun though, doesn't it?
But all right. Basic travel
advice or what, you know,
I got to read some more,
uh,
advertising here before I get on with this
fucking bullshit. Yeah. Uh, live reads.
All right, we got two more of your
body. Two more, two more, two more.
Alright.
Hulu plus tool or plus everyone.
You've probably tried hulu.com now with
Hulu plus you can watch your favorite
shows anytime,
anywhere.
Hulu plus lets you watch thousands of
hit TV shows and a selection of a claim,
movies on your television or on the go
with your smartphone or tablet and it all
streams and HD for the best viewing
experience possible with Hulu.
Plus you can watch your favorite current
TV shows like Saturday night live
community and family guy.
You can also check out exclusive content
including Hulu originals like the
awesome starring Snl Seth Meyers and
Moon Boys' starring Chris O'Dowd from
bridesmaids.
Hulu plus also offers a great selection
of acclaimed films for only seven 99 a
month. You can stream as many TV shows
and movies as you want wherever you want.
Right now you can try Hulu
plus for free for two weeks.
When you go to Hulu plus.com/bill
that's a special offer for my listeners.
Make sure you use Hulu plus.com/bill so
you get the extended free trial and they
know that I sent you.
Go to Hulu plus.com/bill now or click
on the Hulu plus banner on the podcast
page at [inaudible] dot com and
last but certainly not least,
the classic stamps.com every
one if you haven't heard yet,
postage rates have changed.
Again,
this is basically the post office
is slowly going out of business,
so don't get caught up in their awful
business. Uh, you know what that means?
The post office is even
more crowded than usual.
That's why you need stamps.com with
stamps.com you'll eliminate those time
consuming trips to the post office.
Everything you can do at the post office,
you can do right now from your own desk.
Buy and print official US postage for
any letter or package using your own
computer,
a printer and stamps.com always up
updates the postage rates for you
automatically, so you'll always
get the exact postage you need,
the instinct you need it. You
don't even have to think. Plus,
you'll never have to go
to the post office again.
I personally have been using
stamps.com for almost three years.
It's so convenient and so easy.
Even a moron like me knows
how to use it right now.
Use My last name [inaudible]
for this special offer.
No risk trial plus $110 bonus offer that
includes a digital scale and up to $55
free postage.
So don't wait.
Go to stamps.com right now
before you do anything else,
and click on the microphone and the top
of the homepage and type Bern Bu Rr that
stamps.com enter birth. Oh, I
lied. There's one more ie voice.
Last but not least, by the way, I'm
fucking crushing these reeds, ie voice.
Everybody.
You're a business owner,
but automated phone systems
and secretaries aren't
in your budget just yet.
And juggling incoming calls yourself
makes it hard to look like a professional.
Here's something will that
will dramatically help you
make more money in 2014
what is it? It's Eva
[inaudible]. Whether you're on,
whether you're a business of one or 100
he voice will help you manage all of
your incoming phone calls, uh, with
a toll free number, dial by name,
directory and call routing tools.
Your business will sound like $1 million.
Can't take a call he voice,
we'll transcribe the voicemail and
email and email it straight to you.
Never get caught off guard again.
And with the voice you can try
it before you buy it right now.
Just for my listeners, you can get
a 60 day free trial to eve voice.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and enter the
Promo code bill and Cha at checkout.
Take charge of your business and make
more money in 2014 go to [inaudible] dot
com and enter bill at the checkout
for your 60 day free trial.
That's Eva [inaudible]
dot com Promo code bill c.
Then I talked a little bit of Shit and
then I fucked up a lot in the last one,
but still much better than the,
uh, than the past there. All right,
let's continue on here. Um, all right.
Basic travel advice.
A good morning.
To our fearless leader,
sir. Billiard of bald.
Uh,
I am 24,
I'm a 24 year old and me and the
wife are taking a trip to Chicago.
Wanted some advice on a couple of things.
Neither of us has ever planned on a,
has ever been on a plane before.
You are a frequent flyer.
So why don't want it to know exactly
what we can expect at the airport,
when to be there. What close to
prepare to take off at what time,
problems we will mostly raw,
most likely run into et cetera.
Jesus Christ. Dude. Um, all right,
well go ahead and pack and then take a
third of that stuff and throw it over
your fucking shoulder cause
you never gonna wear it. Um,
depending on how long you're leaving,
if it's just a weekend,
I would go with the carry on. If
it isn't, I would check everything,
walk onto the plane with a couple of
magazines in order a drink and watch and
just enjoy watching everybody
else fighting, you know,
for that overhead space. Fuck
them. Um, that would be my advice.
And also just know that your wife is
going to bring half the fucking house and
it's not worth telling her that she's
not going to need it. All right. Um,
the only thing worse than having to pay
for extra bags is watching her cry that
there's nothing to wear.
And then having to go downstairs to
the fucking lobby mall there and pay 10
times the price to get her a fucking
dress. All right. Number two,
best places to eat there.
Best Burgers of pizza.
A personal favorite too.
I would like to add than I am milk
white and red headed like you.
So place that is not in the stabby
stabby Magee Magee part of town would be
preferred. Really wanting some advice
from an experienced vet. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself.
Um,
I don't know where the best
places already eaten Chicago.
Like I visit there and I just eat it the
closest place and then I go and do my
show according to Jim
Croce. Uh, the south side,
the south side of Chicago is
the baddest part of town. MMM.
But if you go down there, you better
best be ware of a man named Leroy Brown.
And um,
I believe he has a custom
continental and he has a Cadillac to,
he got it. 32 gun in his pocket, full fun.
He got raised up any shoe
Ratto and he's bad, bad. Um,
I don't know where to fucking eat there.
All I know is that a, what you should do,
you can find all of that out on a website.
One of those Foodie fucking websites.
They'll tell you where
to go. Um, so, but it's,
those foody things can be wrong.
A lot of the times what you want to
do is ask a local whatever you stay,
just find somebody who has a heavy
Chicago accent and just say, listen,
I'm a tourist.
I don't want to go to the touristy place.
Where do you go to get whatever the fuck
you're looking for? You want a pizza?
You want a burger? And that guy will tell
you, all right, that's the way to do it.
Okay, here we go. All right.
Uh, oh, by the way, you know,
I forgot to mention when I saw that
drum clinic, the common thread one,
there was a musician there,
uh,
drew of a band called drew of the drew.
Um,
if you like not mainstream music and
you'd like to see somebody who's really
trying to do something different,
uh, check that guy out.
Yeah.
Um, I was, I was very, uh, very impressed.
It made me feel old, like they would,
they would draw in from shit that like,
to me,
I already considered like new music.
Like all that Dj Dubstep Shit like to me
is like came out in the last six months
even though it's probably been
around for fucking 20 years. Um,
anyways, drew of the drew, check
it out. Anyways, Jane. Oh, phobia.
Maybe I'll, I'll put up, I'll put
up a link actually. A Billy bobag.
Baggins is it gain or phobia you
afraid of the gynecologists a fucking,
uh, I am a 28 year old
college guy. Who has,
was it Jane or Phobia?
The fear of women?
I've never heard of this. Uh,
he said, when I was a kid,
I used to get the shit kicked out of me,
and girls would always spread rumors
about me and it would really screw with my
mind. Wait a minute, you didn't
get along with men or women.
Well, what were you, what
were you doing? You know what?
That's the last thing needed to hear.
Well, what's wrong with you? I'm sorry.
Forgive me. I'm not a trained
professional, so you know,
you're asking more on and you know
I'm going to behave accordingly.
Here we go.
As I grew up,
I started to resent and hate all the
people around me that my mother tells me
about false rape accusations.
And that makes, oh,
and that makes females look even
more scarier than they already were.
See, guys, just kick the shit out of you.
Females psychologically fuck you up bad
and don't even have a tint of remorse or
empathy. Jesus Christ. All right, dude.
So your mother's a psycho and she
put all these fears on you. Yeah,
you gotta maybe I would seek some
professional help before you turn it into
Norman Bates. Uh, all right,
let's continue this then.
I hear about all the women raping men
in the divorce courts and in general
adding more fuel to the fear. Dude,
you're over thinking this shit. I mean,
you probably heard half of that from me,
but I'm an idiot. Don't listen to me.
He says, gotten to the point where
when a female introduces herself to me,
I just see her as a potential mind
raping and prolonged exercise of getting
verbally abused. So I just
always say sorry, but I have
somewhere to be right now.
Goodbye.
Okay.
And I walk away, sir, can
I steal that from you?
I want to use that next time they get
pulled over. Yeah. License Reza. Sorry.
When I have somewhere to be
right now, goodbye. And you just,
just act like the rain man and
they'll fucking leave you alone.
That's actually brilliant. Uh,
he said they scare me so much,
but I'm still attracted to them.
Oh my God, Dude. You listen,
you gotta you gotta you
gotta get past this.
Hopefully you're still
young and this is early on,
but this is something where you were,
you know,
everybody is trying to go towards the uh,
late,
we'll just call it a whatever
planet live happily ever after.
But if you're off by just one degree,
you're not really going to notice
when you're 22, 24, you know,
but by the time you're 40, you're going
to be about a million miles off course.
So let's try to get you some help.
I would go see a therapist or,
um,
and I know I've been joking around,
but I kind of have to do that
because this is a podcast. But, um,
well actually because it's a podcast,
it's supposed to be funny.
I'm not saying you can't
have a series podcast. Um,
yeah, I would go get some help quickly
and I would get rid of all those fears.
And I would say a lot of
the fears are probably, uh,
put into your head by your mom when you
were really young and you need to try to
get those out of there before they take
any more route than they already do
already have. Well, it's finished
here. He said, my mind says,
stay the fuck away while my Dick
says do it. Do it. Fucking do it. Uh,
but in this climate of unrestrained female
hypo agents,
and what the fuck that mean?
This shit that makes
women invade male spaces,
it makes them change everything
to suit them. Dude, dude,
you're taking your fucking fear
of women. You're, yeah, you're,
you're blowing by me.
Listen, are you a great guy?
If you're a great guy, there's a
great woman out there for you and the,
and it's a beautiful thing
then not all like this.
What you're doing is you're taking the
worst of the worst of females and you're
printing it with a broad
brush. All right? Um, oh,
Jesus Christ. I'm relating
to this guy here. He said,
I'd rather stay celibate for life.
All right. Now I don't relate to that.
I am a loner to a vast degree,
but I got a loving family to back me up
so I ain't on the fringe or anything.
I plan on just working
towards my career and it did.
I write this like 20 years ago.
Jesus Christ plan on just working
towards my career in education.
But either way I'll have to deal with
women and it's been hard to do since
lately too.
So lately since my social skills
tanked over the last nine months.
Yeah.
Trauma,
Conga Line of horrific events happened
and I am working on getting the
confidence back through Brazilian
Jujitsu already lost 11 pounds and I'm
starting to feel a lot better. All right,
well just don't go choke out any women.
All right, I'll try to put
them in the triangle. He said
anyways, is there any way,
but martial arts are a great way to uh,
build self esteem from what I've
heard anyways. Is there any,
is there any way to get rid of the insane
fear I have about women or is it just
15 years of hurt that'll take
almost forever an undo. Thanks.
And go fuck yourself six ways from
Sunday and good luck with your standup.
Um, all right, I'll see. You were
only 15 is that what you're saying?
All right dude. First of all, it's
great you took up Brazilian Jujitsu.
We should know how to defend yourself.
And a don't be a content about it.
When you become a black belt, uh, use
it to save nerds and protect yourself,
but never be a bully. Um,
and then as far as women,
I would actually try and talk to somebody
about this and I would try to have
more of an open mind because right now
if you're only 15 years old or even if
you're young in your early twenties,
mid twenties, you're basically,
you got the lottery pick as
far as women goes. All right.
They're all available.
All first round draft picks,
bunch of first round draft picks
just sitting there and you know,
depending on when you open your mouth
and start talking to one is when you pick
in the draft, if you know what I
mean. Sooner rather than later.
But I would just talk to
somebody about, um, about,
about some of your issues.
Maybe it's school,
they got some free fucking therapy or
something like that if you're too young to
pay for it.
But,
um,
I dunno,
I would talk to somebody,
I would talk to some of your
guy friends about it. I would,
you know what I would do,
I would openly talk about
your fear of women to,
um, to friends. You know, and I would,
I would sit down with your
mother and just say, listen,
I have major issues with women right now.
And I think some of it stems from a lot
of the negative things that you've said
about them. And I need you to stop doing
that because it's fucking with me. Don't,
don't say that part, but say it in a
nicer way. Um, but if she's, you know,
I dunno.
Yeah.
That's the hardest fucking thing is
because you are born into the religion of
your parents ain't no and
into all of their beliefs.
And hopefully they have more
good than bad, but they're human.
So they're going to be wrong.
And you know,
when you're a little toddler all the
way through like seven, eight years old,
your parents are God.
Like you just think they know everything
and they have all the answers.
They never look unsure.
You do everything that they fucking say.
Okay.
So a lot of that stuff just really
takes deep root. Like, it's,
it's law in your head and
then he is a teenage years.
Did you start breaking away? You realize
some of his bullshit and let's win.
Some anger can come out
and that type of stuff.
So I would say what you're
going through is normal.
It's just that you maybe had an extreme,
a helping of some fucking anti woman shit,
which I can relate to because I did too.
When I had to fight through that shit.
I mean it took me out and
get married till I was 45.
I had made your fucking issues. But
uh, it's like anything, look, it,
just use the martial arts thing as a,
a metaphor or a simile,
whatever the fuck you're supposed to.
Whatever the right terminology is. Look
at you. You did that. You stuck with that.
You lost 11 pounds. You work towards
that. Look at, look at what you're,
you're getting, you're getting positive
results and it hasn't been easy. Right?
But You keep showing up.
You get positive results.
I would do the same thing
with your women issues.
I would just start working
on it. Um, you know,
next time a woman comes up and says hello,
don't say I have somewhere to go.
Just say hello back and stay in the
conversation for as long as you can.
And when you feel like
Bailey, just say, listen,
I'm really shy around women and it's
something that I'm trying to work on.
Just put it out there.
And you know what I guarantee
80% of them are going to say, oh,
you know, when they do that, they're
going to love it. And next thing you know,
you're out there watching a romantic
comedy with some lady having a good time.
But I would, I would address it sooner
than later. I'm telling you, dude,
it's you literally, it's, you think
it's a mountain. It's, it's a fucking,
it's stepping up onto the curb.
It's all in your head.
And that's totally normal because I would
guess that your fears started when you
were in your, my mom's godlike phase of
your life. So you think, you think it's,
uh,
what's that fucking mountain everybody.
Everest that everybody tries to
climb up. It isn't. It isn't. Okay.
It's a little fucking ant
hill. And Don, you can do it.
All right. I believe in you.
Good luck, sir. There you go. Well,
that's the podcast for this week.
Congratulations to the, um,
to the Seattle Seahawks.
All right.
You finally won.
You fucking won the Superbowl and
now I can't give you any more shit.
Actually, I still will just stop
doing that loudest crowd ever. Right?
You got the fucking trophy. You been there
now act like you've been there before.
Do not disappoint me next year. You know,
it's, you know, it's coming next year.
You know, it is. There's going to be so
many people dressed up like characters.
You're going to make the raider fans,
I don't even know what the expression is.
I don't know what happened.
Jesus Christ,
whatever happened in
that rate of fan base,
that crushes me every time they panned to
the end zone and everybody's out there.
Somebody dressed like Fred Flintstone.
It's like, what are you doing?
I'm all right. That's the podcast.
Oh, by the way, and I forgot to,
I have been watching our,
actually,
I watched a bunch of hockey this week
because of, uh, you know, I didn't watch,
watch any of the Superbowl
hype, but Gee, Oh gee.
[inaudible] with that Bruins performance
against the Canadians. Jesus Christ.
How do you not get up for a
game against the Canadians?
I know the Canadians have a good team,
but Jesus Christ,
we looked fucking horrific.
Um,
but it's good though. It's all
good. Canadians have a good team,
so hopefully we'll meet each other
in the playoffs. Playoffs and a,
we'll have another classic.
That's what I'm hoping for.
So, uh, all right. That's it.
I'm at, where the hell am I? This week?
I'm going to be in a casino
in a outside of Minneapolis.
It's already sold out,
so thank you to everybody in Davenport
and every other goddamn city out there in
Minnesota.
And I can't wait to get out there.
Hopefully it doesn't fucking snow too bad.
And I'm able to land without incident.
All right, that's it. I'll talk to
you next week. Go fuck yourselves.