Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burn his time for the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
March 28th,
2016 the year of the Yac whatever the
fuck it is. And the Chinese New Year.
I have no ideas and they had new
year. Next, next, uh, next month.
How does that work with those people?
You know how to like,
I don't, I don't get it. I just don't,
I don't understand why we're on
standard and everybody else's on metric.
Can we just pick one fucking calendar,
one unit of measurement.
You fucked over Europe. Jesus Christ
metric. And then some old guys talk. Hey,
way fucking 20 stone,
20 stone.
I mean, I guess we're still
saying horsepower. Jesus.
Fucking, well, what size stone?
What are you a fucking free mason?
Um, she buddy in the Illuminati.
Is that where he's at now?
The little secret group.
You think you're gonna make it
buying up land on the aquifers?
Is that what you're going
to do? And then what? Ha.
All the robots are gonna take everything
over, right? You phase everybody out,
but a big, except you and then you,
you guys, you guys going to be good.
And then all the robots,
for some reason I'm going to turn him.
He fucking movies you need to watch
before you realize that they're eventually
going to turn on.
You stuck out.
You made a fucking robot now,
which choke when you off with
your Dick and you deserve it.
Madec glad you stayed ban on and layer on.
There you go.
There was a little Illuminati with
a Lionel Richie and he'd like that.
Um, somebody sent me this fucking
video. They go, hey, you might want to,
you might want to watch this thing.
And it was basically this
person was talking about, uh,
we showing how the automobile put
the horse out of business, you know,
which it was so funny to me.
Like the Horse was upset like,
Oh fuck you mean human beings and our
nature aren't going to ride on my back
anymore guy what I want now what do I
gotta do? I can't run free on the planes.
Um, I guess the horse population dropped
off, but like nobody who is no one,
you know,
most of them are born into a,
I guess you really don't
see horses running around do
you can be out in Wyoming.
Yeah. See a lot of cows at
the waffle house. I'm sorry.
Well why would you do a fat joke
bill this early and come on,
you're better than that bell.
Hang on a second. We come off
a certain standard of comedy. You got
to go that low. Yeah. You got a tech,
the broads and fat people while at the
same time that early, hey, you know,
whatever, you've got to shoot
your way out of a slump.
It's my second attempt to get to sing go.
And this is one of these times
I'm recording the podcast.
Not because I'm feeling it,
it's because I have to,
cause I got shit to do tomorrow. So, uh,
I got to kind of knock this thing
out on Easter. So anyways, anybody,
if somebody shows me this fucking thing,
so the guys shows how the car put the
horse out of fucking business and uh,
yeah, like I said, like,
like the horse is upset.
It's like when you watch those
weird commercials, we're like, uh,
the Mr potato heads or sneaking
off to eat potato chips.
There's some sort of weird like undertones
of cannibalism going on there and
it's supposed to be adorable. I don't, I
don't get those commercials on any level.
Um,
but uh,
totally lost my train of thought.
Oh yeah.
So they were basically
showing how computers and
everything being automated is
going to phase everybody out and there's
going to be this mass unemployment that
is coming. I'm like, this is fucking
groundbreaking thought. I mean,
a dummy like me has been saying
this for fucking ever. Right.
And he just kept going like, oh,
see are in this industry. Well,
you're not safe either. You
think you know, you actually,
you're a computer programmer. Well guess
what? You're not safe either, buddy.
Just fucking relax. And like he
just kept coming with that tone.
And at some point I was just like,
what are you going to fucking shine that
light on yourself that maybe it does by
the end? I couldn't listen to
them. What about condescending?
Douchebags who think they know everything?
Narrating over these fucking videos,
you know, with the big dude I'd called. It
really is technology in the future
are going to get rid of jobs. Yeah.
I had no idea. It's only been doing that
since the beginning of fucking time.
And these fucking people are just forever
forecasting that the sky is going to
fall. This is the fucking thing.
Eventually the sky will fall.
Nobody knows when it's going to happen.
Everybody's been trying to predict it
ever since that fucking Nostradamus Douche
bag all the way down to a moron like me.
And the bottom line is none of us
know what we're talking about. Oh,
the lovely mia. I'm busting that on your
podcasts. We'll get a microphone in a,
in a plug there in the,
uh,
they in the closet until the bottom line
is nobody knows when all this shit's
going to end. So just fucking
go enjoy yourself. You know,
I just feel like there's fucking, all
this whole presidential election you get,
you got one loan, it's in the
closets on the closet, a top shelf.
You got one Luna tick on the fucking left,
another lunatic on the right.
And then you got this fucking, I dunno
what she is in the middle, you know,
she's not really in the middle.
She's just more of the same,
you know they're going to be, they should
just wheel her into the White House.
Like fucking Hannibal Lecter.
When I was in fucking mass zone,
you just went out to watch her awful
fucking mouth. You need the plug too.
Oh I got the plug over here.
Let me hit pause so the listeners don't
have to fucking listen to this shit.
And with that, the magic of the pause
button, we were able to get by all that.
Don't you wish she had a pause
button in life? Nia? I certainly do.
When all of a sudden something
bad was going on. Like you know,
I was in the middle of one of my long
drawn out stories. You could. Well,
I actually want to fast forward when you,
I felt that your listeners
might need rescuing from that,
from those that what it is. You just
bring it down. Bring into the mic here.
Yeah. Don't do that. Just have it. Just
hold it down a little more relaxed.
You know, like you sitting
there with a drink in your hand.
You're always telling me how to use the
microphone. Yeah, because you don't,
all right, well fucking use
how you want to use it. Then
I got my own style, man. Yeah, you do.
Yeah, you don't, you sound, sometimes
you sound like you don't want to.
A little kid answers the phone. You just
pick up the phone, you know? It's like,
hello
and you're like, Hey, what'd you
do today? Do you have a good day?
Yes.
That's the hardest thing ever.
I just was talking to my niece and it's
just like you gotta like you can't,
if you just ask them yes or no questions,
you gotta be like,
what did you do today? You can't
be like, did you have fun today?
Because they want elaborate
there. Just go, yes.
You're like, oh fuck, I
need another question. Yeah.
They're not the greatest
conversationalist, but oh they're,
they're brutal interview,
brutal interview.
So they just always that white
child actors are so creepy,
you know, like little kid. Cause
it's like you shouldn't be able,
you shouldn't be this articulate.
You shouldn't be able to just like
elaborate in a way because you're a kid.
Yeah. Right. Yeah.
No, it's, it's the combination
that they talk like adults,
they're making more money than you are.
Right.
And they're wearing that little
talk show suit, the whole thing.
And they just peel and they just sit
there and they cross their legs like an
adult does when they do panel and
they'll just be like, you know,
so what was it like working on
blah, blah, blah. And He'd be like,
oh he was great to work with. I've, I've,
I've been a huge fan of his stuff. Like,
yeah, for the last six years,
my whole life basically,
I don't think they should make little
kids do interviews. I feel like that's,
I think it's one thing for
them to do movies and stuff.
But I don't think they should be
doing interviews and press and stuff.
I just feel like that's weird.
I don't think people should talk
the little kids period. Like no,
like you seen like little kids. I don't
talk to little kids, like little kids.
Yeah, neither do I. And I
think that that is a like,
I think it weirds them out after
the age of four to be like, yeah.
Oh,
okay.
When they're just talking to
you like, yeah, you don't like,
do you remember her being a member in
young Frankenstein when he just goes like,
yeah,
tis alive.
I've never seen it.
Frankenstein sitting. They
look looking at him like, dude,
what the fuck is your deal?
No. Gene Wilder. Oh No,
he never saw that movie. No. Walk this
way. You haven't touched your food.
Are you quoting the
movie area saying words?
You're quoting the movie and
to have a tough cookie? No. No.
Like uh, yeah. How have you never seen
that when we was fucking hilarious out.
The one where he's always going
Frankenstein. Yeah, Broncos.
Remember those clips, but I don't,
wasn't there something cool? He's young.
Frankenstein with Yahoo serious,
that comedian and process really movie.
Well God knows I always fuck up the name.
It's the one with gene wilder in it.
I think you're right that that's
the name of a gene wilder movie.
But wasn't there something with
Frankenstein with Yahoo Serious am I?
I Dunno.
I don't know why there's like a wind
tunnel where you're, where you're
talking you, you know what it is.
Does it sound bad? No.
Cause this is what you do.
You're up here and then you're
down here and then you're here.
You're moving it all around.
So what do I do?
You need a steady hand on that microphone.
You don't move your hand at all. Ah,
I'm, I'm pretty consistent. I just, I rest
it like this. I rested against my chest,
my chest tickles my mail, my
mail pecks him, my testicles.
Does it sound far away though if I do
this? Yeah, it does. How about this?
That's fine. This is good. That
is good. All right. That's right.
Then I just don't move and freeze
for the next 15 minutes. Well,
I'm probably gonna leave soon. I just
came in and say hi. Oh, okay. Well,
I didn't know if you had any questions
from all that hasn't come in yet. Oh,
so where are you going on
about Frankenstein? No,
I was talking about the Illumina,
this fucking video somebody
told me to watch was just like,
this guy is just saying how technology
and robots are going to phase everybody
out and you just go, you know, Oh,
you're a milk man. You think you're safe.
Check out this fucking robot and
everything. It's just like, yeah.
Well what about condescending
douchebags who narrate videos?
Like they probably already have a
robot to do that, right? Don't they?
To do what?
I'll tell you this to just narrate shit.
They already have the fucking
robot lady in the elevator
or even that's just a voiceover that
in so many countries only please make a
poster. It's like a horror
film. And what did he say?
That weird robot lady in the elevator.
I want to fucking robot
lady in the elevator.
He didn't do a poster for a movie with
your face looking very concerned and
there's like an elevator
she used to pressing.
She's in like every fucking
elevator and it's like going up.
And then when she says going down,
she goes going down and she really like,
like your whole life is
going in the shitter.
And I can't tell you how many people
I've been in the elevator. I go, I,
it's so fucking depressing. They're
like, I know I hate it. It's not just me.
Okay. You know, it's all of us out
there in the remodel, you know,
hoping they got that little waffle flippy
thing down there for the continental
breakfast.
It was stale blueberry muffins.
Those little bite size ones that
for some reason give, give you a,
what do they call this?
Your little muffin toughened tops.
Those things are like little grenades
for your gut. Feel your belly. You know,
you just pop one of those in there and you
come like, like homer Simpson. Yup. Oh,
you're going to do this. All
right, let's get into the, well,
let's get into this part of it. Oh, I
thought you were giving me shit. Yup.
It's still on that shit.
Let's talk about uh,
your, your little trashing that you'd
say you took like a seller level,
comedy cellar level trashing.
Today we were out to
Brunch and mother in law,
brother in law, my sister in law
and you and me and we go out,
we go out to a lunch and you
are the biggest sweetheart.
You got to your wonderful sense of humor.
You're a cutie pie.
But when you talk to the
wait staff or just in
general, I still don't see
it. Oh in everybody. That
was an agreement. You have,
you put a little mustard on it.
You have like a can you get
your shit together or what?
Like how many times do I have
to ask you the first time,
like when the lady came over and she goes,
what did she ask you?
And I were sitting down while that is
six top while my mom and my brother were
outside waiting for my sister.
So we went to get our table and she said,
hi, can I get you guys into the drink? And
we both said waters and she goes, okay,
and can I get you some appetizers?
And I said, we're just,
we're waiting on three more. That's all
I said. But you make it seem like, um,
excuse me.
You had this tone of like,
bitch,
why would two people sit at a six top?
There's obviously more people coming.
You had a little fucking,
and there are menus and then we'll menus
that see Derek and the menus and it was
totally,
that's what it was.
The fact that there was menus
there and she didn't do the math.
You just have this,
well what the fuck's wrong with you?
But I don't think that I'm a difficult
person to serve in a restaurant.
What'd you say that I know what the way
don't you do it the way that you do it.
It's, it's one of those
fucking zingers. It's a tone.
So the person that you
said something nice,
but there's a tone in there that makes
the person a step and a half away kind of
cock their head like, well she
just being a fucking asshole there.
Am I like you are accusing me of being
shady is basically what it was and that's
not my intention. I just, you do.
You do know though I not shady.
Shady is like dishonest.
You're saying that that shady as in I'm
being shady the way it throwing shade.
Are you going down,
drilling down?
Um, I, I just have,
I definitely have a little less patients
than normal perhaps at a restaurant.
This is good. You're gradually,
they do feel that. Um,
I don't like it when they're not
on top of things. That's all.
And I mean it wasn't just for me,
like my mom got her salad before
she got her wine and the woman,
the bus got drinks and like,
you know,
me and my brother and my
sister all had mixed drinks.
She had wine like hers should have
been the first thing that came out.
And then we all get our stuff and then
she gets a salad with no wine and I said
to her, and she has a wine to the ones
you brought over. My Mom's fat salad.
I just said that she has one.
I wasn't like my mom ordered wine
and she should've gotten that first.
I don't do all that. No, you don't go to
that level. Yeah. So what's the problem?
You have a fucking tone. I can't do it
the way that you fucking do it. I just,
I always look at you go easy.
Nia.
Just fucking take a little
off the fast ball there.
You just have this fucking
do your brother agreed.
You sister agreed when she
pleaded the fifth and he goes,
I'm not going to get involved in
this cause she does the same thing.
To be honest, I'm not trying to
throw them on. That's what you want.
That's what your brother said.
What brother goes when your mother would
tell I said that's where she gets it
from.
Well I mean my mom definitely has
been known to complain about food.
She bitched about the food in Italy.
The funniest thing ever keeps saying,
I guess I'm just used to a sandwich
that has meat on it. More meat,
more meat on it. No, I mean I think, yes.
How hard did we tease her for
complaining about the food? A lot,
but then then good sport
about it. But um, no,
I mean my mom has a tendency to be late.
Just to the point with people like that,
because you know, just
letting them know, listen,
this was the Sunday waitstaff,
this was the Easter Sunday weights that,
like I said,
you're not getting,
you're not getting the Crigila
wait stab on Easter Sunday.
Like let's be real. Wow. You're just,
you're going in there with that attitude
now this is all this type of fucking
predispose thought and
tone that guys like me,
guys like me and offend somebody because
somebody did it shift at it. No, no, no,
no.
I'm saying on Easter Sunday you have,
you're going to say that I'm saying
that they're not the creme de la creme,
but if you had been in this restaurant,
okay, so I'm not talking about you.
If you had vantage restaurant,
you would have seen just
how it was a little off.
That's all. And I wasn't like throwing
a temper tantrum or being demanding.
Here you have a mandate.
You have this fucking attitude
every fucking place we go.
When you order, you have,
I'm always like easy, easy,
all you're gonna do.
Just pump the brakes a little.
I just feel like they asked me what I
want and I just tell them what I want and
what I need and I'm, the thing is,
when you order, I think you're fine.
But then it's when, when everything
isn't chomp, chomp coming your way,
you have a way of like,
can we get some more bread?
Like please, like you have
this, I can't, I'm, that's
my page.
So you're fucking agreeing with me.
I agree that I have a low patience for
service that is not the
quality that I feel that,
yeah, well his is that, yes. Sound crazy.
I know. And if they fuck with your food,
they're going to fuck with my food too.
So it's just fucking,
the wait staff has an unbelievable
amount of power that you're not really
realizing to fuck with your life.
I realized that I was a waitress.
Remember, I understand how
it all goes down. I just say,
what happened to you at that job?
You got fired and here you are.
Oh yeah,
I got fired over some bullshit and they
could never even tell him why I got
fired. Okay. They were like, oh,
you told somebody that they couldn't
have ice coffee. And I said, Oh,
you told me that we don't serve ice
tea anymore because it's the fall.
And they're like, oh, but you still
can have ice coffee. And I'm like, oh,
I didn't fucking know that.
And that was an example of one of the
reasons why they fired me. Bullshit.
It was over some bullshit
little mustard getting slung
around in that place. You don't,
you probably have the
same fucking attitude,
the same lack of patience with the
people ordering those fucking bar flies.
Actually no,
he did a great show.
That was one of my favorite times when
I was first getting that this place
doesn't exist anymore.
The all state cafe on the west side
in New York and she used to work the
lunchtime shift and I would
come in as a fucking, you know,
no name Magoo comedian. Right. So on my
days of free, my phone's not ringing.
You come in every day that
I was working with. So cute.
You come in with the New York Post,
you come in with the paper, I loved it.
And you'd sit in the same booth and you
get a burger. Oh Shit. And I would sell,
Rosa would come by to, Rosen would
come down. You looked adorable.
You looked at during people
love to the people that you got.
You got the chef there.
I wish I just brought that up
there cause I had friends there.
But restaurants are just, they're
weird environments. Anyway.
That's the only place
you ever got fired from.
And I remember how far you took
that cause everybody sells.
You've just gotten promoted, promoted,
promoted. That's the only place. Yeah,
you cried.
So I think maybe that's why you have that
fucking attitude when you go in there
because it brings you back.
Oh, that's ridiculous.
Well then I didn't know if
maybe you're just not nice
person.
Now I get impatient at restaurants.
I will cop to that. Okay, fine.
I cops are being impatient at restaurants.
Well do you remember when you were awake?
Waiter or waitress and people
were like impatient with you.
How did that make you feel?
It didn't make me feel good.
Okay.
So the next time we go out,
do you think maybe I'll
just let you order from me.
How about that and make an all nights
at school and traditional just like you
like that. Well yeah, I liked
it when there was defined jobs.
Define gender roles you mean? Yeah,
absolutely. Well I'll let you,
it made it made a shrew to deal with
when you take me out to eat it made it a
lot easier. And what do you mean the
questions just came in by the way?
One of them them's skin infections.
What am I talk to somebody
I'm wrote you about? They got,
they were getting married or they're
engaged in their fiance wanted to have a
little mermaid theme wedding.
Did you have this question? Yeah,
cause I got sent it to Andrew. Send it
to me too. Um, it's a comment. I'm an,
obviously I'm late, but
I just, first of all,
I just don't think that's a real
fucking question. Are you okay? Good.
I didn't think it was real,
but I was like,
if this is real person would really
like no 28 year old woman wants,
have their fiance dress up
as who was it supposed to be?
Neptune.
Um,
you know,
because that doesn't make any buttons
sense because June is her father would,
would, would be, uh, the
Little Mermaid's father.
Yeah. I, it just seemed
like it would be addressed
stop as Prince Eric and the fact that
you didn't know that just proves that you
lied because a girl who's really
into little mermaid like I am,
would know that those are the facts.
Well, maybe they're just talking
about, okay, here we go. Bazaar 13,
most bizarre and unusual wedding
themes. All right, here we go. Look,
these people are dressed up like
fucking monsters. All right.
Look at these other both dress
zombies. Yeah. No, this isn't really,
this isn't good for the podcast is people
can't see what we're talking about it.
Yeah. Well we can comment on it. I can
you have a little faith in me. Jesus.
Stop treating me like a waiter.
Yeah.
Having your wedding edit
at a department store.
These people got married at Tj Maxx.
Alright,
no comment. No comment. Oh, okay.
Your entire party can be superheroes.
All right,
so here,
this is getting towards a little
Neptune or whatever the fuck it was.
Couple of the Little Mermaid,
little mermaid. Okay,
so one was dressed like wonder woman.
The other one is dressed like Batman.
How out of shape is the Batman? It's
a loose fitting. Fucking Batman suit.
He looks horrible.
That's some shit that you regret later.
He looks like old Batman.
Like we know when your skin loses the els.
This city Super Mario Brothers
can smash it up at your weddings.
That's a wedding cake or
Super Mario brothers wedding.
Just show up naked. Okay. Now is
this scene, is this seeming a,
okay.
Wow.
What a bunch of fucking Weirdos.
A roller coaster of a wedding. People
get married on a rollercoaster. Yeah,
I could see that. Jump off a bridge while
you say I. Do you get the metaphor in?
Yes. Is it hitting you over
the head with the at? Yes.
Uh,
make it so somebody has in their wedding
ring to boldly go where no man has gone
before you. This is, this is the seeing
the theme here. This is Shrek wedding.
Oh really? Well, anyway, I,
I thought the question said that the
dad thrown into a shark cage was not the
dad,
but like the,
the groom was supposed to be dressed
like Neptune and that just would not make
sense unless he was just
all this comic con shit.
All these fucking nerds try to find middle
earth for the wedding of your dreams.
Rocky horror picture show
and a Zombie wedding.
I mean, it's just people out there
that think that, that shit's cool.
I still thought it was a bogus question.
I have. I don't fucking know. Hey,
what do I know? Okay. Um,
I was going to tell the story of seeing
the old guy fall off the scooter and I
hope you saw it, right. Jesus
Christ and you helped him.
Now what was I supposed to do?
The first person there,
it's silly bird of the rescue
fucking guy rolling down the street,
slide on his face.
Pork.
He wasn't phy Ed raspberries. He
knocked himself out. He came around,
he was spitting up, he was pulling out
little bits of teeth. And I dunno why,
it was horrifying when I saw it,
but now I can't talk about it without
laughing cause he was on a scooter.
I had basically I was,
I'm on,
I'm not going to say all the information
cause God forbid the people that are
related to them and listening.
So the fucking dude was like, uh,
I fuck it. I'll just tell the
story. I didn't do anything.
I just finished flying.
Explain his fucking tragic.
Why don't we know is all right.
Just done, finished flying. Right,
which everybody says is so fucking unsafe.
Right.
Fly around and look all this cool shit.
Flyovers Silver Lake to see that
they took the water out of it.
I even realize that. And I came
back, I fucking land, you know,
say goodbye to everybody and I'm driving
out, you know, to the real scary thing.
Driving down the fucking street.
And I literally pull out,
I make a right turn and I don't,
I don't drive more than 40 yards.
And I just see this fucking guy,
just this old guy takes
the turn to come onto the,
on the little two lane highway.
Then I'm on,
he's on the opposite side
of the road and he liked,
he went too fast and I'm
like a motorcycle. You can't
just turn the front wheel.
You're going to go down on a scooter.
You know what I mean?
You've got to kind of look your way
through the turn in lean and your momentum
momentum. You know he's supposed to
look through the fucking turn. He,
he was going too fast
and he went into the,
the fucking island in the middle of that.
Okay.
He fucking,
he jumped the fucking curb.
The whole fucking scooter went up
in the back. You high sided, right?
He just gets launched off this bucket
thing and he's rolling down the street
like a fucking log. Why are you laughing
so hard? Because people falling down.
It's fucking hilarious. He was
fine. He didn't break anything.
He just knocked himself out.
He's Lucas and then he wasn't wearing a
shield and in the end he was sliding on
his face. So I'm going, Oh
shit. Oh Shit. Oh Shit is,
I'm watching it and I fucking pull over.
No,
I made sure everybody stopped and I
got out. I was like, dude, do it right.
Just stay there. You're alright.
You're alright. And um, and he was,
he wasn't saying anything and he,
his fucking raspberry on his face,
his pants with torn up,
you know,
you got fucking attacked by a
wild animal and he's fucking late.
I feel terrible that this happened
to them, but it's just afterwards,
this is funny. And he was
laying there right in like
one of his legs. He had like,
oh, like he was chilling and the island
was just straight out like that is,
and he was like going around and I was
like, all right man. I called nine one,
you find you're fine. And then this
lady shows up and she just kept going,
don't move. Don't move. Okay.
You're okay. Just don't move. Okay.
You just have to keep going.
Okay.
And it started annoying me and I almost
started laughing like, I want to be like,
lady, like the way you're
talking is probably worse
than what the fuck is failing
right now. So, uh, by then you were
like five or six people at stopped.
Everybody called to this ambulance shows
up and like, okay, thank God, and he,
and now he wants to get up. And we just
kept telling him not to get up. And, um,
the ambulance pulls up and he just
goes, uh, he goes, is he all right?
Is he all right? You're like, yeah,
yeah, he seems to be okay. You know,
we're not fucking doctors, but he seems
to be okay. And he goes, all right,
just tell him not to move.
I already have someone on this ambulance,
there's another one coming,
and then he gets in and drives away
and then we're looking down the street.
We don't see any ambulance come and
we're like, what the fuck? And um,
finally one at a, a cop finally came
up and this guy was fucking priceless.
He gets out right? Fucking
horse. You Bald Guy, right?
He's got the whole land in strip.
He just comes out looking like Sargent
Riker from the rookies for anybody's old,
and he fucking just comes walking.
He looked, the guy from d Bluth,
the old guy showed his ass with
the mustache minus the mustache.
She just comes walking up and he just
walks right up to the guy, Dennis Franz.
Yeah.
He just walks up like his toes are almost
touching the guy's body and he just
looks down at Amigos.
You're all right.
And the guy at that point,
it's going like, yeah, yeah,
I'm fine. And he goes, hi.
Know Daniel's going to be kind of
like, he just, his level of just like,
I don't know, he must be like, people
would be on fire every day. So this guy,
he just sees a scooter and this guy
fucked up. He's just like, yeah, yeah.
All right. He also seemed way too
old to still be in a patrol car,
so I think he fucked up
somehow and got busted down.
Or maybe he was on his way
to some a senior police
fucking banquet or some shit.
And he's just like, I'm driving a cruiser.
They know I'm a cop. I have to stop.
So once that was fine,
it was funny,
they were just standing there waiting
for the ambulance. But you know,
we got to get on with that day and uh,
me and there was this tall,
older black dude standing
there, this, he's just like,
he's that guy, man, the here.
And I was like, yeah, yeah,
the here and we just like,
we both got in a car and fucking
drove away. And uh, it was really,
you know, it wasn't too bad. I
mean, it wasn't too glorious scene.
It was just a couple of raspberries
and stuff. I didn't have a, but it was,
oh yeah,
absolutely.
But it wasn't until I got on the highway
and I started driving and I started
thinking about it and I
just started laughing.
I think it was just more of
a surprise that you saw it,
but there is just something,
just watching somebody
get fucked up like that.
I remember the time I was in Griffith
Park and that dude came down the hill in
street clothes on a skateboard. He went
down that fucking, are you serious dude?
This kid will you hike
up to the observatory?
Somebody was going down a skateboard.
Yeah.
So I was just north of where the Greek
theater was and this guy just went flying
by in this thing and I was just like,
oh my God,
that guy is the shit like,
and I'm thinking like, well
how's he going to stop?
Cause this is just downhill to you getting
the traffic and all of a sudden his
legs started doing that.
What are [inaudible] wobbly fucking thing.
And I'm like no fucking way
and I'm telling you this
guy was going like 30 miles
an hour.
Then he just steps off the skateboard.
You always do that either one or
two steps and then you're done.
He was going so fast,
he did like one step and it was like,
who's that guy who fucking jump 30 feet
in 1969 nobody ever broken he fucking
head first
client.
It was like the greatest
study of his sight.
He learned it too and he started rolling
with me. When I tell you this guy,
this guy was rolling so fast,
he was like a blurry. He's like,
he would go like you hit like his elbow,
which would shoot them in the area
and then the best is when you're not
going fast enough to keep rolling and then
you just slide in the sand like
all the way down the thing and
I'll let you escape and kept going.
And he just,
he was just not moving and
I was going like, oh my God.
And he was so he started wiping out like
50 yards away from me and I swear to
God was a quarter mile walk to
get where the fuck he stopped.
And he was just laying in the road dump
moving and like I was like, I think
he had, he had no helmet.
No, he had street clothes on.
He looked like he just came
back from drinking and he just,
he had like this Harrison Ford,
like Brown leather chair.
He just fucking launched
himself. So I get up. So I,
I'm getting close to it at
this point is trying to set up,
he knows he's laying in the middle of
the road and I finally see his skateboard
hit the curb on the other side when
pops into a parked car and then he like,
like crawled. He tried to stand up and
he couldn't put any weight on that like,
and he crawled, he crawled over and sat
down and by then I knew it was all right.
So it was already starting to laugh.
So it's just going like Tony
doing that dude while laughing. I got
you. All right. He goes, he's like,
yeah bro. Fuck. I was,
and at that point I'm trying not to
laugh. I was just like, dude, I go,
that was fucking,
I was fucking hardcore man.
I never seen a wipe out like that. If I
wasn't filming that fucking thing, dude,
it was the most fucking,
it was the greatest log roll,
whatever the fuck you call
that thing that do. It's just,
I never seen him either. I can't believe
these shoes stayed on. Like, you know,
your shoes always fly off whenever
you get hit real hard. Oh my God.
Tremendous.
Fucking tremendous.
And it's just as much as you feel for
the person that's just nothing funnier
than watching somebody fucking wipe out
if they don't die and you don't know him.
Right. God, God, help me, man. Anyway,
so let me do a little podcast reading for
some, uh, for some of the advertising.
Oh, it's advertising. It's advertising.
You do the questions afterward. Yeah,
I can get right to those
things if you know.
I just don't want you to start
talking to me in a certain way.
I was going to ask you
what you wanted for dinner.
I'm starting to get hungry again. Um,
some were moldy. Oh, here we go. Oh.
The advertising would help me read some
advertising yet God knows I can't read
out loud. They don't want me to read
it. Well, I can't read this again.
And she had the whole fucking,
am I supposed to read the whole menu?
I'm not doing this shit. All right. What's
it? Look at it before you do the black?
Yes, baby. Yeah. I didn't get
into this business to have a job.
Blue Apron, everybody. All right.
You need to know how to cook.
Um, not only do you feel like you know
your way around the kitchen, honey,
but cooking at home means eating healthier
and saving money instead of ordering
expensive takeout again,
but where do you start?
It sounds like an almost
old school infomercials.
Somebody like looking at all the pans
and it looks at the camera and shakes
their head. Look, I don't know
where to start. Turn on a burner.
You're fucking checker.
Blue Apron, blue apron.
As you covet for less
than 10 bucks per meal,
blue apron delivers all the fresh
ingredients you need to create home cooked
meals. Just follow the easy
step by step instructions.
This is actually a cool thing. This
is, I would definitely try that.
Can blue aprons and that's
some stuff? No. Oh, okay. Neil.
We got too much shit.
I'm trying to get rid of shit.
I don't need a bunch of
way friends hanging around.
They said you food in a recipe card.
I haven't even finished this.
That's what blue apron is. What are you
talking about? How do I know what this is?
You're doing? The average has any,
you don't know what Blue Apron is.
They send you the ingredients and then
the rest they send you the exact amount
you need so you don't buy
it too much or too little.
Well then they should call it
blue recipes, shouldn't they?
Maybe you do want me to read it.
Each meal can be prepared and I'm just
saying if I was young, right, and I was,
you know, dating or anything,
this is a great way. Hey,
let's stay in tonight. Well,
we're a little blue apron.
We can do that.
Each meal can be prepared
in 40 minutes or less.
No overwhelming trips
to the grocery store.
No more sad takeout.
Oh, look at the noodles.
No matter how I love that,
they just have to shit on everything else.
It's convenient. Why do you
have to take grocery stores down
no matter your dietary preferences?
Blue Blue Apron makes it a breeze to
discover and prepare dishes like I am not
reading all of these fucking
things. At least read three. Let's,
we'll do like a little like a Donny and
Marie here. I'll read the first one.
Chicken Fried Chicken.
With what?
And you've not heard of chicken fried
chicken. You wrote chicken fried steak,
chicken fried chicken with big sweet
potato when Quick Collard Greens.
Oh look at him.
Go
Shrimp Po boy sandwiches with
Tribeca bread. Locked in.
The fuck is striped backup bread.
Maybe we should go to blue apron. Dot.
Steak and egg number for ourselves.
Steak and eggs with Kimchi fried rice.
That sounds good.
I love Kimchi.
Spice Catfish with pious direct
style rice and creamy saffron AOE.
Ooh,
I used to be my stripper name.
Seared pork with sprinkler such an old
jokes. Dot. Dot. Turn off the computer.
Not C'mon, c'mon. I like Yo here.
Uh, radishes and sugar. Snap peas.
Hash with ranch yogurt. I haven't heard
of it after the shit. One word. Oh,
radishes and sugar. Snap Peas
Hash with, I know, I guess. Yeah,
it has to do with ranch yoga. I speak
the language. That sounds great.
In your own kitchen. Cook with
ingredients that you've never used before.
Like watermelon, radishes,
Pharaoh, Pharaoh, Pharaoh, Pharaoh.
And purple potatoes, ab clicks
with purple potatoes. Oh,
we used to go to the farmer's market
every Sunday and it was all
dirty people walking around.
What dirty people are just,
you know,
he's talking about the vendors and all
the lefties you'd recommend like the
Hippie Carmela's guys,
all the man buns,
the fucking hair fallen
into the fucking Kim.
She kind of plays into the way you
could definitely buy weed there as no,
I actually,
I don't mind the farmer's market,
but I hate how you have to get there.
I just hate that.
I know you gotta get there early. He
got to get there early. It's like, do I,
let me just go down the street and
I'll just get the poison oh and recipes
between 500 to 700 calories proportion.
Delicious and good for you right now.
You can get your first two meals for free.
You get blue apron.com/bird.
That's blue apron.com/bird blue
apron. A better way to cook. Actually,
I like farmer's market because if
they actually are local farmers,
I like to, uh, support them.
But I know the corporate food has
worked its way in there. You know,
they just take off corporate potatoes
and they just write, hey man, potatoes.
And then it, it's like me by him thinking
I'm sticking it to the man. Hey man,
potatoes only two this week.
Can you believe it? Great.
I read these things.
Helux a great group. Uh,
right now it's not helix helix. Was that
the name of the group? I don't know.
Gimme it. Oh, oh, see, see
what are you talking about?
What you want to do rob do rocky,
you don't remember that song now?
It was like a, I dunno what it was.
It was one of the most bizarre things.
And there was some reason they
would dress like fucking cavemen.
That sounds like an eighties thing. Oh,
absolutely. It was an eighties thing. Oh,
well you know how old I was in the 80s
like I would, I, I don't remember sermons.
Yeah. But you know, other things was,
speaking of robots taking over everywhere,
how can you have a can make a robot do
what James Brown did? You can't you kit.
You know what?
But there's some fucking nerd trying to
insert oppression in pain into a robot
to see if they can give
it a little bit of soul.
It's like x Masha. They stay, start
treating it worst than the other ones
are ex machina or however you
pronounce it, night after night.
I really feel like it's helix.
Helix night after night.
Two people lay in the same bod.
I was going to say it's
bed night after night.
Two people lay in the same bed, but when
it comes time to buy a new mattress,
only one gets their way
until near the fucking top.
Until now.
Introducing helic sleep Helix Helix,
where you can buy mattresses online,
customized for both of you for hundreds
of dollars instead of thousands.
Go to helix, sleep, dotcom.
Answer a few simple questions based
on four key preferences. Do You pee?
The bed is aren't requested.
Um,
when you jerk off for
you on the couch here,
do you need a plastic so-and-so
mattress cover as a result?
You know, this is what,
that's why they're so cheap.
These are old mattresses
of bed wetter wetters.
I'm keeping it entertaining. So they
listened to the rest of the information.
They know that's not true until now.
Introducing Helix sleep well,
you can buy mattresses online,
customized for both of you for hundreds
of dollars instead of thousands.
Go to helix,
sleep.com and answer a few
simple questions based on
four key preferences and
the results will be custom sleep accustom,
sleep profile use to build you the most
comfortable mattress you'll ever sleep
on. Your mattress will arrive at your
door door, door door in about a week,
and shipping is 100% free.
And for couples,
hey helix customers,
customize each side,
customize each side of the
mattress personalized to
sue each of your bodies and
the way you both sleep.
He looks customizes.
Customers report a 30% improvement
in overall sleep quality.
How do you gauge that you're
asleep when you wake up?
You know whether you've had a good night's
sleep or not. All right, fair enough.
You have 100 nights to try it out. If you
don't love it, they pick it up for free.
And then what do they do with
it and give you 100% refund?
No questions asked. Gross.
And then what do you do?
You throw that back into the rotation
and one of the really a couple hundred
bucks, right? Hey, just fuck
on this side of the bed.
She likes it more software like say
you have a hundred nights to try it out.
Uh,
that's why everyone from Gq magazine
to Forbes are all talking about helix
sleep. Yeah. Yeah. George
Clooney has one of these.
Go to helix dotcom slash bar
and get $50 off your order.
That's helix sleep.com/berry
Heley sleep.com/bar.
I liked the idea of having
a mattress that's tailored
to both of our sides. Look,
if you just want to sleep in a
different bed, just say it all right.
I don't think so. No, of course.
All right. Dollar Shave Club,
Joe Dollar Shave club.com has this special
offer for new members who join today.
You get a free month kid of the executive
razor when you buy a tube of doctor
cabbies. Do Arctic cabbies
Easy Shave Vida? Um,
what Dr Carver's. I say Kirby's. Yeah,
Dr. Carver. Oh, it's carvers. I've
been saying carby the whole time.
Dr Covey's as Dr Carver's.
I never noticed that.
It's a lot to cure disease.
He shaved
Dr Carver's. Shave butter is where
it's called easy shave butter.
That was a little too fucking, I don't
know what, what are we making here? Huh?
What are you making here? I put this
on my face. You share about that.
This is the first time they've ever done
something like this and once you try
dollar shave club.com you'll become a
proud member like millions of others.
One reason is because they deliver amazing
razors right to your door for a third
of the price of what?
The greedy razor corporations judge.
That means when you
join dollar Shave Club,
you could afford to shave with a fresh
blade anytime you want, you want want,
which feels fantastic.
You'll get a first class shave when you
use the executive blade without hurting
your wallet.
Another reason is their Dr Carver's shave
butter carver carver using it with the
executive makes the blade glide
gently for the smoothest shave ever,
ever.
Dr Carver's shave butter,
is it your average shave cream?
It's a unique conditioning formula
with high quality natural ingredients,
leaving your skin feeling unbelievably
fucking smooth. All right, we get it.
And right now, new members who buy
a tube of shit, the shave butter,
get the executive razor for free.
They've never done this before.
Take advantage of it.
And it's only available by going to dock.
Dollar Shave club.com/burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar
high dollar shave club.com/bar
oh yeah, it's tough. It's tough.
That's why I fuck around and them because
I'm not going to have people subjected
to my fucking reading out loud without,
you know, if it's a funny train wreck,
like the way I read is like me watching
that old guy fall off the scooter.
Oh grandpa grampy did you take
it to first? Hey, guess what?
My Boston Bruins did tafe today.
Did they do something that's going to
put them in the running to be in the
Stanley Cup finals? Uh, the playoffs,
the playoffs last week, you know,
we were fucking possibly could be a,
you know, a bunch of shit had to happen.
You know, basically the ranges and the
capitals had to keep losing or whatever.
And we could have gone past them.
I've been in first place in the eastern
conference and then we lost five in a
row. Okay. And today we have, we
want our first one PB Toronto,
thank Gosh in breweries. Yeah.
It was going to be a shit show.
We lost five in a row. We fucking
lost to San Jose, Anaheim, the kings,
then the ranges and then the panthers
and the wheels will fucking coming off.
And then uh, of course as always
Berge run and shower fucking step up,
you know, for the, uh,
I guess the tying goal and then the ahead
goal and what's his face Boleski get
the fucking empty net or I missed the
whole game because we were at Brunch and I
was sitting there watching you
looking absolutely gorgeous.
Treating the wait staff.
Is that why you didn't want to go to that?
No, I didn't. I didn't know.
I didn't want to go cause I thought
your mom wanted to go to someplace where
everyone was going to go and everyone
was going to show up with their Easter
hats and I was gonna be
standing out in the sun.
It's going to be a 45 minute wait.
If you guys want to go down the street
and get some drinks and then maybe come
back, we'll give you this vibrating
square. Yeah. And I don't want to do that.
Not to be that. No, it ended
up being great. Ended up
being great. Oh by the way,
I haven't even talked about it.
And the,
I played the terrorist's data last night
and long beach is the place where a
Richard Pryor did the greatest
standup special of all time.
I want to thank everyone who came out.
I had such a great time,
but for the first 10 minutes I was
literally freaking out going like that's
where he told the white guy, you
know, sit your ass down. You know,
this is where he did. My monkeys died.
And I remember in the end when I waved,
good night,
I remember how he finished to set doing
the woman having the orgasm and the
whole place goes nuts and eating enough
to say goodnight. He just waved. Ah.
I started to watch the special,
I had to stop watching it because I knew
it would fuck up my set but like it is,
if it is the definition of a
comic who's just in a zone,
he walks out from the beginning to end.
It gives me like fucking goosebumps when
I watched that special to this day he
is the greatest,
it's not even fucking close and I got
to basically stand and do stand up there
and I just can't believe I watched
that special since I was a kid.
And you walk in and it looks the exact
same way you drive in his where he drove
him with his wife when they filmed the
special and it all still looks the same
and as I was walking in I was getting
like the chills and you just walk in and
it's like there it is. This is, this
is it, this is the place and it,
and at the end of the show, when I said
goodnight, Dean del Ray came out and out,
showed me in the spotlight,
went on him so it wasn't on me.
And so it wasn't in my eyes anymore.
I could just see the spotlight
hitting the tops of everybody's heads.
And that's the way I saw the theater,
you know,
cause they didn't really show the
crowd in that special. And, um,
it was just one of the
coolest things ever.
And then the night before I
worked at theater in Riverside,
California that they actually debuted,
gone with the wind. The first,
you know, before they had the official
premiere, it Mann's Chinese theater,
they wanted to make sure
the sound was our rights.
So they just headed east and they,
uh, they shot at, I don't know,
they fucking,
whatever.
They played the movie out there
and I got to stand on those stages.
It was fucking tremendous. And I want
to thank everybody who came out. Um,
it was fucking amazing. It's
fucking amazing. Yeah. Um,
and lastly before we get
into the questions is the,
uh, the Lincoln Continental.
All right. I talked about this,
you know, this guy who drove us,
we got a driver to take us down to long
beach because I knew it was going to
have a couple of whiskeys after that. You
know, I was trying to be responsible. So,
um, you know, I, I was sitting
there going like, you know,
I like to Lincoln Continental.
I hope they don't fuck it up.
I hope they make it fuck with
the Mercedes Benz. You know,
like those really make this a nice car.
Like fuck. With the seven series BMW,
I went to seem to be a nice
fucking car and I was saying,
you'll be cool if they actually brought
back the suicide doors and the driver
was going, yeah, they're doing that.
The top of the line is
going to have suicide doors.
And I went and I looked it up
and here's a picture of it.
How sick is that fucking
car? That's very cool. Um,
where I'm going to post this picture
and it's just the concept car.
And as far as I know, they didn't
fucking do it. Why wouldn't you do that?
Look at that. The how fucking food.
That is the sickest fucking shit ever.
Yeah. Look at that car.
Yeah, I see. No, it's cool.
I'm looking at, hopefully you guys had
just you looking at the picture right now.
They even had like the trunk comes up
and slides forward and then the bottom
kicks out and they should fucking luggage.
You can see it in real life. They can.
We know.
What you have to do is you have to buy
the car and then you've got to take it to
one of these wizards out here and say
you see that? I want you to do that.
One of those gas monkey guys.
Tell him to fucking do that to the car.
Wait, what's this one though? I saw on
the bottom this, this is a Lincoln. Yeah.
This is what the led lights and in
this one, the led lights like the,
the Lincoln continental,
their emblem also lights up
in led lights as fucking sick.
That's nice to them.
17 Lincoln continental to
replace 2016 Lincoln Mkx.
Yeah. I'm either going to get that.
I'm going to get that Dodge Ram,
r t s sport, like just a two door, no
extra cab, none of that. I just, I'm,
I'm such a Ford Guy,
but I just fucking love the way
the dodge Ram Hemi truck looks.
One of the other one or the other.
But I'm going to get some,
I'll probably get the old man car. That's
me. Right? You're definitely an old man.
I am. God Damn it. I thought it was cool.
I guess I'm not. All right, so here we go.
Unless they fucked the car up and then
I'll be right back to square one. Um,
look at this fucking guy.
Wait a second.
You are addicted to Worldstar hip hop.
Watch these videos constantly.
Dude. It's the funniest shit ever.
So sick. His fights. It's the funniest
fucking videos. And then there's all this,
all this rap shit that I'm never going
to fucking, I'm just see that site.
I'm too out of the loop. And I ended up
seeing like, oh, it was a guy, I liked it.
Trinidad, Trinidad, James.
James. Yes. The fucking book.
Guy's a genius. I don't
know. It's a fucking G. Yay.
Yes. He's totally different.
You don't think he is.
I enjoy a couple of his songs,
but I wouldn't go that far.
He didn't see the fucking video where
they had the things in that Ida look
cooler shit. They did that in the
fucking, the opening to that movie belly.
This is not like a new concept.
Look, everything's been done.
You could do that to my
Yak. Hawaii being, yeah,
he's treating everybody like
a fucking way to this week.
I'm trying to give somebody a shout out
who got plucked out of a record deal.
You know what I mean? It's true.
You know, unbelievable. All the,
I get to criticize shit. I see that.
All right, let's get onto the, uh,
the scope to the, uh, let's get to the
questions here for this week. Alright.
Daredevil dear Billy. Nunchucks
uh, you know nunchucks are
yes. Bell. That was it right there.
That was it right there.
You just asked me if I knew
what nunchucks I just asked you.
Yeah. I can't even read out
loud. I'm not judging you. Fuck.
All right.
Last year someone recommended
you to watch a dare devil.
I would like to reiterate that a year
later, season two is the shit. Uh,
the punisher fucks people up the way
he should and you actually believed the
love story. Tons of cool fight
scenes. Watch it with the whiskey.
Not sure if Neil would love it, but this
one's, this one's for you. All right.
I'll give it a shot. Heard. It's really
good. Well, let's let her watch. Watch it.
Let's watch it tonight. Okay. We'll watch
it. You want to have a whiskey with me?
Sure. Whiskey with all
frisky over here. Um,
sorry. Skin infection. Oh,
the question everybody has not been
waiting for. All right, dear bill,
I was hanging out with this girl
and I think she gave me a quote.
Skin infection. Oh No, I
haven't been with anybody else.
I confronted her about it and she
said she didn't have any symptoms.
I am 100% sure I haven't been with
anyone else and I contracted it from her.
She's acting like nothing happened.
And I didn't say I got it from her,
but it's still kind of weird.
Should I take my chances and
get back with her or move on?
What kind of skin infection do you have?
Means Std. He's just
trying. I know. Okay. Um,
I was hanging out with this girl.
I mean if you were,
if that was the only person that you had
slept with and like the last six months
and you didn't use protection and uh,
I mean as long as you told her just get
treated and I mean that's up to you if
you want to keep banging this girl or not,
but don't keep being in this girl.
Yeah, I'm probably not.
Especially if she, I mean,
because the thing is she could
at least be like, all right,
well let me go get tested just in case.
Yeah.
And then you could both be tested for
everything and get treated for everything
and that's all good. Yeah.
Going, I go your separate ways.
This is how this thing starts
off. Yeah, it's not good.
He obviously likes bagging her,
otherwise he wouldn't be asking this
question and might not be too many
prospects on the horizon.
If this is what it's come down to.
I'll go the obvious one. She's really
good at fucking, but she's done it a lot.
A lot of people maybe, maybe, well, maybe
she got on well, I mean she got unlucky.
Maybe she just had the gift.
I don't fucking know. Jeez.
Well I hope whatever you
got is hero section. Go to
the doctor. It gets treated.
Use Protection. Like don't be an
idiot. Stop raw dogging out here.
Okay. New Girls. No new
car. Sorry. New Car.
That was like a Freudian slip.
Like get a new girlfriend.
Get the fuck out of that
thing. Oh Man. Dude,
that's brutal. Makes you happy to
be married. All right. New Car.
Dear Billy Blue Book.
I'm in the market for a
new car like yourself.
I want to get something,
use something with character,
but my girlfriend thinks I'm holding
onto the past and I'm trying to be hip in
my own way.
She wants me to get a Passat.
What do you know how much of a creepy
sell out I'd have to be to drive a facade.
Thoughts? Sexy car. Why would your
girl wants you to get a facade?
That's some lame. I would want to see
the man. Mankind, not a fucking facade.
This keep on top of it was that,
but I also fucking drive an eight year
old dented Prius. I know, but you're,
I mean, I'm a frugal son about this. I
think it's a little bit different. Why?
Why is it different? Well, you didn't
tell me to get the fucking thing.
You know what is,
you know what it is out there.
There's so many fucking men and women
out there that that will derail your
fucking dreams.
They,
I wonder if she wants him to get a car
like a facade because I feel like that's
a reasonable safe car because she's
trying to get you to save up for a ring or
an apartment or something. Yeah. Look
at that thing. That is not, oh my God.
That's his solace as my car I've
ever seen in my fucking life.
That that is so boring. Yeah,
free is at least it's like,
what is that a Passat?
Whatever.
I was horrible and defected. Germans made
that Germans usually fucking crush it.
Well then I'm sure it's very efficient.
Leave that one alone. Um, but
other than that, I'm not into it.
I think the biggest thing here is what
happens to a lot of people when they get
into a relationship is, look, there's
definitely going to be some compromises,
but like when your heart's fucking racing
and you want to fucking do something,
or the person you're with and you can
see it, like this is something they want.
This is something of a passionate and
something's gonna make them happy for you
to try to fucking talk him out of
it. Like, why would you do that?
She wants him rain. That's why. And
she's trying to get them not to spend,
I have to spend money on an
older car that needs repairs,
pairs and the this and that and the other
when he could be saving for it rang.
I guaran fucking see it. Switch
to thinking. I absolutely think,
well if he gets a used car,
isn't that cheaper than
going out and getting a new
Passat? Uh, what, what is it?
Um,
what did he wants it?
I want to get something used and then
with character things I'm holding onto the
past and trying to be hip of Myeloma,
but does he meets wrong Kevin?
A little bit of style.
Asset. Car. He must plastic.
The miss means you have something like
that. She wants one of us get up the sun.
Right? She wants him to get a
nice cost. Modern. No, she uses,
we're going to have a family
and a house someday. Oh, car.
That's what that's about. Read between
the lines. Read in between the lines.
Oh, I thought she was the dream
catcher. You know, dream catcher.
Dream catcher is like,
your dream is this is my dream.
And then she catches it and she puts
it in your pocket like a dream killer.
Dream killer. Right? But
you got to catch it first.
It's like an ant.
You can't kill it much.
You just decide that things
are what you want them to be.
That a dream catcher is
really what a dream killer is,
but you have to catch it. Catch it
before you kill it. Okay, honey,
I live in my own little world
over here. Alright. Magma,
magma. Okay, dear bill, have you heard,
have you heard about the lonesome blues?
Have you heard of magma?
I just saw them in la.
They definitely sound like some
sort of fucking metal band here.
I'd never heard of them,
but what the friend of mine
who works in post production,
the drummer is 68 and unreal. All
right. I already loved this band.
He plays a combination of Jazz and
progressive style beats, tons of soul.
The music is interesting. An
operatic, oh, he invited his,
he invented his own language
and it's really out there.
Please look some up and give you
a reaction on the podcast. Well,
let me fucking do it really quickly.
We're running out of time here.
Let's see here. What do you think?
You think you're gonna like it?
Well, I'm curious about it. I'm
surprised the dude I was, I,
when I saw this crazy fucking band,
Bobby Lee's Bobby Lee's brothers in it,
and I went and I saw this crazy fucking
bad. Like I don't, I got to the show late.
I can't remember the name of the
band, but they'll fucking hot. Yeah.
Somebody tagged me in a picture you
took with one of the band members.
I had the best time
they had this one. Still look them up
so he can give them a shout out. Okay.
I the best fucking time.
All I remember was there fucking
they're closing song was,
was that the guitar was like
really likes fresh, fresh, fresh,
and the guy just what's going
like, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no. That was, it was just so
ridiculous. It was awesome and funny.
And I was just going to say,
you should put that on an album cover
and then have all the lyrics like written
out like, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Oh,
there French. Oh, they are Mac, mother.
Weird. Weirdest band in the world. All
right. Let's, let's see what we got here.
Yeah.
All right. I'm already in. I kinda
like it too. I would go see that.
That reminds me by about to this kind
of stuff you always reminds me of.
I used to go see, have you used to go see
Oz noy down in the village? Mas Noise.
O. Z. N. O. Y. Yeah. You
still always have like,
we'll Lee would be down there and Keith
Carlock would sit in and just settle.
He's insane drummers. Um,
look at me. Look at that.
Oh my God. Yeah. I love it.
They all look a little long in the two.
That actually
good. These guys are all BS. That guy,
the bass player looks like the cop that
walked up to the guy in the fucking
scooter. Yeah. All right. Oh
my God. I love these guys.
I'm speeding up. Oh,
what's going to happen?
Hang on. Why can't leave
it here? Here we go.
I'll let me fast forward so you'd
have to sit through. All right,
dude. I would just add this is the, yeah,
this is when it starts getting weird.
It gets all fucking night. Yeah, I'm
in know what I feel like if there was,
if we had our own version of the Andy
Warhols factory or something like that,
like a big loft space downtown when we
just had a bunch of our artists friends
and assorted Weirdos,
we can have magma playing in the
background and it just would make a lot of
sense and we're cause you could drown
out all those assholes that hang around
with people like that.
I'm not an Andy Warhol
fan on on any level.
Or you don't like his like persona?
No, I respect the originality of it,
but I also just feel like a lot of it was
smoke and mirrors and it was very like
that hipsters sort of
sort of the original,
the original of like that hipster shit.
Like am I going to paint a soup can and
then like it's some sort of comment on
capitalism and everything and
it's just like, all right,
but is it a really a deep comment
on it because it's not moving me.
I Dunno. I mean I like Andy
were high like his stuff.
I feel like that was a very cool time
to be in New York City during that time.
I feel like I would've loved to
been a part of that scene, but, um,
it just seemed to me like it was a
bunch of nerds trying to be cool,
pretending like a lot of hipsters to me.
I think there were a lot of,
I Ms. Smith that found each other and
they created like their own little world
and they became cool because of that.
Yeah,
that's what I think. All right.
Because there's a bunch of like,
you know what a transgendered
people and just like, yeah.
College and they're just automatically
cool automatically. Cool.
Can you just listen to what I'm saying?
Like there's no asshole
transgendered people.
Okay.
Can I explain to you what it was the
bringing together of all these different
kinds of people and that was
different in New York City.
It was like a whole birth of interesting,
like outsider perspectives and giving
them like a platform and like you're a
freak and you're cool. No,
no, I absolutely think so.
Then like though the, uh,
what is wrong? Why can't, why
if I have a different opinion,
you gotta fucking get upset. No, it's
not that you have a different opinion.
Is that you literally didn't even let
me finish my thought before you just
hopped on that whole thing
and that just makes you sound.
I interrupt. It's what I do. Fine.
You're taking this way too seriously.
Look,
do I have any sort of artistic style of
looking at me like I'm in a buffalo wild
wings. I'm going to sit here and criticize
fucking Andy Warhol. Her fucking,
oh yeah.
I took an an Elvis cover that somebody
else already created and then I painted
red and blue stripes across the war.
How can a very easily made that poster?
That's the kind of stuff that he made.
Actually there is a poster of
him and on John Michel Basquiat,
that was kind of like my tour poster.
Yeah,
like the kind of like battle of them
boxing and stuff like that poster could
100% have been what Andy Warhol did
if you were famous back in the day.
That's what I'm saying.
So he's saying he's not original.
I'm saying the person that did that,
perhaps putting a head on something,
was he the first guy that he's the first
day I was Photoshop shit style to that
poster, which is really cool
by the way. And like that.
It reminds me a little bit of
what Warhol might have done.
That's all I'm saying.
When you went to a museum though, like
let's be honest, I don't like them.
I really don't like it. Look, if
it's, if it's a bunch of old cars,
if it's painting old cars, if it's
paintings, uh, cars, you know,
there's a big debate actually,
the art community,
our automobiles works of art and they
took a Ralph Lauren's car collection and
they stuck it in one of those
fucking stuck up museums there.
Moma, whatever the fuck it is.
Museum of natural history. The, the,
I don't think they put it in. Let me
see the fucking on the fifth avenue,
whatever the fuck it's called. Every
other fucking broad. I dated in New York,
that was always the first date. Like
they, oh, let's go to a museum. It's like,
well you stop back and look at smart.
Stop doing this.
Just cause you're dumb. Does stop
trying. Trying to be, oh for fuck sakes.
Let's just go out and get a drink and
see if we can deal with each other.
I got to go fucking sit there
and stand next to you in silence.
Reading Shit above dinosaur bones.
Yeah, that sounds like a lot of fun.
I'll meet you there.
Um,
no I don't like them.
I don't like,
one of the worst museums I
ever went to was when we went,
we were in Vatican City and we should've
gone to the right just to look at that
overrated painting on the fucking ceiling.
We went to the,
can we just pause and I just,
they know what I'm talking about.
They know about the Sistine Chapel,
so fucking overrated sizing the
art that was in the mannequin.
Like this art, that's like hundreds
of planet. I'm telling you what now,
like this amazing, if I bought
that building torcal fucking art,
if I bought that building
the Sistine Chapel,
I would turn that into a cigar room and
I would let that smoke go right up into
that overrated. Do they make
it seem like it's fucking huge?
There's no way it took that long
bill.
You went in there and you looked at him
for like five seconds and then you were
like ready to get a fucking
Panini bull shitting you.
I'm going to tell you I'm going to end.
He was like the original contractor.
They said, hey, can you paint my ceiling?
Uh, yeah. Yeah. This will be easy.
I'll have this done in like three
fucking weeks. Fucking four years later.
Yeah. They're fucking the
green page on back order.
He's got 20 other ceilings
he's fucking working on.
Um,
I mean you can't tell me when you went
through the whole Vatican thing and you
watched every fucking investement that
every goddamn pope ward like after a
while you like, I get it. They all
wore these ponchos with a cross on it.
I was fascinated by it because
I love religious art. Oh, okay.
What about sexual assault? What about it?
He'll fucking 800 pound gorilla. What?
Don't they have a little something
about that in there? Yeah,
cause I kind of went,
yeah,
well that would have ruined the
year while there was an art,
the way they hit all those pedophiles,
all those years.
That's an art form to be moving all
those chess pieces around while still
collecting the money and not paying taxes.
What does that have to do with
the art that we're talking about?
Saying of the Vatican?
Well,
if I was to talk about a certain
somebody Sitcom right now,
I think you would bring up
some of his offstage behavior.
Are we talking about Cosby? No, we're
talking about fucking slapping. Right?
Uh,
the,
the priests are the ones that
were painting the fucking
Sistine Chapel Bill. No,
I taught,
I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about when we looked at
every fucking fork and chalice that Pope
John Paul the fucking 58th.
When you go into the Sistine Chapel,
which admittedly I thought it was
the 16th chapel. Did you really?
You don't remember that we are
staying on line. I remember I said,
you know what I would do, because this
line is so fucking long. If I lived here,
I would open a bar across the street.
Now we call it the 17th chapel.
And you're like, why would you call it
that? I was like 16 chapel to 70 chapel.
And he just looked at me and your
eyes narrowed. And he said, Bill,
it's the Sistine Chapel.
And I said,
that's my story about Rome.
Okay.
Alrighty. Fuck all you guys.
All right. 37 years old,
ladies and gentlemen. Yeah,
I'm not into that shit.
Okay. You know. Okay. See that,
look at you. You're an angel.
You can see through my
stupidity. You don't have to
be into it. I still love you.
It's, you know, it is a good
guy. It's still, you know what?
But the reality is that there are
certain things that are common knowledge.
I really should have known that.
I would think so.
But I bet a lot of people think it's the
16th chapel. You know something I don't,
uh, I don't like, I don't get
embarrassed by shit like that.
You really don't know if I think I would.
Yeah. Yeah. I thought it was the 16th.
I didn't know it was the disgusting and
then a big, oh my God. It's assisting.
It's like,
did,
is anything in there from something
that you created then shut up.
What are you, oh, that was the
Apollo 13 mission. Oh really?
You were fucking astronaut.
It's just sitting in this diner with
me getting fucking eggs, aren't ya?
And they're not the farmer's market once
either. It's why you don't like the,
the museums.
Do you feel like there is a pretension
and people who like art and stuff like
that? It's too much fucking
shit. It's too much reading.
It's reading. Oh my God. It just
keeps going and going and going.
And then there's people whispering.
Sure.
That's what happened to me in the,
in the Sistine Chapel when we walked
in and I was just like, oh wow.
It's kind of small anyway.
Sure.
Oh,
I wanted to put that guy's head right
to the fucking stained glass window that
we were in a church. So it's like a holy
place. So you know, you gotta keep it.
Why would think they went on a certain
level of noise to drown out the
children's screen in the basement? Oh
my God. They deserve it. Fuck them.
Pieces of shit. Um, we can't,
we can't end it with that.
Why isn't the dog coming in here?
I'm a little concerned. Oh, play. Oh,
because she's a Clo. Oh, poor
thing. She's right there,
right baby. All right. That's
the podcast for this week.
I'll check in on you.
She was sleeping on Thursday.
What's that? Oh, she was
sleeping. Okay, cool. All right.
She was just sleeping well,
thank you for hanging out on the
podcast. Thanks for having me. All right.
I'm glad you came by.
I don't think those stories of people
falling off shit would have been as fun
and somebody to bounce it off of. Oh,
look who's here. Sleepy old gray bear.
Yes. Seeing your dog. I know.
We just realized that dog's
a senior now. She's eight.
She's eight and a half years old.
Starting to get a little bit
of white in her face. Yeah.
That made me sad and it made me happy.
You know,
she had a rough first year and a half
and she's just been fucking chill in ever
sense, haven't you cleo? She looks
great though and she's still adorable.
She's still our little
baby no matter what.
Well I think she had to pay rent at
this point. All right, that's it.
I'll talk to you guys on Thursday
and once again, Sarah, see Matt,
thank you to everybody that
came out this weekend, uh,
for those shifts are
scratching the shows, um,
at Riverside and the terrorists theater.
And I want to thank Dean
del Ray for crushing it both
nights. And um, that's it.
I got Canada coming up later on this
week. I'm going to be in Ontario. Um,
you know where Ottawa and
a bunch of places. Um,
I think Windsor, I have no idea.
They're all on my website. Um,
I'm bringing oh Jesus.
Oh Geez.
I better hit the fucking treadmill cause
I'm bringing fucking the pride or New
Jersey. Paul Versey and the the
godfather of the Rosebowl tailgate,
Joe Barton. Nick himself is a,
he's going to be coming along too,
and uh, it's going to be a killer
fucking show. All right. That's it.
I'll talk to you guys later.