Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
March 17th,
2014 St Patrick's day fallen on a Monday.
We're really going to see who the
fucking real drinkers are. This.
You don't want to falls in
Monday. Either way, whatever.
I'm still touring Canada with the
wonderful Paul Versey who was once again a
special guest here on the podcast.
Welcome Paul. Versey. Oh, what's up man?
I'm hanging in there. I'm doing well in,
what do we got left? Tell me what days.
Put the blinders on and didn't think
about getting home. You can't and we got,
what do we got? We got
tonight, we got, you had to,
were worth three days away from being
home. We got one tonight and vent. Cool.
Yeah. Then we're in a Victoria,
Korea. Then we go back to Calgary.
Back to those animals, animals, animals
in Calgary. Jesus, not the first show.
The second show. Wow. I'm
like, God, I'm trying to, yeah.
We wanted to reach out to
people in Calgary before we,
we just brand everybody in Calgary
animals like they were fucking pounds.
You know, that first show was
great. They, yeah, they were great.
That second show though. Whoa.
Yeah, yeah. They were like,
uh, they will come in and
with cases, a tall boys,
they were allowed to bring those little,
those little cardboard pallets hammered,
hammered fucking hammer.
Then they had like, uh, at,
you know, I think part of it had to do
with the fact that it was at a college.
So I think there was college kids there
that just put myself in that mindset
going, dude, I drank like that when
I was in college. This isn't how,
I don't know they'll do it.
That wasn't all college people because I
asked the crowd and like, that was just,
I think that was a lot of just Calgary
man. I think that was late at night.
You know, the, I think what
was permitted on the premise,
it's turned them into fucking animals.
Yeah. You know they, you know what,
by the time I went on stage and I
got halfway through my set, it was a,
most of them had kind of like passed out
like it got was getting quiet and I was
standing up there going like,
am I bombing up here?
And I just kind of was looking at like
five different people who will laugh
their ass off. And I'm like, I'm
just going to say my head this sober.
Like there's no way if I'm really bomb.
And I got somebody laughing that hard.
So I was just like, maybe this
show's gone on too long. I'm like,
I'll say that was a rough one. You
know, it was animals and Calgary.
What was at the zoo? So fun. So then,
then we were driving out,
you,
me and [inaudible] were trying to find
a place to smoke a stoby inside. Right.
Or they had this,
they had on that campus,
which was really exciting to me was
they had the speed skating loop from the
1988 Olympics and they still had ice on
it. We were trying to get on that fucker.
I'll do. That would've been
a great youtube video if
they loaned us some speeds.
Gates going out there in a stand up comedy
close with those giant blades on it.
I just want to be going fast enough.
I want to be going fast enough where
I'm turned so to the side they can put
those three fingers down, you know when
you go around the corner. Oh my God. Yeah.
No, I would never, I would have been on
youtube for the wrong reasons. All starts,
you
would have wiped out and I wanted,
you know, when they wipe out,
when the centrifical force
just takes you into the stance.
Yeah,
that would have been a,
that would have been me. So anyways,
we're trying to do that. Uh,
we ended up finding this
great place to smoke a cigar,
so we're driving out and we're trying
to figure out going to do was, you know,
we're talking about the show going like
there wasn't me or that first show was
good, but that second show. Wow.
Um, did you feel the same way?
And we don't basically exchanging notes.
And as we drive out of the venue, uh,
we see this group of fucking hammered
people and this guy he's got,
you know what those things like when
they have a parade, go down the street,
those giant like metal um,
barriers or barricades. Yeah,
those metal ones that have like,
it looks like a fucking, I dunno,
whatever giant metal barricade.
This fucking guy picks it up with one
hand and he's got it over his shoulder,
turns around,
sees us coming and then waves us through
like he's some sort of official for
half a second. The way he did it, I
thought he was. And then as I drove by,
I'm looking at them and I see he's Sam,
he's hammered and then I see on his face
it registers that were the two comics
he just saw. So, um,
I just pull away from him and as I'm
driving and you're going like, wow, man,
that guy just had, was carrying that
thing with one hand. What the fuck?
I turn around and look in the rear view
mirror and this guy's running after the,
the co we're doing probably
like about 15 miles an hour.
And this dude is running,
I was saying he looked like,
you know when they show highlights of
Babe Ruth hitting a home run when they
show him running and fast legs? Yeah
he was, I think he was mocking running.
I don't think he was really gonna do
anything cause I didn't get scared.
But I want to look in the rear view
mirror and I just saw this guy.
Just imagine you're driving along
after a fucking work and or whatever.
I kind of halfway out of it and then
you look in the rear view mirror and you
see somebody running.
But in this exaggerate rated way where
he was like pumping his fucking arms like
that,
it was like he was mocking it.
I didn't see it. All I saw was you
go, what the f you go, what the fuck?
And you just stepped on the gas.
But I was in the past
underpowered fucking rental car
and all of a sudden you go, what the fuck?
And I go, what? And he just stepped in,
I guess you go that got you started
running after the car. And I was like,
Holy Shit. Because I saw
one of his friends, right.
One of the just collapsed, like they
were so hammered that he didn't hit any,
he just felt like I just fell
and I just saw his legs go up.
But they were fucked up
through those kids. I would
be lying if like,
like three times yesterday and this
morning I woke up and I was picturing that
guy running behind the car and I laugh
every time. It was fucking nuts. Yeah.
Those guys were hammering man. Yeah.
So we got tip tip of the cap to a,
the drinking ability.
Yeah.
Not Encouraging that from
where we come back Wednesday.
We definitely like to have people try to
behave more like the first show where,
uh,
you know,
I don't feel like I'm interrupting your
drinking with my most of my jokes. Yeah.
That, yeah. That was deaf stuff. They were
great doll. The crowds are great. Yeah.
Yeah, they were great. But yeah, man,
that was still was another level. Yeah,
there was, there's always
a couple, there's always a
couple of hammered people,
but that was where it was getting to
the tipping point. Like kind of like,
you know, right before Hitler took
power where it's just like, what
side am I going to choose here for?
My own survival is,
that's what the drunk
versus sober level was.
By the time I got about 40 minutes into
my set, it was kind of like you're doing,
you're doing an hour plus I'm going
out there, up front, you know,
I could kind of see that their animals,
but you know, he just, you going out to,
by the time you're
halfway through your set,
these guys are like six tall boys in.
It's a shit show.
It's a fucking shit show is shit show
Edmonton Edmonton was unbelievable.
Edmonton at that venue.
You remember that one with the
orchestra fucking place there. Oh yeah.
That was great. So then when we have
a great time there and then the uh,
we ended up, uh, what the fuck did we
go? I remember we kept leaving the hotel.
We kept joint drove around or, but
you had, you had to get socks first.
He's fucking hilarious birds.
He has not done laundry.
I bought new shit, you know
dude, we're like 20 what?
Seventies we were 16 days in.
Yeah.
You've got 16 days worth the
fucking socks and drawers. Yeah,
I got them in a plastic bag and, and I
went to the store and I bought new ones.
You know what would have cost
me the same fucking thing.
We got to take a picture of your bag at
some point. Post it up big as it gets.
Yeah. Oh, he has them on the outside
pouch. What? You're checking the bag.
So I guess it doesn't matter, but uh,
I just did mine for the second time.
I that I fucking hate
having a dirty laundry.
You go back past a certain amount of days,
like I'm doing three,
four days in a row. Plastic bags
stuffed them in the front or whatever,
but mainly do mine at home.
Is it,
do you do what it does your wife do it and
my wife does it. Yeah. Yeah, me too. Hey,
I got an in line,
you know,
so anyways, last week, uh Oh wait, I gotta
finish the Edmond Think Edmonton thing.
So first he is completely addicted to
skating now and he wants to get better at
it. And um, so we're
fucking then uh, Edmonton,
the next morning we got to
drive down to Calgary in force.
He's going like this gotta be a place here
to skate. So we find out they have, uh,
they have a skating rink at the
mall and I only use it a mall.
It's one of the most giant malls
in North America. America. Yeah.
West Edmonton Mall rivaling. Uh, what's
that one in Minnesota. Mall of America.
All of America. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
So, which I've been to that one too.
So we go to that one.
We're walking through there with a
fucking skates to middle aged guys walking
through this thing with fucking
skates and a, we walk in,
there's like this giant pirate
ship. I mean like, yeah,
you could say all the fucking ocean
with this fucking thing. Yeah.
It was a flicker of official
and I look on the other side.
It was really deep water and they took
all this time to make it look like there
was a ship wreck. Jesus Christ. I
mean like you could fucking, yeah,
it was monstrous man. Like Shaq could
drown in this water if he didn't.
That's how fucking deep it was.
Huge.
And then we look on the other
side and I'm like, Paul, I'm like,
is that a fucking sea lion?
They had sea lions at this thing and
they're like thrown at fishing. Fishing.
It was catching trainer was don't,
it wasn't like people just walking
by throwing shit from the food court.
It was a trainer throwing it.
And um,
so we're just walking through the mall,
walking through the mall.
Endless fuck him all. They had a
water park there. Yeah, it was,
I didn't look at any stores. I was too
distracted by the shit in the middle.
And then we finally get all the way to
the ice palace that called the Ice Palace
and we got all excited and we're the
only people with skates just walking
through,
holding a fucking dump skates and we
get all the way to the other side versus
all excited. Like, dude, I'm telling you,
I'm gonna get better at this. You wait,
I was getting, I was ready this
summer. He was already talking shit,
they were calling it right now.
I'm going to be fucking skating backwards.
You're going to be like, what the
fuck happened? Versie yeah, right.
And then we show up and uh,
there's a big judo tournament where the
ice rink is and they'd fucking put all
this floor flooring all over
it. How is it denial? I'm like,
maybe this isn't the rank. Maybe this
analysis dude, it says ice palace fall.
This is it. They covered it up. This is
it. I've got upset though at the moment.
Remember number, that girl,
man, that really bothered me.
We were walking through the food
court and you know, we had a gyro.
Great Gyro and just, yeah,
yeah, a great shower.
Or just please call Jimmy
the Greek dawn complaint.
And you agreed a little too much
white sauce and it was pasty. Yeah.
Wasn't it wasn't, yeah, it
was a little PC. One scoop.
He went to one school blessing a little
hot sauce and it would have been far
sighted. He got excited. It would have
been epic. Yeah, we, you got excited.
So then I said to bill, you know, I like
a little dessert after I eat, you know,
I like a little candy bar.
I like a little, you know,
so I love sugar. New Tech.
Okay.
So, so I go bill man, it was a
frozen yogurt place. I go, yeah,
pink berry or someone said God's
going frozen yogurt. See, all right,
so we're walking like paint the picture.
So to middle aged men was
skates and I was like, okay.
You keep saying I'm Middle Age,
you are middle age.
I'm 30 I just turned 35 35 times
two is 70 most guys fucking drop.
Well I called, I called like I called
middle it. Yeah. All right. What,
what would you call it? No, I guess, I
guess you're right. I guess, you know,
I always just, when I thought of it as a
kid, I always felt, you know, it was Nah,
I don't know. I just remember,
dude, I, it's, I don't know,
we'll just say 40 forties but I,
you're not bored for 40 people.
Do people live long, man, dude,
I'm fucking be 46 46 times two
is 92 you're going to really,
I can't really sit there and say,
I'm middle age.
Tell you the way I'm eating and smoking,
you know?
Okay.
No. So, so we walked through and
we're, we're like, where's that,
where was that a frozen yogurt place?
Let's go to that frozen yogurt place.
So we too, we see two young
women walk by and we figure, Hey,
I looked at him and I'm like,
these, these, these ladies,
they're going to know where they're
going to know where a pink berry is.
So we walk up and you go first. You say
to the friend, you go, hey, you got,
you guys know her. Oh, that good. They're
good looking too by the way. You yeah.
Good, good looking girls.
And you go up first, you go,
hey you guys know where the frozen yogurt
places and like she did like a double
take. Like she did a double
take, so fucking rude.
Right. And she just was like,
what? And then I looked at the other
one and I go, yeah, like a pink berry.
And she kinda just like gives a shake off.
Like how would I know?
Like why are you and she fucking did.
This is what she did.
She did the classic pretty girl,
you're clearly just asking me this
because you want to talk to me
thing. And I'm like, no bitch,
I want some fucking yogurt.
Okay, I want fucking, I want
to fucking treat. You know,
I just had lunch and it
really bothered me dude.
And we were walking around and I wanted
to find her. I wanted to find this again.
They did the loop on the phone.
I didn't know that,
but I said to bill and we got to the car.
I go,
I wanted to find it cause I would
have just went up to and go,
you know something. I found it and
you're a mean jerk, and then you go,
why would you do that?
Jerk. That's terrible. What am I
going to call her a cunt? Well,
don't call her anything if you're going
to go with me and jerk. I mean, you know,
I hate that you're a girl mentality.
That pretty good day.
You're mean or you're a jerk if you
want to stay clean. But if you go,
you're a mean jerk. No,
you're not. You're not.
You're not pretty inside in a pretty
inside. It doesn't give a fuck.
She's the hot girl at the mall. Pall.
Put yourself in her fucking pumps
with two fucking jackass is standing
there with ice skates when there's a judo
tournament down the way, asking if
they know where the ice cream store is.
They looked at us the way they were
supposed to. I, you know what, dude?
I like a sweetheart.
I don't care how you,
I would love to hear them tell the story
and then they come and then there's
just creepy guy comes up.
Oh good.
Where they're going to
hear it, Paul. Paul,
you ever watch those fucking prison shows?
Which ones? Like the scared straight?
No, not those ones. Where they,
they talk about the worst prisons in the
country and that type of ship. Oh yeah.
I seen a couple of minutes.
And you just sit there watching it going.
How the fuck would I go in there and
not get raped? What would my game plan?
He gets scared watching
it in your bedroom, right?
Women have to walk out of
the house worried about that.
That somebody is going to, you
know, do just imagine if if, uh,
winter hat on with a puffy ball
on top of it, holding ice skates,
asking for yogurt. If anything, she
probably thought I was fucking gay.
You don't look gay, Paul. I
know, but you're not this.
You're not your beards to terrorists who
need to get a little more metro sexual
and not to do that. We were sweared
sweatpants on. Do we want a mess?
Everybody in the fucking girl.
Yeah, that's what you look my beard.
My beard actually fucking says everybody
on the fucking ground. No, but dude,
I don't like the pretty girl who can't
be approached with a question because Oh,
this guy's hitting on me. It's, it's
awful. And you know something that got,
especially the blonde one who went
like shook her head like what?
She's going to be a nightmare. She's a
fucking nightmare for some future guy.
I'm telling you. She's a nightmare.
She's already selfish. It's over.
What if she just knows what
she wants and we're not at,
Oh this is the thing dude.
You actually aloud like how
old do you think they were?
Probably 2122 yeah.
You learn at 2122 year old.
I met a girl at my age,
not even a one way.
She shook it all that and
you let her ruin like to do,
we're driving down to Calgary.
She wrote,
I got the rocky mountains on the right
hand side of the car and you're just
still calling. You're calling
her a cunt the whole way down
and bothered the shit out of me. It was
like, why are you, why would you ask me?
How would I know? Dude? You realize how
funny that is that they did that to us?
Like what? Like yeah, they really made us
feel like shit. That's fucking hilarious.
If you look at it,
it bothered me the whole time is cause
you wanted to get frozen yogurt that how
funny would it be if we chased him down
and frozen yogurt with sugar free gummy
bears on it.
It was still all natural,
no organic gummy because how great would
it be if we chased him down and I just
walked up to her and I go, you know
something, you hurt my feelings.
I just fucking broke down. You hurt
my feelings. I just want a yogurt.
Oh by the way, people listen.
Listening here. This is last
week. You know, you know,
just trying to kill, just trying to
make jokes to not go out of your mind.
Being on tour this fucking long is we
were doing the danger field. Everything.
I'll tell you, I've got a friend
of mine loves yogurt, you know,
so we were doing that
and once that went away,
that got old somewhere along
the line you started doing it,
you started saying really sentimental
shit to me and then pretending like you
were crying and then that just became
like the running joke and then you started
laughing and then you were just like,
you got to do that on stage,
do that crime and things. So now we'll
just go up and like if we'll be like,
hey man, I'm tired, but dude,
you know what? Hang on, hang on.
What you on the road has been great.
You're the only one I
could have done it with.
And then bill would come and tag it.
That's the best thing.
Bill would come and tag and
I would just be like, oh,
I was hoping you were going to say that.
It's been,
it's been fucking wonderful for my anger.
I'm going to try to do that when I got
home and like 10 like I'm crying man.
It's fucking hilarious.
So two stories.
We go in to eat and we have this
Filipino waiter, right? By the way,
I like to play the Games where I sort of
hell, where are we? Was that Edmonton?
Was that Calgary? I was having to, yeah,
it was Edmonson so I like to do this
thing where sometimes I like to fuck with
people so I'll just get on a
phone and I'll be like, Bill,
go along with it and we'll be in
an elevator and I'll go, what? No,
that's horse shit. And like bill, just
look what happens. So like I said,
like he had a parole
officer called and he said,
and bill goes all they worked it
up and then instantly Burgos. Yeah.
What about that video tape?
I go, Nah, Nah, they said
it's insubmissible and like,
and like the guy, there's just
a stranger. They're right.
Sometimes I break out laughing. So bill
calls it, he gets a little emotional guy.
So we turn this crying thing, we do it to
like, this has been great, right? We turn,
we turned that into doing it in public.
So we have this Filipino waiter, right.
And the whole guy guy was great and he
was talking to us and at the end I just
go, he goes, here's your bill.
And I go, I just want to say stop.
And I kept the dead straight face
and you've been a great waiter.
And I put my hand on his
fucking arm and got, you know,
you're bringing the waters and bill just
looks at and goes. He gets a little,
he gets a little emotional, you know
what I mean? I know, but it's big.
It means a lot guy didn't know what to do.
I had no cause he was so fucking polite.
And he was actually from the Philippines.
So he's jumped right in.
Perfectly good for. And he gets a
little emotional like no, but Billy,
he'd been the waters and I'll do it.
Well he was freaked out. Dot. Yeah,
that's the new game on the road.
You have the best one. I got to say,
the best one was at the airport yesterday.
We got to the airport yesterday and
bill starts busting my balls about my
laundry and he goes, Versie fucking 16
days. And you're caring. And you know,
dirty socks and underwear. And I
go, dude, I go, I bought new ones.
You know the dirty ones
are tied up tight in a,
in a plastic bag and bill just goes,
just secure emotions. And Dude,
I fucking could not walk.
I couldn't walk and I had to stop pulling
my fucking the bag I'd checked cause
we were laughing so hard. And it does,
it works though. It makes it, it makes,
it's fucking great. It's driving
a tour manager nuts. Oh yeah.
That's the one thing we yeah,
well because women don't want to see
a guy getting emotional like that.
It's just, well no, cause once
somebody cries it's over. Yeah.
Like when I go out afterwards and I'm
taking pictures with people and stuff,
I always come back. I was just
saying, I got to tell you, you know,
I've seen a lot of people do that,
you know, doing the picture thing,
but you gotta be one of the best
wives. She's going, would
you stop fucking doing that?
Our wives are going to go nuts.
Cause you know the first thing I,
when I see stays and you see your wife,
we're just going to go. It's been so long.
I miss you so much. No, you gotta,
you gotta set it up with talking like
you got to start off normal white day.
You're going to say something really
sentimental to them so they're almost
crying and then you cry, which ruins
their crying and I swear to God,
you get slugged in the shoulder,
which is all you really want. Um,
I'm the minutes in here. I think it's
time to do a little advertising here,
you know? Okay. What have we got then? I
just shut it off. No, I didn't. Oh Shit.
20 minutes in. I'll
tell you Paul, you know,
time really flies with you on the podcast.
It's been so fun.
This is probably only funny to us,
but I don't give a shit.
Try it with your friends stuff. Fuck that.
If people are with the game is called,
he gets emotional and
just walk into a bar.
Just have one of your friends started
hitting on a woman and then the other
friends got to go along.
Yep,
and then just starts welling up and
then the other guy goes on. Sorry.
He just gets emotional and you just got
to let the other person deal with it.
Dude,
you don't want it.
The fucking airport where you walked
up to that lady at the con though,
the little fucking I sell gum, whatever
the hell it is. He said, excuse me,
do you have the one of the biggest
night I broke out of, I go, hey ma'am,
I need to, what are the
biggest condoms you got there?
What's the biggest size condoms you have?
I turned around and walked away and you
turned around and walked away and I'm
just staring at her and I'm biting my
tongue as hard as I can to not laugh and
then I just burst out laughing.
She said what?
And then when you went to repeat it,
you try to point to it and I lost it.
You lost it and had to walk away. Paul,
we're punchdrunk out here. All right.
I got to do a little, I'm going
to do some advertising here. Okay.
Hulu plus everybody.
You've probably tried hulu.com
this is new. This is Hulu plus.
You can watch your favorite shows anytime,
anywhere with Hulu.
Plus they told me to
stress plus this week.
Hulu plus let you watch thousands of
hit TV shows in a selection of a claim.
Movies on your television or on the go
with your smart phone or tablet and it
all streams in HD for the best viewing
experience possible. This is incredible.
[inaudible].
You can watch stuff right on your
phone in HD quality with Hulu plus,
I like this.
You can watch your favorite current TV
shows like Saturday night live community
and family guy.
You can also check out exclusive
content including Hulu originals,
like the auth thumbs starring Snl,
Seth Meyers and move boys' starring Chris
O'Dowd from bridesmaid with Hulu plus
a. Also offers a great selection of
a claim films for only 799 a month.
You can stream as many TV shows and
movies as you want, wherever you want.
How do you get it right now? You can
try Hulu plus free for just two weeks.
When you go to Hulu plus.com/bill this
is a special offer for just my listeners.
Make sure you go to Hulu plus.com/bill
so you get the extended free trial and
that they know I sent you.
Go to Hulu plus slash bill now or click
on the Hulu plus banner on the podcast
page at [inaudible] dot com I would
like a like a morning radio show here.
All right, dollar shave
club, everybody. Okay guys,
you've heard me talk about how much I
love Love Dollar Shave club.com so why
haven't you joined?
It makes your life so much better.
Like you don't have anything better to
do and then go to the store or anything
better to spend your money on.
Then raises what's wrong with
you and the last two years,
dollar shave club.com has served that
saved hundreds of thousands of dollars.
A 100,000 of guys time by delivering
amazing razors and high quality grooming
products right to their door.
Go to dollar shave club.com forward
slash burr shave with their razors.
I'm a forex guy,
but my buddies swears by as executive is
that my split personality talking there
and check out Dr Cab is easy shave.
Seriously.
This stuff is amazing.
It makes shaving feel like you're softly
wiping whiskers off your face. Oh,
what a visual that is tremendous writing
there and you can't forget about one
white Challies the butt wipes from men.
That's right.
A buttwipe for men. Peppermint
tingle enough said, try it out.
Your sphincter will love you.
Is that the right word for your asshole?
What are you waiting for?
You can get deliveries every other month
if you need and you can cancel anytime.
If you don't like it.
Dollar Shave club.com wants you to be a,
I want you to be great and keep
extra cash in your pocket. A,
I'm a member of dollar shave
club.com now it's your turn to,
we've already made the point. Why are we
still going here? Shave time, shave money.
Join Dollar Shave club.com go to dollar
shave club.com forward slash bar to let
them know that I sent you.
That's dollar shave club.com.
Forward Slash burr. Oh Geez.
What are we going to left here?
I'll save, I'll say this
one. One more here Paul,
where you think back to the podcast. Back
the podcast. Here we go. Alright. Right.
I'll tell you what happened in join
up here. Oh, let me tell Ya Dude,
they show fucking, uh, hockey highlights.
You can't believe I'm not watching any
gangs because I'm traveling and I'm
totally staying up on it. Like, you know,
like that a Sunday night when they
show all the football highlights,
it's incredible. Everywhere we've gone
down to sit, there's been a TV within
our right there. Plan,
I ain't write up on it.
I'm watching the Bruins when I'm watching
Tyler Sega and having a great year,
but they got smoked by the sabers.
I watched the flyers highlights
of a big win over over, uh,
the penguins. I know Vancouver
just beat Longo down in Florida.
I know that fucking old
old, uh, uh, flashy toes.
There is back between the
pipes in Montreal price. Yeah.
Hey, look at me. The it got, his
first goal is I'm a Canadian.
I'm just sitting there watching this.
Paul,
as I'm having a beer with you and an Irish
coffee in a pub around the corner and
my listeners know that I never
drink on pet saint Patrick's day.
It's fucking amateur night to use
Jackie Gleason's famous phrase.
Not If you do it early enough though. I
think it's amateur hour tonight. Listen,
not if but we'll be there or not.
If you're in your hotel and all of a
sudden they say there's a gas leak and you
can fucking smell it.
You have to run down the stairs.
Then what he's supposed to do to,
how about the left half?
You Shit in the room and you walk up the
street and there's a guy with bagpipes
playing that green analog 80 no, no neck
goose. You're not going to go in there.
You know. I'm glad you were had to
look at the band. I'm glad that you're,
you're my vantage point
with my back to them.
And you had to look cause when she went
into that like Irish hip hop beat and I
just turned for a second so her
like jumping up and down, I just,
I probably would've lost oh yeah,
this is going, I get it back.
She can't make head could get back and
got my guess.
I told what can eat right now. How
about that? I said where you go dude.
I hope this is good cause if it's not,
I'm just going to have to stare
at my beer. Yeah. Cause she,
she intro to it and it was good.
I just said a version of it,
but it was more saying,
they were actually very text
saying this is like Scottish, uh,
beatboxing and I just looked
at Paul and I go poff,
she's about ready do Scottish beatboxing
from the old country. And I go,
this is either going to be amazing or
I'm going to have to sit here staring at
my beer. Uh, Vancouver's awesome.
Praying for it to be over. Well,
let's go to the guests leak.
So we're sitting here in
the hotel. Oh yeah. And um,
you know, I know verse, he is not a
morning person. I have not called you one.
I haven't woken you up other than before
going to the airport just to make sure
your comments. So if we have a day off,
I don't fuck with you. I let you wake up.
Yeah, it's, it's a great, it's
great. I don't poke the bear,
so I know that we're
going to do the podcast.
We were gonna try to do it
around 12 noon here and uh,
cause I'm trying to sleep off this little
cold that I've, I've caught. But um,
all of a sudden you, you call me,
I'm like, oh great. Versus these up.
And then you're like, damn dude,
Hailey's, hey, what's going on?
There's a gas leak in the building.
They told us to get out of here.
And I'm just sitting there like,
no,
I was walking out to go get lunch and
all of a sudden I see a construction
worker come in full thing. He just runs
in. He goes, hey, yeah, we're running.
We got running. Like it scared me as
I'm walking out, he just goes, hey,
we got a guest and I just smell and
there's a hundred construction workers
outside and just warning
people to run down the street.
It was like a fucking seat. Some
gone, oh shit. Bills up there.
So let me call it bill because
it's a friend like shit
that you thought about me.
Okay.
So I called bill and I go, dude, you got
to go. There's a gas leak and it smells.
You got it. They're going to probably
evacuate you go you, you cut me off.
You heard gas leak and they're probably
going evacuate what? You go do it.
I'm on my way down. And then you just
got the fuck you got the fuck out.
And I don't mind getting blown up.
I'm worried about burning to death.
So I had to get the fuck out of this.
So I'm grabbing everything and I'm sitting
there going, I've got to get out of,
you've got to get out of here.
And I grab my watch and I'm like,
that's going to be the move right there.
That fucking kills me. So I go outside,
you know, try to find the exit
and I've run it down and thing.
And when I got to the the right to right
where I go, I'm on the fifth floor. Okay.
These, this construction guys were working
on some sort of line in the street and
somebody fluffed up and hit something.
Yeah.
So I got right to the fire escape doors
doing and it smelled like when you go to
light a grill and you think you have,
uh,
some juice left in your automatic lighter
and there isn't and you just take that
extra three seconds to find some
matches and then you light it and goes,
you don't get, Whoa, what the
fuck? That's what it smelled like.
A little more intense. And I'm
thinking, I'm on the fifth floor.
This fucking place. Yeah. So
I ran down those stairs, um,
and went out the side and then I got off
the side of the building thinking, okay,
I'm safe.
And I still smelled it almost worse.
And I was standing right
outside the hotel. Yeah.
Trying to find you and I could
still smell it. I'm like,
if this whole fucking thing's going up,
I'm going to get knocked on my ass here.
Cause it at the least because
I can still smell the shit.
I've got a hat on with the pump pod,
Paul,
I'm going to go up like a fucking
bowling alley. So then they finally said,
they told all of us to get the hell
out of the way and we backed up.
We went down the street, we
got some breakfast and it
thought it was really nice.
A little bit.
It's never not funny.
The Nice. Anyways, the Nice thing
is you got, you got the out here.
You wouldn't have blown,
you were a bird right with the balcony
because they're going to bow. Well,
I have a balcony on the fifth floor and
then there's like a patio right on the
other side of it. I don't know, Paul,
when you're on fire, you don't want to be,
I don't mind blowing up. I just don't
want to burn the debt. It's fucking awful.
Yeah. If there's an explosion, I want
to die. I don't want to be coming out,
you know, running down the street like
that naked girl in the Vietnam picture.
That girl like get cause you got
burned by fucking agent orange.
That's what she's,
she's running down the street cause
skin is hanging off a fucking backside.
Horrible. It's fucking horrible. Paul,
you have a [inaudible] greatest Vancouver.
Yeah. Now we got the image of a naked
girl running down the street on fire. Uh,
yes. That's all. But that's
what I was thinking of. Sorry.
That image touched me when I saw it.
Nobody should die like that.
I swear
to God.
I hope they find them is funny.
And this is going to be most annoying
podcast ever. Whatever. Fuck you.
You go to Canada for 20 days
dancing like a monkey. You,
you'd got to come up with some shit too.
We get emotional. Um, Vancouver. Yeah,
Vancouver's great. Love it.
I love the Edmonton Calgary.
Unfortunately I didn't
get a chance like that,
that street right outside a hotel man
and all these bars and all these great
places to eat. Really, really
fucking fun towns. Yeah. And, um,
when I was in Winnipeg, who wouldn't?
That was her off, you know? No,
let me tell you, those people are tough.
Okay. Well I saw a to the other day,
I don't have to finish it, but no
did. Winnepeg was like, you know me,
I don't like to fly when I have to win a
peg. I was like, let's go to the airport.
Like, and the people were
great and the food was great.
There's no way you like that part of the
world to live there in the wintertime.
It's, you have to be a special
kind of tough or you're,
you're out the second you turn 18, like
fuck you parents, you're out. Yeah, no,
the people were great. The
food was great. We had Greg,
who was outstanding was that that Tortilla
I have, which is a French Canadian.
A meat pie. Yeah. Flaky crust. And they
had the crust underneath. They didn't,
they didn't skimp on that.
Sometimes your older at shepherd pie
or a meat pie and they just, you know,
they fucking cook up the meat,
stick it in a bold and they put
just a doe on the top. Yeah.
And I want this thing, you know, oh, well
I want both parents to be there. Right.
The one on top and on the bottom right.
Just necessarily net.
You gave me a piece of it. It
was unreal. And then I did,
I had chicken salad and make
it cry, you know, it was great.
We had great food over there.
Did you get emotional Paul?
If tasted a lot of things,
but that was,
no I, yeah, when my, I love the
room last night. I love that.
Like it's a kind of like a beacon theater
right up front. That's what I love.
Edmonton was like law Edmondton room
almost as a Carnegie was just deep and
layers. I was on that night, dude.
I went out there and the fucking add was
working to my, sometimes it fucks me up.
It was working great.
Oh Edmonton fucking just shuffle the deck
of all my jokes and then that made me
say all this shit and I was just like
one of those things where I felt like I
was on stage for five minutes on that one.
Now Dude,
you from Edmonton was
that was fucking Edmunton.
Actually I had a show stopper where like
literally in Vaudeville I had a fuck this
guy's a show stop now I had a surreal
triple threat. No, I had a
bad show stopper. I'm, I'm
saying that in a bad way.
You Fuck it? Oh, that was my fault.
I shouldn't know. I showed that.
I did that joke where I was just like, you
know women, you know, you guys like it,
personal trainers and you,
you know,
you go all out for your wedding picture
and your wedding day and you look great,
you'll take an Olympian and then I go
and then it just kind of falls apart.
But like, and the place just fucking
stop test someone in the crowd went, wow,
somebody knows somebody goes,
oh my God.
And like I had the bid I did before it
killed. And then I did that and I go, no,
and I kind of saved it when I
go know what I'm saying is like,
you should just come down the aisle the
way you're going to be like what I'm
going to be looking at for
the next 40 or 50 years.
And like half of them laughed,
but I was just like somebody who was like,
well then I told you afterwards and the
look on your face, you would just like,
wow, yeah, fuck up. And I was the idiot
when you sent it to me in the restaurant.
It was fun. It was funny to me. So I
said, dude, you got to do that on stage.
And then somehow the way you said
that you said it, I was just like,
I mean that's fucking let me that
they'll look dude. I mean he can't,
women have to,
they have to give birth.
Can you imagine what the fuck you do?
You stay in shape,
you do all that and then you
can begin to have another kid.
You basically going to have to go
through that and what that the angel,
what I'm saying, how could, you know
what I'm saying is, and this is what I'm,
you know, I know women do and,
and you know, my wife looks great,
she had two kids and everything and I
know women go through a lot of shit and
have kids. I'm saying don't put
on that show for everybody else.
Be who the fuck you're going to be.
It's the same way people, you know,
clean up for company like what? The
regular families not good, you know,
and just being nice and Betty who we
don't see ever who's coming over once a
fucking year is what you've got to get
onto your hands and knees would have to
pick or two, I'll go
with this. It does suck.
When it's somebody that you don't give
a shit about and your wife's saying,
we got to clean this fucking place up
and they're going on. It isn't just like,
okay, let me, let's just pick a
room that we throw all the shit and,
and close the door.
Like you,
they actually want you to clean up
that they're coming in from Maryland.
I don't give a fuck. I'm not going to
see him again. Right. You know? Right.
But as far as I'm looking good
on the Wednesday, I want to,
I want him to look as good as they can.
I would like to know I was trying to do
with a joke and it fucking backfired.
I wasn't there for you as a friend,
you know, and I'll tell you,
that's going to haunt me forever.
Um, yeah. But, oh, what, what, what about,
what was the name of that theater
that we played in Winnipeg? Man? Uh,
Burton Cummings. Yeah. That it was,
it was, it was a, I got a little,
some of the history that that
place was made in, uh, 1908.
And they had these, these
fucking stairs in the back. Now,
everybody's Charlie Chaplin.
Uh, uh, who's the guy that, uh,
fatty Arbuckle, Harry Houdini, all these,
it was a Vaudeville theater for like the
first 30 years before the talkies took.
Oh, I say, and um,
they still had like the
original stairs in the back.
You walked up to the green
room and these are like slabs.
I don't know what kind of stone it is,
but from years of people walking
up and it where you basically,
you put your feet,
there was like these indentations from
people's scuffing up as they walking up
or coming down. Yeah.
And then outside, uh,
the upper deck of it, the, I guess
the mezzanine and the upper deck,
they used to have pews
all the way through them.
And then they put seats in at some point.
But in the upper deck they still had
these wooden pews and during my set,
because the acoustics are incredible.
Can you talk in 1908? I mean,
I don't think they could really amplify
voice at that point. Could they?
I don't know. Yeah. We don't know. We're
idiots, but I don't think they could.
So it's a,
it's was acoustically perfect building.
So when people were way
up in that upper deck,
we're talking like an old
hockey barn for hockey fans.
There are basketball fans where you
felt like if you lean too far forward,
you'd fall right on the emblem at center
ice or center court and these people
would walk down and it's making that,
that sound like you almost like an
old chair makes all that rickety shit.
And it sounded like it was right above
me and I was sitting there going,
are these fucking union guys walking
around and making noise door my show?
And I kept making jokes like that.
They,
that they were already changing
the marquee and they were over me.
And what it was was
people in that upper deck,
we're walking down just to go
to the bathroom and get a drink.
But the acoustics were so unbelievable
and it was so fucking steep. It sound,
it sounded like it was right above my
head. It was amazing. That was one of my,
a place was old school
and then I old shit dude.
So I actually walked up
there at the end of my show.
I wish it did it dude.
It was, it reminded me a,
there's one in Seattle that we did the,
the Moore theater where a,
I think they shut the uh,
the video for even flow
found bucket check at DePaul.
That one right when he's fucking hanging
and he's looking like he's bleary eyed.
You know, like he's crazy but he hasn't,
he knows exactly what he's doing.
He already knows he wants
to fire his drummer.
We played that one and that one was really
interesting where just like this one
that we played in Winnipeg,
they have separate entrances
for the upper deck and that,
I don't know if they
had segregation up here,
but in Seattle that that was what
that was for that upper deck.
You had it completely separate entrance,
no fucking elevator.
And you just walked up flight
after flight after flight.
And these were serious flights,
like 40 14 groupings, you know,
two groups of like 14 to get to
one floor all the way, all the way,
all the way up.
And I was joking with the guy going,
this is why African Americans kicked
the shit out of white people because in
sports, cause we just rolled into the
theater. Hey, he has to just have a seat.
You've got to do like the fucking stair
master all the way up and come back down
just to see a fucking show.
And that's like insanely high man.
Like that was scary. High. Yeah. Steep.
It's like you don't want to lead
forward like steep. Like you'll fucking,
it was scary. Yeah. Like I would
not want to be like hammered, oh,
not the up there. And then, you know,
smoke a little joint or something.
Some of our smoke a cigar that made me
fucking lightheaded. I would just be like,
I mean if I had to leave I would,
I would go hands and knees backwards
down like a little, you know,
a little toddler that goes downstairs.
That's how I would exit with the,
uh, with the fear. He liked the Burton
Cummings when I like, I think, um,
I think the vogue last night
was one of my favorites. Man.
I'll do those are two great crowds to,
yeah,
and we're not shitting on Calgary by the
way. It was just that second show dude.
It's been a while since I've been in
front of people that drunk. But uh,
we had another amazing week. Now
when do we play hockey? I'll wait.
We went to the Bruins.
Canadians game. Yeah. And what
does the name of that place?
Molson Center. Yeah, they changed it. They
changed it whenever the fuck it is now.
You know, I don't know. Some
sort of cellular company, but uh,
it's just an amazing place to go to.
We see all those retired numbers,
all those Bay Stanley Cup banners
and just how into it people are.
And there was some people leaving early
down below that kind of disappointed me.
But it was a beat down.
It was a beat down Bruins fucking killed
three goals in the third period. Hey.
And I wasn't obnoxious either. I didn't
like the guy who brought me into it.
He was a Canadiens Fan. He
said, hey, we're going to go
into this, this, you know,
the famous, I don't know, one of
the levels in the mezzanine level,
they have this pub. And the guy who
hooked us up with tickets said, listen,
I know he's a big Bruins fan, but I
respect, could you just not wear stuff?
It gets weird when you going now.
So it's like, yeah, absolutely. I'm,
I gonna fucking do that. I'm going
to stand up and share when we score,
but I'm not going to be that asshole.
Go, yeah, we're face, you know,
giving them shit or whatever. I'm not
going to do that. No, no. Yeah, yeah.
So I just sat there and like, they're
really fucking enjoyed it. And, uh,
but earlier that day, we actually, uh,
some of the guys from just for laughs,
Bruce Hill hooked us up with some ice
time and I got the shit kicked out of me.
And for as he played hockey for the first
time we played at this, this, you know,
they've got a zillion rinks out
there and it was a old Canadian, uh,
Stefan can tell, uh, we played, you know,
back when I was first going
to games and shit like that,
or maybe we're five years into when I
started going to games and he somehow,
I forget how it was, but his Jersey
was framed there. So anyways,
we played on this little sort of mini
rink. We had the floating Blue Line.
You bring it to the zone and the
red line becomes the Blue Line.
And I've got to tell you, Versie fucking
animal, he's out there with just gloves,
a stick and a helmet. Dude, you
had like three shots on net online.
I mean,
I don't know if you try it like trying
to tap rebounds in his shots on net.
I don't know how that fucking works,
but dude,
you had like three on one shift and I was
sitting there laughing on the bench go,
this fucking guy's got more shots on net
in one shift. Well, one of the guys like,
dude,
I said like we were talking like maybe
throughout the whole game I'm going to
have like 12 shots,
but I didn't know how to stop.
I got the shit kicked out
of me. I'm falling down and
everyone's got pads but me.
So I'm the most novice in this thing.
All right.
And the only thing I had
was gloves and a helmet.
I'm falling on my knees and elbow getting
and like it was so legit that there
were two locker rooms. You had your
own jerseys. There was a timer.
These guys had shifts and I'm
getting thrown into this thing. Okay.
I haven't been on the ice.
You know why?
I've been dragging all my stuff up
here because it's, we're going to play,
I want to make sure I'm protected and
I'm not going to wear somebody else's
smelly stuff. That's
fucking, that's gross dude.
That's like the pad version of using
your buddy's toothbrush. It's gross
but yeah and and and typical me,
I'm like,
I don't know how to play but I just
know scoring position from floor hockey.
So I just would go down,
get into scoring position,
not know how to stop and just fucking
get the shit kicked out. I would,
I'll tell you this one thing a coach
would never have to tell you is go to the
net. That's all you did. The second grade
team. The second your team got the puck.
I just went to do and understand offsides
though are offsides a couple of times.
What the fuck dude, you would just
put your head down and just mirror.
I just started skating and you had you
stick on the ice the wrong way because
every time I shot I wouldn't need a
lefty stick. So I had the righty stick,
which that an opposite and I kept
doing backhands with the wrong stick.
But I did have a post on that one.
Your backhand was lethal cause
you had a right handed stick.
Everybody thought you were right hand
and he's going down and go and look at
this fucking guy.
He's got like all these shots and neck
and he's playing left handed with a right
hand to stick was all right. Yeah. Yeah.
No, no, you're good man. You're, you're,
you're good at it. I, I was, oh thank you.
I was hoping you were gonna say something.
No cause a little self conscious.
I definitely recognized it.
I skate all right until I get the puck.
I just, I swear to God dude, it's just,
it all falls apart and you know, it's
the funniest thing when I play with guys,
it's two passes to me before my,
before my whole team figures it out
and then it's just like, you know,
I then I have to be like literally
going across the Blue Line screaming
something to get the fucking puck back.
But they know now. But you did you,
but you had some good passes shot on goal.
There was like,
I liked playing days was
a 13 year old kid there.
There was a 14 year old kid there
and these, and I just was like,
but I almost hurt myself. Remember I just
slammed my head, dude. Yeah, that was bad.
I was like, no, I knew you were going
to be. So everyone was saying, hey,
go take some Advil. And you're like, no,
I don't do, I feel fine. I feel fine.
And when you fall like
the way you were falling,
those are those deep fucking bruises
and they don't show up for at least 24
hours. The best thing Bruce did, he
goes, dude, you don't want to concussion.
And he brings me a helmet and
I slipped back to it. If you,
if the way you fell on my head, dude, that
would, I would have been over. Oh yeah.
That would have had that awful fucking
sound of a head hitting the back of the
head, hitting the ice. Oh my God. I felt
so bad one time somebody skating by.
I thought it was you. Somebody
just goes, you got air on that one.
Like I was getting the shit kicked out
of me. But this is the thing though.
You were doing it to yourself
that just let people know.
It's not like people were knocking
them down. This was a non contact game.
Paul would just go head a fucking
stage like you were gonna run.
It never leaves something.
I never,
the best compliment I got was
when I saw somebody goes, I go,
I never put an ice hockey before. And he
was like, well you've got good balance.
And I was like, have you been watching?
Yeah, I know, right? Hey, let me, let me
advertising and we know we got some, we
got some great questions this week. Uh,
all right,
a stamps.com everybody.
I know it's tough deciding where to focus
your resources to grow your business.
But one thing I can tell you,
you don't need to waste valuable time
going to the post office for mailing and
shipping.
Just use stamps.com to access all the
surfaces of the post office right from
your desk.
24 seven buy and print official us postage
using your own computer and printer.
Get posted for any letter or package,
any class of mail,
all for just a fraction of the cost
of an expensive postage meter with
stamps.com you'll never have to go to
the post office again so you can spend
your time where it matters
most focused on your business.
I use stamps.com to send out all my DVDs,
my tee shirts,
my posters, Paul, whatever
crap I'm selling at the end
of one of my little dances.
Uh, right now he was my last name
bur bur for this special offer,
no risk trial plus a $110 bonus offer
that includes a digital scale and up to
$55 free postage. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
you
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburrthatstamps.com
enter
birth. Dude, I fucking killed that
one. Uh, he voice now that I said that,
not going to be in my head. Watch
this one. Alright, regroup. Okay.
We still got another half to play.
Okay. I just want to mess it up.
[inaudible].
You're a business owner,
but automated phone systems
and secretaries are not
in your budget just yet,
and juggling incoming calls yourself
makes it hard to look like a professional.
Here's something that will
dramatically help you make more money.
In 2014 he voice whether you're a business
of one or 100 he voice will help you
manage all of your incoming calls
with a toll free number. Dial by name,
directory and call routing tools. Your
business will sound like 1 million bucks.
Can't take a call, no problem. He voice.
We'll transcribe the voicemail
and email it right to you.
Never be caught off guard again and with
the voice you can try it before you buy
it right now.
Just for my listeners,
you can get a 60 day trial to
eve voice for absolutely free.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and enter the
Promo Code Bill B I l l at checkout.
Take charge of your business and make
more money in 2014 go to [inaudible] dot
com and enter bill at checkout
for your 60 day free trial.
That's he voiced.com Promo Code Bill.
Damn,
I wasn't bad killing it, crushing
it. One more people. Uh, here we go.
Legal Zone. If the excitement
of starting your business,
getting your first customer,
and finally quitting your job
hasn't moved you to action yet.
Here's another great reason to
get started. It's national starch,
your business month.
Everybody that legal suit wants to help
you start your own corporation or LLC or
file a DBA so you can get up
and running quickly and easily.
Find out why more than 1
million entrepreneurs use
legal zoom to start down the
path of successful business
ownership this month.
Only take advantage of
their national starch,
your business month special and get a
free three month trial of the all new
quickbooks, making it so much
easier to run your new business.
That's $119 value for absolutely free
when you enter Burr in the referral box at
checkout.
That's legalzoom.com Promo
Code [inaudible] legal
zoom provides legal zoom,
provides self-help services and it can
connect you with the right attorney,
but they are not a law firm. Legal Zoom,
Promo Code Burr. There you go. I went,
you know, I'm up two games to one.
Um, all right. Back to the, uh,
back to the, the, the podcast
here. Oh, before we go any
further, have you buddy? Um,
one of my favorite comics that's on
his way up the company ladder. Uh,
Tom Segura from uh,
the uh,
your mom's house podcast right here on
the all things comedy network that he
does with his lovely and absolutely
fucking hilarious wife Christina presents
visit ski. I'm the worst
trying to read. Um,
Tom has a new special outcall completely
normal that you can download as of
March 15th on iTunes.
I love this guy because
he's just one of those,
he doesn't give a shit in a good way.
Like he goes out,
he's not afraid of silence.
He has something to say, dude,
him and his wife arguably. Okay.
I know burns and Allen. Fuck them.
Okay.
You want to go with these two?
They crush it like we have like those
all things, comedy shows sometimes. Um,
we were doing them down at Luna and uh,
and Christina came down one night and
absolutely just fucking destroyed.
I'm trying to think. We had,
we had Tom down there too.
I've watched Tom and like the
improv forever, but um, he,
he's the real deal and he's on his way to
make it his mark. Uh, and he has a new,
a new, a comedy special, like I said,
completely normal. So check it out.
All right, first question
of the week, and Paul,
I know you're going to love this one
because you've been absolutely obsessed
with this. Uh, this says the, the name
of the question is where's the plane?
Oh yeah, let's go. Uh, he says, Bill,
using whatever knowledge
you have of the situation,
whether it be a lot or a little,
please break down what
happened on that plane. Um,
this is right up my alley.
First of all,
it's right up your id knowing you and
you and you hate flying. I tell you,
we know it's annoying as I have to blow
my nose because I'm coming down with a
cold. So why don't you start as I
walk over here to blow my nose off my,
because I'm a professional. What do
you think Paul? You're the guest.
I'll let you go first here. Would you like
a glass? Go ahead. What do you think? Uh,
I think that,
I think obviously the plane was hijacked.
I think that's why the, um,
the, you know, it's hard to
know. Uh, yeah, a little bit.
I think the plane was hijacked. Um, of
course. I think that's why there was,
the communication was cut out and then
they have proof that it kind of diverted
and, and changed its course.
And then nobody heard anything.
I think the fact that the fucking
thing is not in the water.
There's 230 people on a seven 77.
I flew that,
I've flown in seven 77, two uh, Italy.
Oh yeah, dude, that's your nickname.
Tell us seven 77 you, yeah, I mean,
so when I fly it now, um, and, and,
and there was, I won't go unless it's
a seven. It's not a center. Yeah,
that's not it. It's glass glass the whole
way. The lucky number, you know, seven 30,
70, you know, so, uh, so there was no
debris, nothing. So I don't think that,
I think that the plane,
they said that the plane could have flown
for six hours after they lost contact.
That fucking thing could be anywhere.
Right now there's going to be
a movie about this. I think,
I hope that in off everybody,
you know, God, God forbid,
but I think the plane landed
somewhere and was hidden.
And then I think the people that
did it, I think, I don't know what,
I don't know what they did with
the people, but, uh, you know,
I don't think it's in the ocean, so,
all right, let's, you know, come on.
You've got to put some money on.
Well,
listen what country you
pick and casket Stan,
they said it could have gone as
far as Kazic sedan to Zika. Stan,
all of those standards, uh, Liam for,
okay, let's say we're at Catholic Stan.
I think, uh, yeah, dude, I think that
it landed somewhere and it's fucking,
it's just an awful situation. But, um,
I, this is what I, it's the aliens built,
you think? See, I don't know. I think, uh,
with each day that passes that there's
no sort of demand or anything like that.
I'm thinking more unfortunately,
I don't know sadistically or whatever
they fluid way off course and I don't
know. I mean how, unless you dump a plane
in like the shipping lanes, what does,
what is the odds? The plains has
a beacon. Planes have a beacon,
but it was turned off. I mean,
I dunno, there's something that,
that where they can track.
It was fucking turned off and
the people knew how to do it.
So I think with every passing day,
yeah,
like it's not a good, like
there, there's no demands.
It's just really weird
that, that if, you know,
there's always some crazy reason to
draw attention to something that someone
does something like this.
The fact,
the only hope that I have is the fact
that they haven't asked for any demands
yet is, is I, I dunno, I mean,
what you wanted the plain,
I mean, what the fuck? You know,
how fucked up was your country?
You can't get a seven 77 crest.
They're laying all over the place.
But what's the motive or the, what's the
motive of the hijackers? Uh, I don't know,
but I,
I really felt for the family members
because they're sitting there and they're
talking about the airline, how the
airline is handling this, like a,
a business rather than, you know,
what is going on. And they go,
we can't comment on anything right
now because basically, you know,
it's a cooperation. They're like, we're
going to get the shit suit out of us.
Let's, let's try to limit how much
we're going to get the shit suit.
Like they go into that fucking mode.
Yeah.
But it's one of those awful
things where, you know, um,
also, you know, the victims
are going to go into it.
We're going to sue the shit out
of your mode. So it's just like,
if people could just in this moment,
if the airline could be allowed to just
say, we're fucking devastated. I mean,
we had employees on that plane
too, you know, and they could,
everybody could just share information
and there wouldn't be that stupid,
you know, lawyers licking their
chops on both sides or one cowering.
And the other guy,
other side of licking their chops,
maybe they could at least make it a little
more comforting for those people. But,
uh, it's in, and, you know, I
guess there's no comedy here,
Dude. It's just, it's fine.
I just feel, I just feel bad for, you
know, there's kids in there and shit, man,
it's fucked up man. It's awful. And
it's one of the most unprecedented, uh,
mysteries like a seven 77 with fucking
230 peoples disappeared and nobody knows
where it is in the airlines
don't have answers.
And 10 countries had their navies fucking
just scowl at the fucking ocean and
nobody can find it. Right?
It's crazy, man. Well, I mean,
there's a kind of good thing
there that maybe with the,
they're still alive and there's
something you can do to negotiate.
But the thing about,
uh,
trying to land a plane like that,
it's not like you could just go to some
boot bootleg fucking air strip. I mean,
you need a lead, a lot of fucking
runway to land something that big.
It's not like he could go to fucking,
you know, some little last, you know,
let's say had it planned unless they
had it planned in a hangar. Yeah.
But then what the, what the fuck? So
what are you doing? Okay, you got it.
She took the fucking plane, he
took the people. What do you want?
Where are the people? It's
annoying. I mean that like, I mean,
I wonder if if they had a
plan and then something,
they shut everything off and then
something else went wrong. How, I mean,
because they gotta be
looking at satellite footage,
like say even like remote areas,
jungles and Shit,
looking for pictures of smoke and fire.
Something to try and find the
fucking thing. I mean, look,
the biggest mystery still
on the planet is the ocean.
So I think that that's where it is.
It's at the bottom of the fucking ocean
in some place where we can't find it.
I hope it isn't,
but that's what I would guess,
just for the simple fact that it's just
weird that nobody claimed responsibility.
There's no ransom demands. Um, I mean,
how do you sneak a fucking seven 77 and
into something with the amount of fuel
they had? They know the distance it could
go. There had to be something, dude,
there had to be something
to the fact that it's not,
it should be on every fucking like I
don't think there's enough coverage of it.
Hell, I got a picture of Genoa. Well what
the fuck? They probably would be alive.
Well,
I,
if some point when there's no new
information becomes like this fucking 250,
270 person cold case file that
time to try to find, it's insane.
It's fucking insane. It is. It is. And,
and that's why I kept asking you every
day we'd go hang out and bill would go,
Paul, I can't fucking do you keep talking
about it. And I'm like, I can't get it.
I don't get it because you,
you got this obsession with fucking
planes and safety, you know,
cause you're afraid to fly it.
I don't fucking think about shit
like that and that now your,
your fear is starting to rub off on
me. I'm scared. I go to the airport,
I didn't mean to protect my fears
on you. It's okay. You're all human.
All right. Uh, whatever. Perfect. I
really hope that that ends, you know,
I hope doesn't have some sort of Chuck
Norris Delta Force thing that ends it
fucking happily, but that is a
rough state and I'm like, God,
the fucking poor people, they got
to sit there wondering when, when,
what's going on and they suffer. Now
what's going on is terrible. It's awful.
All right, great question
buddy. All right.
What's your beef deer farmer bill?
If you could only eat one type of meat
and one type of vegetable for the rest of
your life,
what would they be?
Got to figure some choices are more
versatile in the kitchen. All right.
Uh, I wouldn't go fish because I would
worry that I'd get the mercury thing.
Um,
I couldn't go red meat because I ended
up like John Wayne Chicken is all slimy
and you're fucking end trails.
I would have to go, uh,
what else is it? Turkey. I
go Turkey. I'd go chicken.
Cause if you cook it, if you
cook it enough, like you'll
get any kind of, but yeah,
you're right. Yeah. The mercury
in the fish red meat. Your bout,
you're fucking agree.
The fish and God knows what that meltdown
in Japan has done to the fucking Sushi
Jesus. Oh I had sushi
yesterday, man. Fuck yeah. Yeah.
I love fucking Sushi. Oh you got to pop.
You know you're not going to have Sushi,
but uh, no, I'll go chicken and
vegetable. I hate vegetables. So I man,
it's maybe Spanish, a little
garlic. You know I love vegetables.
Oh that would actually make you sad
if like this is like fucking said.
So I guess I would have
Turkey every day with a,
I almost want to pick a vegetable that I
don't love cause I don't want to end up
hating it because I got
to eat it every day.
Cauliflower every day for the ready
fucking, I'm already hate that shit.
No cauliflowers unless they make
the cauliflower mashed potatoes.
That was one of those are bad.
But the one reason why it's not bad,
it's because you've got all the butter and
salt and pepper in there. Yeah. But he,
yeah, I mean I would go Turkey cause
I could make a Turkey sandwich.
I could make Turkey sausage.
I could make shrimp list shrimp that
like we saw that guy in Montreal,
that actor, we were in an elevator
with Bubba Bubba Gump and I didn't,
I only saw that movie once. Yeah. I
walked in there and I was like, Oh shit.
Now we walked out like, you know
who that was dude? I was like, yeah,
he was in heat. He was down,
was funny. It was funny.
He was funny and insanely friendly and uh,
and then I want it to go up and say
something or invite them to his show and I
was just like, let me fucking
leave this guy alone. Right.
You said you saw another, there was a
bunch of people, there were someone,
a movie in a hotel,
Turkey,
bacon to think all the different
fucking ways I could do it. Well,
you wouldn't go Turkey, Turkey, you'd be
a nightmare. The of fifth Turkey Sandwich.
You'd be like, I fucked up, dude. Have
to chicken every fucking day. Chicken,
chicken, Parmesan chicken
Scampi. You don't what?
I just did check in check and Talky,
talky, talky sandwich, Turkey sausage.
I'm talking. You can put Marinara
with Melton boots it. That's fucking,
that's good for a month, you know?
Then you'd be fucking dead shit.
You'd be a tub of shit. Dude, do you
can eat chicken palm every other day.
You wouldn't be a tub of shit
if you eat chicken every day.
You know you've got to mix it up palm
with all the pasta and all that shit.
Got fucking bread. Your
red wine discussing crimes.
Whatever you Sicilians though.
I guess I would go Turkey.
I love a Turkey sandwich and I think
chicken is overrated in and then just the
shit that you know, chickens, you
know you've got the Salmonella,
you get all that fucking
shit with that, you know. Oh,
there's a problem with everything. We know
Paul, maybe we have a problem with you.
You ever think that?
No.
I go chicken, spinach, chicken,
spinach. I would go Turkey.
You have a Turkey really doesn't
go go with the vegetable. Chicken.
Spanish is a good one that Chris Paul,
you're better at this than I am.
All right dude. You're a fucking, you
committed some crazy fucking murder.
You're on death row. You get your
final meal. What are you going to have?
Oh shit man. No, let
me say this a rough on.
You know that's so funny
you asked me that. I leave.
I had to actually lean back in the chair
for that one. That's it. That's tough.
And this is assuming you could eat,
okay,
so nauseous that they're going
to fucking kill me here. Yeah,
I never understood that.
They showed a list of what all the
serial killers got and like one guy,
one guy like Bundy or one of
those guys just got an apple,
but another guy got fucking like,
he wanted a whole pie with like pepperoni.
He wanted sandwiches and
like he got the whole set.
Like he just like everything that's a
true fucking lazy man to be able to sit,
you know. And he said a food court,
like the guy eating an apple,
he's probably just like, let me just
taste one last thing. Let's have fun.
He was a fucking,
I don't know if it was Bundy,
it might've been that McVay guy
that blew the Timothy Mcveigh.
And I remember this, he had an amp,
got a pint of mint chocolate chip.
And that stuck with me cause I was like,
I love mint chocolate chip
and I eat a pint all the time.
And that actually seemed like if someone
was going to fucking kill me and I
don't have any sympathy for
these fucking people either,
but I'm just saying that someone's going
to kill me, you know it would, I know,
you know, we're, we're fucking going to
kill you at this time and it's coming up.
I want something that's going to be a
little easy on my stomach and for some
reason I just think ice cream
would be nice. Just be comforted.
Did I love, I love chicken cutlets man.
Like I know like my mind. All right,
when you asked a question, I'm thinking
Italian or Sushi because I love it.
But I love chicken cutlets
with lemon squeezed on them.
So I might do like a shitload a chicken
because the chicken and I just thought
chicken and dumplings,
which I haven't in a long thing.
It's any better than dumplings was
a great chicken and dumplings in it.
But then the mint chocolate chip did,
they wouldn't go go with the debt.
Did they let you drink on what?
Like on your last meal if you ordered
a bottle of red because that would be
funny if you were hammered.
Yeah,
you'd fuck yeah. Fuck yeah.
You guys are looking at who you're going
to kill the kill you fucking pussy.
Yeah.
You got enough guys.
All my barriers were one on one.
Look at you guys five on one. Ooh.
What are the odds? Uh, you
feel good about yourself?
I don't think tail successful.
Hang your hat on this one.
They let them drink.
That'd be fucking great.
Why are you guys all have the same
clothes on what you all call each other?
Making the other psychos laughing as
you're leaving. Show me the way to go.
That judge was a fucking bag
as what you would do, you would just
start talking shit. Oh yeah, you did good.
It only took his eight years.
You go into the death chamber and all the
fucking family members are looking at,
you guys do stuff. Oh, he didn't say menu.
You was, I got caught. That's
all I'm saying. I don't sweet.
That'd be fucking amazing. Oh Dude.
That'd be hilarious. Just walking out.
Hey Buddy, buddy. Before
you do it buddy, you know,
the way they keep asking the question.
But anyway, it only took you five years.
I had those lockers in the attic for
bad. Did you? Uh, there's
been a couple of guys, uh,
you know, some of the last
words. One of the guys go, well,
his last name was French and he yelled
over the reporters. He goes, hey.
And he was going to the electric
chair. He goes, hey, he goes,
I got your headline for tomorrow. He
goes, French fries. And he's like, well,
like last.
And then they electrocuted him.
Did you see the one guy that
they did it too and he fucking,
they thought it was Friday fucking he
popped up and he was like, fucking,
he popped up like in a fucking
horror movie. He was like
a big guy and it didn't,
he didn't,
it didn't take the electric utem and
they're all sitting there and exactly the
Tom Hanks movie that really happened?
No, no. A guy they showed it on,
they showed it on one of those shows
where they jolted him and like normally
like the normal person,
the show and he just went,
it was like one of those death row inmate
or like, it was like, uh, you know,
people protesting outside.
One of the guys that wrote you were
dead on discovery channel alone
and he like popped up for a second.
I had a fucked up part two
that I'm telling you scare
the shit out of the fight.
You got to make sure that it did.
You know, I've got a friend of mine,
you can electrocute, you can take a beat.
And I know this guys were off. Okay.
Why they put it with putting an electric
chair. He got right back up again.
Boy, I've got a friend.
He's tough. You know,
sometimes I wish I was tougher.
We all do bill.
We're not high. People are not
drunk. This is what would, if I was,
if I was hiring now be fucking losing
my mind. All right. Uh, sad music. Oh,
that's right up our alley. Why you bring
it up? All right. Sad music. Dear Bill.
Uh,
from what you talk about on the,
from what you talk about on the podcast,
it seems like you're mostly into classic
rock and music that involves really
talented musicians. Uh, do you ever
listen to a motional music? I mean,
like a sad acoustic track or
just anything depressing verse.
He's already losing it.
If so,
do you put it on when you're sad
or when you're happy? No, no, no.
I listened to that stuff. Sometimes I'll
need to get emotional when I'm there.
Cool.
What song are we seeing in the car?
Just once.
I'm going to Jan and Megan.
Just one night
try to do something else.
And south.
The South we were doing,
we were saying,
we'd say that to our wives one time
when they would like bitching, yelling,
how come you Blab, blah,
blah, blah. It doesn't,
and it's in the middle of them yelling.
Just go stare at them and just go
it.
Shut the fuck
shower.
Why does it always have to be something
to do? Hey, we just lie around the house.
Joe's Wong,
Paul,
you creep,
you keep procrastinating and you
sleep in late and the kids are up
just once.
We should let me sleep.
You're
fucking talk all the time.
I have nothing to say,
lady. All right, sorry. Um, sad
music. Do I listen to sad music?
Yeah,
probably the first sad songs I listened
to other than Elton John where he was a
little too on the head. Right. Sit her
sad though. Like that's what I want.
AC DC ride on. Lonely guy on the
road. That was probably my first one.
Do it. Every fucking heavy metal
band had those home sweet homes.
I'll tell you what said,
you want to know what's the sad one?
Yeah, no I don't. I, you
know, it's a sad song.
Cat's in the cradle. You
Go, you're going rocked on.
I'm thinking more of like the
just once like, you know, oh,
you can't go hip hop hip hop,
you can't do a sad song.
They tried to do emotional wrap. Remember
that? Yeah. And some people still try.
Yeah. Like when it went wide, that
Guy Drake, man, I just like, I don't,
I mean I get it. Yeah. You know, look
at guys, he's got a beard and shit.
So women like him, but like when it just
gets to a, I don't want to hear like,
I don't wanna hear a rapper opening up.
No rappers trying to open up by
one of their rapper friends dies.
But it's never really sad. You're more
just like, you know, they'll just be like,
you know,
they just wrap it and you know,
then what they did at that point out of
44 and that's like the most of it though.
I like that. Keep it like that.
Okay. Nobody was better than you.
Like it's a debt you can't
get, you know, you don't.
One of my favorite things in this business
was opie from the opiate Anthony show
was he had this thing that he would do
when guys would start crying when they
would play audio. Yeah. Oh my God. That
was fucking, his timing was perfect.
Every time someone would be
talking like retiring from a sport,
like when Mike Schmidt retired, which is,
you know, it's very difficult to watch.
He was like, you know, you know, he
just was ending is like 38 years ago,
a little boy began a journey to
play the wonderful Kiera pace.
Oop would always go,
oh boy.
Okay,
what am I favorite? And it always, oh
boy. It always meant, that's great.
Nobody wants to see a man just completely,
you know what it is. I can watch a guy
cry if something terrible is happening.
Just don't try to talk while you're
crying. You know? That's the thing,
the talking and then bursting out into
cross. Let your shoulders go. Yeah,
let me shut fucking crying.
But don't fall for the love of God a man.
He's a man. Needs to cry and private.
Yeah. You do that in the shower.
You do it in the shower. Like when
my son was born, everyone's like,
did you cry yet? And I'm like,
no, what are you talking about?
And then when my son was born,
it all hit me later and I went home to
go get stuff for my wife in the hospital
and I sat on the couch and
I didn't like weep, but I
gotcha.
I didn't weep when I got emotional.
But like just picturing you sitting
on the couch by yourself and just,
you just go,
that's stupid.
It's just completely unexpected to
use your thing from your podcast. Oh,
that's unexplored. The effect. That's
unacceptable dude on it. Completely.
The talk into it, right? Yeah.
The talk into it. That's,
that's what the fight of about crying
is. You know, it's like, you know,
you always do this to me,
you know,
you always do this to me and I'm trying
my best and it's over fucking over with.
Some of my friends die. I've had so many
who it died. I just cry in shower. Yes.
What I do. I asked a girl,
we asked a girl. Right,
because you don't feel like you're crying
cause there's all that water on your
face anyway. No. We asked the girl,
we go, what would you do if your dude
started crying? Like if it wasn't,
if nobody died,
if a dude and you are just art,
he just had a bad day and he just had a
bad day and you got into it and he broke
down and cried and she goes,
yeah, no over, over, over.
Get the fuck away from me.
Yeah. You know what's funny?
There's some women they think that
they want to see that part of you.
They don't get what that is to them
is that's their total conquest. Yeah.
You know when you bang a girl in
the ass and he's just like, yeah,
I got this shit.
I'm fucking with you.
Their version of that Jesus
built no fuck with you.
Their version of that is is if they can
get you to be so vulnerable around them
that you cry and then
it's one of those things.
It's almost like when the crowd
screams out a joke, they already heard,
they think they want to hear it again
and then you tell it's like, ah,
it wasn't as good. Now it's
the same thing. Is that,
yeah. And you said something,
you said something about
like if a burglar comes in,
if you cry in front of a woman,
all her mind is like,
what if the Burger comes in
at this fucking guy? Yeah,
no, it's over. You can't cry.
You Strip a woman a security if
you cry in front of her. I think,
I don't think I've cried for,
I think my wife saw that's what it is.
Like a stripper for security. Cause now
she's like, well I got this fucking, yeah,
this fairly crisis baby sleep and next
thing, you know. Yeah, it's, it's over.
You know, and Oh yeah, no, you just,
you might as well just have a
pullover sweater on, you know,
walking around and then she mocks
you. What are you going to cry, bitch,
you so me? Yeah, it's fucking over,
dude. You can't have
that. Uh, so sad music.
A cat's in the cradle
with classic one. Uh, no.
I actually listened to a lot
of, I believe it or not. Like,
I mean you always have like your
core shit that you listen to.
I like some Phil Collins when it's sad.
What does it rain
down me?
Ooh.
Well I hated that annoying one when he
was sitting there like ruining my day by
bringing up homeless people.
Like I don't look at them and feel
bad for him day for you and me
twice because it's just another day for
you and meet you and me and paradise.
That fucking stupid song. Yeah. No,
I hate when people do and that's all the
money to that went to homeless people.
That's one of, that's just pandering
to the, if you have a crack,
have you ever cried alone listening
to a song or like not cried,
but have you ever been like,
oh no,
I've completely broken down and I've
told the three cars just weeping
uncontrollably. Have I? Yeah,
like totally cry. No, no.
I've definitely teared up.
Listen as an,
as an artist,
at some point you're going to have
to go to those emotions. You need to,
you need to be a, you need to meet to with
your instrument though. I have, I have,
what was the ones like I had
this weird thing where, um,
I stopped crying at some point.
I Dunno when I stopped
crying and got mad more when,
when I got hurt and my brother beat
the shit out of me. Um, you know,
most of the crying I'd be, it's just
like at the end of it. But I wasn't,
but I wasn't crying.
And then I didn't cry
one time too.
I remember my brother is bigger than me,
my little brother's biggest
thing. Right. Big Toe. Like,
and I remember he thought I said, I said,
if you fucking take my clothes again,
if you take my clothes, and he did it
every day he would go into my room,
we take my belt to take my clothes and
I'd come home and I guess in a boy band
and I, I need to go, I need to go out.
Right. And I go, mom, if he does it again,
I'm fucking hitting him. If, and my mom
be like, oh, you know, he just, and he,
and one time I need really needed a shirt
and I'm fucking throwing shit through
the house.
And he gets out of his friend's car and
he starts walking up and he's got it on
and I fucking snap them.
My grandmother was there and I jumped
on him and I started punching him and he
stood up and he just goes,
well, you made your older brother
cried on my younger brother. Oh,
he's bigger than me.
But he didn't know what to do.
He got so upset that he just got,
and he looked around, he just,
he was so angry that something
needed to come out. And he just goes,
what did you feel bad? And you start, oh,
I kind of just walked away. And you know,
we laughed about it afterwards,
but to now, now he's a,
he's a fuck, he's a big kid.
But you know, my mom had the opposite. I
get a little brother, man, he's an animal,
you know,
my mom says she went to a,
she went to a funeral once and everybody
was there and everybody was crying and
she was overwhelmed with emotion that
they had to fucking drag her out.
She said she had them all.
One of the most embarrassing things
happen to her where she said she
uncontrollably laughed because they
said that that could happen sometimes.
So she's sitting there,
she's,
she's sitting there and
everybody's crying and like,
she went up and she could not stop
laughing and like she, and I said, why?
And she was like, Paul, I
just don't know. She goes,
I could not stop laughing
and I had to walk me out. And
like [inaudible] mom. Yes.
She said because the emotions or somebody
that they said that that could happen
sometimes where it's just you just like,
she didn't know what to do.
So instead of just breaking down,
she went the other way and just couldn't,
couldn't control their, and like, humans
will protect you in a really, like,
that's what they don't get sometimes
when comics make fucking horrific jokes
about some bad event. Make good jokes.
Yeah. It's about a horrific event.
So they go, that's so fucking
me. It's a defense mechanism.
It's all she, my mom is,
my mom was a sweetheart who felt bad and
her emotions just went the other way.
And she goes, Paul, I felt so bad.
I couldn't control myself
so I could control myself.
I hate to say this because somebody
lost somebody, but there was,
if there was video of that,
oh my God. Oh, I'm sorry.
I was saying, so I somewhere
around, I don't know, 10 or 11,
I didn't cry for years, years and
years and years. And I didn't,
I didn't cry until a friend
of mine killed himself.
And even then I was sad and
it's just, Oh, I went, uh,
I was in the bathroom once
again. Yeah. And it was in there.
And I remember I started to cry and then
I started thinking like, wow, I'm crying.
I haven't cried in a long time.
And then I stopped because I could out
of it cause I stopped thinking about the
Duke killed himself. Wow. Yeah. I went 10
years without a cry and then I had one.
What was it over yogurt?
Gummy bears?
No. Uh, I think, yeah, it might've been,
it might've been one of my son was born,
you know, it might've been on
my son. One. That's acceptable.
I guess it's acceptable. Back in the day.
He just stood out in the waiting room.
Right. And smoked a cigar. No,
you Irish dudes don't cry. I said,
today I even just tweeted something.
Irish dude, I swear to God,
I've never seen a funny your group of
people who ae take pain and just take a
vet. Some of the funniest
people to talk. See Acceptance.
They see it's the acceptance of the
beating and you don't try to change it.
He just,
you just keep running into the brick wall.
Something so comical about
just accepting the beading,
not trying to remedy it at all.
I don't,
I don't have that 100% anymore because
of getting into this business and
traveling and seeing other types of ways
of dealing with shit. But like dude,
I was actually thinking the other
day like my bloodline, German, Irish,
Scottish English right there.
I mean that would make a therapist to
a spit take like you fucked emotionally
when you have that blood running through
you. I don't know what it is. And then,
uh,
let's see when we get hung over and we
had a night out the night before and then
I see you in the lobby and you just see
the look on my face and I'm miserable
and I'm looking at him and we'll
go on this guy did what I did.
How is he just taking it?
Like you don't even show you just fucking
put your head down and go me, I put,
that's how I got sick. Yeah. Cause
we, we will, we will find that uh,
that cigar private place. We smoked
cigars and Calgary, we drank,
we got like three hours sleep
and we woke up, came here. Yeah.
Took a fucking steam.
And then I came back and like an asshole,
but I'm going to go work
out. Oh, that's sleep.
And then I fucking jumped on the treadmill
and then worked out and I came back
and then right when we get to the
theater and may head, I was going like,
this is dumb bill.
Don't go down to the treadmill because
you just got all taught in the steam
thing and then you gonna run down there
sweating and you only got three hours.
You go versus, Hey, what'd you do? I go,
I took a nap. I laid down. It was Greg,
what would you do? You? I go, do
you get some sleep? He goes, no, no.
I went to the gym like there's a
fucking animal can be self a break.
I go until I get sick and then I give
myself a break. Whatever. Paul, Hey,
what do you want from me? Okay, then who
else? You got a friend, he doesn't quit.
You know it's, I don't, I want to,
I'm just afraid it's Shabbot does you?
So
it's obnoxious. It's this point
people that I don't care. Fuck you.
You do 20 days in a row. All right.
Problem with ex-girlfriend. Uh, Bill.
Uh, I have a question regarding how to
handle a situation with my ex girlfriend.
I used to really hug, kiss and squeeze
her all the time. After we broke up.
I talked to a pretty 20 year old in
a coffee shop about squeezing and
making out in the blue water in Thailand.
She really got into an,
asked me to show her how I would
pleasure her in the ladies room.
Do this guy's got some game. He sitting
there painting a picture to the points.
There you go. He goes, I have always
been a romantic. So I said, yes,
that's hilarious. I'm a romantic. I'll
take you to the ladies room. Oh my God.
This movie.
I kind of got into eating around
and I don't get this graphic egos.
I added some dirty talk and I think
somebody might have listened in.
I saw my ex girlfriend leave the copies.
Wait,
she was in there later, but she
did not say hello. Wait a minute.
I got with the graphicness
of this. Wait, wait, wait.
I talked to him in a coffee shop. She was
really into it. So wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait. So I saw my ex girlfriend
leave the coffee shop,
so she was there as you did all of this,
but she didn't say hello.
I met with this girl couple of times
and she always wanted to play me to
pleasure her in public places,
like the movies, et Cetera.
She's got a fetish here.
Then she suddenly proposed that I would
pleasure her friend who I had met a
couple of times. Dude, fuck
you. What? This is awesome dude.
You don't have to achieve shit after
it was the coffee shop. All right.
I know from experience that
this would be a red flag,
but I said yes because I am 42 on now.
He's a creep 42 what do you,
what are you doing? He's still out there
and I really log in as question goes.
The more it sounds like a
lot. Yeah, I know. Right?
And I really love to pleasure
women after having pleasure.
This woman in a changing
room in a department store.
I against Sama ex-girlfriend leaving
without saying hello, where dude,
this is fucking bullshit.
You keep pleasure in this woman and your
girlfriend keeps showing up and up and
I'll buy it. Uh, but I got rid
of, this is such a great story.
I'm going to finish it though.
Um,
later my ex girlfriend called me
and was a bit upset. She asked me,
am I not a woman?
You would have sex in a public place
with now the correct grammar would be a
woman with whom you would
have sex in a public place.
Do you think I should
correct your grandma?
This is all a bullshit one or would you
think that correcting her as a sign of
not being over her, I don't buy that man.
That's just too fucking crazy. I mean,
that was, that's like, I never
heard of anything and he's 42.
That was very well written,
phony question and I liked all the
fucking left turns. It was wonderful.
I enjoy it. There's no way that could
be real right now. No, not, I mean,
you sit in a fucking coffee shop when
your ex girlfriend's sitting there.
Not saying hi and then she and she
doesn't work at the coffee shop and other
girls like, hey man, why don't you come
in the bathroom and eat me out? I mean,
it's like I listen that alone,
that could happen,
but to then have it happen again and
it Thailand, you know what I mean?
The departments do. I heard a lucky play.
The Lotto Buddy. Jesus. Um, all right,
well this is the last one in then. We got
it. We got to run here. Um, am I a whore?
A hey there Billy fat face. Fuck
you. I've been on the treadmill. Uh,
I am a senior in high
school and might be a whore.
I know you're the lean mean redheaded
machine when it comes to calling out
whores. So I'll let you
be the judge. I I listen,
I don't fucking judge you here.
All right.
My ex boyfriend who was
a year older than me,
he left for college at
the end of last year.
He goes to University of Washington
and decent leap from Arizona.
Um,
where we went to high school.
We broke up after Jay dating just over
a year because we ultimately agreed that
a long distance relationship
with suck for both of us.
Plus I eventually knew I'd be plagued
with the thought of him balls deep in some
artsy whore and it would get to me.
That's girls hilarious. Um, however,
when we've visited this for his
winter break, about six months later,
I came onto him again.
He initially didn't want to
get back together because
he knew he was leaving and
thought I'd be a, I'd be hurt in
the long run, but quickly gave in,
we were basically dating again
for the entire three week break.
He was here holding hands in public and
going on dates where one of us would pay
or the other.
Um,
what do we got to finally we
left without any incident,
but it felt like we kind of flashed back
to are heavily involved relationship.
Here's what things start to get
sleazy on my part. His friend Devin,
oh boy was always around
hill. Oh boy. Oh boy.
His friend Devin was always
around when we were dating,
trying to insert himself into things.
When my ex and I would hang out.
My ex thought it was creepy and shut
them down, but ever since he left,
I've been hanging out with Devin
a lot. Oh, how'd you do this?
All the dicks in the world. You're
going to jump on this one, um,
which would make you a whore. It
just kinda makes you like, uh,
you could have had a better
selection here. Here we go.
I spent Valentine's Day with them and
then she writes you, oh Geesh. Uh,
but nothing happened.
And I sent my ex a picture to
see what his reaction would be.
That's what she's doing.
It upset Him and he told me that it really
pissed him off and was comparable to
cheating. Later this month, I went
to a formal event with him and pose,
posted a picture on Twitter.
I texted my ex later that week and he
told me it was really pissing them off,
how I dragged him back into having
feelings for me and then rub my proverbial
dick in his face. I apologize.
But ever since then,
he seemed kind of pissed
at me and interest and not
interested in talking to me.
What do you think that Billy boy,
am I a dirty whore?
Is his just anger justified or is he just
being a jealous con loved the podcast,
thanks and go fuck yourself.
Um, you're not a whore.
You're not a dirty whore.
Uh, which you are is,
you're being a really mean person because
you don't know how to express the fact
that you still have feelings for him. So
you dragged them back into it and maybe,
um, you didn't want to
break up with them, but you,
or maybe you thought you did and now
you're having second thoughts about it and
rather than just saying that to him,
uh,
the pain you have that
you're not together,
you're now sort of for some reason taking
it out on him by doing everything that
you know is going to tear
his heart out of his chest.
So you need to stop doing that. That's
what I would say. Yeah, that's exactly
like, it's like just nobody
had come, nobody just picks
up the phone and says, Hey,
like keep sending the poor guy
pictures and fucking doing that tune.
There's no look, they're young.
They're young. You don't know what,
you don't know how to do stuff like that.
And sometimes you're doing shit and you
don't know why you're doing shit cause
you don't know who you are yet.
So I'm not judging this person,
I'm just saying what you're doing is
really, it's really unnecessarily mean.
One thing that's not brought up.
What about Devins feelings?
I know he must really seem to
care for nothing like this.
Two guys getting fucked. She sent him
pictures. I don't know. Just listen.
Without a doubt.
Devin.
Devin is not a good dude
cause it's his friend.
It's his friend and he was trying
to move in on it when, uh, when,
uh, when they were still together.
So that guy, you know, it's weird.
You know who's going to lose in all of
this is going to be you because you're,
you're with this creep. This guy's a
fucking creep. Um, or maybe he's just,
you don't know he's a creep.
Don't maybe,
maybe he always had feelings for
her and the other guy didn't treat.
We don't know.
I just went with creek.
But she said that her ex boyfriend said
it was creepy. I don't fucking know, Paul,
what am I going to solve? The solve the
problems of theft in 18 and 19 year olds.
I can't do this. All right,
look, yeah, stop doing that
to them. Stop posting stuff,
sending pick and you're, you're acting
like you don't know what you're doing.
At least as a far as like a hurting
the person. You're hurting them,
you're hurting them and you
should stop. Um, and if you don't,
then you're a mean person, but you're
not a whore. She's not a whore now.
And that's not a whore. That's not a
whore. What is a hoarder? You, Paul,
if she sent pictures while
she's blowing Devin, I mean,
that'd be a little fucking much, you
know? But even then as you get older,
when you start to think of the psycho
psychological reasons as to why a woman
would do that,
you know,
and it always goes back to some sort
of family issue that they would do then
some sort of insecurity and you
know, having no boundaries, right.
The Times when something like that
happens, you got touched as a kid.
I'm kind of paraphrasing some of
the shit that I've heard some, no,
I just think a horse, when I think of
horror, I think of Eugene using sex, you,
you know, doing sexual things
or using sex in order to,
to gain and do stuff like that, you
know, to, to get yourself ahead through,
through sex.
And she,
and I would actually say that that's more
of a sociopath who just happens to be
using, uh, you know,
sex rather than using a gun or
a knife or something like that.
They're just going up.
They using the weapon that they
got are all horse sociopaths.
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no. I would say, I would say no,
not at all. I would say that, you know,
men and women who have a
bunch of fucking partner,
different partners or something like that,
the older I get,
they're not like dogs and
whores and stuff like that,
like they have does something
wrong with them, uh, beyond, um,
look,
there's something wrong with fucking
being married and this is the only person
you ever going to have sex with
again. I mean that's, it's,
there's something not
fucking natural about that,
but the other side of that is to
just walk around fucking everybody,
just fucking everybody.
Then there's something,
there's something wrong about that.
But what I'm doing is also, you know,
my opinion is, is I'm come, I'm looking
out my own head here, how I would feel.
I remember, you know, I
was out dogging around.
I would always feel like a piece of
shit on some level, past a certain age.
You twenties you like psyched, like, yeah,
he got another one right in your thirties.
It starts to get,
it starts to get sad such to get pathetic.
So I, I wouldn't say you're a whore,
but um,
unfortunately we have to wrap up here.
Paul another effortless podcasts.
Great time. It was always a great time.
[inaudible] effect podcast. Yes.
Diversity effect podcast. And also, um,
we kick off March 31st at
Largo. The all in tour. Yes.
Tour with myself. Joe Barton,
nick, Jason, Lawhead. Um,
these three animals are
going on tour and a,
I'm going to host the kickoff one. It's
not, I don't know. Yeah, that one's good.
That one's going to be at Largo.
I don't know where the other ones are.
Dates are coming in day to come and go.
West Coast dates.
San Francisco Punch line is on the
website now. So you could go to that.
We're going to Portland. We're going
to Seattle. We're going to San Diego.
East Coast will be in Jersey. Uh, we
will be in Cleveland. So check out. Yeah,
we're going to be in Pittsburgh, so
check out all those dates are coming in.
But that's the all in tour with uh,
sponsored by the Monday morning,
the first tour that I'm putting,
uh, putting them Monday morning,
podcast name behind. And we appreciate
it too. I know. I just love your talents.
Uh, yeah. So,
and now you can go to my Twitter
at Paul Versey that's via Rci,
and please download the Versie
effect podcast. Bill was
the last guest on it, and,
uh, the podcast is doing better, so, well,
that's it, man. Thanks for having me.
All right. All right guys, that's
the podcast. Go fuck yourselves.
We'll talk to you next week.