Hey,
what's going on is bill burn.
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for my, Yay. Monday,
July 25th,
2016 what's going on?
How? What's going on? Um,
the final Monday in July
of 2016 and a old freckles.
All Billy red beard. Oh,
fucking belly fat face.
Fucking trying to get the weight off
cam trying to get the weight off,
working out during the day, eating
grade, having a beer at night,
fucking losing everything that he
worked for. It's fucking ridiculous.
It's ridiculous what one beer
does. And I just, I got to do it.
I got a bunch of beers leftover
from the fucking 4th of July.
They're taking up all this space in my
fridge and I'm not going to throw him out.
Okay.
I mean there's, there's children that work
in the Budweiser factory that fucking,
you know,
they sleep on piles of Hay,
right? They pay him 29 cents
a month. I don't know if
that's true. Maybe it's hops.
I don't know what they sleep on now.
There's no people. There's no children.
There's no children working at
Budweiser. That's but paid. Man.
It wouldn't invest in Budweiser.
There was children there.
I'm just going to go give me a couple
birdwatcher we had protection issue.
Um, my wife's on steroids. What Marie?
She blew out her shoulder.
Mike [inaudible].
Shoshi she human growth hormone. Bradshaw.
I'm going to say about that before.
Put my balls on somebodies head.
I'm sorry.
I believe in anonymous. In a great mood.
Um, yeah, so I've got these fucking,
I got all these bears in my fridge.
What am I gonna what am I,
what the fuck am I supposed to do with
them? I can't throw them out again.
Boddington's I got some millis
so I just have like one a night,
right? And then I have a home pour of
fucking whiskey. That's all she wrote.
It's all she wrote.
I barely even get buzzed off of that too.
When I wake up the next day
and I just feel like shit,
I don't know why I keep doing it.
It's a habit I have to break. I am a,
I am a one and a half drink alcoholic.
I have to have one and a half drinks
and get a little buzzed every night.
I want to go to a fucking AA meeting and
say like, that's my problem. You know,
I'll never forget when I started
going off the rails when I, uh, yeah,
I would have,
I'd have one on Miller lite tall in a
can and then I'd have a home poor of a
whiskey and a,
of course after I finished that,
I would just stop and I'd go to sleep
and the next day I'd wake up and I'd be
totally functional and I'd
go to work, but I, you know,
I definitely be a little grouchy
and now that's my story.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you for sharing.
Next guy comes up.
Well go rape me with the 12 pack,
but I was fine.
Right? They'd throw me out of
there. They'd be walking up,
put down him donuts. I don't know why they
all have southern accents in my world.
Everyone in Aa is from the south.
You know why they never got over the war.
This still fighting it down there.
South's going to rise again and do what?
You're going to secede from the union.
You're going to get old stonewall
Jackson, junior, junior, junior
to come back and take over for you.
Yeah. You know what I say to that?
I said good luck. Die. Say
Good fucking, you know, do it.
Just know this.
She can't have Florida and if you
can't have Florida and you can't go to
California,
where are you going to take your kids?
Huh?
When they say,
you know when they did fucking sitting
there watching your confederate TV,
right?
And it's a small world comes on,
which is even more apropos over the fuck
you say it because you just like nine
fucking states down there
whenever the hell you are. Right.
It's a small world after all.
And they're like, you want want,
what do they call father's
down in? Uh, what are the,
what do they call been at Old Gym Dad.
I want to go to Disney world.
You can't cause you
seceded from the union.
You can't go to Disney land and
you can't go to his fucking world.
You know what?
You can go Talladega.
You can go see the Winston Cup series.
How'd they get a water slide out there?
I don't think they do.
They've got,
have a bunch of adults skipping around
and fucking outfit said scare children.
They do not. So let me tell you
something fucking there. Mason diction.
Yeah.
Mason and Dixon.
Why don't you think twice?
Think about everything you're going to
lose out on a few seceded from the union.
Huh? No more Disneyland.
No more Disney world
sea world's down there.
You don't get to see those fucking
fish that don't want to be there. Yeah,
I love people think like fish. Like don't
give a fuck that they were in the tank,
you know?
Just because they don't have an ability
to speak to us that therefore that means
they have defined fine with it.
We treat fish like immigrants. You know
the fish is fucking looking at you.
You just like English.
You got a problem with that.
Takes it out.
Okay.
Fucking sit there staring at me.
But yeah,
I was on the side of your fucking
scaly head. Be happy I didn't eat you.
You look at me one more time.
I'll cut your fucking head off.
I'll above roll you into some flour
with an egg wash and our deep fry.
You mother fucker and I'll
make your friends watch.
Okay.
Sit there and fucking stare at me like
I work for you. I don't work for you.
Who here is in a tank?
That's right. I didn't,
so I didn't think so.
Um,
anyways, um, Bill, why you show off
the fucking walls today? You know why?
Because I,
I,
we wrapped at least the script writing
part of season two of f is for family,
which means I get to go back to being a
fucking 14 year old who has no fucking
job, no responsibilities, no nothing,
just a bunch of beers in my fridge
that I'm slowly going to kill.
I do the elliptical in the morning and
then I give it all back with a can of
beer and that's what I do right?
While I fucking wear out my joints.
That's all I'm really doing right
now. I'm just maintaining. Um,
isn't that what a lot of people in this
digital age you're just trying to do?
Aren't they just trying to maintain,
just trying to keep their heads above
water and this time of change and robots?
Um, if they'd fucking this
election, has that happened yet?
Jesus fucking, he can't go near
the Goddamn TV. Everybody's
so fucking scared. Ooh.
It's going to happen.
Nothing is going to continue
on the way it's supposed to go.
And whether the fucking comb over
or the clam gets in the house,
it's going to go in the direction
that the money wants it to go into.
And if it doesn't, okay,
they're going to Dallas,
right.
And then not going to be in a 10.
They're going to fucking roll out that
63 fucking stretched Lincoln convertible.
That's right. They're going to
get the old right there. Fred,
to their fucking Jesus Christ, the
two of them. You know what I mean?
Their heads. You know what?
If I was in secret service,
there would be a head size that
you could not be above, you know,
or, or else the president would have
to sign a waiver. Just like, you know,
both of them, Hillary and
fucking and Trump, they have,
they have like,
like if you could make sliders
out of Ted Kennedy's head,
that's what the fuck they have. That is
the most amazing thing about Ted Kennedy.
He had the biggest fucking
head out of all of them and he,
nobody ever took them out.
You know,
you would think that that
fucking guy out of all of them,
they all had big
squashes, right? You know,
it's all good looking men dough,
right? You got to have a big head,
big stupid head with the squared jaw
that look in your eye like everything's
gonna be okay. The kind of
thing that make women go, oh,
he can pay for all my stuff.
Right.
One of those heads, well, what's his face?
Ted Kennedy was ahead of his
time, no pun intended, right?
If you want to know how fat
people were going to get,
if you want to know how big
sodas were going to get,
if you want to know how
fucking ridiculous, you know,
mcmansions and all this shit and all this
stuff that we were going to by the age
of consumerism, right? If you will,
back in the 1950s trying to guess,
you had a wage of which
way is it going to go?
Are we going to go back to living
on dirt floors and log cabins?
Are we going to have kegerators in
fucking chocolate fountains in our houses?
All you had to do was look at Ted
Kennedy said it'd be like, there it is.
That right there.
That's an omen.
You know the interesting thing
about Ted Kennedy's head, uh,
it was in his entire time he was alive.
It was never backlit ever.
People try, they just was
never enough light. You know,
there's not even a picture of him
like blocking out the fucking,
like not even the sun could
reach around either side.
It just became night when
you walked outside. Hey,
I'm saying he had a big head. You
know, um, I've got a big head.
Okay.
I gotta pick head. I do
literally and figuratively.
I got a giant head.
I got a fucking ego and a half
because I got the whole week off.
And what am I going to do?
I'm going to rest up getting
ready for my European tour,
like the red fucking
headed whore than I am.
And I'm going to fucking Tuesday night
I'm going to be at the Steve Allen
Theater on Hollywood Boulevard,
the boulevard of dreams.
Um, I'm going to be there and, uh,
just basically saying my shit.
So,
you know, I just wait. All you need to
do is just fucking say it a few times,
right? Just moderate to myself. Walk
around the block, talked to myself,
hands in my pocket, vigorously scratching
the side of my ball sack. Right.
Having the cops come by, having them
pull over, asking me what I'm doing.
Do I live around here?
Are you a vagrant? Um,
sorry. Did you guys see Rudy
Giuliani speech about the policemen?
That was one of the funniest fucking
things I've ever seen in my life.
The way he was trying to get that crowd
going. You know they come to your house,
right?
All right.
I wanted him to keep going.
You know,
he just basically distraught
describe police officers' jobs,
but I wanted him to keep
going and I wanted him to,
to portray how wealthy he is and,
and the influential friends that
he has, you know, they come to you,
they say you're under arrest, but you
have your lawyer made up in the driveway.
And I say, Ronelle turn himself. The
charges go away.
I wanted it. I wanted them to go that
far because here's the deal. You know,
the way the police had been paid
right now it's fucking ridiculous.
It's the same way, you
know, if one comic sucks,
then every fucking comic out there
has a lampshade on the fucking head.
You know what I mean?
There's definitely some terrible
people that are police officers,
but that doesn't mean that they're
all bad. Okay. Now, Rudy Giuliani,
you can't fucking stand there where you
exist in society with your skin color.
And think that you can accurately
describe police officers. You know,
and you need somebody a
little more mid range.
Well maybe it's good that he said that.
Okay, now we've got the high end, right.
Black people fucking said their rent
and then you just need somebody in the
middle. Now. He still can't do it. You
still can't do it because of racism.
You've got to try to balance the whole
fucking thing out. Um, I don't know.
Who knows? So yeah, you'd think,
you know, it'd be great with the,
with the fucking cell phone cameras
and then the cops filling themselves.
What would be great is if
somebody fucked up as a cop,
if they actually got fired,
if they actually fucking were
punished and went to jail,
they actually murdered somebody. Not like,
you know, one or two or three people.
If they actually just started
doing that. I Dunno. I don't know.
I don't know if there's any fucking
solution to it. You know what I mean?
It's a hell of a fucking job to have.
Well,
you got to walk up to a fucking car not
knowing if you're going to get shot or
not. That would make me a little
edgy. You know what I mean?
And I think a lot of cons can sit in
their fucking led living room Perth when
they're perfectly safe, being like,
oh, you know what I wouldn't do?
This is what I would've done.
Right?
Like when you watch your
fucking quarterback throws
an interception and then you
say, I would have dumped it off to
the tight end. Oh, is that what he is?
That's what you would've done on
your fucking couch. [inaudible]
I think it's an impossible job.
And I also think that's a,
there's an element to that job that
fucking sadistic psychopaths are attracted
to bouncers and all those things.
This a lot of people that just want to
beat the shit out of people that go for
that job.
Then there's other ones that go there.
They have their heart in the
right fucking place, you know?
But they don't really make the news.
You know what I mean?
It's kind of like comics.
Like every night we tell jokes,
nobody gets offended and then one cut
gets fucking offended and then all of us.
Is that what it's like bill?
Somebody getting unarmed,
somebody unarmed getting murdered is
like somebody getting in trouble for
Caitlyn Jenner joke. Gi Bill. Thanks for
fucking explaining that one. Oh fuck you.
It's my podcast. Okay.
I choose not to read.
I choose not to be informed.
That's my choice. Okay.
I'm like one of those feminists,
you know and they fucking start
yelling about that though.
Tell me what they do in my body.
All right.
Don't tell me what to do with my podcast.
No more podcast shaming.
Oh Shit. I had the fucking greatest
set I've had in fucking months.
Saturday night at the comedy
store in the main room.
There was this chunk of material
I've been trying to work out.
I finally said it the right
way and then I came home.
I was so confident of it.
I played it for my wife and even she left.
And that's the deal when you try
something new. This is, this is,
this is the litmus test and I mean,
what the fuck that means?
I don't even know if I'm saying it right.
Litmos lattice model.
Right.
Okay.
My fucking test is, I then play it for
the lovely Nia, and if she fucking laugh,
you can make your fucking wife get
behind the new shit that you're doing.
Then you know you're on to something.
You know? Because in general,
what they do when they first
meet you, they're like, oh
my God, you're amazing. Oh,
and they just fucking pump you up,
right? So you start going like, wow,
she's really cool, man. Right?
And then once they get you,
okay,
once you fucking in the relationship,
once you give him the
ring and you get married,
then they fucking just grabbed
the reins and Sean, whoa, Nelly.
Wow. Right. They start
yanking the fuck back.
Not because they're jerks.
It's just out of fear.
Hmm.
He's going to do something new.
He's going to find something new.
He's going to find somebody new.
That's what they do. Unlike guys,
everybody knows that men are
totally secure with who they are.
I'm just doing this right now for any
guy who's listening to this podcast next
to a woman just to listen to her going,
oh like God,
that guy is such an idiot.
Let me tell you something lady.
All right, and don't look at him
right now cause he's not saying this.
I'm talking to you sweetheart, in the
background, shaking your fucking head.
It's your man who's going to die
before you let him have his left.
Okay? What you feel right fucking now is
what a man feels when he comes home and
you're walking, you're watching
those Botox squawk and fucking horse,
okay? Doing the recap of their
fucking season with that, eh,
Andy Cohen or whatever his name is,
that fucking genius.
He's like bees like the gay Byron Allen.
You know where they just found
a show where there was no shelf.
Everybody was like,
there's no show here and the
genius of that guy to be like,
yes there is.
It's not enough.
Did he got a bunch of screaming hordes
yelling at each other that someone's
going to sit down and watch
it every fucking night.
The fact that he then does the recap.
It just sits there.
You don't have to write anything new.
They do it for you.
He just sits there and effortlessly
hosts the show. He's a master.
He just sits there already. Any yeses,
this fucking setlist like a comic.
But all it is is to get these women
yelling at each other. And he just,
he just,
just watch the brilliance of that
meant he just fucking sits there.
And if it's, if it's fucking simmering,
he turns up the heat, you know,
you know an episode for Kathy,
she,
she had some choice words in the warm,
that's all he has to say. Oh my God, what?
She called me a fucking cunt and then
she goes and he just fucking lays back
like Ali.
Right.
And when he was fighting George Foreman
and he just lets these women start
fucking punching each other out and they
run off set and he sits there and this
is the brilliance of this man is he sits
there and he actually has a look on his
face. Like he truly gives a fuck. Like,
he actually gives a shit about these
people. He's just sitting there going,
that's great TV,
Eh,
we go that just sold some toothpaste and
he's just fucking raking it and look at
the guy,
he looks like 1 million bucks.
A lot of people don't know this about
that man. He's 83 fucking years old.
You know,
everybody talking about Dick Clark,
how great he looked right
to the fucking end. Yeah.
Well close to the end that I shouldn't
have said that, but fucking, you know,
whatever. We all go out
like that. Right. But um,
he's fucking 83 a lot of people don't
know that. You'd think the guy was like,
you know, like whatever. What,
37 I have no fucking idea.
Does gotta be people hosting Real Shit?
That's fucking difficult going.
Why the fuck didn't I just do that?
Yeah.
What he is, is he's doing a
sophisticated Jerry Springer, you know,
everybody's sitting down, there's no
punches thrown. They scream and yell.
They crossed their legs.
This is the one thing I'll
say about the real housewives.
They're fucking legs are incredible.
It's fucking amazing.
Their legs are like fucking 22 year olds,
their fucking faces.
You know, Jesus Christ. And I got
a lot of fucking nerve saying this.
Considering the way I look,
considering the way I traveled the world,
looking like an albino balding
Hellboy minus the working out,
right?
I look like the thing. If it was skinny
and didn't have that skin disease,
you know what I mean? But yet could not
go out in the sun. That's what I am.
I'm a middleweight thing minus whatever.
What's it made out of? Oh, come on.
Come on. Comic cons. You
know what he's made out of?
You know how he turned into that? Was
it another accident in a lab? Huh?
Did he come here from another planet and
then get bit by a spider and then got
blinded by some shit?
Now he's a fast aunt living
in somebody's fucking head.
You know,
driving a jet ski down to Middle Earth.
Jesus Christ.
Just when you think,
just when you fucking think that the
real housewives is the dumbest fucking
thing you're ever going to watch.
They come out with another
stupid fucking superhero movie.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Can somebody get the,
just collectively get these
nerds, some hookers, you
know, why don't they go, wait,
what? What did the kids go on
now? It tastes, what does that,
what does that fucking, you
know, it's one of those apps,
whatever the fuck it is,
it's not, is it Tinder?
One of them is like the hoary and then
the other ones like, Ooh, you know,
I look to Scalia to food and when
you look to hill three children,
you know the dose App and then you've
got the other ones. Just like, you know,
hey, you know, I got some bows yet.
Oh I got a Dana Lang.
I want to stick it in your
fucking fucking monkey.
All their whatever it is.
That's fucking amazing.
God blessed this generation. You know
what I mean? That's fucking great.
They have that, you know, it's weird.
Every year like life becomes easier.
You have to think less,
but it gets more expensive. It's
fucking nuts. You know what I mean?
Okay.
I can tell you right now,
if there was fucking free porn
and there was these dating sites,
you know how much easier your fucking
life would have been when you were a kid.
Just not having a fucking, Oh God, Jesus.
I remember having to go out
to those stupid fucking,
you just go on out to these fucking clubs.
You know I was going out there and the
fucking late eighties walking into a
nightclub, pop up, down, pop it
out, put now pow, don't talk.
We don't talk to top it off.
Wow. That girl is boy then
and everybody with their fucking
puffy as pets walking around.
We're driving gloves inside.
Yeah.
Fucking music loud as shit.
You know.
Now you can sit there and your fucking
underwear just scrolling through people
like you're a fucking rockstar on,
you know like whenever you
hear that shit like cow,
the roadies would go out and pick the
fucking women that the band was going to
fuck. And they be like, yeah,
you put your friends got to stay and
then the front can, Fran would leave.
She'd be like,
Martha.
Yeah. And she just fucking
walks away just for one night.
Yeah.
With to, to fuck the guy. Some
guy from deep purple, right.
Then years later, the two
of them mate, you know,
at a high school reunion and
then the fucker one that left,
the other one left Marcy
behind is all fucking nervous.
That Marcy's going to let her and
her now husband know that she fucked,
you know the Maracas player,
the Maracas player from deep purple,
he wasn't even a full member. They just
had them on for that one fucking song.
Cause Santana scared the fuck out of them.
Nick thought that was the
direction of music was going to go.
Then once they realized that mainstream
music was only going to accept one
Santana,
right.
And there wasn't going to
be another fucking type of
Santa's and tell those guys,
bum, bum, bum, bum layer. And then
there was Ricky Martin. How's that?
[inaudible] right.
Yeah.
And years fucking later at, they're
at the, they're at the fucking heist,
the high school reunion and
she's just fucking with her eyes.
She's trying to be like,
oh, it's so to see you.
She's fucking like bringing her in like,
you know,
trying to fucking sorta muffler and
choke around like don't fucking say shit
though. I heard another fucking Mirage
layer in blogging. Deep verbal. Right.
And then Marcy,
she's just now she's a woman.
She's just not going to come out and
say it was the fun there. Then the,
then it's over. You know, it's
like a cat playing with a mouse.
She's just got an a linger. She's
going to start talking to the husband.
Yeah, act it all interest. Not Looking
at fucking, you know, Marcy. Right.
And that she's going to kind of glance
over at her and that she's just going to
just slowly let it. Yeah.
Mya and your wife. Yeah,
we were crazy back then.
Remember all those concert we went to
and she's just going to watch there if I
forget it was Marcy at this point,
the fucking chicken got led.
We'll just say Marcy's done married one.
Right.
He's just going to see
her face fucking fall.
It's this fucking chick just twist the
fucking knife. Is she going to tell?
Is she not going to tell and then she'll
back off and change the subject and
then she'll gradually
come back around to it.
And this fucking guy's just standing
there, doesn't know a fucking thing.
Um, I'm sorry. I was just, you know,
I was just doing a table read
for a fucking screenplay.
I'm writing called a Marcy's a country,
you know,
and I've been shopping around Hollywood
forever and I'll tell you is great.
It's the script is for
whatever fucking reason,
they just cannot get past the title,
you know,
it's just this politically correct
age that we live in. All right,
let's get to some of the
reeds here for this week. Uh,
for Christ's sake, Bill did.
Did you even fucking did you even
fucking, no, you didn't. Yeah,
there we go. All right.
Here we got four reads.
Indochino Indochino
the fuck is this.
Talk about how good it feels to have a
suit that is one of kindness is uniquely
yours. Talk about how when you
look good, you feel confident
about. Why don't you fucking write
some shift for me to talk about
what is this an interview?
Talk about wearing suits.
All right, Indochina Window,
Chino. Alright, Indo Chino is
reinventing. Oh, I remember these guys.
All these guys, actually, I don't
know why I'm shitting on him.
These guys are fucking great. Hey, do you
need, you know, I'll talk about this. Hey,
you remember when you had to go to that
fucking thing and you had to wear a
fucking suit and you put it on and you'll,
you'll look like you lost 30 pounds cause
it was your older brothers. You know,
wouldn't it be nice to have a suit that
just completely fit you was totally
custom made and measured, measured out
your arms and your legs and your Crotch,
right? Seeing how far down your
balls hang. Wouldn't that be Greg?
Except it didn't cost a zillion
bucks? Well, you couldn't do that,
but now there's Indochino Indochina.
They are reinventing men's fashion and
a made to measure suit is the best suit
you'll ever own.
So suit up,
get a one of a kind made to measure suit,
custom. Customize his details. You want,
pick your lining. Lapels, personal
monogram. There you go. Is it good one?
Every chick,
even these feminists,
like when a guy has his initials
on the fucking cuffs, right?
And more the fuck happened to the AC.
Okay,
14 unique measurements go into making
a suit that fits you perfectly.
You can't go wrong with the
well-crafted 100% Merino wool suit.
Also checkout.
Who the fuck buys a wool suit in August?
They're made to measure measure,
dress shirts and men's
accessories. Moneyback guarantee
t money back guarantee.
Today my listeners get any premium
suit just for three 99 that's up to 50%
off@indochino.com when entering burr
at checkout plus shipping is free.
There's no reason not to try your
first custom made suit with the deal.
This good and s and a classic suit from
their premium collection will look good.
Feel good and last.
That's indochino.com Promo Code Burr.
Any premium suit for just
three 99 free shipping.
That's Indochino or China.
Look your look your way.
Okay, that was a rough one. All
right. Oh, dollar shave club.
Dollar Shave club.com delivers amazing
razors right to your door for a third of
the price of what degree you
raise it. Corporations, Chad,
you know why they don't give a fuck,
dude.
That means you can join dollar shave club.
You can afford to shave with a
fresh blade anytime you want,
which feels fantastic.
You get a first class shave when you
use the executive blade. Oh yeah,
and that's without even
hurting your wallet.
And when you use the executive
razor with doctor cabbies,
easy share
the play just glides gently
for the smoothest shave ever.
Shave butter do.
People can do cocaine off your cheek.
That's how fucking smooth it's going
to beach. Dice it right up. Oh God,
that would hurt shea butter
isn't your average shave cream.
It's a unique conditioning formula with
high quality natural ingredients leaving
your skin unbelievably soft and smooth.
Now's a great time to join dollar
shave club. New members who buy a tub,
a tube, sorry, of shave butter. Get a
month of the executive razor for free.
Take advantage of this
special offer today.
It's available by going to dollar
shave club.com/bird that's dollar shave
club.com/ [inaudible] all right, what
do we got left? Two more. Two more.
Hang in there.
Scorebig
you're paying too much for tickets
between all the markups and last minute
convenience and charges even printed
home fees. You fucking kidding me.
Did you end up paying court
side prices for nosebleed seats?
Scorebig is here to change all of that.
Did you know that 40% of all
live event tickets go on soul
and did you know there's a place
to get these take seats and a huge,
it's called score.
Big score a bit works directly with your
favorite teams and artists to get their
unsold seats at unpublished
prices. Ali, with ScoreBig,
can you name a ticket price?
I want it and be guaranteed to pay
below box office up to 60% off.
Here's what you gotta do. You don't have
to do it, but this is what you should do.
One Uno,
uh,
go to score big.com or download the news.
I just realized what French
people fucked it. They does.
A woman thinks she the guys
counting or does he just, you know,
fucking you know. Ah, AH, sorry. Ah,
go to score big.com or download the new
score big APP for your iPhone and find
the event in seats.
You want to make an offer with score,
Biggs name a ticket, uh, price feature.
I'll get an instant answer then
save up to 60% of your tickets,
never any fees.
And shipping is always free.
You can count on and unbeatable
prices and great seats.
And when you're in great seats,
you actually enjoy the game or the show.
All the more.
Yeah,
because you've got more chance of being
next to some gold digging horror might
give you a fucking handy if you've got
your initials on your sleeve there.
Next time you go see any game a show,
go to score big first and see how much
you could save for the easiest Jesus
Christ. We get it for the
easiest way to save on tickets.
Download the new score
big APP for your iPhone.
Enter the Promo Code [inaudible] at
checkout and you'll save an extra 20 bucks
off your first tickets per
purchase. No iPhone, no problem.
Go steal one punching old lady and
they had no get the $20 off online.
Uh, get $20 off online too. What score?
Big Dotcom that score
big.com Promo Code Bar Score,
big.com promo code birth lastly,
but not leastly stamps.com
everybody you know,
trips to the post office have
probably becomes second nature to you.
They seem easy because you've been doing
your mailing and shipping that way for
so long and you live in a first world
country so you don't have to walk nine
miles with a basket on your head to go
get some water while you fight off a
cobra. But think about
all the hassle, man.
Dropping what you're doing to driving.
They're finding parking and waiting.
There's a much better way
it stamps.com everybody stamps.com is
easy as convenient way to get postage
right from your desk by and print
official us postage using your own cup and
with stamps.com there's no guesswork.
You don't have to think you fucking dope.
They make it easy to get exact postage
for any letter or package. Classic Male,
the instant you need it.
No expensive postage meters to lease.
No more trips to the post office.
You have to try. You don't have to,
but you should.
I use stamps.com anytime I'm,
but you know I've got to
ship out my posters. Then I'm
going to whore myself out.
Meet the public. Every 11th person is
going to have a fucking sweaty palm.
Maybe there'll be a tall guy.
He can put his arm around me and I can
feel the heat of his sweaty armpit.
Making my right shoulder
blade damp through my shirt.
Sign up for stamps.com and use my last
name, birth for this special offer,
four week trial plus a $110 bonus offer
that enclose the postage and a digital
scale. Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbirththatstamps.com
and
Tupper. All right. Now that
we got that out of the way,
it's tied to go back to the pool.
Uh,
did anybody watched the
Hungary Grand Prix yesterday?
Did Ya? Well, did you
Lewis Hamilton wins again?
Nico Rosberg came in second and
now Lewis Hamilton. That's it.
That's the fifth time he won that race.
And I learned that uh,
he passed our correct shoemaker
stand up comedian and legendary.
A fucking f one driver?
No, Michael Schumacher.
Um,
every,
every other grand Prix drivers sounds
like the guitarist and Scorpions and the
Scorpions I should say.
Um,
yeah,
yours fucked up about that. Tran.
I don't know shit about this sport.
It just seem whoever was in first
like, like the race was to the first turn
and then it was just fucking over you.
You couldn't get past anybody, you
know. Who was that fucking lunatic?
Zigzag and behind the red bull.
Huh? Going back and forth.
He cut off the front of his fucking car.
Was it Sebastian Vettel
was at Max for stopping.
Um, can you rake one and
was the driver of the day?
If he was in Lincoln fucking 90th place
and he moved up to like seventh Assam
Shit. Uh, I already, it adds, it's warm.
It's race for fourth was really
entertaining, but I didn't like how that,
you know,
there was no way for fucking Nico to
even try to pass Lewis once he got out in
front that fucking track, it was just, you
know, kind of stunk like Lewis Hamilton,
which is driving or I am
right the whole fucking
time. And uh, you know,
they would just showing like the race
for fourth and fifth and third and fourth
and then like they were on the final lap
and it was so fucking boring out front.
They was still back. You know, watching
that Guy Zigzag. Hey Formula One fans.
I don't understand why they, I
like the fucking rules. Well, Bill,
why don't you look them up? Well,
it's easier to ask you guys.
It's also funny or if I talk about him
and I don't know what I'm talking about,
I don't get out when the guy who
cut off the front of his car, right.
One of the fucking fence. I did find
it funny that they were like, yeah,
people do that all the time and it doesn't
affect the performance of the car. Um,
it doesn't seem too anyways,
um,
where they saying you were
only allowed to make one move,
like you went to the right and then he
came back to the left and then back to
the right. And that was considered more
than one move. And I was just like,
what the fuck? He can't do that.
I thought I left this behind.
What the NFL season. Hey,
this is like, you know, he's
got to make a football move.
That fucking guy,
when he tried to go around,
the other dude didn't do anything that
I don't do when I'm on the highway,
when I'm behind some fucking Douche
driving too fucking slow in the left lane.
Right. Oh, you know what? And,
and I'm in the, I'm in the
second to left lane. Right.
And there's some guy driving medium
speed and then somebody during that just
making a wall. And I'm like, what the
fuck? What the fuck? What the fuck?
What the fuck? And then you go
around to the right coming around.
Now when I watched the race,
it was Lewis Hamilton,
then Rosberg and I
remember it was a red bull,
then a Ferrari, then a
red bull, then a Ferrari.
And then today it's saying red
bull, Ferrari, Ferrari red bull.
So did somebody get panelized
it's fucking unreal.
I don't get it. Like it's, there's
always like after the fucking Raul,
you thought you won the race. But, uh,
somebody said something in ta don't shift
into seventh gear. And they were like,
oh, you can't do that. Don't
tell him what he shouldn't do.
You know, if he's only driving a
car at 200 fucking miles an hour,
one guy spun up.
That was it.
There wasn't really any crashes or
anything like that, but it was funny.
I'm actually totally, until my wife can't
stand and she says when I have it on,
it sounds like a bunch of
bees flying around, but um,
it's still fucking cool as shit
though. Love that. I don't know.
That was probably my,
of all the races I've watched,
that's been my least favorite. Um, just
because there was all this, like the,
the,
the start of the race was
the most exciting and then
there was just a bunch of
people in the back trying to go around
people and they couldn't do it except for
Kimmy. Raikkonen the flying Finn
evidently see the flying Finn.
I have no fucking idea. Um, anyways,
but this is really getting me through
the fucking dog days of baseball.
I fucking love baseball,
but I just, you know,
I can't get into it in July and
August. I like it in April, you know,
and the May,
you start seeing what's going to happen
and then I just fucking vege out June,
July, August, the same way
the players too right there.
Just standing up there
like, dude, what the fuck?
How many fucking games do you have to
play in the regular season before we know
who deserves to win the division
hundred and 60 to five.
Isn't that, isn't that
insane? That has to be,
if you're going to own a professional
team, that's gotta be the sport to do it.
162 home games.
If your team selling out the Ballpark,
Jesus Christ.
Those things have to be, I got to
look this up right now. Look at this.
I'm actually going to do research
professional.
See,
I know franchises.
I should've put sports in there right now.
If something's got to be fucking
talking and being about Mcdonald's
worth the most.
Okay, well this is everything. Okay?
The Dallas cowboys for whatever reason,
are worth $4 billion.
Real Madrid,
John Guessing is some sort of football
club in Spain is worth three point $7
billion.
And then there's another one in Barcelona.
Is that also Spain?
3.6 billion.
The New York Yankees.
There you go.
Well that makes sense that like
a world football as we call it,
soccer would be worth that
much money cause that's,
that really is when you
win a world championship,
you're winning the World Cup.
You're playing against the fucking
world, right? It's like an Olympic medal,
except you get paid a
then the New York Yankees,
3.4 billion,
then man United 3.3 billion.
Oh
and then the new England patriots,
everybody's favorite fucking team to hate.
On 3.2 billion then the New York Knicks.
What?
3 billion?
Jesus Christ. No New York. Tell, I'll
tell you, that's a fixer upper right.
That New York Knicks or a fucking
tear down. Oh, this is weird,
man.
Then the Washington red skins 2.9 billion.
Hey,
shut up million dollars. I
hate when this happens. Yeah,
25%
now you've got to figure out where
the fuck the voice is coming from.
shut up. Oh, there it is.
All right.
All right. The Redskins
are, we're 2.9 billion.
Then the giants are 2.8 building,
building billion.
Then the Lakers a 2.7 the Lakers
are worth less than the Knicks.
Okay.
If anything says that this state is
going to fall into the ocean one day,
it's the fact that the fucking nics
are worth more fucking money than the
fucking Lakers. Jesus Christ.
What are the Celtics worth?
Oh my God.
Rappaport's gonna fucking love that.
Well,
you know something that actually makes
sense because you know when you move to
Manhattan, you fuck. Can you
fucking let me get to the site?
I hate when fucking sites do this.
They just got to suck the
fucking information outta Ya.
Forbes going to give you my fucking email.
What?
So Time magazine can start fucking
spam and me. I don't think so.
Why Hillary Clinton should be thankful.
Election is not today.
I don't know why he's her suits all in
the fucking dry cleaners. All right,
let's uh, let's, let's do swear.
Where am I? How much time have I done?
41 minutes.
You know,
some days it feels like work
other days that doesn't, um,
you know, I've become obsessed with
as of last night is, is uh, you know,
I've been doing this grip strength thing
and I've been fucking doing great man.
I can go up a peg board
now at 48 years of age.
I can go up a climbing rope leaving my
skinny fucking Alabaster fucking albino
legs just dangling like a fucking,
I dunno.
Couple of appendixes, right Jason?
I never had to make that plural.
Appendix. Appendix is tits. Today's okay?
MMM.
Yeah. Cause you know what? I got
those, those atomic fucking holds.
Those mother fuckers better send
me some free shit. I'm sick.
I hypen those guys up. But they're
the shit. They are the shit.
So now I want to be
able to do one of those.
Is it called a front lever or front lever?
Um,
and I watched this guy's a youtube
video. I'll, I'll repost it.
The six easy steps, eh, hey,
lovely Nia to being able
to do a front lever.
MMM.
Did you hear about Paula
Abdul? No. Was um, she's,
she's a singer and she was a Laker girl.
Oh, lab door. The National John. No,
I have to eat my cereal. Oh, okay.
I just brought you some of this.
Thank you. Come on to the mic. Mike.
Mike Baby Dude. Dude. Dude, why
did you do that? About Paula Abdul.
Um, cause those love Paula Abdul.
I know. I like making people laugh.
I had to pick somebody, you
know, if I was like, yeah, go.
Did you hear about Paula
Abdul? Like that's not funny.
It is funny. It is funny.
And you're going to sit there and
act like you're not going to do it.
To me that's true.
Who would you pick
one of your rock icons?
Probably, you know,
kind of helps if you pick a name.
Well,
I can't tell you because then it's not
going to be a surprise when I do it.
All right. No, it isn't because you
already told me you're going to do it.
See what I did there.
Oh yeah.
I guess what I could flip it. I
Dunno. It's, it's the morning.
Still drink some of your juice. I
brought it for you. Oh, thank you. Well,
I got to do a podcast. If you don't
mind just dirty right now though. No, I,
people give me shit because I
try not to drink on the mic,
but I have to hold the
microphone does take a sip.
I been talked to them like drinking.
Okay. So my snapchat last night,
if you guys follow me on Snapchat,
I made my fresh squeeze watermelon
juice and I'm giving it to bill,
who loves the wow.
It's taken it down like a champ.
You give him anything in this glass? I
suck it down. Just like my, my juice.
I drink at night. Daddy's Madison,
Daddy's Madison. Um, all right.
I gotta get back to the
podcast. Aniah okay. Alrighty.
Okay. What'd you talk about?
Um, I don't really know. This has just
been one of the stream of conscious days.
Um,
that's her whole podcast.
I talked about some lady with a basket
on her head trying to get water,
what she fought off a cobra.
I do remember that.
And I also talked about how big the
heads are of the people running for
president and our be concerned if
I was the head of security. Okay.
What else? That's all I
can remember. Oh, riveting.
Okay. All right, I'll see you. Hey Nanny.
Do you hear about Lady Gaga?
She had a meat dress.
All right,
let's get to some of the
questions here. Um, oh yeah. Yes.
I became obsessed with the uh,
that front lever and uh,
this guy has a six step thing on how to
do it cause I always wanted to be able
to do the human fucking flag.
You know,
that's just a great thing to be able
to do if you're not a gymnast because
people just expect you to be able to
do it. But if you just like a dad,
you got a couple of kids,
you know,
you fucking into roofing now that's a
physical job. Whatever you fucking build.
I don't know. It just be
something just funny to do that.
You could actually fucking do
that. Just weird people out. Um,
you know what that reminds me.
I wanted to do a bit on these
fucking crossfit people,
but I just feel like it's just too hacky
and every comic is going to have a bid
on it. So what, what's,
why do these crossfit people,
why do they have to like workout
in the gym and outside? Why is,
it's just so fucking, look at me.
We're working out. I work out too.
I work out my garage with
the fucking door closed.
It's the most narcissistic she gives
us. Even they're just like, dude,
fucking running down the street
with like a god damn fucking tire.
Buying them right.
Somebody show me a picture of a guy
doing that and retweeted it. Right?
Running down the street. Dragon a
tire. When he's just run up a hill,
you fucking moron.
You know?
Oh because tire ads more difficulty
when they'd run up the hill more times.
Increase your reps,
you stupid fuck
what?
What are you training for the standard
like I was fucking somewhere in Santa
Monica. These fucking jerk offs. It's
like 10 of them outside and they got,
you know when they got
the double fucking ropes,
that thing that they do that,
the only reason you really need to do
that is if you're fighting in the UFC.
They're the only people who
seem to need to have to do that.
Then everybody else wants to be in UFC
shape without having to actually have the
balls to get in the octagon.
Alright,
so fucking dumb and the,
or even when they're inside there's
like down the street. This one from me,
it's like this giant garage door and
they just have it open. Like look at us,
we're crossfitting. I talked to Neil
about it and she was saying like, yeah,
it was like all the rage to be on one
of those social media things and like,
oh I did, you know, filming yourself,
working out Hashtag crossfit.
It's just,
I dunno when I was,
when I was a kid,
if you wanted people to look at you,
you got into show business. Okay?
You became a male stripper. You
told jokes, you joined a band.
You know,
now these fucking assholes that they're
making a Bundt cake and they got like
fucking 80,000 fucking hits and
everybody's walking around with the same
arrogance that I have. It's,
it's not fair people I earned,
I earned my Eric, it's
um, I'm fucking with you.
You want to work outside.
You want to run down the street
with a fucking tire behind you.
You know what I mean?
I don't quite understand when to apply
the white privilege thing because I am
white and who's kitten who I am
one of the widest of all time.
You know what I mean?
I would say Hitler would not be
disappointed if I walked into his office,
but I think the red hair,
I think I might be out
okay.
Once chalk, white skin,
chuck [inaudible], all
this one is defective.
Alright.
If you want to,
uh,
help donate to this podcast without
having to do fucking anything except buy
something on amazon.com. Just
go to my website, Bill bird.com.
Okay. And there's an Amazon app
there. You Click on that thing.
It takes you right to Amazon,
doesn't cost you any extra money.
I just get credit for driving traffic
to their site and then they kicked me a
little doe ray, me, you didn't have
to do nothing. Nobody knows anything.
And you know, whatever. I go out and I
buy myself a ham sandwich. You can do it.
If you want to get dope,
that's fine.
If you're listening to this podcast and
you're like, I hate this thing, Gee,
I wish there was a podcast network that
had a bunch of other podcasts to choose
from,
I would say to go to all things,
comedy.com the podcast network started
by myself and Al Madrigal and a bunch of
other people.
We got Irish shift fear over there.
I should really go onto
the website right now.
We'll give you and give you a
bunch of fucking names, right?
Oh
yeah.
Things, comedy, right? Of all the
people I used to podcast with.
Um, all right. What do we have here? Oh,
we got Dean del Rey's let Debbie talk.
MMM.
Chris Sane and Anna David. I have
no control over my vagina. Ah,
how do you not fucking listen to that?
We got Steve some all,
uh,
we got Doug. Stan hope. Oh my fucking God.
Damn.
Eyes are going.
I can't even read half of these fucking
things are we should fear skeptic tank.
We got a
with Erin Foley sports
without balls. I mean we, we,
we get whatever the fuck you want. We got
it over there. All things. comedy.com.
All right, let's read some shit
here for this week, shall we?
50 minutes in Professor Dick Wad.
Hey Bill,
you hemoglobin laden a recite.
I had to look all of that up.
That's basically saying I have a lot
of red in me. Let her red blood cells.
I guess let's make this as short and
sweet as possible. Hey, all right.
Why don't you fucking a lecture me,
you cunt. Um, I go to a nice college.
I also manage a movie
theater in my town too. Ew.
Why would you say also and to,
I manage a movie theater in my town also,
or two to win also mean the same thing.
Right.
I also manage it movie theater in
my town to comma too. All right.
At School, I've got a film. He said, you
got to make it short and sweet at school.
I've got a,
I got a film studies class with one of
those pretentious fucking professors that
wears young kid close to come off
cooler than he really is. Yeah.
You know what that means? He's gonna
fuck a stone it. I love movies.
I've seen plenty of them. That's the
reason why I'm taking this class. Well,
that's great. Gravitate to
what you want, what you want.
Every time before we watch
a movie in this class,
the professor asked us to raise
our hands if we've seen it before.
I raised my hand almost every time that
I look around to see if anyone else is
raising their hand. They rarely are. Sure
I'm a nerd. I've seen the fucking movies.
Maybe if he didn't play the most standard
choices like Casablanca and shit,
I wouldn't raise my hand every
time. Look at that. You like movies,
you're doing your homework,
you taken a class on it,
you're gravitating towards what
you want. Very nice. All right.
So anyway,
I was just recently hired,
I was just recently hired on an employee.
Dude, you're killing me. I just
recently hired on as an employee.
You left out the ass at my theater.
Um,
who also happens to be a student
of my film studies per se.
Oh, you went by an employee.
So anyway, I just recently,
I was just recently hired by an employee
at my theater who also happens to be a
student of my film studies professor,
but in a different class
at a different school.
I think I conveyed what you were
trying to say that as a joke.
One day I asked the kid,
so does miss to so-and-so ever
talk shit about our class?
The kid looks me square in the eye
and says, yeah, actually he does.
Dr So and so says there's
this one kid in your,
your your all's class,
you mean y'alls class?
Who always raises his hand when
he asks if he's seen the movie,
but really he probably hasn't and then
he looks around the run to make sure
everyone is looking at him to
know he's seen the movie before.
That's hilarious.
This guy's getting insecure.
You're making your teacher insecures
tonight. He's got ah, Jesus.
That's probably why he's wearing
the young people's clothes.
He's talking shit about the other
class to make himself seem cool. Ah,
this guy's a fucking, this guy's a
bitch. I don't like this teacher.
He goes sell. There we go.
This guy talks shit about me.
It was other classes when all I'm doing
is generally raising my hand after being
asked if I've seen the movie or not.
In any other case,
I'd probably just confront him about this,
but I don't want to risk failing the
class or something petty like that.
Am I overthinking this? What should I
do here? I'd walked right up to the guy.
I just want, who gives a fuck
this fucking insecure can't,
he'll probably give you a better
grade cause what does need to be like?
Just walk right up to him.
But yeah. Listen man, uh,
this seems to be some confusion on your
part that you seem to be trying to work
out with the other class as to why I
raised my hand every time I happened to
love movies. I work at
a movie theater. Okay.
And I've seen all these movies and I look
around just to see if anybody else has
seen the movies because I love movies
and I want to talk to people about movies
if he don't want me to keep,
you know,
raising my hand stopped
doing this paint by numbers.
Basic horseshit movies
that you keep picking.
What are you going to have next
week? Days of thunder. Huh?
You're giving me shit.
You're going to come in.
He address like you
could go into a fucking,
yeah. What are the young kids listened
to? I used to just go see the weekend.
Is that the right thing?
Who's the other guy?
Who was the rapper who won all the
fucking grammys? Kendrick Lamar.
I know who they are. I don't,
I know a few of their songs.
I know the weekends CD
starts off going right.
Wait,
you could actually play the
beginning of the weekend.
I think red next do it as much as they
probably don't like his skin color.
They probably play that when
they're out duck hunting
to try to get the young ducks. You
know, we're into all this fucking,
I'm fucking with you.
I am a fan of the weekend.
That wasn't [inaudible] was hired by
that last joke guy. Let Him Apollo.
All right. Um, a Billy calorie count.
Thoughts on Melissa McCarthy
Getting Flack for losing weight?
Uh, all right, my first thought, I'm
Melissa McCarthy. I did a movie with her,
a number a years ago was called the heat
directed by Paul Feig starting Melissa
McCarthy, Sandra Bullock. And that's
where I first met, uh, Michael Rappaport,
you know,
um,
dropping names all over the place and she
is truly one of the most funny fucking
hilarious human beings I have ever
met and she's an absolute sweetheart.
Um, so anyways, I didn't
realize people were given.
Why would you give somebody flack for
losing weight? Aren't you supposed to say,
hey, great job, good for you. You know.
Anyway said people are saying she's
doing it because of Hollywood pressures
and so fucking dumb. All right. I think
people are just add that isn't it?
That's not what it is. It's, it's, it's,
it's the same townie mentality when
you're, you're finally deciding that,
you know, wearing your football jacket
and continuing to drink in the local bar,
you want more out of life and then all a
smart now like all of them, they don't
want to see her get her shit together.
You know, misery loves
fucking company. You know,
they would stay here and be out of
shape. Good. Far fucking assholes.
What kind of an asshole? When somebody
makes a positive move in their life,
tries to make it negative. Well me,
I'm a comedian. I do that all the time.
But besides people like me anyways,
these people who always say you should
be comfortable in your own body,
no matter what you look like,
completely ignore basic information like
clogged arteries and such. Absolutely.
Maybe Melissa McCarthy doesn't want to
die of a heart attack because she wants
to meet her grandchildren's one day I
lost 30 pounds since listening to fat
shame everyone. I honestly didn't know
I was getting fat. I was never fat ever.
But then three years at an office,
job and college,
I'm 24 I put on the gross 30.
I recently lost. Yeah, dude,
it's 24 man.
You were headed towards being,
you were going to die if you are 30
pounds overweight at 24 that is not a good
thing. So congratulations.
Uh, anyways, he said,
I feel a thousand times better.
I never looked fat because I'm
a tall guy and I carry it well.
So I never heard anything from anyone.
I did it on my own for myself.
These fat defenders are ignorantly
judging and assuming thoughts on this.
Also when the fuck did we
get to see your gym video?
I want to see your pasty legs dangling
from a pullup bar like meat hanging in a
locker. Ah, you fucking cuts. Um, no.
This is the thing about this business.
Uh,
the only pressure that is
as far as I'm concerned,
the only pressure in this
business is what you x.
You as an individual choose to accept.
All right?
And everybody does it to a certain point
when you first get into entertainment
because you don't know
what the fuck you're doing.
You come into this business with
your hat in hand, you're like,
I'll sweep the floors, I'll do whatever
you want. Just give me stage time. I'll,
I'll drive to another state to do five
minutes for no money for $5 gas money.
We all do that shit.
Okay.
Um,
but at some point you then have to put
a value on what the fuck it is you're
doing, right? And then
you start getting paid.
Then what happens is you're like
going, fuck. You know, and you know,
you get in this business,
it takes a while to get going.
And everybody starts creeping into 30
so you start freaking out going, oh,
what is, what does the industry
casting? What are they looking at?
What is the blah, blah, Blah
and all that type of shit. Okay.
Now a lot of people do not ever get past
that because they don't put a value on
their talent.
And I'm not even talking monetarily.
This is just my own belief system.
You have to believe that you have
something to say that you know
you can't be married to the results.
You just got to do that zen thing.
Like I'm talking about this shit,
I'm doing this and like take me all right,
I came in in the business or write
a fucking redheaded con male,
you know? So from day one, there's
not going to be a lot of roles for me.
There's not a lot of redheaded male
leads and shit. You know, I'm the front,
right? That's the deal.
That's how it works.
The redhead and mail is not the fucking
cool guy. So to make matters worse,
I started losing my fucking
hair and I was like, oh fuck,
now what do I go out and get plugs
in? All that shit. And just one day,
you know, Neil is just, just bust your
fucking head down. And I was just like,
I just came to this epiphany
of just like, yeah, Bill,
why are you walking around like you
lose your fucking hair is a big deal.
Does that mean you're not funny anymore?
Does that mean you know,
what were you going to be the next Brad
Pitt if you kept your fucking hair right?
And then I just said, yeah, fuck it.
So then I did it and this and I ever
since I had the philosophy of basically
this is what I look like
and this is what I do.
If you want to book me, thank
you. If you don't, I understand.
The second I went into that mindset,
I never fucking stressed again.
So I really think that all that whole,
you know,
the pressures of fucking Hollywood is,
I understand that when you're young,
but as you're getting
older you have to fucking,
it really has nothing to
do with Hollywood. I also,
I think it has more to do with, you know,
why you got into this business, you know,
the self-loathing, you know,
and, and not liking yourself.
I think, and I have to tell you, uh,
this past weekend I watched
[inaudible] special and um,
it was so fucking great.
And I was sitting there with
my wife and I was saying like,
what I loved. She went out there and
it just was, she was fucking original.
All of us stuff was just, it was just
fucking, it was just a great set.
It was worthy like this,
it really was a standup special.
And you know, she's, she
went out there, you know,
and everybody's making a big
fucking deal that it like,
because she was pregnant that she did it.
Oh my God,
they'll all these fucking questions and
I understand why they did that because
no one's ever done that.
But there should be more questions
about how great the material was.
But I was saying to my wife when I
was watching this, I go, you see this?
She had a special to do and she didn't
give a fuck that she was pregnant and she
just walked out and then she owned it.
And now what she's done is she's
established herself that now she can just
basically do whatever the fuck she wants.
She wants to have another kid.
She can literally go on
tour while pregnant because
she's established that this
is who I am. This is what
I'm doing. I'm married,
I'm starting to fucking family
and I'm right and kill the jokes.
This is what I'm doing now.
All these fucking feminist who
sit there going alien again.
Hollywood won't let you be pregnant.
I would argue you are giving
them way too much fucking power.
Way Too much power.
Just go out.
If every fucking woman out here just
started getting pregnant because they
wanted to and continue to go on auditions,
the whole fucking business,
what adjust you make it adjust to you
rather than the other fucking way around.
And, um, if you haven't seen
her special, you know, you know,
a lot of the hype on it is the fact
that she did it seven months pregnant,
but I'm telling you, just as a
someone who still have, you know,
as long as I've been doing this, a huge
fan of standup comedy, you know, um,
yeah,
it's, the jokes are fucking killer.
The subject matter, all of it.
It was just like, you know, God knows
this a Zillion fucking specials out there,
but you know, every once in a while,
you know, someone comes out like with,
with that, that was, that was one of the
best ones I've seen in a while. So, um,
okay.
I guess I would tie all of that
back end to that. It's like,
I would say that she's losing
weight. Yeah. She's married,
she's got kids and know who the
fuck doesn't want to lose weight.
I'm trying to lose weight. No one
wants to walk around being overweight.
It's not fun. You're life is
easier. And people who, uh,
give a shit about that. I
would just say, you know,
I feel bad for them because I know
they don't want to be out of shape too.
You know? I mean, did used to
being proud to be out of shape.
That's like being proud to be like a
fucking alcoholic, you know, you know,
you got issues.
You,
your fucking heart isn't fucking
excited that you're overweight.
Like that's right. That's
right. You don't, you know,
every pound of fat is five
miles of capillaries. You know,
you get 20 pounds overweight,
you're heart's got to fucking go and
extra hundred miles every fucking beat.
You not stupid. It's not a, it's
not a good thing to be doing.
So congratulations to
her. Um, and you know,
I'm struggling right now to lose fucking
wait. Oh, I'll tell you it's easy.
It's not easy. All Billy blue's
bag. Alright. Uh, Christian girls,
sexual boundaries. Hey, Billy Bob Berman.
I listened to all your specials multiple
times and really loved the advice
segments you do on your podcast.
I'm back home for the summer from my
first year of college and I'm hooking up
with this six to 10. Chris, what?
Oh six out of 10 Christian girl the
last couple of months of school.
I barely even just retained any of that
cause I was hoping everything that I
said came off as positive and
that last thing. Um, anyway,
let me reread this. I've listened to all
your sanity back for the summer. Okay.
I'm hooking up with this group,
this six out of 10 Christian girl
the last couple months of school.
The encounter is basically consisted
of me aggressively finger play,
live g easy finger blasting her
to quench her sexual deviancy.
Oh, I love how you're just fucking
innocent in all this and her giving my,
Oh, okay. Okay. Oh this is a woman, right?
This in a hurricane or given my carpet.
A midnight snack.
What? Oh No, this is a guy.
Why are you saying your carpet?
Give him my carpet.
A midnight snack while jerking me off.
You lost me in that one.
What is your carpet?
Your pubes.
What does this snack,
because you come on yourself.
I don't even know what's
going on here or anyway,
she's a devout Christian so she won't
get involved with oral sex or anything
further. Uh, the thing is her
idea of boundaries are pretty,
uh, are more fuss. I don't
know what that means. No,
you fucking asshole. Now I got to look.
You know what? Actually keep doing this.
Maybe I'll get smart one day.
Amorphous,
amorphous without a clear,
defined shape or form.
How did I never hear that?
My whole fucking life?
There's so many fucking words in English
language and then they always say they
buy, we use like 19 of them. Four
of them are curse words. All right?
She's begged me to pleasure her
with the hilt of my screwdriver.
Do to you from another century. What
the fuck is a hilt? Is that the handle?
Don't know why I even had one at college
and jerk me off onto her face when we
took a late night sleep
over shower together.
Okay.
Yeah, but that's not really a
facial. When the water's right there.
You know what it mate, that's like,
you know, you're going to run out.
You're going to walk on some hot rocks
and you just fucking do a running leap
and touch one for half a second. You
keep going, right? She's also into being,
it's like picking up dog shit with the
little fucking plastic bag around your
hand. You know, you're still touching
dog shit, but you feel the warmth of it.
But you know there's a boundary there.
Uh,
she's also into being
choked and tied up to her.
Jesus fucking Christ
up during dry humping.
Apparently that stuff's still
Christian enough for her.
I've had sex a few times before the cute.
Why are you judging this girl so harshly?
All right. This is this religion thing.
This is where she's at.
Just fucking relaxed.
It seems like you having a hell of a time.
He goes,
I had sex a few times before this girl
and know that even protected fucking is
infinitely more pleasurable than outsource
masturbation. My question to you is,
do you think she'll ever
realize how ridiculous it is
to take a load on her face
but not accept Kinda Linkous
will she ever want premarital sex? I
know I should go to a gym, loses girl,
gets some sleep,
can take advantage of the pussy coliseum.
That is my universe
camp university campus.
But I'm lazy and want to
fuck the low hanging fruit.
What can I do to convince her that
college sex is natural, wholesome.
It would make her feel incredible.
Thanks so much and go fuck yourself.
I would say you should let
this girl go because a,
you don't have any feelings for you using
as or you're using a Reza fucking blow
up doll. It just say, you know, I know
I should go meet some other people,
but this girl's in easy
fucking sex hook up. Um,
I dunno. I mean meantime, is
she getting feelings for you?
Because if he just sitting there hanging
around waiting to be able to fuck her
so then you can then leave. Um, you're
already saying she's a six out of 10.
That's, that doesn't sound like you
have feelings for us. So I'd let her go.
I'd let it go and I'd find some girl,
they just,
it just let them know you're young,
so I'm not judging you here.
Once you got to do early on, and this
is what nobody ever tells young men,
it's just just out of the gate.
Tell women what the deal is.
All right cause believe it or not,
they can have fun. We eat, they don't
flip out when you just say, yeah I,
there's no way I'm going to marry you.
You know,
if you say it right from the beginning,
the second you meet them, right,
if you're not feeling anything
but you're just attracted to them,
just tell them that and just
fucking let them, you know,
work that out.
And maybe they were in the same place
you are and they just want to fuck and
they don't want to have a relationship.
But if you get into that type of a
situation, you got to make sure that you,
you got to have like,
you know,
you fuck and then you don't call each
other or talk or do anything else.
You do not hang out.
And there's gotta be at least 10
days between the fucking hookups or,
or somebody starts failing something
and then it's a fucking mess.
Or they get jealous. Cause you
with somebody else. So whatever.
You know what I mean? And this is
what you fucking say from day one.
You tell him that. All right,
this steel, we'll get to hook up.
Anything you ever wanted to fucking do,
you can do with me.
You're not going to get judged.
You know,
worry about getting judged
because it is what it is. Right?
And then that's it.
We don't call each other.
This is what we just fucking
use each other for this.
Anytime you feel an Organi,
if you're not in a fucking relationship,
I don't give a shit if your date
other people believe it or not.
If you come out of the
gate with that Shit,
you would be surprised how many
women are also looking for that.
It's a great fuck fuck buddy is.
It's the greatest thing ever.
Greatest fucking thing ever. It's
like having fucking, I don't know,
free tickets to Disney land.
You get to ride all the fucking rides.
You know you got VIP parking. It's, it's
like ordering a pizza. It's tremendous.
And you know what? Women also order
a pizza, if you know what I mean.
So have fun with that. But let
this girl go, man. All right.
First Time flying at 30 years of age.
Hey there Billy,
the ginger bats.
Just want to say I've been a huge fan
for over 10 years and I've loved every
special you had.
Well thank you very much.
I'm 30 I've never been on a plane and
heights kind of freaked me out to top it
off. My flight is on nine 11 and
makes two stops in between here,
Connecticut in Chicago.
I'm going there for my job and I'd really
hate to miss out on the opportunity.
Basically,
I'm just looking for advice and how to
not freak out and look like a fucking
idiot on the plane. Seeing as how
you've had so much experience flying,
I'd figured you'd be a good person to
talk to. Thanks and go fuck yourself. Um,
yeah, it's no big deal. It's
completely safe and uh, you know,
you're going to be fine. This is the
deal. You're going to go up there, right?
This is what you do. Get on the plane
and then just say to the person,
next g again, believe it or not, this
is the first time I've ever flown,
hopefully not next to a do. If they've
seem open, just tell him that. All right,
but do believe me?
You're not going to,
if you ever just stomped on the gas when
you've been driving a car and you just
get back in your seat,
it's just sort of like that and then
you fucking up in the air and it's the
coolest thing ever.
It's fucking great.
And you're going to go from fucking
Connecticut to Chicago in like fucking two
seconds. You know, he got two stops
there. Okay, well that's cool. Be Fun.
Well then you'll be a veteran by the end
of it and yeah, welcome to the, uh, the,
the fucking 21st century.
You're going to be fine. Um,
what I would say is, you know, just, uh,
make sure you eat well before
you go to the airport. You know,
maybe bring some food to go
onto the plane, you know,
because the food and the plane sucks,
it's fucking overpriced and that
type of thing. And uh, you know,
that's the only thing I would say.
Other than that,
you have nothing to worry about it.
It's going to be great.
Get a fucking window seat too if
you can. That's the best, you know,
first time you fly, get to look down. Um,
it's actually pretty incredible to be
doing that at 30 years of age because you
can actually take it in.
You know,
first time I flew I was so young that
I don't ever have that. Like, oh,
this is what it looks like from the
fucking hair. Um, you'll be fine.
All Right William,
I've been dating my girls.
This is the last one and then I got it.
I got to get off my day here of doing
absolutely nothing. William William,
I've been dating my girl for a few years
now and everything started out great.
However,
over the course of the past few months,
I've noticed a sudden change in her
behavior and was wondering if you'd dealt
with anything like this before.
Yeah.
She's either using drugs or fucking
someone else. Um, or she's depressed.
I'm fucking with you. Let me
read the rest of this. Basically,
when we hang out lately, she just won't
stop asking questions. She may ask,
what are you listening to? I might say
the bill burr podcasts. Then she will ask,
why? I don't know, because
I enjoy it. He says,
then she will follow it up with,
why don't you listen to the
radio or another podcast
and down the rabbit hole it
goes, oh, I don't like this
person already. The thing is,
these questions are
nonstop and so subjective.
It got to the point where I straight up
asked her if she was trolling me and she
denied it. Everything else in
the relationship is going well,
so I'm not sure what to do.
I've talked to her and told her
she asked too many questions.
She then turns around on me and says,
I never want to talk to her any.
Oh,
she turns it,
turns it around on me and says that
I never want to talk to her anymore.
That's not talking. It's just asking
a bunch of fucking question. She'll,
what should I do? Break up with her. Just
answer the questions. What would you do,
Bill? Why is your name bill anyways? Why
not Dave Hoff? Why isn't it Dave? Bill,
why aren't you answering me a bill?
Don't want to talk anymore.
Why is the podcast and hour anyways,
why not an hour? 10 or 50 minutes.
How bill? Yeah. All right
dude. I just walked in your
shoes there. Yeah. Uh, yeah.
I would break up with her.
I'd break up with him.
Um, I give maybe a, but
if you really liked her,
I gave her one last chance to
just be like, just tell it.
You're driving me fucking insane.
And um,
yeah, it just, you driving
me fucking insane. I like
everything about you, but that,
and if my life with you is going to
be that, I'm going to leave. Okay.
Um, but I gotta be honest with dude,
I don't know how people change.
Changing yourself.
Who the fuck you are is really difficult,
so hopefully it'll work out with you.
So that's, that's what I would do.
I would just say, listen,
I like everything,
but that everything about
you is great except for that.
But that is so fucking horrific.
This is going to walk out that
fucking door if you don't cut it up.
That's it. That's it. If I
could redo my whole dating life,
it would have been fucking communicating.
Okay.
Instead of just being like, Woo. And
then gone. I'll getting shit faced.
What was wrong with you guys
today? Nothing. I'm sorry.
And then you don't fucking working
out. Hey, work it out. Okay. All right.
That's the podcast for this week. Go fuck
yourselves. I'll check in on Thursday.
Uh, thank you to everybody
who's been listening to the
podcast and I'm obviously,
I am beyond excited to do
this tour. Um, starting,
uh Oh my God, the 31st.
No, it starts the 30th.
The Fuck Outta here.
Oh,
my show wasn't until the 31st
well, what are, you know,
I'll have an extra day there in Ireland.
All right, here it is. The case.
You listening? Dublin, Ireland,
Belfast, then Galway, then Bristol,
UK, Manchester, UK.
I like you probably should say that
date's July 31st I'm in Dublin,
August 1st I'm in Belfast August 2nd.
Gallway.
Then I go over to, uh, England.
I'm in Bristol on the third and
on the fourth. I'm in Manchester.
You know what's in between Bristol and
Manchester? John Bonham's grave site.
If I have time,
I'm going to pay my respects.
I'm not going to do a fucking
Selfie, like a Douche. Uh,
just going to pay my respects if
I have the time. Um, August 6th,
fifth and sixth, I'm in
London, England. August 7th.
I'm in Amsterdam. August 8th. I'm in,
I'm in Edinburgh for two shoes.
August 9th.
I'm in Edinburgh.
Um,
for two more shows the
fuck doing all right there.
August 11th. Now wait a minute.
Yeah, I did say Amsterdam,
right on August 7th, August
11th, I'm in Cologne,
Germany, and then August
12th I'm in Antwerp, Belgium.
And then August 27th, I'm in Reno, Nevada,
back in the USA. All right, everybody,
thank you for listening and thank you to
everybody overseas has been dot buying
tickets. I can't wait to come over there
and, uh, make you laugh. All right.
Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you on Thursday.