Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
July 11th, 2012 how are
ya? What's going on?
Oh Jesus. Um, I got a ton
of Shit to do tomorrow,
dude.
You fucking busy.
Go fuck yourselves.
I got to go to the airport.
So I'm doing this Sunday night,
you know, doing all the pre
airport stuff. Wash the dishes,
wash my fucking socks and underwear is,
I'm ready to go. You know, I
had a great fucking weekend.
I didn't want to go on the road.
You know,
you think I want to get on another
fucking tweety bird and go fly to some
godforsaken strip mall in the
middle of fucking nowhere,
which is basically the middle of nowhere
to me at this point is anywhere that is
not near my house. You know,
big come to Chicago. What?
In the middle of fucking
nowhere. I get a bus. Well,
he's second largest states in the union,
but union is that serve the North
American, the fuck away from me here.
An agent if free mason.
Is it an amazing how you can't talk?
You try to adjust yourself. He
just, yeah, that all persons Ah, ah,
you know, trying to fucking readjust
your man tits. No Man sits here buddy.
I've been working out.
I work out.
Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle.
We'll do, um, I've been, uh,
yeah,
I um, let, let's, let's, let's,
let's bring it down a little bit.
Let's bring the tone down a little bit.
Let's just ease it on in, you know,
you sitting there,
right?
Coming down from the sugar rush from
that fucking Curley's shouldn't Eaton uh,
they had bear claw, right? Well,
what else did you have a what?
Do you have the thing at the airport? What
do they got there? The big fucking, uh,
you know, we look like, it looks
like a diabetic. Took a shit.
What do they call a Cinnabon?
A lot of people don't know
that. That's, that's where they,
that's where they get their dough from.
As a,
when a real fat person takes
a shit, they, that's when you,
that's when you know you have to lose
weight is when you just shit a Cinnabon
and you didn't,
you knew you didn't eat one.
It's not like it went straight
to your system. Okay. It's,
that is just an amalgam of that is the
waste of what you ate that day. You know,
something. I is it my goal to
lose every female on this podcast,
any fee remote female listener.
It's almost like this subconscious
self self sabotage. Two minutes,
40 seconds into this fucking thing.
And you know,
I got to put that visual out there.
You know,
I probably lost not only all of the women,
I lost some guys who were like
in touch with their feelings.
Anybody's a remotely a human
being. So now, now it's just a, now
it's just us. It's just a sociopath's.
Let's just let them slowly co,
you know, file out of the room.
I thought it was going to be something
different. I did too. I like sweets.
I don't shit set up month.
Sorry. I said the f word.
Um, my fucking dog, Cleo,
I want your life, you know,
what is your biggest decision?
What room am I going to lay down and go
down and fucking go to sleep? Sleeping.
Is that what it is? You've got a
fucking spider web on my, uh, uh,
the remanence of a spider web.
I can't figure out I'll all the spiders
in my house like me or they don't like
me,
you know,
cause I kind of let them be when it
gets a little ridiculous, you know,
the size of the spider webs. Cause I
figured that they're here for a reason.
That must mean I have other bugs
here and they're going to kill him.
So like I look at them like they're
my like insect police squad,
you know, and I'm the rich guy
is, isn't that what the uh, uh,
what do you call them? The
fucking policemen? ARF.
Isn't that why they initially came about
was to protect the rich people's stuff
just in case everybody
working farm was like, hey ya,
how much does that vase worth? Their
fucking, what's a rich guy's name?
Hg fucking cunt face. They help
that we had those names back then.
Not The cunt face part, but they always
had the initials. Right. You know,
Hg Rockefeller, Jd Rockefeller, you know
JP Morgan, JP, it ain't fair man.
I don't care if with kitchen
put my shooter got out. Right.
And they all talk like Edward G.
Robinson for some reason,
30 years before even fucking was famous.
C'Mon pill,
get your shit together. Um, I
have a sugar rush right now.
I had fucking spaghetti again.
Bet At four times his fucking week.
That's what happens when all your recipes
that you got from your parents or for
like 10 people, you know, and it's
just you and your God damn dog.
Whatever you make and you know,
you make sketti you're going to
eat and that for fucking two weeks,
I got fucking octopus coming
out my fucking nose here. Um,
that was the soprano's version
of a Tony Montana case.
You were wondering that knee is out
of town again this week. You know,
I think she's slowly breaking up
with me via vacations, you know,
just sort of easing me into what it's
going to be like when she's not here.
And I got to tell you I'm doing fine.
You know, I can't fucking do the laundry.
I can't make spaghetti 10 times in a week.
I don't need you.
Yeah. Jesus. What'd you do
with your weekend bill? Well,
I had too much to drink Friday night
and I'm back on the wagon, you know,
back on the fucking wagon.
I don't think this is an old Jimmy,
that old joke where they say,
uh, I'm not an alcoholic.
I just drink like one a that,
that's me. You know what I mean?
I'm one of those guys,
if I'm going to have a pizza,
I'm going to eat the whole fucking thing.
All right,
let's save some for later and maybe having
it for breakfast and then talk about
sports on ESPN.
All right.
And they have a show called cold
pizza with skip Bayless was, uh,
always losing his shit about something.
Do you guys buy,
do you guys buy that guy?
Do by his outrage?
Um,
you know what I mean?
I think his outrage is about as
believable is ice cubes, anger.
Ice Cube has had the exact same scowl on
his face from Nwa all the way to these
cores like commercials.
It is the exact,
he is the exact same look on his face
when he was talking about the man as he
does when beer bottles take
over his studio. You know,
maybe he's just straight across the board.
Angry. God knows I can relate to that,
but there's certain people after
a while you gotta be like, Dude,
you got to have another emotion in there,
don't you skip Bayless is another guy.
I don't give a fuck if you said,
hey, you need air to breathe.
He would somehow argue the other side,
put his eyebrows up near his fucking
game show host hair that he has.
You know, is that his hair?
It's gotta be his hair.
Either that or he went to like, he got
a, do they make weaves for white guys?
You know,
if they made weaves a white guys,
everybody would want skip Bayless is here.
I get it. If it came in some sort of a,
some sort of red, I'd get
one. I get one in a second.
I'd be hot at some of the, you know,
that's why I never get a fucking toupee,
you know, just sitting there with
your full head of fucking here,
just slapped on there like a shingle
scalps sweating underneath it.
You know, what the fuck
am I do with, you know,
and then one at night I come home and
I take it off and I just look at me,
just look at the landing strip on top of
my head, right where, where, you know,
the rest of my face got sun and then this,
I got this blind.
You know what I would, I would
look like the globe, you know,
on top of my head would be
like the North Pole, you know,
my chest would be the south pole and
then my face would be the tropics.
And that basically it, I mean that's
basically the climates, you know,
my nose would be some sort of mountain
range coming down from fucking Alaska.
Why do you guys listen to
this stupid podcasts? Um,
anyway, so, oh, I didn't tell
you this. I got to fucking,
I gotta I gotta I bought one of those,
those giant eggs
to fucking Bobby Q.
I bought one the ugliest fucking sin,
but they are the shit.
This is not an advertising.
This is a Freebie. Alright.
People over at the big green egg
in case you sell half of one, um,
I love the goddamn thing.
It looks like an unripe avocado.
It's one of the ugliest things
you've ever seen in your life. Okay.
But they got a couple of gaskets.
They got a seal here.
It's a seal here and you
run it up the alley. Um, oh,
I made some burgers and dogs.
That's what I did first.
And then there was this barbecue place
that was going out of business or
relocating. I Dunno what was happening,
but all I know was all their shit was,
was half off. So I went down there and
I got the thing for fucking ribs, right?
Not Baby Becky to the fucking,
the good ones, you know,
you just lay the fuck are
right over there. Okay. Doing
ribs isn't even that hard.
They'll just fucking Douche you see
on, uh, on, on the food channel,
talking about all the shit that they do
when they sit sitting there with their
little fucking based or hey,
well what do you do?
You slather it with some
shit that this tastes good.
You stick it in the fucking thing
and then you come back four hours later
and he'd go, oh, would you look at debt?
Oh, which you look at debt
falling right off the boat, right?
And then they eat it and then they
always tell you it's good. Well,
of course you're going to say that
it's your fucking cooking show.
Have you ever seen on a cooking show?
A guy took a bite and was like, ah,
God damn it, I overcooked it, dried that
shit out. Well, you know, you win some,
you lose some,
come on back next week folks,
maybe I won't cook the shit out of
this salmon. They never say that.
They always eat you. You know, it's like,
and they always eat it too when they're
like running out of time. So before they,
they, he'd take half a bite
and they go, ah, ah, ah,
I wish you could take, you
didn't even fucking show it.
You know what that's like?
That's in, in uh, in
the acting profession.
I learned this one, I did glee. That's
called playing the end of the scene.
Okay.
You know what I mean? Like if you,
you know, if you read like you,
you're all seen, you know, you
have to audition for, right?
And it's basically your,
your character walks
into a rental car place.
She's supposed to have a fucking
rental car. They don't have it.
And then you flip out and you yell,
right?
And in the end there's a big
fucking yelling bullshit, right?
And the inexperienced actor comes in
already fucking amped up. And it's like,
why you already amped up.
You'll walk in and expect in
the fucking car to be there.
You wouldn't already be mad.
You're playing the end of the scene.
That's what those cons
do on the food network,
because they're running out of time.
Oh fucking Susie mother and hips there,
whatever the fuck her name is,
who I said I'd like to bang her before
she highlighted her hair and did the
whole fucking j Lo thing was she
toned down her fucking Brunette Ish.
Look on her face. You know what I
mean? Uh, what's her name? Rachel Ray.
Rachel Ray did the exact same
make over that fucking j.
Lo did both of were uh,
were,
were Brunette Brown eyes,
big bushy fucking eyebrows.
They did the same goddamn thing. They
fucking, they thin that shit out.
They throw with a little, throw a
little sun in their hair. All right?
Then all of a sudden, Oh wow, look,
you jumped off the page. You know,
you don't want to do an
over correction though.
You don't want to over correct Brunette.
If you over correct Brunette,
you go right past blonde and into red
head and then that's a slippery slope into
albino and you're not getting,
no one's going to see your fucking
movie or watch you make some French dip.
All right. So I'm not making
fun of the profession that,
that's a very delicate process to take
someone who has brown too much brown,
you know, and they got to lighten
them up and the eyebrow hair area.
But what I always think because I'm a
fucking pervert is it's like all right.
Yeah,
you fucking, you know, you dialed in the
sun up top. What happened down bottom.
You know what I mean? Cause if your
eyebrows and that fucking bushy,
what in God's name is going down,
they're going on down there
and you and the slacks area.
Did you get that highlight? Is
that going to match? You know,
am I going to see who you really are when
you're draws? Hit the floor sweetheart.
Oh, Jesus Christ. Um,
well that was a fun first fucking
15 minutes, wasn't it? How? Oh Hey,
guess who's advertising this?
This, this week? Guess who's back?
It's our old friends at pro flowers.
Remember them way back on Mother's Day?
Mema them I on Valentine's Day. Well
now they're hitting us up every month.
They want you to buy flowers every month.
And I know what you're thinking.
What the fuck would I do that for?
I don't know, but it's up to me is
the pitch man that I have to some,
they have to somehow
come up with an angle.
I got to come up with an angle here.
This is what you gotta do. Okay.
And I actually do this. Okay. So this is
coming from my heart, not from the wallet.
All right. This isn't the
magic bullet here. This is
coming straight up. All right?
Didn't make a right turn down on my ass,
right in my wallet. It didn't. Okay.
Um,
every once in a while.
Okay.
Every once in awhile I'll wait.
Cleo, shifting, shifting Ed,
she stretching and then that's it.
She didn't get up.
Um, you look like a little pig.
You know that little wild boar,
Cleo,
no size on you.
Do you do squats when I'm not looking?
Is that what you're so tired from all the
time? Anyways, portfolio is everybody.
It's July 4th. You could've given
some to Uncle Sam last week,
but it's too late for that now.
Uh,
is that the original goatee by the way?
Uncle Sam.
Uncle Sam looks like an old retired
like NBA player from the 70s,
but somehow he's white.
By then,
by then Whitey was, was getting pushed out
of the League, wasn't he? Um, all right,
let's get back to the advertising here.
Uh, proflowers. Proflowers it's July,
it's July. You know what?
This is what you got it.
You were in a relationship every
once in a while, just out of nowhere.
You've got to give him some
flowers, you know? Okay. You know,
is it ever a wrong time to
give your mother some flowers?
Are you going to go visit them?
Do you have a mother in law
who just looks at you? Like,
why did you marry my daughter?
You know,
give her some flowers. Maybe
she'll lighten up. Either way.
If you get a big enough arrangement,
you have to look at his stupid
face across the team. Uh,
the table when you sit down to eat.
You know, if you don't like somebody,
what better way to block this stupid
face than to go out and get a bunch
ofFlowers@proflowers.com.
Just click on the microphone
in the upper right hand corner.
You'd type in the Password Berbee
you U R and they'll get the vase,
they'll stick him in the water and
they'll send it to that person.
Love them or not send them flowers.
And that's the end.
And the dismount. Oh, speaking
and the dismount. You know,
I was telling you that I was starting to
put on weight again. Oh, Billy fat again.
You know, Billy McPhatter again. Um,
and I decided that I was going to halt
that and I was going to turn this bus
around
and tried to get myself back in shape.
And uh, I've been doing
all, all bodyweight stuff,
climbing the rope. I'm doing the pull
up some during the day. I'm doing,
uh, what else you got there?
Whatever. I don't do chin ups though.
Yeah.
Chin ups or are for girls. Pull
ups are for men. All right.
In fact,
I remember when,
when Demi Moore played that chick
who got her head buzz down Gi Jane,
right? She wasn't doing shit up. She was
doing pull ups cause she was a marine.
Right. I think that wasn't
the message of that movie.
What was the message of that movie?
Other than men are horrific.
What is the guy version of
that movie? Like, like hot dog.
And when those,
those tits and ass movies they used
to make when you first got cable,
but ski bunnies in the same premise
and now they're on the beach and they'd
always be chicks like just taking
their tops off. Like that happens,
you know, maybe it happens on
the French Riviera, I dunno.
But then they got hairy armpits. This
is always something to balance it out.
People, it's the ying and
the Yang, you know? Um,
I just completely forgot
what I was talking about. I
was talking about pullups.
That's right. So, so I
don't know if you guys,
Melissa,
how long have you listened to podcasts?
I F I fucked up my abdomen
on the right side. Uh, about
five years ago,
I was at a Pittsburgh pirates game.
I was one of the field and I was there
and I was drunk as always, alcohol,
always playing a role. And I
was drunk. I was drunk, Bill.
Um,
and I was with Paul Versey who said,
yeah, I fucking called.
Yeah, look at the bridge.
I said, it ice when they
make this ballpark. I said,
you know what they're gonna do.
They're gonna have it where you
could see the bridge from the, from,
from home plate. Looking right
out there it is. I call it,
you're not taking this one away from
me. You're not taking, I called it. Oh,
look at the bridge.
Um,
by the lightweight,
I love when you
guys send me tweets or twitters or
whatever the fuck you call up when, uh,
whenever Robinson can know does
something and you make fun of mercy.
That always makes me laugh.
Like Quinoa had a double Versie called it.
He called, he called it, I'll Paul Versey.
Do you want to be the guy who calls
it? Well, all you need is my dude.
I called it system number
one fucking call everything.
Think about it.
If you call everything,
eventually something that
you said will happen, Dan,
what you do is you yell about it,
you continue to yell about it hopefully
until everybody forgets everything else
that you called.
That did not happen.
Yeah.
You know it is at this point,
the fact that virgin, he
still talks about his call,
that Robinson Cano was
going to be a hall of fame.
He watched him like fucking three weeks
and said this guy's going to be a hall
of famer evidently. Okay.
Which is absolutely asinine.
Okay. Unless you like Ted Williams,
unless you're really a guy in baseball,
you can, you can look at those things.
All right. Versus one of those guys.
He wants to be the guy who said it first.
So he just says shit first. You know,
like if he was on the prices right,
there's no way he would pass
the first showcase. He wouldn't,
he would bid on it cause he wouldn't want
that other person to bid before he did.
That's what he would do. Did that
make any sense? I don't give a shit.
MMM.
So anyways, I've been working out this,
what the fuck I'm trying to talk about.
So this is how I fucked up my
app abdomen. All right. I was um,
I was at the, what, $10 with
this other comic Doug's in.
Yay. I was with Paul Versey
don't,
I don't what I said.
Um,
and myself and I think Doug's brother,
right?
We were all having a good time
drinking some beers, right?
We're all talking shit is old guys do.
And next thing you know,
I'm trying to show them that I
can go into the pike position.
Hammered.
All right?
So I put my fucking hand on one
sheet and then on what another seat,
lift myself up and then I bring my legs
straight out in front of me like I had
been doing, but I'm old. I didn't stretch.
I don't know what happened. Right?
And then later on the night, I
remember being drunk. It's somebody,
we were skipping rope on a sidewalk and
it had like a 45 degree fucking angle
across from this place where a
bunch of drunks were getting food.
I feel the life of me. I don't know
where we got the fucking jump rope.
I don't know where we got it.
I think somebody there had it from the
gym and then that's what it became.
That's probably when it became cars.
I actually fucking went into the
pipe position so then they will,
I could fucking skip rope.
Typical guy. Shit. All right.
And I know this bugs the ladies,
but you know something.
That's why there's air conditioning.
Okay. That's why, because of that shit,
because that's how we're geared.
I can do this while I can do this,
while I can do that fucking better.
Right. And next thing you know,
you got wall to wall carpeting.
All right,
so shut your face and make me a sandwich.
Um,
anyways, so the next morning I
wake up and I don't, it feels,
it felt like somebody took
some sort of medieval,
like if that Freddy Kruger glove dipped
it in fire and then fucking raped right
down the right side of me.
So for years I've been babying it.
Finally at one time I went and I got,
I got a Roth I believe,
which is a really deep fucking massage.
It was really weird.
It was a the only person I found,
although I was kidding who the first
person I found, I just clicked on that.
Okay.
Um,
I went to that,
that person's place and I went there
and ended up being a guy doing it and it
was really fucking weird. It
was just weird. I was like,
we'd done yet not on it.
We still got more. You got to do the other
side, but I think that's all right. Um,
did it help? I don't fucking know.
So, you know what I finally just said,
I finally said, um, I found is that,
is that homophobia by the way?
That I will only go to a girl to get a
fucking massage unless I'm really hurt,
you know,
if I'm really fucking hurt and I'm just
so fucking like time I jacked up my
shoulder, I just don't give a shit and
just like, just make the pain go away.
Is that homophobic?
You know,
I bet if a woman did, it was
like, you know, I, I don't
want, well, she would say,
I only want a girl. All right, so I'm a
little homophobic. Go fuck yourselves.
I got issues. Um, so anyways,
so I finally, I finally
just said, you know what,
why don't I just try
pushing through the paint?
When do I stop being such a fucking pussy?
Just push through the pain.
So you know, you know those, uh, those
little wheels with the handles on them.
I just started doing that. I do 10
reps a day. I wouldn't go too far in,
in like a week. The whole pain's gone and
gone away. She know me. I can't be like,
oh, fuck it now. Now I feel good.
Is that good enough for bill? No.
Now I'm on youtube trying to
learn how to do the human flag.
It fucking 44 years old.
I'm literally going down the street
to a stop sign doing my little,
the little side things,
trying to build up the strike for what?
For what purpose bill? You know,
you got your health, you, you,
your core feels good again.
Why are you going to go down there
and just blow something else out?
You're a fucking moron.
You know,
you're gonna be right back on a table
getting massaged by a dude. Um, all right,
whatever.
It's what the fuck I do.
So this weekend a knee has
been away and uh, so anyway,
I got this big green fucking egg thing
and uh, I got the, the, the uh, Dee Dee,
Dee Dee, Dee Dee Dee Dee, the
table that came with it. And uh,
that took like a fucking month by the
way, to get that thing. You know, I got,
I got the table where the egg sits in it
cause I hate that shit when you fucking
barbecue and they give you that little,
those two little,
it looks like those trays that you know,
that you have like an airplane and
you just set them down a both sides.
And that's supposed to take your
whole fucking, you know, all the meat.
And then where do I hang the fucking
spatula? I don't need that shit.
All right. That guy, he's going to die
in jail. I don't need that shit. Okay.
Ain't happening to me. Hey, you
stopped dealing in that shit. Um,
you know something? I watched Goodfellas
the other day and I think, uh,
I think what the fuck's his name now?
I,
I'm starting to like him the best
in that movie. To Fuck's his name.
Pauly Paul Sorvino.
I love that.
I love that fucking thing.
When he told him not to deal drugs and
he's telling him how that guy's gonna die
in jail.
Okay.
Then it happened in me and stupid
sweaty piece of shit and re hill,
the fucking rat, by the way. I didn't
get one when the real Henry Hill died.
Why people like,
they kind of confuse their love of that
movie and kind of forgot that this guy
ratted out all his friends, you know,
if, I mean, if that movie's accurate,
right? I mean, I know he
ratted out his friends,
but I don't know if that's
the exact reason why I did.
Was it because he was fucking dealing
drugs? Was there a guy saying,
don't do it.
Am I going to keep asking questions?
So anyways, I get this table
for this fucking thing and uh,
you know, it comes, comes here like a
newborn baby. It's fucking naked, right?
It's got new phone and it's not
staying, just got nothing on it, right?
So I gotta I gotta deal
with all that bullshit.
I've been doing that the whole fucking
weekend and doing it the right way too.
By the way.
I stand on top and the bottom.
I know a lot of your weekend
warriors. Yay. You're like, fuck that.
I ain't doing that.
Nobody looks under their door.
What if any water gets on there
prior to the fucking table?
The whole thing's going to be underground
and underwater. Well, go fuck yourself.
I did the whole thing,
two coats on Friday,
on Saturday, and then today I did
the fucking the varnish and uh,
I gotta tell you, man,
that's a bitch of a job.
It's just tedious.
Okay.
Fucking tedious.
Especially if you do the underneath too.
I'm sitting there laying on my back,
like fucking funds a rally, you know,
just fucking lay in there. I've
working on this shit. And, uh,
I got to tell you a lot of times I
was going to tap out and just be like,
you know what?
I'm not going to do this the right way.
I'm just going to do this stuff the fuck
headway and I didn't and I was happy.
I was proud of myself.
And you know what?
I'm going to show it to Nia and I'm
telling you, I, if she fucking says,
why did you pick the heck?
Why did she do this?
Right?
I'm going to take what's left of that
fucking stain and I'm going to dump it
over. I would never do
that. You know what?
I'll do it to myself and become the
martyr and then we'll see what she has to
say.
So anyways,
I got this fucking egg and I'm going to
make ribs and all this shit is somehow
still be able to do the human flag as I,
as I'm going to fucking,
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I'm going to buy like a fucking bison off
of Ebay and freeze that son of a bitch
and cook it slow, Cook it for the rest
of the summer and that's going to be it.
I'm going to get fat, girls going to get
fat, my dog's going to get fat and uh,
I'm going to have a whole new hour of
material and when a tub of Shit I am,
that's how great that thing is. Um, all
right, let's plow ahead with the podcast.
Everybody, if you're new to the podcast
and you would like to send me an email,
if there's a topic you'd like me to
discuss, go off on it for year. Possibly.
You want to give me shit?
You're probably saying bill,
where the fuck do I do that? You go to
bill at the [inaudible] podcast.com.
That's where you email me, bill
at the capital m, capital m,
capital P odcast.com. All
right, that's it. And a,
Oh, before I get into this shit, um,
I'm going to be in Washington DC
tomorrow night. Uh, not too. All right.
Tuesday night at the DC
Improv's celebrating their
30 years in the business by
telling my Dick and shit jokes.
And then this weekend I will be
at Hampton Beach in New Hampshire.
Hampton Beach Ballroom Casino. One
of my favorite venues that I do. Uh,
led Zeppelin played there.
One of the few small venues that they
played on their quick little tea party
tour that they did before
they just blew up. Um,
and then I'll be at the Newport Yachting
Center in Newport, Rhode Island.
I know that sounds fancy,
but I swear to God it's an air condition
tent in a parking lot. You know,
when you walk out the tent, you can see
a bunch of yachts, but I'm not on one.
It sounds good though. All right.
Okay. Here we go. First one,
first one out of the gate.
Validations. Son's mother is a nut job.
This is coming from my nut job.
That's an east coast dual.
She's a fucking nutjob up.
Um, all right, dear Billy.
Boy did I just fuck this thing up?
Come on, come on. I need life here.
Here we go. All right, dear
Billy. Boy, a couple months ago,
I split up with my son's
mother. Uh, we weren't married,
so I basically packed my shit up
and my son's stuff and moved out.
We hadn't been getting,
we hadn't been getting along for a while
because she didn't help me out with our
son and was texting all the time.
That's what she was doing.
She was texting all the time as she's
probably talking to the other guy.
She's probably fucking, I'm sorry.
Didn't mean to put that out there. Um,
the night before I moved out,
I received a text talking about
treating her better than I did.
I asked to see her phone
and she wouldn't let me.
So I moved out the next day and she
spent the night with some dude that same
night I moved out yet. Dude, let
me tell you something right now.
If your girl isn't paying attention
to you and she's texting all the time,
she's talking to the Dick
that she's riding. Okay. So
unless yours is vibrating,
she ain't texted you.
All right? No. Okay. Um,
anyways, next night, the next night,
this guy started living with
her. Jesus Christ. Yeah.
So she had a full on relationship
going on the side. Uh,
so we were pretty much through but a
couple of weeks later it was mother's Day
and she told me what my son
wanted me to get her. Uh,
my son is two years old and
doesn't really talk a whole lot.
So she was telling me what she wanted.
I told you to go fuck herself because I
wasn't getting her shit. There you go.
Good for you.
Uh,
she told me that she was still the
mother of my child and I should get her
something. Jesus Christ is this
people who use that kind of guilt,
who you actually use, like the
children. The fuck is wrong with you.
Anyways.
Also,
I had paid the rent right before I moved
out and when I found out this guy was
staring,
staying there the night I moved out,
I cancelled the rent check and
also got my name off the lease. Oh,
there's a nice one too to
the fucking jaw bone. Uh,
I know I did the right thing.
Please tell me that you agree that this
chick is fucked up in the head too. Oh,
and since I moved out, she sees our
son one or two days a week tops.
Uh, so to me, she's a shitty mother
who didn't deserve it. Deserve a gift.
Go Fuck yourself ps when he come
into the Kansas City area. All right.
Uh, well granted, I just heard your
side of the story, but uh, yeah,
sounds like the way the picture you're
painting there, sir. Absolutely.
Look,
the fact that the day you move out,
she bangs another guy and then
the other person moves in. I mean,
I think he got it good. I think
you got it. Good. That's a,
that was nothing but victory
in there as far as I see.
You didn't marry or you didn't love her.
You're knocked her up,
you toughed it out.
He tried to do the right thing.
There was no love there
to sustain it in the end.
And in the end she was
doing what she wanted to do.
She was trying to find love somewhere
else and she's probably a little relieved
that you're gone. Um, I
will tell you this self,
the fact that you have a kid with her
and she's going to be in your life for at
least another 16 years until this kid's
18 years old so she could make your life
really fucking miserable. Don't ask
me how. I don't know. They find a way.
It's what they do. So, uh,
you know that this one, you're right. If
she gives you shit, just be like, listen,
I move out and that night you bang another
guy and the next day you know the guy
moved in. Okay, I can do the math.
Am I really supposed to sit
here and believe that you
didn't have a relationship
going on while we were still together and
then you want me to go out and buy you
a a fucking Flowbee.
Rarely is that what you're telling me?
Well screaming into your content cause
on that list, Jesus. Bill, come on.
I'm surprise we're getting a divorce.
All right, here's a new story. All right.
Hey Bill,
I know you have,
you aren't a therapist but I think I just
want to talk to anyone at this point.
So here it goes.
I've been married for just under four
years to my wife who I dated for four
years prior to marriage.
I love being married and have said that
to anyone that asks. Since day one,
we own a nice house together. We have
three dogs, pit bulls, too. Good man.
And both make a decent living. I share
everything in my life with my wife. Uh,
when something makes me happy,
she knows when I'm upset about something.
I tell her,
uh,
throughout the course of our relationship
about once a year she would suddenly
without warning say she she was
unhappy and has been for months.
Oh God. Here we go. Uh,
she says she has discussions with their
mom who loves me and is the sweetest
woman alive and close friends about
the things that make her unhappy by,
I never hear a word about it until it
boils over and she floors me with how
unhappy she is. Oh, that's
not fair. All right.
We tried to work it out though.
Make changes.
She would act like it was okay
while it bottling it up again once,
once the lid goes on. The bottle.
There is no opening and again,
each and every time she
calls the unhappiness state
of the Union meeting and to
session.
I've always been completely honest as
saying that I'm very happy with her.
I love our jokes and honesty and honestly
enjoy spending time at Baba Baba Jesus
Christ to get to the fucking point.
All right, last Wednesday, here we go.
We had a good night together.
We went out for dinner and ice cream
and laughed at about, ah, Ba, ba Ba ba.
So I thought I'd come home the
following night in general, great mood.
She told me she had talked to her mom
and a friend and that they recommend that
she talked to me. I was confused, Eh,
most shit about not being unhappy.
Okay.
Uh, anyways, I wanted
anything to make her happy,
but she told me she didn't
think there was anything.
It was very emotional as she finally
mustered up the courage to say that we
might need to get separated.
I was floored and not in an almond asshole
husband that sits around drinks beer
and watches football with his buddy way.
I love my wife. We have free. Okay Dude.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Uh, so the
following day, after much reluctance,
I get her to agree to try
marriage counseling so we
can work out our happiness.
Do it.
I'm not giving you shit that this is,
you're pouring your heart out cause
this shit just happen. I understand.
But for the of the listeners,
I got to fly through this. Uh,
I get to agree with her. I get to, I
get it. Okay. So the following day,
it's like Lord of the rings here,
after much reluctance I get her to agree
to try marriage counseling so we can
work out her unhappiness. I was
willing to do anything at this point.
I immediately scheduled an appointment
with the counselor and it was looking
forward to having someone
neutral for us to talk to.
Later that night we were laying in bed
and I asked her if there was someone else
in her life. She said, no. Yeah
Dude. Oh Jesus. Oh Jesus. Uh,
Jesus, here we go. We just went over
the waterfall folks or where we,
you know,
it is not all in this story.
We were hearing the waterfall and we've
just looked at the other person in the
raft with a panicked look on her face
for that split second before we tried to
desperately.
But futilely try and paddle the fucking
thing over to the God goddamn coast.
Okay, here we go. We're going over.
I got a feeling we're going over.
Um, she said no, there's
no one else in my life.
I asked her if she's ever been unfaithful
and our relationship relationship and
she adamantly said no again.
Then she turned out the light and laid
down to sleep five minutes later and she
sat up and turn the light on.
Oh fuck.
She told me she just lied to me and said
that she had messed around with someone
a year into our marriage. And he
writes in capital letters, what period?
The period fuck period.
I probed her to tell me what
messing around was as got
to at least be a blowjob.
Ha Ha, ah, fucking whore. Um,
and after a minute of me guessing
her silence told me that she went
down on a guy she works with.
Swear to God.
I hadn't read this. Oh, if
I was [inaudible] right now,
you heard me.
You heard me
fucking creep.
I was furious and hurt.
Then furious again. She cried
and cried and said she was sorry.
We cried together. Dude,
you're a bigger man than me.
While I tried to wrap my head around how
she could possibly have done that to me,
I've had casual flirting
with people over the years,
but to act on something physically
with someone other than your spouse's,
completely disgusting.
To me,
the worst part is I love this woman
more than anyone. She's been my og.
Here we go again and he's going to be
a best friend for the last eight years.
She knows everything about me.
I want to hate her and make her sleep
at her parents' house until we divorced.
But all I want to do is be near her
again. Yeah, dude, that's because,
yeah, dude, she, she was in a hurry
up offense. That's what happened here.
So now your scamper and trying to figure
out what the fuck is going on. And she,
you know, she has the next three plays
that she just called in the huddle.
That's why this, this is why it
sucks to be you right now. Um,
one of my close friends tells me what
I know is the right thing. He goes,
let it go.
Don't bother with cloud ceiling.
What else has she done that you don't
know about how he never trust her again?
Bill's it possible for me to forgive
my wife. Am I wasting my time?
Okay.
Um, also I find out who this guy is
and I really wish I hadn't had to,
of course, all I wanted to do was show
up at the job, beat the shit out of him.
Like Ed Norton, Pete's the blonde,
pretty boy up and fight club. He writes,
I wanted to destroy something beautiful.
My other thought is since this guy also
cheated on his girlfriend who was still
with,
mmm.
My,
he did it with my wife.
I'd threatened to tell his girlfriend
what he'd done but not actually do it.
Yeah.
You don't want to do that that way.
He live in fear of coming home and her
knowing everything because I told her or
he would try to beat me to it,
admit to it,
hopefully ending his relationship
and getting terminal cancer and aids,
terminal cancer and aids. And you know
what? You're still being a gentlemen.
I still think that you're,
you're handling this with class wishing
terminal cancer and AIDS on this guy.
Um, I know you don't give a
shit. Of course I give a shit,
but not occupying. Ah, but I've got
to occupy my mind. So I thought I, I,
I do it here. Yeah. Do, why
would you think I don't give
a shit? You know, I mean,
I'm not a friend of yours, but you know
what I mean. Give me a fucking break.
This is horrific. Um, all right.
Your first question bills it possible
for me to forget my wife. Uh,
eventually you're going
to have to, uh, and
or you're going to go on a fucking tear
and you're going to meet some really
damaged fucking women and they're going
to reinforce everything that you've now
found out about your wife. See, can't do
that. You're going to go on a fucking,
uh, hate fuck pussy spree. That is, yeah.
You don't want to do that. Um, he
said, am I wasting my time? Yeah, dude,
it's over. She's not happy.
She's not good at communicating.
Um, she puts a lid on it, you
know, until it boils over.
This is the deal, dude. You know what?
I, this is going to kill you. All right,
let's go with the positive. You
don't have any kids with her. Okay?
You can just walk away.
Okay.
We had a prop and there was a,
there's nothing we can do.
So he didn't make it.
Did you just fucking walk away?
Just walk away. It's over. All right. Um,
that's a good thing. All right. One thing.
You've had a bunch of
kids with this fucking,
this person who for whatever reason,
couldn't say that they will.
I don't think that she wanted you
to wanting to fucking marry you.
I think she ignores her feelings.
She's actually having a
fucking breakthrough right
now while stomping all over
your fucking heart. All right, well
I dunno. I Dunno. I Dunno. Fuck
her. Give me a break, dude.
You fucking, you loved her with your
heart. You say a mother's a sweetheart.
You got dogs.
You like communicating dude.
You know something your like
the fucking guy. You're the guy.
My girl wants me to be.
Every fucking woman wants a guy like that.
You know guy who actually wants to be
married guy who actually comes home and
communicates,
you know a guy who gets along with
the mom and all that type of shit.
You're a family man. All
right. Unfortunately,
you know you met the wrong person,
so forget that dude.
All right. Forget it. Forget it. Fuck
that. Fuck that. It's over. Walk away.
Yeah.
Walk. Walk away, Dude. Gimme a fuck by.
You know what you talking about there?
You're talking about like the,
the amount of fucking shit she asked to
go through before she even learned how
to just communicate or fucking emotions
and the frustration of that's going to
meet every once in a while she's
gonna blow somebody at work.
Are you wasting your time
apps? A fuckin lutely. Okay.
Apps a Fuckin lutely.
And as far as like going there and
trying to fuck over that other guy,
that other guy is, he's already,
you don't need to fuck him over.
He's fucking himself over.
He's living it.
He's living a life of misery.
That life is miserable to fuck
around with the person that you with,
with somebody else.
That is a miserable life.
You know, I dunno. I think it's
something that a lot of guys do,
myself included back in the day in my
twenties going into thirties trying to
fuck them, you know, figure
myself out. I lived that life,
that whole fucking double. It's
horrible. It's a fucking horrible thing.
Then in the end I ended up alone and
I heard a lot of people and I was a
complete piece of shit.
So, and believe me, dude,
it was a miserable and ended up
me with me on a fucking futon.
So,
um,
yeah,
yeah. Do you, you're, you know,
don't become a piece of shit now.
Don't judge other women like
that. Just fuck it. You know?
Yeah.
Get out of it,
get out of it and just know that
it's going to be a fucking a,
I dunno,
it's going to be a hundred yards of pain
that you never fucking dealt with in
your life and you just got
to go through it. And um,
I would say the next time you
get with somebody, uh, make,
you know you're going to get serious
with somebody who make God damn sure that
they know how to fucking
communicate because that's a,
that's a scary thing to get
with a woman who doesn't,
how to communicate because
that's something that
they're supposed to teach us
how to do. You know, in a way they make
you better because you're like, oh,
I can just say, uh, no,
I don't feel like doing that without
fucking punched in the wall. You know,
they do that set up,
sell you down.
If you get with some psycho and
she can't settle you down. I mean,
she's a, she's damaged goods.
All right, here we go. Next one.
It's just these things just
keep getting deeper. Asexual,
just from a plant or
something. Dear billion, uh,
this is a bit of change from
the emails you usually get,
but I hope you can help me out anyways.
I'm a 26 year old guy.
Completely normal in every way
except for one. I'm asexual.
For your listeners who
don't know what that means,
it means I don't feel any sexual
dot desires at all. I never have.
Take a moment to wrap
your head around that one.
I think I'm going to need more than
a moment. Dude. Let me ask you this.
What do you do with all your free time?
You know,
how many fucking languages can you speak?
You want to think about that?
How much fucking shit you would get done
if you weren't chasing it all the God
damn time. All right. Uh,
but believe it or not,
I do have a girlfriend. Uh, we've
been together for four years.
So what do you do to get aroused?
Think about like when it's over.
I'm really being a Dick Right now.
I'm sorry. Um, and he goes in.
Before that we were friends
for about another five years.
We both helped each other through some
rough shit and eventually decided that we
wanted it to be more than friends.
She's the first girl I've ever known
who made me wish I wasn't a sexual,
she knew all about it when
we started dating. So there
were no surprises. In fact,
she's been really cool. We joked about
it a lot. And when we did have sex,
which was once or twice a month,
I did everything I could to make it
good for his is like fascinating.
So like what are you thinking of,
you know,
three more minutes and she
should be happy. Row, row,
row your boat gently down the street. Uh,
but lately things have been different.
It wasn't a sudden change,
but something I just noticed recently,
she doesn't joke around about
sex as much as she used to.
And we now have sex once
every two or three months.
Our emotional bond is still
as strong as ever. In fact,
just last week we were
talking about marriage by,
I have a feeling my gut that she
might be fucking another guy.
I know her well enough to know that having
sex four times a year is nowhere near
enough for her.
The thing is,
it wouldn't bother me if she
was fucking someone else.
I know she has needs that I can't fulfill.
So I'd be willing to have a pinch hitter
come in and get the job done for me.
Jesus. Talk about a fucking
180 from the last story.
Um, I just, sorry,
I had to pause and do the math and just
make sure that I didn't say that the
wrong number sometimes. Yeah, it was a
total three 60. Now that was a one 80. Um,
I just wanted, I just want to know about
it. I've, I've wanted to ask her about it,
but I'm worried about what will
happen if I'm wrong. What should I do?
I love this girl that get death and I
never forgive myself if I fuck up a good
thing we have together.
A dude that's outside my
totally outside my bounds.
I don't know what to tell you. I
would, I would start going to therapy
alone first and then possibly
bring her in. But, um,
you know,
that's a,
yeah,
I don't know.
I don't know anything about,
I don't know anything
about being a sexual, um,
so that,
that would
be my advice. You know, if you want to
fix that problem and that type of thing.
But I dunno, I feel like I've
let you down, dude. I'm sorry,
but I'm not gonna sit here and
fucking run my Yap. Like I, I mean,
I don't know what the fuck I'm
talking about to begin with.
I definitely don't know who I'm
talking about with that. I would,
I would go get some fucking therapy.
It just say, I don't know what it is.
I don't fucking, nothing
gets me going. Um,
and then hopefully you,
you go to some asexual specialist.
Jesus. I'm the worst.
Sorry, I let you down.
I'll give you a podcast magnet
next time. I see. All right.
27 year old Virgin Jesus
Christ. Uh, hey Billy,
I love to hear your humorous take on
my pathetic situation. First of all,
dude, let's work on your
self esteem. All right?
You're already shitting all over yourself.
Um, all right. Hey, watch this guy.
Watch him shit all over himself. I'm
a 27 year old virgin. Oh, ggs. Uhh,
that's what he wrote.
Now your first question is going to be,
how the fuck did that happen? Well, to
protect myself, I'd actually preserve,
prefer to keep my background
is quite as possible. Hey,
I'm not trying to get you to rat
yourself out. Here's what I can say.
I come from a rich town inhabited
by obnoxious [inaudible].
I was always the weird kid and very
socially awkward people hated me no matter
how nice I was, Jesus Christ. Dude,
are you like a superhero that's like
the exact same background of like every
fucking superhero movie, isn't it?
It's probably cause nerds, right?
Those movies because they don't have to
fight and all of a sudden you're like,
what am I knew how to fly? What if I could
fly? There was a guy who can save me.
Um,
then they draw it and then nerds line
up around the block to go see it.
Did he see you spank him in? Yes.
It's exactly like the other ones.
Um,
I was always the weird kid and very
socially awkward people hated me no matter
how nice I was. And eventually I
came to hate myself and still do.
I called it dude, I fucking called it.
Uh, he's shitting all over himself.
Eventually it was discovered that I most
likely have a mild case of Asperger's
syndrome, which is a mild form of
autism, which is way out of my league.
Are you guys trying to make me look dumb?
I thought I did that.
I achieved that by how
awful I read out loud.
Here we go. That causes social
ineptitude and Quirky personality traits.
Well I would go find a hooker
with Asperger's. That's
the first thing I would do.
You get the Fucking v off my back.
Definitely wear a condom.
See that's where my advice is
going to be coming from. You guys.
You have some weird conversation
in some ironic vehicle. Um,
at least discovering this made me more
of self aware and I've been able to clean
up my act over the last few years,
but I still have a lot of social anxiety,
shyness, and very few
friends. On the flip side,
I'm actually pretty decent looking,
have a decent job in a laboratory.
These are fucking,
he's going to get bit by something
radioactive and he's going to become a
superhero.
Uh,
and I'm a certified commercial
pilot and do volunteer work
dude. Like you know something,
if, if I was in the FBI,
like so many fucking red flags
just went up there. Uh, okay.
That's the set up now.
Now for the question
first, what the fuck would you
do if you were in my situation?
I told you I'd get a hooker
with Asperger's syndrome
and you guys could just bond
over that. Uh, I don't know. Let me,
let me, let me read all your questions.
I'm obviously kidding him off.
I'm trying to find a hook with
Asperger's syndrome, right?
You couldn't find one that would
be like needle in a haystack,
which you'd have to do is go to an escort
service and request that personally.
Um,
I would think
I'm looking for 36,
24 36 with Asperger
hair color does not matter.
Yes, I can hold a next if,
if eventually everything I ever
do make it anywhere with a chick.
Should I tell her up
front about my status?
I had this conversation a few weeks ago
with a friend who has a lot of romantic
experience and she said it would be
extremely obvious that I'm new to the game
and that withholding that information
could itself be detrimental.
But I also know that if I do tell
a chicken 27 year old virgin,
she will demand an explanation before
going any further and it will send up red
flags for the most. What do you do, Bill?
Thanks for doing your awesome podcast
and go fuck yourself. All right.
This is what I would do.
Okay.
I would just start hitting on every check
that fucking interest me and I would
be just totally honest.
Okay.
Tell him, tell her what your, your,
uh, your situation is. And, uh,
you know,
if she doesn't accept it,
then fucker let her walk and then you
don't have to deal with any of the
bullshit you didn't know.
You just,
you just fast forward through a three
year fucking horrific relationship. Um,
I would just be up front with people.
I wouldn't open it with Ai.
You have beautiful eyes and I have
Asperger. I wouldn't do that, you know?
Um, I will work on my self esteem.
I wouldn't talk shit. You just,
you shit on yourself right out
of the gate. I mean, obviously,
I know you're going to do that. When you
said you were 27 year old virgin and,
and you probably going to go that route,
but uh,
think good thoughts about yourself, man.
I know that's kind of like simple, but I,
you know,
you gotta like,
okay,
you got to amp yourself up a little bit.
Go out there and you know,
you don't have to go find the check
he your dreams, but just go out.
You don't get to tell some girl you got
fucking Asperger's syndrome. You don't,
why don't you just do that with somebody
that you're really interested in,
but it's just want to go out and get laid.
Just go out there,
start hitting on chicks,
turning into a game so you don't have
to deal with the pain of the rejection.
Just be like, all right, I don't
have the balls to take the next step.
Whatever that step is.
Peeling yourself off the fucking wall.
Striking up a conversation.
Just saying hello to a pretty girl.
She walks down the street.
Just try to get over fucking hurdle and
give you permit yourself permission to
suck and you just, you gradually build it
up. It's like learn how to play guitar.
You're not going to pick it
up and immediately be able
to play all your songs.
You learn a couple of fucking cords,
you know? Then your fingers hurt, right?
And you get frustrated,
but you keep coming back and
eventually you can fucking play.
Pussy is no different.
That's what I would do. Put The ass burger
on the back burner. Who knows? Do it.
Maybe not as fucked up as you think you
were socially. You know what I mean?
Maybe you've got a sense
of humor under there.
I think you do your shit on
yourself in a funny way. You know,
spin it around that way. Do you
have any interests? Go, go to a,
go to a fucking, I don't know.
Whatever, you know, do you fly kites?
Go to some flying the kite.
Good venture. There's gotta be some
woman there also likes to Kate.
I know that was an overly simplified thing
by, that's what I would do. All right.
And then when you go to like a
hookup with somebody, uh, they,
you know, edgy yet. Tell him
if he stopped and you're not,
don't know what you're doing to watch
a couple of fucking pornos, you know,
you'll get the idea. Actually
no, don't do that. Don't do that.
Cause then you'll suck and start
slapping them around. You don't do that.
I know what to tell you, dude. I get
buy some books. I say go buy some,
buy some books in that data that,
that part of the bookstore that you know,
if bookstores exist anymore going gone
line has got to be plenty of information.
I bet if you literally looked up finger
banging technique is you looked how to
kiss. I bet this is going to be
reams of fucking information.
Okay.
I've never done that cause I never had
to. Oh, just kidding. Of course I had.
Do you think of that?
I didn't wish that fucking information
was around way back in the day when he
had no id,
just practice kissing your fucking pillow
and tried to overhear conversations in
the fucking high school cafeteria and try
to figure out what people were talking
about. That's all I could do. You, you
have the whole world at your fingertips,
you know,
so when you're done in the laboratory
working with radioactive shit before you
get bit by something you don't want you
to go on and get late before you learn
how to fly. All right. All right.
Personal dilemma. Hey Bill.
Hey Bill. Hey Bill.
Read my fucking letter.
I got some problem.
Oh look who's up.
Look who woke up.
What's up buddy?
How are you? You want to go
outside when we make my dog howl.
This is Cleo.
You won't go outside.
Cleo.
She's dancing around Cleo.
Cleo,
do you?
I tried to go low. Cleo, come
here. Cleo. Ah, you fucking,
you know I feel right and I feel like
I'm that bugs bunny cartoon when that
bullfrog is singing. How my
baby hell am I on a, you know,
and now you guys are here so she won't
do it. Cleal now she's licking herself.
I'm not gonna fucking be able to top that.
All right, personal dilemma. Hey Bill,
a few days ago, a good friend of mine
lost her dad in a motorcycle accident.
Jesus Christ. Is there any ray of sunshine
at the end of these? We started off,
let, let's, let's just rewind here.
Let's see where the fuck we were.
How we got to this point. All
right. Start it off. Validation.
My son's in that job that was
kind of, oh, whatever surprise,
we're getting a divorce. I blew
somebody at work. Holy Shit.
That we go asexual,
fucking whipped that around and then
we can hit the 27 year old virgin now.
Now we're talking about death.
Okay.
And none of this am I qualified to
talk about, um, bill a few days ago,
a good friend of my lost her
dad in a motorcycle accident.
It's obviously an incredible
emotional time for her and her mother,
much younger brother and
rest of the family, her dead.
This is such an awful joke.
Did they tear?
That sticks his stick figure like
picture off the back of the SUV.
Sorry, I had to lighten it
up. I had to lighten it up.
I'm sorry.
All right.
Her Dad loves his motorcycles and we'd
take it across the continent with his
body and his wife and he had his kids
on dirt bikes since they were young.
Everyone is giving all the support they
can and will continue to do so in time.
Uh, during this tough
time about bar last week,
my buddy and I both bought
our first motorcycles and
I've been really excited to
get it out on the road.
We both pulled over 15 grand into it.
Not only our bikes,
but Ryan and gear and two courses.
Obviously this is pretty bad timing and
we can't cancel or reschedule the first
course or else we both give a
grant to these dicks for nothing.
The course is next weekend and we're not
sure whether or not we should go under
the circumstances.
Okay.
It's a funeral falls within that weekend.
It's obviously more important,
but if not,
should,
yeah,
we take the course.
Okay.
I told her about the bike and
do this is fucking hilarious.
This is fucking hilarious.
Yeah.
This guy is trying to act like he really
cares about this guy and he's trying to
weigh whether I go take my
funds are really course or
go to the fucking funeral.
I thought the stick figure was a bad joke.
Now I don't feel bad about it.
All right. I told her about the bike
and courses before the accident,
so hiding it really isn't an option.
I don't think she would want us anywhere
near a bike after this. Uh, okay.
I see what you're doing. All right. A
strike that. Strike what I just said.
I've been close with this girl for a
while and I don't want to do anything that
might make the situation work.
Where's my buddy and I both know this
sounds incredibly fucking selfish and if
we had the option even rescheduled,
we would have done it,
but a grant to a student as a lot of money
and we don't want to give it to these
pricks. I love how these guys are pricks
how they fix these. Then that practice,
they have a business, they said what?
It was up front. They didn't Jack it up.
You paid it for them. You're trying to
make them out to be the bad guys here,
but we also don't want to offend and make
her and maybe make a fender and maybe
make things worse if that's even possible
at this point. What should we do? Thanks
stowed.
You want to go to this fucking course
and the worst way you give a shit you
care, but you don't want
to lose your fucking money.
MMM.
Yeah. I mean 1000 bucks is 1000
bucks. I don't know what to tell you.
You got to answer that one on
your own dope, but you want to go,
you definitely want to go on.
There was a way for you to go and not
go to the funeral without getting in
trouble.
You would fucking do it in a second.
And it has nothing to do with those
fucking pricks with their business.
MMM.
All right. You know
who's kitten? Whoa, dude.
Steve with all the fucking
dancing and skipping around there.
You want to fucking go learn
how to ride a motorcycle.
You have $15,000 motorcycle.
All right. With the [inaudible],
Punky Tuscadero outfit,
you want to go put that on?
Is there a way for you to fucking
go to the course and then come back?
Dude, this is what you do. You go
take the course that day. All right.
And hopefully the funeral's at night
and right is the service starts. You're,
you come flying back on your bike and
then attribute to that guy who died in a
motorcycle.
You come through right through the
fucking church doors on the motorcycle and
when everybody fucking gas,
if you just yell out,
yeah,
you want a water. He died doing
what he loved and I brought my bike
and I went to that class because I
knew he would want me to do that.
Look at me that way.
All right. Continue on with the
service. That's what you do.
All right. That's my advice. If
you're going to fucking do it,
cause I know you want to do it. What's
your wrestling with right now, sir?
Is the selfish cunt within you.
And I'm not judging you.
I am.
I'm relating.
Good luck. Alright, Matt chicks. Oh wait,
I haven't done any advertising this week.
All right, here we go. Here
we go. Here we go. Um, oh,
I forgot to mention this,
that today's show is brought to you
by feel like I'm on sesame street.
The number three in the letter l. Uh,
today's show is brought to you by audible.
Please visit audible podcast.com/bill
for your free audio book download.
Do you like books?
But don't want to read them.
They got a free audio book download
for you@audiblepodcast.com slash bill.
Look at that. I give you bad yet.
I bring it around with free stuff.
Okay. Um, what are we doing here?
What am I doing here?
Um,
audible podcast.com/ [inaudible] go
there and get a free audio book download.
Check out their website, listen to the
podcasts and all that type of stuff.
Have a good time with that. There we
go. Can you tell, can you tell him,
I'm trying to look for other stuff here
as I'm doing this. Hang on, hang on,
hang on, hang on. Hang on. Eric
Clapton. Hang on. That's sent mail.
I wanted to go into the inbox.
Christ, the fuck is wrong with you.
Uh Oh Gigi is. Guess
who's back? stamps.com.
Everybody stamps.com.
Okay,
let's get through this one cause I know
you guys got to have this one memorized
at this point. Do you guys like
going to the pot to the podcast?
So the Post Office, Huh?
Maybe you do. Maybe a dump.
Wouldn't it be nice if
that was one more thing?
Off the list of things to do that day.
You could just cross off.
Would it be great if he just could
handle it within your own apartment,
home or sleeping bag?
Would it be great if you could print
official US stamps off of your computer
where they gave you a little scale?
You got to buy the hat.
But what if they gave you a little scale?
You could, you could just weigh boxes,
put the official US postage,
take a right out to the post office box.
She could do at two in the
morning while eating cereal,
watching reruns of the Jeffersons.
Well, you can do that@stamps.com.
Anything you can do with the post office
you can do right now from your desk
with Stan. Stop Calm, um, uh,
unlike the post office
stamps.com never closes. See,
get postage whenever you need it. 24,
seven. I've been using these things,
sending all my DVDs, uh,
through stamps.com I, you,
I love using my scale and
all that type of stuff.
You get a no risk trial
plus $110 bonus offer.
It includes a digital scale and up
to $55 in free postage. Don't wait.
Go to stamps.com before
you do anything else,
click on the radio microphone at the
top of the homepage and type in burpee.
You IRR that stamps.com enter bur bur are,
there we go,
Eh, what else do we got? Uh, the last two.
You want to get him out of the way,
amazon.com you know the deal,
go to [inaudible] dot
com slash podcast okay.
Or billboard.com and you click on the
podcast page and you look on the right
side, you'll see the Amazon
banner. You Click on that,
and if you want to buy something, if you
buy something, not saying you have to, uh,
they kick a little bit of money
to me and I take 10% of that.
And to kick it to the wounded warriors
project, actually, to be honest with you,
when I'm starting to do is just
10% of everything I make on this,
all this advertising I'm just sending
to the wounded warriors project.
So if you do any of this stuff,
um,
you going to be helping out vets and
uh, and this podcast, it's a win win.
You can feel good about yourself, uh,
game if not saying you don't already.
All right,
game fly.com.
Are you a Gamer or do you
just look like one game?
fly.com offers over 8,000 video games.
Uh,
they sent disks in the mail
to you and you send them,
you can send it back when you're done.
There's no late fees, no hassles,
man with access to all new releases
works for your playstation and Tendo we x
box and now your PC for my listeners,
8,000 video games at your
fingertips. Second, you're done.
You can send them back like a bunch of
whores you never loved the begin with. Um,
and keep the one, keep the
special ones. You keep that one.
You keep the soulmate
games. Uh, for my listeners,
you can get a free 15
day to two disc trial,
2195 value. If you go to
my website, a podcast page,
and click on the game fly
banner or go to www.game,
fly.com/bar. Check it out.
There you go. Look at that.
Post Office is in your house.
8,000 video games in your house,
audible podcast.com. You got that going
on. Send some flowers to your check.
You can have a great week. You
can have a great week. Oh look,
I'm going to go buy a widget on
amazon.com you just helped out the troops.
Who's a hero? You are not me,
not me. I'm just the Messenger.
I'm just, I'm an open channel. I just
let it flow right through me. All right.
Smart chicks. Bill,
you're an American hero.
Lead talking to May for what
if I did?
I, I uh, I must know somebody
at the American hero awards.
Nepotism. Uh, my dad started
it so he just gave me one.
I'm smart chicks,
smack chicks.
My girlfriend dumped me because she could
sniff out my bs before even realized
it smelled.
She was definitely smarter than me
because after I was through pouting about
being dumped, I realized she was
right. That's very mature. You know,
you're not that dumb. There's a lot of
smart guys, you know, they can't do,
they think Albert Einstein would do that.
Some chick who's smarter than him,
he could fucking handle that
with his Phil Spector
haircut before Phil Spector.
Tom Selleck, mustache. All
right, so here's my question.
How do I make smart chicks dumber.
Thanks for you help.
Don't go fuck yourself. Fuck others.
Okay. Um, this guy's a wise ass.
I like, how do you make
smart chicks dumber? Um,
all right,
this is what is what you'd
do.
I don't care who they are.
They got to have some sort of physical
thing that you can tell it there that
they're sensitive about.
Okay.
Maybe they have little arms like that
little hot Italian chicken on the food
network.
You know,
every time she goes to reach something
like her arms are always totally straight
or else she can't get it yet. She somehow
like five foot two. That's what you do.
You just look for something.
Okay. And then you focus on that.
Anytime she starts being smarter, you
bring up her little arms, you know,
you bough,
you gradually destroy her spirit.
That's how you do it. Now,
do you want to do that?
I hope you don't because if you do,
then seriously go fuck yourself.
Oh, sorry. Anyways,
let's go dilemmas bill.
Would you rather gain a three pack a day
smoking habit or have to wear a dress
for the rest of your life?
Yeah.
Oh,
I take a dress all day long.
I'd take all fucking day long.
I would get some fucking,
a fruity smell and shampoo to wash
what's left of my Hayek and uh,
I'd wear, I'd wear down the street.
You know what I would do? What?
I would start hanging out in coffee houses
and act like I played guitar and I'd
probably get more ass than I ever did
as opposed to fucking three pack a day.
Smoking habit. There's no fire. I want
to do that. Then what? Die earlier.
I'll be at my desk bed going
out, dress still be alive. Uh,
the Bruins still at first place. Fuck.
I know that. Got To win it again. Uh,
would you rather have a third nipple
in the center of your chest or a third
testicle? Oh, without question. I
take the third ball all day long.
Who the fuck's going to see
it? You know, and then a fair,
we get kicked in the balls.
I got one that can get out of the way.
So maybe it can like somehow offset
the pain of one and only feels like,
like when lance gets kicked in the balls.
Does that make any sense?
Yeah.
I mean, I dunno when, when is a
girl really gonna what is it girl?
Really even look at your
boss. You know, it's funny.
I could have three balls and my
girl would know. You know, I know.
Notice that course you're dead and it's
all fucking inflated and not inflate it
and shift in and it's, it's like,
uh, I don't know what it is.
It's like a ball sec. I don't even
know what the fuck is in there. Yeah,
it's throw another one in there.
I don't give a shit as opposed to having
that third one sitting there looking
like a late model Ford 1948
Ford, it was at the, uh, no,
what was that guy?
That Tim Robbins,
that car Tim Robbins made in that movie.
Tucker.
Look at like the front end at one of
those Tucker's, yeah. I'm not doing that.
Having a third headlight.
No fucking way. No Way.
There's not enough makeup to cover
that up, but you know, whatever,
throw something else in my ball bag. Hey,
you know what I say about my ball bag?
The more the merrier. And he liked
that. All right. And what that,
that's the podcast for this week.
Everybody up nice and early,
it's able to be downloaded perfectly.
What could you think about
bitching about next? Who knows?
Please visit me on Twitter.
I'm almost up to 100,000 followers,
you know, and I think once I get to
100,000 that's going to be critical mass.
And that's when I can really start hitting
you guys with my conspiracy theories
and, and possibly start getting
a little momentum, you know?
Um, that's it. Okay. This week everybody,
I'm going to be at the DC Improv.
It's already sold out,
but I'm going to bring it up just so
I can tell you that it's sold out.
You know like when they have a poster
up on the wall and they just stamped,
sold out on,
it's like,
well the why you still advertising
it to rub it in that I'm not going.
That is exactly what I'm doing.
I'm at the DCM prop down.
I'm out there to celebrate,
celebrate their fucking
a 30th anniversary.
It's one of my favorite clubs of all time.
You know?
There's some special ones out there,
ones that I dreamed of playing
and that is one of them.
How do you like that endorsement?
People at the DC Improv.
I love him so much and we'll be there
in a Tuesday. Oh Jesus. You know what?
I just try to overly cross my leg over
the top of the arm rest here and I just
crushed one of my balls for a second,
you know?
Why do you think that just happened?
Do you think my house is haunted?
Do you think there was maybe somebody
who used to live here named Ulysses who
was killed by a bunch of fucking mean
neighborhood kids because they found out
he had three balls and now I finally
brought it up and I unleashed him.
You know what?
I think I'm going to call ghost hunter
as cause it's the grace,
the ghost of three ball Larry.
And you know what's funny about that
fucking ridiculous Goddamn show is they
would actually show up to film it.
You know? You know I want to do it.
I want to film them filming my place
and catch them when they throw that rock
down the hall big. Oh, what the fuck
was that? Did you still saw a door?
I definitely felt something.
You know that show is,
it's like a bunch of Paul
versus chasing ghosts.
All right. You want, you want to hit the
biggest, the biggest fucking scam ever,
and this is such a big fight
between me and Nia all the time,
is the use of the fucking dishwasher.
I think the dishwasher is one of the
biggest scams other than the Federal
Reserve. It goes Federal
Reserve, ice cubes, anger,
and then the dishwasher.
Yeah.
And you can throw, skip Bayless
in there somewhere. His,
his screaming and yelling somewhere.
You can throw it in there somewhere.
I don't give a fuck. Um, you know, it's
all, it's all up to personal opinion.
The dishwasher,
it doesn't fucking wash dishes.
And I know this is a Seinfeld thing.
Why?
Yeah.
Did you call it the what?
Um, yeah, it doesn't,
it doesn't,
the dishwasher does not scrub the dishes.
It basically like you have to take a piss
and there's a skid mark and the toilet
and you just start pinging on it.
That's what a dishwasher does, you know?
So basically if the food has been
there long enough, it's not coming off.
All right.
And My lady will fucking put dishes
in there and they'll stay in there for
fucking days. And then she runs it
and it gets, it gets most of it done,
you know?
And then I go out to make myself an egg
and there's fucking dinner from fucking
three nights ago, a couple of like
skid marks in the toilet, Lasagna,
skid marks on the fucking plates.
It drives me nuts.
I had a hissy fit.
Everybody,
okay? I literally, I had a hissy fit,
I'll even call it that. If you saw it,
you would have laughed your asses off.
Cause I was here by myself cursing and
screaming when I couldn't figure out why
we didn't have any fucking forks,
where are the forks?
And then I finally was like,
you know what, I bet during
the goddamned dishwasher.
And I went over and opened dishwasher and
it was like fucking 10 plates in there.
All with this shit that
you couldn't get off yet.
I didn't have to hire one of those fucking
guys who paints cars at this point to
come over here with that sand blaster
to get the shit off. And uh, you know,
I don't know. I'm, I'm, I'm
talking too much about the ship,
but the dish dishwasher is completely,
it's a scam.
It doesn't fucking work. And for some
reason it adds value to your house.
When people show up, does
it have a dish? Oh honey,
they have that thing
that doesn't really work.
You know? Ah, Jesus, your bill, you know
it's, you're an hour and 15 minutes in.
You gave them their fucking money's worth.
Do you really need to end it with your
goofy little riff about dishwashers?
Do you think other people never used
them and realize that they don't quite
fucking work? You stupid cunt. All right,
that's the podcast. Go fuck yourselves.
We'll talk to you next week.