Hey, what's going on is bill burn? It's
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
June 24th, 2013. How are Ya?
How's it going? I know it's
Tuesday morning. Had to do
the math there on the date.
I apologize for not doing
the podcast earlier.
I was a,
I was in New York this weekend.
Being a fancy man is Jimmy
Norton would say I was at the,
uh, the, the premiere of this movie
that I have a really small rolling,
it's called the heat.
It stars Sandra Bullock and Melissa Muck
and uh, Michael Rappaport. Now all these,
all these people,
all these people are in it and a yours
truly bill Billy red faces in it for a
couple of seconds.
Don't blink or you will miss me.
But that movie comes out this weekend.
Um,
this upcoming weekend I should
say. So, uh, do me a solid day.
Had to go out and check it out if you can.
I'd really appreciate it's
very funny movie and uh,
I got to do the whole Hollywood thing.
Went back to New York,
walk the fuck and red carpet.
You know,
it answered a couple, two or three
questions. I went in, I saw the movie,
I enjoyed it. And then I got drunk
with Joe to Rosa and Paul Versey.
You know, what else could
you ask for in the weekend?
I know what she could
ask for. Yeah. Victory.
Send it to fucking gave
seven back in Chicago.
That's something I could have asked for.
I could ask for the
hockey gods to be just,
how about we get a fucking lucky bounce.
How about one of our shots goes off the
boards and bounces in a weird way and
record Shay's off five fucking
guys and goes in the neck.
Can we get one of those?
Just one. And you know what,
it was not meant to be. Hats off
to the, uh, Stanley Cup champions.
Chicago Blackhawks say, or
definitely without a doubt,
the best team, uh, this year.
And um, you know, they would
just say what is better?
It's all I can say they were better.
Uh,
one goal better every fucking
game it's saved. But, um,
I got to admit, I, I, you know,
there's no one on their team.
I hate and that says something
after watching them for six games,
it's like nobody on their teams a
cunt, you know, they got one, they got,
they have one pest. That's it. Other
than that, you know, we've got a pest and
Marshawn,
so I will tell you that.
What's fucking annoyed me though is I
dunno what this white hair dude's name is,
but I'm watching on nhl.com how do
you mispronounced Charisse name?
You know,
he kept calling Chera.
Well abroad's Gadda they got chair
a bat there. Eight and Burley. Yay.
It's like he just got brought
up from the fucking minors.
Guys want to Norris trophy. You can't
pronounce this fucking name correctly.
Um, anyways, Jesus Christ,
you want to talk about a fucking,
just taking the wind out of his sails,
sitting there on the edge of your seat
thinking, okay, just hold on. Hold on,
hold on.
Don't let them tie it up and he fucking
tie it up and then they score another
one. What was it? 17 seconds later. The
first one I'll go with, but you just,
you can't let that other one happened.
But uh,
okay.
I don't know. Fucking Dave Bollen
guys, just a great hockey player.
I don't know how the fuck that happen.
How does it happen? You know, it kills me,
fucking kills me. But, um,
it was a great series and an original
61 and I actually still like the Black
Hawks and I think they have fucking
great uniforms and a God dammit.
God fucking damn. What
the fuck to goals? I mean,
we literally went from,
okay. I mean, I'm like,
okay,
thinking in my head. All right, game seven
can, do you think they can do it again?
As I'm freaking out. Hold on, hold on,
hold on. And then they fucking tie it up.
And I was like, Oh God, another
fucking over time. You're killing me.
Okay.
Can I fucking mentally make it through
another fucking overtime as I sit here
having no effect on the game
for some reason stressing out.
Could I make it through
it? Oh, right day, I guess.
I guess we don't have to go to overtime.
Thank you day Boleyn for just a
fucking end in that real quick. Um,
but I got to tell you,
um,
I was blown away by what the Bruins
were able to do this season that,
you know, actually, you know,
game one and game six was kind of the
Bruins team that I saw years where they
would get up to one, three, one and
they had problems holding onto a lead.
So I actually thought,
I didn't even think they were going
to make it out of the first round.
So I can't say I was psyched
that that happened. Whatever,
we got a great core base. We can, we come
back, bring up fucking Douggie Hamilton.
He got a lot of experience.
The blood, the blue. Uh,
the only good thing about the hawks
winning it in Boston was I didn't have to
listen to that stupid
Dota.
Just when you think nothing could be more
annoying than Oh, whatever. After that,
after a goal,
that fucking mindless song and looking
at those fat fucking brought Eaton
Chicago Fed back dumb
mustaches. They even have on my,
just thinking of a fucking SNL
sketch at that fucking song,
you mine as well be.
You might as well.
What does that fucking
Song I get knocked down,
but I get up go and like those are songs
that should only be played. You know,
when you're on a cruise ship and you've
just signed up for the aerobics class,
you know what I mean?
Nobody listens to those fucking songs.
She really got to get rid of that.
Other than that top to bottom.
I think Chicago is a great
organization, but uh, you know,
they always got to have something fucking
Douchey to either appeal to kids or
just get mindless fiddle. Faddle eat
and fucking morons. The buy tickets.
Yeah, I did say fiddle.
Faddle it's still exists. Um,
goddammit.
That shit was good when you were a kid.
Send it right through the fucking roof
with the sugar and they always got to
have something like that. You
know, like the Red Sox, Wally,
really Wally,
how many women were in the room when
that came up? That fucking name Gail.
Hey God, that's cute. You know
what? I'm not going to blame women.
This is not a sex,
a battle of the sexiest topic.
This is just a fucking dose shills
topic. And you, you can file all of that.
Let's say I told, you know what I mean?
Now I'm being honest about my teams.
Why don't we do that next week
for a topic? Write in something,
you know of your home team that
they do that they just really,
that's just such a blatant fucking reach
out to try to grab non sports fans.
Um, you know what's creepy about Wally
with the Boston Red Sox is that's really
like, I mean, the team is
basically like a religion.
So you're trying to get them
when they're young. So it's,
it's like you giving them candy, you
know, it's just something creepy about it.
We'll have a fucking adult come walking
up in some big furry fucking outfit or
whatever the hell the guide,
they have thing where's right.
Be like on a mission
to be friendly to kids,
not because it's the right thing to do,
not because you love kids,
because you know,
someday that kid is going to have some
sort of alcohol problem and want to
hopefully want to get hammered at your
ballpark and you want his booze money in
your fucking pocket.
Right.
All done under the guise or dressing
up like a fucking woolly mammoth,
you know. Oh, that's right.
People. I'm polling. Um,
well I'm looking behind the curtain
to mascot mascots this week.
I'm pulling back that curtain. I'm
showing you the ugly fucking truth. Um,
oh,
it's going to be a while.
It's going to be a while before I
get over the kick in the balls that,
that last fucking minute
and 10 seconds was
it was,
I think they kicked my left ball first
and then the Dave Bolan was the fucking
right ball.
Uh,
not only did they knock the
Bruins out of the playoffs,
not only do we not win the cup,
but now simultaneously hockey is over and
I have to wait for the Nhl all the way
until October.
So you know what,
you know I'm going to get over this Bruins
loss. I'm going to watch the day game.
There's nothing better than watching
a day game, a Dodgers game out here.
You just sit there by yourself sipping
on a fucking login and you listened to
Vince Scully. It's great.
It takes a second though.
Like I think how deep
into the, uh, the summer,
obviously there was a strike this year,
but how deep into the,
into the summer that basketball and the
NHL goes and like how up tempo and high
scoring and all that while hockey's not
really high scoring, but whatever, um,
just how the energy level to go from that
to then settle into a great day for a
ball game. Uh, we got a couple of,
it's going to be a pitcher's
duel here at commits Geek.
That's ball one. Yep. Yep, Yep, Yep.
Don't even play that as fast,
but that they've just fucking,
you gotta settle into it.
You have to settle into baseball.
You know what I mean?
It's like you haven't been driving like
a fucking maniac and then your girl
looks at you and just like you're
scaring me to have it right.
And then you have to fucking mentally
bring yourself down from that play off
energy that you will fucking drive and
with and you've got to somehow calm
yourself down and then literally
waves somebody into your lane.
That's what it's like to go from the
Stanley Cup finals or even the NBA finals.
NBA Finals are great.
That was another heartbreaker watching
the spurs lose that one. And um,
and my frustration continues with these
pile on fucking teams. I've come to the,
uh, the acceptance that it is
a new fucking error I guess.
So I'm going to quit whining about it and
obviously all of those guys who won on
Miami could have one in any era,
but it's just,
I hate it cause I don't know how to
compare him to bird magic and all those
other guys because uh,
you know,
cause bird magic and Moses Malone never
hung out on p Diddy's yacht right there
on line of flip flops or whatever the
fuck they would have had back then if it
was like today and uh,
decided that they were all going to
go join the fucking Milwaukee Bucks or
something. So I dunno. So
congratulations also to the Miami Heat.
I don't hate the heat the way,
uh, most Celtics fans to um,
or hate ray Allen.
I mean,
Ray Allen wasn't ours the way Miami got
them. It's the same way we got them.
So I don't know what you crying about.
And as far as the Miami heat go, hey,
good on them.
I mean there,
there are always going to be a fucking
expansion franchise to me. All right,
put that little single digits. Fucking
championships. What are they got three.
Okay.
They got three. Is that what they get?
How many they got? I don't fucking know.
Yeah,
they got three and a,
they might be the next Lakers cause
they bought all three of them.
All right. Enough of my fucking bitch
moaning and complaining and whining.
Um, oh by the way, I did last night.
I don't know if he's posted it yet,
which would be classic Jay more to post
it and then give me shit for not re
tweeting about it. Um, I did Jay
Morris podcast. We had a great time,
uh, about 10, 15 minutes in.
I tried to take them to task about his
it fucking or how I read is a flip and
text message and he fucking took my,
he took my legs out by
immediately apologizing.
Just kind of ended the whole fucking
thing. But uh, you know, it was still,
we still at a great time.
Um, so anyways, what a,
what a fucking week in
the world of sports,
especially in Boston. The
Bruins loser had Greek. Yeah.
Um, doc rivers signs with
the fucking clippers.
Um, I'm, I'm going to believe
in Danny Ainge on this one.
And I'm going to go with the philosophy
that you don't want to pay a coach $7
million a year when he has no chance to
win because you're going to just start
from scratch.
But I got to tell you,
like eventually you're going to need a
doc rivers to take you to the promised
land. You know, the guy
knows how to fucking win.
MMM.
I Dunno. It sounded like, I don't know.
From the couple things that I saw,
it sounded like doc didn't want to go
through a rebuilding thing and the Celtics
wanted to rebuild so they
let him out of his contract.
So thanks to doc rivers and everything
he did for bringing the fuck and shelter
x back. And, uh, I'm going
to believe in Danny angels.
We go through the rebuilding process,
although I hate getting rid of
fucking proven people for draft picks.
I was actually watching it this morning.
I couldn't sleep.
I was so fucking upset about
that loss last night. And, uh,
I put it on the NBA channel and I
was watching the 2001 draft. And,
you know,
it's not the guys that make it.
It's the guys that don't,
that fucking, it just,
I forget who the 76 is picked in 2001,
but he was some 20 year old kid,
you know, supposed to be this
shot, block and phenom. And I,
I never even heard of the guy, not
like I'm the biggest NBA Fan, but uh,
so that's what makes me nervous about
that shit. So, uh, other than that,
what else happened in Boston sports?
Aaron Hernandez.
That story gets sadder and
creepier by the fucking day.
Did you see the guy's house
fucking house? That's it.
You made it,
you kept that house at 20 fucking three.
I would just think he's just sitting in
that house just wishing he could just
rewind his life fucking six days,
you know,
and just stay home and watch
fucking Beethoven part three.
You have to be thinking that unless
you just a complete psycho. But uh,
all this shit is a legend at this point.
But all of his fucking actions,
he's gotta be neck deep in this shit.
Then you turn in your cell phone and it
comes in you like you drove over it with
the fucking car,
you clean your house and then you have a
bunch of people come in and reclean it.
By the way, any cops out there? Any
cops out there? Hey, you know what,
let's let's go against the
grain here. Um, I actually,
long time ago when I was doing
the uninformed show with the, uh,
the teen idol sensation, Joe
to Rosa, we actually had a,
this police officer come in that we
knew through a Gotham comedy club and he
came in and the big thing was,
uh,
me and Joe are going to try both
of us individually, individually.
We're going to try to come
up with the perfect murder.
So we come up with our scenarios where
we bring the cop in and I go to pitch
mine, and this is, this is how far
I got in mind. I go, all right,
so me and a friend of mine, and
then he goes up. That's it. He goes,
you're already caught. And I'm like,
what do you mean I'm already caught?
He goes to second,
you involve somebody else.
He goes, the chances of
getting caught, it's, it's, if,
if mathematically it was
possible to go beyond 100%, um,
that's what you're doing with
that because now you got,
you had just have twice the
chances of somebody rolling over.
Somebody's getting paranoid,
somebody saying the wrong fucking thing,
somebody's feeling guilty.
Somebody leaving some hay is at the
crime scene, the whole fucking thing.
His,
his basic thing was if you have no priors
and you just go out and kill somebody
that you have no connection to, no
connection to and nobody fucking saw it,
you know, how are they going to catch
you? And then the other thing he says is,
do not move the body. He
goes, just leave it there.
He talked, told me a story about
somebody fucking killed somebody.
It felt bad for the dog. So we took the
dog with them or something like that.
And that's how they ended up connecting
them to the crime scene was the dog
hairs. He took the dog and let it go.
Hoping someone would fucking rescue it.
I don't know what,
but they found this,
the dead dudes dog hairs in his fucking
car is, it's over. You know what I mean?
It's fucking over.
How did I get on this subject?
It was just a fucking creepy ass week.
And it Paula Deen running around dropping
the fucking end word ever dental.
He is,
she's making a fucking souffle.
You know I actually met her
one time when I was in Atlanta.
She seemed like a sweetheart. I
told her, I go, you know what? I go,
you cook like my mom. And
she's like, you know what?
That's like the nicest
thing anybody could say.
I don't know what, what
do you do? So now what?
So now your fire and does
that make her less ignorant?
Does that help her say the n word
less when she's baking cookies?
I don't know.
Then you know what?
I think each race should have
like an ambassador. Right?
And when somebody does some shit,
like, like the ambassador just,
they just go out and they go
fishing for a weekend, you know,
and they just sort of talk it out and you
give that person of frame of reference.
So anytime they think it's some
ignorant shit, they go, oh wait,
now what about so and so I went fishing
with, you know, it's not all bad. Right.
Or that guy in ESPN when he said the
stuff about gay people, you know,
God go send them to a musical
and I'll fucking now,
I dunno, but I don't know if the,
the firing thing at Jesus Christ.
Oh, speaking of Jesus.
No, Jj. Did you guys,
uh,
did you guys see that
fucking dude walk on that?
Why all the way across the Grand Canyon?
Did you see that shit?
That was one of the most incredible
fucking things I've ever seen in my life,
in my life. I always have to repeat
that twice when I say in my life.
And you know why that is?
Because I saw,
I watched wife swap a long
time ago and this one family,
they will live in like pirates if
anybody can find this clip for me.
It's one of my favorite clips. This
guy just decided, he, we were all,
his whole family was going to live like
pirates and they dressed like pirates
and arc and they just walked around.
They had no fucking responsibility.
The guy was totally avoiding
being like an adult.
So he worked from home or whatever.
So they'd swap wives.
So his pirate wife leaves and then
incomes like some fucking totally
conservative Nancy Reagan
business suit wearing woman.
And she's just like, no dude, you
need to go get a job or whatever.
So he goes and he does some job filing
and he comes home that day right after
living like a pirate,
he has to put on this monkey suit and
go down and fucking earn a living.
And he comes home and she just
goes, so how was it? And he goes,
that was the worst day of my life.
And she goes, well, you know, and he
goes off my, he screamed at again.
It's fucking great.
So anyways,
getting back to the fuck and ginger
who walked across the wire, dude,
I watched it after cause everybody
kept tweeting me gone bill, Hey,
I'm really rooting for you.
You put on some weight,
but I'm really rooting for you
to walk across the grandkid.
You'd so I kind of heard about it. So I
was already laughing going, all right,
this guy must look like me a little bit.
But anyways,
when I was flying back from New York City,
I watched it and I was,
I was like,
my palms were sweating
watching this fucking guy,
1500 fucking feet in the air with no net,
no lifeline,
know anything.
And he's walking across the wire and
he every step is a thank you Jesus.
Oh, thank you God lord you, Lord,
thank you for getting rid of the wind.
Like this fucking 30 mile an hour wind.
This guy is, and then he's got his
douchebag. Father going, okay, you're uh,
you're one minute and six
seconds and the journey
your one minute and 36 seconds. He led
his dad do this until about minute 18.
And he just finally just goes, Dad, dad,
I don't need you to tell me how long I've
been out here. Like it's fucking arms,
a tired as hell.
It was like slanders getting mad.
Like he couldn't be like dad, but if
I was on the wire back down his truck.
All right, what difference does it
make a fucking long. I'm out here.
What am I going to punch
a clock and fucking go to
sleep and come back tomorrow?
You asshole trying to walk across a wire,
right?
Yeah.
This fucking guy, he's just
sitting there, that's sitting here.
He's walking across doing
like this little slide step.
You know how you would sort of like
insert yourself into a photo to photo bomb
somebody at this.
Do you know that little slide step you do?
He's doing that with these little ballet
slippers on and I gotta tell you I was
interested that he didn't have those
shoes with the little toes on them.
You know, there's creepy fucking things
that just makes you want to just,
you know, it makes your teeth hurt to look
at them. Surprise. He didn't have those.
Maybe it's his case. He had a prom. Make
your luck. His big toe with the, uh,
the index finger or toe. Right.
Hang on like a fucking monkey.
So anyways, he sit in his stepping across
it going, thank you. Fine. Thank you.
Jesus. Jesus. Oh, glory to you.
Thank you. Thank you. Yeah. Away.
At one point he actually sounded like
he was having sex. He was going, yes.
Jesus. Oh Jesus. Right.
I know it was bugging people who aren't
religious. Uh, it didn't bug me at all.
I thought that guy was the shit.
And if you think I wouldn't be out there
talking to every God that I had ever
heard of, I would have.
Except that would've been,
I would've been cursing at the same
time. I would have been. Oh, thank you.
God.
You mother fucker.
I would've been doing that. The
whole fucking work. Thank you. God,
you all of Fargo.
I would be doing that way at some point.
I were to crouch down,
let go of that balancing thing and I
just would have been hanging on to the
fucking wire crying. But
what, what would you do?
Do this no fucking way you could ever
get me to do what that guy is like.
That guy is the shit. I don't even know
his name. I don't even know if his name,
if he's listening for listening to
this, please pray for me. Um, dude,
how is time flying by this fast?
23 minutes in 23 minutes
in on your Tuesday. Um,
all right, let's do us read a of
ads for this week. Everybody. Dude,
I would have been praying
everybody, oh, Buddha, Buddha,
you fat motherfucker just
can't meet across this.
I'd want boulder to be laying down in
the Canon in case I feel like Atlanta on
his fucking stomach.
Do that guy had to deal with like,
I guess if, if, if you, uh,
if you're walking in a rhythm,
which you know is basically,
if you have a consistent gate to how
you're walking, when you're on a wire,
it starts to bounce up and down.
So every once in a while,
I guess you either have to slow it
down, switch it up, or crouched down.
Like this guy was, he paid,
he took a fucking knee.
How you do that on a fucking
cable? I don't know. Um,
I'm actually predicting this that they're
going to start setting up fucking a
little tight ropes at gyms because
it's good for core strength. You know,
somebody will sell out,
analyze that and they'll put it like
literally two feet off the ground with a
bunch of AMF mats all around it.
And you've got to wear a helmet and a
fucking harness and all this shits and
nobody gets sued. You
know, they always do that.
Like somebody does some really like
manly takes balls the size of the Grand
Canyon Shit. And then somebody
turns it into like a workout,
like the boxing workout.
They have like the UFC workout,
we'd do the fucking rope thing,
you know,
when you shaken out those fucking ropes,
doing all this,
the same shit those guys do,
you do everything except fucking get
the balls up to go fight another man,
you know, or woman. Um,
so anyways, you know, I just realized,
you know, that you ever see that,
that that bully beat down
thing, which is really an, it's,
it's a terrible show because the cowards,
they still don't stand up to them.
There's usually two pussies that
the dude's picking on. So it's like,
why don't you teach them how to fight?
They joined forces and then they go in
the ring and they fight the bully. Right?
Why are you sitting there
having them outsourced? They're
nuts. They lack of nuts.
You know what I mean? Download to somebody
else's balls is more, is more, uh,
what they're doing and then he goes in
and he kicks the shit out of them to make
it a little fair. You know, it'd be
great. They should take those, those, uh,
the female ultimate fighters and bring
him into the ring because they can knock
out the average bully. No
problem. And then what's
funny, that's extra humiliated.
All right. That's just an
industry note for that show.
All right, let's get to the,
uh, let's get to the, the
fucking reads here. Uh,
Hulu plus everybody you've tried
streaming hit shows on your PC,
on hulu.com. Haven't you done
that? Well, if you haven't,
why don't you catch up
with the rest of us?
Now it's time to start your free trial
of exclusive content in your living room
and on your mobile devices,
on Hulu plus with Hulu plus,
you get total control to watch
thousands of shows wherever you want,
whenever you want. Use Hulu on
connected TV's, game consoles,
blueray players, a Roku, apple TV, PC,
or watch anywhere on your smartphone
or tablet on demand at all times.
And with Hulu plus you
can binge on full seasons.
What's your favorite current shows?
And even full series runs of classic
TV shows it, it's endless. Personally,
I think this is the new way that
people are going to start watching TV.
You're going to watch it where you want,
wherever you want,
and you're going to watch entire
seasons. Um, there's just so many,
this is like a golden age and television.
I don't know if you
guys have realized this,
but as great as this shows where when
I was coming up in the 70s and eighties
and that type of thing, um,
they, they were nowhere the law.
There was nothing like
breaking bad on television. Um,
nothing like the wire, nothing like
all these, you know, walking dead,
walking dead is like a
Zombie movie every week.
You can watch all of this stuff anywhere
you want with Hulu plus and can get
caught up, you know, so you'll
have to fill out of the loop.
If you go to a party and everybody's
talking about some show you haven't seen
anyways, they got all the
shelves, they got community,
modern family, southpark, SNL,
Jimmy Kim, oh family guy and more.
Hulu plus is only 799 per month,
but right now they're offering an extended
free trial of Hulu plus that is only
available to my podcast.
Listeners.
Take control of your TV watching
experience by going to the podcast page at
[inaudible] Dot Com Click on the Hulu
plus banner for your extended free trial
trial or go to Hulu plus.com/bill and uh,
starting enjoying TV in the buck
Rogers age here and uh, he voice,
hey, what's the reason you're
going to make more money in 2013?
He voices the reason
when your customers call,
you'll have your own toll free number
of professional grading dial by name
directory and more.
You'll sound like a fortune 500
company and blow away your competitors.
Eve Voice lets you give out one number
that rings wherever you are, the beach,
the bath, doesn't matter. You'll
sound like you're at the office.
You got to go to [inaudible] dot com and
use the Promo Code Bill Evos even takes
all your voicemails,
transcribes them and sends them to
you instantly as a text or an email,
however you want it done so he can check
your voicemails before the meeting ends
and not look rude. Ie voice is
only 10 bucks a month. Right now,
my listeners get a free
trial of a voice for 30 days.
Stop what you're doing right now.
Hit pause and sign up for your e voice
free trial and see what I'm talking about.
It's a great way to support my podcast
and an easy way to make more money this
year.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com Promo Code Bill.
That's [inaudible] dot
com promo code build.
Or just go to the podcast
page on billboard.com and
click on the voice banner
right now. All right, back to
the podcast. Everybody. Um,
oh, you know what I've
been doing here? I didn't,
I didn't mention this to you guys.
I've been trying to become a
little more worldly. I'm trying to,
I'm trying to learn all the, all the
countries in the capitals. Oh Jesus.
Um, I got, I can do the
Middle East and all of Europe.
Europe's a motherfucker when you get to
the, uh, when you get to Eastern Europe,
cause once checklists of Aki
and Yugoslavia splintered
into like seven or eight
different fucking countries,
you know what I mean? Just Shit.
You never really hear about like,
uh,
what are some of the ones over that?
I'll fucking enough.
I don't even have it in front of me.
I'm still trying to memorize them.
But what I did learn there was some, I was
just like, what the fuck is San Marino?
San Marino,
capitol San Marino.
And then you had like VAD, VAD, dues,
Lichtenstein, and everybody over here.
It makes fun of Lichtenstein. I remember
growing up everybody, cause it's,
it was like Beavis and butthead shit.
Like as the word lick is in there,
what are you doing? Their fucking liquid
shy, you know, stupid shit like that.
Um,
evidently there's like five
sovereign states in the world,
uh, or cities, whatever
the fuck you call them.
And they kind of exist as
their own little entities.
Okay.
And uh, that sounds, if you got the
money to live there, they're great.
The tax rate is low. It's like
Vatican City. Liechtenstein
Monaco,
I think Singapore and then something
else that begins with an m.
Yeah.
I don't know if it's Malta, I don't
know this, this, this five of them.
Okay.
And I got to tell you like
I would love if they have,
if they ever came up with
this show called, uh,
the money trail or blood
money or something.
I can't imagine how much is oozing
out of those fucking places.
Vatican city goes without saying.
All right.
That just goes without fucking saying.
You can't imagine what goes
on in that city. Right.
Considering the pope quit, even when
the pope's just like, listen guys,
I can't be the spokesperson for this shit
anymore. Um, and interestingly enough,
you never hear anything
about Lichtenstein.
You never hear anything about fucking
Monaco other than the fucking Grand Prix.
And it's just a bunch of rich countries
over there tagging fucking top shelf
ass.
Yeah.
Like fucking a third of their goddamn age.
You know, how do I get into that
party? That's what I want to know.
Hey, by the way, did you guys see shit
is heating up between China and Japan?
They're going to, maybe they're going to
go at it over some islands and you know,
it would be great as a citizen
of the United States here,
you don't have to be phenomenal.
If we just stayed the fuck out of it,
you know,
we just stayed the fuck out of it and
he just just got to watch this renewed
rivalry. Oh rivalry. That goes
way back to the beginning of time.
All kinds of great fucking
games they add back in the day,
you know, Japan ran up the
score and Nan King, right?
The rape and Nan King, there's a of
bad blood between the two of them.
This is like when the Celtics and Lakers,
like rivalry went dormant throughout
the 90s and then it came back with a
vengeance.
So I think from what I've,
the looks like eventually giant in Japan,
China,
which is just a fucking
environmental disaster.
The biggest mistake they fucking
make, they would just like, look,
we're going to have so
many God damn people.
If you ever decide to attack this country,
there's just gonna be wave after wave
after wave of fucking human beings coming
over the fucking hell.
Right.
Did they not know about nuclear weapons?
You know,
you just were one person can just
kind of end the world. I mean, why,
why didn't they just go that route?
This part of the podcast is
called in way over his head,
Bill Byrd discussing world events without
really reading up on him. Everyone.
Um, so anyways, yeah, I can do all
the capitals or the Middle East.
It's great. Then you'll hear world knows
you kind of know where shit is. You know,
like I didn't know that the Czech Republic
was tucked right in between that like
a Poland and Germany, like West
Virginia, between Ohio and Pennsylvania.
You see that I use something normal,
something that I could relate to.
Hey Bill, why don't you shut the fuck up
and read a question for this week? Okay,
I could do that. Oh, by the way,
the email is bill@themmpodcast.com.
If you want to send it in an email,
let me know.
What's the most embarrassing thing that
one of your home teams does that makes
you uh,
wanna either choke somebody in the front
office or punch the fan next to you
cause they're participating. I'd love
to hear it. All right. Butte, Montana,
Billy boy. Uh, when, when you were on your
red state tour, stop and check out Butte,
Montana. Um, I'm excited for your
upcoming show in Bozeman, Montana.
I happened to live about an
hour west of Bozeman in Butte.
That's just a great fucking, that's
a perfect name for a city in Montana.
Butte, Montana. Beaut.
Where are y'all from? Butte.
Butte won't panel.
I ain't got time for two syllables.
I gotta go man.
The fence.
You'll always a southern accent if the
fucking most northern part of the country
actually may not. I'm
sorry. Alaska is all right.
You're fucking geographical cut there.
Uh,
when you're making the
drive from Boise to Bozeman,
you will have to drive through
Butte, Butte, Montana. You're, uh,
you're driving through at a great time
to stop for the afternoon and check it
out.
We have a beauty.
We have beautiful old architecture
in old and new giant minds.
Older new giant minds. You're mining
for giants. The fuck does that mean
huge minds? I don't know
anything about mine. Sorry sir.
Talking shop there and he goes,
and the day of your show,
it will be evil Knievel day.
I gotta go.
Well, the day of the show might
be cutting it a little bit close.
We got to stop in. Anybody can get a
picture with an Elvis impersonator.
I've never seen an even evil Knievel.
Putin Personator I want I wanna.
You know what sir? I might, I
might, uh, I might check that out.
Why am I saying everything fucking twice.
Get the papers, get the papers. I might,
I might, I might check it out there.
They're the up, uh, the uptown.
I've got to do it again now.
My fucking myself.
The uptown is filled with daredevil
stunts, booze, good food and crazies.
Something I thought you guys
might like to check out.
Probably get a good story out of it.
At least. Can't wait for the show.
Fucking and
I gotta tell you I love
those kinds of places.
I love going to these places that are
considered the middle of fucking nowhere
and checking out, uh, you know,
the architect texture here in all the
fucking, uh, history of the places,
seen what they do for fun.
I've never heard of an evil Knievel day.
I'm assuming he's from that area.
Beer, Butte, Montana, evil Knievel,
the size of balls he had,
he would have fucking g would have
driven his fucking motorcycle.
They weighed like 10,000 fucking pounds
in the early seventies he would have
driven it right across that wire,
you know,
with some sort of shoot
that came out too early.
Knock that Jesus freak right off the
fucking wire. Oh, thank you Jesus.
Oh that step was in your
name. Oh, glory to you,
God for making these dancing slippers.
Marrying too young.
Doris billing. Billing's worth
the Reddington. I liked that one.
I would have just gone with
Billingsworth Redington you know what?
If I ever moved to Lichtenstein, that's
going to be my name, my fake name.
When I tried to hide my blood money,
you know,
because one day I go to a show and I sell
the DVDs and I take pictures first and
I take the door and they take all the
fucking march money and then I just don't
do a show. And then I'm going to relocate
to Lichtenstein and I'm going to go buy
Billingsworth Reddit,
Billingsworth Reddington and I'm going
to have a fucking pocket watch. And a,
and a little spectacle spectacle. What
do you call that? A little fucking,
not a gargoyle. What do you call that
thing? A cyclops. What do you call it?
Thing when you gotta you gotta fucking a
bifocal now by means to not a trifocal,
uh, sing a unit. Unifocal
I'm going bicycle here. Hey,
how many more wing walkers are going
to die? I didn't know people were,
were fucking wing walking.
I didn't know that.
Still fucking existed in like three of
them died. See bad things happening.
Trade. Now you start over at
three. Keep counting them.
I bet thousands of wing walkers have died.
Bad things happen when you walk out on
a wing. You superstitious. Cons. Um,
eight bill, am I getting
married too young? Well,
never gotten married, so I don't know.
I don't know what to tell you. Uh,
but I will read this.
I'm 25 and live with my girlfriend.
She's great.
Pretty and things are going very well.
I've dated her for four years and she's
by far the longest relationship I've
ever had.
She's from a somewhat traditional family
where people get hitched and their
early twenties.
Dude,
where the fuck do you live that you're
25 and you use the word hitched from
Butte?
Me and my girl getting hitched going to
have the wedding out there in the barn.
You know,
figured,
figured we'd she could get
dressed up there in the loft.
I'd stay down here next to the horses.
You know,
we ain't gonna have no mute a music.
Don't want to spook anybody in
any animals here in a barn. Right.
And they're not consummate
the relationship over there
and that stack of shit
just fucking knock her
out right over there.
Okay.
Um, God, just go there.
Cornhusker sorry. Let's,
let's stick with the fucking letter here.
I'm in Dayton for her for four years.
Uh, but, but Bob, people usually get
hitched. Where the hell am I? Um,
and because we dated for a
while and I lived together,
I already feel pressure from her and her
family to pop the question. Oh, Jesus.
Yeah, yeah. You know, you're fucking,
you've been with her for four years in
the middle of nowhere where they say
hitched surprise, they're not coming
down there to have some sort of exorcism.
Anyways,
he says,
I'm conflicted as I totally agree with
you on the whole drafting and the first
round idea.
Oh that's my whole theory.
You don't want to wait to get married
too long or else you're going to fucking,
you know, all the good, all the
good draft picks had gone. Um,
or what you do is you, you, you
pick up someone who's proven like,
but has had a problem like a Randy
Moss type of chick, you know.
Well,
you know,
it's going to be good for a couple of
seasons before she fucking tries to run
over the mailman with the car
or something. I Dunno. He goes,
I've had a great time with her
family and she does with mine. Do,
do you love this girl? He goes, hello.
Marriage is a scary
concept to a young guy.
It's not much more than what the situation
I'm currently living in with her.
I probably have a Peyton manning on my
hands and I can see my single friends
holding out for a Shannon shap or a Tom
Brady in the sixth or seventh rounds and
it seems too risky.
I see them chasing mediocre girls around
while I'm going scuba diving and biking
with my girl. However, I'm still a young
guy. I haven't dated that many girls in.
It seems like it would be fun to have
random sex with some pretty ladies and my
city. My girl is awesome, but I
have a penis. Thus the conflict,
that's one of the truest things
you'll ever hear. He goes, all right,
I look forward here.
And your advice saw you
kill it up in Boston and you
have more hair in your head.
Then you think you do. Ah, that Nice.
It's fallen out by the day
by the second. Um, all right,
let's go back here. What does he
say here? Uh, you know what sir?
You say a bunch of Nice things about it,
but I never hear you say that you're
crazy about her or that you love her.
You know,
I think that that was the biggest thing.
I think maybe that's why you'd have more
of a wandering eye rather than the fact
that you just have a dick.
Um, if you love this girl,
I would get married
sooner rather than later.
You know,
every guy that I know that ever got
married and married the right one always
said it's the smartest thing I ever did.
All right.
You don't want to grow up like me.
All right?
You don't want to still be out there
drinking fucking whiskey, you know,
looking like the owner of
the bar rather than a patron.
Okay.
MMM. Yeah. The like, look,
you're asking me one of the
most important decisions in your life.
Who Do I marry?
Should I marry this person? Um, I
would ask myself these questions. Uh,
does all right, are you in
love with this girl? This is,
is this the one? Is this the mother
your kids? If, if the answer's yes,
then by all means get on with it.
If the answer's no,
then man up break up with her by a fucking
year supply with the condoms and uh,
go have some fun. That's my
advice. How was that sir?
I'm fluoride conspiracy.
William,
I just listened to you and
to Rosa on uninformed. Oh,
our old talk show comes up again.
Talk about fluoride in the drinking water.
I've reached,
I've researched this for some time along
with the other conspiracies and it's
true fact is there are independent
researchers from all around the globe that
I've done study after
study on sodium fluoride.
Now they all found the same thing.
Sodium fluoride damages,
soft tissue including brain cells.
Well,
you know what I've learned with all this
shit after years of being a conspiracy
theorist is you have to,
you have to then research the researchers
and it just becomes way too much
fucking work. And I just, after a while,
just put my head down and
go as just gimme a bacon,
egg and cheese and just get
off my fucking day here. Um,
that's like somebody tweeted
me, said, uh, some scientists,
sometimes some sciences say that
redheads are going to be extinct by 2060.
I love that. Some scientists
say, what scientist,
what else did they say?
My buddy just had a red headed lady.
Now I had already had a baby.
Um,
okay,
what last year
in 2012 so in 2060,
that baby God willing,
we'll be 48 years old.
So like I've said,
unless you people who keep
sending me this shit about the,
the complete extinction,
um,
the final solution for
fucking redheads by, you know,
within 40 fucking years essentially,
uh,
you might want to look into
your research a little more.
You might want to research the researchers
unless you have some sort of plan
that I don't fucking know about.
All right.
Yeah.
Jesus.
I just pictured myself hiding with a
bunch of other red heads with some fucking
brunettes sympathizer,
you know,
sitting in the wall like
some old Anne Frank.
Um, anyways, what are we talking
about here? Sodium fluoride.
All right.
As well as bone.
It doesn't really matter if you switch
toothpaste and buy bottled water because
sodium fluoride can be absorbed topically.
One study stated that dental fluorosis,
which is slowly sodium fluoride,
was proposed by the u s
government to reduce reduced what?
Brag, I'm guessing cavities.
You left that out, uh,
is in fact up to a lot higher in Florida.
A water supply areas. What happened there?
What happened with this whole point?
One study stated that dental fluorosis
is in fact up to a lot higher in
fluoridated water supply areas.
Yeah,
that's a fragment sir, isn't it? Or is
it the way I'm reading it? What am I,
what word people am I not emphasizing
that's making this sentence makes sense in
my head as I hear it.
Um,
keep in mind that they get the
sodium fluoride from smokestacks,
scrub it and acid then sell it to
the municipal water supply companies.
They haven't produced one studies to
suggest it does anything remotely close to
what they claim.
It does not even a study to combat the
other studies that are done almost every
year by various independent
researchers from around the world. Um,
yeah, I mean, I dunno. I don't fucking, I
don't even know what's sodium fluoride is.
I don't fucking know what it is.
Do I want the scum from inside of
a fucking smokestack on my teeth?
I probably don't. I'd be willing to
say that that does more harm than good.
You know what,
sir?
Why don't you take that fucking email
and send it to a smart podcast to a
podcast that's fucking smart.
Why don't you do that?
Is there a science one
couple of guys in lab coats
sweating in their lab coats,
podcasting. I don't know. Fucking it.
Here we go. William Burp. How do I
come to terms with being average?
Well, let me tell you, sir,
you're asking the right guy. Um,
love everything you do. Coming to see
your show on August 23rd at the MGM.
That's right.
I'm going to be at the MGM and Foxwoods,
Connecticut on August 23rd all in,
by the way,
I have a super secret,
very special show that I'm going to be
doing at the end of August. All right.
I'm teasing it right now
with another comedian
that is way beyond me or my abilities
and I've always wanted to work with them
and I reached out to them and we're going
to do a co headlining show where you
ask, I'm not saying shit
until tickets go on sale.
When you ask,
I told you towards the
end of August why bill?
Why are you doing this?
You Ass?
Because I'm learning from other radio
guy ship kind of put half the information
out there.
You get everybody at the end edge of their
seats and then the fucking Black Hawk
score two goals on you and it's over.
Sorry.
How do I come to terms that I just won't
be financially successful to the point
where money is not an
issue. Jesus Christ. Dude,
that that just made me feel sad. Why
would you, why would you think that?
All right. I guess going to go
into detail as to why he goes,
I'm 30 held many technical positions
in the corporate ladder at a few big
companies. It is everything
office space made it out to be,
which has driven me to file patents or
ideas and improvements as well as start a
few side businesses that didn't seem to
really take flight. Well, there you go,
sir.
Yeah,
you know you're, you're, you're,
you're basing your self worth
on other people employing you.
All right. God knows I got enough shit
on my podcast. He voice legal zoom,
stamps.com all of that shit for you to
run a fucking side business while you're
holding down your job at this corporate
nightmare that you don't want to be and
believe in your talents.
Dude,
you think I just walked on stage and
tried three fucking jokes and then it
worked.
I bombed for fucking years.
For years and years and years,
like almost
the first 11 years of my career,
I swear to God.
Every time I went on stage
it was a crapshoot whether
it was going to go well or
not.
It was even longer than that.
It's basically once you start selling
tickets and people come out to your show
that the bombing goes way down and it
also makes you softer as a comic because
people are coming out to see you.
They give you a giant ovation as you go
out there, they're already on your side.
It's a home game. All right? Before
you sell tickets as a comedian,
every night is a fucking away game and
it's a rivalry game and they fucking hate
you.
All right?
Okay,
so I think you're a really talented guy.
I think you know what?
A lot of smart people, slightly
depressed, which is what the,
how this is reading and dude,
you just got to get yourself,
force yourself to pick yourself up off
the mat and throw yourself against the
wall. All right? That's what not
yourself. Sorry. Stupid idea.
Don't myself against the wall.
Whatever idea you got,
just keep putting it out there.
All right?
And you pat and all those fucking things
and you get yourself a goddamn lawyer.
So when these corporate come sniffing
around and they want to dangle some carrot
in front of you,
you make sure you get as much as that
carried as humanly fucking possible.
All right.
Is it donkey really that dumb that it
just keeps walking towards that carrot?
Is it looking at it like it's a mountain?
Like wow,
it's just way off in the distance,
you know?
Is the donkey sitting there praying to
it's God as it just keeps [inaudible]
thank you. What? What? What the fuck
would that God be? Can't say Jesus off.
Piss them off. Yeah. So we told me that
day. Why don't you make fun of Muslims?
You Pussy.
Right?
Okay.
I made fun of my own fucking religion.
All right.
I stay within my wheelhouse.
I make fun of what the fuck.
I know you heard me try to
talk about Eastern Europe.
I don't know shit about it embarrasses me.
I know anything about Muslims other than,
than they throw down the yoga mat every
day around four o'clock when all the
stoners start getting baked, they're
actually talking to their higher power,
which is my hour pi or power.
And it's your higher,
we're all praying to the same
fucking vibe, that same spirit,
you know,
so fucking ridiculous.
And everybody's got to
do it their own way.
Now you've got to fucking tap your elbows
twice before you did it and you didn't
do that. So now I'm going to
saw your fucking head off. Yeah.
In payable, people still show up and give
it money and put on a silly hat. Right.
Who's getting home?
Anytime I think I'm going to die,
I always start praying and I pray to
the God that I was told, you know,
I say a prayer,
I say a prayer every time my plane takes
off and ripped Fort Lance every fucking
time, say a prayer that it
doesn't fucking crash. You know?
And when I think about it crashing,
I know exactly what I would say
to a higher power. I'm sorry.
Okay.
All right.
And then it'll be like,
when I die and I go and get judged
and he's like, sorry for what?
And it just fits. You know what your way
Lord Buddha, whatever the hell you are.
A just straight as straight
across the board. Sorry
for Dell. Dell. Yeah. All of it.
The whole fucking kitten caboodle,
other than 8% of it, the
other 92%. I'm just sorry.
I knew it was wrong.
I know what I was doing.
I tried to pull myself out of the muck
and I just, I was too weak a person,
you know, which baby that's on you
because you didn't fucking, you know,
you put a four cylinder in me,
you know,
instead of giving me enough fucking
horsepower mentally to pull myself out of
the ditch. Yeah. Yeah. Blaming.
You want some way? Get Out.
You made me, you know the fuck.
If I made a car and it didn't run,
I'm going to blame the car. Ah,
Dad, do what you gotta do. Whatever.
Sorry. Anyways, back to
this year. Um, he goes,
I work 50 to 60 hours a week,
feeling burnt while trying
my last side business, uh,
with no time but work. I'm about
to realize, fuck it. Don't,
don't, don't quit. Do
not quit. He goes, uh,
he's about ready to say,
fuck. It just won't be me.
I won't be the guy with the lake house
or a guy who can buy cars with the
briefcase of money or a guy with 22
year olds on his arm at 40 all right,
now you're scaring me dude.
I thought you would.
Just some guy that you know wanting to,
you know,
wanting to invent something and feel
good about himself, but you sound like,
okay,
don't you? Oh you want to move
up in your company? Tell him,
tell him that the end of your
corporate fucking a company.
They're just tell him
that that's what you want.
Okay.
Just walk in and just say, listen,
this is what I want. A house by a lake.
I want to buy vintage cars with a
briefcase full of money that nobody knows
where it came from and I
want some 22 year asshole,
22 year old ass on my arm the
whole my whole fucking life.
I just want to keep trading them in.
You know like that guy lived across the
street who got the new corvette every
year cause he worked for Chevy.
Right?
You tell him that shit,
they're going to love it because
they're going to be like,
this guy is a fucking sociopath.
He doesn't want to find love. He doesn't
want to make the world a better place.
He wants to go out there and get his,
that's great.
He wants a house by a lake.
We'll get a house by a lake and we'll
give them the chemicals to dump into it.
That's okay.
You want that house by Lake.
You got to take our fucking
waste and dumping in that
Goddamn Lake. All right. No.
Yeah. I want you to practice shrugging
your shoulders. Oh, I dunno. I got down.
I want to, we want to see that you're
going to be able to do that. All right.
And if you get caught,
you got to take the fall.
Walk up to that podium over there.
Let me, let me see you just improvise.
Taking the fall. We're going to throw
out a couple of scenarios. All right.
Just relax. Yeah, we got, we got a glass
of water up there. You have a drink
or generic. Okay. All
right. First scenario. Um,
fucking Sheryl crow somehow gets behind
some can't that figures out that we have
three year olds, uh, making the
pampers down there in Honduras.
All right. We need you
to take the fall. Go. Ah,
yeah. Um, okay. Uh,
it's come to our attention
that some of our, uh,
practices in the a undergarment infant
under garment industry have come into
question. Um, we are looking into it.
I accept full responsibility.
The buck stops with me.
Okay.
A Dye.
I'm the head of that division.
I don't like babies. I, I'm
sorry. I don't, I don't know
where to go. I have fuck it.
Fuck you. And you're like,
that isn't good. That was bad.
And we could see a sweat from over here.
Go back to your cubicle.
Yeah,
that's like parole. That's like a parole
hearing in a corporate office. You don't,
they bring in once every seven years
and they see how good you are lying.
And if you're not fucking good at it,
they send you back to the whole back. Gee,
a cubicle. It's like
reverse Shawshank. Um,
anyways, let's plow ahead here. So this
disguise depressed in the shit out of me.
He's given up on his dream and he
wants young bitches on his fucking arm.
I don't know what to do with this guy.
He goes,
I'm starting to think I need to accept
the corporate grind for the next 35 years
or the whole life is going to pass me
by spending all my free time trying to
start something.
Your thoughts,
it wouldn't be right unless I n ended
this way. Thanks. And Go fuck yourself.
All right. I don't think you're that bad
a guy, sir. I'm just fucking with you. Uh,
all right. Don't quit. All right.
Don't quit it. You could.
If you quit on yourself,
nobody's going to believe in you. It's
going affect your entire fucking life.
You can't fucking quit ever.
You never quit unless you wrong.
You know if you fucking rock,
but then what you do is you just
go in another direction. That's all
right.
Like, let's say you always
wanted to be a singer,
but he's saying like me at some point,
you got to have that honest moment and
be like, I have a fucking stick at this.
But it, who's to say that you're,
you're not a good producer.
You couldn't record singers,
you know,
or you couldn't manage singers or you
couldn't go down to the church choir and
just lip sync and act like you were
singing, right? I'll get a sex change,
right? And turn yourself in
some hot piece of ass and be,
get to the top of the pop charts.
There's always a way,
sir. And I'm not saying to get a sex
change. I'm not saying not to get one.
All right?
Just listen to me here.
Just fucking keep. Don't fucking give up
on that shit. That's, you know what it is.
That's your passion.
Your passion is what you're doing when
you're not working 50 to 60 hours a week.
All right?
And the reason why this is coming off so
depressing is because your heart is in
that.
And this voice is getting louder every
day saying you don't have what it takes
and you need to quit. I'd been there as
a fucking comic. It's the fucking worse.
It hits you, hits you right in the chest.
All right? You got to push through that.
All right.
What I do is I come up with new jokes
and I go even harder the next show.
So that's what you gotta do.
You gotta come up with a new Flowbee,
a new George Foreman Grill,
a new fucking iPad.
Whatever the hell you're working on,
you got to go even harder, right?
And someday you'll have a podcast and
you'll repeat shit nine times in a row and
you'll mispronounced stuff,
right?
And you'll have a house by a lake.
I don't have a house by a lake,
but I had one come through my fucking
rough three months ago. Sorry.
All right, sir. Don't quit. That
will crush me. No one that you quit.
There's your halftime speech. Do not ever
fucking give up on yourself. All right.
What I would do if I was
in your fucking situation.
I would quit the corporate job first.
I would,
I would downsize my life.
Okay.
All right. You got to make the
sacrifices. Downsize your fucking life.
Take a job that pays less with less hours.
Live with less.
Do you need all those fucking tee shirts?
Do you need all that shit?
Yeah.
Do you need a laptop? Do you need
an iPad to do you need a mini iPad?
Do you need every new fucking
cell phone yet? Don't you don't.
How many fucking glasses can you
drink out of at once? One baby toe.
If you joined in a Frat,
right?
You drink out of one reality is sue.
I'll eat one bowl.
One plate, one fork, one knife,
one spo. You know you could
have all your shit. Yeah,
you need a fucking, you need a
bed. You need a to, you need a TV.
You gotta see you gotta stay in touch,
right?
Cause you've got to see what's out there.
What they're selling for 1995 but other,
other than that,
what do you,
what do you mean
nothing?
You don't need shit.
So downsides,
you fucking life have a fucking
yard sale, sir. And with that money,
you know,
go by whatever the fuck it is you need
to buy to invent some shits you can get
out of there. All right? But by all
means, do not accept this as your faith.
It isn't you just,
you're doing your open mics like I did.
And you know what? A lot of people fucking
quit. I don't know what they're doing.
Okay, but are they doing standup in a
parking lot in an air condition tent,
Rhode Island next month
like I am? No, they are not.
All right. You know what I'm saying? Man,
I hope that that fucking pumped you up.
Don't fucking quit or raw that don't
make me sad. You want to make me sad?
You fucking cunt. I don't even know
you and you're making me sad. Stop it.
All right. Smoking problems.
Hey Bill. What's up? Nothing
much. What's up? Yo Dope.
Uh, my husband, yes, I'm a lady. Oh, I
love when a woman writes in. Finally,
maybe if I wasn't such a Dick Moore
would write in my husband. Yes,
I'm a lady introduced me to your podcast
last year and we both think you're
awesome. Well that's great. Uh,
we've been together for nearly 17 years
and have two young children together.
I'm hoping that you can do something
using your unique sense of humor and
perspective that I um,
all right.
Did I have been unable to do after
years of nagging and that is to try and
convince him to quit smoking.
Uh, you know something.
I don't consider that naggy.
You're trying to save his fucking life.
Okay.
All right. She says, I know you,
you like to look after your health and
he really respects what you have to say.
I want them to be healthy,
not just for his own sake,
but so he's around for a long time for
myself and the kids when we retire in 30
years or so,
I want us to have health and money to
travel the world and enjoy ourselves after
a lifetime of working.
Okay. Cigarettes are
incredibly expensive in Australia,
around $20 a pack and are only
set to get more expensive.
This happens costs thousands every
year. Thanks for your help. Bill.
Please never stop doing it. You're doing,
oh, that's nice. You're welcome. Um,
oh, she says Australia next. Come
to new castle just north of Sydney.
Go Fuck Yourself. Uh, well listen,
if I'm jumping on a 14 hour flight,
you can't come one down, one
fucking city south for me. Listen,
next year I'm doing Perth to Sydney.
All right.
I guarantee it. Or else I'll go on
youtube and I apologize. Like Paula Dane.
Um, I, I'm sorry that are
never came out to Australia.
Okay.
Uh, all right. You guys sound
like you're pretty young still,
and that's just the thing. You think
you've got to fucking live forever.
And I'll tell you what I have learned now
that I'm in my forties, unfortunately,
is once you hit 40,
it's no joke. All right?
When you hit 40, whatever you've,
whatever you've been doing.
Yeah.
Since you started being a
knucklehead in your teenage years,
starts to take, not even take
root, it starts to blossom.
It comes to fruition, if you will. All
right? If you've kept yourself in shape,
okay.
And any Vieten healthy,
you know,
you go back to your high school reunion
and people tell you how great you look.
All right.
If you've been eating like a fucking
maniac and smoking and all that type of
shit in your forties,
unfortunately I've learned the hard
way is when people start to die.
You know, there's nothing funny about
this shit. Look at, look at, uh,
uh,
James Gandolfini.
Okay.
You know,
that fucking guy was doing what I've done,
but he was just doing it too much.
You don't want we all doing over and
indulging. Everybody does that. I mean,
I shouldn't say this like I fucking know,
but like,
okay,
you know,
I've lost way too many fucking friends,
way too many friends in the
business and outside the business.
I'm telling you when,
you know,
and this isn't to tell your
husband to wait till these 40.
Yeah.
Uh,
basically from what I've read is your
body is designed to go 150 years.
That's how great your body is. And
that's how fucked up the environment is.
And the amount of shit that
you're going to encounter,
that it has to start counting down to
one 50 just so you can make it to 70 or
80. All right? And there's
already enough shit,
enough wear and tear enough crap.
Forget about all the manmade radiation,
fucking radio waves and all this shit.
What the fuck we're putting in our food?
There's already enough shit out there
that can get you and you're just,
you're basically, you're in the fast lane
and you're gonna die. You are basically,
you're going to die or you're
going to have fucking emphysema.
This is what got me to never fucking
smoke. When I was in fifth grade,
this guy came to the school and he said,
if you want to know what it's like to
have emphysema, he goes, make a fist.
So you make a fist and you,
oh shit.
What did I just do there?
Huh?
Yeah.
I turned down the fucking volume. Sorry
about that. I just stepped on my mixer.
Um, he basically said, he
said, make a fist. All right,
this is hilarious. This is
what you're, tell your husband.
Just say and this just say,
hey honey, do me a favor.
Make it like you're going to
mind like you're sucking a dick.
Yeah,
that's what you do.
You know what's funny is the amount of
people who are in cubicles right now
looking over their shoulder because
they want to see the emphysema thing.
Bring it right up to your mouth. Now that
I did the Dick thing, every guy stopped.
But they'll do it when they're
home alone tonight. You know,
they'll turn up the TV and bring
down the curtains and we'll try.
Basically you try to
breathe into your fist,
try to draw it in through your mouth,
through your fist.
That's according to this guy what it was
like to have emphysema and that's which
that's what you're headed towards.
I don't know if you guys have a daughter.
I mean what if,
what if you're not around to make sure
she doesn't marry some Douche bag?
What if the guy is a dick?
But you're so frail at that fucking point
cause you can't do a pull up anymore
and you got that little fucking wheelie
walker thing and you're coming in with
the oxygen tank and the
shit up you fucking nose.
Okay.
You know,
I'm telling you all of that shit.
People start getting those a gin blossoms
on their nose right around 40 all of
it, all of it. Fucking comes,
comes to a head at 40 but if
you take care of yourself,
if you keep yourself in shape in your
twenties and your thirties and that type
of thing, it it, it,
it pays off fucking 10 fold and
considering you have kids, man, you, you,
you, you, you owe it to them,
you owe it to them. All right?
Jesus wasn't this just sort
of a feel good podcast.
You'd think I'd be more of
a concept and my team lost.
Yeah.
All right. I got one more read here and
then I'm going to close out the podcast,
a stamps.com everybody
I've told you about this,
I've been trying to teach you guys how
you don't have to go to the post office
anymore. All right? You only have
so many seconds on this earth.
Why would you want to spend any more
time standing in line? Then you have to,
alright,
stamps.com have you by you.
There's nothing instant about getting
posted from the post office driving there
parking there.
It's really a waste of time when something
like stamps.com is around because you
can instantly get postage for any letter
or package right from your own desk.
stamps.com is so quick and easy to use,
even a more unlike making use it by and
print official us postage using your own
computer or a printer,
stamps.com we'll send you a digital
scale that automatically calculates the
exact postage you need.
They'll even help you the best class
of mail based on your personal needs.
No guesswork. Plus it's convenient. Take
care of your mailing and shipping where?
Wherever, oh, excuse me. Whenever you
need to 24 seven right from your own desk,
you'll never need to go
to the post office again.
I use stamps.com to send out all
my DVDs to all my gigs right now.
We've got a special offer.
Use My last name for a no risk trial
plus $110 bonus offer that includes a
digital scale and up to $55 free postage.
All right?
You're getting this for free and they're
giving you 55 bucks and he'd get a
little scale, a little meda, a don't
wait. Go to stamps.com right now.
Before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburbborrthatstamps.com
and
enter burr and a you'll never have to
go to the post office again. All right?
Unless you're one of those Weirdos
that collect stamps, right?
I feel you could collect stamps.
She also have like a butterfly collection.
You've got them pinned to that thing,
that little fucking needlepoint thing.
How creepy are human beings? Has just
wanting to continue looking at them,
but they fly away, so I had pinned
him to the fucking board. Um,
all right. Is there anything
else I need to talk about? Oh,
next month everybody tickets are on sale.
They're going fast,
and you people have told
me for the longest time,
please come out to the middle of fucking
nowhere. Well, guess what? God dammit,
I'm coming out to the middle of nowhere.
How am I doing that on the Billy red
face tore red state towards, sorry.
And my website is down again.
What the fuck?
What the fuck do I have to do
to get this fucking website?
Not The fucking go down every
God damn fucking three days.
All right. I got a phone call
to make everybody, that's
the podcast for this week.
I was going to tell you where I was going
to be. You know, I don't fucking know.
The weekend of July 12th I'm going
to be at the Cape Cod Melody Tent.
That's where I saw George Carlin.
I saw him before it was ever a comedian.
And here it is 25 years later,
I'm going back to perform there.
So if you think that I'm not going to
give you a fucking show that night. Well,
let me tell you something.
You're about ready to see a show that I,
it should be under a fucking big top.
I'm gonna bring elephants
to that fucking show. Um,
now it's going to be a very special
night and if you'd like to come down and
share it with me, I would
love to have you there. Um,
next I'm going to be up, uh, that
same weekend I'm going to be at the,
uh, Nantucket yachting center, the
air condition tent in the parking lot,
just trying to be on an honest,
and then I'm going to be up in a,
at the Hampton Beach Ball Room Casino.
That's where I'm going to be that weekend
of July 12th and playing two tents in
an attic. Everybody see what happened,
sir? Working in the corporate world,
when you follow your dreams, um,
you get to play intense and addicts.
And, uh, then later on that month,
I have the Billy red state tour that
starts in Boise, Idaho, goes to Bozeman,
Montana, deadwood, South
Dakota, Colorado Springs,
Colorado, Wichita, Kansas. I got another
Colorado date in there. Tulsa, Oklahoma.
Ends up the whole thing,
wraps up in El Paso, Texas.
I'm going to be with the New Jersey's own,
Paul Versey and a Rosebowl
Cook and legend and number one,
Cleveland Fan. Jason Law had,
uh, we're going to be on the bus,
will come to your town.
I got this fucking sick ass tee shirt
that I'm making that has an old Ford f 100
on it. Then I'm only
selling on the tour. Um,
it's going to be a great time and tickets,
like I said,
they're flying right out of the venues.
So like I said,
I never go to these places,
so if you want to see me,
please go and get tickets now. All
right, that's the podcast for this week.
If you'd like to help out
this podcast financially, um,
please visit [inaudible] dot com when
it's fucking up and running and click on
the podcast page. And, um,
you'll see the Amazon banner,
you click on that and you go
to amazon.com anything you buy,
they'll kick me a little bit of
money for sending traffic their way.
And I take a portion of those proceeds
and I give it to the wounded warriors
project.
Also,
this hard copy versions of my latest
special available on my website,
a hardcopy and downloadable.
If you want to get a hard copy version,
bring it out to a show.
I'll autograph it,
take a picture and all that shit cause
I appreciate you buying it and I got a
garage full of those fucking things.
All right, that's the podcast.
Everybody got blushes. Go Fuck
Yourself. I'll talk to you next week.
Okay, now that the show's over, don't
forget us to support our sponsors.
Go to go to,
set up the free trial of he voice.
Join thousands of entrepreneurs who use
their voice, personal receptionist 24,
seven right now.
Get a voice for 30 days.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com Promo Code Bill.
That's evils.com promocode bell.
Um, and Hulu plus, as I
mentioned, start watching TV,
your favorite shows right now. Go to
the podcast page at [inaudible] dot com.
Click on the Hulu plus banner for
extended free trial or Hulu plus.com/bill.