Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 23rd I'm sorry,
February 23rd February 23rd,
2000 and uh,
we'll go 15 [inaudible] I know
what you're thinking. Jesus belt.
What happened to your voice when
we would have from my voice,
it's fucking February.
That's what happened to my
voice. Okay. It's winter out.
I was just in Southeast Asia.
Blatant breathing and fucking pollution.
And then I was in fucking New York City,
you know, hanging out with that animal.
Paul Versey. Yeah. Jesus Christ
from drinking throat coat tea.
I don't know what happened.
I was kind of fighting off a cold all
of the whole time I was in New York,
but there was just so many people that
I wanted to see and all of them are
turned out to be raging alcoholics.
So, you know, what are you going to,
I've actually been doing really well.
Okay. I haven't drank in like a week.
Oh Man. Well me and this other guy
I'm on the other guy's name will,
will remain nameless.
I cause I'm all stolen.
I don't name names. Okay.
I'm not taking notes,
I'm not going to write a book someday.
Some tell all book about every cunt that
I went out and smoked a fucking cigar
with and drank booze with and all
the shit that they said to me.
It's a great thing about alcohol.
You can't really remember it anyways,
somewhere in my brain they used to
be a tell all book and it's gone.
And I think that's a good thing.
I think it strengthens
relationship friendships when
you fucking drink it away.
Anyways, I was staying at a
hotel and a, for whatever reason,
the bartender just decided that he had
to do something and take inventory or
some shit. So the bar was open all
night and uh, it was hilarious. We was,
we were staying at the
hotel, right. And um,
I don't,
I didn't really remember what happened.
It was just basically it was one of
those things where the place was full and
then it was half full.
And then it was like me in this
other comic just sitting there now,
it wasn't very easy and it wasn't any
of the Rosebowl legends all right.
With somebody else.
And we would just sit in there and uh,
you know,
okay.
And of course, you know the tail
once it gets to around four,
five o'clock in the morning, right?
You get a text from your lady, right?
Then the text becomes a phone call and
then she comes down there in her bathrobe
with the fucking rolling pin and drags
you up. Nia said when she came downstairs,
I had his full scotch, not a full
God, probably like half full scotch.
And I,
it was tilted so far in my hand.
It was almost pouring out of the
glass, but it wasn't. And um,
and then the next day I had to get up
early and I had to fly back to finally be
back out, you know, out here at
my house. And, uh, Jesus Christ,
I gotta tell you, man, that's the
closest I've come to. Just, you know,
like you drank so much and
someone just goes, okay,
you want to get breakfast? And you just
got to tell him to stop talking. Like,
just please don't bring up breakfast
or I'm going to Puke. No, no.
People will be like, what? It
get the fuck he talking about,
but the look on my face and
the dead serious tone, she
just knew. So she was like,
alright. And I forget what the
fuck I had. I don't even remember,
but I was just like, you know
what? The whole freckles here, oh,
Billy bread face needs to fucking
shut it down for a while. So, uh,
you know,
whatever.
I'm like fucking eight days into it and
I have no desire to drink again for a
while.
I think I'm just going to fucking,
I think I might have a couple of pops
towards the end of the month and then I'm
going,
I'm going to go clean and,
and fucking a march going to go in
like a lamb and out like a lamp,
going to go a whole 31 days,
no booze, no cigar, right?
No cigars. Just going to be
me and my fucking thoughts.
How long has that month going
to fucking drag? You know,
I got to finish up some shit anyway,
so I might as well do that
every once in a while.
You've got to give you a liver a
fucking break, right when that work.
Well anyways, I'm recording
this Sunday night. I apologize
for how lady got up. Uh,
last week. I actually recorded
at Monday morning and um,
I just have really bad internet where
I'm at. I don't know why. And uh,
you know why? Because it's technology
and nothing works out for me.
So what I do now is I just fucking,
yeah,
I'm just going to start recording.
I'm going to upload them to my computer
and then I'm just gonna drive to a local
fucking Wifi.
I'm writing a script,
Coffee House and I'll
just upload them there.
So you cons can stop fucking bitching
about it and everything will be fine.
But I know you guys like to bitch so
it's kind of good when they're up late,
you know,
it'd be even better.
What if I did two podcasts a week and
both of them were kind of late then you
could pitch twice. Maybe you could
feel twice a good about your life.
Would you like to add? Would
you like to, what would you do?
Like if I did another cause I'm thinking
about doing it. In fact, you know what,
maybe just maybe next week there might
be a big announcement about a possible
second podcast that I'm going to be doing.
What should be a culmination of, uh,
so maybe some classic clips from the old
ones and then me also just going off on
topics that you guys pick, you know,
rent a rant or something like that.
I don't know what the
fuck I'm going to call it.
I don't even know what I'm going
to call the podcast, you know,
I don't know what the epilogue,
I have no idea what the
fuck I'm going to call it.
But I'm thinking of doing a random
Thursday every once in a while.
Maybe a couple of Thursdays
that was maybe slowly,
I'll just do this like a fulltime
fucking podcast, five days a week,
like a real radio show.
I'll quit doing,
stand up and I'll just stay in a little
tree house talking to myself five days
of fucking week and you guys can
slowly listen to me slip it. Uh, no,
you can listen to me slowly slipped
into madness, not slowly listened to me.
Slip into madness. Listen to
me, slowly slipping America,
there's something fucking
wrong with my brain. You know,
the more I do this podcast,
the more I understand the grades I got
in high school and weren't necessarily my
fault. You know, I just think it's
the way the thin apps with fire.
So anyways,
it's,
it's fucking five 40 to 5:42 PM.
Uh, I got a big day tomorrow I'm
doing the Goddamn comedy jam again,
Josh, Adam Meyers. And
uh, as you guys know,
I always go down there
and whatever drummer,
do a little bit stand up and then
you jam with the band. And I always,
whatever drummer I'm imitating, I always
dress up like him cause uh, you know,
I want to keep it, it's gotta be a
go for fuck going to do it. You know,
I couldn't just sit down bill burr behind
a fucking, I'd look like a jerk off.
But if I dress up like an idiot,
then he can laugh at me
and then I can play drums.
And everybody has a good time and this,
there's no tension there.
There's nobody sitting in the crowd going,
wait a minute,
does he actually think that he can also
do this as a profession? Now I don't,
I'm just having a good time.
So anyways,
I'm not going to tell you that drama
I'm dressing up is because that's always
supposed to be a surprise for the
people come to the show. So anyways, um,
so I'm trying to on the costume tonight,
right?
And I put the wig on and I got the fucking
sunglasses, the jacket, the t shirt,
and I'll let shit, right. And uh,
I come downstairs to show Nia and as
I'm going down there, right? My fucking,
my dog Cleo is in the bedroom with her
and the door is closed. And I'm like,
what if my fucking pit bull
doesn't recognize me? What's
going to happen? Right?
And I fucking open the door. I'm like, Hey
Nia, my dog just goes, Whoa, whoa, Whoa,
whoa. Fucking launches
herself at the fucking door.
And I closed the door and I'm going,
Cleo, and I'm not taking off the wig.
Cause I'm thinking like she'll
smell me. Right. How does this work?
I'm actually doing an experiment behind
this brand new door that I just fucking
had put in that costs me a
fucking fortune downstairs. Right.
So I'm going to Cleo, it's me. Relax.
Okay, relax and I, she stops barking.
Then I opened it up again and as you
just go blah flipping the fuck out.
I finally had to take off the
wig and the sunglasses. But Dude,
she went to fuck this mode and
when pitbulls go to fuck this mode,
it's too late to take the wig off.
So my wife had a totally fucking calm
her down and the dog was just looking at
me like
sideways for like five minutes,
almost like don't do that to me.
You don't know how close she just came.
Do you understand that?
You don't know how fucking close you came.
I'm not shit,
not pit bulls.
I'm not shitting a pit bulls
because once you get a pit bull,
you actually realize how many other
dogs act exactly like fucking pit bulls.
They just don't have the capability.
You know what I mean?
It's like if some little twerp said,
I'm going to fucking kill you.
Do you just laugh and keep walking? That's
like one of those little chihuahuas.
But if a big guy said, I'm
going to fucking kill you,
you'd be, you'd be afraid.
You know, like you'd call somebody and
be like, can you beat that guy up for me?
That's what pimples.
Cause it's this little cunty dog.
Every five fucking hate this dog.
There's two dogs.
When I walk my dog that I fucking hate.
All right,
there's this one little
fucking dog he lives.
Okay.
Whatever it's allowed to live saying
he lives like he's making payments.
It's fucking dog lives at this House
with these people that allow him to live.
Although I don't know that they fucking
like the dog cause it's always outside
and they have one of these driveways.
It's like a little horse shoe, right?
So you get know entrance and an
exit could spin right around.
It's probably fat. People live there,
right? Fat People can't back up cars.
That's why I didn't know if he know that
that's why they have the backup cameras
now is because the fatties when
they would turn the neck fat,
which stopped the head and they can only
look so far and I was causing a lot of
problems. So uh, that's why they had the
backup camera. It's just right there.
They don't have to fucking turn around.
Oh, they got to do is move their eyes.
They're big Fred Flintstone. Waterhead
can just sit there. Right. So anyways,
he's fat. He's got this dog. And uh,
and what it does is when we
come walking up the block,
okay,
this, it's, it's on one side of the
driveway. The second is sees us,
it immediately runs to the other side.
Wait for us to come is probably like,
you know,
whatever,
like 20 feet between two and it
just fucking talks all the shadow,
all this fucking shit. And my dog
just looks at it and it's such bull.
Like my dog doesn't even give a fuck.
I actually react to the dog now.
Like it's been bugging me.
I'll take a little short step towards it.
A growl at it.
I do other shit like put my arms up.
You know like you're supposed to do
when there's a bear coming at you,
which I'm sure doesn't work.
Put your arms up so you look a bigger,
yeah. Well My, well my arms are up.
I don't look bigger than a bear,
so I mean I don't see what
the big fucking, if it,
if I was going to step on an ant and it
fucking put four of its legs in the air
while it's still not two of
them, I'd just be like, wow.
It's a very talented and Smush, right?
Isn't that what the bear is going to do?
Okay.
I level those people with theories.
What to do,
what to do if you're in the water
with a shark swim underneath it.
They don't like the vulnerable
underside of their bodies. Oh,
is that what I'm going to do?
I'm just casually swim underneath it
and it the thing they can swim 10 times
faster than me.
Do you know,
go to fight or you are when you just
use your mouth. Think about that.
That thinks not worried about taking
any sort of fucking, you know,
mad at you if you've just fought with
your mouth, you just fucking, you know,
kind of what if you just put your
arms out like they were fence,
you cut them down by your waist and you
just turn your hands out like they would
fit. How many bar fights do
you think it went? All right.
What was the last time you saw
a bear loose in a bar fight?
What if a shark could go in a bar?
You think it would have a loose
to say could breathe, right? Yeah,
but some sort of reverse auction can mass.
It was like full of water.
You know when you sit at
the end of the Bar, right?
And you're fucking lady just can't stop
looking at the shark down there. Right?
And then you're like,
you fucking looking at this all night.
Will you make me a fucking jerk off?
And then you went down there,
you know how many punches do you
think you'd get in? He fucking eat it.
He your damn man. Alright,
so fuck your whole, you know,
put your arms up to make yourself look
bigger, curl up in a ball, play dead.
You know, you've only
got one option. Okay?
Hope you're near other humans and run
near them and hope they don't see what's
chasing you and maybe they get eaten.
That's the move.
That's the fucking move.
You never go in the woods by yourself.
All right?
You always want to go into the woods with
somebody that can't run as fast as you,
and it looks a lot tastier, okay? That's
called the buddy system. All right?
And I don't do a lot of scuba diving
is everybody knows I'm terrified of the
ocean. But I would think that that
would be the same case when you,
like if I was scuba diving,
I'm trying to think which one
of my friends looks like a seal.
Uh, Joe to rose. It looks like an eel.
Sort of like an old eel. You know,
it's got a little bit of a punch.
A God. Who else? I don't know. Fucking,
I'm going to start this bullshit.
Whatever I picked, somebody is
going to be somebody. I know.
Somebody I know that
it looks like a Walrus,
although you know walrus can kill a polar
bear. God knows. We've all seen that.
Right.
And pull the IRIG must seen that famous
youtube video with a polar bear just
rather than picking on a little one.
He went for the Thanksgiving
dinner and went for that big one,
a big one with the giant fucking teeth.
It didn't even lay,
got him that bed and a polar bear justice.
It was like a fucking,
he got shanked and that was it
fucking thing like walked off.
I thought it was just like regroup and
like, all right, that wasn't worth it.
Maybe I'll, I'll live to fight
another day. And it didn't,
it just kind of walked away only
about 50 yards and just laid down,
curled up in a ball and uh,
just bled out and died.
I felt really bad for it too.
It's weird how, you know,
you fucking look at a polar bear
just attack and walruses you like,
it's so vicious and everything
that you fucking hate the thing.
But then the second you see it vulnerable,
you actually kind of feel bad for it.
Like you guys ever seen that Youtube
video where that that pride of lions are
attacking,
I dunno,
one of those bowls or whatever the fuck
it is and one of them gets kicked in the
John at breaks his jaw and his
mouth is just hanging open.
Like you have a Roger
Rabbit right before he died,
that fucking awful cancer he had.
That's what this line looks like, right?
Just sitting there and how can I,
as his mouth opened,
and it was trying to play it off,
but like all the other lines where Eaton
and this thing was and eat and it was
getting skinnier and skinnier and they're
just looking at him like, dude, just,
you know, either say it or shut
your fucking mouth. They were just,
and the thing just basically
starve to death and you felt bad.
You felt bad for this thing
that would have no problem.
Just eating alive actually
don't eat you alive.
They fucking go right for your throat.
The worst thing is if
you ever got fucking,
I'd say a Komodo dragon where they just
bite you and then just fucking follow
you around for two days and wait for
you to die because the kind of bacteria
that's in their mouth,
once it gets in your bloodstream,
you know you had just done two days
and they just sort of linger around.
You just wait,
this thing's just waiting to eat you.
He's sitting there talking to you mother
fucker. It's just walking behind you.
Like Jason, you know, Crystal
Lake, no matter how fast
you run that fucking thing,
it's just lumbering along by, yeah,
I would just pick up rocks and just,
I would stolen it to death.
You know like what you know.
I don't know.
Like somebody who steals
an iPod and Saudi Arabia,
like what they have to fucking deal with.
I would treat the lizard the same
fucking way. I would just be, all right,
something's eating me,
but not you and mother fucker.
You're not going to enjoy this meal.
All right.
I think I would be a delicacy out
there. It's pasty as I am, you know,
God knows everybody likes still
for fucking breast meat now.
That's why they inject those
chickens with all the steroids.
They can't even walk because they got
such big fucking, you know, breast.
This is now I'm talking about. All right,
this is the Monday morning podcast.
Everybody, I do this every
single week if you're new to it.
And I'm doing it a little bit
early this week. Ya Know, why?
Cause my fucking lady,
she's downstairs,
she's watching the Oscars,
she's watching the pre red carpet
Oscars and every year, you know,
I try to hang in there, you
know, I was like, all right,
I know this is your Superbowl.
I'll sit and I'll watch it.
Much of this as I fucking can. And
you know, I can only get so far.
You know, it was really interesting
at one point was the guy, uh,
who's hosting Daniel Day Lewis,
whatever his name is. Greg [inaudible].
Okay.
Kirk, I don't know what the fuck his
name is. Thomas [inaudible] Thomas House.
Thomas Haden Church. It's one of
those three name guys. Stiggy houser.
The fuck's his name.
I had it.
I had it anyways. He was talking
to this other gay guy, right.
And I felt like the other gay guy was
like the old style gay guy and the new
guy. Diogenes what? I got
to look up his fucking name.
It's going to ruin this story.
It's going to ruin this fucking story.
I love when they asked the guys,
what are you wearing? You know,
we're all wearing Tuxedos.
Does it fucking matter?
Okay.
You know, what are you wearing a, it's Tom
Ford. Oh my God. I knew it was Tom Hardy.
Tom Ford. Yeah. Actually it's missed
a Tux. Alright, you're dumb. Fuck.
Uh,
I like how Ryan Seacrest has
his own line of fucking clothes.
It's hilarious to me.
Doogie Howser.
What is his fucking name?
Doogie Howser. Alright,
MD. Wikipedia. Here we go. Okay. Neil.
Patrick Harris. I knew that. So anyways,
he's talking to this other gay dude,
right? And I felt like the other gay dude,
let me ask gay guys,
any gay guys will listen to this.
Is there a such thing as hacky gay or a
zero kind of gay that fucking annoys you
on television, this gotta
be, you know what I mean?
There's a kind of redhead that bugs me,
you know what I mean?
That aw shucks guy tagging along
with the fucking funds. A rally guy.
At what point was Richie Cunningham
going to be like, hey, you know, Fonzie,
you kind of a cunt, you know you're
bang and everything that, well,
you're not that tough. I'm fucking
taller than you. They might kick my ass,
but I'll get one in. I wanted to do
all fucking five, 10 seasons of that.
He never did it. So the
other, the pudgy gay guy,
like he was going, he was like, that
really affected gay, like gay dude.
Just go and like, uh, go over to Neil,
Patrick Harris. He was going like,
is there anybody in the crowd that you're
just like excited to say, you know,
like those gay guys that
say honey, right? It's like,
isn't it like hackey gay
because the Pudgy guy goes,
is there anybody you're excited to say?
Like for me,
it'd be lies them Minnelli
and I just went like, really?
Would it really be Liza Minnelli?
Okay.
Wasn't that like funny for a gay guy to
say like 30 fucking years ago? Come on.
Right. I mean, I'm talking out of
school here, but I just seemed like,
what's his face? Neil Patrick
Harris. He had like, you know,
yeah,
he was a fucking human being.
The other guy was just fucking,
I don't know what he was doing.
It was like he was uh, uh,
who was in that fucking movie with that
guy or hung himself. I can't remember.
I can't even remember
the name of the movies.
You know what I mean?
Just because you're gay doesn't mean
you're not a person. You know what I mean?
It's almost like when
somebody is acting regular,
then all of a sudden they plug become a
game show host and then they just stop
being human. They just become
game show host guy. Alright,
let's bet the whale.
I feel like when,
when gay dudes that's like
the gay version of doing that,
I just want to shake that fat guy
and just be like, who are you really?
How do you, what? What do you
really talk like? Um, anyways,
I'm sure summer we'll fucking take
a snippet of that and send it to a,
we've had enough of that.com
and next thing you know,
there'll be another story out there, but
that's what they do. And you know what,
you should do that. You should take
this podcast seriously, goddammit.
The nerve of me to be out here joking
around. Okay, this is in my park.
It's your podcast and you
should take it seriously.
It's somehow shape it into whatever
fucking cause you're trying to get an
attention to. Um, anyway, so she's down
there watching these, these fucking,
okay.
I don't know what the hell are you?
I really helped somebody gay
chimes in on that because I got,
as I got a sense that I'm fucking right
on that one. You know what I mean?
Anyways,
going back.
So Nias downstairs and she's just totally
into it and somebody is the red carpet
and she's just gone. Oh my God. No,
I can't stand it. I can't. Sounds like
it was a bad call, but she's actually,
that's like how into the dresses she gets.
And I sit there and go build,
don't ruin it. Don't ruin it.
Okay. Just let her enjoy this.
You Watch sports,
it's just as fucking stupid.
If you really sit down and think about it,
it's just is fucking stupid.
It's just as stupid.
All right.
And I get more fucking upset about the
outcome than she does with the Oscar.
I think.
You know what?
I actually had to walk away from the
Oscars with at one point they were like,
you know all the best pictures, all
of them are starring men, you know,
like every fucking award show. Is
that? No. Well, what the flow. Well,
can't that just mean that guys
make better movies this year?
You can't say that, can you?
You gotta be like, no, no, no.
The witches of Eastwick that was fucking
phenomenal. Which is at Eastwick.
Really? I don't watch movies, so fuck
you. Why do, what do you want from me?
Is this every goddamn time,
every time I swear to got
best lemonade stand. Hey,
how come there isn't anybody from
Bangladesh and this, you know,
what are you trying to suggest?
They don't like lemonade. No,
I wasn't thinking about it. I
was just making lemonade. Um,
anyways, let's, let's
get to the fucking gonna.
Blame my cold for Huc. Dot. My son this
week. This is like extra dump, extra dumb.
All right. Dollar Shave Club. Everybody.
Dollar Shave Club. Hey everyone.
Can someone tell me when raised has got
so goddamn expensive? Well, personally,
it's been my whole frigging life and
it just keeps going up every damn year.
It just keeps getting higher and
higher and they lock them in that day.
I'm vault and you got to get that
old retiree. You know what I mean?
To come down and lock it, unlock it. And
you feel bad for him because you know,
we worked long enough to
live off social security,
but the banker Kunze took everything.
So now he's got to go down there
and guard the razor blades.
I use sick it through and that he is sick
of taking out a second mortgage on the
home. You're upside down in the
buy. Some God damn raises. Well,
don't get beat up by
ridiculous rates of prices.
Get you shave gear@dollarshaveclub.com
for a few bucks a month.
Dollar Shave club.com delivers amazing
razors and other great grooming supplies
right to your doorstep.
They're plant starts
at just $3 three bucks.
Jesus Christ. Your Dad has
more change on the dresser. Uh,
here's how it works.
They send you a handle for free and
every month they send replacement blades.
It's one less thing to worry about.
You can get deliveries every month,
every other month, however the
hell you want to do it. Okay?
Aren't you getting screwed over enough
in life isn't a nice when you can take
one scam off the table, we'll do
it now. Why pay $20 for a raise?
We can get a fantastic shape from dollar
shave club.com for just a fraction of
the price. So getting smacked around
by a hyper. I raise her prices.
Dollar shave.com razors are great
and they're a fraction of the price.
Trust me, you'll wish you
had done it sooner. Don't be
a dumb ass. Shapes smarter.
Go to dollar shave club.com/burr that's
dollar shave club.com/burr dollar shave
club.com/bar ah, fuck.
I don't know if I look to make this one
fucking voice is killing me. All right,
legal zoom. Let me try to read
this a little more relaxed.
Legal Zoom, everybody.
The best time to start your the best time.
The best time of waking up
is legal zoom in your cup.
The best time to start getting your
life organized is right now. God dammit.
Get off the couch.
You Lazy Bastard and the easiest place
to do it as legal zoom.com I said,
get off the couch.
Getting your life organized starts with
protecting your family and a great way
to take control of your family's future
is making a will or living trust.
Never step on a plane again and
every time this turbulence go, well,
those fuckers are going
to be in the street.
How you can solve that right here with
legal zoom.com they can help this.
No easy way to make sure your
family is legally taken care of.
No easy way to do it.
Getting your life organized also makes
taking control of your financial affairs.
So if you're thinking of starting
a business or you have one already,
legal zoom can help you form your business
and provide the support you need to
run he successfully. Hey, you know,
it'd be great if you could
come up with a will that said,
this is what everybody's getting in this.
No challenging it and I was of sound mind.
If you don't like the outcome,
go fuck yourself.
Be Happy.
I didn't know that or I wouldn't
have left you anything anyways,
for more than 10 years,
legal zoom has helped millions of people
get the personalized attention they
need and if you need
legal advice or guidance,
they could connect you with
someone that can do that.
An independent attorney in most states,
since they're not a law firm,
don't wait any longer to organize your
life and Eaton save even more money by
entering bur bur are into
the referral box at checkout.
That's discount code bur bur for legal
help you can count on for your family or
a small business.
Go to legalzoom.com today,
legal zoom.com discount
code per uh oh look at,
there's only three reads this week. I
might as well get, oh no, there's not.
There's even more. Oh,
here's our newest one.
Let's see what you guys think about
this one. It's called Trunk Club.
Everybody like Elephant Trunk Club.
Guys,
you might hate shopping, but you
still want to look good, right?
Uh, what if you could snap your fingers
and have a trunk full of clothes that fit
perfectly and make you look amazing?
Would that be awesome?
You're gonna love what gets delivered to
you from Trunk club@trunkclub.com slash
burr. You answer a few simple questions
about your look style in size,
and then they assign a real
person who helps to style you.
Dude,
my podcast.
You're never going to have to leave the
house again unless you're ready to dress
up. You have a nice clean shave.
You could have a will made out.
You're going to send all your mail out,
you know,
then he is reaching to the trunk.
You're going to look funny.
You're a fucking great.
Um, they had, excuse me,
they email you a list of clothes
they recommend sending you.
You approve at no cost to you.
They ship you a trunk full of fresh
new clothes to your door. Try them on.
Keep what you want. Send bad point. You
don't in their prepaid box. That's it.
A better wardrobe than you could ever
pick out yourself in minutes and you don't
have to do it. This is the,
this is what movie stars too.
This is like having your own Goddamn
stylists. Just son of a bitch.
You guys don't even deserve this. This
is phenomenal. I got to sign up for this.
Did I mentioned, yeah, I should sign
up this just to piss off my wife.
Where'd you get that? Who is that? Who's
buying your clothes? Trunk Club, baby.
He'd go make me a sandwich, uh, that
I mentioned. The service is free.
What do you mean it's free? Why do you
make money? Your stylist, the shopping,
the box, even the shipping. All 100% free.
When you go to Trunk club.com
only pay for the clothes you keep.
Well there you got, we
add, oh Jesus Christ.
I thought I've got the whole thing
for free. Uh, no ongoing subscription.
No hidden charges. No malls.
We say that again. No malls.
Just great clothes. Handpicked
for your style. All right,
you're going to thank me that you used
this. And right now it's completely free.
So go get started@trunkclub.com slash
bird that's trunk club.com/bar man,
you're out of your mind if you don't
do that one. Well, I mean, you know,
you like to shop if you're in
the shop and you can do that.
I went to the mall yesterday. It
was a shit show. Absolute Shit show.
But you know what the
icing of the cake was?
There was selling girl scout cookies.
You know, they should always snide.
Are we sell girl scout cookies every week.
They should bring it back
more than once a year though.
Make those trips to the mall a little
more exciting. All right, me undies,
everybody. Here we go. Can I sing
and I have to do this differently?
My raspy voice.
Who do I sound like you'll never find?
That's a hacky loo roll.
So I like lady love way better.
Your love is sweeter than the summer
breeze. I got puberty. Sweet, sweet.
Alright
me undies,
90% me undies,
me undies.
No more sweaty balls, but it'll
boop, boop. Me, Andy's me undies.
You don't have to where I'm at the mall
cause you went to fucking trunk club.
All you gotta do is grab
your underwear in a Atar.
You slip them on and your paws out wet.
That's all you fucking get. Oh yeah.
Hey,
when you were fucking me undies who?
They make them poor ladies to her clamp
will only be wet because a you Bam.
All right, 90%. That's
the percent of your life.
You're in your underwear and underwear.
It gets old fast.
You know the feeling of
putting on old saggy underwear.
You need to know the feeling of great
fitting underwear that's two times softer
than cotton. I've got to tell you,
everybody's raving about this.
Anybody I know on my podcast when they
send me a tweet that they ordered me
undies, all they talk about
is how great their balls feel.
The I'll less annoying your boss would
be if your balls felt that nice and dry.
You need to know about me.
[inaudible] dot com who wants to
get yelled at and saggy underwear.
It's like you're losing on two fronts.
It's like Hitler.
You know when he went too
far into fucking Russia,
[inaudible] is the most
comfortable underwear you
will ever wear and it's insane
how good they make you feel.
They fit perfectly.
They'll write up on you and they literally
pull moisture away from your groves,
from your skin, so you stay
cool. I had mine on right now.
You know what I actually do?
I fucking love them.
They come and superhero colors to uh,
they have cool styles for both
men and women and they look great.
Check out the photos yourself.
Me,
undies.com this quality with typically
retail for two times to me, undies, price.
I would love to talk to an expert in
underwear to actually see if that claim is
true. I mean, what is two times? What
is the price of underwear? Who knows?
It's like that old George Bush. How
much is eggs? I don't fucking know.
I'm the president.
I have a chef.
Too busy trying to make sure nobody
shoots missiles out of shit. Cunt.
How many missiles does Russia have? Will
I write? Then you worry about the eggs.
Can you do me a favor and not in just
fucking audit that guy. All right, sorry.
No retail middlemen means more savings
for you. Here. I'll make it easy.
Go to me undies,
dotcom slash burn and get 20% off
your first order and free shipping.
Save even more.
When you buy a pack of them,
they guarantee you're going to be happy
with your first pair or your first pair
is free. Well, if I'm not happy, does
it make a difference on the price?
I fucking hate this underwear.
Oh, and it's free. Whoa.
Okay.
I love this woman. Well, you know, she
doesn't have to clap up. Okay. All right.
Did Legal Zoom, right? Oh, so
like one more read. All right,
let's get back to the podcast.
All right, so what else?
Oh, for those of you out
there that want to email me,
the email for the podcast is bill
at the m m podcast. Once again,
that email is bill at the m M podcast.
Yes.
Um,
and also I've been getting a bunch of
emails about people who did that swab
testing there to see if you could be a
bone marrow donor or a blood donor. Sorry.
Uh, here's what, hey, Billy blood dota.
I'm not looking to get red on the podcast,
but I wanted to tell you that I joined
a be the match.org because I heard you
talk about it on the show.
It sounds like a great organization.
I hope you followed through with signing
up. I haven't yet. I got to do it.
And then the obligatory thanks.
And go swab yourself. There you go.
Um, I have to do that. I have to do
something positive with my fucking life.
Are you like me? That you will fucking
drunk? Don't do something positive.
Go to be be the match.org that
was swab your mouth, you know,
then you'll be a match. You'll save
somebody's life. Yeah. It's funny.
I would save somebody's life and
they also get slightly buzzed
and their booze bag.
Um,
okay.
All right.
I uh,
I've gotten back into reading everybody
and by reading, I mean I just,
I just liked reading autobiographies
right now I'm reading this actually the
book about Richard Pryor. That was fucking
amazing. Then I started, um, you know,
I got add. So I'm always reading like
two, three at a time. So reading that,
the ESPN book,
uh,
those guys that having too much fun and
I'm also tearing through Steven Adler,
my favorite drummer from the 80s.
I just, I've fucking, I dunno,
I absolutely love the way he played.
Um,
and he's got a book called a my
appetite for destruction, sex,
drugs and guns and roses.
And it was really cool as if you've
already read slashes book to hear him go
over like some of the same
stories in his version.
I mean they line up pretty good,
but uh, I don't know. It's pretty,
it's pretty fucking awesome.
He actually talks about some shit that
I had no idea it happened to them and uh,
maybe have even more empathy for that guy.
You know,
what I watched recently this week was,
um,
they actually,
I never knew this.
I was literally like two
things devastated me.
Like two major blows. One was more severe
because it was a death of somebody.
But in 1990 as far as the
music fed was the first,
obviously the top of the list
was when Stevie Ray Vaughn died.
I couldn't fucking blow
was the first time, um,
someone that I was into to that level,
uh,
died and just, it was just
so fucking shocking. Like,
I didn't even, uh, you know, it
didn't register until after, you know,
then family style came
out with Jimmy Vaughan,
so there was still new material and
I just remember thinking like, wow,
this is going to be no more Stevie Ray
Vaughan and double trouble, new material.
And he kind of had this,
this theme where he would always,
with a lot of his albums,
he would start with an instrumental
and end with an instrumental.
So I'd always be excited when
I bought his new album too. Um,
what did he do that or wouldn't eat?
Maybe he did it in a few, getting older,
starting to get a rude mood. I think it
was the first song on the second side. Oh,
I guess you would have one
instrumental every album or to wait.
He had stang swing and couldn't stay
on the weather and scuttled button.
He had rude mood on Texas flood.
It's say what?
Unsold his soul. He had Riviera
paradise. Oh, y'all said Lenny,
how can I forget that one? So
anyways, I was always thinking like,
oh man in his plane always would go to
next level. I just remember thinking like,
wow, this is never going to happen
again. So there was that and then um,
Steven ads or got kicked
out a guns and roses.
Okay.
I couldn't fucking believe it. It was
just, he was, he was the guy for me.
Like I was all about all these
other guys from the 80s that I saw,
you know, and they all had the
double bass drum set up and all that.
And I just remember when I saw guns and
roses live at the Ritz on MTV and I saw
all the music that Steven Adler was
getting out of that little four piece drum
kit and it was so fucking cool to just
go see somebody go back to having the one
rack Tom with just the one ride symbol
and this is how dumb I am when it really
comes to spatial relations and shit.
Like I'm really fucked in the head like I,
so I don't have a good mechanical mind.
Even like when they say if there's
cooking directions, like, you know,
turn it on the front burner.
When I look at the stove,
the front burner is not
the burner closest to me.
It's the one furthest away to me.
I always view the stove like I'm
standing behind the car and that's,
I don't know why that doesn't
make any fucking sense,
but I'm always looking
at shit ass backwards.
So at the time I had a
five piece Slingerland late
seventies all bond of size is
24 like 14 by 24 bass drum.
I think I had a 1214 and a 16
two racks and a floor.
And I had my ride a pie
over the second rack,
Tom and I was telling a guy
at work, he's like, yeah man,
I really don't play a fourth.
This is how dumb I was.
I really want to play a four piece, but
you know, I got a five piece kit, man,
maybe next kid I'll buy it would
be a four piece. And he goes, well,
why don't you just take that other time
off and then it becomes a four piece.
And I was like, Oh yeah, do you know bad?
I want that story not to be true.
But it is true.
So I took that fucking rack Tom off and
it changed my world as far as drum and
how much fun was it?
I've never gone back.
I absolutely love that setup because the
way it makes you go around the kid is
totally different because once people
started having the two rack toms,
it became start your fill on the snare,
go up to the first rack Tom and then
just blow down every fucking Tom you had.
And every fill kind of
started to sound the same.
But when you had the fucking sorta the
l shape thing going there one up and one
to the one straight up,
but one over to the right,
it made you go around the kit differently.
I mean nowadays I don't even think kids
can relate to that shit because there's
so much information on Youtube and kids
compete with each other that the, the,
the growth of the average
drummers through the fucking roof,
like in the last five years,
how good people have gotten into playing
the drums compared to five years when I
was a kid, it's not even close. Um,
okay.
And now, you know, they had the bass
drums in with the fills and all that.
Did that just fucking there there are
unbelievable, you know, but whatever. So
that was my thing,
know I started off playing with to ACDC
records and then rolling stone source,
Phil Rudd, Charlie Watts,
really simple two for shit.
And then I'm moving up to
two appetite for destruction,
which was all, you know, rock and
roll type of shit. But you know,
Bass Drum was more busier and uh,
he had,
he has a signature licks
and that type of thing.
But the degree of difficulty as far as
just technically was harder for me and I
used to play the hand,
got stripped it down to the four piece.
I ice to play that fucking album
every day after work, man, I would,
I would unload trucks all day in
this warehouse, laugh my balls off.
One of the great jobs, I have a
hat, you know, and then I would,
uh,
I would fucking go home,
lift weights.
This is my day lift weights.
I go on a bike ride and then I fucking a,
then I would sit down and play drums at.
That was it.
I would just fucking play from the
first song all the way to the end of the
album. And my older brother used to
drive him fucking nuts because I sucked.
But Steve,
what was funny was Steven's drum parts
was so unique to each song that in his
head he knew all of the tracks.
He knew what,
what's if he came home in the middle
of the album, he'd be like, ah, fuck.
He's only on Mr. Brown stone.
He's only on the f. He's only,
he's only halfway through the first
side of the, the fucking tape. You know,
it was funny is I had the tape and a
boombox. I didn't even have headphones.
I should've just got headphones that I
did and I could have heard it so much
better. I would have that
thing fucking cranked up.
And I have my head turned to the side
with this little shitty plastic fucking
poor excuse for a boombox. And
I used to play that thing, uh,
all the fucking time. And I
remember just in, you had no idea,
just had to figure shit out for yourself.
There was no youtube.
He just listened to it and I was convinced
anytime any drama was playing on the
snare drum,
it was never just singles with accents.
I always see was convinced it was some
sort of rudiment he's got to be playing a
rudiment. It sounds too cool. And um,
well I guess a single stroke roll is a
root of it, but you know what I mean?
I thought it was some
sort of special sticking.
So I remember it's so easy
in the beginning where he's
got those fast 16th notes
on the snare drum with the what?
The crash accents.
I thought he was playing paradiddles
so I would be trying to crash and play
paradiddles. It was, oh my God,
it was a shit show until fucking
somebody at this other warehouse,
this burnout musician.
He showed me that it was singles and
a, I dunno, that was just a great,
it was a great time of
my life as far as like,
mmm,
I was fucking up bad.
But like it was going to be a while
before the chickens weren't going to come
home to roost because it was still in
my early twenties I was fucking up in
college, but nobody I knew had graduated
college. So even though I was behind,
you know, none of them had jobs yet.
I hadn't started doing stand up.
I was working out like a fucking
is the best shape I was ever in.
I lifted weights every fucking day and
rode a bike like 11 miles every day.
In other weekends I have one dad right
at 18 miles and I was like 20 years old
and I had like zero body
fat. I was just like, yeah.
And I would go out and booze like
fucking four nights of the week,
eat McDonald's at the end of the
night. Just metabolism was, it was,
it was the best. And I went to work
and my job was unloading trucks.
That's all it was.
And then stock on the shelves and
everybody I worked with was a fucking,
either it was a warehouse,
they were the class clowns,
struggling musicians or some sort
of just, I dunno, drug addict,
free spirit. It was just the best fucking
group of people I ever worked with.
And um, anyways, I remember, um,
okay.
Somewhere. Yeah, he, I always
heard they played farm aid.
I remember hearing a story like it went
nationwide I think as MTV was running.
That's right.
Was Axel said that someone in this band
is fucking with Mr. Brown stone when
they opened up for uh,
the rolling stones and I was
like, Oh wow, that's cool.
They live in just like that song.
I didn't know that that was a bad
sign for the band. And then, um,
I dunno if they played far made or
whatever and I just heard that, you know,
I heard that he got fired and
I couldn't fucking believe it.
And I never thought the band was the same.
Once he left and his,
he left and then they got,
they got all those other guys,
they added a fucking keyboard thing. And
it just, the whole thing, just like, yeah,
you know what happens. So, um, anyways,
this is a long drawn out story,
but I didn't realize that,
that uh,
there's video of Steven Antholis last
performance with guns and roses and a
slash tells a story that Steven was high
and they went out to go perform any,
went to jump on the,
the drum riser,
but his depth perception was off
because of whatever he was on.
And he missed it by like eight feet.
And he does,
he comes out and he fucking just eats it,
does a face plant.
Then he gets behind the drums and
evidently he didn't really know what songs
they were going to be doing, got to
know that was his fault or whatever.
So they did civil war. Then you see
the look on his face in the video,
like what the fuck we do? I haven't,
I've rehearsed this with a bear,
but never with axel dude out to zip me.
He fucking kills it.
I mean, they're all a little bit
sloppy, but I thought he did fine.
And then they pulled out some punk tune
and duff had to count it off for,
but even then,
he still fucking did a great job and it
made me Madec all over again that they
fired a, but like I'm getting
through his book and I think, uh,
obviously they wouldn't have got rid of
them if he wasn't completely fucking up.
But,
um,
it's weird to read this book because
know how it ends as far as this trip with
guns and roses,
but I'm still fucking rooting for the guy.
Like that's how big a fan I am of his.
So all right,
there's your drum nerd part of the
fucking podcast for this week. So anyways,
so I'm reading that Shit
and um, oh, here's what for,
I wanted to read you this shit.
All right,
let me type this in here. People always
say this shit like, dude, you're type A,
type a right?
Like this is some negative fucking thing.
MMM.
Oh, you're tight B and all
that. Here's, here's what you,
next time somebody says that,
because people usually what they do when
they run out of points to make with you,
they say, oh, you're type
bay, you're tight bay. Right?
Rather than being like, no,
I made some good points and now you can't
refute them, so now you're going to,
you're going to fucking hide behind
this fucking pop psychology horse shit.
This is really interesting to me.
A type A and type B personality theory.
Yeah,
the big word there theory,
the those type A and type B personalities
are just theories and it basically
describes two contrasting personality
types that could either raise or lower
respectively one's chances of
developing coronary heart disease.
There was a considerable controversy
about the role of these personality types
in coronary heart disease and the role
of the tobacco industry funding of early
research in this area.
Early research turns out they funded
this study for 40 years and basically the
theory about the tobacco industry is what
they were trying to do is cover up the
fact that cigarettes smoking caused
heart disease and they tried to blame it
more on if you were this type bay guy who
gets impatient with people that's goal
driven, that loses his temper and all
that. Like you, you had a bigger chain.
Like that was more of a cause of the heart
disease than smoking then that if you
were actually like more chilled and
relaxed, like a type B personality,
you wouldn't get heart disease.
So
as far as my ignorant way of reading this,
like these personalities are just like,
okay
cause I feel like everything
that they bring up by him,
like Taipei describes individuals
as rigidly organized. I'm not,
my office is a shit show and I don't
write anything down and I never look at
emails. Highly status conscious. Yeah.
I mean I drive a Prius and
I dress like Malcolm Young.
I don't give a fuck a
sensitive yes. Impatient. Yes.
Take on more than they can handle
it. I got like 20 Ha uh, hobbies,
maybe one other people to get to the point
who doesn't anxious that as much as I
used to be proactive. Depends on what
you're talking about and concerned with.
Time management. Who wants to waste
of fucking time? I'm all right. Tight.
Yeah.
By definition,
generally live at lower stress levels.
It typically work steadily
enjoying achievement,
but not becoming stressed
when they do not achieve.
I mean,
I've kind of come to that point,
um, where I'm at, you know,
I think they're just means being more
happy with your life. You know what,
I'm a comedian and I sell tickets.
I mean, what the fuck else is there?
Everything else after that is gravy.
I felt like I made it like four years
ago after like a somewhere between, um,
why do I do this and let it go.
Once I was selling the tickets at clubs,
I could go out twice a month, live my
dream it live a comfortable lifestyle,
take care of my wife.
What the fuck did I care?
So I dunno. But anyways,
it's good to know. There were
actually a fucking theory.
It's just a theory. You know
something, you know, poof.
We came up with this pussies
fucking jerk off.
Stick up for yourself. Good.
Come on up with this crap.
Here's funding by the tobacco companies
further discrediting the so called type
a behavior pattern.
A study from 2012 based on searching
the legal tobacco documents library
suggests the phenomenon of initial pro
initially promising results followed by
negative findings to be partially
explained by the tobacco industry's
involvement in the type a B personality
research to undermine the scientific
evidence on smoking and
health industry is newest.
The industry's interest in type AB person.
I lasted at least for decades until the
late 1990s involving substantial funding
to key researchers
encourage to prove smoking,
to simply correlate with a personality
type prone to coronary heart disease and
cancer. So I dunno, I
find that interesting.
After the 50th time somebody said,
I'm type a
yeah,
let's just say it's not a theory. I think
I have elements of type A and type B.
I really think a type a type person
wood,
we'll throw it down in a bar,
which I never did.
I never did that.
I haven't had a fight since like
fucking junior high and I lost,
I was playing stick hockey and I
lost to this fucking guy that was,
it was over and I was just like,
yeah that sucked. You know,
just cause you have a temper,
it doesn't mean you type a does it.
I don't think it does to me it type A's
like a fucking guy's guy knows how to
fix a car or break your jaw. To me
that's type A, he's like a hero.
I think very few people at type A
and type is the whole, you know,
either live in like the Zen.
I think there's,
there's two ways to live in both
if they actually exist. Okay.
It can be type A, this is zenway
maybe you'll live both. I don't know.
Cause like there's the type B person
that actually knows how to fight but re
recognizes how stupid it is.
It doesn't throw down unless they have
to and then they throw down and they win.
In the end they still think it's stupid.
That person.
Does that person exist or am I just
thinking about a cool guy saw in a movie?
Speaking of that,
do you guys see the movie the drop?
I saw a bunch of movies and my 70 plus
hours of airline travel over the last,
uh, month. Uh, the drop
is a great fucking movie.
James Gandel Finis last movie and there's
another actor in there. Of course,
I didn't get his name.
I was on the plane. Um,
I can't, I don't know. I don't, I gotta
I gotta get his fucking name, his son.
He'll fuck this up. I absolutely love
that guys performance of that thing.
Really cool movie.
Come od the drop.
2014.
What would be great if I actually
looked this up in the meantime,
as I'm waiting for this to come around,
I saw horrible bosses too,
which I thought was fucking hilarious.
Did you see anybody else
see that movie nanny body?
Um, today? Chris was fucking hilarious.
Is it Tom Hardy said, oh, it is
Jesus Christ. He looks so different. Every
fucking picture. Yeah. That's the guy.
Tom Hardy was the shit in the drop.
He was so fucking good in that
movie. Um, horrible bosses too.
I fucking love that. Would Kevin
Spacey's fucking Hilarious in it,
Charlie Day so day because all
three of those guys, just a payment,
just funny ass fucking movie. It's
laughing like an asshole on the plane.
Everybody looking at me and I didn't care
cause I had another 10 hours to go and
I was drinking the fucking
Johnny Walker black there.
I saw a dumb and dumber
two was disappointed.
It was a couple of really good scenes,
but I was disappointed.
I didn't think that the script
was there for those guys.
And that's obviously a fucking classic.
Uh,
okay.
What else did I see? I think I told you
I saw a chef a while back when I was, oh,
I was in New Zealand. I saw
chef. What a fucking great, well,
let me ask you this as,
as John Leguizamo ever been bad.
Okay.
That guy,
he's been in bad movies,
but he always makes the movie better
as long as he's fucking in it. So,
okay,
it's a great script. He's great. If
the movie stinks, he's still great.
The guy's fucking money in the bank money.
That's probably why he's been
working for like 30 fucking years.
It's unbelievable. Uh, it was that
feting that I'm talking about.
This shit on Oscar night. Everybody
as you don't watch as many movies,
I usually don't fly this much.
I usually talk this much.
I usually don't start sentences with
I usually every fucking two seconds.
Let me get back to what the fuck I
was talking about here. Um, oh yeah.
Hell is it? What was I gonna
talk about those Bruins. Huh?
Beaten the Black Hawks. Oh, by four
goals. How do you like that? Chicago.
What's up? Ah, Vancouver, Calgary,
Edmonton St Louis. That said we
lost two on this trip already.
Brutal fucking losses. I
got all of my tape. Uh,
I don't have the nerve to watch the
Calgary game. I watched the, uh,
the Saint Louis one. I was really
jet lag last week, so every,
every to Vancouver and Calgary.
But I watched the Saint Louis one,
we called up [inaudible].
It was probably the wrong team to do it.
Some people said, well, who gives a fuck?
He'll be fine. Um, but I can't imagine.
Why don't we try and get rid
of two kinds? I mean, you know,
guys had a little bit of a rough
patch all of a sudden. What?
He's not good anymore. It's his fucking
fault. We lost all these great defensemen.
It's been all these injuries. We lost
a fucking boy, chuck. I mean, come on,
you're gonna blame him. It's
stupid. That's like, well,
you know what that's too,
does shit like that New York does that.
Boston does it too. It's so fucking dumb.
Yeah.
You know,
every two fucking years,
the goddamn giant fans trying to get rid
of their coaching. Fucking Eli Manning.
It's like, oh, you mean those
Superbowl champions? Yeah,
I'm sure it's their fault.
Um, what else? I think that's it. I got
into, I'll watch the end of the day.
Total of 500. I've got to go to that one
of these years. The OT is self someday.
I never been to Nascar.
I've been to two Indy 500 racist.
But you owe it to yourself at some point
to go to any sort of auto racing event.
Because the funniest fucking thing
about it is the difference in intellect
between what's going on in the pit row
and what's going on in the fucking stance.
It's unbelievable. I mean,
you're talking state of the art,
like
mega brains trying to figure out how to
go half a second faster 10th of a second
faster it like 200 miles an hour.
See when by a fucking bumper.
Right.
And then literally you
look across the street,
which is the track and there's some guy
fucking just crushing old Milwaukee,
you know, would dip in his mouth. He's
so fat is t shirt can't cover as navel.
That's what I loved and I,
you know, I would love to
say at the Indy 500 you know,
open wheel racing though is a
little more snooty. It wasn't,
you could bring a cooler end, you
get, do whatever the fuck you wanted.
It was a great time.
And uh,
I've been meaning to go
to Talladega and Daytona.
I got to scratch those off the bucket
list at some point. I always forget,
it's just NASCAR starts at such a weird
time. It's a great time. It go right.
No football. This is the time of year.
I was getting into like college hoop.
Like I didn't realize Kentucky was
still undefeated. Saipem watching.
I just hate the fucking pack.
10 I like watching Kansas,
Kentucky and liked tobacco road man.
I like fucking a Carolina Duke, NC
state. I like watching that shit.
It just sucks. The big east has gone
now. Well he's back in the day, man,
the 80s when I first started
watching fucking who?
The ACC and the fucking big east lake in
a five year period I watched like James
Worthy. Uh, Michael Jordan. Patrick Ewing.
Ralph Sampson.
Yeah,
Elijah one. And what's his face?
Clyde Drexler wear out and Houston.
Chris Mullin was Saint John's.
Pearl Washington is Syracuse
and it was just fucking,
every week there was some sort of fucking
epic goddamn battle always would come
down to the end.
Those great coaches,
I forget the coach for St John's always
wearing the Cosby sweaters then. Yet.
John Thompson, who was as big as fuck
in you and almost always wondered like,
how fucking long is his tie that it
goes all the way down to almost as belt
buckle when that fucking guy,
he was like six foot 10.
It's like when a fuck do
you get your suits made?
You know,
just picture like the, like the
haberdashery guy. Like they like Elvis,
like standing on ladders
trying to measure the guy.
MMM.
Yeah. And you had, what's his face?
Okay.
Uh, oh my God. Am I going to
forget his name? Dean Smith.
I told you, you guys all these
fucking stories about, go to the dean.
Don't see Michael Jordan play.
I told you that
as an NBA player right
before the Charlotte,
whole year before the
Charlotte Hornets came,
they tried to get NBA excitement
going on down in North Carolina.
So they scheduled a two NBA
scrimmages during the summertime.
Okay.
And before the NBA season,
probably like in September,
and I went to both games and each
NBA team had a former tar heel on it.
So it was the Chicago Bulls. Michael
Jordan, no championships, still had hair,
still was skinny then bulk up cause
Detroit had beat him up enough. Right.
I saw him play, uh, who was it?
I think the Cleveland Cavaliers that
had a Brad Doherty think his name was,
he's that guy with the fucking hairline
that went right down to his eyebrows.
Who'd actually now he
actually commentates for a
okay.
Stock car racing. And then I saw the
Lakers with James Worthy magic. Karima.
I think Kareem didn't show up though.
He used to weld at that point.
Like man ain't fucking coming down for
that shit. He might have been retired.
It was 87 [inaudible] 87. Um, yeah,
he didn't play 87 88 30. I don't fucking
know. And then they played the Cavaliers.
They had Sam Parker's. That's
right. Anyway, so let me, uh,
let me fucking read some of
the letters for the, Goddamn,
we camped before 40 fucking
go off the rails here. All right. Um,
okay.
Okay,
here we go.
Alpha brain build a half
a man. Thrill ride. Uh,
go fuck yourself. I know your
buddy buddy. With Joe Rogan then.
I'm not sure if he's already
turned you onto onto this,
but his company on it pronounced on it.
Thank you.
Oh, you know what? I think I already
knew it was on and I wouldn't have known.
I wouldn't have known how to say it.
Anyways,
PR produced a product called Alpha brain,
which helps with cognitive brain function.
He's been talking about it for years,
but try to a couple of
months ago and is great.
It helped me focus on a novel.
I'm writing on nights and weekends and
nights and weekend away from my boring
day job. Weekends away from my boring day
job. It's why he should have written it.
A, you always talk about I forget
stuff and have trouble concentrating.
You should give it a shot
and report back to us.
I'm sure he gives you some free samplers.
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself. Ah, yeah.
I don't fuck with drugs other than boots.
I just don't,
you know.
All right.
Sorry. Um, do you that tried to do
with solid thought she was downstairs?
Um, yeah, I'll fuck
around with miracle drugs.
If I have a disease,
I'll do that. Like, look,
being scatterbrained is working out for
me. It does. It just churns more comedy.
I just fucked up and I embarrassed
myself. You know, it's like,
didn't you ever see that episode of taxi
where they showed Reverend Jim before
he fucking ate the pot brownies? It was
just some boring guy with the sweater on.
If I took Joe Rogan's pills and all
of a sudden I started focusing more
that what I would just,
I don't think you'd like me
now. I don't fuck with pills. I
don't fuck with pills. I don't take,
I don't take sleeping pills, you
know, I don't fuck with them.
I think they beat up your liver and he
thinks it's a bunch of shit out there
that they say is healthy in
it doesn't have side effects.
And I feel like the food and Drug
Administration has, you know,
I've seen documentaries where people
used to work for these drug companies are
now they've infiltrated the food.
Uh,
the five, whatever the fuck
it's called. I just said it,
uh, who's a better candidate for
this shit than me? The fruit,
food and drug organization,
food and health, whatever
the fuck it is. I just said,
and I just had it. It's
unbelievable. The FDA,
there you go.
You've got the nuts running and not house,
so they just push and shit
through clear and it, you know,
they're getting kickbacks on the side. I
don't fucking trust any of it. All right.
I think the way I was born is natural.
You know,
I don't think being
scatterbrained is necessary.
It's bad as far as the way
things are set up right now, but
back in the day, if we were still living
in the woods, I'd be fucking killing it.
I'd have those squirrel like instincts,
so I fucking be looking around, you know?
But it just weirds people out in the
office environment. I'm all write with it.
I'm staying with that,
with how I up. All right.
I saw Joe the other night.
I had one of my best sets of the
fucking year up at the ice house band.
I just had a great time.
I saw Joe the other night and I got to
tell you something that Matt had laser
focus when he was talking to me.
He didn't break eye contact.
What's so maybe that shit works.
I have no idea.
I taken any drugs, man. I gotta do enough.
I do enough fucking damage to myself.
Last thing I need to do.
Does that make any sense though?
I play devil's advocate here. Oh
my God, I can't fucking think. Oh,
take this pill and then now you can
think straight. All right, and that's it.
That's it. Right? Those
side effect. No, nothing.
I just take this and magically I'm fixed.
I Dunno about that. They're, there
always seems to be like this,
like back in the day old
school shit like penicillin,
thank shit like that seem to work, but
all this shit since then I feel like the,
the drugs, like they just
sort of peeked at some point,
you know,
and there was no more new drugs
to kind of come up with Lsa.
They fix something while fucking
something else up like Rogaine. Right.
You put that shit on your head,
you grow a little bit of hair and then
your kid has like three feet, you know,
or whatever.
Your heart starts racing and it was always
something good to have your cake and
eat it. This is what I want
to let, it's a brand new drug.
I'm going to let all you guys take it.
All right?
And if 10 years from now you
still have laser focus. All right,
can you levers are fine then
maybe I'll think about doing it,
but at that point I'll be uh,
I'll be pushing 60.
So what the fuck do I
care when I'm pushing 60?
That's what I would start thinking.
Like, what am I going to feel like?
I can try heroin only once.
I'm going to do that.
Most smoke it not fucking
with you. I ain't get it.
I shouldn't say that. This,
you know, people who actually
give me shit about that.
I would never fucking try that.
How many fucking people got it?
That's bad this week to bring that
shit up so I'm not going to, anyways,
that's the trouble with Improv. All
right. Girlfriends. Breath stinks. Dare.
Billington the red. Uh, I been,
I've been seeing my girlfriend for a
little over a year now and if you could
tell me your fucking breath
is stuck the entire time.
I've really not gonna have any sympathy
for you and I don't know how you fucking
bring it.
And the only way you bring it up now
is if you act like it just started.
I've been seeing my girlfriend
for a little over a year now.
We're very much in love and have a
great time when we're around each other.
However,
in the past couple of months I've
noticed every so often or breath stinks.
I'm not talking.
She had ate something bad,
but some deep seated stench that
makes my eyebrow hair burned away.
I noticed that her teeth have a certain
yellow tint to them that is hard to look
away from. It's like a film of American
cheese. Oh Jesus. Sorry for the grocers.
But that's just the truth. It's not
like she doesn't take care of herself.
She's very beautiful, responsible. Anyway,
she has health insurance but not dental
and hasn't been to a dentist in three
years. Well take her, take her. Okay.
Cause she's starting to sound like a
woman that lives in a tree in a fucking
fable.
Um,
I think she might have some buildup
of Tartar or gum disease. Yeah.
Or something she needs a deep cleaning
to start with and then they should have,
if that doesn't work, I would check
for some sort of sinus infection.
Okay.
Yeah. If that doesn't work, uh,
you know, I dunno, consult a specialist
rather than a comedian doing a podcast.
MMM. We're going to move out
together when I go to my new job,
but I'm going to pay for dental insurance
when I make the money because everyone
should be able to see a dentist,
especially as a girls asked him
of her until that day comes,
I want to say something but don't know
how to say it. Obviously I just can't say,
honey, your mouse smells like shit. We're
very open with each other all the time,
but I can't get the balls
to tell her to say this.
Any suggestion from you or the loving
you would be appreciated. All right. Ah,
fuck. I got to get Nia. Nia
for this one. Yeah. Hang on.
Hey Nia.
Nia.
Yeah.
Can you help me on the podcast?
I need you to help me answer a question
cause I can only think of a way to say
it in a mean way.
Okay.
I just,
I don't understand.
Shut up or you're not capable of just
pressing pause and come and get me instead
of I have shit to with a crazy person.
I have shit to do it. What do you want?
I'm watching something. Alright, here we
go. This guy's girlfriends breath stinks.
Okay. Um, I'm gonna, I'm gonna
go through it really quickly.
Can you talk about how
you ate garlic today? No,
I did raw garlic because I had
a sore throat, ate raw garlic,
and then you wash it down with milk. How
gross. Is that too fucking? Yeah, I know.
What's to somehow fixes your sore
throat. I Dunno. Is it working?
No, and I feel like I fucking
ate a lit cigarette. Um,
anyways. I'm just gonna say it real quick.
Was the only of what would microphone.
So anyways,
her breath didn't stick.
And all of a sudden lately
it's just stinking. She's,
he's noticing a film across the teeth
kind of yellowish. She hasn't, um,
seen a dentist in like three years.
How does he, how does he say, listen,
yeah,
I love you but your breath stinks.
I want to pay for you to go to a dentist.
I don't want you walking around the world.
You're going to get a nickname.
Like that's how bad your breath smells.
Does she not brush your teeth? No,
she does. She hasn't been to a
dentist who I said it takes care.
She might have some target built up.
The first thing you'd do is go
brushes her teeth every day.
And she still has all of this going on?
No, we said there's a yellow film. Yeah,
that means he's not brushing her teeth.
Cause why would there
be a yellow film on her?
But she brushed her teeth in the
morning and then before she went to bed,
even if it's once a day, she needs to
go see how does, how does he tell him?
How does he get her to go to the
dentist? Okay. Okay. You know,
I would just say it to me how,
no,
how would you want me to say it to you
if that's, if that was going on. Oooh.
See I practice one.
Let me practice one.
We all know you're going to anyways, it
doesn't, go ahead. Yes, go ahead. Hey Nia.
No, no. You don't have to get up. You can
sit right over there. Stay over there. Um,
do I love you, but it's sometimes I like
looking at you from across the room.
Listen,
I'm only telling you this because I
love you and I would want you to tell me
this. It hasn't been, you know,
the whole time I've been with you,
but at some point in the last six weeks,
like you've had like moments,
especially like actually right now,
like I don't know what's going on,
but your breath really smells bad
and I,
I don't want to be near you
and it kills me to tell you this,
but your breath stinks.
And I think you need to go see a dentist.
I know you don't have dental insurance
and I want to pay for it. Okay.
Cause you're too beautiful to be walking
around with that rotting smell in your
mouth.
You still love me.
I wouldn't be mad at that cause I haven't,
I would start with it.
We're using that to me.
I would laugh at it and I would know
that was coming from a good point.
Would be mortified. Mortified though.
I would be really, really embarrassed.
But obviously,
you know,
if anyone's going to tell me it's going
to be the person that has to kiss you
and be around you all the time. So yeah.
Well then fix it. Fix what I just said.
How's Kaushik? How can you tell it where
a lady wouldn't get pissed? I don't know.
That's actually not too bad.
I don't think. You know,
it's just, that's so hard.
I don't, hey ya. Shit mouth.
Why don't you go see a fucking dentist
before you kill the house plants.
All right. Go eat your
pizza. Yeah, I mean,
I think that's it just to be
really just brutally honest,
but try to do it in a
cute, funny way, you know?
And just be like, yeah. Oh God.
That would be so hard. Yeah,
you're beautiful.
You're too beautiful video walking around
because at least you're throwing in a
compliment your body and faces a 10.
Your mouth's a negative too.
We got to get those numbers closer
together. How are we going to do this?
All right. Can you be fair? Can you
give me a glass of water by fucking,
I ran out of water.
My throat is killing me.
I sound like this woman's
breath. Um, all right. Good
luck with that, sir. All right,
let's wrap this up.
Um,
bodyweight exercises, spelt, B, O, d, y,
boody weight exercises, Willie Bond Bond.
Uh, I heard of the podcast last week.
You like body weight,
exercise me to fucking love him.
Last year I found a great app with a
shit load of great bodyweight routines.
It's called,
is this the one app that you invented?
This might be free advertising.
I don't care.
It's for working out a bodyweight
training. You are your own gym.
I think it's about three to $3
and it's fan fucking tastic.
It was developed by a navy seal fitness
trainer and it has four different 10
week programs for
different fitness levels.
All the workouts are short and
will kick your ass in a good way,
plus a bunch of other goodies.
I can't recommend it highly enough and
I am not in any way feel affiliated with
the APP. It's just a great
workout at a great price.
No equipment needed by recommend
picking up a pull up bar.
You stick in your doorframe for 20,
$30 at target or somewhere.
I started using it back in September
and in a much better shape because it,
because of it. Fucking awesome
dude. Uh, while I'm at it,
I also recommend a regular
full body stretching routine.
I've been doing that for months as
well and I'm as limber as a whole.
It's clamp. That's
something he wrote near. Oh,
what was clam there and for the ladies,
um,
as bendable as a drunk and
louses WIC whiskey Dick,
they a kid see that he was trying to,
it's trying to do one for the women. Yeah,
like a negative noodle deck. You
know, when there's no blood in a deck,
he can bend it. Let me, let me ask you,
if he's talking about how
great and how in shape he is,
why would he ever compare himself to a
limp Dick Women's sucking the common,
I have everything for over a hundred
years. All right. Take this. What is it?
It's a fucking Ricola. Oh, Rico law.
All right.
By the way,
it'll recent study I read about
and health showed that to best,
the two best things you can do before bed
to get a good night's sleep is stretch
and visualize.
Correct.
Um, what do you jerk it off
after you fucking touch utopia?
I'm sorry.
It's so fucking childish and I love it.
So I often stretch and then do a guided
visual mental meditation from Youtube
before bed.
What
does that mean? You're
watching a video, do you think?
I took it to a weird place
there. I didn't, these
guided meditations are Corny,
but they're great.
Super relaxing.
Hope this is his info is useful to you
and my fellow m m p see brothers and
sisters be well, um, you know something
right. I think that makes a lot
of sense. I might try that. Oh,
you don't wanna use it. Do you know
when I was doing the helicopter lessons,
which I'm going back to my final and
much before I test for my license here,
um,
I was having problems with auto rotations
and I just sat there visualizing doing
them but not close my eyes.
I was just like my minute at the end of
the bed pretending I was in there and
the next day I did them, I
was much better. So maybe
there's something to that.
I have no idea.
He said a be well miniature
version of animal to your bill.
Okay. Miniature version of animal. Here
we go. I think this is the last one here.
Um,
if you could have a smaller version of a
normally large animal, what would it be?
Ideally it would be trained and you'd
have it as a pet signed weird roommate.
Well, it couldn't kill me. Um,
I love animals too much to have
a, make a wild animal, a pet. So,
oh they, I have, I'd have a
miniature version of my talk, Cleo.
So even when it flipped out,
when I dressed up like a drummer,
I wouldn't have to worry about it
killing me. That's a lame answer.
I'd have a miniature gorilla.
That's what I would
have made sure gorilla.
Right then I do pull ups as it
climbed a tree looking at me like,
why can't you go all the way up?
But I'd be like, because I'm human,
miniature gorilla. The fuck's wrong with
you. Then we'd smoke some weed. Man,
that's a weed fucking question man.
If you could,
if you could have any animal miniature,
what would you have?
I'd have an alligator man and I'd have
a clip. My toenails, dude. Alright.
Old Billy red face. First
off, go fuck yourself second.
I'm having some issues with my roommate.
I'm in college and share a campus
apartment with one roommate.
My question is how do you motivate someone
to be more considerate? Uh, you can't,
I grew up in a house with
brothers and sisters,
so I try to respect other people and
those who I live with, for the most part,
my roommate on the other hand,
doesn't do dishes.
It doesn't take out the garbage and
doesn't even change the toilet paper where
we're out of it. I've asked him to do
it, do the above, mentioned nicely,
and he gave up on it pretty quickly.
He doesn't even say what's up and make
eye contact when he walks in the door.
I'm not trying to be a Douche,
but at what,
at what time do you think I should take
a shit on his bed now or later? Thanks.
Um,
I don't think you need any help.
I think you're mentally
moving in the right direction.
You know, there's gotta be, um,
you don't have communal dishes,
right? Dental start using yours.
Uh, you know, you're going to have
to drop this guy at some point.
Okay.
This is what you do next time. He
doesn't flush the toilet. Yeah.
I would just stick his pillow in
the toilet. I mean, I think that,
what else are you going to do?
What does pillow back on the fucking bed?
Um,
I had a roommate like that.
I had a roommate like that
and we almost came to blows.
And I'm thrilled when you live in with
an animal you live in with an animal and
it's just like,
you're just going to have to tough
it out for the rest of the semester.
We get somebody different and,
um,
is the deal, just know that some, he's,
that's the type of guy that's probably
going to get divorced or he's going to
marry an unbelievably understanding woman.
Um, I fucking hate guys
like that. I never,
that whole fucking,
you know,
you know that stereotype of how on a
guy's apartment it looks like they just
slice a pizza between the cushions
fucking and I never was like that.
What a fuck what you want to live
like that? Never did that. I mean,
when I was living in New York, right? Um,
I had this roommate and um,
you know,
from day one if I did,
fight dirty some dishes and he had a
few in there. I did mine and I did his,
you know, if I took out the trash couple
times in a row, I didn't give a fuck.
And you know what, he immediately was
the same way I showed him respect,
he showed me respect, we got
to look fucking great. Alright,
I've fucking move out.
Other dude moves in and all of a
sudden all the harmony goes away.
He starts telling me what a fucking
asshole the other guy is. And I read,
it took me awhile to
realize this. Like, no dude,
you are the fucking asshole and you
pissed. This guy was a respectful guy.
If he showed him respect,
he took out the trash to without asking.
He actually hooked me up. Took me a
minute to figure out the math on that one.
So you just got a bad roommate and
when you live with that animal,
you got to treat them like a, you
know, you've got a wholesome doubt.
I Dunno what you do.
Just break one of his glasses
in front of them. Just say,
let's just start throwing out his dishes.
Go look, I'm not going to wash up,
so I'm just going to put
your dishes in the trash.
Okay.
Okay. Which is ridiculous. And it will
be like, why I go, because I'm like,
you fucking bitch. Do your dishes, your
fucking animal. I would literally take it.
I mean, I don't know. I don't know if
you can take this guy, but like, I dunno,
that's make us making me go back
to an angry place in my life.
So I'm not going to give you
any more advice. Talk to that.
Don't bring it to violence.
Don't stick his pillow and the toilet.
They'll do that.
It's a short time when your fucking life,
you'll get a better
roommate. But, uh, just,
you learn a lot of lessons with this cut.
And, uh, when you go to meet a woman, uh,
you know, check out her fucking
apartments. Yes, she lives all right.
And don't do a one and done either.
So, yeah, she has over time.
She's a fucking does nothing
worse than a messy woman.
They have way more shit than
any guy could ever have.
Just imagine all your
fucking male roommates. Shit.
Just multiply the amount of sneakers.
He has times 20 fucking pairs of shoes,
all that makeup and crap fucking animals.
I used to clean bathrooms and um,
when I worked in this restaurant,
okay,
and you'd think the guys bathroom would
have been dirty or at the fucking a
woman's bathroom?
I swear to God.
It looked like there was a ticker tape
parade and then somebody shit all over it.
I was a fucking right
water all over the place. It was like,
what the fuck are they doing in here?
Because they have to sit down to pee.
They would just build a nest.
I don't know what it was.
It was just an ungodly amount of toilet
paper all over the fucking place and
you'll getting dolled up in
there. And I was just, ugh. God,
it was fucking horror show. Um, all
right. stamps.com everybody you know,
that feeling that you can get when you
can get things done with just a click of
the mouse.
You know that great God damn feeling
it can't get more convenient than that.
And now you can even get your mailing
and shipping done without leaving your
desk.
Thanks to stamps.com stamps.com turns
your PC or Mac into your own personal post
office that never closes.
Talk about convenient buy and print
official us postage with any letter or
package, uh, using your
computer and printer.
Then just hand your mail to the mailman.
Drop it off at the mailbox.
She now they have to go
to the post office again,
I use stamps.com to send
out all my posters that I
sell at the end of my shows.
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now you spell your
last name bur for this special offer,
no risk trial plus $110 bonus
offer includes a digital scale,
calculates exact postage for letters
and packages you had up to $55 free
postage. Don't wait. Go to stamps.com
before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
enter
burr. All right, everybody,
that's a podcast for this week.
Thank you so much as always for
listening. Uh, that's it. I got to go.
Go Fuck Yourself.
So I'll talk to you next week.