And free.
Oh,
can I do,
hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
April 6th,
2014 and won. Some of you
are probably wondering, hey
bill, you're a, you're a fear,
a full blooded fucking
American, right? What are you,
what are you're coming in with this week's
podcast singing the Canadian national
anthem.
Oh, can a duck we, oh uh,
four.
You know why?
Because my stupid fucking recorder for
some reason I got to talk for 30 seconds
for it to get the proper, the proper
levels. So what am I going to do?
Huh? You sing the national
anthem is what you do.
I was singing about the walls in my house.
Why do people put Shit?
Yeah.
Oh no walls.
All it
does is crack the fuck
and plaster there bod.
If you don't have pictures on the wall,
people think you have
bodies in the basement. Um,
speaking of all Canada,
how about those Boston Bruins?
Turn it on when they needed to turn it on.
All you fucking fans up there and Otto
was skating down the river on your way to
work.
What'd you think was gonna Happen?
Did you think that you are going
to catch the big bad Bruins? Huh?
One in the original six.
How dare you Ottawa?
You stand down,
you stand down and you
watch that river melt.
You watched the water run like the tears
going down your fucking frostbitten
cheeks cause you ain't making the
playoffs. Playoffs, the fucking playoffs.
The Bruins are,
and I'm calling it right now.
We're going to play the Montreal Canadians
in the first round and we're game
one.
We're getting our first win against
those fucking silly shock French Fox.
Oh French people love their silly socks
and their little pocket squares going
into the game with their blue blazer
thinking that they know more than the
fucking coach. Those cuts. Right.
What beaten him in game on?
That's what we're doing. What's going
to happen in game two? I don't know.
I didn't take that far,
but if you would like a prediction,
I just heard the door slam.
I think my wife just woke up.
She's pissed at me already. Um, if
you would like a prediction, uh,
I say that we come out there
and we, we win again. Yup.
Then we'd go down to Boston,
right? Oh, shared. Well,
don't you take eight to nine?
Is Your fucking a killer?
We're going to sweep them up.
We're not going to sweep her money.
No.
If we're going to fucking
get out of the first round,
but I can tell you right now, if
we, if we actually, if I'm fucking,
I'll tell you right now,
if I'm a Montreal Canadian
fair and I got to be thinking,
if I'm playing the fucking Bruins,
if we loo,
if you guys fucking lose to us after the
season we had after the domination that
you guys fucking it. You got
to, you can't tell you this.
Not Creeping in the back of your little
French fucking brain. There is, you know,
your little want to be French braid.
You're not French. You're Canadian.
That's right. You're part of North
America. You're part of, you're,
you're attached to us. This
obesity, it goes right up over.
The fucking board is right up to your,
Timmy.
Ho's with you guys sitting there eating
your fucking donuts. What do you think?
You're better than us because you get
you Canadian GG fucking donuts with you.
A little pinky sticking out.
Ah, with your loafers. No socks.
You little fucking pocket squares,
Huh? Is that what you think?
I'll tell you right now the playoffs
to, I'm going to go total cliche here.
Prostart who to Hulu? Susan. Oof.
[inaudible] though.
They're play their play desperate.
We'll tell you a little desperate tables.
Dangerous.
Did you guys watch any
sports this weekend?
Can somebody explained to me how
it was constant beat Kentucky.
Somebody explained to me how a team
playing the game of basketball,
a team that is wider than my thighs
somehow beat the Kentucky wildcats.
C. Dot. That's why you
can never be prejudice.
You can't be racist because it is
always going to prove you wrong.
I don't know shit about hoop. I don't
know shit about college basketball.
I don't know shit about a lot of things
and I sat down to watch that game and
I'm looking at that number 44 in
Wisconsin. I'm like, this guy is a mess.
Look at him.
He looks like he's in a jam band.
This guy does not look like a fucking
basketball player and all of a sudden he's
doing all this Kevin.
Yeah.
Cale stretching around. I don't know. It
was, it was a hell of a game. And, um,
I actually, uh, I become a
Wisconsin fan just because of,
uh, uh, I told you guys this, a
couple of guy developed the show with,
and I want to talk to Nick Craig.
It was a big Wisconsin guy. And uh,
so I like those guys. So I
root for the team, but however,
I'm also a big Kentucky Fan.
So it was this weird thing I didn't know.
I love John Calipari and,
uh,
a John can of Perry over the cold.
Let's go to [inaudible] cal pair.
We will be all flooding.
We're gleaning a little clear, I'm
sure. So, yeah. Um, yeah, you know,
I fucking love Italians and I love
Italian food. So he has this guy.
And then I also like how Calla Perry's
a little shady, you know what I mean?
How did he turn that
program around a Memphis?
Somebody explained to me how I never
even knew that Memphis even had a school.
Forget about a fucking basketball
team and next thing you know,
he brings him to the final four.
Maybe didn't, I don't know.
I'm just repeating shit. I heard other
people say, I'm just repeating shit.
I heard Bobby Knight Pitch About, Huh?
That fucking drunk with power maniac.
Good Lord.
You ever see anybody needs a bit more
of a swift kick in the ass and that guy,
Jesus Christ, right? His fucking Khakis.
Uh,
my hope when they bury with me,
they bury it may face down Joe Critiques,
Kid Kiss
my ass. Hey Bob, whatever
you want us to dope.
That's when he fucking went off the rails.
There was some rails and
he went off on people.
I'm speaking of going off the
rails. Uh, I would like to,
I'd like to commend of for a certain
channel out there right now that's a,
is not responding to a bunch of
horse shit that's coming their way.
That's the exact way you handle
this.
This new era of,
of offended over nothing.
This guy tweeted something in 1840.
I don't know about this and you've got
to go back six fucking years to find
something bad that somebody tweeted about
Jesus fucking Christ.
What do you break out? A
boat, an old borscht belt
joke. I'm sure I'll find fell.
You know what I mean?
Fucking people.
Jesus Christ and other comedians
getting involved. Well what the fuck?
What is going on? Everybody acting
like a bunch of goddamn babies.
Fucking grow up. There you
go. Pill birth. Speaking out.
Vaguely. Vaguely at best. Um, so I
didn't do shit last night. Oh I know,
I know. I did last night. I got
absolutely fucking Hamad. Um,
got hammered when I get drunk.
I called the people I love and I leave
long rambling messages about how great I
think they are that I'm that guy.
So you get mad at me cause I
call you at three in the morning,
then you wake up in his lab. I was nice.
That was nice. He was speaking of me.
Um,
I actually,
I have one thing in my office that is
hanging on the wall and uh, it's a,
it, it's a pit bull
calendar. I don't know why.
I forget where I got it. I think, isn't
it called for the love of Pit Bulls?
Isn't that what it's called?
I think that's what my
calendar is called is great.
You just look at this adorable
pit bull for a whole month. Right?
And then all of a sudden the month change,
it's like,
I just changed it this morning for,
for March to April.
And I literally turn the thing and I
just went, no, I'll look at me. No bold.
And I just laughed at myself.
How pathetic I am. You know,
even my dog right now, my dog's laying
on the, on the floor, it's beds,
got his back to me. It's embarrassed,
embarrassed by its fucking master. Um,
master fucking magic. Give me a
fucking break and not as things master.
It's run the Goddamn House. Um,
Shit's wherever it wants to.
And then I pick it up. I'm
the master. I don't think so.
Does the master walk
around? Huh? Then again,
the dog is on a leash.
I Dunno.
It sounds like a bad 80 standup Dick.
Why?
That's a good fucking character.
How filthy Seinfeld. Um,
a bad impression of Seinfeld wellbeing.
Completely filthy. I'll work on that. Um,
well when you put your Dick in her eyes,
don't she always cry?
Ooh,
sorry. I'll go fuck yourself.
You fill an hour every week. Um,
anyway, so the Bruins and
making the playoffs, I don't
even know if they in yet.
I think that rent, I have no idea. Um,
we got to play the capital's tonight.
Nobody gives a shit, so whatever. So,
so Wisconsin,
the fucking white.
His team since the Washington
generals is playing Duke.
All right. The Duke, the Duke,
I'm sorry they're playing Duke tonight
and I don't know shit about either team.
All I know is that coach k always
seems to fucking win these games.
So what do you think's going to happen?
Huh?
Do you think these cheesy eaten
yogurt making ice cream sandwich,
scarfing down fat fuck of a
state is going to go down.
Where are they playing? Are they
playing the Lucas oil? If you know,
they actually annoyed me that they will,
that they sold it out there at Lucas oil
field and I was thinking about a gym or
say making all that fucking money,
you know, and it's just like, what,
what is he going to do now to try to
attack the Patriots because that fucking
jackass can't beat us.
Hm.
Oh fuck
you fucking cunt. You such a, you know,
you stole our offense then you won a
super bowl. Isn't that enough? Leah?
Jimmy, Jimmy. Um, so ridiculous.
It's the only owners name
that I know him well.
We have an old Bobby Craft who made
all that money with the cheese, Denise,
which brings us back to
Wisconsin. Um, so anyways,
I'm going to watch that game tonight
and uh, and I think that's it.
I think that's all I got. I don't know
what else I'm going to do. I went to F,
I drank, I guess stopped drinking. Dude,
I drank way too much this fucking week.
You know, I have nobody, you know
what is, I have nobody to answer to.
All right. You can sit there
and say that you know you're,
you're one of these people, right? Oh,
I'm one of these people. I just, you know,
everything in moderation.
Fuck you. Shut your face.
All right? You're wearing too much
makeup, first of all and shut your face.
Okay?
First of all, the reason why you don't
drink it cause you have a fucking boss,
which is like having a parent, all right?
So I don't want to fucking hear it.
You have somebody to answer to.
Anybody can be fucking responsible
and not drink when they have a child,
okay?
When they have a boss, when they have
somewhere, they have to be the next day,
all right?
When you really find your willpower and
what you're made of is when you have
none of those things. When you
have no children, you have no boss.
You have nobody to answer to. Your
wife's cool. You know, you snore.
She just sends into the guest room,
right?
That's when you find whether or
not you're an alcoholic or not.
That's when you see if you're really
going to pass the fucking test.
And I'll tell you right now, oh, freckles,
all freckles is failing miserably.
Oh my God. I was drinking. A buddy of
mine was fucking leaving town. So I,
we go out and we fucking drink and he's
got a buddy of his and at one point the
guy comes over with like, I don't know
what it was. It was some sort of fuck,
it was like red bull
with a Jaeger shot in it.
And I have to commend myself for
the, for everybody. Fucking drank it,
but me as like, I'm drinking scotch,
I'm a fucking drink in that. She says,
Christ fucking mouthwash and monster
drink the fuck is wrong with you,
but you're homeless.
I could literally go out to the dumpster
and find something better to get drunk
off of. What the fuck? What the four red
bull at a gate, whatever the fuck it was.
Okay.
Was given all of them shit. Like why
don't you just fucking, you know,
do a shot of shampoo and some fucking
licorice. Um, is that what you said bill?
Well, you know, I don't really remember.
I don't really remember. I just remember,
uh,
being smart enough not to drive.
I don't do Uber though. I'm old school
man. I got a taxi, but everybody can hug.
I'll do it. I'll fuck it over.
Yeah. It's just weird to me, man.
I don't like just getting
in a stranger's fucking car.
Okay.
You know,
without that fucking partition there some
sort of writing on the side of the car.
You know,
a phone number of somebody you can
call off when the guy takes out an ax.
Okay.
I just,
I don't understand like
how lazy are serial killers
that they can't even fucking
muster up.
Okay.
Well I guess that makes them more,
I,
they can't even muster up
to fucking wear with all,
just to become an Uber driver.
Why don't you make your life easier?
Quit fucking pulling over and
dragging people in the car.
Why didn't you just become an Uber driver?
Just let him get in the fucking car.
Why don't you just do that?
Is there any checks and balances on it?
You just fucking show up and there's
a guy, hey, how you doing? Hey person,
I don't know what the company that,
I don't even know what it is.
Does it even exist? Is it in the
air? Is it a digital company?
I don't understand any of this shit works.
Speaking of that,
you know what's the dumbest fucking
thing I've seen in a while is the fucking
Iwatch.
I really hope that that thing bobs,
you really got to sit
there watching video.
Like you're fucking g can't figure out
what time it is and you just staring at
your wrist. Is that what you got
to do? All those stupid features.
I think they're out of ideas over
there. That's what happened. I'll,
Steve jobs died,
right?
He's not cracking the whip and
those scientists over there, they,
they getting lazy. What are
you gonna make next? Huh?
Earrings that you can watch
youtube videos on. It's, it's over.
Everything that needs to be invented
is invented and that's why all these
scientists are, that's
real reason. All these
scientists, they're dying.
You seen all this shit.
You had another dead scientist,
right?
Alberto Har was a robotics
expert for NASA at the JPL.
And everybody in science knows
that that stands for, uh, the, uh,
jerk plain longitude.
Whether the fuck is,
he died instantly when a single
engine plane, nose dives,
fucking scientist. God, you have
scientists right nosedive shortly.
Have to take off Friday
morning from Van Nuys Airport.
He worked on two Mars missions and spent
years researching how robots work in
harsh environments like
volcanoes and underwater. Well,
I can tell you they work in volcanoes.
They'd fucking melt you to
do research on that. Um,
as part of NASA's team exploring
Mars with the curiosity rover,
ugh.
Maybe that's why he killed himself.
He had to keep what
project you're working on.
Just mumbling curiosity for over the y,
the curiosity rover.
Awkward silence at the dinner table
and then somebody with a GED started
snickering. Curiosity rover, let me get,
cause it's curious fucking eggheads.
It's the best she can come up with.
Bay was responsible for a device that
detected hydrogen on the planet's surface.
As the rover moved curiously
over the surf over the surface,
47 year old nasty that I'll fuck it all.
That sounds to me.
47 I'm going to be 47 in June.
Does that mean I'm good at Psi?
Um,
47 year old NASA scientist help Berto
Bihar helped to prove that there had once
been water on Mars according to
the sad daily mail. Oh well shit.
Daily Mail is a credible source.
Published two announced his recent
death in a plane crash that happened on
Friday in Los Angeles,
California while playing crashes do as
it is where you go into conspiracy theory
right here.
While plane crashes do
happen and scientists do die.
Uh,
Bay whores name has now been added to
a very long lists of scientists and
astronomers who've met their
untimely ends prematurely leading,
leading us to ask,
did bay hard know something that they,
that they in quotes don't want
the rest of society to find out
what the fuck could this guy is
possibly not. I don't understand what
people are saying. Was global warming,
so overwhelming to him and he knows
that the seas, we're going to rise.
So he just pushed the fucking
yoke forward. And that was it.
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
Okay.
This guy worked on robots.
They designed a device that discovered
fucking hydrogen a existed on Mars.
Okay.
How could that hurt it? I, I, you know, I
remember I used to be a conspiracy theory.
I still think that there are conspiracies
and I do think that, you know, I mean,
I'd done,
I'm conspiring right now to try to
somehow do some fucking hour and act like
this is entertaining.
So you guys will listen to this shit.
So you'll come out to my shows.
This whole fucking thing doesn't even
exist and here you are listening to it.
They can get here in some sort
of truth. Right? All right there.
I'm going to debunk all of these six.
Why he
die. Um, because scientists are
underpaid and he didn't have a,
so he couldn't afford a twin
engine. So when this first one, uh,
the first one cut out, uh, you know,
he was kind of a, it's kind of fucked.
Sorry. I Dunno. John Rogers
Tropica disease expert.
Well maybe you got too close to the
disease and if you see the size of his
glasses, I think this is why,
you know what these fucking
scientists problems are,
is they read too much and they
ruined their eyes and then they get,
then they start flying planes and
they drive cars and they hit shit.
You know what I mean? It's got
a shock, you know what I mean?
Is your life is flashing before you and
that split second and then you know the
exact way you're gonna fucking die.
Cause you're a,
you're an egg hedge scientists.
So rather than me just flying towards
a tree doing the macgruber knew no,
they're actually going to,
the library does go to us
sliding against the front of the cradle
vortex and fuck. It can, they can just,
they can do all of that.
Yeah.
Wonder if they're going to be brain
dead, a male. This is just fucking more,
but all right, Glen. Thomas ades
and a bullet expert. Dan, we,
why don't you just work with poisonous
snakes while you're at it guys sitting
there juggling plagues while he's eating
a subway sandwich. No wonder riff.
Let me guess. Did he die of a bowler? Um,
and a spokesperson for the
World Health Organization. Well,
this isn't that the trifecta.
This guy just shuts everybody
down at the dinner table.
Maybe people were sick of him
dominating the conversation. Right?
This is my husband Glen Thomas.
He's an a Bulla and aids expert.
And what he's not doing that.
He's a spokesperson for the World
Health Organization. What do you do?
I tell shit jokes in a strip
mall. Um, a bola expert,
Glen Thomas,
who looks surprisingly like Chris
Elliot was among the 298 people who were
killed when a Malaysian airlines flight.
Mh 17 was shot down and cracked in
the UK. Well, what the fuck? Yeah.
Okay.
He got he. Yeah, I mean, what about all
the other people that, yeah, well that
died on there, but there was some
plumbers, couple of teachers.
How come everybody's paying attention
to the scientists? You know what,
this all this shit comes from.
It's the fact that everybody knows,
everybody knows everybody's got, yeah,
everybody's got some secrets. Right?
And you know there's people up there.
Just the excitement. They must have,
you know,
having the cures for diseases or whatever.
The just the shit that they
know, like say they, you know,
they're talking about this giant
fucking iceberg that's going to melt in
Antarctica, that's going to raise
the entire fucking ocean eight feet,
which I don't get.
It's like how big,
okay.
At what point is it
stopped being a glacier?
It's just all of Antarctica is melting.
You know what I mean?
And I don't understand how
Antartica right. It's just
all fucking ice. Basically.
You sitting there floating in the
fucking drink, you know, if you put,
if you put ice cubes in you, and this
is what I'm really going to sound dumb.
If you put ice cubes in a glass of water,
the water goes up.
So isn't that ice already in the fucking
water? I don't know what's going on.
No Bill. It's on land. Is it?
Is Their land underneath there?
I don't know what it is. I just
thought it was a bunch of frozen water.
And the reason for this is
the sun is hitting the top.
I used everything I want for my whole
life. Everybody told me the reason why.
Okay,
I'll ask you guys this.
Do you know why it's hotter at the
equator than it is at the pulse?
Do you know why?
From my whole life everybody said,
well it's because you know it's
closer to the sun, you know,
because it kind of puffs out, right? Like
when you had too many donuts, it's gotta,
you know, or it's got a
little muffin top, you know,
it's got a lot of water weight down there.
Like so all of a sudden you're whatever,
you're like this club much close to the
sun it. That's actually not the case.
Just waiting for you guys
to fucking yell at me.
What's basically is is it's getting direct
sunlight and as the curvature of the
earth goes up, that sunlight angle,
it becomes more angled. And again,
you're not taking a, it's basically,
let's just put it in terms,
everybody can understand the equator
is getting a facial from the sun.
Okay. It's not wearing glasses
either. Okay. It's just,
it's just taking it right in the face.
All right.
The polls are kind of looking
away and fallen out of the
way. Right? That's basic.
What does it, so it's a
glancing blow. They still got
a little jizz in their hair,
but it's a lot easier to wash off and
that's why it's a hotter at the equator
than it is in the North Pole. You
see that everybody? I'm smart.
I know. Thanks. Now, like
everybody says. So anyways,
let's get on it. So how did this, how
and Glen Thomas Dye is understood?
He was one of them,
one of more than a hundred researchers
who were aboard the flight on their
weight or an international aids
conference in Australia. Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Wasn't it?
Because there was some more on on the
ground who couldn't tell the difference
between an f 16 in a seven 47
okay.
Maybe he had a quote, you
know, like those meter maids.
It just got to start writing tickets and
it was getting towards the end of the
month. The edge shut anything
down yet. And he was just
like, fuck it. I get fucked.
Fuck it up. They're moving.
I don't give a shit.
It's a fucking drone
or a Goddamn parakeet.
I'm shooting that fucker down and all
of a sudden they come flying over.
Yeah.
All right.
Mark Fairy.
Oh Jesus. Yeah. Grow Up.
Hey, you're fucking fairy.
You had to deal with that. His whole
life is poor bastard. 59 years old.
Nuclear engineer,
a renowned American engineer was found
dead in his hotel room in Salford after
his heart suddenly stopped working.
Isn't that mysterious? Isn't that weird?
But somebody could have a
heart attack at 50 died.
This is the dumbest conspiracy ever.
Mark Ferry 59 from Tennessee.
Well there you go.
Sort of Tennessee grew up on fried food.
Jesus Christ,
they barely even have books in that state.
The fact that this guy became a
nuclear engineer grown up, you know,
we didn't have shoes, right?
And he just sat there.
He was just this fun going anomaly
on his crickety front porch,
watching his whole fucking family
playing instruments they made out of the
fucking junk they had in their front
yard and he's just sitting there going,
I'm better than this. God dammit,
I'm going to start reading.
And he did. He started reading like Johnny
Appleseed, except instead of walking,
he was fucking letting his eyes walk.
Walking all over those books.
Yeah.
Turning them into apple sauce.
That's what mark ferry did.
I'm going to eulogize this guy.
Okay.
Mark Fairy wasn't dumb luck
the rest of us in this state.
Okay.
That mother fucker. I know
I'm in charge. I'm sorry.
Or I'm speaking from the heart here.
Okay. Is understands that mother fucker.
He said, I'm getting out of this state.
All right, I'm gonna. I'm going to read.
I'm a find me a book.
First of all,
you know he had to go to lease to Georgia
to discover he was walking the wrong
fuck and why you thought I was going
to say something good about Georgia.
Danielle. Fuck Damn. Fuck Damn. Bull
dogs, right? Go balls, golf balls.
So this fucker said, wait a
minute, I need to go up north.
That's where they keep all the books,
right?
Cause we lost one fucking war and they
got to take away all the books. I get it,
I get it.
So he walks up to Ohio
and he found himself a fucking book
and next thing you know he became him.
So he became a nuclear nuclear engineer.
I don't really know what that means
and I don't know what that does,
but he did it.
Okay,
you're not going to believe
what the fuck just happened.
My stupid recorder got full.
I fucking eulogize that guy
for like another five minutes.
God dammit say it's a conspiracy.
They shut off your little recording thing.
Let me finish this.
I got to go back to this guy mark ferry.
So he walks up to fucking Ohio,
get themselves a God damn book and
he becomes a new player engineer.
And as I mentioned before,
before the fucking Illuminati
shut off my fucking recorder.
I don't really know what
a nuclear engineer is.
I just know it takes a long time
to say it. So that's some shit,
but I'll tell you there's mark.
Very. All right. And I beat him up.
I call him a fairy. I did all that.
I never really even locked the guy.
Who the fuck's kitten. Who? Oh,
I'm sorry Martha. I had to say it.
I'm in God's house. Go tell
true. Come here number seven.
I want to ever, it is fucking bitch. She,
she deserves that won't see me outside.
Anyways,
this mark ferry.
All right.
Despite him leaving Tennessee,
he never forgot who the fuck he was.
I'll tell you right now,
ain't nobody up north dies of a heart
attack if 59 medicine southern shit.
All right. You know why that is? You know
why that is? Cause I don't give a fuck.
How far are you leave Tennessee.
You ain't leaving that died. Yea.
Leaving had died and British gets
them ham hock and piggers sandwiches.
He probably had he probably a barbecue
grease all over their lab coat.
That's right man. A real
southern man. Y'All.
You've met southern man
that makes it to 60.
If you make it to 60 is to sell the man.
I hate you.
You're laying down with another man. I'm
sorry. Putting the whole phobia into it.
Well that's true.
According to the Bible.
Um, so there you go. Let it go.
Evidently mark ferry was not
a fairy cause he died at 59.
I blew somebody once to the truck stop,
but I didn't do it in this day,
so don't make a gay. Anyways, mark ferry,
he dead now and I'll tell you right now,
I don't think you're ever going to see
another nuclear engineer coming from the
state. You ain't going to see
another one like that guy in a long,
long fucking time. All right,
so everybody raise up your jars.
Okay.
It was shot at shine from our
fair. Um, recorder's still going.
It is still going. So basically what you
guys missed is, as I continued to read
these fucking like any conspiracy theory,
it's like the more you start reading,
you start believing professional Carol
amp. Bruster. Okay. She's 69 years old.
69 you think? Ah, she had a good run. She
was found by a roommate and a kitchen,
all right. With a knife in her neck and
she'd already been stabbed in the chest.
So it's just like, that's
usually not what's Ha, you know?
Okay.
It's the other one had been hogtied
and burn to death. It's like, what?
What are you scientists fucking gang
bang. And now, you know what I mean?
I'm starting to bleed the
shit. Here's what, here's one.
I actually believe Shane taught 31
phd in electrical engineering
with an expertise with gals,
gallium nitride, nitride, Shane, Todd,
the man with two first names.
All
right,
here's the mystery.
Dr. Todd felt increasingly uncomfortable
with the work he was doing with the
Chinese company. Who, who are we?
Who, who are we? Who the fuck are,
you know, so I can't, I'm
sorry. I can't do that.
Maybe if I did an a bad Chinese accent,
it will work. Oh wait, hold on. Fuck.
Are y'all, um, to the point Shane told
his family sweaty. Got, who are we?
H U a Weei
man.
They must be cheesy commercials.
Any ways to the point.
Shane told his family that he was being
asked to compromise US security and he
feared for his life. Now this guy
got whacked. Of course he did.
What the fuck are you doing,
dude? You'll be over your fucking,
you're wearing the wrong
fucking lab coat here. Melissa.
Can nudie scientists have weird names?
She was hogtied and Bernard. I'm
starting to believe this shit. This guy,
58 died of a heart attack.
Zachary died of fucking boating accident.
That happens, right? Potomac.
Everybody's hammered on the fucking
botanic nother part. Attacks.
Heart attacks a dismissed.
Here's a weird one. Fan.
John Mang and Chung Yang
Sang [inaudible] Chung exam
table for two Zang,
a drown in a branch and
hotel swimming pool.
Both were in China. Both up were
from China and we're working, dude.
How the fuck does to people drop?
Two adults drown in a
fucking hotel swimming pool.
They don't even have deep ends anymore,
right? All you gotta do is stand up.
I mean, I'm going to go
up. Maybe they got drunk.
It's like fucking too
bouncy steps into the side.
You've got something to
hang onto. Oh, Jesus Christ.
I'm starting to believe this shit.
Gregory Stone 54 from an unknown illness.
While that happens,
Bradley 56 died in a car crash. What?
You know, they're reading, they're,
they don't have good eyes.
Okay.
Dr Masud Alley.
Mohammed d 50 was assassinated January
11th when a remote control bomb inside of
his motorcycle near his car was detonated.
I mean,
that happens an avenue.
A buddy of mine the other day,
the professor of nuclear physics at Terra
in university was politically active.
Oh yeah. Yeah. He, this guy got
whacked. You should see his picture too.
It's like he knows it's coming and got
a couple more days left for this shit.
Jack P.
Wheeler,
the third 66 last seen December
30th found dead in Delaware.
A Delaware landfill. Yeah. He got whacked
anytime. He ended up in a landfill,
fought to get the Vietnam memorial built
and was served and served in two Bush
administrations. His death has been
ruled a homicide. Yeah, of course.
It has its price. That guy's a fucking
hero. That's a terrible one, is
it was a horrible website. It
can't stop reading it. Mark A.
Smith 45 do this guy looks like he's
90 that's 45 I'm a year older than that
guy.
Renowned Alzheimer's disease research
or has died after being hit by a car at
Ohio.
Yeah.
Is that suspicious? I don't know how many
of you can try to say this woman, Zane.
She was dead.
I'm an apparent suicide by cyanide.
Okay.
At a temple terrace hotel,
she left a suicide note saying she used
cyanide Hazmat team officials said the
cyanide was found only in a granular form,
meaning it was not considered
dangerous outside of the room.
It was founded and chemical is considered
more dangerous in a liquid or gas form.
Potassium cyanide,
the apparent causes potassium cyanide,
the apparent cause of deaths as a
Kimberly come and use it. But I, I,
I don't understand what the fuck that
is. I mean, she said she, you sign,
I just fucking right there.
Okay.
Now the woman died at the hands of Amy
Bishop. Her background was in Jason's.
Who would've thought, it's so fucked
this, these guys are dying like a,
okay.
Bloods and crips here. Anyways, let's
get to the, uh, enough of that shit.
I don't even know what to believe anymore.
I don't even know what to say anymore.
What's going on? Um, all right,
let's get to some of the, uh,
some of the questions here for the
week. No, no, no. What am I doing?
I want to get to some of the advertising
trunk club. Everybody Trunk Club.
The first rule about trunk club is
you don't buy any more fucking shirts.
Trunk Club, guys, you might hate shopping,
but you still want to look good, right?
Do you want to look good for the ladies?
All right, well maybe you want to look
good for the Fellas, but either way,
don't you want to look good?
What have you could start?
What if you could snap your fingers,
hey and have a trunk full of clothes
that fit perfectly and make you look
amazing?
Where was this shit when I was a kid?
You're going to love what gets delivered
to you from Trunk club@trunkclub.com
slash burr. You answer a few
simple questions about your look,
your style and size,
and then they assign a real person who
helps to style you and don't lie about
your size. People are also, you can have
a bunch of tight jeans coming your way,
smuggling your grapes.
Then they email you a list of
clothes they recommend sending you.
You approve and at no cost to you.
They ship a trunk full of fresh new
clothes to your door. Try them on,
keep what you want, send back what you
don't in their prepaid box. That's it.
A better wardrobe than you could ever
pick out yourself and mental minutes.
Then I mentioned the services
free your stylist, the shopping,
the box,
even the shipping,
all 100% free when you go
to trunk club.com/burr only.
Pay for the closure. Keep no ongoing
subscriptions, no hidden charges,
no
fucking malls.
Just great clothes.
Handpicked for your style.
You know is is great too.
This is great for crossdressers who are
still ashamed. You know what I mean?
They could just deliver it to your door
and be like, yeah, that's what my wife,
you sign it and you get the fucking,
you know,
you get to try on a bunch
of shoes. Um, here we go.
You're gonna thank me on this
one and now it's completely free.
So go get started@trunkclub.com
slash Burger today.
That's trunk club.com/
[inaudible] all right, here we go.
The Classic Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody,
you heard me talking all
about dollar shave club.com.
The company that delivers amazing
razors for just a few bucks.
I know a razor that costs a few
bucks delivering what? I know,
a razor that costs a few bucks.
Delivering a great shave seems
too good to be true, right?
Me Reading that sentence correctly
was too good to be true. Uh,
but you really have to try the razors,
the dollar shave,
dollar shave club.com razors. Give me
the most amazing shave I've had in years.
Don't pay triple the price when you can
get a fantastic shave delivered for just
a couple of dollars. When they
see you getting clothes delivered,
the fucking shave,
you're out the door.
You have to be an idiot to
keep overpaying. All right.
I am a massive celebrity and I'm
constantly getting my picture taken by the
Paparazzi who was his because
copy supposed to be for
this Jennifer Aniston have
a fucking
podcast.
Why would she get docked tea?
Coffee?
Why would she get this shit not to shave
a fucking favor? Oh, in an image that is
anyways,
don't pay triple the price.
When you can get a fantastic shape
delivered for just a couple of dollars,
you'd have to be an idiot to keep
overpaying. I already read this shit.
You have to be an idiot to
reach shit you already read.
Don't be fooled by the price. These raises
are legit and they will never go back.
What?
And you will never go back.
Plus they got Dr Covey's easy shave,
but it's phenomenal.
If you're still using old shave
L's fashion shaving cream,
you're a loser and I feel bad for you.
Try it.
Try Dollar Shave club.com/birth
today to get started.
You wish you had started sooner.
That's dollar shave club.com/bird
dollar shave club.com/burr.
All right, we got to do one more.
Uh, people, this is, I'd love to say,
I think this is,
I'm going to blame the booze on this one.
I can't fucking eat foods. I
said, well check it out her
fucking mouth. All right. Draftkings
everybody. The wait is finally over.
Baseball season is
here@lastandtheexcitementcontinuesallseasonlongatdraftkings.com
the
official
fantasy partner,
daily fantasy partner of the major
league baseball daily fantasy means now
seasoned long commitments. Just
instant cash. Instant gratification.
Why wait until the end of the season
to claim victory when can win huge cash
every day. Let's fast forward this
shit. Huh? That draft kings.com.
It's kind of, it's like a brand new
season. Every time you play you play,
just select two pitches and
eight positional players
stay under the salary cap
and you could it be on your way to an
enormous payday. I think that's cool.
You got to stay under the salary cap.
You feel like a real gem there, don't ya?
Last year.
Peter,
here comes Peter cottontail
hopping down the bunny trail.
Peter from Colorado won 1 million
bucks that you won 1 million bucks.
Jesus at draft kings in one day
just playing fantasy baseball.
He later was found with
a knife in his neck,
a hundreds of thousands of fantasy sports
fans just like you have already one
cash it draft kings, now it's
your turn. Call to action.
Hurry to draftkings.com now and
enter the Promo Code Defense,
d f e n s e to play for free.
You could win part of the $300 million
in prizes being awarded this season.
Use Promo code defense for free
now@draftkingsdotcomdraftkingsdotcomthatisdraftkings.com
right
there.
All right, there you go. Let's
get back to the bullshit here.
Do you guys have a Nice Easter?
I had an awesome Easter.
My mother in law came over right? And
uh, she actually wanted to go to brunch.
Okay. And I was just like, oh. I was like,
oh,
GG age.
Oh my God,
I thought this was a day of celebration.
Why would you drag us into the
hell of Brunch on fucking Easter?
A yard of your mind, right? This how
cool my wife is. I just say to, I said,
she goes, do you want to go to Brunch
with me and my mother on Easter?
I was like, no, I don't.
I don't want to do that.
Why don't we go drinking on
St Patrick's Day? Why don't,
why don't we go out on new
years and go to Times Square?
The fuck are we doing here? She's
like, I know. That's right. I go,
why don't we just have brunch at home?
I'll make some eggs.
I'll throw in some fucking waffles
whenever you want. I'll cook it right?
She goes,
I got one better for you.
Why don't we just sort of some fucking
Chinese food? That's what we did.
Chinese food on Easter.
Don't Jewish people eat Chinese food
on a Christmas. I got to tell you,
I loved it on Easter. Why stop on
Christmas, those Jews, I'm telling you,
they're on to something. This fucking
Chinese food on on Christian holidays.
I'm all about it, dude.
It was awesome. We had a,
what do we have there? We
have, we had, uh, we had,
I don't know what the fuck
we had crab ran Google,
all that deep fried shit that's fucking
sloshing around in my belly right now is
tremendous.
And then she showed up with a lemon
meringue pie and that was my Easter.
No bunny, right? No fucking
going down to church.
And you've got to listen to the Jesus
story over and fucking over again.
You know what I mean?
It's such an amazing story.
You think that they could make a good
movie about it? You know what I mean?
I mean, technically it should
better than all of those
born identities, but it
isn't, I don't know what they
need. They should make just,
you know, if I look the Catholic
churches, who's kidding, who,
it's sliding down a grease
pole. You know, nobody's buying.
Nobody's going anymore. All
right? It's like it did.
It's like the Jacksonville Jaguars of the,
of fucking religions as far as you
know, old stadium. Nobody's showing up.
Plenty of seats. What do you want to
sit down in front? Get you got it.
It's all you. All right. You can hang
out with the fucking players afterwards.
So when I would do is I would,
I would invent like the eye
Catholic church, you know,
just rip off apple to get these kids.
You get flat screens in there, right?
You do. You get Tupac, whatever they
did to him where he became the, the,
the homogenized version. Where the
fuck is it? The the Holyoke graph.
What the hell has it? Because
it was an h, a holograph,
a little cube, whatever the
fuck it is. You do that,
but you just do it with the priest.
You have some of the best priests
of all time. The two parks,
the fucking biggie smalls of priests and
you bring them back to life just like
Jeeva. Fuck it. You just bring
Jesus back. That's what you do.
Yeah.
If I'm up there right,
he comes down from the fucking all
pixelated coming down from the ceiling.
You know what I mean?
People don't believe it's him
at first day. Oh, what are you,
did you fucking make dad?
You shoot that with a potato?
Laughing my ass off on the floor over
here, shaking my head. That guy, you know,
you got to take a little shit
from the Twitter Razzi right?
And then all of a sudden you
just, you just keep saying
no, that's actually Jesus.
Right. And if you watch that
thing on Scientology like I did,
you know what I mean?
What did you learn?
Other than the fact that it just takes
2,600 lawsuits at the same time and the
IRS will cave. Uh, that's the only
thing I learned other than that is,
is that, you know, is that they all,
they dress like they're in buck Rogers,
which is, you know, it's kind
of cool, right? I'm going to
space movies. No, I ain't,
what the fuck? I'm saying
you get some flat screens,
right. Get some Chinese food,
you go easy with the guilt and
you bring them back, you know,
and you try as hard as you can
to not fuck any more children.
And I think he could turn this
business around. This is like,
that's what does that,
what does that show with?
A guy comes in and he's tries to to fix
your bar. What's it called? Bar Fixer.
Huh? Dive doctor. Whenever the fuck
they is, some stupid name, right?
It comes in your fucking beer. Tap
smell whacked. My wife's but Jen. Oh,
July. When she gets off and
elliptical. All right. Just
even at people about their dumb ass bars.
Do you just got to do that
with the Catholic Church?
You just go in there screaming. He
why's that guy? Fucking a child.
All right. Can you turn the whole
fucking thing around? What would it be?
Gotta be alleged literation like Christ
fixer, but it's gotta be with another c.
Cry.
Christ crier.
Jesus. Jammin I don't know
what the fuck you call it.
Christian mingle.
How bad is that Christian mingle.
How fucking creepy is mingle
that's going on here and mingle.
I really want to see your tits.
It's just seems like you'd just
be mumbling a bunch of shit.
I don't want to see it. There's no
fucker. No three way. Oh, I'm sorry.
All right, here we go. Let's,
let's, let's read some of the, uh,
that's really some of the
fucking questions here for
this week, shall we? Well,
I don't give a shit. I'm
running shit. Okay. By the
way, if you'd like to email me,
if you'd like to hear me read out loud
something that you wrote and butcher it,
uh, emails can be sent
to bill@thempodcast.com.
If you would like to follow us on Twitter,
you can go to at the m m
podcast. All right, here we go.
Here we are a hug if somebody were
rough on here. Okay. All right.
It is my husband to cheat.
Dear Bill,
and I'm a 34 year old fucking lady
and had been married for six years.
I'm hoping you can help me with some
advice on my marriage. For the most part,
my husband and I are pretty similar,
but we have completely different
outlooks on finances already already.
I'm already thinking sexist shit
here, so I got to stop. All right.
I'm picturing you just buying a bunch
of dumb shit that any of fucking you're,
you're driving them to an early
grave. But let's see. Maybe, maybe,
maybe this guy is a cunt. That'd
be openminded here. All right,
open mind. My husband works full time
and I work part time myself and I'm,
and am a
startup with my husband works full time
and I work part time myself and am a
housewife. I swear to God that's how
she wrote the sentence. Should be.
And I am a housewife and am a housewife.
You'd never have fucking three short words
that begin with a in a row myself and
am a housewife and Ama and am a housewife.
That's awesome.
My husband works full time and I worked
part time I thought and I, my house,
like I get it. You fucking spoke
this into a speaker, right?
That little magic device on your
phone. Um, early in our marriage,
we both work full time,
but it became difficult for me when I
would clean the house on days off and he
would not be helpful in sharing
those duties. Oh, this guy,
he's old school lifting his feet up
as you come by with the fucking swift.
Um,
he would Paul's,
he would just play video games and
I'm not a clean freak or anything.
I just don't like living in a
shit show of a house. Oh my God.
I fucking love this woman. You're right
up my alley. Uh, before we were married,
he would let dirty laundry pile up for
weeks before he washed it. Jesus Christ.
This guy's an animal. I probably
should've spoke to him about it,
spoke to him about that before we
got married or live together first.
But I did not see it as a huge
issue at a time. Uh, you were young.
What did you know? Anyways,
after a year of marriage,
we decided that the best way would be
for me to do the housework and work part
time and make dinners while he worked
full time. Jesus Christ, this fucking guy,
he's crushing it. You know, he's,
he's got an old school wife here.
Listen, listen. You quit your dream.
I'll live mine when I come home.
You better have this place tidy
with the fucking steak on the table.
Um, all right, here's the issue.
Here's the issue with our marriage
and I would love your opinion.
This is where if I was her girlfriend,
we'd be clasping both hands,
both of our hands across the table.
This is what I need. You. Okay? Oh,
I'm here for you, Karen here
for you. Just get it out. Uh,
my husband is very, um, it's
very conservative with our money.
This guy doesn't have one redeeming
fucking thing. He's a slob.
He's a fucking tightwad.
I hate this guy. Um,
he will save and keep our 20
grand in our finances for any,
well that's smart though. I
don't know. He's kind of smart.
He will save and keep our $20,000 in our
finances for anything that could happen.
I admire it and think it's very smart.
However,
he loses sleep over it and we were rarely
will go out and do anything together
as a couple. Yeah, his guys, he's, oh,
he's taking it too far. All right. Um,
we make enough money between the two of
us to pay our bills and save. Mind you,
you don't get a fucking reprimand. Me. Um,
he gives me a sum amount allowance
every month to buy groceries and other
personal items.
If I use another card,
he will confront me and tell me
not to use the other debit card.
And if I am low on funds for groceries,
we need to buy ramen for
the rest of the month.
All of our arguments are about money,
I believe in saving money.
But at the same time,
I think it's great to live a little and
buy items for enjoyment from time to
time. I love to go out somewhere fun. I'd
love to go out somewhere fun on a date.
Oh my God,
dude,
this is sad with my husband without him
worrying about money the whole time.
I can't buy concert tickets without
asking him first to surprise him.
Like he's kind of,
he's fucking likewise.
He never surprises me
with anything either.
If this thing ends with you
on your fucking hands and
knees scrubbing the floor
boards cause he wouldn't even
buy you a fucking swifty. Um,
what should I do? I've confronted him
about how I think his fear is unhealthy.
Am I wrong? I'm telling you. She goes,
I'm telling you it's a rough one. Okay.
I love it. I love that you threw that in
there. She's got a sense of humor. This,
I think this woman's cool.
Thanks.
I love your comedy and listened to your
podcast every week. Uh, go fuck yourself.
All right. Yeah. This, this
woman's a fucking champ.
The amount of shit putting up with
all right. She's got a sense of humor.
She's listened to the podcast. I Aye. Aye.
Aye. Oh, maybe she snow me, I think. I
think, I think you're totally cool. Yeah.
This guy needs to fuck
and he needs to relax.
MMM.
I don't know. What would
you do here? Just say, look,
something's got to change here.
All right.
Cause I haven't been to a fucking
cheesecake factory and like nine years.
Right? You gotta take me this guy.
He this guy. You know what it is.
He doesn't understand. He
doesn't understand women.
He doesn't, he doesn't eat.
He doesn't get it. You guys
like to go out, all right,
and I think you're cool enough that you
don't like what the fuck doesn't like to
go out. That's such a
dumb thing. I just said,
okay.
I, I, you know, I'm too stupid to explain
it, but I totally get what you're right.
This guy needs to take you out.
All right?
It needs to remind you why you guys
fell in love. He needs to, you know,
just go every once in a while,
just say, you know what? Fuck it.
Okay,
let's go out and just blow fucking a
couple hundred bucks on a meal, right?
That's it. And then we just, Jesus
Christ, if you spent too much money,
it's ramen noodles. I mean this guy,
it's like this. This guy sounds like a,
he grew up during the,
during the depression.
I am you in your nice enough to admire
that he thinks about fucking money.
You got 20 grand saved up,
which is better than most people.
He could just loosen the purse strings.
Let a couple of nuggets fall out once
every six weeks for Christ's sake. Um,
what do you do there? Uh,
how do you go about that?
I don't know. A tightwad that's a tough
one, man. It's cheap. Guy Is just a,
just a cheap person.
They just fucking cheap.
Yeah.
That's like, you're not even going
to enjoy life for Christ sake.
MMM.
I think you got to start roofing in
them. I hate to say it, but you know,
every once in a while the date
rape drug is a, it's called full.
I think you need to fucking, this is
what I would do. No, you can't do that,
so you can't do that. That's fucking,
I'd say I would just fucking,
okay.
Give him the date rape drug.
Let them pass out at the table.
Then I would just go out and booze it up
and then I'd come home and it'd be like,
and he'd just be like, did I, did I
fall asleep? I the kitchen table. Okay.
Last night. Yeah. Yeah,
you did. It was weird.
It was like you were
eating the ramen noodles.
It just, you went facedown
in it. I'll tell you.
Thank God you're too cheap to boil
water and that water was at fucking room
temperature.
You might've burned your face.
MMM,
I you, you either got a roofie
them is in Goa are, are you good?
Are you got to just say,
listen, I need to go out.
Okay.
I can't keep living like some fucking
broadened a fucking miserable fairy tale
that's waiting for is for,
for fucking prince charming.
Didn't show up. All right,
here's the deal.
Fuck. Oh, once a month you're
taken me out. All right.
You're making me feel like a fucking lady.
You're making me feel attractive.
All right, around, I'm going
to start fucking working again.
I'm sitting here watching
your sweaty balls,
fucking underwear and you can't even
take me to a Goddamn Chuckie cheese.
Huh? You cheap content. I
Dunno how to do you know what?
Maybe he's listening to this. Don't take
her out for Christ's sake. All right.
Listen, the dollar's going
to collapse anyway. See,
a 20 grand is going to be worth shit.
So why don't you go out and fucking buy
a pork chop with it while you still can.
There you go. All right, here
we go. Fear of damnation.
Dare Bill.
Growing up Catholic.
Hello
Gj age.
My parents instilled me,
I'm still me with a, a healthy fear
of damnation. Like so many others.
As I got older,
I grew away from the church,
but the fear of going to hell
was never far from my mind.
This is why it's funny that everybody
made fun of the fucking Scientology movie.
Just San us a cult.
Those people are fucking crazy as
opposed to what the shit we're doing.
I love Scientology for the simple fact
that they sued the fucking IRS and they
went, all right. All right.
All right. Jesus Christ.
These people are crazy and they beat
the IRS. That goes a long fucking way.
All right. A couple of kids die
every year due to the common cold,
but other than that, I think it's a good
religion. Um, over the course of my life,
I've had many opportunities to wrong
others somewhere out of necessity and some
due to my own greed or poor judgement.
Jesus, this took a fucking left turn.
Did I miss a paragraph?
Um,
I lie awake at night with the details
of each sin running through my mind,
how it affected those people I hurt and
what their lives would be like had I
never altered it with my
own destructive presence.
What the fuck did you do to these people?
This guy sounds like a
worse person than me.
This sins weigh on me as they should and
I wondered if I'm going to burn in hell
for the things I've done or if I
could possibly turn it all around.
The Bible provides some
details about the afterlife,
but doesn't get too specific
about how each person is,
but it doesn't get too specific about
how each person is tormented when they
reach hell. Well, don't ever read Dante's
inferno. You don't want to read that.
My biggest fear is that after I die,
I would arrive.
And while burning in the internal fire,
your plot chess would
be playing on a loop.
Ah,
fucking hilarious. Please
help me. I'll do anything.
Give to charity, save a
puppy. Whatever it takes.
I have to redeem myself somehow so I
won't have to hear your voice yammering on
about the NFL and cackling
at your own jokes forever.
Yeah.
Ah, you got me. You of a bitch.
That's fucking hilarious. Um, alright.
Icebreaker.
Bill.
I'm terrible at starting a
conversation with the girl.
I'm good in an actual conference I'm on.
And why that guy?
Why don't you just not listening to
the podcast? You know what I mean?
Maybe he listened to one and
I was so fucking annoying.
Or you know what's even better?
Maybe he works with somebody and they
played in like the warehouse. Uh, do what?
I'm sorry. I know I'm annoying. I
can't argue with anything you said.
Ice Greg icebreaker.
Bill.
I'm terrible at starting a
conversation with the girl. I'm good.
In an actual conversation.
What does that mean?
Oh, okay. So you can just like if somebody
says, uh, Hey, welcome to fucking daddy's.
Can I help you? You're like, yeah, I
like texted a placket dude. I'm crushing,
crushing that Shit. Um, anyways,
but I rarely get anyways.
I'm good in actual conversation,
but I rarely get there because it starts
off bad. What advice can you offer?
Do you have any lines or topics that
would work? Thanks and go fuck yourself,
dude. You just going to have to learn
to have a sense of humor about yourself.
You're going to have to fucking bomb.
Okay.
You just kind of have to go up and bought
me this. There's no fucking, hey baby.
What's she assigned line that
works? You've got to just
come up. Here's the thing.
Don't, if you're not good at hitting on
women, don't go to a fucking meat market.
All right?
Okay.
What you gotta do is you got to chat
him up while you're just doing a,
just do it. It's been so long
since I've been fucking singing.
I was never good in the meat market bars.
I was always better.
Like I met women on the train. I met
him in like the fucking gym. Okay.
Yeah,
I met him like,
uh,
like when we were doing like we're
both riding on a fucking trade,
you know what I mean? And there's no, they
don't, they, I, they have their guard up.
I guess you're not going to be
a mugger the fuck would I do,
how would I talk to them on a train?
I would just wait for someone if I saw
someone that I liked on a train. Uh,
the only way I could start up a fucking
conversation is if some crazy homeless
guy got on the fucking,
you know,
some crazy person gone on the subway
and everybody's got that Oh shit.
And then you make eye contact with them.
And then I always had a joke about the
fucking homeless guy. That's right.
I took the piss out of somebody who didn't
have a house and that would break the
ice and then maybe,
you know,
okay,
no, you're on the subway.
It's like speed dating.
You got to try and get the fucking
number before they get off. Um,
okay.
But if you're not good at conversation,
you've got it. You got to get good at it.
And, um, I would say the
Jim, Jim's kind of creepy,
hey, what are your working on? You know,
she's fucking bent over doing bent
over rows. Whatever the fuck it is,
the only advice I have for you,
it's just like doing stand up.
You just have to get on stage and you
just see you have to figure it out. Um,
so that's what I would do.
I would get over your fear of bombing by
getting out there and just bombing and
have a sense of humor about
how fucking bad it's going.
Laugh at yourself and it
just keeps swinging away.
Just keeps swinging away. I don't
know, just uh, go go Ron Burgundy.
Just be like overly arrogant about
yourself. How fucking awesome you are.
And just say the,
the,
you know that she's thinking all this
awesome shit about you. You know,
if you're an average looking guy,
she'll think it's fucking hilarious
and you kind of taken the piss out of
yourself is that angle, you
know what I mean? I mean I
don't, I don't fucking know.
You got, can I ask a married guy?
I have no fucking idea anymore.
Somebody helped us. You know
what? Why don't you guys,
why don't you guys send me in your best.
Okay.
Icebreaker lines.
The only one I think I ever had a good
opening fucking line was when I wanted to
hit on this woman who was,
I already told you this.
I wanted to hit on this woman who
was with this woman who was a redhead
and I walked out my, what did
I say? I said, Oh, I go, oh
hey, another redhead. I go,
you go into the meeting,
and then a friend left and then the red
had thought I was into her and I had to
do like,
you know that swim moved that rushers
do when they get trying to get to the
quarterback. I had to fucking push her
out of the way and talk to the Brunette.
And then she was like fucking
annoyed that I was hitting on her.
And then her friend I think
caved to the pressure of,
or conti friend or maybe she
just looked at me like a,
I don't want to fucking talk to you. I
made her laugh though. I got one laugh.
I think I got one laugh.
And in all my years in those meat
market bars, oh, that fucking horrible.
Fucking horrible. You
know what dude? I Dunno.
You're asking another person that's
stuck at it. I can't help you.
So how bout uh,
how bout a listener's gimme your best
and your worst fucking opening lines,
your best and your worst results.
And I'll read those next week or whatever.
And with any luck,
that guy who hates me,
someone will be playing it in the
fucking background. Neighborhood bully.
Hey Billy, bag of donuts. Hey Bill,
I am 15 years old and I want to know how
to deal with the kid who was bullying
my six year old brother.
Okay,
well you go fuck them
up. Step on his head. Uh,
we live in a cul de sac and all the
neighborhood kids know each other.
They often play at the end of the
cul de sac in somebody's backyard.
I just recently learned that my friend's
brothers sometimes brings over a friend
who's seven years old and this kid goes
over to the backyard at the end of the
culdesac without the person who brought
him and starts playing with the kids who
belong to the neighborhood.
Jesus Christ.
Isn't that just called kids playing with
each other? Now it's all supervised.
The problem is that the kid is an asshole.
He calls my brother's names,
cause my brother names for no reason.
I know my younger brother isn't
lying based on his body language.
Now I need your advice
on what I should do.
I told my brother to come get me so
I could come over and talk to him.
I was going to be as intimidating
as possible without yelling or being
threatening by completely
keeping my calm and emotional
and emotionless as he tried.
Wait a minute.
What the fuck just
happened to the sentence?
I was going to be as intimidating
as possible without yelling or being
threatening by keeping completely calm
and emotionless as he tried to bust my
balls. Wait, what the fuck happens?
Would that sentence that was in
the past and in the presence,
you tried to do that and
then he bust your balls.
I don't know what's going on here.
I don't necessarily know if this is a
good idea. I was looking for advice.
Should I tell my friends moms,
so this sheet,
this little shit can never come back.
Thanks and go fuck yourself. Ps,
if you are reading this on Friday,
April 3rd it's my birthday.
I'm not reading it Friday, April 3rd
but happy belated birthday. All right,
that's okay.
Okay.
That fucking email was in
like 12 different times zones.
So what should you do? I don't
know. Just walk up to him.
You're 15 he's seven.
Hey Yo.
You know what's great about
that age? If he, if he,
if you catch him off guard with a hey,
they might piss themselves a little bit.
You just walk up right behind him.
He just go high like that.
Like fucking ps himself and can
I talk to you? They'd be, Hey,
can I talk to you for a
second there again, that's
my little brother over there.
He's, he's telling me you keep
calling them bad names. What's,
what's going on with that? Me just
let them sit in the awkward silence
and then when he tells you why
he's doing it, just say, look,
if you keep doing that to my
brother, I don't know. I, I'm just,
I don't know what I'm going to do,
but I just keep picturing my entire hand
covering your face and then me throwing
your whole body like a baseball
over that fucking fence.
You don't want me to do that because
you weigh enough while you might land on
top of the fence and that could, uh,
that could poke into your entrance there.
Do you want me to do that? Because
I don't want to do that. All right,
well then stop fucking with my brother.
Your little shit.
That's what you do that don't do that.
You have to be an adult.
You have to go over to that fucking kids.
Awful mom and say,
Hey, can you fucking, you
know you're awful fucking kid.
Okay,
I know you're a single parent. That's why
your kids stinks. All right. Legal, zoom,
everybody.
Legals on five things you can count on
when using legal zoom for your business.
Ready? Number one, reliability.
More than a million people have already
trusted legal zone to help start their
business. If you're looking to
incorporate form an LLC or nonprofit,
get a DBA or more legal zoom can
help you get started the right way.
Number two,
experience.
They've been helping business
owners and legal challenges.
What they've been helping business owners
with legal challenges for more than a
decade, you can count on legal zoom
for all the details. Number three,
helpful support. They have the right
people on hand to answer your questions.
All based in the United States.
Jesus Christ was that echoing
number for legal advice.
Since they're not a law firm,
law firm,
legal zone built a network of independent
attorneys available in most states.
They can get advice on
the best way to get plus
provide content,
contract review and other useful
services to help you run your business.
And finally, number five, no surprises.
Legal Zoom provides complete transparency
with upfront pricing and customer
reviews and they have a hundred percent
satisfaction guarantee. All right,
they have a hundred percent satisfaction
guarantee and make the smart choice for
your business@legalzoom.com today and
don't forget to enter burpee you are
are@thecheckouttosaveevenmorelegalzoom.com
Promo Code Burr.
And lastly, but certainly not
least, Lee a stamps.com everybody
stamps.com everyone makes mailing and
shipping so convenient and saves you time
and money.
A buy and print official US postage right
from your computer and once you try it,
you won't go back to making time consuming
trips to the post office to get you
started. stamps.com has a
special offer for my listeners.
Just use my last name bur
bur to get a no risk trial.
So there's nothing to lose plus $110
bonus offer that includes a digital scale
that calculates exact postage for
letters and packages, no guesswork,
and up to $55 free postage.
stamps.com is easy to use.
Print postage for your letters
or packages right from your desk.
Then just hand them to your mailman.
Over 500,000 small businesses are using
stamps.com and you should too. Uh,
I use Samsung [inaudible].
He's sending them out when use
stamps.com to send out my, uh,
Billy Bible belt tour posters.
MMM.
For the big tour coming up though the
really big shoe and if I'm a moron,
if I can do it,
you can do it too.
That can figure out how to use
the scale and all that shit.
Remember for my special offer, go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top of
the homepage and type in Burb, B u. R. R.
All right. That is it for that
mercifully reading out loud.
Portion is fucking over.
Alright, don't save.
Let's click over to here. Let's, let's
read the last, the last couple here. Um,
oh, the last one. 20 year
old blonde female request.
All right. That's already annoying
because you feel like what? Why?
Why do I need to know?
You're a blonde female and how old you are
you trying to get preferential
treatment here ladies? No. Okay. Bill,
my boyfriend and I absolutely love your
podcast. You're a favorite comedian, Yada,
Yada, Yada. Could you ask,
yeah,
I'm not going to say the name and your
next podcast to marry me and I'm not
saying your name. Go Fuck
Yourself. Love this person. Ps,
when are you coming to Portland,
Oregon.
I'm going to be coming
to Portland in June.
I'm putting together another
little bus run that will include,
it's going to be Portland,
Oregon. Uh, Eugene. No, you Rica.
Sorry. Oh, sorry. Sorry.
The people in Oregon. I just
fucked up. Portland, Oregon.
You Rica,
California.
MMM.
Where else?
Fresno.
Why don't I just fucking look it up here.
It's all going to tie into that
Vegas tour. And then I think I,
we ended up somewhere in Tucson.
It's going to be great.
It's going to be me and
Joe Barton, Dick, and, uh,
I think I'm going to get law and
in a couple of those fuckers too.
It's going to be a great time.
So anyways, as far as me, well,
I ask your boyfriend to marry you.
No.
Why would I ever do that to another man?
First of all, you're only 20 years old.
You're too young to get married.
All right? And as a guide,
like the amount of Guy Code,
I would be breaking to put this
guy in that fucking position.
There's no fucking way I would
ever do that. You know what I mean?
And since I've been married,
I've never been that person that said to
a couple that isn't married. You know,
when they did Holly, you
guys, man, I ain't got nine.
We have kids. When are you having
kids? When you shut the fuck up?
That's when we haven't kids. Um, all
right, that is the podcast for this week.
Everybody.
Uh,
congratulations to the Wisconsin
Badgers and the Duke Blue Devils.
I'm hoping for a great
game tonight and uh,
my condolences to the fence of
a Kentucky and a Michigan State.
Um, I watched both of those
games. You know me, I'm a
fucking, I love college hoop,
but I'm a fair weather fan man.
I watch a lot of hockey and then this
time of year I always jump in and I'd jump
in. Um, I just watched
the final four games and,
and watch the, the final,
that's all I do. So I don't,
I don't know what to tell you. All
right. I'm a bandwagon guy. I am.
I'm showing up with a brand new funnel
for fucking hat tonight. No, I'm kidding.
I'm going to watch it over.
A buddy of mine's house was
actually a Duke blue devils fan,
so I don't know who I
want to win this one.
I like coach k one and another one just
so we can become more of a legend, but a,
I'm trying. Hey, well, let me look
this up. When's the last time?
Wisconsin when a fucking championship.
Yeah,
Wisconsin. How do you spell it? Wisconsin.
How do you smell it? Wisconsin.
Stop eating fucking cheese.
Okay.
Uh,
Bass last basketball.
Why don't I put the fucking microphone
down so I can type faster. Last basket
ball.
You guys can get on with your day
at this point. This is just for me.
Champion ship.
There's some fat guy driving a Chevy Luv
somewhere in fucking Rhinelander right
now with a big red
jacket on. Screaming. Um,
college basketball badges.
Men's basketball. All right,
here we go. Here it is.
Every Wikipedia.
We're going to go on Wikipedia.
I'm going to guess that
they want it in the 1950s.
Let me see. Let me see. Let me see. All
right. All right. What do we got here?
NCA tournament champions.
They won a 1941 they made it to the
final four in 1941 2000 2014 and 2015 the
crushing it this century,
the elite eight 414720002000 five.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
They haven't worn it since.
Fuck Hitler was still alive the last time
these guys won. I got to root for them.
I've got a roof for the underdogs
were [inaudible]. All right,
so I'm going to root for the badges
tonight. Uh, although I liked both teams,
I don't give a fuck. I have
weird allegiance, you know,
I'm one of those people.
I like Ohio State and Michigan all
at the same time cause you know,
Adam on from either state,
I don't give a fuck.
I just want to see a good game
and I'm really happy that, um,
that that fucking guy with Bill Clinton,
the hips is now coaching fucking
Michigan. The fuck's his
name. Gavin come back there.
John Wesley Harding.
I can't remember anybody's name.
His brother coaches the ravens and thinks
there's not enough air in the balls.
And that's why he fucking
lose this Jim Facile. I know.
Fucking Jerry Tarkanian.
I have no idea. All right,
that's the podcast for this
week. Thank you everybody
for listening. Uh, this week.
Oh, freckles is coming to Florida.
Florida is not part of the staff.
Don't ever forget that.
Florida is Florida. Texas is
Texas. The South is the south.
I am going to be, um, a [inaudible]
vulnerably. Uh, April 10th.
I'm doing two shows at the Fillmore in
Miami beach and I'm doing two shows,
April 11th at Ruth Eckerd Hall in Tampa.
Um, and there you go. And then I come
back for a couple days and then the, uh,
the Bible belt tour starts kicking
it off. Can't fucking wait. Oh,
this is going to be a fun month.
April 18th. Savannah, Georgia, right?
Savannah, Georgia 19th. We go up
to Johnny, Knoxville, Tennessee.
April 20th, Chattanooga, Tennessee.
April 21st Memphis, Tennessee,
right. April 22nd Shreveport,
Louisiana. April 23rd, New Orleans.
We hang there for a couple of
days. Get shitty, gets sideways.
We get back on the bus. April
26. Huntsville, Alabama. Fuck,
are you looking at then we drive back.
April 27th to Jackson, Mississippi.
April 28th we go to mobile,
Alabama. Get the fuck out. He,
I didn't know I was going there.
Holy Shit.
The fuck song is that?
I didn't know what the hell it
is. Um, who's that fucking guy?
If you want it, you know something.
I, I actually feel bad for that guy.
That doesn't like that.
I laugh at my jokes because he's that
rapper who laughs at his shit and he
drives me up the fucking wall to
who's that guy where he's like,
I agree.
Fucking idiot. He does that too,
but I'm still looking at it.
It's like, okay dude,
look at her. Teddies like,
I don't know what your snickering
about Mobile Alabama, man.
They built all those fucking
ships in World War II.
I learned that watching that
Ken Burns documentary. Wow.
Mobile Alabama. That's fucking,
then we're driving up to Lexington,
Kentucky. Oh my God. This is going
to be the sickest fucking tour ever.
And then we go to Evansville,
Indiana,
and then May 2nd we go to
the Kentucky Derby. Alright,
go fuck yourselves. Come on.
It's tremendous. Um, so anyways,
that is the, uh, the podcast and a,
you know what I'll do, I'll do a little,
uh, I'll do a little preview here,
a little preview on my other tour in June.
You guys don't have to listen to,
to podcasts. It's over, man.
You just listen to me fucking talking
to myself in my apartment at this point.
Um,
yeah.
All right.
None of these are confirmed.
Okay.
Except for the Vegas date. All right. But
rumor has it all right. I heard a rumor
that that bill is going to be Portland,
Oregon.
Okay.
I'm going to be an a Eureka,
California. I got to reno date,
possibly Santa Rosa, San Jose,
Fresno biker, feel Highland.
And uh,
then I'm definitely doing two nights
in Vegas at the Mirage casino and then
Tucson, Arizona. This
is, this is the idea.
Okay.
That we're trying to put this
fucking thing together and uh,
I'd go on there with Joe Barden,
nick,
and then he's going to have to jump off
the bus to go do a couple of dates with
Versie and then, uh, I'm going to
get ahead on a couple of those.
That's stat is the, that is the game
plan as this comes together. Um,
so anyways,
I'm babbling here.
Whatever the fucking enjoying myself
this weekend went a little bit long.
Go fuck yourselves.
This is the Monday morning podcast.
Thank you for listening and
I'll talk to you next week.
Okay.