Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast from Monday,
August 29th, 2016 what's
going on out? Why? Yeah.
Ah, I'm back. I'm back on the time.
No more jet lag and all that.
I apologize for the, um,
I sounded like I was coked up
on my last fucking podcast.
I was listening to what I was cracking up.
I was like,
I literally sound like I'm wired out of
my fucking mind, but if I didn't do that,
I was going to fall asleep. Um, so sorry.
Got a little loud. I got a little fast.
I got a little hyper, but um, I
think last night I finally beat,
I was starting to fall asleep again. It's
seven. I kept falling asleep at seven,
then I wake up at two 30 in the morning
and I, that's not a good time to wake up,
you know, as a person by yourself waking
up at two 30 in the morning. You, you,
you have nothing to do but your mind
to just sit there fucking with you.
You know, what are you doing,
Bill? You're getting older.
I don't everything you're supposed
to be doing and you just like,
you're walking around,
shut the fuck up. You know.
Isn't it amazing how loud your feeder,
when everybody else in
the house is sleeping?
It's so full at two 30 in the morning.
You can literally like I'll be at my desk
and I'll take a pen out of a glass cup
and I swear to God by full,
we'll start downstairs.
What was that?
Oh that,
oh I'm sorry honey.
I put a sock on.
Well can you keep it out of sleeping?
Everything is so fucking
loud at that hour and a,
yeah.
So I've just been a last night I started
to fall asleep again and around seven
38 so I just drove down to the Improv.
Didn't even do a spot cause I felt
like my head was in a cloud and I just
fucking, I just walked around
and talking to people and um,
you know, it was great. I went
down, I got a fucking salad,
you know one of those comedy clubs,
Salads. Except this was a good one.
So I'm back right now cause I got to drop
like fucking 10 pounds before I do my
next special, which is
going to be recorded, uh,
in Nashville at the Ryman
theater on October 21st. Uh,
very excited about
that. And, um, you know,
I gotta I gotta drop like 10,
12 pounds,
so I don't look like a fucking Billy
fat head on this thing. So, uh,
last week was the a, all right, I'll start
doing some cardio, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Still eat like a fucking
jackass and that, you know,
but make attempts to not totally
eat like a fucking jackass.
And now this week is when,
now it's like, all right,
I'm going to the grocery store.
Yeah.
And I'm doing, I'm going back to
my fucking that fucking, I need,
need to lose weight diet,
just like a third of a cup of
oatmeal and a fucking egg over easy.
No fucking toast.
None of that bullshit.
Okay.
And what do I have? Have like a
fucking apple between then and,
and then for lunch I have like fucking
Turkey slices and some other bullshit.
And then around four o'clock,
I don't know what the fire of a protein,
like a Turkey patty with a
little bit of fucking salad.
And then for dinner, a couple hours
later there's another fucking protein.
And sometimes I'll just go like a
fuck it sell. It sucks. It's not fun.
You know, my wife asked me to make
a strawberry fucking shortcake,
so I'm going to do that,
you know, so I'll have that.
I always got to have a little bit of
crack on the back burner. But um, anyway,
so I'm back into that.
Just going to do fucking cardio.
45 minutes of fucking day over there
and hopefully the ship, we'll uh,
start to come off because a,
I was disgusted with myself when I
got back from vacation. Holy Shit.
Yeah,
Dude. I was doing that shit, putting on my
socks and making those noises. Uh, uh, um.
Anyways, I want to thank everybody
who came out to, uh, the, uh,
was it the Silver Lake Casino?
Whatever the fuck it is.
This silver something casino
up there in Reno and uh,
hey was I write about Todd rex t rex was,
I write about Todd rex.
I told you the man was a beast.
I told you he fucking kills. I told you
one of the funniest guys in the country,
this fucking asshole.
I say that most endearing way ever did
15 minutes in front of me and got a
partial standing ovation.
Okay?
Okay.
All right. And I'm sitting
there going like, dude,
you're supposed to be opening the show.
Like, hey, how's it going everybody?
Let's get settled into the little
fucking knock knock. Who's there?
This guy did like a closing
set for 50 fucking minutes.
I heard it from the crowd when they clap,
they didn't want him to get off. Um,
but anyways, we had a, we
had such a great time update.
The crowd was fucking amazing.
And I'll tell you an underrated,
underrated right here and
now is fucking not only Reno,
but Reno is international airport.
Okay.
I don't know why they were all
international. I've never heard him.
But where are you going?
I'm going to Paris flying out of Reno,
like I've never heard that connecting
through Reno and then I'm going to South
Africa. Um, Reno's
international airport, um,
great food. I, when you walk right in,
this is place across from
where they have all these, uh,
they have all this golf where by the way,
which I am totally fucking addicted to
those polo shirts in the fucking action
slacks. You know, can I
just just stop for a second?
Can I just want to thank all the F
unathletic fucking people out there.
All the fat fucks.
All the people who literally if they
tried to bend down and touch their toes,
they do a somersault. I just want to
thank all of you for taking up that gate.
Attempting to walk a couple of
holes and rather than addressing it,
dressing yourself and how
fucking out of shape you are.
You turned around and complained to
the companies that your balls were too
sweaty and that your shirt was too tight
because all of your fat fuck complaints,
right is,
is basically created the most comfortable
fucking clothes I've ever worn in my
life.
I wear them all the time now it's that
get comfortable as hell and my wife hates
them. So it's, it's, oh,
every time I walk out the fucking door,
my wait, wait, wait. Are you going?
You going to go meet Tiger Woods?
Other the greatest fucking clothes over.
It's unreal.
You put on one of those golf shirts,
you go to reach for something.
It just stretches with you.
You feel like you're doing yoga,
but you're like just reaching for a donut.
It's the greatest.
If you're not wearing fucking
golf clothes. All right,
let me tell you something.
If you're an old fuck, like you're in
your forties, like me, 48 sliding into 50,
you are a fucking asshole.
If you're not walking around wearing
just golf clothing, you know,
and the sweet spot is,
is to just buy the clothing and
not get sucked in to that game.
I'm not saying it's a bad fucking game.
It's actually a fun, it's more, it's like,
I dunno, it's like smoking
a cigar with your friends,
but you're also walking around hitting
this fucking ball. Um, I have a good time.
Anytime I played,
just because I do not take it seriously
and I count every fucking stroke.
I don't do any mulligans. I don't say
there's any gimmes I come in and about,
you know, I played nine holes.
I come in and about a buck 30,
you know, and I count every
stroke and I do it loudly.
So all the fucking cheat and
cons that I go out. Well,
it's a gimme that's a Mulligan fuck
you're talking about, let's see.
You know something that's the
only fucking, I'm telling you,
it's why it's not as it is. It is.
It's an activity. It's a fucking skill.
Okay. And the guys at the
top level domain in the lase,
they are athletes without a fucking
doubt. But I'm just saying, you know,
Michael Jordan plays a game of
darts. I mean, he's still an athlete.
You know what I mean? Darts is not
a fucking athletic endeavor. Right.
I Dunno. All I know is the
fucking clothes are tremendous.
And um, you know, it was
great. I was looking yesterday,
I was actually watching this golf event.
Um, I like watching on Sundays. Like,
you know what I love about golf is how
they try to act like it's this upper
crust thing and you listen to the crowd
and you can hear it with the people
yelling.
They all go to the track like golf
and betting on horses in bowling,
you know they're all fucking kissing
cousins, all of them. All right?
And Boland just is like whatever.
We're fucking bowling.
Eat a fucking grilled cheese sandwich as
your role in it. We don't give a shit,
but golf,
golf fans that fucking like that
arrogant in l cut above type of thing.
You know like Democrats,
like Republicans are
the bowlers of politics.
They are not to pretend to be sub. They're
not. They don't give a fuck about me.
They don't give a fuck about you.
And they don't pretend to.
Democrats on the other
hand try to act like they,
they actually give a fuck about people
when they get paid by the exact same
fucking assholes. You know, they
keep the fucking war is going.
They know what's up,
they know what's up.
They didn't want to see
that 1963 convertible limo
pulling up to the White House
staff.
I don't want to get back in that thing.
You will give them what the fuck they
want or you serve will be taking a trip to
Dallas. Um, I know I'm out of my fucking
my, what am I so fucking podcast?
Just relaxed. I don't
know. Fucking read. Um,
but when you listen to the crowd at a golf
event, I'm telling you right now like,
like, you know, you don't, golf actually
has the nerve to fucking pretend.
They think that they have the same sort
of crowd that you find it a formula one
event.
All right?
What you have at a golf event is a
bunch of fat fucking dopes and really,
really comfortable fucking clothes,
you know?
And anytime anybody hits the ball,
why they all have to yell at the ball,
get it.
You know, they, he, he, you know what
it is. You know why they yell like that?
It's because there's so
used to being at the track,
yelling at the dog or the
horse getting outcome. Right?
Come on, you're six. What type, right?
You take it to a golf Canada
Golf Event Day. They, that,
that's just how they're behaving.
If you really look at the people,
if you have time, they're fucking
animals. And this is thing too.
They know their animals and I know that
they know their animals because those
fucking assholes. We'll stand
in front of somebody teeing off,
looking down at like you ever see people
like when the subway's late and they're
fucking looking down the tunnel.
They're doing that while somebody is
driving a professional is God forbid.
I can't believe nobody's ever
gotten killed. Good, fine.
I mean I would have, I'd have a fucking
pan if I was a professional golfer.
Like that would be my nightmare. I hit
some little kid in the fucking forehead.
Um, yeah, the fucking
animals. But anyways, uh,
I cannot say enough about the clothing.
So I'm sitting there
watching the event and uh,
one of the guys who of course is falling
apart, they all end up falling apart.
You know what I mean?
All of these golfers,
I don't understand what the fucking
problem is cause I don't play the game.
But I just don't understand it.
There's nobody stopping you.
Nobody's getting in your face.
You know, like Tony Romo,
you fucking rolled out and somebody
tackled you and you're broke.
You're broke bones in your vertebrae.
Okay?
Standing over a fucking ball. You got
a club. Just hit the fucking thick.
What is the fucking problem?
You're already in the winner's circle.
You're already going to win six figures.
Everything else is fucking gravy.
And then he's like, no, you
don't understand dude. Yeah,
it's a game against yourself will
be once you have that one bad shot,
you know you got, you got to forget
about it, blah, blah. It's like, dude,
you're literally
describing life right now.
I love,
I absolutely love oversimplifying the
game of golf because people have such a
passion for it.
And um,
when people really enjoy something
as a comedian, if you make fun of it,
you get to see them get upset.
And for whatever reason,
if you're truly a comic, it, it fills
up your heart. Not, don't listen to me.
I'm fucking with you. I think golf's a
great game. It's a fun me look, you get,
you get yourself a six of course
light, right? You get yourself a nice,
a nice fucking stick. You know, I do that
right now, but I'll tell you right now,
I can't do 18 holes.
I can't do what I like.
Yeah.
Do an 18 holes. That's like a marriage.
You know what I mean? I'm going to fling.
I want to do, I want to go to a
fucking par three, nine hole course,
you know? Uh, actually that'll
probably go by too quickly. You know,
from smoking a stick, whatever I do,
your honor, I would just like whatever.
Where am I go? Right. This is how I
would like to play golf. I have a cigar.
All right. I like the fucking
thing I should do. Right.
Set it down. Wherever the fuck I said
I have a, I'll have the little fucking,
they've got to have like a on your bag.
You know what I mean?
Remember a Rodney Dangerfield
in Caddyshack. He had all
those extra, you know,
the radio. He had all that
shit. There's no fucking way.
They don't have an attachment where you
can have your fucking lit cigar still
gone. As you stay, have
you address your ball,
you mean stand over and
get ready to hit it. Um,
ugh.
And those watching those fucking old
fucking people getting down on their
fucking hands and knees when they're
on the green trying to read the Putt,
you're watching their face
getting all fucking red, you know,
and you're just standing there
halfway down the fairway. Well,
you just fuck it that day.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Okay.
Trying to take a couple of strokes
off my game. Oh, kill yourself.
Just hit the fucking ball. Just be happy.
You're still walking around. All right.
You Bacon and cheese on leading.
Fuck. Um, that's another thing too,
is then it always ends up getting backed
up or, you know, something that I,
I uh, I just feel too much
stress when I'm playing golf.
There's always that group
of people behind me.
There were always better than me
and I feel like a fucking asshole.
Like I'm ruining the day,
you know?
Like when the few times I've golfed,
I feel the same level as stress.
Like when I'm the first person
and a red light to make a left,
you know,
and there's like five people behind me,
like literally my heart starts racing
because I know that not only is it my job
to make sure that the person behind me
makes it through the fucking light. Okay.
Like the, the person behind the person
is that works out here in la by the way,
for all you Boston people, so you don't
fucking almost get yourself killed.
You know that move you do in Boston
with the light turns green and you just
stomp on the fucking gas and
you cut in front of people is,
as far as I know,
Boston is the only area of the country
that does that and it's totally
acceptable.
Like as soon as the light turns green,
you just stomp on the gas and fucking
cut in front of two lanes of traffic out
here. If you do that, you're going to
get killed. Uh, nobody's ready for it.
They're not good drivers and it's going
to be at least three lanes of shit
coming at Ya.
Um,
my brother came out and visited me one
time and I forgot about that move and we
were on like Venice Boulevard and the
light turned green and he stomped on the
fucking gas and I just put my foot up on
the dashboard was like Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh,
Doh, Doh, Doh.
We made it halfway across and up and,
and he was like, you
know, like when you don't,
like when you're driving and you don't
know what's going on in the other
person's freaking out, but you can't
figure out what you get. Like mad. I was,
I was like, dude, dude, dude,
dude, he just stopped me.
He's like, he's like, why?
Everybody's beeping at him. And I was just
like, dude, you can't do that out here.
You can't. And he goes, all right.
Then we had to just sit there and everyone
drove around us looking at us like,
what the fuck? Anyways, getting
back to the golf thing. So, um,
so out here,
one of my pet peeves is fucking people
who's the first people in line. Your job,
you get out into the intersection, you
get out into the intersection, right.
And you make sure that not only the
person behind you, the person behind you,
yeah.
Behind the person behind you. There you
go to fucking cars back. Jesus bill.
You know, that's why I feel like,
like when I'm golfing, I swear to God,
one of these times I'm just going to do,
I'm going to fucking,
I got this Gopro for my birthday. It's
still sitting on my desk just mocking me.
Gone. Yeah. You thought you could
figure this out, didn't you bill? Yeah.
He really thought you were going
to use this fucking thing. Um,
I would love to give a fuck in tutorial
on how to drive in La. I really wouldn't,
you know what I mean? And I'm
talking, I just had to behave.
There's too many fucking people out here.
The traffic is fucking ridiculous.
I just really want to do this. I'll even
tell you how to be a good pedestrian.
Alright. You get in the crosswalk,
he fucking hustle. Okay.
You know what I mean? I've,
I've been with walking. Okay.
And I see I'm approaching the intersection
and I see that person wanting to turn
in looking at me like,
fuck, you know what I do?
I stopped by wave from throw to third
base coach waving like five cars through.
Go ahead. Go ahead. Cause the
second this thing's turns red,
I can just run a crossed,
it'll be fine. Five cars,
we'll fucking make it and I'll get
across no biggie or I can be a Douche and
just completely not even pay
attention to the situation you're in,
in your car acting like I've never been
that guy and just stroll across the
street and I'll fuck at least two people
out of the light. You know what I mean?
You know,
to start when I'm talking about right
now I'm talking about having a little bit
of empathy,
which brings me to Colin Kaepernick.
Oh, a segue. I am not going to watch,
um, I'm not gonna Watch
any part of this story.
Only thing. I'm a, I'm just going to
listen to what he says, which is I think,
you know,
I'm not going to sit here and these
fucking assholes on sports radio are going
to try to get me all fucking stirred up.
Like what he's doing is going to somehow
bring down this country and second of
all,
like I'm going to say I can't,
I cannot sit there and listen to a
bunch of people act like they don't
understand where this is coming from.
You know what I mean?
This is a good time. I
think. I Dunno, I, you know,
I'm not going to tell you what to do,
but I think this is, for me personally,
I'm like, you know what, I'm
a white male heterosexual.
I could basically within reason
do whatever the fuck I want to do.
Here's a guy who was making zillions of
fucking dollars and he still feels this
way. This is, this is,
I should probably shut the fuck up and
listen to what he has to say as supposed
to. All of these soapbox cons
saw this person. Like, you know,
of course, you know, shows a picture of,
of a soldier who lost both his fucking
legs and writes all this fucking
bullshit. And I so wanted to just
tweet to the person and be like, Hey,
let me ask you a question. What
sets soldier's name? You know,
what happened to that person?
Are they being taken care of?
Do you know anything about that person?
Well, you just fucking whored out though.
The worst fucking thing that obviously
has happened in this guy's fucking life
is, is for your own political
propaganda. I don't know.
I can't even talk about it.
I just can't stand white people who don't
act do act like they don't understand.
Okay.
You know, I don't know.
But you know something,
I can't even get mad because
I'm a hypocrite. Everybody's
a fucking hypocrite.
This literally people out there,
they're going to chastise that guy and
act like they don't understand what he's
talking about when,
and completely not in touch with
the fact that if he moved into their
neighborhood,
okay.
You know,
let's just say he was unknown and a black
guy moved into that neighborhood that,
you know, how not thrilled they
would be. You know what I mean?
But it says this,
the amount of fucking people out there,
it's fucking hilarious if you read what
half the shit that people are writing
this say as guys should be lucky
to in this fucking country blood.
And then in the, in the middle of
that are writing racist shit. Um,
that's why I think this is a great thing.
I think it's great that
he's doing it and uh, um,
it's just a way that to open up by a
little conversation. I mean, I dunno,
as soon as, I don't
think it's, it's, it's,
it's going to turn into a bunch of people
fucking yelling at each other as it
always does. And then unfortunately,
nothing's going to get changed.
It's going to be a bunch people
go on my kids in the fucking navy,
my uncle thought, dear
doctor, you're free to
go back to fucking Swahili,
write whatever the fuck they gonna say.
Completely ignore the fact
that, you know, there was,
there's been an astounding level of
cell phone video over the last couple of
years.
Can you at least admit that?
Have some pretty questionable
fucking slash murderous behavior,
all this shit yet your whole life
that you heard black people saying was
happening now this video,
and I'm not saying all cops are bad,
I'm not saying everybody
black is fucking innocent.
I'm just saying I've seen
a lot of fucking people,
black pinned on the fucking ground.
No hopes of getting up shot the back
of just shot in the fucking chest.
So you kid, you know, if you're a
fucking rational yeah. Human being,
regardless of color,
can you really sit there and act like
you don't understand where that's coming
from? So I don't want to listen to, uh,
I dunno. I, I, you can't fuck it.
You're going to argue with
somebody on their experience.
Let me tell you something. Your, your,
your idea of how your life going is wrong.
And I can say that cause I'm over here
live in my own fucking life. So anyways,
um, I think it's great that he's
fucking doing it and hopefully it,
it goes into a, uh, in a,
in a positive direction because, you
know what, I don't, I don't think that,
I don't think any cop wants to go out and
shoot somebody that's innocent either.
You know what I mean?
I don't know what's going,
I have no fucking idea what's going on,
but I definitely think something
ought to be discussed. You know,
they're now I'm off my fucking soapbox,
but I,
I'm hoping more people than not won't
respond to this guy with fucking anger.
I really don't think that that's
the way to go about it. Um,
but in my heart of hearts,
I know that that's what's going to happen.
I know he's going to get booed on the
road by a bunch of fucking lunatics and,
uh, it, it's going to be ugly.
It's going to be fucking ugly and there's
going to be people holding up signs
and they're going to make his
life experience about them.
Um, which I think is a selfish
thing to do at this point. Okay.
Nobody's saying that you know, anybody
who fights for this country isn't a hero.
Nobody's saying that. I think this
guy's just saying, hey, you know,
my group of people is getting murdered.
You know,
innocent people are getting murdered
in this needs to stop. Uh, how,
how you could be against that,
I don't know.
And how you would then somehow wrap
your fucking life into his shit when you
know, at least I can't do that when
I can drive down the fucking street.
You only have fucking hilarious story.
One time my brother in law, right,
was going to move across this country
and he was driving across the country in
this sheer panic.
My wife and my mother in law
had it instantly a sketch
to me cause I'm thinking,
Nah,
you drive it across the country.
You got to do route 66, you
know, make sure you hit the arch
and they are in full on panic mode
going, don't, don't drive at night.
Always stop in major cities.
Do not get off the highway in the middle
of major said like they were in like
you would think that this,
that he was in Russia and uh,
you know,
okay.
I mean right there,
can you imagine?
You imagine fucking driving across the
country and if you get pulled off in the
middle of nowhere that it could be a
chance you could get shot to death just
because you're reaching for your license.
And I'm not saying it's fucking
everybody and all that shit, but that,
that is actually a,
something that could happen to a
citizen in this fucking country is,
is pretty crazy. So, um, I dunno,
I already said I was off my soapbox,
but I was instantly just
picturing that as a sketch.
That would be like a great Chappelle
show sketch. Now would it be a great one,
Bill? Why I think Chappelle could make
it great. How about that? You know,
just have to really white
guy in the background. Okay.
You got to see old faithful,
you know,
he's big on route 66 Europeans.
I Dunno what propaganda
they sent them over there,
but they are fucking all about,
I've met more God the, and people,
when I go over to Europe that have gay,
they always say you have a
driven route 66. I'm like, dude,
I barely know where it is. I know
Santa Monica is a part of it and um,
I want to say it starts somewhere in
Illinois. Does it start out of Chicago?
Okay.
I Dunno, but they're all about it.
They're all about coming over here,
renting a classic car.
And so many of them are done it.
And they showed me the
pictures. I'm like, fuck,
I got to do that when I get out
there and big daddy don garlics.
Um, all right. Let me read a little bit
of advertising here for the fucking week.
Um, all right, go.
You guys had mentioned going to figure
out my fucking podcast cause I have to
mutter to myself at the time. I fucking do
this shit. I always fuck it up. Hang on,
let me hit pause so you don't have
to go through this torture. Okay.
Just like that. We're back. All right. Um,
let's do a couple of reads here for
the week. Uh, oh, the Tim Ferriss show,
everybody,
you know,
what we hear at the Monday morning
podcasts are huge fans of the Tim Ferriss
show,
which was selected as one
of iTunes best of two 50.
Now,
the Monday morning podcast wasn't.
His show was look how big on being
right now. I could be all upset.
Have a podcast protest. The podcast
has been downloaded by more than 80,
more than 80 million times Jesus Christ.
And in each episode, Tim deconstructs,
world performers from every
walk of life, business, sports,
ad investing or more to find the tools,
tactics,
and routines you can use. Favorite
books, check morning routines checked,
and that's just to be getting
pass gets guest seven clued,
the Great Arnold
layered,
Hamilton serial billionaire Peter Thiel.
The stories are captivating and the
lessons will help you upgrade your life.
Just listen. Uh, just visit, um,
four hour workweek.com/tim,
that's four hour work week.com.
F O U R H O,
u r workweek forward slash.
T. I. M. Jesus. No wonder
he's got 80 million.
You know what I mean?
He just appealed to me all the way
down to people who are illiterate.
The fact that they had the copy had to
spell out four hour and the name Tim
is that t. E. M I can't find
it. All right, loot crate.
Gimme.
I'm looking for gear collectibles,
houseware and more from your
favorite pop culture franchises.
We've got your covered loot crate offers
a range of Geek and Gamer items for
less than $20 a month. Want to
bring you allude to the next level,
get a bigger box,
even bigger lute with loot crate DX.
If you're more the type to where your
geeky heart on your sleeve, then loop
where
then Luke,
where our monthly wearables and accessory
subscription is what you're looking
for.
Get ready for September's high
octane theme speed this month.
Loot crate.
Give me the look.
It has a high octane assortment
of goodies from Batman,
CWS.
The flash is that country
and western and Arrow,
Battlestar Galactica iron man in gone
in 60 seconds. If you have a style need,
you'll love speed loot where collection
featuring sonic socks like Seattle
sonic socks for when you go.
Got to go fast.
A transformers wearable for your world
saving needs a winning Mario Kart t and
more.
I have no idea when any of this shit is
this loot where collection is gonna zoom
away quickly. Come on a
zoom, zoom, zoom, zoom.
You have until the 19th at 9:00 PM Pacific
to subscribe and receive that month's
crate. And when the cut, the cutoff
happens, that's it. It's over.
Make sure to head down to
www dot [inaudible] dot com
slash burr and enter the
code burr to save $3 off
on any new subscription.
I don't know what any of that is.
All right. Frame Bridge everybody,
not Cambridge frame bridge.
Um,
you got an empty walls. You got
something special you want to frame.
Well God damn it. You're never going
to do it because it takes too long.
It costs too much money and it's a
pain in the fork and age. Remember,
remember when cameras
weren't part of your phone?
The way we take pictures to change but
the way we frame them hasn't until now.
A frame. bridge.com is the easy
way to frame the things you love
like,
well I love,
what am I going to fucking
frame symbol.
Some people do that though from the
treasure trove of photos on your,
on your phone to posters in at work.
Frame Bridge makes it easy and affordable.
Just go to frame bridge.com and pick out
the frame you want or their let their
designers help you choose.
You can even preview your,
I just pictured some eight year old
in El Salvador like that's his job.
You know it gets paid like 30 cents a day.
You can preview their
item in any frame style.
This send you a prepaid package to ship
your items safely or you can simply
upload a pick picture onto the
frame bridge site or your app.
You can even upload a picture
directly from Instagram.
They can't make it any more easy.
The extra the expert team at frame bridge.
We'll custom frame your items in days,
not weeks or months,
and deliver your finished
piece directly to your door.
Ready to hang in style
called frame bridge.
The genius sites that
makes framing cust easy.
You know what I'm going to fucking
do. I got to, I, you know something.
When I was over in England,
I sold out a show and they sent me this
little fucking picture of selling out
the, uh, the Apollo Hammer
Smith. So fucking cool.
Looks like I sold a million albums or
something as opposed to selling a couple
hundred fucking tickets.
Um,
but of course it came here and
it's all cracked up and I'm like,
I don't want to deal with that. Thank
God his frame bridge. All right.
Frame Bridge offers happiness
and guarantee their team
gives each item personal
care and attention because meeting your
expectations is as important as meeting
their own instead of, oh, I think it's a
little less important. The end of the day,
you gotta make your money and it can
be homeless. In medicine is Canada.
They just talking pictures instead of
the hundreds you pay at a framing store,
their prices start at $39 in all the
shipping is free. Jesus fucking Christ.
This is too much copy at right now.
When you go to fragrance.com and
use the Promo Code [inaudible],
you'll save an additional 15% off
your first order to just go to frame,
bridge.com, Promo Code Bar frame,
bridge.com Promo code birth. All right.
How many more of these? I've
got to break this up. Uh,
the fuck is it?
What do we got left here?
Yeah.
Ooh,
okay. We got two more simply safe
and MVMT watches. I'll, I'll,
I'll read that shit later. Um,
anyways, let's Talk Formula One racing.
Everybody did. Uh, did anybody,
anybody watched the fucking Belgium
Grand Prix? I watched the replay of it.
Thank God.
I want to thank whoever texts me going,
you watching this fucking race cause I
thought they will off for all of August.
Um, congratulations to Nico. Rosberg I
don't know if that puts him back in front.
I should probably look this shit up. Okay.
Through the magic of the pause button.
I just looked it up.
A Formula One standings.
Lewis Hamilton still in front of 232
points to Nico Rosberg's two 23 bite they
go is really important to come out
of the Craig for Nico to get a win.
I don't know what happened with Louis
for some reason. He started in 25th, um,
25th fucking place.
Uh,
for some reason he had a bunch
of penalties or something.
It's like he had a bunch of parking
tickets and he's like, well,
I'll just pay them all at this race.
And they stuck him at the back of the
race and because he's one of the greatest
drivers are at least right now,
he went from 25th to third.
The guy still made the podium,
which was pretty, uh, which was,
um,
yeah,
which is pretty amazing. Um, I look at all
of this, the gun, a little gossip here.
I've never seen more people bumping
into each other. Yesterday's race,
it was fucking unreal. In the
first turn. The Ferrari team,
they slammed into each other while it's
other client was trying to cut down low
and then he says to his team, are
they ran into me? It's like, dude,
what were you were driving
on the sidewalk, whatever
the fuck you call it. Um,
so anyway,
somebody said Max for staff and will cause
a massive accident sooner or later if
he does not change as driving tactics.
Ferrari driver Kimmy Raikkonen and
says, oh, he must've ran into him.
Reagan was angry after an incident
during Sundays. Belgium Grand Prix,
the latest of series of controversies
related to the Dutchman's driving the
fence said, if I had not break, we
would have had a massive accident.
It will happen sooner or later.
If he doesn't change,
I am fine with good heart racing.
But that is not correct.
A raikkonen swore over the radio because
of a tactic red bull's Verstappen had
adopt. Oh he for stopped
employment with the red bull.
My fault has adopted repeatedly this year,
which is to drive in the middle of the
track and only make a defensive move at
the last moment when he sees which way?
The drivers attacking is coming for
stopping, raking in and Ferrari.
Sebastian Vettel vital collided at the
first corner of the race with all three
cars,
suffering damage.
But it was an incident on the chemicals
straight later in the race that angered
the fin. Other guys defend,
but they do it correctly. Yeah,
I uh, yeah, I guess you're supposed to,
you're only allowed to make one move
is somebody is going around you.
You're allowed to make one
move to get in front of him.
He can't start fucking
zigzagging back and forth. Um,
oh man. It's just, I don't, I can't,
I can't believe I finally got into this
shit and I, as you can listen, you know,
if you actually watch this stuff, I don't
know what the fuck I'm talking about,
but I really enjoy it.
And yesterday's race was the kind of
race than I wish they were all like,
I think when they're fucking
bumping into each other,
it was like fucking Mad Max, you
know? And this track was crazy.
They had like major fucking downhills.
So He'd be coming up the hill and
I learned yesterday, you know,
they call it compression, the cars, you
know, sticking to the fucking ground.
So you've got a lot of traction.
Then you come up over that hill and
they say the road falls away from you,
which really made my fucking stomach
drop because it driving like, you know,
180 miles an hour with the road dropping
away from now you're like coming out of
this seat and this guy in this fucking
yellow car came up over. He lost it.
He got it. Then he just
fucking, it's unreal.
If you saw what the car looked
like after this guy's accident,
you would have thought that like a family
of five was dead and he got out his,
his ankle was a little tweaked,
you know,
I don't understand why they
can't make our cars like that.
We just put on helmets and just drive
like fucking lunatics that I mentioned.
You guys help bad.
I want to buy a motorcycle again.
I can't fucking do it because everybody
just tells me I'm going to fucking die,
but I really want to buy.
I want to buy a fucking bike so bad.
I miss it man.
I want to get that Ducati,
that Deval one,
that cruiser have it all in black.
And then on the side just right
underneath where it says, uh,
the name of the bike just had that
little Italian flag sticker on it.
That's all I want to do.
And I wanna get it.
But Saturday and Sunday morning at
like six in the fucking morning,
cause I had jet lag and I was
walking my dog and be like,
this is the time to fucking right.
There's nobody on the road.
Slow down at every intersection. Just
look, take it through the gears, you know,
ah fuck everybody.
Last night it was talking to somebody,
don't know you can't do it.
I've had fucking three friends of mine,
they'd died and I'm like, yeah, but when
they were young driving like maniacs, Nah,
they were great writers. Somebody else
hit him and I'm just like, why can't they,
I wish they could come up with like,
like a suit you could wear right
where right as you get hit.
What are those?
What does that thing that's stupid.
Then you put on your desk that people
have where you can totally compress the
thing or open, it's like a toy or you
can open it up into this big ball.
Ever seen that toy for kids?
It's a little plastic ball.
You can make it as a really small
building. You make a big one.
What if you just had that thing right?
Because it would be heavy as fuck.
I don't know.
The solution is that you always just
make carbon fiber always seems to be
solution, which evidently is
flammable. Is that what I'm seeing?
I have no fucking idea.
You can't be right. Um,
yeah,
it always does seem a
carbon fiber. Lee. A,
the particles when they go to make it
like the underneath the guy's cars on fire
a little bit. Um, anyways, why can't
they just have something like that?
So when you get knocked off your bike,
somehow it's senses it.
This is in the perfect world and it just
expanse this giant ball around you and,
and the ball takes the hit
right and you're inside of it,
right? Isn't there a fucking
way to do that? I mean,
I can Skype with somebody on the other
side of the planet and there's no delay.
Is that talking to me?
And you can't come up with some sort
of fucking suit that allows a fucking
freckled cont like me to ride
down the street. Oh my God. I, uh,
if you go to Europe,
there's no way to not get into
motorcycles cause everybody's,
there's so many people
over there riding them. Um,
and uh, I got into it fucking
hardcore again and I'm trying to, uh,
I'm waiting for that thing to
go away and it's not going away.
If I just wrote like twice a fucking
week, six to seven. Yeah. I know.
Everybody has to ruin it.
Okay.
Why does this fucking business
have to be in this city?
Why can't it just be like in Montana?
Just the middle of fucking nowhere,
you know,
just a bunch of self centered concert in
the middle of that giant fucking state.
And then he just fucking,
you could go out and cruise on a bike.
Still don't understand why it has to be
here. All the fucking places to pick.
They had to pick here at the middle
of a Goddamn desert, a desert. Um,
I always say dessert and then desert
because of the Lake Greg, Greg Giraldo,
when you talk about the, the, the troops
right in the home during the civil war.
Okay.
Like how eloquent they are. Writing
was as opposed to like, you know,
during the Gulf War, you
know, age fucking hard.
You're not have your ball
sticking against your leg.
Is you sitting out here in the,
in the desert.
A fucking Mr Gun. All right, let's uh,
let's, let's read some questions here.
For some reason, after all the ignorance,
she just heard, believe it or not,
people actually write in to me and they
asked for my advice knowing that I have
no background in psychology
whatsoever. All right, so here you go.
At your own fucking risk.
Jeroen risk. All right, Kenya,
uh, I built, I'm a
Bostonian. Like yourself. Uh,
I'm a suburbian outside of
Boston and I get it right. Okay.
I lived in a cul de sac and played
street hockey. Okay. I wasn't,
I wasn't down in southeast steel in
cars. Good at math. Like an apples.
It's a whole different breed of
tough guy. All right. I had legos,
I had Lincoln logs. I had a
tree fort. Okay. All right.
I'm a Bostonian like yourself
that has a question for you.
My wife is Kenyan and we have a place
near a narrow Nairobi national park.
The government is ramming a railroad
straight through the middle of the park in
clear violation of the environmental
efforts put in place by past generations
for the betterment of the Kenyan people.
Uh,
this park is considered a world heritage
site and this construction would be
devastating. Would you be willing to
champion this cause with your connections?
Yeah.
What do,
what connections do I have to stop?
A railroad being built in Kenya
may not going to lie to you.
My last couple of specialists,
we're pretty damn good,
but I don't know if I can stop.
He goes,
I hope just to bring attention to this
cause as it is being implemented very
rapidly before people
can complain about it.
I can assure you this is a very good
cause and deserves the attention of anyone
who values natures nature.
Now I'm off to fight in the
traffic on the Jamaica way.
Um, all right, wait a
minute. Well you know,
if you send me a fucking link or
something I can definitely retweet it. Um,
but I think the best thing for your cause
would not be me to be a spokesperson
as long as I don't have to speak about
it because I'll tell you right now,
I'm not going to read,
even if I read up on it,
I'm going to stutter and
it's just going to, you know,
as kind of come a cautious
has a dope. Right. But yeah,
just tweet me a link today and I will,
I will retweet it.
And um,
yeah,
I dunno. I mean they're not
listening to their own people.
Then we'll still fucking comedian in la.
Don't John Play yourself pill?
Everything counts. We'll fuck it.
Then I'll positive, okay, I'll,
I'll join the God damn.
Cause
I'll say don't build that railroad
through that park. And then they'll say,
well what's your other solution? You got
to, you got an alternative and I'll say,
no, I don't. All right. Concert Story.
Hey there, Billy vanilla
tits. That's a good one.
A month ago I took my niece the little way
and a couple of friends to a concert.
They wanted to see,
I get free tickets to lots of
shows, Yada Yada. So I took, uh,
we get there and I'm
immediately and immediately
I'm standing out in an ocean of
teens to get into this thing.
Another group of friends show up and they
accompanied by one of the other girl's
dad's. So we say hello and
walk into this situation.
It's pretty slow.
At first,
the opening band didn't have me in mind
when they made music, but they were okay.
The second band came on and they sounded
real familiar. The Dad says to me,
I heard about these guys from bill burr.
They're amazing. So I'm immediately like,
I'm like, fuck yeah,
this guy knows about bar.
So after they're sent,
we walk outside and decide,
I would guess that was 21 pilots because
I went to go see mute math and they
opened,
uh,
for 21 pilots and they had a very young
young crowd screaming like it was the
fucking Beatles. Um, so
anyways, so after they're set,
we walk outside and decided to have a
couple of beers while the kids enjoy the
main act.
That definitely didn't have us in mind
when they made their music and talked
about, uh, Jesus, she talked about me
and laughed our asses off in the lobby.
What a turn. Not only did I get to stay
with my, is this like a fluff piece?
Why was this sent to me?
Okay.
Not saying that you sent the email, I'm
just saying my fucking podcast guy. Uh,
not that I didn't want to stay with my,
my niece,
but I had an excuse to let it hang with
the friends without me standing there.
And if I didn't have this guy to talk to,
I'd be the lone dude in the lobby,
or even worse on the floor watching the
show. But it doesn't end there. All right.
I'm guessing this is one of
the email was sent. Here we go.
While I'm standing out there,
a girl walks through and asked me what
time it is because her phone died.
I answered her in a couple minutes later.
We're talking about everything and
anything. The other dad was a champ.
He laughed at my jokes and then pieced
out when he saw things going. Well,
what was going well?
Not like some married dudes.
Uh Oh, what? This chick came. Wait
a minute. Wait, wait, wait. What?
Oh, I answered her in a couple of minutes
late. Oh, we're meaning you and the lady.
We're talking about everything and
everything. The other dad was a champ.
He laughed at my joke. Then pieced
out when he saw things going. Well,
I don't know if guys like that, right dad,
he fucking made it look like this guy.
He's holding court there.
Has a guy right there that guy get,
he gets in the intersection
when the light turns green.
He makes sure to cars
by and it gets through.
That's what I'm saying about
that guy. He said, yeah,
he made sure he peaced out when
he saw things were going well,
not like some married dudes who don't
get out much and feel the need to flirt.
So they have, uh, something
to jacket too later. Anyways,
I've gone out with this girl a bunch of
times then and got into a new band that
I love,
whose name I won't name because you don't
like to name names all because of all
Billy original recipe tits. Uh, thanks
and go fuck yourself. Well that's great.
That's great.
You know what,
and that's a nice fucking story
for all the cock blocks out there.
You know what I mean?
Those people who fucking cock block,
I've never understood that. It's
such a like a, it's such like a, Ah,
this is bad, so I'm going to trash
women in this and I'm the worst.
I was looking to see that such like
a female thing to do. You know,
chicks have that fucking thing
where it's just like, well,
if something good's not happening for me,
then I'm in.
Everybody around me has to suffer.
That's like what?
That's like the male version of
that is the cock block. Well,
if I'm not going to get laid,
you're not getting like get the fuck
is what the fuck is wrong with you.
You know what I mean?
I said fucking Douche.
Who throws the lady out of the way and
jumps in the fucking lifeboat on the
titanic? That person, right?
MMM.
I Dunno.
I had fucked it.
That's like male behavior and I
still ended up trashing women.
Like what the fuck is wrong with me?
I mean,
part of it is I have issues
with women obviously,
but the other part is it's just
so fucking fun to annoy him.
Maybe that's my fault.
Maybe it's my problem.
Is it wrong that you'd rather
annoy him than fuck him?
Is that weird or is it just sort of a,
as a different approach?
Oh my God. The best people
watching in the fucking world.
Reno International Airport, that fucking
burning man thing was coming in and I,
I was going on, you know, a couple of
everybody kept asking me hilarious.
They're going, are you going
to hang around and go to
burning man? First of all,
it's like two, three hours away from Reno,
I guess. And secondly, it's like, dude,
look at me.
I was joking about that on stage.
I'm a 48 year old fucking bald white dude.
I'm not going to show up there and freak
everybody out. I looked like a cop.
Everybody's gonna be in the middle of
the taken acid or whatever they're doing,
and then I fucking show up looking
like I have a walkie talkie on my,
on my waist. I don't want to do that.
That's, that's some young kid shit.
I hate when fucking people my age right
before the day, just totally just dead.
Just too fucking old.
Even hide it anymore.
I hate when they still try
to go to young people's Shit.
It's over.
It's not your time.
You don't remember when you were back
in the day when I'd be in the clubs,
you know, way back in the day, old Billy
red face in the clubs won't bump it,
don't,
right.
They'd always be that fucking old
creeping. Then you just bleed.
Looking at him like I remember just
looking at somebody who was like 35
even like 27 started to seem old. Like
what the fuck are they still doing their,
we'd like 2021 fake ids getting this
plane. There'd be somebody 27 in there.
Like what? That dude, you should be like
married with kids by now. That's what,
27 now here I am 48.
I don't,
you know what we were fucking
mind to tell you what to do.
It's just my own personal choice. I
don't, I like going to adult shit.
I want to be with the adults.
I don't want to be um,
yeah.
You know what I mean? I don't want to
be around that shit. Oh, by the way,
and speaking to young shit,
I have to give a shout out to a DJ named
Afrojack who I'm not going to lie to
you.
I never heard of the guy.
I'm not in that fucking
world and everybody's sending
me this stag where he took
a clip of some shit. I guess I talked
about Djs like a couple of years ago.
That's how it works on my podcast.
I'll say something and it takes like two
years before anybody really hears it.
Like that car Dashi and thing or
the Yoko Ono thing. Like I said,
those like they did the podcast.
Yeah.
And it goes like two years goes by. And
then somebody who actually has a, uh,
a podcast with influence, like Joe Rogan,
Joe Rogan blew up the Yoko ono thing.
Um,
so anyways,
people would send me this shit
and he did like a, I don't know,
do you call it a song? Is it a
track? Is, is it as something else?
I don't know what the fuck is.
I don't know what it's called.
I don't know what the fuck it is.
But he somehow aligned the shit up and uh,
he put me in a song and um,
as much as I still don't get
what the fuck is going on,
I want to thank the guy because there's
a bunch of young people in the crowd and
uh, you know, performers, you need that.
You've got to keep getting the next wave
of young people is your fans start to
get older. They have kids and they can't
even go out if they want to go out.
You know what I mean?
Like he just,
he probably just stopped me
from going on cruise ships.
He delayed that for another like
six years. So thank you very much.
Afrojack I don't know if
your name is Afro Jack,
like that's your first name or it's if it,
your name's Jack and your nicknames
Afrojack like you know, Billy red tits.
I Dunno. I Dunno what it is, but I
appreciate it. Thank you for, you know,
whatever the fuck you know, what,
how, how have you seen however,
however you could say that
shit. Um, you know, it's funny,
I actually watched this thing
one time with Nia recently,
this documentary on Dj a m can I just
say that again and you guys so I can make
you cringe again. The fact that I as
old as I am just said that name, um,
on Dj a m and I watched it and uh, I
actually started to understand like, oh,
what I to see the,
I know there's an art to everything,
but I actually was really starting to
understand it and Neil was talking about
how one time she and a friend of hers
were in New York and went to some fucking
club and that guy was DJ in there and
she said it was like the sickest night
ever have music and uh, you know,
within 10 minutes of being in the club,
everybody's like,
who the fuck is a DJ?
And then they figured out it's that
guy and I don't know what it is.
I guess it's like what song leads
into the next song? And you're,
you're changing the energy of the crowd,
which I'm relating to stand up, right.
You don't open with the closing bit,
but you got to open strong and then
you've got to take him on a ride.
You bring them up and then they go,
they're going to give you burned out.
You got 40 more minutes,
what do you do?
You take it down a little bit and he
started building it back up Dan a little
bit and then you're throwing them. Fuck
yeah. You know, it's like wrestling.
It's like what I did while I was stone
cold fucking a podcast and he talked
about how you can bring them up down,
up, down, up, down, a little more higher,
a little bit lower,
a little higher.
And then you get a right that last fucking
moment and then they fucking explode
and go nuts. So I dunno,
I haven't said that well.
Like I just fucking,
I like seeing live drummers.
Yeah,
that was a problem my hand when I went
to go see fucking lady Gaga, like I can,
I can go see anybody. If I can see the
band. She had a band and a fucking house.
They're like,
I was in this fucking cast on,
she's riding around on a God damn horse.
Okay.
Oh Jesus Christ. Jesus fucking
Christ they believe was my quote. Um,
okay.
By the way, what, what the
fuck's Tony Romo right now? Okay.
If,
if he was, it's hard
to say this, you know,
cause I could never retire
from fucking standup.
I don't feel I could and obviously he
loves football. The way I love standup up,
I would think, but like this is the time
to retire. This is the time to just say,
you know what? Fuck this. You know,
it's like Ali, those last few
fights, if he didn't have those,
maybe it would have been a
little bit different. I know.
What the fuck am I to say that shit.
I Dunno man.
You fucking break a bone in your back for
the second fucking time. Jesus Christ.
How fucking tough is that guy by the way?
Everybody always breaking his boss.
Um,
okay.
And I probably shouldn't have
said that shit. You know,
I don't know if he's married and he's
got a woman in his life because what if I
just gave her ammo and then I
just ruined his breakfast. Tony,
do you hear this?
You hear this podcast?
You hear what this person who never
played organized football paths,
the fourth grade said,
sorry, look at that.
I'm sitting there fucking
shitting on cop block.
So then I turned around and I make a
move like that. What a fucking asshole.
That's, you know what bill, that's
just typical you. Um, all right, let's,
let's read these last couple then
I'll read a couple more fucking
questions or whatever. Um,
all right. Simply safe.
Thousands of people seeking home security
get ripped off every day and home
security industry and the home security
industry wants you to believe it's your
only option.
They've got hoards of salesmen out there
trying to scare you into signing one of
the alarm turn contracts.
You get stuck writing huge checks
month after month with no way out.
It's robbery by contract and
it can cost you thousands,
but there's a better way to protect your
home with simply safe home security.
Simply safe has no contracts, none. You'll
get award winning 24, seven protection
named best in the industry.
Security professionals watching,
ready to instantly send the police.
It's just 1499 per month.
That's less than half off what the
companies charged. Protect your home,
the smart way. Uh, protect
your home, the smart way.
Visit simply safe birth.com.
Go right now.
And you also get free shipping on your
order and a free key chain worth $25 a
$25 key chain. The fuck is it made
out of? It only takes a minute.
That's simply safe. bird.com simply
safe bird.com and finally, lastly,
but not leastly,
m v m t watches when you're in
your early twenties and thirties,
money can be tight. Just lacked up
pussy. Yo, fuck if you're not careful,
dressing well can drain you quickly.
Have your bank account like spending
four to 500 bucks in a department store.
Watch. There's some brands out there
charging insane prices for watches.
You know what, they're not even worth
it. Well, if you want to look good,
if you want to look great when you go out,
but still have enough money to
buy him or her a drink. Hilarious.
Checkout Movement,
watches.com I've seen,
I've seen them before and
these watches are sharp.
I hate when they say what I've
seen. You sent me some. Yeah,
that Nice watches originally founded by
two broke college kids movement watches,
cut out the middleman and
they're big brand retail mockups.
In order to give you a stylish watch
for an affordable price movement,
watches start at just $95.
I'll watch what department store
quality for a fraction of the price.
They're sleek and minimalistic.
A modern twist on a classic style moving
has grown organically purely by support
is like you.
So join there more than 1 million
social media followers and get movement.
Get a movement watched today.
Go to Mvmt MVMT,
watches.com/berm and they'll give
you 15% off your entire purchase.
MVMT watches.com/ [inaudible] all right.
Um,
here we go.
I think that's it. Okay, let's get back
to the questions. What are the questions?
I'm a little out of sorts here.
Uh,
okay. All this'll be a good one.
Stand up at high school reunion.
Oh No.
Oh, this just has fucking
train wreck written. I'll, uh,
if this is a comedian and they're going
to do stand up at their high school
reunion, uh, it takes
balls, man. All right,
Bill. Fuck you. Sunscreen burr. Uh,
we've missed a couple of reunions now
all my classmates are married with kids,
so we,
I'm guessing your significant other.
I've been doing local
standup for a while now,
but that's been two hours away from
where I grew up and none of my classmates
have seen it. S. C. E. N.
E. They haven't seen it.
Uh, this is why it's great
to get into show business.
You can be as dumb as me and
you can still be successful. Um,
now they've asked me to
do a set for the reunion.
I'll admit it's different for people,
you know.
So your advice on going after the home
crowd that knows you keep it clean,
offensive, use your best shit regardless.
What are your sunburned thoughts?
My sunburned thoughts is you're
out of your fucking mind.
There is no fucking way.
There is no fucking way
I would do that Gig.
I'm going to stand up there in front of
these fucking people that I knew for 15
years of my fucking life and
having seen for 20 years,
and I'm going to be as I'm looking at
them trying to de age their faces and
figure out who the fuck is who?
Oh my God.
And go right back to being like the,
the pecking order.
I'll tell you right now,
you've got balls like right now,
the fact that you just said that,
you know I'm going to do standup at my
high school union is the spider moment in
Goodfellas where he goes, why
don't you go fuck yourself, Tom?
And then Dinair or goes,
oh,
tests like dead pause
shows them in the 40 tell him to go fuck
himself. You know, I, it's kind of like,
don't take no shit off. Nobody. Right?
Yeah. Go ahead and do you know what dude?
I say you fucking do it. And this is
the thing, dude. I would, I would fuck,
I would not hold back.
I would give them both fucking barrels.
The only thing you have to lose is,
is if it goes bad,
you're going to have a great panel story
about bombing in front of people you
haven't seen in 20 fucking
years. Um, my advice would be,
I would definitely,
I would see the humor in the situation.
How fucking ridiculous it is.
Um,
that's what I would do. You know, I don't
have to make some sort of joke that,
you know, after me, you know, fucking
Joe Blow over here was a biologist.
He's gonna come up here for 10 minutes
and look through a fucking microscope or
some shit. I don't know why, but I
have no idea what I would do. Um,
but I've actually, I ain't, you know what,
I've done something like that. I'm like,
I'm not gonna lie to you. I've
done something like that. I, um,
I,
I did stand up in a bar in
my hometown and there was,
it just so happened there was,
there was like, I don't know,
there's like a table of people I went to
high school with and I'll never forget
looking at them.
The look on their face was holy
shit that said fucking guy,
he used to have snowball fights with like,
they're not even listening to that.
Just what they, this is the thing that
they've there, this site, you're doing it.
It's all between. It's all about keeping
your own fucking head together. And uh,
I'm not necessarily good about doing that.
Like I don't even like seeing
the crowd before the show.
I hate that. I hate when before I go
into something, somebody goes, hey bill,
looking forward to the show or
like gay really like your stuff.
I hate that because I feel like
I always feel like,
well now what if I go in there and I
bomb or what if you don't like my shit?
And then you already said that you liked
me and then you're gonna feel bad that
you said that because I stunk.
Like after the show,
I'll talk to people after it went well
and I felt like I gave you your money's
worth. Then denim fine. But I feel like
if I get compliments on the way in, um,
I'm like a, I'm like taking out a loan.
Does that make any sense? I don't know.
Okay.
So anyways, I, I gotta say
as you, you, you got more,
you got more balls than I do.
And if that sounds weird and disjointed,
like from that,
my last thought is because I had to pit
pause and go fucking shut off the air
conditioner. Oh, it's going
to be a fucking hot one
today, you know? All right.
I think this is the last one here.
The last question. All right,
last question here. Uh,
ex girlfriend's sister.
I hate Billy Birkenstocks. Uh, I'm 26. Um,
and still in love with my
high school sweetheart.
We've been on and off again for 10 years
and I've gone through a lot to say the
least. Jesus Christ. Yes.
I just got back from a two week vacation
with her where everything was perfect
and we had the time of our lives.
This is the woman I want to start a
family with and it became more and more
apparent on this trip.
Congratulations. What could go wrong?
Um,
here's the thing.
I slept with her sister on a drunken
blacked out night three years ago while me
and her,
we're not together and we're on bad terms.
Oh boy.
My heart was broken and I had a lot
of resentment. I was 23 drunk week.
Shut the fuck up dude.
You had a dick.
You fucking jerked off to where while
you were dating her other sit, stick.
Get the fuck Outta here. Don't fucking
come at me. I got a dick too. All right.
Don't fuck. And our younger
sister came on to me. Oh my God,
you victim. Things were different
then and I was a mess. Listen,
I'm not saying you weren't
fucking heartbroken. You A, yeah,
you were fucking psych the next
day. There you go. You know what?
You just got to check off a whole family.
Well you got left to do
is bang them mother. Um,
okay.
That's got to be called
something like the Grand Slam.
You don't like when tiger woods won four
in a row and they was saying he won the
Grand Sake, you won, you won. All four
majors would be if you bang the mother.
And all the daughters. That would be
the Grand Slam. Uh, the amount of guys.
Laughter right now. Why the women are
pissed. Uh, well a year or so later,
me and my high school sweet,
he started talking again.
It started to become close
leading up to where it is now.
I had an unbelievable guilt for
what I did with their sister. The,
the closer me and this
girl got years later.
It is the only thing that I haven't been
honest with her about and I had to tell
her, you fucking idiot. No you didn't.
You should have talked to his
sister and just been like, look,
what are we going to do
here? You know, easy. Is it,
how does it make things
better that you told her
that's such as and I, and then like
for the rest of their fucking lives,
that's going to be a problem
between the two of them. Ah, Jesus,
you shouldn't have said
Shit and just waited till 20
years later when the sister,
you know, who never got married gets
fucking hammered and the guy, yeah,
well I fuck Jasmin 25 years ago.
And at that point, you know,
what are you going to do? He'd
be like, yeah, it was, dude,
I was in the fucking two thousands.
What do you want from me? Um,
anyways,
okay.
He goes, well, a year or so
later mean in the high school,
sweet started talking again, blah, blah,
blah, blah. I had an unbelievable guilt.
MMM.
So I had a test sold the last
night of our vacation. Oh my God.
We were laying in bed and
I told her everything.
I took a slap.
She was crying for hours and it was
as ugly as you can imagine. Well,
you know what, Dude, I commend you. You
got it off your fucking chest. He goes,
I feel terrible. And I'm torn on if
it was the right decision to tell her,
my friends are giving me mixed answers
and I would like an outside perspective
from someone who I respect greatly.
Uh,
Jesus Christ. I appreciate the
respect me. Um, I don't know.
Do you know if it was really bugging
you and you felt like you had to tell a
good good,
you told her,
you know
now you don't have to worry about that
fucking thing coming out of nowhere.
He goes, it is still fresh and
everything is confusing on what is next.
We love each other very much,
but obviously I fucked up big time.
Do you think this relationship stands
a chance? I really hope it does,
but I'm worried I ruined it.
She seems to be getting through it
better than I thought after her first
reaction,
she told me she loves me,
but I really hurt her and she
needs some space because when I'm,
oh well she needs some space.
I hope you don't have a brother
because when I'm with her,
okay,
okay.
She told me she loves me,
but I really hurt her and she needs
some space because when I'm with her she
can't be mad at me.
I'm not a scumbag and this is completely
out of character for me to do.
I just made a terrible mistake.
Thanks to go fuck yourself.
I will say the fact that you actually
feel this level of guilt, um,
uh, you're a better man than me
cause I wouldn't have said Shit.
I just would've just been like,
well I hope this doesn't
fucking come out someday.
Well we're having a pumpkin
pie over thanksgiving. Uh,
and I bet there's a lot of people
out there that live with that secret.
My thing is not only the cowardly self
preservation that I would try to have,
I would also,
I'm also thinking like
this is, I, I would have
handled that situation.
I either wouldn't have said shit or I
would just break up with her and just walk
away from it because
I wouldn't say, Hey, by the
way,
I banged your sister and then for the
rest of their life they have to fucking
deal with that.
MMM.
When I'm the piece of shit that did it.
But I have to commend you that you
actually felt that level of guilt and said
something. Ah, cause I don't know.
So it sounds to me that
you're going to get past it.
So the good thing is that now you don't
have to worry about that fucking grand
piano fuck crashing down on
your fucking life someday.
So that's the upside.
MMM.
Maybe there's an upside that you told
her where she'll have faith in you that
like, wow, this guy actually
feels guilt about stuff like that.
So I can't trust them.
We were broken up while it happened.
MMM.
Let me see if I can get Nia in here
for this one. Hang on a second.
All right. The magic of the pause button
again. The lovely Nia is here. Hi. Hey,
I you doing watching the Vma is because
you refused last night and we were
walking cause I was watching the car race.
Is that Formula One formula one was,
is it called? Yeah, I said it
sounded like a swarm of killer bees.
It's a lot longer than I thought it
was going to the corners. Yeah, I know.
Yeah.
Little playstation fucking game boy
they have or a steering wheel now.
I didn't know they had to go around
44 times. That's a lot of times.
Um, well it's a long track. It's
like a four and a quarter mile track.
What's the going like 200 miles an hour.
You can't fucking him driver on a
parking lot. God I know. But yeah,
it was just a lot longer than I thought.
And I know the first time you go to a race
track you don't, you never, you can't,
you can't believe how fucking big it is.
Like I've,
I've gone Bob Talladega and it just,
it just keeps going. And you're like,
oh yeah, they're driving like
a 180 miles an hour. Yeah.
So it's gotta be long. Okay,
that makes sense. Yeah.
And then I fell asleep so I wasn't
able to catch up on all the moments
everyone's talking about. I don't know
what anyone's talking about, but the Vms,
I have to go and watch, obviously
the, not on MTV, but they're all,
they're all online. Yes. Videos
are still produced and made,
cause you're always like,
they don't even make videos anymore.
They do make music videos, but
there will have it, how do I say it?
They don't even make music videos anymore,
but they're all online.
But they do make them and they
still have big budgets to,
so that was gonna be my next question.
All right. Ex girlfriend's sister.
Oh, Geez. All right. Really
quickly, this guy. All right.
I'll give the abridged version A.
I've been on and off again for 10 years.
Just got back from a two week vacation
with her. Everything was perfect.
We had the time of our lives. This is the
woman I want to start a family with a,
here's the thing.
I slept with a and a drunk and blacked
out night three years ago while we met
while we, me and her were not
together and we're on bad turns.
My heart was broken.
I had a lot of resentment.
I was 23 drunk week and her
youngest sister came on to me.
Uh, no. I'll tell you, that's a
rough one there. A real rough. Then
you're like, oh, he makes himself the
victim. She came onto me. I said, really?
I said, dude, I have a dick too though,
fucking light. And I stopped that. I said,
you rubbed one out to her
before you fucking eat.
The seeds have been planted for a while
that you've been wanting to fuck the
sister. Don't try to act like, oh, I was
so heartbroken. You and the sister or both
dirty. Okay, so here's the deal. He goes,
he felt toward terrible the
last night of the vacation,
he couldn't deal with the guilt.
So he told her,
he goes, I tell him,
he goes, I took a slap.
She was crying for hours and it
was ugly, as you can imagine. Yeah,
I'm all right.
She told me she loves me,
but I really hurt her and she needs some
space because when I'm with with her,
she can't be mad at me.
I'm not a scumbag and this is completely
out of character for me to do.
I just made a terrible mistake.
So he's basically saying,
do you think the relationship stands
a chance? I really hope it does,
but I'm worried I ruined it.
She seems to be getting through it
better than I thought after our first
reaction.
What do you think?
Yeah. No, it's, it's not
going to happen. He fucked her
sister. It's over. That's it.
I think so. Yeah. Because I mean maybe,
maybe there are some people who are
more emotionally evolved than I am,
but I couldn't get,
but like that's her sister.
Like her sister's not going anywhere
and like how's it going to be at like
Thanksgiving and Christmas and
like all that kind of stuff.
Like you're just going to avoid each
other or just kind of like, it's weird.
I mean maybe the three of them
can have a threesome. That's
what I was thinking. You can't, you
can't have a threesome with your sister.
That's disgusting. That's
gross. I would never want to see
each other on these bonds. Yeah.
Talking to each other. Hey,
I know we went to a, the
waterpark. Oh No, stop.
Unless the three of them sit down and
both the guy and the sister are so
repentant and so whatever.
But like you,
you'd never be able to trust them.
You'd never be like, Oh yeah,
can you guys run out and like, you know,
get some extra sugar and more groceries.
Exactly. So, and that's the thing.
She might be okay with him now,
but in the end she's going to choose
her sister like that no matter how her
sister betrayed her. That's the
sister. So you are disposable.
You're just like the
dude that's her family.
So if you think that you really like
hands on to her and the sister and the
sister will probably get past it long,
a long,
long ways from now and it'll
probably always still be there.
But because their family family
betrays each other all the time,
you know it's a thing. I think what
she did was worse than what he did.
The sister? Yeah. Oh definitely.
If we're going to like put them on,
who was the worst person?
That situation?
The sister 100% here's what I learned.
You never do that if you're
with a woman. Okay, okay.
And you guys break up and blah blah blah.
If her sister comes onto you like you
are effectively ending that relationship
forever and only they told
her her and the relationship,
you think he should have told her.
The thing about it is,
is that he told her
because he felt guilty.
So it was to unburden his own conscious
because it wasn't real because there's
nothing in telling her that would
make her feel better and oh my God,
thank you so much for being
honest with me. That's the sister.
So I don't know.
I don't really know nothing.
Nothing compatible that he had such guilt
that he had to tell her. Not really,
because people are paired with shielding
all the time and they like, oh,
I had just had to get it off my chest
and it's like, great, congratulations.
It's off your chest and now I feel shitty.
So was that really for
me or was that for you
need Renee hill coming
in and bringing the love?
Yeah, I, I don't, I don't,
I'm not with that whole like,
well at least he was honest
with you. It's like, for what?
For me now that was all for him to,
I never looked at it that way.
Wow. Yeah. Not that I don't think
apologies are worthwhile or I don't,
I,
it's not like,
I don't think that you should
apologize for something you did wrong,
but I just feel like you really need to
question. That's what you were saying.
Yeah.
You really need to take that question.
Your motivations for confessing something
of this level. You know what I mean?
It's like what are you
really trying to do?
A lot of times people are just
trying to unburden themselves.
Well that's what I was saying,
that the best thing now is he got it out
there so he doesn't have to worry about
that grand piano coming crashing down
into his life someday. Like I'm saying,
well they haven't like
fucking Thanksgiving dinner.
What I want to know is what is going
on between the girl and the sister?
Cause obviously that's no sister.
That's no real. I don't know.
That's what I'm wanting.
Something else.
Why that's fucked up is because
now you know that the parents know.
You know, you think she would have
told the parents like, but if they know
yeah. And then they gotta be
like, Oh my God, we raised a whore
and I don't think that she's a whore.
She's on a horse. People make mistakes,
but it's got some really, yeah,
no, no, that's, that's beyond,
that's a power thing yet
it is total power. It is.
I wonder if this was a younger
sister and I wonder like, who knows?
But that's what I'm more
intrigued about now.
It's like what's going to happen with
these sisters? You know, that's like,
that's some deep shit right there.
So I don't know.
That's like a power thing on
her thing saying like, you know,
it was much as you're into her, you still
can't fucking resist me. What is it?
Yeah,
maybe so because who does that?
Who goes after the medicine
to the female mind? I,
I can't let you win on that.
That's not a female thing.
That's like a dirty ass ho bitch,
nasty person.
I don't know what that's like.
I would never go after, uh,
relatives like significant other.
So where do you draw the line?
What do you mean coworker?
So you're not
just so that people know because you
really have strong opinions on this.
So I want to know too. So family
obviously. Yeah, no you don't do that.
Yeah.
If the person that is clearly
in a relationship with
somebody else and you know
that all of that together,
I want to know that.
I want to know where you draw
the line. Coworker. You've okay.
You guys occasionally up lunch together
with the sisters. Coworker. Yeah.
And there's something the guy's got like
he does like the Paisley tie with the
suspenders.
Camera's that something that you guys
always go nuts about that no belt.
Yeah. Well if you have suspenders, you
don't need a belt. So, but anyway, um,
what if he has both suspenders and a
belt and then you're thinking like,
I don't know what it is
that you're trying to do.
Well maybe how would you have both when
that, when that like get that thing,
that female thing with
like you'd feel safe.
Like this guy's really going to have like
he's going to have an alarm system and
a gun. Yeah, and a sword and
where to condoms. Yeah. No,
I don't know about that. Yeah. No,
I mean if they're not involved,
if they're not like in a
real relationship, neighbors,
would you bang a neighbor when I
Bang like my sister's neighbor? No,
not your sisters. Now we're taking
family out of it. I'm saying where?
Where is the line where it's just
like, well whatever bitch, you know
isn't that you guys say you put
the hand up, whatever bitch,
what are you talking about? I'm saying,
cause you're saying like that's family.
You can't fucking do that. I was just
trying to find a comedic angle here.
Oh I see what you mean.
I mean neighbor two streets over.
Your neighbor knew them, invited you over
and you went over there. You know what?
I have a real life example of the guy.
The guy was an architect. Okay. All right,
I got it.
I have a real life example of this during,
during my prom I went my senior prom.
I love somebody else already.
Wait a minute. I went with somebody
who was just a friend. Okay.
But my friend has Biz Markie,
he was just depressed.
Um,
but my friend went to the prom with this
guy that she had just met and they were
set up by another friend.
He went to a different school.
So they didn't really like know each
other. That was the day of justification.
They was set up by friends.
So I'm totally innocent.
So really we really connected
during prom and like,
as you know, that was not
what happened. As you know,
my prom did not end that great.
My parents like came and like took
me from this house and I was in,
because I was dumbing up,
wait to tell them the truth.
I called my parents because I was supposed
to spend the night at a girlfriend's
house, but instead we're going to
be hanging out at this boy's house.
His older sister was there. There's
a whole bunch of us were hanging out.
I was having such a great time that
I call my parents and I said, hey,
just so you know,
I'm staying here.
My mom completely flipped out and she and
my step father came and like extracted
me from the home. So that's how my prom
ended. Exactly. So it didn't end on any,
it was a very traumatic, but ultimately
they did the right thing. Um,
but anyway,
he,
me and this guy ended up connecting
and we ended up like dating afterwards,
so you know, um, oh that's different. I
thought you were saying that, you know,
like I,
we went in the bathroom like to the front
part of the Limo and put the window up.
No, no, no, no. But it wasn't
her boyfriend. They had just met.
I think she definitely felt some
type of way about it, you know,
only because he chose you over her.
Exactly.
You guys didn't have any sort of
like friendship, friendship? No.
She and I were really good
friends. Yeah. That yet. No, no,
that's not good. Oh, that's a
rough one. But it wasn't, Oh Fred,
a lot of rough ones and
we dated for a while.
We dated up until, you know, like I
went to college basically. And that was,
that was the end of that. So it wasn't
like this law of the term, you know,
toward affair. It wasn't like he
was my first love or anything.
He was just really cute and a football
player and Nice Bob Marley, you know. Hey,
what can I say?
Sorted, sorted, sorted
details here. All right,
well that's the podcast for this week.
Um, Jeez. And he came hard this week.
You came hard. You're really fucking
just put that guy you just said.
You know what? And that's it. It's
a fucking rap. And you know what?
I think you're right. I think you're
right. I could say that. Yeah.
Cause I sit here and my yes. Yeah. How
long have you had these fucking buddy?
I've had these, as long as I've known
you, he's fucking Pajama bottoms.
There's two things that I'll never die.
Pajamas, we'll never get holes in them.
Right. And sweatpants. You
cannot kill sweatpants it
and made out of that fucking,
um,
I think we'll go do some break dance.
Was it boogaloo something rather than
one of the fucking movie is, yeah. Yeah.
Whatever that fucking movie. Electric
overload break electric boogaloo right,
right. Those are is that breaks
the breakin two electric boogaloo.
There was such a weird period where
all those dance movies are coming out.
You know one of the worst dance
movies of all time is footloose.
That is some of the worst dancing ever.
It's, yeah, not a great dancing.
It's Brits Pretty Peak White Dancing.
But it's still a fun movie.
Why, why are you looking at me like
that? Cause I, I don't, I just,
it's how you can fucking sit through the
excruciating dances in that movie and
still see the fun and it's cute and
it's like it's a town where they live.
That's right.
Cause dancing and folks,
was that an off Broadway play
that they turned into a fucking,
they made it into a Broadway show
of course. Cause they always,
that's where it should have
stayed. Yeah. I don't know.
You should have to decide to go.
Kevin Bacon was hot in it.
I remember that part where he goes
and he does that Solo dance out of
frustration in the barn and he's like
flipping around on the beams in the
ceiling along the barn. And he just, you
know, now he's at the Billy Squier video.
Who's Billy squire?
Squire, the poor bastard.
The guy was a foster this guy that you
were like obsessed with watching off his
videos when we were on
vacation. Yeah. Cause I,
when I was watching them live and like
Detroit is like this guy was a fucking
rock star. You got to see
the video. It's so bad. No,
I remember you showed me the video.
Did I show you when he was crawling
on his fucking name? I feel bad too.
Piling on. But like I know the guy
already feels like it ended his career.
What are you doing? I don't
want, I said I wouldn't do it.
I said it wouldn't do it and here I am.
No, I don't know what it is. It's the,
you need to apologize to Billy squire and
get that off of your chest while he is.
Why he's still feels shitty about,
oh by the way, it's drummer.
I guess it's pronounced shoon art.
Bobby Chouinard Green to that book
and I'm reading that WBCN book,
which is fucking great. Um,
all right, that's it. That's
the podcast for this week.
Thanks for stopping by Nia. Always with
your wonderful advice. Just stories,
your general adore ability.
The dog needs to go for a walk.
Take around saying, Hey Cleo,
you want to go outside?
Look at that. Look,
she has been wanting to go
all morning port thing. Cleo.
Let me see. Can I get it?
A Howell on the, on the podcast.
Cleo. Wait, ever sit down, cleo. Sit.
Sit.
Okay,
sit. Sit down. Come on. Sit.
Cleo.
You want to go outside?
Cleo? Come on, man.
Fucking this is like the frog.
Cleo,
do
you
now you want to go outside cause she
knows you're trying to get her to do it.
Oh wait,
hold on.
Yeah.
All right. I'll see you guys.
Check in on you on Thursday.