Hey, what's going on? It's Phil Burn. It's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
October 20th,
2000 and [inaudible]
14. How you doing? How's it going and how,
um, I'm actually in a hotel right now or
a Sunday afternoon recording this on a
Sunday after dude,
um,
out in Santa Monica here.
I know what you think of bill.
What the hell are you have fucking staying
in a hotel room out in Santa Monica?
I thought you lived in Los Angeles.
I do. I do. You know what I'm doing?
I'm taking a little stay vacation.
[inaudible] one of the
most annoying things that a
phrases that's come up in the
like the last seven or eight
years, stay vacations, you know,
after the bankers completely
fucking robbed the American people,
all the God damn money
and then said fuck you.
You pay for it cause we're not going to
pay for it. What is how he long Evan?
His hair. Sorry, I got the TV on.
Is that as gray hair?
Fucking glistening there is as
Grecian formula not working.
Um, yeah. So anyways,
after they fucking robbed,
everybody ripped off fucking
everybody and didn't go to jail.
Nobody could afford to take a vacation
anymore. So then they came up with Stevie
occasions.
We're finding that more and more people
are doing what's known is this stay
vacation.
Rather than going away and
spending all that money,
they don't have that money anymore
because it was stolen from them,
from their banker cunts.
But they're too big to fail.
So now when people go on vacation,
they stay where they
live. Isn't that cute? No,
it isn't.
It's not cute.
I'm on the same. That's
why I did it. Um, you know,
I just don't have a lot of time right
now and I wanted to fucking do something
and a anyways,
whatever.
So I'm out here having a stay vacation.
Um,
I love how they fucking do that shit.
Anytime they fucking rob
everybody have everything.
They always come up with some
cute little fucking phrase.
It's supposed to appease
you. Stay vacation. Well,
we earned the money. We went out
and worked our fucking asses off.
We had the money to go on a real vacation.
And then these cunts stolen.
I'm really pissed off.
When did she have a stay vacation?
Oh,
that sounds like a good idea.
All your anger goes away and
then they keep your money right.
And then they'd go out and they fucking
blow it on hookers that you can't even
imagine what they look like.
A level of beauty that does not exist
for the person on this side of the teller
window. Right. Sorry,
I'm combining like 12 conspiracy
theories. Um, anyways,
you can tell them getting over
stuff or whatever. Everybody had.
I got all right.
And um,
I want just for the record,
I at no point that I think I had a bola.
Alright.
Unfucking believable.
I'm so fucking ashamed of my fellow
man and the absolute fucking panic
that six people with their head cold
can cause the entire herd to start
stampeding towards a fucking cliff.
Got Airplanes.
Just freaking the fuck out.
You know,
Jesus Christ. People age. All right.
Act like you been there before that,
that take us down.
Well, did it look at
Magic Johnson, that guy,
he's in better shape than 99% of people.
Okay,
please.
Some professional athletes going to get
a bulla is going to have to retire and
everybody thinks he's
going to fucking die,
but he's going to have the fucking money.
All right.
I was thinking of the best South Park's
ever when they showed Magic Johnson's
cure for aids and he had a blender and
he was just shoving golden cash into it,
blending it up and then
drinking it. Um, anyways,
I'm all over the fucking map here.
All right.
Act like you fucking been there before.
All right. It's not going to take us down.
Shit. Hang on a second. Hang on. Hang on.
Hang on. I gotta answer this. Hey Georgia.
Sorry about that. I had to answer
that for two seconds. Um, anyways,
um, that was I talking about. Yeah.
Okay.
We survived that one. We're going
to survive the way it'll be fine.
We're going to be fucking fine.
The great thing about a bola is it kills
you so fucking quickly, Bang, Bang,
boom, get gone. You're done.
All right. Over and Africa,
when it would start to spread
like wildfire, everybody
just ran into the woods.
You stayed out. There is shit in
the woods for a couple of weeks.
He came back and everybody was dead.
Then you throw them in a pile,
you lit them on fire and he's just
fucking get on with your life.
Everybody running around
like the sky has fallen.
What am I good friends? Paul
Versey. He was freaking the fuck out
dude. Why do they keep
bleeding? People get on planes.
Look, you guys have seen
my shit. You know that.
I know that the world needs a good plague.
It needs a good one.
All right.
We're too smart for our own good.
You know if there's always shit out
there wiping out animals and then they
survive. Not all of them. A
lot of them die or whatever,
but this day still survive and
then they go on and it's balanced.
Look at us.
We're all over the place.
What the fuck is knocking
those goddamn cabinets around?
It's probably the broad next door.
This fucking lady next door.
I swear to God her in
his stupid ass friend,
they were up at seven 30 in the
morning. Okay, and I'm a morning person.
Believe it or not, even though I
have this job. Oh my God, look,
I got the TV on in the background.
He's his fucking no more commercial.
Am I the only football fan
who gets fucking annoyed
with this stupid commercial?
I don't hit women.
I don't need to be brow beaten and get a
fucking lecture in the middle of my God
damn game here because one
running back on one fucking team.
Okay.
Knocked out his wife.
Not during a football game.
Yeah,
he did it in Atlantic city.
So why don't you run that
commercial down in Atlantic city?
Show it on the fucking boardwalk.
So God damn annoying.
You can't get away from it.
Constantly giving you a fucking
lecture on how to be a better person.
I love how they look at
that stupid commercial like
that's going to stop a wife
beater from hitting his wife.
Like he's about ready to do it.
And then fucking ice tea,
Yo no more.
She tell where's my money bitch? Right.
And then he's going to be like, oh, okay.
Okay.
Ah, in everybody's dressed in black, like
they're doing a fucking Beatles album.
I swear to God, I just, you
know, I've got, you know,
I thought I was in a good mood. This is
pathetic. Kate. Anybody watched the, uh,
Indiana Hoosier game yesterday?
The football game?
I can't remember who the fuck they
were playing. It was hilarious.
Indiana Hoosiers like the,
any,
the University of Indiana and I should
say they had like the widest fucking
school on the planet.
All right.
And one of the most racist
fucking states on the planet.
And that's somebody who fucking
grew up right outside of Boston.
And I can say that
because I'm a Republican.
I just did that with like race
relations. Um, so anyways,
uh,
I'm watching the game
and you know them, they have that classic,
you know, fucking uh, Gene Hackman,
who's your fucking uniforms?
It's just white as white can be.
It's as Corny as extreme whiteness is.
But the influence of those disco uniforms
that the fucking Oregon duck show
wearing this people literally signing
with Oregon cause they want to wear the
uniform.
There's athletes making that decision.
Fucking unbelievable. You know,
like it's a goddamn fashion show.
I like playing football, but let
me tell you something, honey,
those helmets are to die for.
There's literally people's siding.
Jai, they're, they're, they're,
they're, they're shining. Their football
lives away to go play with that program.
So now everybody's got to have some sort
of fucking disco ball football helmet
now. So, um, I, you
know, I put on Indiana,
which is the last fucking team you'd
think would ever change their stupid all
red with the dumb white.
I think they just had the eye for Indiana,
you know,
classic Bamfam fucking old school.
Trump owned goddamn school.
And even they had to give into it.
They had to address the fact that they
were losing recruits because of that
disco helmet that the
fucking Oregon ducks have.
So they actually got themselves
some shiny fucking lantern helmet,
but they kept everything else.
They kept everything else.
Totally like the Corny fucking old school
when one for the gipper like did like
the,
even like the texts that they had Indiana
University look like it was written
like pre war as something
in the end zones.
And then they've got these
fucking disco helmets on.
It looks like they stole them.
I don't know.
That was a long way to
fucking go to say like, look,
if you're going to fucking do the uniform,
you got to go the whole way.
You got to have the flashy fucking helmet.
You got to have chest hair showing between
your fucking shoulder pads with the
medallion.
Right.
Zip Up fucking pants and that no tear
away pants is what you got to have.
And then you got to have some hoary
cheerleader. So you got to go all out.
You can't just have the helmet.
Right?
I Dunno.
Anyways. Is it true that like
the cheerleaders on the um,
Indiana Hoosiers like their pompoms are
made out of like a recycled dot clan
sheets? Sorry, I'm telling you.
I'm saying that racist people.
Oh, this podcast sucks this week.
I'm just not on my game. I have good
ideas. I'm just not, I'm just, you know,
I've just thought it's
all in the execution.
I'll tell you right now with the x's and
o's, who all don't read on the board,
I mean the coaches could only do so much.
I mean the coaches coached the team,
but at the end of the day,
the players go out and they play the game.
And if you're not out there,
if they're not firing on all cylinders,
if they're not out there
acting as a cohesive unit,
if they haven't bought into the system,
then you know you're going to have
problems and you can get national football
week.
I actually have the packers panthers
game on in the background and a pack.
Is it kicking the shit out of him?
28 to three yeah. No, here we go.
He's a little highlight. Sates first.
The lions. Nah, there's a lone pairs.
Are you fuckers here? Beg, beg,
beg scores. All right. 17 to three.
I went to a line, so I'm game a long
time ago. Beautiful feel. Ford field,
great name for it. You know, and
damn,
every time they made a play, a decent
play, they had this awful son of a lion,
roaring sound like that, you know,
like it was getting prison
rate and it just ended
every time they make a play, watch a the
home game. If you've got the NFL package,
watch a lion's game and listen for
every time they do something good,
you just hear, oh, I guess
that's supposed to be a roaring,
why didn't they just buy the rights
of the 20th Century Fox line?
It was probably overdoing it.
Like you've ever watched a nature show
and you see how a lion roars when it's
trying to like say,
this is my territory.
I don't want any you young bucks coming
here trying to fuck my 30 fucking women.
You know Jesus Packer,
fans of fat, Jesus Christ.
Every time they cut to the fucking,
there's not one treadmill and that
God damn state, I'm sorry. Anyways,
anytime they cut to the fucking lion,
okay
now cut to 11 when they show up,
they just, they just go like, Ooh,
we're over and fuck it over again.
I'm always disappointed. I'm like,
that's what they sound like. I thought
they sounded like that 20th century Fox.
Would you just, I didn't
know that they stand,
they're sounding like they're
going to fucking hurl, you
know, like did like they,
you know, those fucking things.
Eight day eating everything shit.
And get a couple of bones in there.
He's like,
I think I got a Yak every once in a while.
That's what I thought it was going
to do. But they were like, no,
it's its marketing, its territory.
Oh, is that what you think?
Is that what you think you're
going to have one be a pet.
So that youtube video the other day
and this fucking guy goes over these
people's House that
have like a pet lioness.
Okay.
And the thing pounces on him
playfully and, but like, you know,
weighs like 600 pounds as like digging
into this fucking guy's dress shirt.
The guy doesn't even have a
t shirt underneath it. Right.
He's fucking walking around like he's
uh, Gabe Kaplan or whatever. Right.
That's Clark Gable split meant to
say. Right. And um, he fucking,
it's digging into his back,
which causes him to cry out,
which excites the Predator in the wild
animal and it's fucking hilarious.
Cause like when wild animals,
yeah,
like they get excited causes them
to just fucking snap your neck.
Like you have to know like dog toys,
you know, those little squeaky dog toys.
And all that. Do you know why they
squeak? It's not cause it's cute.
Is it supposed to excite the Predator in
them, which gets them to play with it?
It's supposed to sound like
a fucking animal dying.
And you know when they pick it up,
when they shake it around and shit in
your laugh and thinking always play it.
He isn't, that's their natural
instinct. When they grab something,
they shake it like that and it
breaks the neck of the prey.
But we've pretty much
bred that out of all dogs.
So they just sit there in the corner
with that stupid look on their face.
But every once in a while you get, I'm
one of those squeaky toys and you see it,
you see it in their eyes again.
You know,
it's like when I was in that Italian
restaurant in San Francisco and a time,
and I look over and I saw Joe Montana
sitting there on a double date,
right? The fucking Joe
Montana and I got up to leave.
And as I walked out, you know, it was like
a crew of like five of us or whatever.
So there's motion and the restaurant.
He looked over at us and I was looking
at him and he looked at me and my fucking
stomach dropped cause he still
had that look in his eye. You know
that two minute offense, I'm going to cut
your fucking hard out. He can't help it.
He's sitting there with a fucking risotto
in front of him and he still has that
look in his face. Every once in a
while you get a little squeaky toy.
You put it in front of
your dog and you'll see it.
I don't care how little foofy
little prissy dog you have.
You give that thing a little fucking
chew toy that's squeaks. You Watch it,
fucking shaking it around and the
owner's going, oh look at that.
She thinks she's big. She thinks she
doesn't understand that smell she had.
See she takes on all the big dogs
and whatever. It's like, sweetheart,
she's not cute right now.
She's trying to kill something and
she doesn't even know she's doing it.
It's just in her fucking DNA.
She's trying to break the neck
of that fucking thing. All right.
Put some shoes on. Um, anyways. Yeah.
So there's broad next door, right? I mean,
just the stereotypical,
awful fucking female talk.
The kind of thing that if I
actually did it in my act,
I would once again be branded a sexist.
Okay.
Which I'm not even
saying I'm not all right.
The definition of the word, by the
definition of the word, I think I am,
I mean, basically in this, uh,
in this climate and this culture,
I think basically if you publicly call
women on for anything at this point,
then you're a sexist because it no,
no point could they ever be
doing something wrong. Right.
I mean, they're human beings.
They're just as good as us.
Unless they're doing something wrong.
If they do something wrong,
you call them out on it thing.
You're obviously a sexist and you don't
think that they should be allowed to
vote.
Correct.
I mean that seems how the math
works in comedy clubs anyways,
so I'm such a cunt this week,
so I'm fucking sitting there and this
fucking woman is talking to this other
woman and that literally
just talking about shit,
not literally shit but just like stuff,
stuff that they bought.
I got static newest trends. Yap. Was it
good deal till at that at bat the bat,
Sheila's Blablabla Blah Blah Blah
Bell-to-bell Blablablabla Blah pocketbook.
Like the level of fucking excitement that
they had for that was the same level I
have when I talked to Versie
when like the NFL season,
week one is about to begin
equally fucking stupid.
Equally not worth getting excited about.
But because I can't relate to it,
I have to make fun of it.
You know, kind of just killed my whole
point of view there. But you know,
whatever the fuck you want. So
anyways, so I'm staying at this hotel
and Lo and behold, oh there we go. Down
the sideline. Not that darn has 25,
um, green bay packers just kicking
the shit out of the panthers.
This cannot be Cam Newton's fault. Cam
knew it looks like a fucking superhero,
you know,
he looks like a war hero,
a quarterback and an astronaut all at
the same time. So it can't be his fault.
I'll tell you,
I got to blame that on offense of line.
I don't care how good you are
at the quarterback position,
you cannot play if you laid on your
back 60% of the place bike. Oh,
absolutely. Yeah, absolutely.
Boy, you know what, when it
comes down to it, you know,
you held out for a bigger car,
tractor jar,
you know you're going to get
all the glory and old criticism.
Sherif he said high ankle sprain,
touchdown packers. Jesus Christ
has got to be 35 to three year.
Hey, you know, I don't know that this
is actually a movement in the NFL,
but according to Paul Versey
from the Versie effect,
there's discussions about
getting rid of the extra point.
MMM
inverse.
He's claiming it's so fucking stupid
because 99.9% of them are made and it's
just a big fucking waste of
time. Blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Blue. I mean,
I just fucking blows my mind
that a guy who loves the de,
the NBA,
right,
can watch a fucking NBA game with the
final two and a half to four minutes,
can take as much as 45
to 50 fucking minutes.
Okay.
That this fucking guy gives a fuck about
a play that takes 30 seconds and takes
no time off of the clock.
You know,
I love the extra point.
I love that play for the simple fact I,
this isn't even my opinion.
I just, somebody else said this
and I totally agree with it.
It's the one thing that really happens
on a football field that people in the,
if you fuck it up,
people in the crowd legitimately can
get mad because who can't make it?
Like most of the people in the crowd,
if you'll remotely in shape,
you can make an extra point.
So when they miss one,
it's like,
how the fuck did you miss that?
And then at what I love is
whenever you miss an extra point,
it always seems to be
like you lost by one.
I'll tell you those extra points.
Don't Miss Texta points.
He'll come back to haunt you. I
fucking love the x deploy. All right.
Keep it in the God damn game.
They got rid of the extra point.
That'd be like the American league
with the fucking Dh rule. Okay.
Have the pitcher hit well, it's
a fucking waste. It's an uh,
you know, this is a picture is
always strikes out. Anyways.
What the fence, the fun
thing of game. I like it.
It also keeps the pitcher fucking honest.
You're going to go out there and
throw it somebody who's head.
Then you got to go up.
You've got to come up to bat.
How much more fun would have been to watch
Roger Clemens pitch if he also had to
hit?
Do you remember when he fucking threw it?
Mike Piazza and then they finally
played the mets in Shea Stadium.
He had to come up to bat.
Do you remember how we went up to bat?
He went up to bat with nothing
other than a batting helmet.
He went up there like a man after
thrown in people's heads for 20 years.
He didn't give a fuck. He
was so roid it up. Bring it,
hit me in the head. It'll make me
throw harder the next day. And he,
she need to have on batting gloves.
He just walked up there.
His big roided up Texas ass in the
fucking pitcher threw at him and he missed
him. Amen. At his hips.
I don't fuck do you miss something
like that? You know what I mean?
There's gotta be like fucking
up cow tipping, right? You
can't hit Roger Clemens,
all that text message mex in his belly
and all those roids in his fucking ass.
You can't hit this guy.
It's unbelievable. Actually.
He was acquitted of it. So I shouldn't say
that. Right. I can't even say a legend.
Now,
can I accused steroid user,
Roger Clemens?
I remember when I lived in New York City,
every fucking two weeks it seemed
they did. Uh, they did, uh,
before he got busted or accused,
um,
they used to do a fucking local
news piece on Roger Clemens,
workout a routine. It was perfect
because then when people go,
going like, dude, you just
see his, uh, I, you know,
I think that guy's doing roids so that
guy's on roids and everybody would be
like, dude, you see how much guy
fuck a workshop? It was perfect.
His people put that out there first.
You know, if they're in the locker room,
they know people are going down. They
know people are going to get busted. We,
we got to get out in front of this thing.
Let's do some pieces on how much you
work out. [inaudible] all this shit up.
He's stolen.
He's the one squats everything,
whatever. Alright, hang on a
second. I apologize. This is rude.
Jesus Christ that was actually going to
tweet that I was fucking sick, you know,
and make a joke about it,
but I didn't want to listen to everybody's
fucking hacky of Bulla jokes when I
had my own anyways. You
know? So anyways, I,
I'm staying at this hotel and you know,
when I'd be staying in a hotel,
they have to have a fucking steam, a
steam room. Right? Well, you know what,
let me actually,
uh,
I gotta I gotta read some
fucking advertising here
before I get too deep into
this podcast. We're going to pause
here just for a moment from this word,
from your local douchebag.
All right, here we go.
I'm going to read all the advertising for
this week's podcast right now because,
uh, yeah, it's a long fucking
story, but just the way they information
came in this week. All right,
so fucking brace yourselves for five
minutes of accidental comedy is Bill Burns
tries to read advertising on his fucking
podcast for you for the 900th time.
You'd think I'd get good at this,
but you know,
and I always keep trying
and dollar shave club,
everybody guys,
dollar Shave club.com I've been
talking about them for years.
They deliver great razors for a few bucks
a month. If you're not a member yet,
what in God's name are you waiting for?
Think they'll hit you up with a bunch of
fees. Dollar Shave club.com has no fees.
You just pay for raises that they
shipped to you. And that is it.
Get there,
four blade razor and for replacement blade
sent to your door each month for just
$6 including the shipping.
You don't want to get locked into
a monthly commitment. No problem.
Dollar Shave club.com doesn't have any
contracts and if you decide you don't
want raises for a month or two,
they don't send you any and
you don't have to pay a dime.
It couldn't be any easier.
Don't know if you'll like their products.
I already told you this stuff is amazing,
but if you don't agree,
dollar Shave Dot Dollar Shave
club.com we'll refund your money.
No questions asked.
Stop with the excuses.
Unless you're some idiot
who likes wasting money,
go sign up a dollar shave club.com/bar
right now. I'm telling you it's great.
Once again,
that's dollar shave club.com/burr Oh,
here we go.
Everybody, me, undies, me undies, no
more sweaty balls. Boop, boop, boop,
me undies everybody. 90% that's the
percent of your life that you are in.
Underwear, malicious sleeping, the new
and underwear. It gets old. People
gets old real fast and when it does,
it ain't pretty.
All right.
You know that feeling of
putting on all saggy underwear,
you need to know the feeling
of great fit and underwear.
That Cup and your balls all day long.
That is two times softer than cotton.
You need to know about me undies
beyond ease, no more sweaty balls.
Beyond these is the most comfortable
underwear that you will ever wear and it's
insane how good they make you feel.
They fit perfectly.
They don't ride up on you
and they literally pull
moisture away from your skin
Garros so you stay cool.
Here's what I love
having never worn a pair.
Me undies is environmentally friendly.
The materials they use are sustainable
sourced from the Austrian Alps.
I'll see. You know they're good
and they are completely natural.
How they also use a o neutral process
with a low carbon footprint. Good.
I was going to ask them if they did that.
They save water and energy due to
their spun dried fiber process.
These guys went all out on these
things, Huh? They have cool.
They have cool styles for both
men and women and look great.
Check out the photos of yourself
or don't out the photos yourself.
It's going to say it's creepy. How do
they have photos of you in your undies,
your undies?
How did you get those photos?
Did you hack by fucking phone? All
right. Check out the photos yourself.
Me undies.com.
This quality would typically retail
for two times the me undies price.
No retail middlemen means
more savings to you.
Here I will make it easy for you.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr and
get 20% off your first order and free
shipping. Save even more. When you,
when you buy a whole pack of them,
they are guaranteed that
they're going to make you,
you're going to be happy with them
or your first pair is free. Uh,
once you feel me undies on your body,
you're going to love your
life for the rest of time.
Sorry the coffee got cut off anyways,
it's me undies. Mandy's snow,
more sweaty balls. All right. There
you go. Get yourself some underwear.
They'd cut your fucking balls the
way they need to be. All right,
stamps.com everybody,
uh,
getting your mail and shipping done
can seem like a no win situation.
Go to the post office.
Takes up valuable time.
Leasing a postage meter is
expensive with a multilayer,
multiyear commitments and hidden fees.
It's all a bunch of BS.
You don't want to deal with it.
Well, luckily I know a better way.
It's called stamps.com.
Everybody buy and print
official US postage for any
letter or package right from
your desk using your own
computer and printer, uh,
even get special postage just counts.
You can't find it.
The post office plus stamps.com is more
powerful than a postage meter at just a
fraction of the cost.
You can save up to 80% compared to a
postage meter and you'll avoid those time
consuming trips to the post office. I use
stamps.com to send out my posters, my,
my, uh, my twizzle sticks, whatever
crap I'm selling at the end of my show,
I can figure out stamps.com I am a
moron. If I can do it, then God damn it.
You can too. Right now use my last
name bur bur for this special offer.
No his trial plus $110 bonus offer that
includes a digital scale and up to 50
$55 free postage.
Do not wait.
Go to stamps.com before
you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbarthatstamps.com
enter
burr
and a. What do we got here? We've got two
more. Everybody hang in there. Evil voice,
everyone.
I love the flexibility.
Flexibility that owning your own
business provides. Look at me.
I've created an empire with Dick Jokes,
but when it comes to handling business
calls, you're stuck with the challenge.
Either hire a full time receptionist
that you bang and then ruin your marriage
or handle all your calls yourself.
It's a lose lose situation there.
That's why I love III voice.
They'll set your business up with a toll
free number and a local number when a
cost.
When customers call,
they're greeted professionally by a
virtual receptionist. She's not there.
Everybody and she will route all
your calls to wherever you are.
There's even a dial by name directory.
You'll sound like a fortune 500
company and more importantly,
you'll never an important call for all
for under 13 bucks a month right now for
a limited time. My listeners can
try he voice for free for 60 days.
Give it a shot. God Dang it. All right.
Okay.
Draft Kings.
The final one here.
Draftkings listeners are winning huge
cash prizes every week@draftkings.com and
you could get your piece of the million
dollars being awarded this weekend.
How do you do it?
Well,
I'm going to tell you a draft kings
is America's favorite one week fantasy
football site.
One week fantasy means no season.
Long commitments play whenever you want.
Gotten an inch a pro player,
not a problem at draftkings where it's
like a new season every week so you're
never stuck with the same players.
Pick your team and minutes and you
could be on your way to instant cash.
Last year, one player turn
11 bucks and the four grant,
another one,
a hundred gram and his first time ever
playing and another player won a million
bucks in one day.
A bunch of other people lost their shirts
so they could pay these people out.
But you don't look at it that way.
You're going to be one of the wetness,
hungry or hurry and get a free entry to
Sunday millions of events this weekend
where 1 million bucks in
cash prizes is up for grabs.
Head over to draft kings.com now and
enter the Promo code defense to play for
free. draftkings.com bigger events,
bigger winnings, bigger millionaires.
Enter defense for free entry
now@draftkingsdotcomdraftkings.com
one more time.
That is draft kings.com.
Okay.
All right.
And we are back.
We are back. I don't have the advertising
yet, so I got to edit that in.
I hope that came back smoothly. Um, yeah,
so I go downstairs to take
a steam, right. And uh,
I walk into the steam room.
There's nobody in there.
All right.
Thumbs up. Number one. It's early in the
morning. So a lot of times they don't.
You might be the first one down there.
So the steam is an odd,
which sucks because you've got to wait
like 20 minutes for it to fucking heat up.
I walked to the steam. It's fucking, not
only is it on, it's cranking. All right.
Thumbs up number two. So I
fucking, you know, I get ready,
I bring my own fucking flip flops.
Okay.
Cause you cannot walk around
in that slime barefoot.
God knows what the fuck's going to
be grown on your feet the next day.
And I'm not using people's,
the flip flops that they give you because
I don't know how well that they wipe
it out. Okay. Think about that.
That's somebody's job to fucking clean
off the fun Gal free slippers at a spa.
All right.
I don't want to judge anybody
who listens to this podcast,
but there's no way you dreamed about
doing that job when you were a child.
So I would imagine if you get that job,
you're not exactly exactly like enthused
about doing that fucking job. Right.
So what I'm saying is, is probably a lot
of bullshit that's left behind. Hence,
I bring my own fucking flip
flops. Um, and I haven't,
where the fucking,
you've got the thing that fucking goes
all the way across your foot. Dot.
That stuck between your toe. So it
goes full flip per flat, per foot,
flat on the bottom of your feet and
you know the shit out of somebody.
All alright, I'm courteous. All
right, so I got my flip flops on.
I got my towel and I got another towel
to wipe off the fucking sweat when I'm in
there, right? All the toxins and I
fucking go to the goddamn steam room.
I fucking the steam thing,
right? I open it up,
I go inside and immediately sitting
right next to the door. Is it dude?
Completely fucking naked once again.
Right dick out for fucking days.
Just sitting there and you know,
I'm just getting in there.
My eyes are getting adjusted.
Some like, okay, you know,
I can naked guy nine o'clock and now
like how big is this steam shower?
How many fucking people are in there?
I'm feeling my way through here and
I'm walking away from this guy in his
fucking schlong. And so I'm taking
like baby steps as I'm walking through,
kind of feeling my way in.
And this guy's opening fucking line to me.
First words out of his mouth.
You know what he says?
He says it's just us.
Oh my God. If it wasn't so creepy,
I would have burst out laughing.
It's just like, really that that's
you coming out of the gate with that.
That is so creepy and fucked up.
I almost have to applaud it.
It's just us.
Oh my God.
So then he goes, you want me to warm it
up more, right as I sit down? I'm like,
yeah, sure. You know, staring
down at my fucking sandals.
So we fucking stands up.
I don't know what he did.
I don't know what the Knob or he threw
some water on it. He just goes, he goes,
watch your feet. And I said,
I'm cool. I got sandals on.
I didn't know what the fuck he was
talking about, but the steam comes out,
you gonna burn your feets. We
fucking cranks to think all right.
Okay.
Yeah.
Now it's like hot as fuck,
but it's great because it creates like
this cloud where I can't see him anymore.
So now, now it's great. There's like
this divide or a steam. So you know,
I don't have to sit there
staring at my feet. Right.
And then after about like 90 seconds to
steam starts to dissipate and as it does
appearing out of the mist,
the guy is standing up in the shower.
Like if you took a picture of
somebody like mid jumping Jack, Jack,
except his feet were
on the fucking ground.
He was standing there like arms outside,
like doing this like heavy breathing
and shit. And it's just like,
I don't know what I don't know.
Okay.
I like to think I'm not homophobic.
I'm not homophobic in the
sense of I don't give a fuck.
Okay.
You know, I don't give a shit. You know,
if that's what you went to g, you know,
God bless you or whatever.
But as that homophobic take,
when I'm sitting there like when
there's a fucking guy like that clinic,
what are you doing?
Why don't you just fucking bend over,
grab your fucking ankles while you're
at it. What's wrong with you? Sit Down,
you sitting in steam,
the steam is going to get you.
You don't got to stand up.
And what are you doing?
What the fuck are you doing?
Set Out.
How about some fucking etiquette, you
know? Oh, maybe I'll, you know what, Hey,
whatever, I'm open to
change. Maybe I'm wrong,
maybe I should have stood up
and just face the guy in it.
Started mimicking his fucking
actions, right? And then, and then,
then do I pass the test?
Jesus fucking Christ so that he leaves.
Thank God he fucking leaves. You
know, and I just start, you know,
laughing and then I have to fake like
I was coughing just in case you get to
hear me,
cause it was echo in there and uh,
he fucking goes, uh, and then
I look and I see his hotel key.
There's locker key is still there as,
oh my God,
fuck this guy's coming back or whatever.
So whatever. So he comes back in, um,
you know, sits down, like
to get wet leaves. Fucking
doesn't even take his towel.
Just walks out naked as a fucking
Jaber just walking around,
right?
So he comes back in.
Now I'm done. So I was like, all right
man, have a good day. And he's like,
all right, thanks. So I leave right
immediately. Go into the shower,
ice cold fucking shower,
close up the pores, you know,
wash away all this shit. You sweat
it out. You know, Big Bang Boob.
And I'm thinking, all right,
no more naked guy. I'm good.
I get out of the shower.
Who's staying?
And they over by the lockers
fucking naked as hell. Dick out.
Save fucking guy.
Okay,
now once again, baby, I'm
homophobic. What is this guy doing?
What is his fucking obsession with
just being in my line of sight with his
fucking junk? Look, you were there first.
You're naked in the fucking steam and good
on you, but I show up. All right? Hey,
how you doing? Whenever you throw
a fucking towel, cover yourself.
You fucking animal, right? He
doesn't want to do it. All right.
He's naked in the steam room guy.
Fine.
Then he walks out without a
fucking towel on, you know,
he doesn't give a fuck. He
comes back. Then I leave,
stay in the fucking steam
room and put a fucking towel.
You guys walk around like, is this
house? Why don't you just take a dump?
Right. I was just Adam. I
Dunno. I Dunno. You know,
I don't want a lot of you guys just say,
well bill,
why do you keep taking those
fucking Steve? Cause I like to,
it's one of the perks of those other
have double the, the fucking hotel.
There's always somebody is
going to fuck it up, right?
There's always going to be the guy
with his deck out the steam room.
There's always going to be somebody's
pain in the hotel pool, right?
There's always gonna be somebody down
at the hotel bar that can't handle their
liquor and either pukes just
starts to fucking fight.
There's always just going to be
that guy. And this is why, you know,
like when you see lifestyles of
the rich and famous, you know,
and they're always doing that shit.
They have their own movie. They attack.
They have their own bowling alleys.
That's because they have the money to not
deal with the guy with his dick out in
the steam room.
They have their own money to not deal
with the person who can hold their fucking
alcohol. You know, if anybody's going to
pee in their pool, it's going to be them.
You know,
they got the money
to basically just exit
the society and I understand
the older I get, Jesus Christ,
look at Saint Louis,
Pete and Seattle
at the Fuck Outta here.
I don't see this whole up.
Oh my God,
Pete is going to beat his family dog
tonight. If they fucking lose this one,
they lost last week to the,
to the cowboys. It's so,
this is what it's so fucking hard to
repeat his super bowl champion because the
second you win the fucking thing,
every coach
on like the team immediately
thinks that they're a head coach.
They're not the best defensive
coordinator in the game that year anymore.
Now there are fucking head coach,
right? The offensive coordinator,
defensive coordinator, both of them,
I don't even know if they lost them,
but it's inevitable they're going into,
if they don't lose them this year,
they'll lose them within a couple of
years. I was under Pete Carroll and uh,
you know, now I know shit, right?
That's what happened to the Patriots.
Charlie Weis, Romeo,
Krummel, all of those guys,
that fucking baby face kid
who's back coaching with us,
he got a head coaching job at,
I'm in Denver.
Romeo chromal got fucked.
He went to Cleveland.
Charlie Weis got a head coaching job and
Notre Dame and then all your players,
you know,
you've got to have a couple,
two or three that are
going to take the money.
Maybe they feel like their body's breaking
down or they don't feel like they're
getting it.
They got respected for them,
their part in what they did
to win the championship,
and then they take some money
elsewhere. It's so hard to keep the, uh,
the group together, which is why
one of my favorite speeches ever,
which I had never heard. I didn't
know how. I didn't hear about it.
Watching the Celtics Lakers rivalry.
I didn't hear about it until I read
Bill Simmons Book on a Bass Basketball.
The uh,
the um,
okay.
Patrick Riley's speech to disease of
more when he wanted them to repeat,
he said the disease or more
when everybody, when the,
when everybody wants more,
people want more playing time, they want
more money, they want more screen time,
they want more of this,
they want more of that and if
totally fucks up what got you there?
MMM.
You know, what do they always talk
about? They always said, well you know,
they played a lot of games
this year and a a, you know,
last year in the playoffs,
you know,
they didn't get as long as break and then
the celebrated too much and blah blah
blah blah blah blah. Which
obviously I think plays a role. But
um,
I dunno,
I dunno. I've sucks cause back
in the day was like free agency,
that type of shit that
didn't really exist.
You could actually hold a group together
and you could have like those big time
dynasties,
you know,
like that Seattle defense should have
been doing that for like a good three,
four years.
Okay.
Um, and would have been one of the
legendary defense has had they done that.
You dominate a Superbowl like that. I
mean, that was like, I, that's like,
I haven't seen anything like that since
the 85 bears. That's just, it's a shame.
So fucking shame. Um, but anyways,
what else did I want to talk
about already talked about a bola.
I'm not afraid of that. Even if there
is like a fucking dope, it's a win win.
Okay.
It's a win win either.
It doesn't.
MMM.
Do you know either they contain it,
which is a win or they
don't contain it and, uh,
we have a much needed burn
off of the population.
I know it's brutal to fucking
say, but you know, if you take,
if you take the emotions out of it,
okay.
I mean, people, you get 7 billion
people on the fucking planet. Well,
we're on our way to 14
billion. Everybody's going
to have a couple of kids.
What the fuck are we doing? Okay.
We got manmade salmon people.
I mean, if anybody needs a
fucking plague, it's human beings.
Jesus fucking Christ.
How many more casinos can they build out
Vegas and they keep getting filled up
with mouth breathers.
They just keep coming in.
And then if you don't believe
that we need a plague,
then I would say you did not watch
that Fsu Notre Dame game yesterday,
which for my money was the best
college football game of the year.
Unbelievable game.
I took my wife out last night,
so I missed a lot of the second half,
but I kept peeking in when we
were in bars and shit. But um,
it was just an instant classic.
But the only in as much as it killed
me to miss the game, what I, uh,
or a lot of the game,
what I loved was that I didn't have
to listen to those mouth breathing.
Fucking morons.
Yeah.
I mean they play that God damn, Whoa, Ooh,
every fucking day. Play it for every
occasion. If they do something good,
they play it.
If the other team does something
good to get their fans psyched up to,
to try to get back into the game.
It's like,
why don't you just write like
two or three of those songs?
Just switch it up a little bit.
Like I don't,
I just can't imagine as a fucking
fan. I can't even do, once again,
the fucking Boston red sox play that
stupid sweet Caroline boop, boop boop.
I've never sung it.
It was stupid from day fucking
one and I never fucking song it.
And just to sit there and watch those
people and that's just once a game.
Okay.
Magic. If anytime everything
went good during a red sox
game, everybody just went,
Bob,
Bob like a hundred times
in nine fucking innings.
How could you possibly still be a fed?
I Dunno.
I have no idea what I feel like somebody
just walking into the hotel room right
now, probably complaining about
me cursing and Shit in here. Um,
yeah, that's the type of shit that I see
and then I'm just like, you know, I is a,
it was a plague really that bad
a thing. Uh, Jesus Christ. Bill,
Jesus Christ. Um, all
right. What do we like 37,
38 minutes into this fucking thing?
Minus whatever the hell it to however
long it took me to read these.
Yeah,
the fucking, uh, advertising. Uh, all
right. You don't have to do it. I went to,
I'm going to take a break
right now cause I'm waiting,
still waiting for the advertising of
the questions to come in. And, uh, we,
you guys didn't need to know that.
Did you? Hey, why you don't want came.
I want to watch this week.
Uh,
the big game I want to see is a cowboys
and giants because I'm actually a
closeted, um, cowboy's fan.
I never quite got on board, wants
to, Tex Schramm and Tom Landry left.
It was so fucking different. It
was this stoic, classy franchise,
which of course I know the players are
like, they were brutal and cutthroat,
but I didn't see that
part. I just saw the, the,
the propaganda and they went from
that to habitat, them cowboys,
right? And this guy with a facelift
and everything. And it became,
I just felt like I was
watching like Falcon crested
or literally the show Dallas,
um, became like a reality show.
So I never quite got into a,
I dunno,
I just never got into them after that,
even though they went all those times
and I was psyched that they won.
But I don't know, I never quite was, I
was a rabid fan when I was growing up.
Um,
okay.
But now that they're back again in,
cause Tony Romo took so much shit to
finally see this guy getting protection,
it playing great and everything, I'm
really hoping, uh, that guy wins one.
There's certain people you just have
to root for after a while. Tony Romo,
Don Mattingly,
um,
just people that I think are just good
guys that have just taken a fucking truck
load of Shit and uh,
I dunno if they could use a break.
So anyways,
I'm looking forward to watching that.
And plus I also believe it or not, even
as a patriots fan, I love the giants. Uh,
I always love teams that are like
defensive minded and I just feel like,
uh, ever since the Harry
Carson Lawrence Taylor days,
when they revived what the
giants were before my time, well,
they had Sam huff, the violent
world of Sam hough. MMM.
I Dunno.
Like I,
I like those teams that are allegedly
like boring that when like games like 17
to fucking nine,
um,
in Ely always steps up during big games.
And I would say that the guy has a
horseshoe up his ass, but he did it twice.
So at that point, you know, once
you're lucky twice she had good. So,
um, you know, I dunno,
I'm really looking forward to that
fucking game and uh, and that is it.
So I'm going to take a break here,
wait for this shit to come in and I'll
be answering your questions, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, whatever. All right. Okay.
Taking a break at,
why am I saying I'm taking a break?
Because you're not going to hear the
brake is just gonna come right back.
You know, see, watch.
Oh, look at that. And
I'm back just like dad.
And it didn't take any time out of your
life, just like a fucking extra point,
just like an extra point.
Um,
I was actually sitting there waiting
for the questions to come in, um,
for my buddy to send them to me.
And um,
I saw that stupid commercial. Have you
seen their commercial? The Ah, no, no.
Drinking and driving commercial with
the dog is sitting there waiting for his
master to come home and it's sitting
there and the dude doesn't come home.
So they make you think that all,
maybe he died in the drink
and drive and or whatever.
And then the kid comes
home in the morning,
he's like, you know, hey a fluffy,
he couldn't drive last night,
but I'm home. No, what
are you doing? You know,
I just want the dog to be like, Hey, yeah
dude, it's great you came back. But I Fyi,
I took a shit in the kitchen.
You know,
you haven't been home for
like fucking 15 hours,
so don't even look at me like that.
I peed on the carpet.
I shit in the kitchen and I need to go
out right now and I need some fucking
food. All right, next time
you're gonna to go out pose.
And how about leaving some food
out? Maybe some water, you know.
Okay.
Jesus Christ.
Every time you fucking come home I greet
you like he accomplished something.
Even if he just went to the store,
it would it kill you to leave out
some food but it fucking kill you.
Um,
anyways,
you can't do that anyways cause fucking
dogs would eat all of it in two seconds.
And then Yak,
if he left out 15 hours worth of food,
they'd have it done in 15 seconds because
that's what they do because they're
dogs. They're fucking animals. All right,
let's read some questions for
the week. A stinky coworker, a,
uh,
Billy switchblade.
I work in a small office with another
girl who was really nice and helpful,
helpful.
Her and I share a small cubicle and I've
noticed since the first day she does
not shower and she smells
like B. Oh. Oh Jesus.
Oh Gee gauge. Um, anyway,
since we are so close together
for eight hours a day,
it seems to be ruining my concentration.
My question is,
how do I tell her to get rid of the
smell without offending her or without
getting my boss involved?
It seriously is making me think about
switching jobs. Thanks for the help.
Big Fan of your comedy and the
podcast. Ps, go fuck yourself, dude.
I don't know.
Okay.
If it was a dude, you could just
say it. How do you say it to a lady?
Yeah.
All right, well let's, let's just
brainstorm here by the way. 21,
19 and they go for two points.
Seattle, La, where they don't get it.
Okay.
They don't get it.
Yeah. It keeps a fucking, just 21, 19.
Seattle's gonna win this fucking game.
Anyways, let's see. What the
fuck would I say? Hey, listen,
I'm not trying to be a
jerk. You know, you know,
I love you. I love working with
you and everything, but uh,
you know, you just Kinda, I
don't know, how do I put this?
You just kind of like
smell really bad. I mean,
how the fuck do you, there's no way to
say it, dude. You stink. Hey, listen,
let me try this one. Hey,
listen, semantic, come here
for a second, you know. No,
that's close enough.
Uh,
come over here, but stay there
if you know what I mean. Um,
I want to hose you down. I, what the fuck
do you say? I don't know what to say.
You fucking smell. There's no
way to say it. Like, listen,
okay.
I hate to be the one to tell you this,
but you don't smell good.
You need to bathe more often.
You're coming in here and
you smell like body odor.
Ah, dude, there's not, there's no
way to fucking do it. There's no way.
The only way you do it is you go to your
boss and then you look like a bitch.
Okay.
Or
You,
you can go passive aggressive.
Okay.
MMM.
You could just bring in like a ridiculous,
not, you go out and you buy a bunch of
air freshness. All right. And he just
stick an air freshener in the cubicle.
Okay.
And if she doesn't get the hint the
next day you have to air fresheners.
Wednesday there's three.
You get the point right?
And you just keep bringing in more and
more air fresheners until she finally
takes the bait and says,
why do you have all those air fresheners?
Why do you keep putting all these air
fresheners in there and it without saying
a word? You look at
her, you hold your nose,
and then you just pointed
her and then that's it.
And then you turn back around
and you go back to work like it.
Like it never happened.
And then when she runs
out of the cubicle crying,
you quickly take all of the air
fresheners. You throw them in the basket,
he tie him off,
you hand them to a coworker
who's obviously Ben informed,
you know of what to do.
You handed off to them and they sprint
to the fucking trash bin and they throw
it out. No one, the
boss shows up and says,
why did you tell old fucking stink
toast over here that she smelled? Uh,
you like, I never said
that. I never said anything.
I know w w and she says you
have a bunch of air fresheners.
There are no air fresheners here, sir.
I do not know what you're talking about.
And he just fucking deny all of it.
Okay.
Did you at any point pinch your
nose and point in her direction?
I have no recollection of
any type of behavior. I was
at my cubicle doing my job.
Did anyone hear him pinch
his nose in point in her?
Absolutely not. No one can hear that, sir.
Even if he did in you're covered.
You just have to realize at that point
you're going to be trashing a year
working friendship.
Yeah.
What if you just went out and you
bought some ladies Deodorant, right?
And he put a little pink bow on it and
when she walked in you bowed your head
and genuflect it as you held it up to her.
Okay.
I'm trying to think of a nice way of
telling somebody that they stink a female.
MMM.
All right. Here's another one where you
get like your other coworkers involved.
MMM.
It's like throwback sports
fan day and you just sign,
everybody's going to do the wave.
All right.
And then the one person conducting them
also has this little spray bottle of
perfume oil rig comes by her for
be like, Hey, she raises her thing.
Like people on either side just spray
perfume into our armpits really quickly
and then everybody runs away now
than ever. She'd start crying again.
Just ask her. Just say, listen,
is there a way for me to tell you that
you have body odor that won't make you
cry?
Is there a way for me to do that?
How quick is there anything worse since
when somebody puts you in a position to
have to fucking do that,
you know,
oh my God,
you fucking stink.
You know what's the worst
is the air freshener thing?
Cause there's going to be this,
this tipping point where the air freshener
in the BIA or con or are competing
for your fucking sense of smell.
And if you can somehow tough your
way through that day without puking,
you're a better man than me.
MMM.
Is there anything worse than when you're
watching your own fucking team and a
guy catches a ball and you
just watching the quarterback,
so to just escort him down the field,
it's like at any point are you going to
try to take a proper angle or at least
dive at their fucking what are you doing?
Sorry. Alright. [inaudible]
animal research. Uh,
Dear Bill Nye the scientifically
illiterate guy. Ooh, he got clever there,
everybody. Um, all right.
I'm curious if you have any thoughts on
performing research on lab animals for
the benefit of humans.
Um,
we're not talking about testing
lipstick on bunnies here,
but serious medical research using flies,
mice,
primates and other animal models of
devastating human diseases like cancer and
Alzheimer's disease.
I bring this up as I recently made the
difficult decision to leave a prestigious
genetic lab,
Nobel peace,
a Nobel prize winning researcher.
No Shit.
Real deal during my phd training as I
couldn't rationalize subjecting mice to
painful procedures and an
all around shit life anymore.
I am currently refocusing my career
to only performing research on human
patients that give informed consent.
This decision has already
helped me sleep better at night.
So what do you think through
the costs of animal suffering,
ultimately justify the means of
increasing our knowledge of human disease?
Let's get fucking philosophy
philosophical here.
Thanks for your comedy and the podcast.
Best regards. All right. First off, uh,
I take back making funny. If you're Bill
Nye the scientifically literate guy,
sometimes it pisses me off when I know
morons are writing me just as dumb as I
am, and then they're going to make
fun of me for being dumb. But you,
with your background, you had the right
to do that. So my apologies. All right.
Secondly,
secondly,
who would know better than
somebody who actually did the job?
There's no way I could
fucking do that job,
but selfishly I reap the benefits of it.
I think what you're saying is
ultimately the way we should do it,
um,
is that it should be human beings making
an informed decision that they want to
be tested. And uh, you know what?
They'd still figure out something evil.
They go to the third world and they would
find people don't have a fucking pot
to piss in.
And they would somehow flimflam them
and get them to sign some shit that they
didn't even know what the fuck
they was signing. But, uh,
that's what human beings do.
But yeah, I would say that, uh,
yeah, we should not be doing
that. We shouldn't be doing
most of what we're doing.
Um, and then a lot of
times I think, you know,
I go back and forth on,
you know, whether we, um,
being a vegetarian or eating meat,
I just love the way steak tastes
and chicken and all that shit.
But I definitely think that, uh, you know,
we shouldn't, shouldn't be killing as many
animals as we do or if we're going to,
you gotta be like raising them like
cattle and then you kill them. I Dunno,
but I don't know.
I saw something recently
about how Vivian Campbell,
who's been playing in Def Leppard
for awhile has cancer. And, um,
so I was reading up on him and I saw a
picture of Def Leppard and what are they
guitars? The guy with the short
hair who's been in the band forever.
He standing there in his fifties,
shirtless in the guys absolutely
fucking shredded. So I'm like,
what the fuck is this guy though?
And I looked it up and for the last 20
years he quit Busan and he's eating a
Vegan diet and he's kind
of on a mission to, uh,
tell people that you know,
that you can get shredded and be fucking
ripped eating vegetarian and all that
type of stuff.
So that fascinates the hell out of
me because as much as I love cigars,
I love booze and steak and
all that type of stuff.
You definitely feel fucking awful.
Afterwards,
the next day hung over.
He got that cigar fucking awful
taste in your mouth and you know,
and eat a steak dinner.
Especially if you have like the taters
and you eat it with something that you
know, it's going to be difficult
to digest. You fucking,
you just need to take a nap.
But if you eat a vegetarian
meal, you'll, yeah,
I don't know. I always still feel
light and I feel fucking energized.
I feel I might, I'm in a great mood and
it's one of those things where like,
I know that I should be
doing that most of the time.
I just Kinda like doing the
wrong thing more of the time. Um,
and also I'm stuck in my ways
and I'm too lazy to read up on a,
you know,
learning vegetarian dishes.
Like tonight I'm going out and I'm
getting a pork chop. I know. Yeah. Yeah.
I've been thinking about it all fucking
day and I'm going to smoke a cigar later.
I already know doing that. But every
once in a while while I'm doing it,
I pictured myself 30 years in the,
in the future,
sitting on one of those hospital examine
her things. You know what the fucking,
that frontal covering smoke with
my ass hanging out the back,
waiting for the doctor to come back and
I'll start thinking about all the pork
chops and cigars. I smoked
and I'm thinking, I don't
want to be that guy either.
So I gotta I gotta do something here.
Um,
but getting back to what you say, yeah,
no, I don't think that they should do it.
Um, ultimately, no.
I think that the fact that we've always
put human life ahead of everything else
is why there's 7 billion people on the
planet and the polar ice caps are melting.
Now, do I have any sort of background
to make that statement? Absolutely not,
but that's what podcasting is all
about. So go fuck yourself. All right.
Calls after a date.
[inaudible] Hello William.
I went out on a date with a girl.
Congratulations.
We both seem to have a great
time. Uh, at the end of the date,
she initiated the hug and yes.
What I asked if she wanted to go
out again. That's wonderful. Well,
I called her a few days after the date
and left a message. No callback. Texted.
I texted her the day after.
No reply.
Should I give her a few days to reply
or move on? Move on, dude. Move on.
Abso-Fucking-Lutely move on.
And a,
that sounds like somebody who
doesn't know how to say, Hey,
I had a great time, but I don't want to
see you again. I think you, you know,
what does it say? You asked her? Uh, yeah,
you asked if she wanted to go out again.
She probably initiated the hug
so he wouldn't try to kiss her.
And then she just said what you wanted
to hear so she could get the fuck out of
there. And that's what I would guess.
But uh, either way, who gives a fuck?
You asked her out. She said yes. You
know, you're in the game. You know,
they're not all going to be hits,
but if you bat 300,
you make the fucking all star team.
Don't ever forget that. So keep,
keep swinging away. Their
buddy, they fuck. Oh, um,
all right.
Oh Jesus.
I thought that whole was going
to go on forever. Should I dumper
uh,
dear Barbara Rasa
the fuck does that mean
and hopefully Nia to, um,
I'm in a fucked up situation right now.
I've been dating this chick for the past
six months and it's been going fine and
Dandy until a few days ago we were
at the house having crazy sex,
but just as she was about to climax,
she kind of yelled her ex's name.
Fuck you. That did not
happen. I'm calling bullshit.
Get the fuck Outta here,
dude.
That's hilarious. That is fucking
not only what I have laughed,
I would have kept fucking her until she
was done. I just be like, Hey, look,
I understand. Sorry. I'm getting on a
cough drop here. I understand. You know,
you're not ready. You're not
ready to get into a relationship,
but you're ready to fuck somebody else.
That sounds like a perfect situation
for me. I don't give a fuck.
Yell out anybody's name.
You want to,
I'll ghost write this fucking
this blowjob. I don't give a fuck.
Sorry. Jesus Christ. Um, anyways, uh,
he goes on to say I was dressed up and
just left and we haven't talked since.
Now I know for a fact that she can't be
cheating on me because her x is dead.
He died like two.
Oh Jesus.
He died like two years ago
when they were still together.
My rational side is telling me that
I'm a dick and should just forgive her,
but my instincts are telling me,
fuck that bitch.
What should I do best regards
from Italy? Oh, first of all,
uh, I can't, I had a great
time. I was in Italy, went to
Rome. I can't wait to come back.
I know rob was kind of like, uh,
the basic place you go
when you first went there,
but this is the first place ever
when I learned to see the column a,
the Coliseum, where
else should I go? Milan,
Florence, Venice. Where should I go?
Person from Italy or anybody from Italy
listening. Let me know where I should go.
But getting back to your question,
should you move on? Absolutely.
She should always listen to your
instincts. They're always right.
Okay.
Are there,
are there is a reason.
Okay.
You know, there's a reason. I mean, dude,
your rational side is telling you that
you're a deck and you should forgive her,
that there's nothing rational about that.
Yeah.
Let me ask you this, dude.
If you were banging her,
let's just say her name was Maria,
right. And right as you can and you went,
oh, and then they're like, what?
What the fuck would she do?
Do you think she'd be back with you?
Okay.
Would you even question her if
she didn't get back with you?
You're totally agree with it.
If she actually got back to you
with you after you did that,
when you be sitting there going,
what the fuck is wrong with this person?
How low is your self esteem that
you're going to put up with that?
And if you have low self esteem to that
level, how many dicks had been in Europe?
Ah, sorry. That's how guys
stick. Yeah, Dude. No.
Okay.
I only thing I would say is
don't say fuck that bitch.
She went through something
unbelievably traumatic, you know,
and Java c loved the guy.
I feel bad for and so should you,
but you shouldn't get your heart and
mixed up in that shit. All right.
That's what I would do.
Um,
okay.
Yeah, they didn't add a very nice
way. I would just say like, you know,
I just don't think you're
ready to be in a relationship.
MMM.
Yeah.
No matter what she says,
you just hold it to the fact that you
called out you're dead boyfriend's name
when you had an orgasm.
There's really no, uh,
you should just stop talking and
come in for the hug right now.
Okay.
And I will not let go til you tell it too.
I'm sorry.
Ah,
oh, big love. Until you
say somebody else's name.
Um, alright, let's plow ahead
here. I'll tell you one last story.
I did a benefit this
weekend for a all simas.
Now the joke he gave the officers would
be like, for what? Alzheimer's for what?
You see what I did there? You know
that guy whenever you say, yeah,
my grandmother is hard of
hearing, he goes, what?
You get it fucking joke book Larry.
I fucking hate people that do that.
Unless you're doing it because you know
I hate it then I love you then that's
funny. But if you're
actually it for real, I,
it just like gives me joke Douche
chills. Like I, uh, oh my God.
Look at the fucking tits on error.
Whoa.
What kind of an asshole is still brings
a defense sign? The d and the fence.
We get it. It was a funny joke
and NFL films in the Seventies.
MMM.
Holy Shit.
Saint Louis is up 28,
19 with five 30 to go.
What do they down by right now?
Was that nine points?
Seattle's got the ball.
What do you think, Bill?
I think if they didn't win
the Superbowl last year,
they would actually win this game.
But I got a feeling they
probably lost too many guys
that they're going to come up just
short. Oh, there he goes. Russell Wilson.
I just don't see the rams
being able to hold on though.
I got to root for the underdog. Oh, pills.
Quit being a bitch. Just pick
a team. You know what I say?
I say fucking Seattle comes back. They
come back now that they're past midfield,
GI bill really going down in
Olympia. Anyways, so I did this, uh,
I did this benefit for
Alzheimer's for y and um,
it was for a,
Seth Rogen put it together.
It was just fucking amazing.
Lineup. And, um, I didn't realize,
I mean usually what do you do? Those
fucking things. Nine Times out of 10,
they're fucking, ah, they're
outside and it sucks.
And it's a bunch of fucking, you
know, rich people walking around,
trophy wives with their red bottom
shoes and nobody paying attention.
And then it's a benefit.
So if he call them assholes,
then you're the counter or
whatever. Um, I actually, uh,
it was not outside.
It was at the palladium,
right on sunset strip.
And that's actually where Richard Pryor
recorded a live on the sunset strip,
you know, way back in,
I think around 1980.
He did it and it was a bucket list of
mine too, at some point do a show there.
And uh,
it was so fucking amazing to be
able to perform that. Unfortunately,
I was really sick, so I couldn't be
as social as I want it to be. But um,
it's fucking awesome.
Show Craig Robinson and his band,
uh,
with a house band and they will
hilarious. Plus an awesome band. And um,
Seth hosted the thing.
Yeah.
And, uh, what the fuck was
appointed? My God damn story. Weird.
Al Yankovic was on it. Sarah Silverman
was just a fucking awesome show.
And um, I can't remember what the
point in my fucking story was,
was the point of my story
just was awesome to form there
that it was a good cause. Oh
my God, it was for Alzheimer's.
I'm literally doing the joke. Um, let
me see what happens to somebody's brain.
Fuck of works.
I started watching the rams Seattle
game cause it's getting exciting.
It's Russell Wilson rods for a foul.
They stopped.
Yeah,
I fucked in a, I don't know what I'm
talking about it anymore. Anyways,
I want to thank Seth Rogen, um, but put
me on the show. Uh, I had a great time.
Anytime,
you know,
anytime he wants me to do something like
that I'll definitely do it cause I'm
such a fucking asshole and I lived such
a great life and I'm still a dick that I
need to do benefits to somehow
balance out my Karma. Um,
okay,
I'll definitely do it. But
anyways, it was a fucking amazing.
Okay.
What's amazing about that?
Places it's still looks
okay
like the prior special when you walk
in there, even if you didn't know, um,
that they, uh, recorded it there.
Okay.
Get the fuck Outta here. He goes. Seattle
all the way down to the nine yard line.
St Lowest. Same Old fucking rams. Come on.
I always got to root for the underdog,
but my money says Seattle. Jesus. Fuck.
Ah,
the guy slips on the turf.
Yeah.
Um, anyways, it was
fucking amazing. And um,
I'm hoping to someday
do my own show there.
That is definitely one of the
bucket list I'd ever read.
Told you guys the bucket list.
Uh, theaters, they're all just,
staters were my favorite.
Standup specials were recorded.
I already got to do constitution hall
where, uh, Eddie Murphy delirious was,
um,
okay.
And then the palladium is Richard
Pryor live on the sunset strip.
And then there's a theater in Long Beach.
I don't know what it's called now,
but that's where the greatest
one was. Richard Pryor, uh, live,
uh, live in concert. That
one I want to perform there.
Whoever bill Cosby did, Bill Cosby
himself. I can't remember where that was.
I did Carnegie Hall. That's where Lenny
Bruce and George Carlin voltage specials.
Well, Lenny Bruce was an album. Um,
okay,
where else I want to do red rocks.
Okay.
I did stand up there one time, but it
was before a, uh, like a film thing.
Um, and that place was unbelievably
cool, was not a good show,
you know,
that was outside and everybody was here
to see the movies and then they just
brought me out. No one knew who the
fuck I was and I sort of survived it,
but it was still cool to perform there.
Um,
so I got a bunch that I want to do.
Oh, I know. Uh, I want to do whatever.
Sam Kinison did,
his standup special on the sunset strip,
which I don't think it was at the Roxy.
I want to do a show there.
Um, whatever. I have all these, these
different things. But anyways, let's,
let's close out here by talking
about patriots jets, but, but
Bordeaux,
um,
that was fucking ridiculous that we were
actually able to win that Goddamn game.
And I felt vindicated by watching that
where all my friends was trying to say
that the patriots turned around and that,
that team that I saw that got pounded by
the chiefs that now somehow they're not
that team there, this team this
week. And I was trying to say no,
they are somewhere in the fucking middle.
Um,
okay.
And uh,
I dunno,
statistically we didn't deserve the
win the fucking gay by a long shot.
I guess that was the first time anybody
ever controlled the ball for more than
40 fucking minutes and still
lost the game, you know.
Uh, as much as I want to
credit the Patriots' defense
that we stopped them in the
red zone,
I felt that they were stopping themselves
a lot with bad fucking penalties and
shit like that.
Um,
okay.
And I got to admit,
as much as I can't stand rex Ryan
because I think he talks a bunch of shit.
Okay.
Where he has a good team and I thought
he was really disrespectful to a lot of
people around the fucking league.
I still think he's a great coach and um,
okay.
If they shifted jets didn't fire him
and wanted to start all over again
because he's not the GM of the team,
so he doesn't get to pick the players.
As far as I know.
I think the guy,
yeah,
I think he's a good coach,
is not a lot of good coaches out there.
I think he's a good coach to the jets.
Just fucked up with their player
personnel or whatever. Um,
okay.
I Dunno that guy. I think that that
guy, if he gets fired, that's a,
that's still a good pickup.
Even though I don't like
the way he conducts himself
when he has a good team and
he talks all that shit. Nah, I dunno.
It just always clearly comes across to me.
Okay.
That you're insecure when you
talk like that level of Shit.
Do you know what I mean?
Like up,
my wife watches his fucking reality show.
Okay.
I don't know if it's called love and
hip hop. I don't know what it is,
but it's this chick who has like this
re ridiculous fake fucking tits and a
ridiculous fake fucking ass.
She looks ridiculous.
And she walks around talking about herself
like she's fucking God's gift and I'm
sitting there watching this shit.
Okay.
And I said to my wife,
I was like,
do you realize how truly fucking
stupid you would have to be to be that
confident
to just be walking around like that,
thinking that you're the be all end all
and that you fucking know everything.
Like how truly fucking stupid you would
have to be. Cause whenever I listen,
people who act like that,
you're either unbelievably insecure and
you're trying to overcompensate it or
you just unbelievably fucking naive.
You're a fucking moron.
So that allows you to be that confident.
And then every once in
awhile you'll meet somebody
who just
is just the man and they're
confident and they fucking know it.
You know what I mean?
Which to me is like 1% of the population,
basically that benchmark person
that everyone's trying to be.
Then when they're that fucking confident,
you know,
it fucking makes sense
as far as confident,
but only confident as far as like
what it is that you do. Like,
if you're an athlete or an actor or a
musician, or you're running a business,
like, you know, you're the best at it,
you know you're the best and you're
fucking confident that I understand.
But just straight across the board,
walking around like you're
the shit and you know, you,
you like moving planets
and shit with your mind,
like walking around like you
fucking know everything. Let's just,
how fucking truly dumb you have to be.
Um,
to be that confidence. So I could
never get into directs. Ryan,
when he was talking all that shit,
I'm like,
this fucking guy is actually
good at what he does, his job.
But I don't know if it was cause he
has to live up to his dad or whatever.
I just feel like this guy's beyond
fucking insecure and it's uncomfortable to
watch. And uh, I dunno.
I Dunno. He just, I don't know.
He just always looked like if
you punched him in the belly,
he'd cry and make like that
Pillsbury doughboy knows
noise. You know what I mean?
Those noise, I dunno, I'm
fucking rambling at this point.
Go fuck yourselves. All right.
That's a podcast for this week. Um,
thank you for everybody
who's been listening. Uh,
I'm site the new hours common to get,
no,
it was looking bleak.
I've been writing on this show.
I haven't been getting the stage time.
I wanted to. I've got a couple in there,
a couple reps. All of a sudden you've
got the Ebola thing coming out.
I got some new material.
It ties into some other bullshit,
couple of random thoughts and it's all
starting to come together and I can't
wait. I got a gig coming up down in, um,
down in Florida because I'm
going down for the FSU. Whoa. No,
no, no. I'm playing against
a University of Miami
and, uh, Oh, 28, 26.
Sherman just knocked down,
uh, just knocked down a
pass. And believe it or not,
he walked around nodding his head,
uh,
as quickly as one possibly could.
He can't believe how good he is.
He just can't, he can't
find, can't get over himself.
The guy is in awe of themself and
that's always fun to be around.
Um, all right, listen, that's
a podcast for this week. Go
fuck yourselves. All right.
Cowboy's giant's my prediction.
They had the lost Victor Cruz.
All right, I'm going to go.
I'll make a gambling prediction.
Not even knowing what
the fucking spread is.
Rams with a first down rams with
the first down. Where's Sherman now?
Nodding his head.
Oh wait,
now the rams guy is not in his
head and he's walking around.
Everybody can't believe
how awesome they are. Five.
Jesus Christ. Oh wait, no, I'm
sorry. It was a fake fucking
pun. That was the punter.
Hilarious.
The putter is walking or can't fucking
believe how awesome he is. I knew it.
I knew I was better than this position.
Yeah,
I used to do a joke about that way back
in my way back in the day that I was
going to start celebrating
after fucking jokes worked.
Like they way that the way they do when
the NFL, when you run for a first down,
you start stomping around like
Jerome Bettis. Um, anyways,
I'm rambling at this
point. Uh, by the way, oh,
you Fsu people. Okay. I know
I'm coming down on your team,
but you guys really need to come
up with a couple more songs. Okay?
Before you give me shit,
because I performed at your school.
I had a great time at your fucking school,
but you know what?
You know I had a great time because you
guys showed up and during my fucking
show you weren't going to be
fucking two seconds. All right?
So don't be a bunch of whiny cuts about
the constructive criticism that I'm
giving you. I'm not saying
stop doing the Tomahawk Chop.
That's up for the date of Americans to
try to fucking enlighten me about that.
But why don't you get a
couple, you know, switch it up.
P did he come down there and do maybe a
couple remixes on the same fucking idea?
You know, just to, you know, just
for the viewer at home. Anyways,
that's the podcasts. Go fuck
yourselves. We'll talk to you next week.