Alcohol. Hey, what's
going on? It's bill burr.
And as promised this week,
there's going to be a Monday morning
podcast epilogue with uh, the wonderful,
the lovely, the lovely Nia who's
a little under the weather,
a little under the weather.
But I'm here for you.
I'm here for you guys to
make me laugh too much,
but I'm here. Yes, you are
here. Be in a fucking true.
Yeah. Well, I'm also on my
way to the freaking airport,
so we got to do this one quickly
turning old friend into girlfriend or,
and I see, and I just thought that
this was a question for me, Nia,
as most of these ares,
considering this is my podcast,
but you have become such an
epic personality on it. Wow.
That more often than not, these
questions start this way. Hey, Bill,
love the podcast.
We'd really like your,
and then in parentheses and Nias if
possible, thoughts on the subject.
So you've gone up to not being mentioned
at all to saying Nia if possible,
right? Yeah. Right. And ask and
ye shall receive right. Here I am.
So you're basically at this level,
the same level of the
professor and Maryanne on
Gilligan's island. What do you,
what do you mean the professor
and Marianne? Because they did,
they did that song two ways at the
beginning. Right. Pat, can you hear it?
Tails and they'd go
[inaudible] ran his wife,
they're movie star and then they'd
be like, the professor ran Mary Yang.
So they already said, um, last,
but then a couple of times they'd
be like the movie star and the rest.
Oh Hey. Yeah. And the rest and the rest.
And I want to say like that had they had
done that first and their agents had to
been like, listen, who's kidding?
Who Marianne is fucking hotter. Yeah,
she was definitely hotter and
hotter than ginger. I liked her,
but I always like brunettes better.
I'm a ginger.
I'm not going to put Yaba Daba do, you
can fucking the same thing. Ginger was,
you know, she was, oh, she was
definitely smoking. But I mean,
when Marianne was the more, you
know, she was the girl next door,
she's more accessible. And I thought
the professor is pretty hot too far.
We really riffing about the Sherwood
Schwartz. We are. All right,
let's get into this here.
All right.
There's a lady I've been friends
with for over a decade now.
We met in college and for about a year
or two back then I would have considered
a one of my closest friends. That
means he's jerking off to her, um, to,
I really, I really cherish our
friendship. She walks away. How's,
Yup.
And then he feels really bad and then
he goes to church and he gives money and
that money is used in a pedophile case,
you know,
so ladies really taking it
out. They're all friends. Yeah.
For the kids. Oh God. Um, during
that whole time she had a boyfriend,
so I never thought about making a move,
stupid and lack the confidence to do
so anyways. It's not a husband. Um,
as time went on,
we gradually lost contact until recently
I found her on Facebook like you do,
like you do.
And we spoke for the first time in a,
we live in the same city. So I
suggested we get together and catch up,
which she is enthusiastic
about and is going,
it's going to happen sometime soon.
Now for the details were both single and
30 years old. She's recently divorced.
No kids clean break with little to
no drama. Nice. She is beautiful.
And honestly one of the
nicest people I've ever met.
That's funny cause I see a red flag. Oh
yeah. Then why'd the guy just dumper, uh,
you know, that she didn't dump
him? Oh, come on. Oh, come on.
Was seriously, seriously. What do you,
where are you based in a stop it people
get divorced for a lot of reasons.
Stop it.
Um,
I had no point. I just want to annoy you,
so, all right, go ahead and finish it up.
Hurry back when we were close,
I was okay looking,
but extremely skinny and shy.
Since then I put on about 25 to 30 pounds
of fat and muscle distributed pretty
evenly.
This guy's an honest guy,
so I'm looking much better and
that is boosted my confidence. Um,
yeah cause you can use your gut
to pin them against the bar.
He'd going home with me.
That's disgusting.
My question. She has only know
me as the friend Zone Guy,
the classic Chris Rock Bit.
Uh,
but does eight years with no contact or
racist and you think I might have a shot
with her.
Any advice on how to go about this and
how to act and what to say on the night
we catch up would be greatly appreciated.
Thanks in advance.
A PS, one thing may be an issue
here. After I suggested a ketchup,
I checked on her Facebook page and it
turns out that she changed her status from
married to single only a day or two
earlier. How would you find that out?
Cause he was watching it, watching
stalking her on Facebook. Yeah.
He knows every little fucking
change she makes it. Yeah.
But this could be as hard though.
It could be as hard, you know? Yeah.
But I think at a certain point you got
to step away from the Facebook. Yeah.
But without that he wouldn't, he
wouldn't have seen it. But anyways,
he gets his button real life.
That's true.
She said she's been signal for a few
months. Yeah, so that was inadvertent,
rotten timing on my part.
Hopefully I don't come across as tankless
opportunities. Opportunistic douchebag.
No, no, no, no, no. Not at
all. I don't think so. No,
because they are probably separated
for a long time, you know,
but still technically married. Look,
no marriage falls apart in three weeks.
She was already mentally out, you know?
Yeah. They probably having problems.
They separate and he moved
out or she moved out,
but she still technically married.
She's sleeping in the bedroom.
He's downstairs on the couch or whatever.
Or they're in separate places.
They might have different bedrooms. I'm
not, no, I'm not saying it like that.
She could be paying for the house.
I didn't mean it like that.
I was saying like that weird,
like the end of the relationship where
you're in the same place and like you got
to pass each other in the kitchen,
you know,
and act like you're on
a subway and don't know
each other.
Well,
I guess that does happen if people can't
afford to go and get their own places.
But yeah,
you'd think in an ideal situation they
wouldn't have to still be under the same
roof looking at each other and thinking
about all the things that went wrong.
All right,
so he wants to know,
does the eight years I've not
contact erase the pass. Yeah.
Does that erase the free now? It
does not. No, no, no it doesn't.
I don't know that it doesn't erase
the friend zone. How does that
work?
Like I can't hang out with someone who
has a vagina and not eventually wanna
Bang,
Bang them
with.
Yeah. Unless I'm just completely
not attracted to them,
which means they would have
to be some sort of, you know,
major car accident or something.
That's, that's a horrible thing to say.
Yeah. I'm just, I don't, it
doesn't, it doesn't. Um, no,
it's more like you guys have
a history of friendship,
but it can always change
because things change.
At what point when you, when, when
you're hanging out with somebody,
would you be like, oh, this person's like,
cause I would just think if,
if you're hitting it off and you'd
be like being in friends. Yeah.
Then eventually aren't you thinking
like, well hey, you know, maybe, uh,
maybe this would go to the next level.
What it does cross your mind.
So what exactly does a guy do?
How can we avoid this purgatory? Because
none of us want to be friends with you.
Well, really we look at bump, Bang
them with you, then a friendship. Bang.
If I'm begging you,
then I can become friends with you by
discovering who you are after the ass.
But you don't think that people can
be friends with each other. Right.
Hang out and,
and not have that energy between them.
Listen to you. I'm a closer, I'm hoping,
I was hoping to give you a spit take. No,
I don't know. Is she
drinking your I'm sick. T I a
hi philosophy that I'm friends
with guys and I bring it with you.
Yeah,
exactly.
You're not friends with women because
you're one of those people that doesn't
think that men and women can really be
friends because the sex thing always gets
in the way. Which I used to feel
big time. Yeah. I don't know,
but I don't think that's true anymore
because I'm friends with a guy, isn't it?
It's not like that because
it's 100% it's not really.
It's a maturity thing. Yeah, absolutely.
Mm. I Dunno. Maybe. Well, all right.
Well, you know what? It's not like I'm,
I'm not going to waste time on this thing
actually trying to defend that I'm a
mature human.
Yeah,
I'm not, there would be no
point now. That wouldn't be.
I don't think I would just trash myself.
Then you piled on. Hey did. So anyway.
I don't think that the eight years
it doesn't. I had to get out of it.
How does this guy get out of it? You
go and you meet and you, you, you,
you take it up notch. Now you're both
single. You're both older and wiser.
Don't stop speaking in code. Is it the
take it up and watch what you throw?
Some sugar in there, like a Mario
Batali. Oh No. What's his name? Emilio.
Estevez. What's the name of that
fucking cook? Mri. Got some sugar, Bam.
And the crowd goes nuts. Yeah.
You just, you flirt with her.
He just maybe compliment her a little
bit more than you did before and all that
kind of stuff would take it slow.
Start hanging out more. All right,
let's break your attentions. Next role.
Play. Okay. Okay. You're the dude. Okay.
And I'm the chick. Oh God. In the friend
zone after eight years. Right. All right.
We're meeting. Okay. And we
see each other. Hey. Oh my God.
Look at you. You look amazing. How are
you doing? Oh, thank you. Well, you know,
considering, yeah, marriage just
ended. I'm sorry to hear about that.
I don't know what that was.
There's a lot of cards in this
restaurant that's really, oh,
we don't have to eat here. No, I got
it. Okay. I saw some things on the menu.
Yeah. So, well, we can go wherever you
want. It's up to you. Okay. Yeah. Um,
I'm sorry to hear.
I was just bringing that negativity
and that's why I was never this person.
I would never, this person, he
brought that in my car and I remember,
I remember you. Okay. And
you were the most positive
radiant person I've ever met.
Oh, stop. I have no doubt. No, seriously.
I have no doubt that it wasn't,
it wasn't your fault. Listen,
I know it takes two to tango to,
to end the relationship.
Jumping into this sign up. You already
met the host of Shit and you're just, wow.
I have to admit. I'm excited to see you.
Uh, can we kitsu please. That's nice.
You know, it's been a while since I felt
somebody was excited to see me. I am,
I'm excited for it for awhile to see. I
got to admit. Um, but anyway, tell me,
tell me what else is going on with you.
At what point are you going to throw a
joke out there? If I could just interject.
You've got to make a laugh at
some point. Why? I'm sorry,
I'm not a professional frigging comedian.
All right.
I'm just going to get you nowhere,
the ground. Alright. Okay. Alright. Okay.
Um, you want to eat in the high road?
Whatever you want to do. Okay. Well
you didn't inside. Okay. All right.
Can I get you want something to drink
or uh, oh yes. What do you want?
I'll have a alone and lethal bottle. Okay.
Oh, just a lot. A lot of stress. Yeah,
I understand. Can we get a bottle of
your house? Where though? Thank you.
You want some food or like a
salad or burgers? Absolutely.
So what have you been doing?
You look different. Well, yeah,
muscular and kind of fat and it all works.
Let
me try to take care of myself. I got to
to, I wanted to look nice for you tonight.
Fuck this. W W like I
personally, I would try one,
I'll throw my theories out here.
What I would do is I would come in and
immediately try to make her laugh and
it's some point I would point out how
gorgeous some other woman was that just
walked by. Like, wow, that girl's, you
know, and cause that would be like, oh,
you like her is that was,
you're fucking me into that.
But by me kind of start steering it
towards the sex thing to get out of the
friend zone. Wow. You've changed,
you're like really forward.
Now you're on the side of my breast.
That's not really a hug is it?
That's ridiculous.
Terrible idea.
It's the name of my next special what?
That's ridiculous. That's a terrible idea.
That sums up all of my theories. No,
no, no. He should go on there and be,
he should be flirtatious
with her and have it not you.
So you can then get the motor running.
You can then as as that, and you're right.
Cause it shouldn't be too much
dwelling on the past that Oh my God,
what happened and all, I'm so
sorry about that. It shouldn't be.
So you want to get her out of that.
He
wants to go in and just be like,
I'm living life. Bring in this.
He's got a light up there. He's got to go
magic Johnson on this one. Right, right.
Exactly. Not Corinne. He's gotta
be magic. Not Kareem. It's right.
Yeah. He wouldn't know. You should go in
there. Be flirtatious. Be Complimentary.
Definitely. Definitely. But don't
be in a, not in a predatory way.
I don't know that this guy
really understands the balance,
or maybe he does and he's just got,
he's a stalker,
but he doesn't want to be too far the
other side because then it's like,
what happened to you? You used to be so
nice and all of a sudden you're a creepo.
So he's got to be able to
bring back that flirtatious,
sexy energy without
being totally disgusting.
And Are you guys picking up on this?
This is what,
this is why it's so hard for guys to
get laid because it's literally like
dismantling a bomb. It's gotta be
the perfect combination of flirty,
but not creepy,
but not overbearing,
but not disinterested or whatever, if I'm
using that word correctly. Um, listen, I,
I think you've, you've, you've, you've
helped without a doubt. I'm sorry.
No, no, no. It's just that I have
to go to the fucking airport. Um,
shout out to Jacksonville.
Shout out to Jacksonville.
I'm coming to that strip mall out
there to the comedy zone with dude.
I called it. What did I say?
What did I say? Robinson Cano.
Dude Robinson could know.
Um,
Paul Versey as guests that your pulverize
the impression. It's really, I'm just,
I started to do Bobby and
then I tried to tone it down.
I thought it sounded like Bobby,
anything. That's it. Yeah, that's Bobby.
But that's just become a
generic sort of impression.
Kind of like your generic female voice.
Yeah.
It was kind of sounds like a stereotypical
gay man. It's a little bit different.
I twist it up. Oh, I see. That's
what's set up just a little bit. Yeah.
I never claimed to be Michael
Winslow. Okay. I'm a one
trick pony. I see something.
It makes me angry and
then I yell about it. Uh,
just tell this guy I,
I'm excited.
I'm excited for this guy
as the one I want to say.
to reconnect with her
to possibly take it to the next level
cause I think they've got a great
foundation. Your friends.
Yeah. I don't know. It's nice.
It's a nice story and it's a,
he seems like a nice guy.
Go in there and make it happen,
but it doesn't necessarily have to
happen on the first meeting, you know,
you'd meet up, it'd be kind
of flirty, you walk away,
you come back to it and
then you hang out again.
Then you playing ping
pong and it's just like,
well he just got to learn not
to get into that friend zone.
You got to make it more about
like how she's attractive,
make it clear that you're interested in
her and you've always say for certain
just reach across. He puts your hand on a
forum and you say, listen, listen Selena,
I really hope this isn't too forward,
but I have always,
always, you know, you got to maybe
pull the move. You pulled on me.
What do you, what do you mean when
you were like let's share a cab.
When we were living in New
York and I was like, why?
Why do you want to share a cab? And I
said, cause I want to kiss you. Yeah.
And that was like the perfect thing
to say. But he got, see, it's honest.
It's like, you know, it
kind of sets the mood.
I looked at your fat
and then I looked away.
You can't say that in the continued
to stare it up. No, that's,
that is the world series of poker moment.
When you go fucking,
I'll let you go all in and then
you stand up, you walk around,
walk around the table. Here
comes the river. Right. Exactly.
I'll take a cab with you. I was
fucking, I was on my game that night.
You were then we got in
the cab and you said, uh,
is would riding along and that fucking
jerk off was driving like a maniac.
You said, you're going to kiss me yet. And
I said, no, I'm waiting for a red light.
We had a red light and then we kissed.
Right. That's true. Then what happened?
We drove again. The guy's being a maniac
and then he slowed down and you're like,
it's another red light.
And then that was it.
And I was in Bingo
Bango and then hit left.
Fuck. I am years later with the dog
living with you and it's awesome.
So good luck to you sir. Um, that
was a nice ending, wasn't it?
Was all right.
What can I hype crane horror out my stuff
cause I forgot to say my new special
you people are all the same
is going to be available, um,
for download off of Bill
bird.com on October 1st USA time.
I don't know what, but it's going to be
there. We'll probably try and put it up.
Do you say USA time? Yeah. I got people
in Australia and a bunch of people. Uh,
October 1st is USA.
I'll go fuck yourself.
Thank you to everybody who was
sent me all the nice comments.
People liked what I did on Twitter.
I'm sorry to those Twitter on Conan.
They tweeted me.
There you go.
And they said that they enjoyed
my performance and I had a uh,
I had a great time.
I thought you, I thought you did an
amazing job on Conan. It was a hilarious,
people were really, uh, taken
aback by your Steve Jobs.
Yeah, but they weren't though. They
weren't, but they weren't. Come on, man.
You know what it is.
It's like those are a bunch
of happy people who came
out to Hollywood wanting to
go to a TV taping are all in a great
mood and all of a sudden this 44 year old
curmudgeon comes out.
It took half a then they got
on board. I had a good time.
No, it was funny. Yeah.
And Conan was was awesome as always.
He just started teeing me up.
The end of wars is really likes you too,
which was a fantastic Bam.
You guys watch the whole cone and
you should have because they have to.
Florence band of horses is at the
troubadour on Thursday night. Yeah.
So if you want to see these
guys, you should go. Yeah,
they are kick ass bad and they loved
you and they're opening up for a Willie
Nelson coming up. So it's, Oh my God.
Usually when they come through here,
like my buddy Solomon, like the Wiltern
theater, which is like a 300 seat or so.
The troubadour, you know, it's a good,
good venue that holds like 400 people.
That's like the coming over to your house.
They're probably sold out already.
I don't know why.
Why do we go with the
negative? No, not to happen?
Because they will see the horse assuming
that they're going to be sold out
anyway. All right, well, I'll try it.
I'll try and see if I can get you some.
All right. I have to go to the
lovely Nia. Everybody. Oh, the, uh,
the epilogue. Well, love.
I'll talk to you on Sunday.
Maybe I can drag Versie onto the podcast.
I'll see you.