Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
December 3rd, 2012 and uh, how are you,
this is going to be a as promised last
week and promised all over Twitter that I
would have a special guest this week.
Stand up and Rosebowl legend,
the one and only the guy whose name I
would never mention on the podcast after
our first experience at the Rose Bowl.
And here he is,
the statue of limitations had run out.
Ladies and gentleman, Mr. Joe Barton.
Oh Man. Thanks bill.
Now in that coffin. Uh,
well I know as soon as coughed into
the, this is a, this is fun. Finally.
Absolutely. After all the rose
bowls and a dude, the rose bowls.
I mean you've given me probably the
two greatest thrills of my adult life.
One obviously setting me up in my first
six seconds on the ice with a goal or
setting up your periods
and then then the rolling
when we,
when we were playing pickup hoc pick up
hockey and you gliding around there like
the great white shark.
I got shout in front.
I mean to step on the ice,
tap my stick.
Rocky would tool hits me in the slot.
I go top shelf.
I should have just quit.
Then w why I ended up,
why I spent 500 bucks on the
equipment and only played once.
Well I played like 10 times with like no
pads, eat bag, finally gave me a helmet.
Then I bought all the stuff. I played
once after that, but it was good,
scary.
Joe Joe's like me,
he's one of those guys who's
watched hockey for a good
35 years but never played.
We just didn't come from hockey families.
We both figured we'd take up the game
in our forties and we both looked like
make a wish kids and
when we were out there,
the look on your face when you scored,
you scored the goal and you just put your
arms up and you just left them up and
you said you had this big grin on
your face and I saw it in your eyes.
You're like, this is
what it feels like. This,
you would have thought you scored
one at the NHL Level as opposed to
I felt like his NHL level cause I'll tell
you I was scary when I first got there.
I mean you guys know Ian bag, he's
like six [inaudible] five. He's big.
He's on skates unlike
from Canada and that he, he can fuck it.
Like I heard he's skated with the conduct
did he played junior hockey.
So I'm walking into the rink with just
literally like my street hockey stick and
those, then the rented scapes am I read
it and I walked in and I see him skating
around. I didn't even recognize him.
I'm like Holy Shit, what did I get into?
And then the step and to do that
and I scored another one real quick.
So I'm like I'm looking for the,
I'm looking for the natural hat trick,
your hat trick and 10 seconds
and after that then bag,
cause there's no hint league unless
you can't stop. Right? Like me.
Uh,
so the bags like you're not going to get
the hat trick and then cause I love bag
and he loves me.
He just started cross checking me
in the crease and then that was,
I never got the other thing I touched
another park. But uh, like I said that
back when that, that pickup game is still
fun. But that was, that was hilarious.
It like the bad news bears,
it was like everybody out
there was a different level.
So you could tell like how good somebody
was by much equipment they had and how
new or how old it was.
You went out there,
you had that fucking Pittsburgh
penguins with no shield mass.
That's all I remember.
And you kept playing do and
you are getting scary cause
you're like fucking Cam
Neely size.
So that's what everybody was kind of
saying was like if that fucking guy ever
learns how to skate and doesn't
learn how to stop, like he can't,
if someone's going to get fucking killed,
well that's why I quit
playing roller hockey.
I played roller hockey in San Francisco
for a season and like 10 like eighth
game in.
I couldn't stop on roller skates either.
And I just absolutely buried
some kid about your size,
but not really athletic like
you not to make it nice.
Yeah, my son. No, no, no, no.
Like you're, you're like, you know,
you've been climbing your rope and stuff.
I mean, you're, you're,
you're not like this was a little kid
trying to be actor in shape and I just be,
I buried him like when Kevin Stevens had
to buy a new face after the islanders,
that's how hard I buried him and I'm like,
you know what,
I'm not here to hurt people purposely.
I mean, it's, it's time to give that,
but you got a good heart. I do
have, I do have a good heart.
Really. You get one of those guys, if
you played in the Nhl, you'd be that guy.
You would fucking knock the dude
down and the dude's land in the ice.
You'd cochlear arm back and
then you'd be like, no, no.
So now he's had enough and it, I don't
think that would have a good dance though.
After I won the fight,
I do a nice Hogan.
I'm sure it had one of those where I
would have been in the stands once.
Well I hope everyone has a good,
like either junior ae or in Europe.
Some every good goon has
been in the stands was like
someone would say something
about Mulkin in like, you know, some,
some mafia heroin, den in the, you know,
uh, Mag Nita Gorse and that'd be up
there swinging away protecting his mom.
No, I like that. You know, did you want
to have to have you watched a fuck was,
I just think it might, I have like
add, you've just brought up something.
Oh I know. For Fans, you know,
cause you know hockey's like
the rogue sport for fans, uh,
who don't know what Joe's
talking about. Well, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna have a link up to that,
that classic one where the Bruins went
up into the stands at the Madison Square
Garden and Mike Milbury, who now does
like commentating wearing a suit.
You actually watch him. He takes this
guys loafer off loafers. We're big in the,
uh,
the 70,
speaking of which you actually still
have them cause you're old school.
He took them off. He never hit
the guy, he cocked it back.
He was gonna hit him with the heel
of it and it was uh, it's, it's,
it's just something that
can't be described. So you
have to, you got to see it.
These,
these loafers are my guilty pleasure and
everybody remarks on them now because
I've passed into the age where now I
wear loafers and don't give a fuck.
Like I went to Ross to buy some,
I was by,
by the time she was at Ross because why
not buy Air Jordans that were 140 for 29
bucks?
Like I don't need to know
like giant guys. Like you go to those
kinds of places like when I go to like,
like Ross, uh, for
people on the east coast,
was it Ross dress for less shit for less,
whatever the fuck they call it.
You walk in that they actually have Shaq
size shoes in there for that six foot
eight guy who couldn't dunk.
Yeah. And like neon green and
purple, they're all that crazy shit.
It's always like that fucking shit
you get when your house gets flooded.
Those fucking giant sneakers that are like
neon green. Yeah. Apps a Fuckin lutely.
So dude, I gotta tell you,
speaking of the fucking Rosebowl,
the granddaddy of them all like got a, I
went out and I got the tickets, you know,
every year that's my job.
I go out,
I get the tickets and then I rent the
fucking four door fucking dodge ram pickup
to drive over there doing.
I'm actually, uh, I,
I've just completely checked out of
Christmas shopping and all the other shit.
All I'm doing is thinking about that.
What do you think about fucking
with Wisconsin's in it again?
Uh, yeah. You know, we could've,
we could've been ugly game.
That's going to be ugly
in the parking lot. No,
I mean there's some Nice Wisconsin people.
I wish I in Nebraska, I liked them.
Corn husker girls you've ever
played in Nebraska, Nebraska.
La had said like,
he,
he was rooting for Nebraska yesterday
because he said so we can look at
different fat chicks.
Yeah, the brass because they're a
little bit, they're like younger,
little healthier,
like did their kind of like this,
like the playboy centerfold kind of
chicks. The present Cornell's for girls.
Uh, when they get them, they get them
from that sort of the uh, Oklahoma,
Nebraska.
Right. The bigger loss though was UCLA
because Stanford has nicely can girls,
but they're really smart. Then that
the type of girls that like, Hey,
let's get her,
let's take her tops off at 8:00 AM
that girl last year with
the, the fucking, uh, oh,
is it tequila with the pickle
juice? Dirty Mexican. Oh my God.
Is that what they call that drink? They
did, yes. They did the dirty Sanchez.
I actually walked around
with Picardy dirty Mexican.
The leaf blower. It's what they call
that a leaf blower. There you go. Oh,
we actually walked,
I actually went to like five different
people's houses with Tequila and pickle
juice. Try and explain to them
and everybody thought I was like,
you've lost your mind. Bardic I'm like,
yeah. I mean obviously I did 30 years ago.
Right, but here's the great
pickle juice. It's cost effected.
Everybody for saving money over the
holidays because you can get the most rot,
Gut Tequila in the world.
It tastes good.
If you chug pickle juice with afterwards,
you chase it because I hate,
I hate to kill the dude that's always,
not like I ever drank antifreeze,
but if I ever did,
I always feel it tastes like some
sort of cleaner. It's really fucking,
and it's the amount of people too who
really like, uh, just slam that shit.
I had somebody a long time ago,
one of one of work for one of my managers
that I had back in the day and he,
he fucking drank Tequila and he drank.
He drank that shit like, you know,
like we drink crown royal. Like it was
nothing. Now I'd like to this day, dude,
as much as we'll fucking booze bag as
I am, if you give me a shot of Tequila,
I will make a face like I'm
in seventh grade. I just
can't get that shit down. Oh,
remember that coalesced she,
she had the fucking overalls.
Yeah, I remember bad ass in the
fucking half shirt and underwear.
I remember all of it. He was
good. Yeah, I remember that.
That was before it got a little blurry
or that I in the chronological history of
the Rose Bowl Rao. Uh, first
one ever. The epic, the,
the granddaddy of them all the one,
it's like every great empire
starts with a big crime. Yes.
That was a crime against you
made that was this the greatest?
That was probably my funniest time
as an adult ever. That there's,
why was that? Cause I feel like
we get just as drunk every year,
but that there was just something about,
I think because it was all new. Yeah. No,
but everything worked out. We walked
in that completely fuck hammered.
I remember I bought that, that
50 year old guy. A program.
Cause he thought it was too
expensive and I was like,
let me get to you like technical.
Do you know what you're looking at?
You're looking at a big shot.
You're not going to see a lot of,
I suppose chocolate,
like a fucking idiot.
And we smoke in those Cubans and we
what we got in and somehow you still had
your Cuban cigar. I could, you
have your ticket around you.
You bought the, uh, the super duper
ticket holder and they do, I'm a nerd.
I tried to say it was so many people's
squishing in that they weren't even
looking at me that I was
still smoking a Cuban cigar.
There's something about eating a steak,
drinking a bottle of crown,
smoking a Cuban cigar that makes
you feel empowered to do anything.
People listen to this thinking that you
mean he means splitting a bottle every
year. Joe shows up with two bottles
of crown, one for us and one for him.
And Dude,
I heard Jimmy page and all that picture
that he takes where he puts the,
the Jack Daniels back like that.
I already just stuck his tongue in the,
in the holder. Just, it was
just like a photo op thing.
You actually down the hall.
Oh, that's considered a fifth.
That's terrible. Yeah, it's, well,
it's the regular size crown,
but that's terrible than though.
I didn't want to know that.
Well, he made it up with the
fucking, uh, the heroin abuse. Oh,
I'm just repeating something from somebody
in a bar who allegedly met fucking,
well,
let me tell you something Mr and a bar,
if you're going to talk
shit about Jimmy page,
I just make sure it's true because that's,
that's not a rumor that she'd be like,
you know Jimmy page,
he's not really drinking.
That's like Jay Jimmy Page's jacked.
His is really ice tea. It's like when
you find out when Dean Martin like,
like no dean was drunk most of the
time just when he was already gone.
Like the producer,
like let's put a little less water,
this one down because now people
want to revision is history like,
Oh dean was drinking ice tea like yet
in the hookers were fake like gimme a
break.
Like these guys were partying
their asses off and they could,
they had a good buzz going, look,
you got to know me.
Most of my shit is just stuff that I just
repeat shit that somebody tells me and
then that's it. That's
it. I don't, I don't.
No, but we do drink a lot, but I haven't,
well I had though liar is the cook lie
ads looking at a barbecue brisket or
something.
Dave gave a game too.
I'd say the other thing too,
just the planes coming over when you're,
when you are bombed,
there is nothing better than to uh,
to like f 16 flying right over your
head that you're not expecting.
I mean that was just like,
yeah,
those are like two like
historic teams too.
It's like we went to first
year and it was USC versus
Penn State and Penn state gained six
total yards in that game and I celebrated
it.
Like they won 40 nothing.
Well that's cause you yelled
at that fucking contract
was sitting in front of Oh,
she got mad at you with the cigar.
Yeah. Yeah. The funny thing was was I mean
I, my sister went to Penn state, my sats,
I could've taken him six times,
I wouldn't get an independent state
if you added them all together. But
like a three 90 or a four oh four oh
seven combined and I took a prep course
but we were like, actually the day
I was going to take the sats, I uh,
the night before my, a
friend of mine is like, Hey,
come help me collect some money.
So I didn't get a good night's sleep
before I took my test. Oh, that's right.
Back in the day when you were in
Pittsburgh back in the day. Yeah.
We want tell them those stories.
But that's, that was my essay.
That's what I didn't do
too good on the sats.
You don't, yeah. Is it those
that, that stuff about uh,
collected money back in the day
when you are, you are the, uh,
the fucking dude they brought
around the enforcer that you,
you don't get into that stuff ever,
Huh?
No, it was just fun. It's just, it's
just, it was just for beer money.
Let's talk about that.
That's why that guy,
that one year,
the first year the wife were that
lady after she gave you shit,
she said something about your nose and
then you said you need to lose about 20
pounds before you talk to me,
bitch.
And then she turned to her husband and
he turned around and took one look at you
and then started John at me.
You know,
I send me, like I said, like 40
though. She was a big ugly woman.
The thing was, I'm a nice guy, bill
and I, if you just went and said, hey,
can you please put that cigar
out? I always said, oh my
God. Oh my God. I actually,
I snuck this in. I'm, I'm
sorry I didn't sneak it in.
I just forgot it was smoking it. I'm like,
uh, uh, sorry. I'll put it out. You had it
chomped in your mouth,
like you were a general surveying,
conquered land. It was like
I was, it's like I was,
it's like I was a a boxing efficient
auto from the 1920s yeah, it was awesome.
She said
she came out of the gate
and then I was just like,
well that's uncalled for
and that's what I said,
you need to lose about
40 pounds to talk to me.
And then I thought we
were getting kicked out.
But in defense of her though,
like we were,
so you realize how fucking
ridiculous it was. Well first of all,
I fell on that fucking old lady
sort of fell into her. Yes.
And nobody helped me up. I had to push
off her and I felt folded her and half.
And then you got to the seat and
then you had the fucking cigar too.
So already we, we were kind of
a spectacle will be, we have,
we have to have a little bit of empty
to paint the picture of
where we were at though too.
If you ever wish to a college football
game, you see the stands and it's like,
oh my God, there's 100,000 people
wearing red or orange or green.
There was literally 50,000 people wearing
USC colors and just a speck of me and
bill just wearing like neutral.
Nothing yet. But they knew we were
Penn state immediate. Once that lady's
started yelling at me, I was just,
I mean I'm not a USC fan anyways,
so I uh,
but I,
I did like to use because the girls were
so hot and then we met a guy that was
such a fan.
He literally had the uh,
the Trojan outfit and let us put on
the Trojan helmet and at the helm.
That's the beauty of the rose boy. I
think that makes it so much fun as, hey,
it's 80 degrees outside everywhere else
the weather sucks and the teams are so
happy to be there. There's nothing
really on the line. Know what I mean?
Other than you know,
your own bedding purposes.
So everyone's just happy to be
partying is not like in your, in your,
in Pittsburgh and I mean like some of
the best tailgates or green bay or any
other city where rules,
there's tension in the
air and it's 20 degrees.
It's sunny. Everyone's happy to be there
throwing the ball around. It's just,
it's the way it should.
No, you told me something the other
day. I thought it was, cause you know,
you know I'm a big like maniac as far as
going around to different stadiums and
all that.
Like I love all of them and I got a
chance to go to three rivers before they
knocked it down.
I saw and didn't see a Steelers.
I saw a pirates game there when they
honored Willie Stargell literally like two
weeks before he died. Oh, pops. Yes.
And I remember it was a cubs game and I
was sitting down in the right field line
and Sammy Sosa was still playing.
And uh,
but you were saying your dad has had
season tickets since the stadium that they
played in before three rivers,
which was what,
yeah, my dad has had tickets
since Forbes field, Forbes.
And then they went to Pitt stadium
or something for a couple years.
I may have this reverse, but he's had
them like in both of those places.
Then they went to three rivers and my
dad sat exactly on the 54 rows from the
top four rows for us
top. And he sat there and he,
he watched them go from sucking,
I mean you guys were the absolute,
you know,
you're one of the original NFL teams and
you are a doormat for the good, what,
30 40 years.
It's finally come back to where now
we're like better than we suck. Like,
like I was born in 1969 that's
the year they drafted Joe Greene.
I'm 43 for the first 40 years.
They you when like four
games now we finally,
now it's like we'd been better than,
and then we've been, then we sucked.
It was probably when I was
watching the Super Bowl era. Yeah.
Cause when I was like five or six,
my dad would take me to games.
That's when it was all steel workers
went there. And you saw Lambert Ham?
I saw every,
I saw the game where Bradshaw supine
in the ice anyway. Lay off games.
Yeah. I mean the greatest
thing was we were on our,
our side was this dealer that was on
the cover of sports illustrated I think.
Yeah.
Our side was on the Steeler bench.
So the greatest thrill ever is in a is
the Steelers would kick off and then
this, then okay, the other team would
have the ball one, two, three and out.
And then this too,
this come off to our side and then it's
like watching the hall of fame induction
community come off. But I mean that's
the Steelers and the place of that.
There's 11 guys on defense,
like six of them,
maybe a well four for four on defense
and a dude LC Greenwood bell sees not in
yet. He isn't. No,
it's mean Joe Lambert Ham and Mel Blunt
and then it's on the offense as Webster
Swann Stallworth Bradshaw Franco and of
course the emperor Chuck Noll and they
used to be flat.
That's nine.
Nine out of your 22 that's almost
half the guys on your fucking t.
Your of your starting team made
the fucking hall of fame on a foot
ball team.
Well the thing was is in for years they
wouldn't put swan or Stallworth in and
it used to be the old
manager of the punchline.
Jim Cornet knew at like five in the
morning when I'm bottle of crown and you
want to get me to argue for an hour,
just say,
I don't think Lynn Swann
should be in the hall of fame.
Okay.
That, that was always, it's almost
like now I can die in peace.
Like the ranger fan?
No,
like that was the first time we brought
up you and I discussed all Samuelson and
Cam Neil and you were like, yeah, I
mean, yeah, you know I didn't take off.
Was that bad a guy I was
like, you got and you,
what's funny about you is you
just don't ever lose your cool.
You just sit there and just
be like, hey, you know,
which was making me
fucking matter and matter.
I remember we were over fucking Jimmy
doors and Jimmy was killing everybody
playing ping pong. Oh, take an inbetween.
Jimmy was fucking talking shit to him.
Just,
I'm just returning the ball bill.
I'm just returning the ball and he
put all this fucking spin on it.
I get my ass kicked off.
Well, the Democrats must've
been losing that year.
Don't play door when the
Republicans in the White House,
he'll take it out on you.
Exactly. So we got in that epic fight,
but you know, I'm trying to think.
So the first NFL game you went to you,
he brought you there when you were like,
what,
four or five years?
Yes. There was like 10, 10, no women,
no women ever in like just 10 boys
that were lucky enough to have.
I went with my dad and my grandpop
and that was the original curtain,
the original everything.
So wait, um, now can you remember, did you
ever see Oj Simpson? I'm eats a frame. No,
I won't eat some of the guys you saw
because the first game I went to was like,
I'm the 80s. I saw the guys
like Dan Marino. I saw Jim Zorn.
I saw guys from like leftovers 70
guys and all the 80 guys when I,
when I would go to the patriots,
but like 70s guys,
that's when I collected football cards.
That's when they were like gods to me.
So can you remember anybody,
uh, any party you saw Earl?
Oh yeah.
I still saw Earl Campbell to me,
still the greatest running back I've
ever seen because he's the only guy that,
that was when I was a kid.
I was ever afraid of like when I was a
kid that the Steelers were like the globe
trotters.
Like they never law when they lost in
[inaudible] 77 to the orange crush in
Denver in mean Joe,
my favorite Steeler,
obviously he punched the guy in
the stomach and got thrown out.
It ruined Christmas.
Like I still believed in Santa Claus,
but the Steelers losing and
mean joke and tossed out.
It was like Christmas was ruined.
I was such a fucked up. Yeah.
That was the year with Craig Morton
and those guys, right? Ah, yeah.
That's next week. They'd beat the
Raiders. Yes. John Madden, Madden,
and then they got crushed by the cowboys,
which is such a joke. Oh, the team.
The team. That decade where there,
you'd never beat anybody for real.
When it ever really mattered. Dallas,
they wouldn't have a called the team.
They would call Americas two Americas
team. Yeah. That's like, whoa.
Nope. America's team means is
that you have fans in every city.
It doesn't mean that you're the
best team will take that the wrong.
Well for years though, it's like they
always revisions. We know this and that,
you know, and it's like Lynn Swann
always says the game gives you moments.
It's what you do with those moments. Yeah.
And Jackie Smith, you dropped the ball.
You must be the sickest man in America.
Bless his heart.
He's got to be the sickest man in America.
I got to put that clip up
there too. That was like, dude,
I gotta tell you something though.
When I went over to, uh, Stockholm,
Sweden and I was totally jet lagged,
some fucking Steeler fan put all four
of the Steelers Superbowls in their
entirety. I don't know if is still up
on youtube. It was the fucking shit.
And I gotta tell you something
about the Dallas cowboys.
1976 they had you guys beat,
they played Marty Ball and they started
the game with the fucking reverse on the
kickoff to fucking Hollywood Henderson.
He runs up the sideline.
Roy Jarell knocked it, knocked him out
of bounds. He took a need of the ribs.
He missed like three field goals
because of that fucking place.
And Tom Landry got all fucking
conservative and shut his offense down.
No, ensued the kickoff and let
it in the hands of his defense.
I really like,
I mean,
yeah,
like those games really did.
That to me is those who like to be like
the best soup I ever saw us just as far
as two powerhouse teams was
that 79 one the Steelers first,
the cowboys and the to that worst,
uh,
matchups to the worst matchups that were
almost great fucking super bowls was if
the fucking Raiders beat the
stupid orange crush that year.
They were defending super bowl champions
and they would've gone up against the
Dallas cowboys with a
rookie Tony Doerr set.
Now how much fucking better that guy
and said it's stupid. 27 to 10 game.
And then in 85,
when my stupid patriots,
we beat the fucking Miami Dolphins.
The Miami on reason why the bears
didn't go undefeated was because the Dan
Marino beat him on Monday night
football beat the 46 defense.
They were 15 and fucking won.
It would have been the rematch.
Dan Marino defended the
undefeated dolphins that
Superbowl would have happened,
but the stupid fucking patriots.
We went into the orange ball one for the
first time in like 20 years and then we
go in there and just, we got Rick, I think
we've got raped. We literally got raped
and I hate the, I hate the shit on
the Pittsburgh guy who I love, but he,
he should let pate and get the touchdown.
That was a disgrace when he gave the
fridge the ball really going to get there
and to give the fridge the ball
because the fridge is the fridge
cause they got caught.
They got caught up in that soup
as opposed to like Walter Payton
who was playing on like two and 14 teams
or two and 12 teams when he started
because they didn't have
wait when everyone's still
ran the ball like the SCC,
when football was about it was
a man's game. And it's not like
spread everybody out and
get a pass interference. Oh,
can we talk about that? I,
I got to read some advertising
here real quick, but we got to, uh,
we got to talk about that because I know
you are definitely on the same page as
me when it comes to, uh,
this pass interference shit.
So let's get the advertising
out of the way here.
Everybody stamps.com you know the
deal. I read this every week. Ah,
you sick of going to the post office.
Would you like to have the
post office in your house?
If anytime of the year you're going to
sign up for stamps.com this is the time
of the year to do it.
The holidays are coming up.
You literally don't even
have to go to the mall.
You go to amazon.com
you buy all your stuff,
they send it to you and you and a with
stamps.com to give you a little scale you
can print out. Um, he could print out
actual postage for the boxes, stamps,
letters, anything you want to do. You
never have to go to the post office again.
Uh,
what do we got here?
I use stamps.com anytime I'm on the
road and I sent out my DVDs, it's, it's,
it's the greatest thing ever.
I can literally do it at one
in the morning and a right now.
This is a special offer when use my last
name bur bur you got a no risk trial
plus $110 bonus includes a digital
scale and up to $55 in free postage.
They're literally giving you 55 bucks
during the holiday season. So don't wait.
Go to stamps.com right now.
Before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top
of the homepage and type in Berg,
B u r r that stamps.com enter
bur for the love of God.
Do yourself a favor
during the holiday season.
Bring the post office into your home,
go to amazon.com.
Order your presence off of
that and then just get a beer.
Turn on the TV and laugh at humanity
when they do those stupid commercials.
Now they do those stories
on the news about people
getting trampled at a Walmart.
All right, there you go. And
a amazon.com real quickly,
if you guys want to support this podcast,
uh,
just click on the banner ad on
the podcast page on my website.
Anything you buy, amazon.com will
kick me a little bit of a percentage.
And then I kick a percentage
of that over to the, uh,
the wounded warriors project.
So you support this podcast
and you support the troops.
Can you do any better than that?
I don't think so. And once again,
for this holiday season, we have
the wonderful man, great system.
What is the man great us.
They are 100% made in America,
cast iron grilling greats that are
revolutionizing the way people grill.
Basically when you buy a grill, um,
they usually give you, you know,
they give you grilling greats.
They have those little skinny grates on
him and he can't get those great marks
that you see at the steakhouse.
This just basically upgrades your grill.
It's like ripping out the four cylinder
you have in your car and slamming a four
54 in there. That's
basically what it is. Um,
they got that nice thick grilling greats.
Ah,
it's named one of 2012 best grill
accessories by men's health magazine man.
Great. So the perfect gift this
holiday season, click on the man.
Great banner on the podcast page of
billboard Dot Kahn for their 1999 holiday
special 20 bucks. You're renting,
you're out. There you go, dad,
thanks for raising me.
I love your son. Uh,
remember each Monday morning podcast
or to comes with a heavy duty grilling
brush. Good Lord. They actually gave me
one of these. They're, they're awesome.
I swear even when the
apocalypse comes down,
you can melt this thing down and get
your 20 bucks back or at least slam a
Zombie over their head with it.
And they're going to give you a brush.
You're Outta your mind
not to do this again.
That's the man Greg grills enhancement
system order today on the podcast page of
a billboard.com. Okay. All right. Back
with the legendary Joe Barton. Nick,
before we get into this, aside from the
fact you were one of my great friends,
both in and out of this business, uh,
we're here to actually promote Joe Barton.
ACC has a new standup CD,
uh,
hour long a CD that he's going to be
releasing off of all things comedy,
our podcast network called
salute. Um, tell the, uh,
tell the fine folks about it.
Oh, it's a, it's a fun CD recorded it
live at the punch line San Francisco.
It's about 15 minutes
of Barton a classics,
so I can hopefully bury
some of that material.
I've been lagging around and need
some new stuff. Everyone's like,
we've heard that 10 times. It's like,
well, you can keep coming back. Thanks.
But I'm actually buy it on Amazon
and it comes out Tuesday. Help Bill,
help the wounded warriors and don't go
out and traffic. I'll tell you what,
I was just in traffic yesterday
going to a Gig and I was like,
heavenly people figured out Amazon yet.
Like you can just sit at home in your
underwear. It's like they have your, your,
your, they have your mastercard, they have
your sister's address. You just go boom,
boom, boom. And then is it,
that's it. It's amazing. But yeah,
it's a called salute. Like instead
of cheers as Italian scope salute.
And since I'm a big drinker and a lot
of the jokes are about drinking and the
one way or the other,
it's good.
First time I ever heard salute was
that on some live old a Sinatra album.
I heard it,
it was with him with the count Basie
orchestra and they brought out a drink.
He said something and he said,
salude Gin Donna,
I could almost somewhat Italian shit.
I don't know what.
And he laughed or whatever.
And I was just like,
it just seemed like even just
in that moment on the record,
it just seemed like it was
so much better that like, uh,
I dunno, it was just like
if you went and saw frank,
it's not like somebody would take out a
fucking iPhone and then film it and then
if you didn't make it, you could see
a clip of it. It's just like you,
it was such a fucking, everything was just
such a fucking event. That's why like,
you know why I'm sitting here being
a total geek about listening to you,
going to those, you went to NFL
games in the 70 through the 70.
[inaudible] that was like the
golden age of NFL football.
Like the level of quarterbacks
that were in the League,
Stabler Bradshaw Stop Act,
Fran Tarkington.
Uh,
who else?
Some of the biggest ones.
Even the Shitty quarterbacks like
Ken Anderson or Brian's site,
Dan Fouts. Oh, balance is amazing. But
even like, bet, even the backup plan,
pastor Areni,
Dante passionate like junk.
Don Strock construct would be a
playoff quarterback nowadays. Oh,
the way they fucking throw now. Yeah.
They don't even run for four yards.
So those guys will throw for 300 yards
and they're literally like, you know,
42 for 48 and you're like,
oh my God, the accuracy.
It's like now they're throwing
four yard fucking passes,
but allowed to touch a wide
receiver. I mean, think of,
think of what swan would do now.
They couldn't touch them. I mean,
they used to just try to abuse them
every second did the Raiders are like,
you know, hit him in the head
swan play with concussions
every week. It's like, oh,
Mel Blount
rule,
which if you can find this
guy's footage on the on on,
on Youtube of the 1976 soup bowl,
Mel blanches beats the shit out of,
of a Golden Richards,
the whole fucking game called Richard's
almost as crying and the end of it.
And he finally gets so fed
up in the fourth quarter,
he punches Mel blunt back and Mel Blunt,
just,
I forget it was a forearm shiver
or something to his ribs and uh,
Golden's laying on the ground,
almost crying, no flag.
And like the ref saw like the,
the the fucking elbow and stuff.
It was just considered football.
It's a man's game.
They used to be football.
Well he used to be football was like
the 12 like the 10 guys in the bar.
You wouldn't mess with those guys played
football now it's like the 10 guys who
when they were 15 started
taking steroids and like,
and they went through all the best
schools and they got recruited and they,
they they did good in the combine
and Blah Blah Blah. It's like,
cause the guys that played the stuff
here, you don't even see me. I'm
just pitching about the rules.
I still think that those
guys are fucking maniacs man.
I just think like the level of like,
like the money and there's so much at
stake now that you can't just be going
down to the bar, drinking a 12 pack and
then going out and playing your, your,
your high school football
game Friday night. You know,
you really got to take it.
But I think the, I think in the 70s
those, those guys were way more outlaws.
They were the outlaws,
the steel.
I mean like Ernie Holmes shot at a
police helicopter and Rooney brought,
uh, brought a bag of money up to
Cleveland. Like I let them off the hook.
It was like, it was like that, that
that wouldn't happen now. Nowadays,
now that they should have rate [inaudible]
have a Rachel Nichols outside the,
outside the facility that
was wrong with Ernie.
I mean it's like, I just read that big
ESPN book, that like thousand page book.
I'll give it to you and it's all like
behind the scenes it's like, you know, I,
anyway, you painted, I
still hate Suzy Kolber.
She despicably did not kiss.
I would kiss Joe Willie
name if on national TV.
Why would you disparage Joe Willie
name if it's like it's Broadway Joe.
Everybody loves the ladies than
poor man had to go to Rehab.
He was embarrassed like you can
funny was the second he started
talking. You knew he was hammered. Yeah,
he was just, he just had that
fucking, I can't feel my nose glow.
Look on his face, but it's
Joe Namath. He's allowed.
I know Andy was back
there with his friends.
You know what they would do and you know,
they would talk and shit gone.
Come on guys. You know, if
we were healthy, we'd fucking
kill this team. You know,
they were having a good time and all of
a sudden he's talking to some fucking
lady and you know him. He went back to
the 70s back at the playboy mansion.
Well she grabbed them, the show come
over here and she grabbed was like, well,
what's he going to do?
I really want it kiss.
Oh I love do I follow him on Twitter.
He's the best. I love that. I just,
I love Joe. Ease the is Joe name. That's,
that's one thing about Pittsburgh too.
It's like, you know, and then you hate
when I go off of it. But you know Johnny,
you basically invented football.
Oh
No, no, no, no. I just, I give you shit
about the amount of times that you quote.
Like, I don't give a fuck what situation.
We could be in the middle of the desert,
like running out of water and
you just be like, wait, no.
One time Mike Wagner said,
well John Stallworth to quote you on to
Stallworth my fucking super fair man.
I keep my two favorite sports coats or
Lynn Swann. The game gives you moments.
My other one is actually,
I told it to John Madden's face and he
loves to tell that story though. Okay.
So we're out in a business park,
me and my buddy,
the captain out in like an
hour west east of Oakland,
which is basically, if you're not on the
coast and California muzzle be in Texas,
right? This is like, this is actually
where they shoot the sons of anarchy. Uh,
it's just the bad lands of California.
Anyway, we're out there, uh,
probably dropping off a bag of weed to
a friend of mine or something when we
were there around lunchtime and uh,
[inaudible] and we see this massive force
coming out of a diner and John's huge
and he's wearing like a big winter
coat because it gets cold there.
It's like 42 recognize Matt.
And immediately, immediately,
and that it would be like,
Hey John. So I'm going to go
into captain like, hey man,
like kitten. I'm like, look,
look, look, look, look. And
all of a sudden, so anyway,
we started walking and he's like, oh my
God. So then so there we go. Hey Mr. Mad.
Or like, hey, hey, hey, what,
what was, was he freaking
out? He just said guide to be.
Yeah. And I mean the captain at noon
and an office park, it's like a,
it's like an office park. We're getting,
you know what these guys want. Yeah.
So he starts walking really fast.
Like I'm getting away from these gals
trying to go to his car and he's like not
fun with his keys. He's trying to hurt
with his keys. So then I, so then,
so he's totally ignoring us.
Just like maybe these guys will go away.
I'm going to blow my rape whistle,
like get away.
And then I just yell out my
favorite quote actually, which is,
he told his super bowl pregame speech was,
this will be the greatest day
of your life. Only if you win.
So you yelled that I yelled at him,
right. Then he turns around and goes, oh,
hey fellas, how you doing? And
he showed us his Superbowl ring.
We went over and shook his
hand and then an autograph guy.
And until like a year ago, I
wasn't even a picture guy. Right.
But you kind of have to do that now.
So I'm just like, it was just a thrill.
And then literally we got in our car and
just called the first thousand people
we could talk to,
like we just met.
They use that line on myself for like
big sets are big shows or big appearances
or something is like, oh, that's what
you use it to psych yourself. Yeah.
Like this'll be the
greatest day of your life.
Only if you kill, I'll leave you kill.
That's hilarious. Fucking late. Yeah.
I gotta admit like I'm, I'm,
I'm, I'm fighting really
hard not to become the, uh,
the crabby old guy sitting there
talking about how the game used to be.
And I think, you know, I understand
they got to do what they gotta do.
You understand dude, this,
there's future football.
They're going to start with
the Lyman standing up so
they don't slam their heads.
Well, I would, I understand
is that you know what,
you want to live till you're 70
drive a bus. You will, you will,
you want to have baby Mamas and mansions
and drive cars. It'd be on Yo MTV raps,
then you're going to die when
you're 50 and that's the way it is.
If he don't it play in the
CFL, like, I mean that's just,
that's just, that's football.
See that's the thing bill. I,
that's what I grew up on. I grew
up on that. That's, it's just,
I still enjoy it. How I work for
the NFL on Fox, it pays me. I love,
I get to take it. I watch
every game. It's still good.
It's still better than what you,
98% of everything else,
but it's not the third one.
You got five wide receivers in the game.
That's not football. Right. I mean, that's
what I love about me. You know, like,
and all these tricks and like Chuck Noll,
coach Chuck Noll again or for the,
you know, like, Eh, you can, you can
fool some of the people some of the time.
But in the end it comes down to blocking
and tackling. And that's football.
It's about lining up. It's
the Oklahoma drill, you know,
it's bad. Then he would do
you quote Steelers the way like a
Jesus free quotes like scripture?
Well, NFL films to me, it
shocked knowl three 16 to me,
if you grew up in Pittsburgh,
if you're from Pittsburgh in the
70s you can jerk off to super,
but you could jerk off to NFL films.
It's that great.
In San Francisco I was roommates with,
that's the greatest running the soup
bowl. Have you guys won? Four and six.
Four and six. My, my old roommate, one
of my old roommates who is a complete,
uh, art guy and drew and it was sensitive.
He probably wrote poetry, I dunno,
but he hated football,
but he just loved the cinnamon tography.
If NFL films unreal, I mean, that's,
that's how great. It's almost like,
it's almost like regular football. If
you just watch a game, like whatever,
you're going to watch,
whatever today.
It's not as good as watching
the NFL films version.
And if, yeah, NFL films, I always
forget the guy, the voice of God.
Oh John Facenda what? The
autumn wind is a radar. Oh yeah.
You know, it was great. You haven't
heard already a already lang.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Oh, all the
time. I love that. We can dig
in already. That's the best
when he quotes that. Oh
yeah. I want to, I went in,
I did nick and already showed such a,
if you guys aren't listening
to what your autumn audio mind,
if you just want to listen to two people
talking sports and even if you're not
into sports, you can just going to
love listening to it. Cause it's just,
they're just guys, guys. It's fucking
great. And I was sitting out, uh,
waiting to go in and he went into his,
uh,
his impression of that the
autumn wind is a radar.
I can't remember how the fuck it goes.
And he just did the whole poem. And, uh,
he fucking, he's just his delivery because
he's a fucking great actor too, man.
You know,
he's, he's, I mean, I love already
like, I mean, are you laying his,
his football jokes on his,
uh,
Jack and coke special is the greatest
when he wrote, when he rips on the eagles.
Let's just the funniest thing ever,
I made Kevin Shay watch or like tape.
I got to see it.
It's just funny to do a chunk on the
eagles and his standup special. Yeah.
Do my buddy Paul verse. He said
one time he goes, you know,
it's fucking weird is everybody
watches sports for the most part.
We say everybody. I mean the masses
watch real men. Yeah, but, but no
people who you're going to talk to. What
sports? Not that the guy with the, well,
we,
anybody who's into our
shit,
real guys,
guys that you like it if you're wearing
a hat just because you think it's cool.
Uh, and I like, you're
trying to do like, you know,
I'm not going to talk
to you anyway like that.
That's just how I have you stand up.
Like,
I like the guys who I
would be drinking with.
I don't like the guys who I
wouldn't be drinking with.
And that's just the way it is now.
Some guys are just,
do I like hanging out with you?
Cause I need a,
over the years I've gotten
a little more fucking,
a little something of your bite neck stuff
has rubbed off on me cause I'm one of
those fucking, I'm like,
you know, I'm a liberal.
I'm one of those empathetic people. Hey,
let me see the other side of this shit.
Lot of people wouldn't believe that.
Listen to this podcast.
Well that's like you go ahead. I'm
sorry, but I fucking, uh, you know,
at finally I've gotten to the
point of IOL actually now,
like if someone's a fucking
Dick, I'll just be like, all
right, that guy's a dick.
But it's still won't stop me from
trying to understand why they're a dick.
But you're, you're, you're like, you're
just so fucking efficient with that shit.
Like I know a couple of guys like
you in my life where it's just,
you've just real efficient,
you size somebody up.
And the second you think that they're
udicky like fuck that guy and you don't
give a fuck about whoa. Maybe his
dad laughed. You don't give a fuck.
You just like fuck him.
I Dunno. I mean I feel bad for him if
his dad though I feel bad. You know what?
I feel bad for people who lose their
mothers cause and just like the,
not to be tragic,
the Kansas City thing.
That's what's sad is like some weeks
it doesn't have a mother, but uh,
that's a fucking, I didn't want to get
into it cause it's just a sad topic.
But uh, the uh, no, uh, we're
going to talk about now, uh, oh,
sizing people up. Well, I grew up in
bars. My grandfather owned and ran bars.
And so
wait a minute, why the fuck isn't that
the name of your Special Joe Part? Nick?
I grew up in bars. If you
somehow had picture, if you
sitting there on this stool,
I'm sorry,
I'm interrupting you Greg Story.
No, no, no, but that's
so, you know, when you're,
when you're like four years old in
Pittsburgh, in, in the 70s. And bars.
You can size people up.
You understand people's Mojo in
about a second if they're good old.
Were you when they, when he, when you
were getting brought into these bars,
like three, four, five, six
of my grandfather always
have three. He was like norm,
he had a seat in every bar. He
goes and people are like, hey hair.
He can everybody Harry,
his name was Dominic.
He was like the original
guy that would say, dude,
cause he couldn't remember a million
people's names. So he would just go,
hey hair. Hey Harry. And he was totally
bald. That's why it's either games.
He was the genie cause they'd
rub his head for good luck.
They actually rubbed his head before
the immaculate reception and that's,
that's a true story.
So he was always the genie after
that to lift up what's happening?
Say that you were at that game.
I was not at the immaculate
reception game. No, it was not.
My first live game was in
1976 actually it was the,
it was Tampa Bay versus the Steelers.
They won 40 to nothing in a blizzard.
No ones.
Half the quarterback
was Doug Williams there.
I don't remember.
I mean I was like six years old.
It was just a blizzard and
everyone was mad that we went.
That's where my dad would
go to every game to Mac.
Now if it's like raining and in early
October, Eh, it's a little chilly outside.
I'm going to stay home.
But before Kizzy waited 40 years to see a,
but just as you saw I sites were up like
and women to spray like that and an old
girlfriend of mine was like, she was
like, I love Sarah over by there.
Her name was like, Sarah. Sarah is a
great friend of mine. She's my friend.
I'm like, she's like, cause I'm
like, don't, don't deal with her.
We broke up three years later,
this girl comes in because you were so
right about Sarah. She was such a big,
I'm like, I told you I can just, but other
people in Hollywood or they were like,
they're, they're nice to everybody
because they were all only one.
If that guy gets it. Tonight's show
and, and the old way, like really?
Who gives a shit? Like life's
too short. If he's a dick now,
he'll be a dick then I don't really care.
Like I'm friends with who I want
to be friends with, but I'm nice.
I'm pretty much nice to everybody though.
I'm just not their friends.
No,
no I wouldn't.
I would 100% agree with that before we
get too deep into the podcast and we're
going to talk football the whole time.
I mean I guess there's not a lot to talk
about. What about fucking hockey? But uh,
and there was Saturday I been kind of
blaming the owners cause it's been a
lockout and they agreed to a deal but
someone was giving me shit on Twitter
saying, did you see this
shift to players did now you,
are you still on the player's side?
I hope not.
And I haven't really been paying
attention. Last I paid attention.
They were down to like, you know,
players were going from 57% and out of 50
I have three things to say about the
hockey thing. One is why does it just,
I know, let me Save, talk you three
times. But he used to come back again.
What does it Lemahieu Shanahan,
Holly and Steve Eiserman just getting
a room and just say, you know what, we,
you know, this is the fucking game. Here's
the deal. Just play hockey in. That's it.
But the two things I do want to say is
like, you know the other for like a month,
I'm like, it's dark outside. I need to
be watching five games. Like I'm shaking.
Then last week I just was like, you know
what? I'm reading the book. I don't,
I don't miss it. And you know
what? Nhl, if I'm not missing it,
who the hell is going to
be watching like Carolina,
Ottawa on Fox sports south to alternate,
you know you don't want, I've got me
back in the hot. I'm not watching it.
Who's going to,
who's who's coming back?
They're really sad thing is my daughter
for Christmas got this doll that's like
the super doll that you have to
knife to buy $80 outfits for.
So my sister was like,
I'm going to buy her a penguin outfit.
The lady in Pittsburgh is like,
oh,
we're not making penguin outfits
this year because of the strike shit.
I'll get her a Steeler one. So that's
just how far down like everything is.
The hockey just gets lower and
lower now because of the stress.
Stupid. And they made more money
than they ever made. They get the,
they have the winter classic dude,
it's an NHL hockey has not been
on network television on NBC,
CBS or ABC has not been on it
the entire time I've watched it.
It was on in the 70s.
The worst time they could've made the
deal when it was just absolutely a fucking
bar room brawl every, um, every game you
don't something, this is the one thing,
the only thing I like it just two things
I like about the Montreal Canadians
being a Bruins fan.
One was when they booed Patrick
Wa and he said, fuck you guys,
I'm never playing here again,
cause that really fucked that franchise.
And then he goes to when
to with the avalanche,
which were the Nordiques
so that could piss off
the, uh, the, the Ray Borg Cup. Yeah.
Yeah. It was awful. We, we, what
do you think about that though? Um,
I actually,
I don't have a problem with it because let
me get you the other thing. Okay. Yeah.
The thing about that I
loved was when fucking, uh,
Larry Robinson beat the shit out of
Dave Schultz to start the Canadians run
where he was just standing up to
him was like, all right buddy,
you want to play this fucking
game? No, that's, I mean,
you, you, you, you know my,
I love that. You know, my hatred for
the flyers. Oh, it's, it's legendary.
Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh and Philly. They,
they're in the same state. They are.
That's Hatfield and McCoys.
That's the only rivalry Pittsburgh
has because people like when the bed,
the browns, it's like, Oh, you're
not Robert with your doormat.
The ravens there like new
and who, who cares? I mean,
the flyers and the penguins.
We've, we used to be, oh,
for Nixon we were like, oh,
for Watergate in the spectrum until
[inaudible] 88. I mean, it's just, I mean,
that's it. And that's fans
and their fans hated Lemieux,
but then they actually cheered
Lemahieu when it came back for cancer.
They hate Crosby.
Lot of fancy Crosby,
but they hate Crosby and he
cries be just sticks it to them.
That's just the best people have to
have a hateable face. Crosby has,
he has sort of a Danny Ainge pouty
face. That's that. Unless he's your guy,
you're not going to like it. He's, he's
the best. So it's like Lebron people just,
there's haters. No,
they're already, exactly,
they're already going to fucking
hate him. But he, he's so much east,
so much easier to hate because
there's something about his face.
It'd be like Eli Manning would
be so much more respected.
You'd be at least considered
at Aaron Rodgers level,
which I think he finally has after that
second one. But like, it was, his face is,
he just doesn't look like, you know,
he doesn't have like that fucking, uh,
everything's gonna be okay.
I'm banging the fucking captain
of the cheerleaders fucking, uh,
in high school, maybe hooked
up with a teacher, just said,
fucking get out of that fucking
five o'clock, shadow the gunslinger.
He doesn't have that. Look. Luck
has that look luck. Luck is a myth.
I love the fact that, you know,
something I realized, I, uh,
cause the fact that actually like Andrew
Luck and actually liked the cults.
Now I actually realized that I never
really even hated Peyton manning.
I just hated the Tom Brady that
wasn't getting the respect.
Cause now like I'm watching,
I'm watching Peyton manning with
the Broncos and I'm rooting for him.
And I actually think the
Patriots, dude, I, man,
I don't even know if we beat the
dolphins at this point. It was close.
But like I say, we already beat
Broncos this year. We got a 50,
50 chance of, of, um,
of, of losing fucking,
uh, we play them in the
playoffs because he, he's,
he's so jelled with that
team now. Oh, they're good.
The Broncos on anybody, but I mean,
anybody be Houston. Give me a break.
I'm saying Houston,
Houston.
I mean like gimme your old school
hatred of the Oilers. Oilers,
not marijuana.
I used to have this shirt that had the
little iron on from the mall that had a
bum Phillips beating on the
door that said Super Bowl
and Jack Lambert's in front of it.
Just holding it back like,
like a bomb knocking on this door. They
can't, they won't let him in. Awe Dude,
if you still had that,
that's fucking legend.
The sweat rings of visa right through.
But uh, no, I mean I just used it.
Certainly. I mean like, I mean this dude,
these are down here. But I mean like I,
the thing about the AFC to me is like,
you always either go through Pittsburgh
or you gotta go through the Baltimore
Cause unless you,
unless you can look James Harrison and
Polamalu in the face and say we're going
to cover both.
Or you can look uncle ray in the face.
Then you haven't really beaten,
you haven't played man football and
Houston Schwab, really. Schwab, Schwab.
You think boot ballot check is Gail
that Schwab go to the Super Bowl,
the patriots. So we we put up Gadi numb.
I feel like we're the patriots right now.
We're like how the colts were back
in the day when, when pate manning,
they would go 13 and three or 12 and
four and then losing the first round.
We don't lose in the first round,
but like,
like we're not going to play the bills.
We're not going to play
the jets in January.
So who gives a fuck that we
put up 50 fucking points.
It inflates your stats and it
makes everybody think that yeah,
this juggernaut and the best thing our
secondary has going for it is our running
game because it can chew up the clock
and keeps them off the field as long as
possible because dude,
we fucking let up like 300 yards
to that bomb and fucking Buffalo,
whatever the fuck his name is. Patrick.
Yeah, he's out there like he's fucking
his contract. His horse, his
country is horrible. His country,
he's like 10 years for all this money.
He's like just not even my strength and
their contract with Ryan for his back
deck
is that Ray Borg thing. Where you going
to ask me like how I felt about it?
Like you got to understand that that
the Bruins fan base was so loyal.
It didn't matter that
we weren't winning cups.
They were still going to
sell it out and send it in.
Those guys would just cheap fucks and
they would never just make that extra move
to get us over the top.
And Ray stayed with us dude from 1979
to June of 2000 and he went through,
I don't know how many
rebuildings especially in the
90s when we really started
falling off. He went through he
fuck, what was he supposed to do?
He had one more year left.
There was no fucking way we were going to
win it and that was they denim a solid.
They traded them to a contender and
they still had to go out and win it.
The only thing I didn't like, and I
know his heart was in the right place,
but when he finally won the cup,
he brought the cup back to Boston as
like a show of, hey man, you know,
here's the Stanley Cup.
And it's just like,
I know his heart was in the right place,
but it was brutal. It's like, yeah,
here's this thing you have in fucking one
in 30 28 years at that point you're 28
years. But um, but so I
don't have, I don't know.
It was cool. We went to Denver
too, so it's like a new city.
It wasn't like he went to like,
oh,
I would say the flyers and fan he went
to like the rangers or someone that's
just like, oh look, you've hated him
for 30 years now here it's like, yeah,
I don't forget,
don't get mad at a laundry.
Didn't even have a team like Ray Allen
going to Miami. It doesn't bug me.
Like people actually get like pissed.
Like he was one of our guys.
It's like he wasn't, he was, he was a
free agent. He's, he's Jim Calhoun's guy.
I don't, I don't, you know
who my way more than me.
I mean hoop is a hoop is and it's so
sad. Talking about the demise, the NFL,
the biggest demise. Demise of
the big east. Why now? Huh?
Big He spec college basketball. We
was supposed to talk about that. Oh,
there's gonna be worth it. Yeah.
Oh, we still can't. It's the gray.
I used to watch that all the time. Fucking
Georgetown. Chris Mullin. Pete. I mean,
whenever people say they were
the Washington, I read that book.
Oh you know Nascar and
no,
he know what you know what invented ESPN
was the big east because then because
he had no stupid
programming in the African,
you didn't have like a Michelle
Beale on in the afternoon talking.
Let's see what Collin Coward things like
who gives a shit what that guy thinks
they, they just ran big east basketball
games again in the afternoon.
So what we need when you're out
all night in high school playing,
then you just stay home from school
the next day and watch the big east all
afternoon.
My Grandmother,
let me stay home from school at the
time I just watched the big east.
It was the best used to go to New York
too. And you will go to New York City,
the tournament's. Yeah, absolutely.
So you saw Ewing and I saw,
I saw two years in a row,
I saw the Patrick Ewing the year that
they won the big east championship.
We actually saw them in Laguardia,
their whole team.
And my dad's still pissed this day cause
I became a Knicks fan because I love
Pat Ewing didn't give me an autograph.
My Dad wanted to sucker punch him.
He didn't give you an autograph
though, the whole team. So Bill Martin,
who was the power forward back
then gave me an autograph.
But these guys were huge and Thompson was
the biggest unwell. And Thompson goes,
who wants lunch hoards?
Remember horns Broadnax he the stack a
hundred dollar bills like John Goddy.
He's ripping them off, give him
the, giving them the players. Jesus.
And then two seconds later, Andre the
giant walk past and I swear to God,
I'm almost ready to call bullshit on that
store size. What I can call my dad's,
except he's at, he's like,
you know, panicking over the
coals over the Baltimore.
I said colts. That's how old
school I am. I getting ravens.
That's fucking awesome.
I,
you know he's already happy interrupted
eight months ago. The work already.
What happened to a bottle of a J and
B or something? Whenever he's 18,
he my dad like he likes to mix it up.
I respect that. He's like, you know,
he changed it up some days but he
married some these, they never know.
He's ain't gon go back to Andre. Oh always
interrupt your great stories. So, so, uh,
so literally, uh, just right after that
we lock up Andre the giant walks bet.
Honestly, John Thompson was
bigger shoulder wise than him,
but he walked by just how big he was.
He actually duct and assign
in Laguardia Airport signs.
Like she can see from six 10? No,
he's like seven, four. Who is Andrea?
The giant. I'm sorry, I thought you were
talking about Oh John Tops. Like, so yeah,
he's backed up bill. Okay. All right.
That's how he knows how to play
center cause he worked with giant,
they had a thing in sports
illustrated one time and they would,
they would just uh, they
talked about, you know, all the
shit he would do as a joke.
Like he would like somebody's car.
He would like turn it around and face
it and make it facing the other way.
And they showed him like one
night he allegedly drunk,
drank like a hundred beers and they showed
him when he holds a 12 ounce beer can
in his hand. I liked the top of
the can is flush with like if you,
how old your hand sideways,
the way you would hold a bear,
like from the top of his hand to the
bottom of his hand is the whole beer.
He could fit a 12 ounce can
and there it literally looked,
it wasn't even like a pony. It looked
like half a pony shot. So it's just like,
yeah, this is like him
doing like three swallows.
He'd be done with it and
still raise a hundred beers.
It's still fucking respectful. But, uh,
he's one of the greatest biographies
on a and e ever cause right.
What he knew was gonna die
at like four months left.
He just went back to his hometown and
just played cards with all of his friends
until he died. Just like just bought like
a cabin. Just like, yeah, come on over.
I got a kegger playing cars I
think is fucking on, you know,
so you know how bad I
hope I go out like that.
Cause you know this something to be said
about dying peacefully, like in your,
in your sleep and not realizing it.
But there's also, there is something,
if you've lived long enough and you've
done, you know, he had the kids,
you get you, you went after your
dream, he did all that stuff.
Bendis whatever did did
shit you wanted to do and
was the most recognizable human being
on the face of the earth. That's all.
That's the only thing that Andre
accomplished at his Wikipedia page.
It was unreal. Yeah, he was,
he was like bigger than Jordan,
like literally bigger than I,
they still have those fucking
stickers that obey thing.
That's his face that they
have all the way around that.
But I would love to go out
like that and just be like,
when you're like fucking 85
and they just go, all right,
you have three months to
live. And you're like, cool.
And enough of your friends a
left. That's the one thing, dude,
if you live too long, you fucking
outlive all your friends. I just said,
my grandmother, God
bless her, she just, uh,
she passed away just
shy of 105th birthday.
She was on her third set of front,
like generation. Like she outlived,
I mean, it's just unbelievable. I
mean, uh, you know, she played bridge,
kept her mind sharp and she had
to just keep getting new friends.
She outlived my grandfather
by fucking 25 years,
25 fucking, they were married for
62 years. Mean granted they get,
they eloped when they
were like, you know, six,
it's 17 like way back in the
day when you could back then
you weren't,
you weren't like,
I think we're going to move in together
for a while and then see how it goes.
We're gonna get, we're gonna get the dog
and if we can do that then yeah, yeah,
yeah. No, they to do anything.
You better be married. Lead.
Exactly. That was exactly his yesterday.
They eloped. But yeah, so they made,
cause I remember going to their 60th
anniversary and that was like in the
fucking eighties,
dude.
That was like 84 85 my grandfather passed
in [inaudible] 87 and then she lived
all the way to 2012 but that's the
thing there is you, you actually,
you end up like you, you
outlived everybody. Somebody
was telling me last night,
I'm working with Todd Rex, who I
got to get on this podcast. Todd,
we're at t rex is one of the
funniest motherfuckers he ever, oh,
that's that story I told on this podcast.
You know, he says, Hey, what do you say?
It's him. You know, he
says the Shit we, uh,
we got pulled over cause his windows
were too tinted or something.
This guy pulls us over. We're on the
101. The Guy, you know, the guys talking,
a little cops talking on the
loudspeaker. He goes, you know, uh,
get off at the next exit. And that got us
onto the one 10. Now we're on, we're on,
we're on our way to the break improv.
It's now on the one 10.
We had to drive that quarter of a
mile to get to the next fucking ice.
When we get off, we literally like five
miles away from where the fuck we were.
We pull off and for some reason he
has a stop under the fucking overpass.
Right? So I don't know what
we're underneath the thing.
And Todd's been silly all week. Never seen
any anchor. Now first time seeing him,
like he's looking angry,
right?
And this baby face cop comes walking up
and he didn't, Todd doesn't give a fuck.
Puts the window down as the
cop comes walking up, licensed,
had ready. Good. Yeah.
What do you say,
dude?
We just start fucking bursting
out laughing and the cop
stood there and he kind
of looked her,
I guess he watched comedy central.
So you recognize someone in the car
and then he recognized Todd and then he
literally got on his fucking heels
like, Oh shit, you guys are comics.
And we just started laughing and
he actually let us go. You know,
I don't want to tell too much more
because he end up being like a really good
shit about it and I don't get the
guy in trouble. And uh, you know, uh,
but whatever.
Well he didn't find the heroin in
the truck is what you're saying.
Maybe a few weeks later somebody you know,
had a fucking moving violation and maybe
he did something to make it go away.
He was a good shit.
Oh, right on. Oh, there's
nothing like good cops.
Well thank God he was a good guy because
even if the guy was like a fucking old
school,
I'm going to shoot you and plan a gun
on you taught that t rex still would've
said the same shit.
Well
those say some. That's the problem
in Los Angeles on the west coast.
San Francisco has got some old school
city cops and they're cool and they let me
off the hook on a couple of
Duis. But I mean like, oh,
Pittsburgh cops were the best for
Duis. Just like, yeah, go home.
Like y'all right, good. Get outta here.
I mean, there's not black or white,
old school. City cops are the
best, cause they don't give a shit.
They've dealt with everything.
So he's like the young,
like straight out of the academy.
We were in Desert Storm Republican
kids or need or collar or, or, or, or,
or the broads. They're the worst
cops. But the old school man,
they don't give a shit.
They're over. I mean, I mean,
the worst was the one time I just,
we just did the party in her
ass off in New York City.
I'm coming back out in New York. I'm
like interstate 80 or two 80, whatever,
going through jersey, they get to
Pennsylvania. And um, you know,
when you're just in that morning,
the sun comes up and you're still
just gagged and just like drunk.
And I was like 10 lanes of traffic.
I didn't know I was
actually in the 11th lane
in the middle like I had, no, I wasn't
paying. I didn't know. And I'm like,
why is this cop just shitting?
It stopped in the middle of the freeway
here it was the center lane. What we win,
like the breakdown lane, like I
was in the middle, like whatever.
It's like right next to the wall
being like the mediums? Yeah,
the median strip lane. Yeah, the that
lane. It's not grass. It is pain but no,
it's paved. Yeah. I'm thinking like
what's a cop doing sitting there.
So then I pull over and I'm like,
hi,
swerve out of the way is he drived Uber
pulls you over for pulls me over and at
the time my card,
my window didn't work so I had so like
I went to open the door to get the,
if I kicked it in theirs there was like,
I think when they trade the car in
the boot print of the New Jersey state
trooper, we still in the car here.
It was his first Monday back.
He'd been hit by a drunk driver.
He was out eight months. Oh No.
But it was so early in the morning
on a Monday morning and rush hour.
He just couldn't believe
I was drunk. Yeah. He,
he's just like, what's wrong with you?
Oh my God, you need to see as a, as a,
you know, strung out. And he's like,
or whatever. I said, he's like, oh,
you need to know.
I luckily had the Pennsylvania,
nothing like out of state plates.
Like I'm the asshole.
They don't have this stuff in our state.
I didn't know you couldn't drive on
the fucking medium strip. Pennsylvania
legal really got three lanes. You're like
a big city officer. I don't really know.
But that's,
that's why I don't drink and drive ever
anymore because I've been pulled up.
I got literally got off.
That's why not. Cause you don't want to
kill somebody because you don't want to.
Well, I mean, I don't, I
don't want to waste 10 grand.
That should be the thing. How much
of that last shot cost me 10 grand?
I mean, obviously I don't
want to hurt anybody, but, uh,
for that shit and 89, December of
89 it was, it was a duty as a layup.
It was a layup. I was so fucking
drunk. I couldn't even get my shit.
I wasn't even nervous. That's how drunk
I was. I was like, ah, you got me.
But that's, that's just stumbled
through the, I blew a one nine mm.
That's the problem. They had the two
problem nowadays though, it's like, yeah,
you know, if you're that
fucked up. And like I said,
I was like five or six times out of my
mind and then each time I left the hook,
that's why I was like, you know
what? That's it. I can't do it.
Right, right. Did you ever
get busted for it or no?
No. I was always, I always like knew
the cop or that my boss knew the cop.
It was always in Pittsburgh.
In Pittsburgh,
it was five times legitimately
like just off the hook. Like,
ah, Yay. I know you are blah, blah, blah
friends, friends. You
know. One time I was,
I was coming home from a Christmas party.
I was working in this warehouse.
We were under age and me and this other
guy, sarge was his nickname. We got,
we got absolutely fucking hammered and
we were driving his mother's like Pontiac
grand am you remember
those things in the 80s.
So what they look like with that
plastic shit, they're like side,
they were like this Chevy celebrity.
Yeah. Except for pawn. Yeah. By Pontiac.
Exactly. Yeah. So we were driving right
through the center of town and uh,
there was this jeep sitting at the red,
old schooled CJ seven when they made him
like out of fucking steel and the guys
stopped at the red light. I got
a beer between my legs, you know,
drinking and the other guy's fucking,
he's, we're hammered. We both see it,
we see it.
He starts to slow down.
He just didn't press the brakes hard
enough when we just sorta, yeah.
Oh Bam. Slam into it. Right.
And this shit at all.
Like the brand new safety,
it's to the edge and fucking drops
down under the fucking there.
Just the whole thing. Just crumpled
up. I've slammed my head off the visor.
Beer just goes all over me
covered in fucking beer.
We're right in the center of town in my
hometown. Fucking cops have it and like,
and, and it was so funny, the whole,
the fucking grand am was totaled.
There was like just a
scratch on the back bumper.
The CJ seven like I don't even think
the fucking guy that keep barely noticed
who was sitting in the GP got out.
Right.
Cops are there and like
fucking two seconds they show.
I'm literally covered in beer and the
cop, you know, standing there, he goes,
you guys been drinking like, Naw, Naw,
I'm a just get it all right there.
Fucking beer shower. So we stand
down. He goes, yeah. He goes,
his car resale called get out
of the car. We're like, fine.
So I'm standing there on the sidewalk,
on the other side of the jeep with a
stooge sarge covered in, fuck, I'm, I'm,
I'm so drenched in beer.
I'm actually cold.
It's like fucking like 30 degrees out
and I'm soaking wet and I'm sitting there
like an I already been through.
I know I hadn't been through my shit yet.
I ain't got arrested yet.
So for drinking and driving,
so I'm sitting there talking to sergeant,
I'm just going to give a fuck
they arrest y'all go to Cornell.
I under oath that don't give a fuck. I'll
say weren't drinking. I got you back.
I'm fucking lifeway.
He said all this shit.
And then when I was done I turned and
faced the street and there was a cop
sitting in the cruiser staring right at
me when I thought heard the whole thing.
To this day, I can't believe we, he
didn't get fucking arrested. Yeah,
that he didn't get fucking, I don't know
what happened. I have no fucking idea.
I had the empty beer, there was beer
all over the windshield, all over me.
Somehow we got out of it. He
didn't get, he didn't get busted.
I remember my dad picked me up and at
that point I was smart enough to shut the
fuck up and he picked me up. Dude. I
mean, I am like swaying in the wind,
the car smashed and I get in the car just
covered in beer and he's just like a I
doing you all right. I was just
like, yeah, yeah, I'm good. I'm good.
I didn't say shit.
I think he wasn't mad at me cause I
wasn't driving and we just fucking drove
home. But yeah, but that was the 80s
everybody that that's what happen.
They let you go are so cool about that
stuff in general. It's like, oh it was,
it wasn't my car. It wasn't like,
yeah, shit happens. Like who?
Like what dad hasn't been the passenger
in a drunk driving incident? No, my dad,
my dad was in the navy and
he was in a Frat, so he has,
and he did that shit in the 60s so I
remember when I finally got busted for
drinking and driving, uh,
my dad was totally cool.
My mother was upset and that, that
was their dynamic, like little shit.
My Dad flipped out like Christ
fucking clean up your room,
but big shit. You got arrested for
drinking and driving. He was just like,
you all right. All right, cool.
We'll fucking blah, blah, blah.
My mother was the opposite. She let the
little shit go and then the big stuff,
I just remember, dude, I, I,
my dad woke me up like they bailed
me out of fucking jail and uh,
take, I'm still fucking hammered.
They fucking takes me home.
By the time I get home,
it's like fucking maybe like four
in the morning I go to sleep.
My Dad wakes me up at seven
in the morning. All right,
three fucking hours later.
I'm like, still just ham. I'm still going
up. That's how drunk I was. And he goes,
I think should go downstairs and uh,
tell your mother what you did.
You know that old school shit.
So I fucking stumbled downstairs.
Mother already knows. Hammered
out of my mind. I'm like,
should I get a drive? And she had
this fucking look of pain on her face.
It was brutal.
It was fucking brutal.
Then I went back upstairs and I
probably slept til like two and a,
I only got 45 days.
45 days is all you got back then.
Now it's like fucking 90 days or like six
months. We're not making light of this,
by the way. People, we realize
this is a serious crime, but
oh yeah, please take a cab. I mean,
that's what gets me about the,
when these athletes, like there's nothing
I love better than being driven around.
I mean like me and now magical actually
have a thing like we wouldn't have,
we have a race in our careers and
obviously he's way ahead of the first one.
Do a drive going on the daily show and
one of the founders of this company,
the podcast company, the record company
that the CD salute is coming out on.
Please, please. By the way,
everybody go on Amazon down.
Can they download it anywhere?
Yeah, they can download it from Amazon.
I believe in buy it from Amazon.
It's on everything. But iTunes,
literally everything. But I think, yeah,
and when Joe says,
these are his classic jokes,
like the first time I worked with you
met you was in the punchline in San
Francisco. Molly had booked
you and she goes, you're gonna.
I think you're going to like this guy to
do it within five minutes. I was like,
not only do I love his bitch,
I fucking love this guy.
You would like every one IA jokes,
especially in San Francisco,
how liberal it is would
totally be offensive and
you'd feel the crowd pull back
and then you would just keep tagging the
punchline with even more offensive shit
and they just had to just give in. Like
this guy just doesn't give a fuck. It was,
I just remember that when you did about
the chicks sucking Dick for something.
What the hell was that when you would
run from the side of the stage going, oh,
oh, that's sucking a dick. The
difference between La and San Francisco.
That's my differences.
It was
so loud and it was so fucking graphic
and everybody was just like pulling back
and you just kept doing it.
Running from side to side miming sucking
a dick to get your fucking career going
and it was just, it was so fucking over
the top. It was, it was awesome, man.
It was awesome.
So I really hope that people are going
to do the right thing and you know,
something like, and, and speaking of
doing the right thing, dude, uh, we, uh,
me and some of my friends,
we put together, uh, a
benefit for the lake. Great.
Patrice O'Neal in New York City
tickets went on sale on a Thursday.
And I know a lot of my podcast listeners
are going to give me shit for not
announcing it on Monday, but there's
a reason why I wait until Thursday.
Thursday was the one year
anniversary of Patrice is death.
And I just feel like the stuff
that opie and Anthony did for him,
like they just had like this just hours
and hours of stuff of Patrice and this
show is ridiculously amazing.
Was that
the benefits show? Oh,
the shell that we got to,
we're doing that show could be held in
the astrodome. Yeah. Is that good? I mean,
it's really,
so it's sold out. It's
sold out in 24 hours. And,
um,
you know,
I was able to tell Patrice has mom and
it's the happiest I've heard of since all
this whole fucking awful scenario started.
So I want to thank everybody,
Ona fans and everybody who saw it on
Twitter who went and bought tickets. Uh,
you really fucking did a great thing by
buying those tickets and it's going to
be a fucking awesome
show. So, um, anyways, um,
I don't know where the fuck to go
with that. So do another solid here.
I know I didn't bring it up
about the own Neil tickets.
So if you want to fucking
do with solid Joey,
be salute from the all
things comedy network. Do.
We're an hour and seven.
This has been fucking effortless.
You've been a great fucking
yes. Thank you so much for me. Like hours.
I forgot I was holding
the microphone actually.
It's like we're so used to a bullshitting.
Well, let's talk fucking Rosebell. Ah,
well, uh, what do you think Stanford,
Wisconsin. I was working with
Nate Kraig last night. Uh,
one of the guys you played hockey
with these openings out there. He was,
he was saying Wisconsin
stinks. He's like, we stink.
Oh one like a thousand. I mean, you
know, honestly about the Rose Bowl,
the least the most,
the thing I hate,
the thing I liked the least about
the rose bowls, the game, I actually,
it's like a drag. Oh, there's
going to be a game. Oh, you know,
I mean it's like he's so much fun in the
parking lot. I'm telling you, it's the,
by the way,
people is a fucking golf course.
You owe it to yourself at
some point in your life.
If you've ever wanted
to go to the Rose Bowl,
I'm telling you the tailgate
is better and do it up.
Bring somebody who knows how to cook,
bring a bunch of booze and you just
sitting there. It, dude, it's, it's,
it's the greatest fucking
way ever to start the year.
All those years of doing stand up and
going on stage where they gave the
noisemakers out to the crowd before you
go up and absolute hell and then like
the fucking clock strikes, whatever.
And you got to do the countdown. Okay,
you fucking an animal's ten nine all
those years of doing that shit and just,
I don't even know how the fuck we ended
up talking about it. We just bought it.
That's the greatest.
We went to the,
we went to that amazing Tennessee Ucla
game when Tennessee was up like 20 to
nothing, and we're like, we could leave
at halftime. This game's over. We stayed,
Ucla made the comeback and we were like,
we gotta go to the Rose Bowl.
This place is amazing.
Right.
And then we had the ultimate
experience of the first year.
Second year we brought along Jason.
Jason had showed up and if
you don't know Jason Law had,
unfortunately he's not the trademark
batting stance guy he got, he's like,
it's like someone stole the formula
and then he got screwed out of it.
But law head can do the big
red machine batting stances.
Reggie Jackson,
he won't let me post the Reggie Jazz.
He said he was out of shape
when he did it. Oh he it.
His debt. Reggie Jackson thing. He
does this Reggie Jackson. He goes,
when do you want to see them?
Do you want to see him when he's younger
or when he's older? He does the hall.
He does the home run. He hit in
the fucking all star game through.
He stands up there. Right. I'm standing
up now for people listening here.
Obviously he fucking,
when he does that thing where he brings
the bat up and then fucking adjust the
glasses through the second he did
that I was like, it's fucking Reggie.
The fact that you can do
the whole big red machine,
but to me my favorite is Pete Rose's. Uh,
when he, when he beat ty Cobb, he does,
he does him rounding
first base, the clap, the,
the handshake. It's anyway, he showed all
the way to crying on his son shoulders.
Yes he does. He does the whole
awkwardness at first base.
And how great is it when he does like,
he does like Pete Rose's stance stay where
he's sitting there crouching down and
he literally does. What about
when he did? He did Willie McGee,
he had his dying laughing, do a Willie
McGee and when he does the swing,
we're on the fucking ground laughing
and then is classic quote. He goes,
he loved the high fast ball,
didn't it? I don't know Jake diddy,
it looked just like him.
So, so he joined the crew.
Then we have Andrew during the Q does.
Yeah.
This is the fifth year universe
analysts. This is it. Yeah. Universally.
So let's get plenty of thank you.
Think Stanford's is going to
come in and pound them. Uh,
I think Sanford has a better team,
but you never know if they knew.
They take like a month off.
It's like,
it's like when you don't go on stage
for a month, you never really know.
Even though you know your jokes,
you don't really,
Sanford Sanford should burn those
uniforms they played in last week.
That flat black helmet. That was
just fucking, oh, the black on black.
Was that designed by Jay z?
It was terrible.
[inaudible] y'all because of Jay z did it.
It would have been the shit.
If you've seen the fucking
bar place center, you know,
knowing that this is a Celtics fan,
we've got 17 fucking banners.
We just went down to home depot,
bought a bunch of cinder blocks and built
a fucking square dude Barclay Center.
The hardwood floor is supposed to
be like a brownstone in Brooklyn.
If you have a nice one in you redo
it right. And the luxury boxes,
I like mini fucking brown spots. I, I'm,
I'm just kinda night into the cities
with two teams. It just kind of like,
you know what? Move somewhere else. Give,
give somebody a team how you
can be a lifelong knick fan.
Go through coming this close to win in
the championship with Pat Riley and the
finger.