Hey, what's going on? It's
Bill Burr, all la Mi Amigos.
Dawn that as own panel.
Della Mae Sai. Sorry,
I'm back into the fucking Rosetta stone
Spanish. What's going on is bill burr.
It's the Monday morning
podcast for a September dose.
Don't say oh no.
Set All.
I've been listening to a oh by the way,
before I get before he,
before he could go on.
Today's show is brought
to you by audible.com/bill
don't I'm supposed to say no.
Today's show is brought to you by audible.
Please visit audible.com/bill for
your free audio book download.
All right.
Would you like to go to a party with an
ascot on and sound like you're well read?
Even if you don't read this reading,
make you sleepy,
but for some reason somebody else's voices
in your head reading a book makes you
feel like you're being held well.
I have the solution for you.
Go to audible.com/bill and get
your free audio download book.
When you listen to Spanish radio,
right whenever you call it, Latino,
Puerto Rican, whatever. He's
supposed to a mere Amira.
Whenever the fuck you supposed to say,
you know,
you're just trying to pick up words,
right?
So all I do now is I just listened to the,
uh,
you know, am radio of course, you know,
white people are on or on FM Latinos and
like fucking psycho political people in
sports are all on am radio,
religious people.
You know what I mean?
Like if you're just on FM radio and
you're going up and down the dial and
whatever, like you're living in
a completely different universe.
If you switch over to am radio,
you know, it's, it's a interrupt. You,
you can literally listen to like some
gaming at Laska and Alaska. You can,
next channel is somebody
talking about Jesus.
And Jesus said to the
Episcopalians in John 3.6,
you know, then, um, gay
people are all going to hell.
Whatever the fuck they're talking about,
right?
And then you get over to the Spanish
station and you try to fucking listen.
He's supposed to immerse
yourself in the language and uh,
it's starting to happen.
I can actually hear different words.
I don't know what the fuck they mean,
but it's slowly but surely happening.
And I don't know what the fuck they're
talking about unless it's like a word,
like that's just totally like the
English word with like an o at the end.
Mouille important though.
And you're like very important
but always in the end, always in the
end when they give out the phone number,
I know what they're saying. Oh No. All
Chels Santo, Santo Quatro, Cinco, quatro.
Today's Uno.
Um,
anyways, and they see, they
see pedal pedal I water.
That's now let's get down to brass tacks.
This is the Monday morning podcast,
Mi Amigos and Mi Amigos.
Um,
I got a lot of shit going on,
you know, you know, it's weird.
The last few weeks when I do the podcast,
I do it downstairs.
My fucking dog looks like it got
shot with a tranquilizer gun.
Okay.
Just fucking lays here
mocking. You know, I literally,
I feel like I'm bombing because in reality
the dog is my only audience and I'm
going to take a fucking picture
of a right now. You know what,
and we're going to upload it.
I've never shown you guys a picture.
You know what's great about this?
You guys have never seen what my dog
looks like and now I'm going to send you a
picture and all the dog
people like, oh my God. Yeah,
he's finally got it to it.
Where's the thing?
You're not going to see her face.
It's going to be like people magazine
when they used to try to get a picture of
it
and these to try to get a picture
of like Paul Stanley from kiss,
you know that yet another
horrific group from Detroit.
What is wrong with white
music from Detroit?
They got the black shit down so well,
Motown,
all those guys right through Marvin Gaye,
who I guess was a Motown artists.
MMM.
But Jesus Christ, they're white
music other than M and M. Woo.
Yeah.
That is a fucking mess out there.
Huh? The Bay city royal up rollers.
Remember them
is this thing about Saturday nights,
a little coke spoons hanging around,
twist it up in the chest.
Hair was not that Gig.
MMM.
Who else? Ted Nugent. Gay. HBH. Viva.
I throw him on the fucking trash heap.
Um,
kiss.
Who else is from there?
Kid Rock.
You know,
you should melt all of those people down
and then fucking reform them into maybe
like a coffee house music. You know, Bill,
you've got a lot of fucking nerve man.
How many fucking albums you sold? Oh,
go fuck yourself.
I got a God damn hour to fill here.
Okay,
kid rock always walk around with no
shirt on and a Budweiser. We get it.
You're down to earth. Oh,
was there a Paparazzi here?
Who as I stepped out of
my limo with my bud tall.
Did you publicists fucking open that
for you? There you go. Bill Trash.
Somebody who was relevant in 99. All
right. Have you ever been relevant bill?
See that?
That's,
that's why I like to think that I'm even
handed because as I trash other people,
I also trash myself.
Don't die. Maybe not. Um,
anyways, I'll shut off the
fucking goddamn camera. You know,
I keep playing on my iPhone.
I keep playing ice rage.
Do you guys play that hockey game?
I play at the highest level and
I had this motherfucker be like,
I just refuse to play any other level at
this point other than the hardest level
and a at this point I
am one and about 260.
That's my record. And the only
time I won the first time okay.
Was Cause I did this bitch move where I
got two goals right in the beginning and
then one another face off and then just
fucking skated with the puck for like a
minute, kill on the clock,
just skating around.
Whoop getting chased by that
little motherfucker. Right.
So yesterday I'm like,
I'm going to beat this dude
fair and square and um,
singing in sweet home
Alabama in the morning.
Who downloaded that? I mean, gee,
how many fucking hit songs do
you got to fucking slam together?
And then you get a hit song out of it.
It doesn't fucking make any sense.
You know, you got the whole, the
I woo. Where will the London,
you're coming out of the gate with that
bomp bomp bomp ball to put the pool ride.
Hey, we just swiped a hit
song. What do you think?
I don't think that's enough.
Why don't we swipe another one and
we'll put that in the chorus singing,
you know, sweet home,
Alabama, Sheryl Crow's tits.
Um, isn't that what happened? She put a
tits in the camera and then they that,
do you know what it is? That's,
that attic is actually [inaudible]
product of everybody stealing
music and there's no music stores.
So this is, and I'm, I'm wrong. Maybe
I won't kid rock and apology. Like,
this is what these,
this is the level of fucking hoops
this dude has to jump through in,
in order to have a fucking hit record.
How do you get your music out?
That's the amazing thing about lady Gaga,
right?
The new Queen Queen of the gay community.
You know,
they always loved checks like that, who
played like dress up and wear crazy hats,
you know, pulled down over there,
beat noses. I don't know what it is,
but gay people, they can't get
enough of chicks like that. Right?
But I was sitting there looking at lady
Gaga going, what the fuck is she doing?
And now, now I get it.
There's no, there's no audio.
That's another Spanish word for you.
It's not radio.
You just roll the out of audio sake.
Now I'm speaking Spanish,
now I'm back to English. That can me, ah,
I'm fucking crossing you over in a
verbal way. Breaking your fucking ankles.
Um, I'm such a Douche
this week. All right?
So don't even send me emails about what
a Douche I am because I'm completely
aware of it.
Okay?
I don't know if that makes me more
of a Douche or more tolerable,
but I'm just letting you
know where it's at. We
didn't even move,
didn't even fucking move.
And I get her to move all that goes.
Do you want to, and then
it goes to tail. Cleo,
do you wanna fucking dogs
like, yeah, I want to,
I don't have a fucking driver's license.
I can't open the front door.
You know,
maybe my dog isn't happy. Maybe
it's fucking depressed and, Hey,
what's the point man? I'm going to do is
walk in another room with nothing to do.
It's going to lay here all day.
Um, the fuck was I talking about?
I was on a nice roll there. Oh yeah.
There's no fucking way. There's no radio.
There's no Fuckin,
MTV doesn't play videos anymore.
Nobody buys your music. How the fuck
do you get your music out there?
You got to put on a meat dress.
So then all that guy,
that guy there with his little sippy cup
on that Paparazzi show, we'll be out.
They'll just say list, but eyes.
Yeah, lot of flood. Good mate. Ah, ah.
It's not maker the shelf.
Um, anyways, people,
you know what, I'm going to start actually
a am I gonna use audible.com/bill.
She can I use it audible.com/bill
can I go use that and then fucking
what books would I get?
You know why when I,
when I used to read when I was 27 and
I thought I was going to be smart,
I started reading books thinking it would
make me more likely to get a blow job
bought. It never fucking happened. Um,
because I looked like
Ron Howard when I was 27.
Um, so anyways, now I'm 44. Um,
if I was going to have a books read to me,
I would do that.
The Irvine Welsh series, you know, cause
I'm a big fan of that. That fucking,
what is it? Cockney accent.
Fucking Irish spring.
Let me cut into some soap with a,
with a shank accent.
And there was a bunch of words in there
that I kind of figured out cause he
literally writes it how they say it.
Huh.
And uh, maybe if I, you know, I wonder
if they actually have like somebody
you know who's,
if you're going to do the urban Welsh
series of books on audible.com/bill trying
to fill my contractual
obligations with these people.
I'm trying to say it as many times as
humans, but I actually like these guys,
you know, considering there's no more,
there's no more bookstores anymore.
These guys are actually
picking up the slack.
Right?
I like audible.com/bill. You
know what? I don't like I, I'm,
I'm not doing the pro flowers thing
anymore. Okay. I like those guys,
but I like them on Valentine's Day
and mother's Day. Other than that,
I can't sit here with any sort of good
conscience and trying to sell you guys
flowers in the beginning of
fucking September. What do you get?
Somebody flowers for fucking Labor
Day. You know, unless you accidentally
ran over somebody foot on September 1st,
there's no fucking reason to
get anybody some flowers. Well,
what if they have a date? Oh
go fuck yourself. You know,
then I got to fill out all this
bullshit to, to get fucking $17.
It's not even worth it to me.
All right, so pro flowers,
if you're listening,
I will see you in February.
Um, anyone face this is
like reverse good business.
So anyways,
what the fuck am I talking about?
Did Anybody Watch any college football?
How great is it that football's back?
Anybody gets suckered into that Michigan,
Alabama game like I did,
I had the fucking fellows
over. You know, my woman,
my piece of property is,
um,
she killed me if I ever said that
is fucking, uh, she's out of town.
So what am I going to do?
There's only two options.
Either I get some hookers and I cheat on
her or I have the fellows come over and
I fucking get hammered.
I chose the louder they give me.
I'm still fucking bitch.
Can't drink like I used to man. I
picked up a cigar habit, you know.
Anyways, so yeah, number eight,
Michigan for his fucking number to
Alabama. And in my head I'm going,
why is Michigan Number Eight? How are
they number rate? They sucked last year.
What happened?
Who did they get did,
did a couple of fucking beast
from Penn state, you know,
but you'll even then you're only allowed
to sign one. What the fuck happened?
How were these guys number rate and about,
I dunno when Alabama was up like 21
nothing or something like right in the
beginning of the second quarter,
that's when I figured it out. Oh,
they weren't number rate.
They just made them number rate.
So I would tune in and invite my
fucking friends over like an asshole.
We watched like seven minutes of
that game and then that was it.
We were downstairs fucking hanging
out at the grill. You know,
I took out my climbing rope cause
everybody, oh, you climb a rope,
I can fucking do that. Then people are
drunk trying to go up and down the rope,
you know, back in the day, that
would be funny to me and all in all,
I'm thinking in my head the whole time
is somebody is going to fall and they're
going to break their hip and then
I'm going to get sued. All right?
And that's what it means to become old.
Okay.
You know, when you're young,
when your friends fall down,
you could just laugh when you're old.
There's some,
there's somebody has to pay for it.
There's a liability. Oh Jesus.
Why didn't I bet that game?
Maybe they do. Do I just know
it because now the game is over.
But if ever there was a fucking lay up,
everybody [inaudible] he's so fucking,
he's fucking sec fast.
And now he's playing an SEC team.
Okay.
Which means you regular fucker.
He just became another fucking
quarterback and that was it.
He actually made a couple of nice throws.
But uh,
I don't know. I don't know
a bunch of fucking people
all in that Goddamn stadium.
Yeah.
Who honestly, who the fuck
would buy flowers in September?
You know what I mean?
Why are we selling flowers? That's
that corporate mentality. You,
why don't you just make all your money
on fucking Valentine's Day and then you
make the varsity of money,
the back end,
the back nine you make on mother's Day
and you call it a year and go sit on your
fucking boat. You know what? What if?
What if we just created this need for
flowers 12 months out of the year?
What if you just left him in the ground
and you let them continue to produce
oxygen for us?
Why don't you do that instead of
ripping them out of fucking ground every
goddamn day. Now, oh Jesus, I
am on a fucking tear here. Um,
you know what it is? No,
Bill, what is it? I am a,
I'm getting geared up. I'm doing six
straight fucking weeks on the road.
Six straight. Well, my, my year
is basically over. Summer's over.
The summer is over.
I'm going on the road.
I'm and to you with Dick Jokes
and a clothes and shit joke.
And that's it for you.
Yeah.
By the time you realize
you got fucked over,
I'll have your money in my
wallet. Bottle. Bottle, bottle,
baby.
I'm fucking doin.
I'm fucking doing the white trash tour.
What do you mean by the white trash?
The white trash tour.
Listen to the cities that I am going to
this week. I'm going to be on Orlando,
Florida.
Okay.
And unless you have kids and you want
to go visit a giant fucking mouse with a
struggling actor inside of it,
there's no fucking reason to go there.
If you're some whore and you
want to go blow tiger woods,
I guess that's another reason to go there.
I don't know why else would you go to
Orlando to buy some bait? You know?
So I'm going there first and then next
week I'm going to be in Charlotte,
Charlotte, North Carolina, east bound
to Dachau and load it up and trucking.
We didn't realize the civil war head and
it, um, I'm going there. Do you want?
Or the comedy zone
and uh,
then I go to New York City.
Oh,
I'm standing next to a bunch of shit.
That must mean I'm successful too.
Right? Let's get a slice. I'm going there
and then the week after that
I go to Jacksonville, Florida.
This is how bad Jacksonville is.
People in Jacksonville go to
Orlando to vacation. All right.
Okay.
Jacksonville, Jacksonville is another one
of those cities that if it started to,
if there was a flood, you know, you
think you had it bad in New Orleans. If,
if Jacksonville literally
fell into the sea,
I think it would take at least,
I would say 36 hours before like that.
Lighten that news actually hit
the national airwaves. You know,
36 hours after an entire
metropolis fell into the ocean,
somebody would finally
come on TV, be like, uh,
we have a developing story,
something going on in Jacksonville,
Florida. Is that in the south? Eastern.
Northeastern. Thank you.
Thank you. Robert. The
northeastern part of the state,
like no one even fucking know
what goes on in Jacksonville.
You had a USFL team back in the day.
Right?
The Florida gators and the fucking
Georgia bulldogs play there once a year.
Everybody comes to town, they drink their
beer and they fuck you. Women, you know,
and they drive out and then that's,
it becomes quiet again.
A couple of tumbleweeds blow across,
you know, you got the Jaguar.
That's actually pretty amazing,
you know,
for a city to get a professional franchise
when they have no other professional
franchises. Like his late in the game
is Jacksonville got a fucking team.
You know what I mean?
Like take a,
let's say Portland, Portland,
Oregon. They got a basketball team.
I could see them maybe
getting a baseball team,
you know, I had to get a basketball
team. They showing up for that.
Let's fucking try this. Right?
Jacksonville had nothing. Nada,
zero, Zilch. They had nothing.
The Florida gators and Georgia bulldogs
play there because it's some neutral
shit in the middle of fucking nowhere.
It's like a musical, you know what I mean?
Like when they have like a, the two
gangs are going to fight before they do.
They're going to walk in a circle,
snapping their fingers. Right.
This stupid fucking jeans rolled
up for some unknown reason
other than probably the sexuality
of most of the guys in the play.
Good. How tough guys it. Um,
anyways,
so that's what I'm doing.
And then after that I go to Cincinnati,
Ohio and Cincinnati,
Ohio.
That's one of those Zombie cities is all
these great hardworking people right up
until four 59 in the afternoon in right
at five. It's like the Fred Flintstone.
They all slide down the
brontosaurs getting a God
damn cars and they vacate the
city and then all that
is left is drug addicts,
unbelievably poor people. And the
comedian working at the club walking,
that's what's walking down the if five
oh one as the sun starts to go down,
you know what I mean?
Okay.
You started, you know, it's probably the
same feeling like you know that Zebra has
and that that split second where in his,
his peripheral,
whenever the whole herd
scattered and you don't know why,
and you start to feel the breadth of
an alligator and you're like, fuck,
I guess it's me today, right.
Jesus. Bill is Cincinnati that bad?
You know what? Go visit it. Go visit it.
I did. I even mention any
dates. Jesus. What the fuck?
What kind of ways that
to sell a Goddamn tour.
That was like reverse
rock singer right there.
We're fucking rock singers would go
out there and be like, let me tell you,
he stopped in Jacksonville.
We've done a lot of cities on his door,
but I've got to tell you,
and I think the fellows by me will agree.
We need carbs to crowds,
right?
Just fucking jerking him off.
The reason why I'm excited
to go to these cities,
I just want to see what the
fuck people do in these cities.
I've already been to our
land. Oh, I know what that,
that's just a bunch of fucking
strip malls. Those Adobe structures.
You know the excitement out
there. You want to go to
five guys, burgers and fries.
You want to go down there, you my name,
and they make the base Goddamn burgers.
You know, they probably all look
down on Disney world, you know,
bunch of fucking posers. Like that's how
you like you were a rebel in Orlando.
Has You trashed Disney world?
You know?
I don't know why. Why would you
continue this way? You know what it is.
It's not going to be the shows.
It's not going to be the people that
come up to me after the shows and say
something mildly racist. You know?
It's not going to be that. It's,
it's going to be the getting
on and getting off of
fucking airplanes out. Jesus.
This is like the Tampon fucking menstrual
cramp fucking podcast right now.
We shouldn't. I feel lucky that
I have this amount of work.
You know when all those glass workers got
laid off recently out there in Dayton,
Ohio, then they just closed
down the glass factory.
Do you know they're not going to make
glasses in this country anymore? Anywhere
are all gonna be made in the Philippines?
I saw the whole thing on 60 minutes.
Did you guys watch the last
episode of breaking bad?
Did anybody see it as a bunch of fucking
psychos right now covering their ears?
I,
I can't recommend that show enough and
it's not cause old twinkle toes got an a
couple of episodes here.
It's just,
it's the most unbelievable
fucking show I've ever seen.
They just keep,
they just keep twisting it
tighter and tighter and tighter
and every time you think you can breathe,
you know,
cause some problem got fucking solved.
Something else comes along
and it's even fucking worse.
Okay.
Unreal.
I'm not gonna say anything that happened.
I probably shouldn't even brought it up
cause this is probably half the fucking
people listen to this. Aren't even
listening right now for fear that you know
I was going to give away
something from the show.
Um, I'm not going to do that. All right.
This is the Monday morning podcast.
Everybody, if you're new to this
show, um, welcome. Welcome aboard.
If you live in any of the cities I
just trashed. Uh, I stand by that.
That wasn't a joke. Now I know when I, I
know what I'm going to do in Charlotte.
Charlotte, I'm going to go
visit a street side customs.
I'm going to go check out the old cars
there. That's what I'm going to do.
Their New York City. Come on
New York. I'll be fine. Orlando,
I have no idea what the
fuck I'm going to do.
I tried to find some college football,
I something,
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I think I'm going to walk from the air
condition comedy Condo to the club and
then go back.
But I'm actually excited to be there
cause I've never done that one. Let, let,
let's,
let's try to put a little positive shine
on this fucking white trash tour here
and a Jacksonville.
Um,
there's gotta be some
redneck shit going on.
There's gotta be some sort of
rattlesnake roundup, you know,
some sort of gun show,
you know,
two rednecks with their
trucks chained together,
trying to drive in different directions.
Whoever ends up with the other guys,
differential wins,
you know,
can I go to something like that as if
fucking something for me to do there.
But actually, when I'm in Charlotte,
I'm going to go to the panthers game,
Carolina Panthers Game,
and when I'm in Jacksonville,
I'm going to go to a fucking Jaguar's
game. And when I go to Cincinnati,
I'm going, oh, bangles games.
See that? That's how I do
the fucking road. That's how,
that's how I do it. Pointing
at himself with a thump. Um,
all right, here we go. Let's, let's get,
let's get this shot. Let's get some stuff
out of the way here. He voice everybody.
This is like, this has taken off
like wildfire. You know that Cleo,
okay.
I know you're just laying there with
not a fucking excited bone in your body,
but I'm telling you, he
voice, he voice is a, is, is,
is killing it. And you're probably
saying eight belt. What is, uh,
what does the voice, he voices
basically your mobile phone at work.
Okay. You can get all kinds of
different phone numbers. Uh Oh.
I always forget the word
virtual virtual phone numbers.
Like when it'd be great if you could
give some guys some guy coming up to you
and he wants to buy your widgets,
right?
And you want to give
him your phone number,
but you don't want to give me
your real phone number, right?
But you don't want to have 20 cell
phones. All right? With he voice.
You can have a whole bunch of different
phone numbers all ring on your cell
phone, but nobody really knows your
number. All they know is those other ones.
Right? Did that make sense? Did I
just get lost in the math of that? Um,
it basically,
it creates a way that you can actually
make it seem like you have an office
building in the beginning when you're
really don't, they got music on hold.
They have professional
voiceover people to be like, oh,
La don the s lay something or other,
right?
Whatever English accent,
whatever you want,
they're going to make
you sound professional.
Like this is probably the best way that
I can think if you're starting off a
business or if you already have them.
But if you're starting a business,
taking that crucial step to get yourself
out of that cubicle and make your
dreams come true today
is to,
is to get the, you got to have some
sort of infrastructure going. Okay,
but that costs money. You
know what I mean? Usually it
costs you a bunch of money,
but with he voice, it's not going
to cost you a bunch of money.
You just sign up for this stuff
and you're good to go. Uh,
one of the great features is music
on hold makes your business seem more
professional is the voice.
We'll treat your clients and customers
to music on hold. You can even set up,
he voiced to run a promotional
advertisement for your
company while you're on
hold instead of the music. He voice
also has the call recording feature,
which is perfect for doctors,
lawyers, real estate agents,
hiring managers in any hundred
professionals, uh, discussing contracts.
You can do conference calls
with up to 95 people, you know,
in case you're in some sort of
worldwide drug cartel meeting.
I don't know what you need 95 people for,
but just in case you do,
he voices there. But when
you have your 95 person, Kay,
you dig it, a conference
call, um, it's easy to use.
You just press two to start
and to, to stop. Perfect.
If you're driving and can't
write something important down,
he voice makes your life easier
and seem more professional.
For a free six month trial,
go to www dot [inaudible]
dot com slash bill burr, uh,
once again,
www dot [inaudible] dot com slash bill
burr or go to the banner ad on my podcast
page at [inaudible] dot com. Um, I really
hope you guys start utilizing this and,
uh,
no ps,
I've been getting some great feedback
from people out there from listeners who
is trying to start their own business.
This is the perfect thing, you know,
and if you're starting a business,
do you want to pay taxes like a regular
lunch pail? Larry? I don't think you do.
When it be great if you
could get incorporated for
a very low amount of money.
Well, let me tell you this at legal zoom.
Um, you probably heard about legal zoom,
but I'm telling you about them right now.
You've got to check them out.
These guys are phenomenal.
Um,
if you've been waiting for the perfect
time to start your dream business,
it's right now.
Incorporate Your Business or form an
llc@legalzoom.com starting at just 99
bucks. I paid 1500 to do this
when I went through a lawyer. Um,
and if you have a family,
guess what?
You need to make sure that
they're protected too.
You can protect your family and assets
with the legal zoom will for just $69.
And the past 12 years, over 2 million
Americans have used legal zoom for Llcs,
wills, trusts, trademarks, and more.
This is the way, this is the way to go.
All right.
And if you get too confused,
they even have attorneys
that will help you out. Uh,
if you need it through their legal plans,
um,
Start Your Business and protect
your family@legalzoom.com.
You could also get a special discount
from listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter a burr in the referral
box as B u r r at the checkout for
more savings.
Legalzoom is not a law firm and self
help services are provided at your
direction. In other words, if you
need help, ask for it. All right.
So back to the podcast here.
Yeah.
Hey,
you know what?
I want to buy a pegboard hanging ended
up on my garage and basically start my
own little gym here. It's all body
weight. I got a climbing rope,
I got a dip station, pull up thing and
then I get that peg board right? And I go,
I'll and be able to go up and down it
with my skinny little legs hanging off it.
Cause I'm not doing any squats you don't
really want to do is a buddy of mine
was telling me a on Joe Rogan's
podcast. He's got this hope, uh,
those kettle bell workout.
I heard his listeners are going nuts.
Getting all Jack doing that.
I want to do it.
So if anybody knows
what podcast of Rogan's,
I got to listen to,
um,
where he basically breaks it down and
then I'll do my cheap ass version of it
when I'm on the road by basically going
out and buying two grapefruits and
putting them in plastic bags.
Well,
tourists to say principals, um, advice.
Uh, right. Bill Boehner problems.
Oh Jesus Christ. Here we go. Dear Bill,
I'm approaching my 27th birthday and in
the past couple of weeks I've had some
issues with getting erect. Ugh.
All right. All right, well I'll,
Jesus. Okay, here we go.
Instead of getting wood,
having sex or looking at porn,
I now have to fiddle with
myself just to get hard.
I don't know if this is due to
mild do this is so fucking beyond.
Okay.
This is a doctor drew question.
All right, so don't listen to me,
but I got to make this funny dude.
All right,
so fast forward this cause I don't want
to add to your psychological problems.
Um,
I dunno if this is due to mild depression
caused by stress being overweight or
I'm just getting old and this is how
I'm going to be. I am overweight,
but since April, I've been steadily losing
weight and exercise and good for you.
I do have mild depression. I know
where you're coming from. I got it too.
And I've had bouts of erectile
dysfunction in the past,
but they usually don't last
more than a few days. Um,
yeah,
I don't know what to tell you.
I would say don't rub one out
for a couple of days, you know,
and then stand on your back
porch with the junk hanging out.
And I imagine the first time the wind
blows, I think you'll be in the game.
That's my advice. And it's off
to Chicago and let's win there.
Yeah. I don't know what to
tell you, dude. Like I would,
I would seek some sort
of professional help.
See if you've got a circulation problem.
Um,
but I think the biggest
thing you're doing,
which is great as you're losing
weight because a, you know,
eat too many fucking Cinnabons.
It clogs up the plumbing.
And I know that because I
don't have a medical degree.
I'm ignoring girlfriends past bill.
I am an Aussie with the beautiful
girlfriend out. Speaking of Australians,
I'm going to Sydney in, uh, in October.
You see what I just did
there? This guy's, you know,
actually he basically
started a conversation with,
with me and I just interrupted them and
being that do shit the party right now.
But I actually,
you guys have seen,
did you see that video where the fucking
little Aussie bullies punching the fat
headed fucking kid who I like outweighs
them by 80 pounds and finally the,
the, the kid getting bullied
just can't take it anymore.
And he just picks this kid up and I
can't even like lifts him up basically a
little above his head.
And if you just dropped him there,
that would have been amazing.
But he liked fucking,
it was like he was ringing out a mat
is how he threw this kid down to the
fucking ground,
like shaking out a beach towel,
except it was this kid's
rag doll body like his,
the kid's whole body did the fucking warm,
except when he came back,
he'd just from like six feet in the air
and he slammed this kid on the ground.
I couldn't believe this kid's legs
still worked. It was fucking awesome.
But now they got like, they have like,
it's become this entire like mini series.
They interviewed the kid who got bullied
and then they interviewed the kid who
did the bullying and the funny,
the bullies crying and he's trying to say
that the fatty fucking was hitting him
first, which is total bullshit
because if you look at the fat kid,
which I really shouldn't be saying, but
you know, I'm just trying to, you know,
I only have so many minutes here
in the podcast, the Husky Kid,
the fucking kid punches him in the face
and he just stands there with his hands
down to his side. He could tell, you know,
if he was walking around hitting people,
his whole body language,
but in a different,
I didn't believe that the little
mosquito looking kid. But um,
and then so the interview,
both of them and then they have the
two of them interviewing each other.
And I gotta tell you, I don't think
I've ever laughed so fucking hard
in my entire life. Not because I think
it's right or I think it's funny.
I just fucking this
just something about it.
It just took me back to my childhood.
Just how fucking mean kids are.
Maybe like what, what, what was it
like, what was it like when, when, when,
when you went to skill,
like what was some of,
what was some of the things
the kids used to call you?
I know this is a brutal
fucking Aussie accent. Um,
he'd be like, well, you know, they
call me, they call me fatty and,
and with every mean name,
I'm laughing my ass off.
It literally gets to the point where the
kids said he was suicidal and I've been
through all of that.
I've been through all of it and I
actually sat there laughing my ass off
watching it and I'm asking you guys, why
am I laughing? I don't find it funny.
I feel bad for the kid,
but with the main,
or the detail is the
harder I fucking left.
I don't know if that,
I don't know if that's like some
sort of like a fallout from trauma.
We're after a while you just like, it's
just becomes funny. There's like nothing.
What else are you going to do?
Okay.
Like, I remember like every
fucking movie I go to see,
I know I've told these stories
a zillion times, but this,
this actually fits in it. Like
I'm a one, I saw sling blade.
Okay.
And when that country singer
Dwight Yoakam, when he's zoomed,
the guy in the wheelchair
out of the house,
why don't you go home and practice Randy
and he get the fuck out of my house and
he fucking zone that can the wheelchair
and the guy in the wheelchair like it
did like the whiplash thing and
went through the front door, like
the people who are watching the movie
around where either quiet or gasping and I
was roaring laughing
and not that. I think that's like it's,
do you know what I mean? Like it's,
it's so wrong.
It's funny.
Ah, I'm probably coming off like
a maniac. I did that one time.
We were flying over to fucking one of
those magical kingdoms over there in
Europe where they got a Starbucks
next to a fucking castle, you know?
And uh,
okay.
I was sitting in the aisle,
neos in the middle seat and then there
was some girl on the window and uh,
yes, I was flying coach, um,
to go do the funny bone in
fucking Afghanistan and uh,
okay.
I was watching a movie on a laptop and I
was laughing so hard at one point I was
fucking wheezing and it was one of
those deals where I'm laughing so hard.
People around me are laughing
just at how hard I'm lat.
Like the girl on the window was laughing
at how hard I was laughing and I was
laughing so hard that I woke me up and
Nia woke up and immediately was like
laughing, like, what the fuck are you
laughing at? And then she leaned over,
you know, cause you can't
see in the computer screen.
She leaned over and saw that I
was watching the precious and um,
you know, she starts punching me in
the arm, which made it even funnier.
And then the girl by the
window found it even funnier.
Okay.
I totally got lost in that fucking story.
I don't know what point I'm trying
to make. Like, I'm trying to ask you,
why do I find shit like that?
Hilarious.
You know, like whenever I
watched the biggest loser and
they'll be like, you know,
so how do you feel about yourself, your,
your fucking Zeppelin, you, you know,
and the guy will be like, well, you know,
I have my good days and I
have my bad days. And uh,
then his voice cracks and it's fucking
forehead wrinkles up and he just starts
fucking crying like a baby.
I, I, I can't, I don't,
I fucking laugh.
Okay.
I laughed. Like I'm watching
stripes, intervention,
you know,
intervention.
When the family starts reading their
letters of pain to the fucking degenerate
drug addict and a,
they start fucking crying.
I immediately,
I just start roaring laughing.
Yeah.
Like it's funny,
like I get more laughs out of that than
if I was watching one of those sitcoms
with the good looking people in the couch.
I don't know what the fuck I'm
talking about. Um, anyways,
let's get on with the podcast here. Oh,
Australia, the Australia Guy, right. Um,
if anybody knows what that is, if there's
actually anybody with any steel, what?
Look,
I was just gonna say if there's some sort
of psychologists listening to the shit
as if I deserve professional opinion.
After you guys listened to my fucking
moron opinion every week, whatever,
if you're a plumber, I'd like to
hear what you think. All right.
Ignoring girlfriends. Uh, pass bill. I'm
an Aussie with a beautiful girlfriend.
How the hell do I stop picturing
her getting nailed by guys.
She's dated before me.
I'm torturing myself with these thoughts.
We have great sex and everything. Yeah. Oh
yeah. How do you think she got that way?
Do you use the dice clay line from
banging all those other people, sir? Um,
from what I understand, it's something
no one likes to think about it. Dude,
I'm just breaking your balls.
All right.
Look,
if you love this girl,
you just got to get past the fact
that she sucked other the Dicks,
you know,
probably enjoyed it. Nah, I'm
just fucking with you now. Um,
that was mean. How do you get past it? Um,
yeah,
I never think about it. I just
look at, I look at women like, uh,
you just picked up a fucking
free agent that's got, you know,
good fucking career stats here that
shows that they can get the job done.
You know, they can perform an
October. You know what I mean?
Just look at it like that way.
It's like the Dodgers just picking up
all those red sox. They got Gonzales.
You don't,
you think that they cared that he fucking
was playing baseball and some other
towns,
they don't give a fuck.
Just come in here and get the God damn
job done so we can win the championship.
That's how he got to look at it. All
right. If she shows up and she's clean,
she doesn't have any good.
What about you sir?
Yeah.
Next time she's fucking blow in.
You thinking about,
think about all the fucking trolls
at the truck stop that you left put,
put their mouths on you
and now she's down there.
You know,
there's not enough shampoo and
conditioner to clean your Dick.
Pass a certain fucking age,
and that's the God damn truth.
And you don't say anything about it.
That right
as you put it inside of her, give
me a fucking break. All right,
Sarah. It is what it is.
She's banged other people.
You're going to have to get facet and uh,
I can guarantee you this.
Okay?
She probably hasn't been with remotely
the amount of people that you have,
not to mention some of the
fucking complete tramps
that, uh, you know what I mean? I like
to think that women are a little more,
uh, have a little more discretion
and my issues with women right now,
it just kills me that I'm saying something
pro female because I know they're all
fucking nodding.
I AskPat um,
yeah,
this is one way or the other.
They're either really discretionary
or they're just fucking womping horse.
And that was a generalization. I
apologize. Um, friends, unholy wedding.
Oh Dude, I was doing so great on
this fucking podcast. I don't know.
It's somewhere I lost
the fucking momentum.
I lost my Mojo when I was talking
about why I laugh, you know,
at people with the fucking crutches
falling down a flight of stairs.
I don't know why I got into that.
A friend's unholy wedding bill.
I got a problem that I don't think
I can go to go to my friends with.
A friend of mine is getting married.
I've been good friends with the guy since
we were five years old and we are now
23. He's getting married
about a year from now.
He has selected me to be the groomsmen.
Alright.
I'm guessing either you fucked his wife,
future wife,
or she's banged,
you know,
70 people or as fucking around on
him. That's what I'm guessing. Um,
or she's into the devil. One of
the other. This has to be white.
This is an unholy wedding. All right? He's
getting married about a year from now.
Good. You got time. He, he is a selected,
sorry. I need to just was calling
him. She's going to kill me.
He's calling from another fucking country
and I just shut it off because I had
to pee.
I gotta finish this fucking podcast.
He putting the podcast enemy. Yes. Uh,
he's getting married about a year from
now. He has selected me to be a groomsman.
This means I have to pay for a flight
to attend the wedding. Furthermore,
his bachelor parties being huge sheet.
Motherfucker.
This is what it's going to be about money.
All right. This me, I fucking hate.
Oh, hang on a second. The lovely Nia.
Everybody.
Yeah.
Nia.
Hey listen, I'm doing the podcast.
Can I call you right back?
Okay.
Say hello to the podcast listeners.
Tally Ho I'll talk to you later.
See that she had a fucking hard day and
I'm not there for what? A piece of shit.
All right, let's get back to Tightwad
here and I have to buy a Tuxedo.
You know, uh, a rent one. Ah,
this means I have to pay for a flight
to attend the wedding. Furthermore,
his bachelor parties being held in Las
Vegas and I would also have to pay for
this light as well as other
expenses of a bachelor party.
Normally this wouldn't be an issue.
I'm a college student and saving the
approximately a thousand dollars,
this would cost, would be,
uh, would be stressful,
but it would be worth it to see one of
my greatest friends get married. Okay,
so you're not a cheap fuck you
just having money prompts. However,
my friend has often lied to
and cheated on his fiance. Oh,
okay.
I didn't see that one common. Why
didn't, I guess that. There you go.
There's a whole new fucking
Jesus.
I'm not judging him. I, Tricia,
I disapprove of how we treat.
So this guy is actually a good shit and
I actually called them peace of God ever.
I judge you on your first couple of
sentences. What are you gonna do? He goes,
I disapprove of how we treat sir,
but I don't get myself involved.
He sleeps around and hides from her.
The fact that he smokes pot and
drinks heavily on a daily basis.
I don't know how she hasn't noticed.
She's probably because she's a sweetheart.
Okay.
Sweethearts always end up
with fucking dicks like this.
She's never smoked or cheated.
Uh, as far as, you know,
I don't understand why he doesn't find
a different relationship, but again,
I don't get myself involved.
The problem is I can't imagine this
marriage will last very long and I don't
want to pay $1,000 for a sham marriage
at a time when $1,000 is like the lottery
to me.
I'm actually offended.
These asked me to do all of this for the
wedding and thus spend all this money.
I could not imagine asking any of my
friends to throw away that much money on
something I didn't give a fuck about.
Should I decline to attend the wedding?
Any advice would be appreciated.
Uh,
I dunno if I can go to our
other friends with this one. Um,
all right.
This
as always as a million different ways
you can play this. There's two options,
three options. All right? One,
you just fucking bite your tongue and
you just go to the goddamn whiting and
think that all right.
Even though it's gonna fucking blow up,
maybe he'll learn something
from it. And then, uh,
you know, by the time
he's 30, he'll grow up.
And you guys can actually
be friends again too.
You fucking did I say there was three.
I already forgot the other ones. So we,
there's only gonna be two here.
Oh, I'm the why do you guys listen
to this? You know, you know why?
Cause it makes you feel better,
doesn't it? It should. Good. No, I,
I feel like I'm serving a purpose
now. Um, just sit the guy down.
It'd be like, dude, can I ask a
question? Yeah, sure. Matthew, what's up?
What the fuck are you doing? What
do you, what do you, what do,
what do you mean what
am I doing? I mean what the
why are you getting married?
Cause I love her anyway.
What is this going dude,
you're fucking everything that moves.
I walked slower when I'm around you.
That's how much shit that you fucking do.
You understand me?
Do you understand where I'm coming
from and you're asking me to go out.
She doesn't know you beaus she
doesn't know that you smoke weed.
Yeah.
You know I, this is 1000
bucks. If you were actually,
you know,
this is like me flying
to go see the fucking,
I don't know, go see it.
The Padres versus the fucking Colorado
Rockies. What is the fucking point,
you know? Yeah. You're,
you're a piece of shit.
This marriage isn't going to last and
what's worse is you're doing in front of
me and then I got to sit there
and have a conversation. You know,
I got to figure out what part of a face
I'm going to look at cause I can't look
at her in the eye. You
dragging me into it. Oh Jesus.
This bad advice. I mean you've got to
have, I at least don't say it that way.
Just be like, listen, I don't have $1,000.
I just don't have it
to go to the marriage.
And then they had to go to the wedding,
start with that.
And then if he gives you shit,
just say,
oh that's your other option. Just say,
listen, I just don't have the money.
And you bite your tongue and you look
the other way so you don't see them.
The train wreck that's going to happen.
That's the option.
Or you can just come clean and just say,
listen dude, I love you to death. Yeah,
my buddy. But what you're
doing here, this is wrong.
All right?
You're not being fair to her.
You're not being fair to me,
ed. Yeah, you're fucking,
you're screwing yourself in the long run.
So
this is what you want to do. Go do it.
But I don't want to be a part of it.
All right.
Okay.
Yeah.
So my guess is a,
your best fucking option as far as
like the least amount of drama is to,
uh,
and mental trauma for yourself is to do
the one, I threw it there in the middle.
We just say, listen, I
just don't have the money.
Do Acute believe I'm
supposed to be you, bro. Bro,
it's my wedding dude.
I can't believe,
dude,
I can't believe you're fucking everything
that moves and you fucking smoke weed.
You booze every day and this girl
doesn't even know how about that.
And you're acting like you're not doing
it even at a fucking me and you expect
me to stay on there. Do you
understand that? You understand that?
I realize that you're fucking everything
that moves right now and you're going
to go marry this girl and I'm have to
sit there and watch you toast this girl.
I love you. You're the, uh, the, the
blood that pumps through my heart.
That bullshit. I got to sit there
staring at my fucking Lasagna.
You know there's going to be lasagna.
Anytime you got to cook for
more than fucking 10 people,
they just make a big tray of that shit.
We have a meet days.
We have a vegetarian.
Is that big fucking silver tray?
All right.
Is the last one off. This is
a short podcast. 50 minutes.
Satan, this person says, Bill,
if Satan punishes the bad,
doesn't that make him good?
And that's from a lady.
Um,
yeah,
I don't get the math on that.
Like most things when it comes to
religion, it doesn't, it doesn't add up.
It's like
Satan was in heaven. Right? How
the fuck does it go? Isn't it?
What an iron maiden song.
Can I just go listen to like die with
your boots on and then I'll know how this
story goes.
Like I fuck or Judas priest,
you know,
point of entry are screaming
for vengeance, don't they
have a song about it?
Whatever St was basically,
you know,
he was like the Zildjian brothers before
they had a fight and then one broke off
and created Sabian.
Right.
How about something a
little more mainstream?
It was like Bill Gates and Steve Jobs.
Right.
When they will have been a little
circle jerk around a fucking TRS 80 or
whatever the fuck they were doing
and that little fort, you know,
playing dungeons and dragons,
playing poker for each other's loafers,
whatever the fuck they did.
Then they went their separate ways,
whatever Satan was in the club,
but he wanted to run shit.
What did he do
the fuck did the guy do again?
Yeah.
Somehow we pissed off God,
Oh, I know. He tried to take over.
He tried to take God's position
and God was like, Oh no, you da all right.
And then cast him into this fucking
pit of fire that never goes out.
But Somehow Satan is such
a bad motherfucker that
he sits in the flames and
adapted. You know what I mean?
Like somebody back in the day,
they had bronchitis so they'd send them
out to the desert to fucking dry out.
Like that was going to cure you.
He actually got cured to the point.
Now Satan's down there and it's
just chilling. Oh look who got up.
Okay.
Oh Cleo,
get over here
now you got to Itch
fucking for nine hours.
MMM.
Yes. So now he's down there
like fucking uh, you know,
lucky Luciano hanging out at the fucking
Flamingo and then you go down there,
you go down, you basically live
your life the way he wanted you to,
and then you show up at the club and
that he's mad at you and then kicks the
shit out of you.
It doesn't make any sense.
And technically he's then punishing
you for doing what he did.
Is it like, uh, like that's like
the mail room, like God's mail room.
So we sit in this sort sorting envelopes,
like he's still working for God.
I don't, I really don't know how it works.
I actually went to church this week.
Oh Gee.
I went there in the second I
walk in, I just can't, like I,
I don't buy into any of it.
I went with the,
I went with Nina's mom,
we went to church.
Okay.
And what I tried to do when I go in
there is it go above all of it and try to
like, you know, connect with something
like Whoopi Goldberg in Ghost,
you know, try to connect with something
else other than what they're saying,
like literally what they're preaching.
It's like,
I ain't no.
Okay.
You guys had the holy wars, you had the
fucking inquisition. I mean, you fucking,
you know,
want Jewish people after World War II.
We're trying to get this shit back.
Like the amount of stuff that
went into the Vatican, I mean,
you would down with the Nazis.
Okay.
Like how has this plate, like, how did
Penn state lose all those victories?
Okay.
Right. Lost all those victories. And
what happened to the Catholic Church?
You know, I've, I've talked about
this a zillion fucking types.
They have broken on a global level,
every major fucking
commandment that there is,
and they just sit there.
Okay,
holy,
holy by Buddha.
Fucking tell me how to
live my life. Um, yeah,
I just don't buy into it.
Okay.
And then the money basset came around and
my, I've given these motherfuckers shit
as with me, his mom, and I was like, ah,
I don't want to be an
asshole in front of us.
I threw five bucks in their five bucks.
I just paid $5 for the fucking defense
attorney in a pedophile case kind of ag
telling me I'm not going to hell right.
Then they'll being so goddamn stupid.
Yeah. Who was a, and they
had the guy, they had the,
this Irish tenor guy who was singing
songs keep and behind it and he would do
like this big conducting thing.
He was like totally fucking into
it to get the crowd going. Right.
He had this awful suit on.
It didn't fit them, you know,
looks like he ate donuts and shit
and they stay in the guy in the,
the preacher gave him a fucking
shout out. He goes this week. Ah,
yeah.
We would like to extend a congratulation
to a, that guy over there.
It can't fit into a sport coat
for 20 years of sagging sogs hair.
This church yet,
I want to say here's to another
50 years Eric has church.
Nobody clapped and it's like
he's going to be dead in 50
we're all going to be, I'll be
dead. Well, maybe not right.
94 what?
Fitbit with dentures.
That's going to be a sad fucking day.
Me fucking wheel in my ass under
the stage. Fucking at 94 years old.
You know somebody with a Jetsons
haircut interviewing me for the show.
Do you still enjoy it?
Do you still a joke every night?
I could get out there bigger Chabot,
the people's faces.
MMM.
Fucking sitting there instead
of like bottled water backstage.
I'll have like vital organs being grown
to be inserted in me before I go out
there. That's like the level of a,
Oh no, that won't be available to me.
Dick Cheney. You'll have that shit.
He'll still be walking around.
MMM.
Anyway, what the fuck was I
just talking about? Oh yeah.
Phrase another 50 years there. Deck
Chair. He's going to be dead. Look at him.
He's like 40 pounds over fucking weight.
He's sliding into 50 at about 90 miles
an hour without a helmet on the way this
guy's fucking eat and he's not,
he's not gonna make it.
He probably has some fucking
horrific collection of porn.
He's not wearing a wedding ring.
This fucking, he's sweaty. Like,
what is he doing? Sky's sad. He has
no fucking life. I feel bad for him.
Let's get him a haircut.
Get Him a gym membership.
And how about we make the last seven
years of his fucking life enjoyable?
How about that? Why don't we go
out and get a harlot for this guy?
You know,
the physical equivalent to a dozen
donuts. He'll be able to relate. You know,
I'm not even saying any
of that's true people.
That's just what was going
through my head when I was there.
There was some guy in the pew
hate that Word Pew in front of me,
and he just looked like an evil
motherfucker. You know, he was balding.
He was like in his, uh,
he was like pushing 60.
He was Tan.
Okay.
He fucking balding,
but he still's Diana's hair,
jet black and he had a pinky ring
and a bracelet on right there.
Pinky ring and a bracelet. You're a
dishonest motherfucker. All right.
Unless you were a check.
If you're a guy and you're wearing that,
you know that Dr Vinnie boombox
fucking outfit. That's it.
You're a piece of shit. And he
just, Oh, when he looked over at me,
peace be with you.
I want to be like fuck you.
Yeah.
Now what do you mean what?
You know what it's for.
If whatever the fuck you did since last
Sunday with your pinkie ring and your
bracelet, I, Jesus Christ. I think I
was just sitting there judging people.
You know, they all two girls, you know,
set of the altar boys just to
keep the priest honest, you know,
which I thought was brilliant.
That's a brilliant way to keep them away
from little boys is to let girls do it.
Cause they were all girls.
There was no boys there.
What else can I trash about it?
I can't remember. You know, I, I,
he gave the homily and I didn't remember
one fucking thing that he said he
wasn't Mike. Well, I couldn't understand
what he's saying. I don't, that was my,
those are my little trip to
fucking church. But I went,
but I went and I actually saw the
confessionals and I was thinking, Jesus,
this shit that I have to get off my chest.
And then,
but then I always think like a,
what a fuck do I want to tell this guy?
Why do I got to go in there and tell
it to you? And then it goes, yeah.
Then you run it up the fucking line,
you know,
fucking Weirdo.
You just want to hear all the bad shit
that I did because you're not allowed to
go out and fucking bang a
broad, ah, Jesus fill you. Just,
you're just, you're just going over old
fucking points. You've already made.
We get it. Oh, Geez. You don't like to
shit. All right, let's, uh, let's, let's,
let's conclude here with,
let's,
let's try to bring this around to
something positive. All right. Um,
let's start with the video games.
Video Games.
Why don't you like, um,
video games? See that.
Always come up with like a
jingle for everybody. Ah,
amazon.com now that's not where I want
game fly.com but everybody did I you want
to say baby gamefly dot
Dotcom baby. Um, all right.
Would you like to play 8,000 video games?
Get a two week free trial at $23 value.
Jesus Christ. That's what
it costs. 23 bucks. It's,
it's almost free anyways and
they've given it to you for free.
Let me tell you something.
If I played video games,
I would go to game fly.com
I'd go to www.game,
fly.com/ [inaudible] or
click on the banner ad on my
podcast page and get a free
trial. And I would joy 8,000 video
games for two weeks. And you know what?
I do have to two weeks,
I'd give him 23 bucks for a membership.
I put on my virtual glasses and I would
go to another world and I would kill the
bad things, right? And
when I couldn't do what,
I would get frustrated and I would go
online and I'd find the cheats and I get
all the weapons and I would
finish the game in 20 minutes.
It would make me feel good,
right?
Then I would yell out at other people
because I would feel guilty. Um,
anyways. Yeah.
gamefly.com/birth go on there.
Get all the video to you that
you could possibly ever want.
Stack them all up around your face and
you won't have to deal with the world
anymore.
All right.
amazon.com would you like to help out
this podcast and support the troops?
Um, go to [inaudible] dot
com click on the banner ad.
Anytime you're going to buy
something on Amazon, just do that.
Click on the banner ad,
the Amazon Banner ad on my podcast page.
It'll bring it directly to amazon.com.
You don't have to do anything else.
Go out there. Go Buy yourself a ladle.
Whatever the hell are you looking for.
A pegboard possibly like what I'm going
to buy later on after this podcast and
I'm
okay.
They kicked me a percentage
of whatever you know,
people buy and then I take a
percentage of that. I, I basically,
I'm kicking her overall 10%,
as I say,
every week of the advertising
money that I make,
and I sent it over to the wounded
warriors project. It's a great damn thing.
And a why not after this last hour of
filth and all the horrible things that
I've said, it's nice that I
could bring it around to this.
This a nice little moment here.
You know?
Holy Moly.
All Right Dad. Still fucking
podcast. Go Fuck Yourself.
That's it.
That's the podcast for this week.
Please come out and see me at
the first stop on the white trash
tour. Um, in, at the, uh, what
the hell am I going to be?
I'm gonna at the Improv in Orlando,
Florida. Would you like the exact dates?
You want me to hold your hand
through this whole thing?
I know we're Alando with the,
when am I supposed to be there?
Go this fucking computer. Come
on. Orlando Improv September 7th,
eighth and ninth since September
7th and eighth. Is that true?
I thought it was there for
three days. Thursday, Friday,
Saturdays when I'm there.
Comedy Zone, Charlotte, September 13th,
14th and 15th and I'll see
you at the game on Sunday.
MMM.
Oh by the way,
if anybody has any ideas of some shit
that I can go to a gun store or something
that's going to fucking be a cool thing
to do in any of these cities for the
love of God,
let me know.
Cause God knows the travel
channel never comes to your towns.
Caroline's the makeup date from July,
I'm going to be there September,
2021 22 and 23 and I will be there with
the teen idols sensation from the and
Anthony Program, the one and
only Joe, Joey Rose's Derosa.
Okay. This is his farewell
performance as a feature act. Okay.
This is literally the end of an era.
Um,
I can't even say he's arguably the
greatest feature act of all time.
He is the greatest feature
act of all time. And A,
we want to thank him all the headliners
in this country for his dedicated
service in the, uh, feature
position for all of these years. Um,
he stayed there longer than he had
then he had to kind of like a blue chip
prospect in college sports who leaves
after his freshman or sophomore year.
Joe is like the Tim
Duncan of feature acts.
He did all four years and this
is his farewell performance. Um,
of course he's going to get even
more dressed up than usual. Uh,
which usually is the one thing
that if I could criticize him,
it's the way he always out
dresses me as a feature. But um,
he always pulls back the
reins on his talent, you know,
because he chooses what's good for the
show over what's good for Joey roses.
Okay. And that's why he's the,
he's the greatest of all time.
He did things in the feature position
that have never been done before and a,
and in the opening.
Okay.
And the opening slot is Sean Pat and
one of my favorite new comics out there.
It's going to be a great show.
All of us have drinking problems.
So we'll be at the bar afterwards.
Please come by and say hello,
but don't overstay your welcome,
if you know what I'm saying. Right.
Come by little fucking high five,
get a picture with Joey roses on
his final performance and then move.
Keep it moving.
All right.
Unless there's somebody there that's
going to show us the tits. Okay.
I think that that's reasonable.
I think that's a nice little zone
that we can exist in. Can't we? Um,
then the comedy zone in
Jacksonville, Florida. Okay.
I have never been here before.
If this is literally carved in the side
of a fucking barn right next to a check
cashing store,
it will not surprise me.
I'm really looking forward to
seeing what human beings look like.
Like what if you were gonna say like
Jacksonville, Florida, you know,
you got a cities, you
got B cities, c cities.
Like where would you put that?
You know what I mean?
That was like the other day I was
talking to a, I was talking to somebody.
Okay.
And we were talking about this guy who
was dumb but wasn't mentally challenged.
And I basically said, yeah, he
got the f brain is basically it.
That was my way of saying that, you
know, there's nothing wrong with them.
He just got, you know, there's
the a brain, the bee brain,
okay.
The sea, like the brain
would be fucking, you know,
Bill Gates and those types
of guys. Einstein, you get,
you get the deal, right?
It's just like writing a paper. You
get the f brain, you know, you failed,
you failed at life. There's nothing
technically wrong with your brain.
You know what, it's like a car, you know,
like when they had the z 28 but they also
had like the rally sport with like a v
six engine and no air conditioning.
You've got the brain version of that.
All right,
so I'm going into a city.
I wouldn't even, I, when I
say Jacksonville's an F, I
wouldn't say an EP. I was,
it's a d, it's a fucking day. All
right, and you people in Jacksonville,
if you fucking offended by this,
come out to the show.
And I will give you the floor.
I will give you a minute during my show
to stand up like it's a town meeting and
I want you to defend your fucking city
and tell me why it deserves a better
grade than a d.
All right.
If you can tell me why
you're better than Tampa.
Yeah.
You know, at the end of the day to
use that overused expression, um,
I'm going to be in all of these cities so
I'm not above them. You see that? That's
me pretending like I'm being humble and
down to earth right now. Hey, can I,
can I talk to you guys
about that right now?
Not being humble or pretending to
be humble, kind of, uh, the fucking,
the amount of hacky shit
that's on the Internet,
like on Twitter that somebody comes up
with something and everybody dives on it,
you know,
like when people do that,
that,
that feeling when those tweets.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
Like why,
why would you think when you like the
90th fucking person to do it in a last
minute? That that's still fucking
cool. The shaking my head.
Okay.
You know,
just a bunch of fucking hacks and then
they'll turn around and criticize movies
and Shit, you know, or a guy like
kid rock. What's wrong with people?
Alright. Oh, full of shit. Huh?
A hypocritical bill. That's it.
I'm done. Go fuck yourselves. Have
a great week on all the podcasts.
Was a little wait late today,
but uh, you know, it's a day off.
Stop acting like you were in your cubicle.
You weren't doing shit to you today.
Right? Football season
starts. Who Do you like?
Jesus, I can't end this
podcast. I got to tell you this.
I have fucking issue with
the quarterback on my team.
All right. I saw something very
disturbing that started to, you know,
to start this season and it had nothing
to do with the horrific pass protection
that I've seen in the pre season.
It has to do with a particular quarterback
on the cover of this magazine with a
Doberman pincher and
the Dobermans growling.
And he's also going like,
ah, like the dog too. And uh,
it's just,
it's just not a good look.
I remember there was a time when this
particular individual said, you know,
I'm not into commercials in that I just
want to win championships and now I'm
looking at this guy with
his perfect teen idols,
stubble on the cover of the
magazine as if he said, hey,
I have a shoot on Tuesday.
What Day should I stop shaving?
Um, I dunno. I'm hoping if I do this,
this'll be like the reverse jinx will
this will actually make them win a
Superbowl this year.
Okay.
Because we won that thing last year in
fucking choked it away and it's still
bugs me.
We had that fucking game one
we had at one and we fucking
choked it away. Actually,
I can't say choked it away cause that's
takes away from the giants victory.
I'll say this is what it is. We had the
opportunity to win the game and choked.
They then had the opportunity to win
the game and did not. They delivered.
We did not. All right, so I don't
know what the fuck we're on.
Magazine covers for ground
with dogs for when we came in.
Second doesn't make sense
to me. I don't, you know,
it's like back in the day when I used
to watch Peyton Manning, you know,
lose another fucking playoff game.
And next thing you know,
he's driving down fucking street in a
pacer, waving at a camera, you know,
with a Gillette razor in his hand.
I don't fucking understand that.
Really build with 20 minutes of
fucking advertising on your podcast.
You don't get it. You'd dump
content. Alright, I'm RDF Sia.