Hey, what's going on? Is Bill Burn? It's
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
November. No, sorry. December,
December. Sorry. Sorry about that.
December 15th, 2014 sure. Some new
fucking uploaded the rule.
Big Fail.
Okay.
What a fucking loser,
man.
You Internet comments
just up your fucking ass.
All the God damn time.
You know it's some fucking very rarely.
Very rarely do too.
Why ever block anybody on Twitter?
Just because I don't want to give people
the satisfaction that they bugged me
and this technology
fucking cunt bugged me.
He bought, you know what I
am? What am I an asshole?
How long have I been
in this Internet game?
I'm going to tell you
what the fuck he said.
I'm not going to tell you what he said.
Go Fuck Yourself.
So could you guys all warming up your
fucking little Flan. Geez. There to go.
Send me a fucking tweet. I know
what the Flange, these tassels,
metatarsal flange. Geez,
that's on your feet. Right?
And then carpals metacarpals Phalanges.
Remember that when you took biology class
and they talked about the bio juices,
whatever the fuck they did.
No,
the whole place cause I have to tell
your respiratory system, the respiratory,
so still this massive data
scientists for centuries.
Um Oh God.
Did that bring back some fucking bad
goddamn there anything good about am I
think one of my science
classes is that like,
you know with the books back in the day
you had to sign your name, right? Yeah.
In the year you had the books,
so then you get books, you know,
and he knows somebody in the grade above.
You got your old math book right.
Y'All ain't good about my science class
was I got the same book is the hottest
chick, two grades in
front of me, you know,
so it was just sitting back there with
my orange hair, not even listening,
just to be like,
she actually hold this book.
Oh my God.
That was the old thing and
enjoyable about science class.
What's funny now is I,
I love science.
I love fucking science.
The sound of the shit,
the fucking crappy ozone layer
was that I love a parade.
How simple his life back then
when you could just write a song,
you could write a song like that.
First of all,
no one would even question your sexuality,
right?
You could just fucking rattle one of
those off little sound with the beat.
The fucking trumpets.
I come walking by [inaudible]
who didn't love a fucking parade?
What else were you doing?
Okay.
Standing around.
Going out and shooting the
fucking varmint, dragging it in,
carrying it by its fucking tail.
Fucking wife for their huge dress goes
all the way down to her ankles and up to
her fucking chin,
you know,
to look at where were
all the horse back then?
It's not me.
That was a brothel.
Okay.
And what? What did you fucking,
what'd you rub one out too?
He imagined by a new horse,
right?
Is that what you have
those no celebrities.
What the fuck did you do back all
you gotta do you just fucking,
we're trying to live,
you know?
Yeah. Don't worry about the fucking native
Americans coming back to take what was
rightfully theirs.
Okay.
Okay. And I can guarantee you
when they came over the hill,
the lasting they were doing was gone.
Oh,
they didn't.
Those fucking things,
those fucking takes those,
you know,
as I was already trying to think
of the animal to compare to. Sorry,
didn't mean didn't mean to offend
any casino owners out there.
Those fucking people.
Okay.
Yeah, you had no idea. Remember that
step fucking line and good fellas.
The second I heard all that noise. I knew
they were cops if they were wise guys.
And when you shut the fuck up.
Okay.
They were native Americans.
You'd be fucking hanging upside down by
a tree right above your Cadillac before
you put the keys in the ignition.
You'd have no fucking idea.
And then they'd slowly skin you alive.
A breaky on the wheel. All right,
Henry Hill. Um, Daniel, what
the fuck I'm talking about?
Ah, whatever. This fucking
technology content, you know,
it's like all you douchebags last,
last week when I was calling iclouds
soundcloud and you guys thought it was
fucking hilarious.
I actually was proud of the fact that,
I don't know what the fuck it's called.
You know?
Is that your big fucking claim to fame?
All you fucking douchebag.
Ellie's none at all. You just said
small. They just, you guys live.
Yeah,
you get on the few Staci. Let me
tell you something. All right,
you middle of nowhere.
Fucking staring at a computer screen.
Can't you go start a podcast? You riff
for a fucking hour and 20 minutes.
All right?
You're gonna make some mistakes.
Half the time you're trying to think what
the fuck am I going to talk about next
door and say I was talking to Joe Rosa.
We did an uninformed,
I was all excited about those Mercedes
Benz that I checked out and all that shit
and I, I fucked up. I was talking
about a wagon. How's that?
Is four or a coop or whatever.
This fucking guy.
All capital letters.
Freaking the fuck out because they
said four door coupe instead of sedan.
Did your too
woo woo woo fucking fell. Oh,
you know what it is.
What I shouldn't do is I shouldn't
get upset by that nick pick and stuff.
What I should really do is read between
the lines and see the misery of that
person's life that they just
live for that fucking moment.
Sitting around, listening to a God
damn podcast, waiting for somebody,
some uneducated asshole to
fuck up so you can write in
right
and feel better about the
all weather carpet underneath
your fucking hammer toes.
I know it's the holiday season.
Dolby,
Dolby doe and school Billy Bob.
Stick it up. Your dms guys regard.
We'll do the Christmas wreath or,
yeah,
he's got a red fucking shoe,
which some cotton glued to it.
He probably 23 is that the worst one?
They get the fucking awful Santa
Claus. It's like, can you even try?
I mean it's a fucking woman.
Okay.
She's got blush on, you know,
you'd make a great Santa Claus,
Tom Kauflin or the New York giants.
That guy would make a great Santa Claus
because Santa clause is not obese.
He was considered a fat fuck
when I was a kid. That's how,
that's how fucked up my country is right
now. That's how out of shape we are.
Dead like a,
what's his face like?
A Santa Claus isn't really considered
fat anymore. What would you call them?
Husky. If he had to go buy a new one, a
new red suit by, when would he get that?
Okay.
He probably does it sometime in
the fucking summer. Like, ah,
I gotta do this fucking shit again.
You know,
he takes off like January to May and
then in June or start stretching out the
old hammies.
I gotta get him another fucking sued
Jesus Christ can have that shut up.
Lady arrived.
I'm second a fucking out.
If they make the same God damn
day every day, every fucking year.
Save God damn show. All right, so
what does he do? He shaves the beard.
He gets a fucking hair cut.
He rolls down to fucking Tom Ford gets
himself a fitted red suit, you know,
but they don't think he sees a fatty.
Okay.
You know,
that's how fucked up it at this point.
Like that guy would be considered like a,
not even a cruiserweight if
he boxed db like welterweight.
And despite the fact that he has a sleigh
that can fly around the fucking world,
your average fat fuck sitting in a
Taco bell could beat him in a fucking
fistfight matter. How Nimble he is now.
Much omics.
Christmas does t sprinkled on
his fucking Jerry Garcia haircut.
They'd just be some of
Shit is leaning on him.
Yeah.
Lean in on just wearing
them down round after round.
Just keeping that one fucking
keeping that arm up. You know,
left keeping the left up. Just covering
this fucking big Ted Kennedy Fed.
Fuckhead leaning on Santa Santa
is work in the fucking body.
Okay.
All right.
Old Tub is just eating him up.
Fucking lean and on Santa loses his hat
halfway through the first round gets in
the corner, right. Takes off his jacket.
He's got some stayed wife beater
on the Fat Fox and you know,
doing the Ali thing, he
doesn't, I don't need and share
it. I'm already know. Right.
He's just walking standing in the corner.
Right.
They already got that fucking cold
compress right on fucking San his face.
Okay.
I think when I'm talking about,
all right.
All I know is this Christmas and we're
like fucking 10 days away and I haven't
even fucking,
oh, you know, Dasher and dancer and
Prancer and victim. No, I don't, don't,
I was standing there. He ain't giving
it to dose, make comment and Cupid.
Donna red bled sin.
But do you recall,
Oh man, what'd you shoot a reindeer.
What'd you shoot a reindeer?
What'd you do with what if your plane
crashed up near the North Pole? You know,
there it was. You couldn't shoot fucking
Rudolph. That's like shooting Elvis.
You can't do that shit.
You gotta wait for him to Odey Odey
sitting on the fucking reindeer toilet,
which is basically what
any words standing.
Okay.
You know, I'm so fucking against
technology. People are just, I've had it.
I just fucking,
I know all the shit that it does for you
and how convenient it makes it and all
of that bullshit. Oh, by the way, you
know, piss me off. I was watching this,
the fucking commercial where they
talk about like the first, uh,
you know how the first half time came
about was basically people, you know,
these fucking, you know, racist
white guys. I mean, you know,
they were back then, right?
Jesus Christ the fuck.
Hmm.
Anybody in a striped fucking uniform
with no face mask. I mean he,
you could only imagine what was coming
out or red Granger's miles back in the
day.
The Gallup and ghost straight.
So they got this commercial where it's
like supposed to be that era and these
guys are playing football and then
talking about how the first half time came
around and basically how it came around
was these guys were playing and a bunch
of fucking ladies came by with some pop.
They came by with like some coke or
whatever, the f Pepsi of Fucking,
I don't know what tab.
I don't know what they brought.
Okay.
The whole fucking thing is, you
know, it's just a metaphor, right?
It's like you're a guy, you're on point,
you have a fucking goal and what happens?
Pussy walks in the room and
everything gets thrown to the wayside.
And next thing you know, you're 53 going,
wait a minute. What the fuck happened? Ah,
I want it to be an astronaut. Hi. I
wanted to learn how to play the Tuba.
I wanted to own a fucking hair salon.
What happened?
Plus he came in the wrong,
you took your eye off the ball
and you started drinking some pop.
I ain't know.
They say that in the Midwest in fact,
that they call it pop and then they
say, pop, you want some pap? No.
Do you have any soda? Soda? What's that?
I can't do a Midwest accent.
As you can see,
I've gotta be out there hanging
around with those cons. Um, hang on.
I just remind me of something about
the southern tour I want to do next.
Fucking I type that in. So I
write them st later. Anyways,
so long story short,
because the women's show up,
these guys who are fucking knocking
the hell out of each other,
basically inventing the NFL,
they stop
and they look at each other and
like, hey, you know, maybe uh,
one of them will give us a one of them
fucking 23 is good news over there.
What he say? What did we just knock off
for like 15 minutes to go over there?
A sprite? You know, the guy's
like, what the fuck's is
sprite? It doesn't exist yet.
Douche bag. So, all right, let's get a
coke. It has got to be Coca Cola, right?
What was that? The first one?
And they went over there. I mean,
the original Coca Cola had a little
bit of blowing it. Next thing you know,
they're dumping it down her ass crack,
right?
The whole fucking gang
goes out the window.
But that's not the problem that
I have with that commercial.
The problem I have is in the middle of it,
somebody takes an old timey camera,
turns it around on them and does a selfie.
Now I know the people
who made that commercial.
I'm going to give him the credit
to be like, they realize that no,
we took a fucking selfie back then.
Okay. No, we took a fucking selfie.
Not only did you not take a Selfie,
nobody smiled and photos back then.
I don't know when the fuck that started,
but if you look back in the day,
nobody is smiling in photos unless
you caught him off guard. Okay?
They're doing a little Jig or some shit.
And you took a picture
with that fucking cannon.
That fucking gunpowder fucking went up.
Sorry for everybody's ears here.
I didn't realize it
was gonna be that loud.
Fucking would go off in the background.
Right?
Okay.
And then you know that. Then the guy be
like, you just take my fucking texture.
Okay.
Yeah.
What's all the smoke in there for?
Do you keep that fucking witchcraft
away from me, buddy? All right.
Nobody fucking smile.
You understand?
When they took pictures
of the native Americans.
The reason why they didn't smile,
they all fucking world was going to a
help than a fucking hand basket by a bunch
of fucking Douche bags
whose ancestors were eventually going to
walk around wearing those fucking beats
by Dre,
which aren't even that good ad folks.
Oh, now they're wireless. Tell you what,
fuck the technology making them
fucking no invisible wires.
Why don't you make them good?
So somebody gave me, I got a fucking
pair of those goddamn things.
I was listening to a fuck fucking
year and I finally just sat around.
Any of these things aren't that good.
I can hear the music,
but it's not blowing my mind.
Okay?
You know what beats by Dre or,
and this isn't against Dr Dre
cause he already sold the company.
He's sitting on $1 billion. Think he
gives a fuck. He doesn't give a fuck.
Plus I never fucking trash anybody.
He's got a scar on the neck. Okay,
that guy saw death stare
it down one and then what?
I'm going to come at him with. Where
am I fucking PJ's? I don't think so.
All right.
And if you think I'm the kind of guy
who's going to do something like that,
you're listening to the wrong
power podcast, my friend. Okay.
Um, anyways, this is the Monday morning
podcast and it's 10 days before Christmas.
Don't, whoa. Who wouldn't go?
Yo Paul who wouldn't go all up
on the house top click, click,
click down through the chimney with
those Saint Nick gonna. Fuck that.
I remember that one.
Just trying to sing when different,
you know what fucking Christmas song.
I absolutely is a bunch
of them that I don't like,
but the one that just really would
wear on me with silver bells,
silver bowels sale verb or a Raga
in and around the Christmas tree.
I am white and I'm giving it a shot.
Um,
Bob in my head,
like a fucking end dose.
Where in this title suit.
Oh,
the missile total shoved up.
Yolo fucking plot. This is the,
this is when the guy scant sang it,
you know,
and he was just trying to feel out some
words. You know what? We'll put Christmas,
he shit in there. Let's just jam with
the band, right? Well to psalm body suck.
My Dick bought up beat by dude.
Oh Emmalie right.
That's probably what they did right
down there at capitol records.
We have a melody. If you could just
sort of riff on it, Dag and do that
jingle bells, jingle bells
jangled and down the street yet,
but bad in Edd. I got a
friend named Pete. Oh,
something Christmas. Get her a gift.
Maybe they don't shut her the fuck up.
That's how am I feeling it today
guys? Shut down. Shut down.
Um, all right. It's
probably, Oh, you know what?
It is time to do some advertising and
the most important advertising than I do
all year. So listen up everybody.
All right, listen up everybody.
The third annual,
Patrice O'neil,
um, comedy benefit. All
right, it's coming up on.
Let me get everything.
Third Annual Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit
and you want to do something great.
Okay. That really, I'm not going to
bullshit for the bottom of my heart.
This has been such a great benefit and
has helped so many people that Patrice
loved in his life. You know that he was
taken care of and all that type of stuff.
This is just a wonderful,
it's my favorite thing all year.
I get to see all these great comics that
I never get to see cause we're always
traveling around. It's the third annual
Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit, uh,
Wednesday,
February 11th,
2015 and it's going to be at 7:00 PM at
the city center where we always have at
one 31 west, 55th street between
sixth and Seventh Av. Uh,
the lineup will be Ben Bailey,
Ben Bailey Boulevard.
Um, one of my great friends
in this business probably
done 9,000 shows with him.
Cash cabs. Ben Bailey is all
alphabetical order. Colin Quinn,
Dave Attell,
the Great David tell a Hannibal Burress,
Jim Florentine jme know,
and Michael Che Snls,
Michael Che and rich Vos and myself.
Yours truly,
you know, comics is so I got to fucking
give a credit for all of them. All right.
Snls Michael Che, be in
Jimmy's, Jim, uh, Jim Norton.
Okay.
A cranky acres and, uh, that metal show,
Jim Florentine Creator have to fucking
shows that have made it onto the air.
Strasnick practically impossible animal.
Boris, the man of destroyed bill Cosby.
I'm fucking with the animal. Uh, he
didn't, the person in the crowd did.
Okay.
Sick of that shit.
Comics tell a fucking joke.
Somebody records it and then they got,
they talk to the fucking comic about it.
I didn't say that shit to you.
I sent it to the people in the crowd.
I told a joke and a comedy
club not on a news program.
You've brought the wrong
person here on splitscreen. Um,
legendary.
Colin Quinn,
tough crowd SNL one man shows on Broadway.
Okay.
This man is leaving his
dressing room on Broadway.
Okay.
He's leaving the Charles Nelson
Reilly suite to go do this.
Taking time out of his schedule. Um,
it's going to be fucking awesome.
It's great. Every year. Uh,
if you want to get tickets,
you can get them online at New York
City's center.org or over the phone by
calling city tickets to one, two,
five, eight one, one two, one, two.
Once again, it's two, one, two,
five, eight, one, one, two, one, two.
If you live anywhere in New York City,
you want to see one of the best comedy
shows of the year that also all the
proceeds other than we got to pay to rent
the fucking building. Other than that,
they all go to, this is all,
this is above the board.
There'll be no pick microphones,
no mustaches grown now support the troops
and then I keep all the fucking money.
None of that shit. All right?
Everybody's donating their time. This is,
it makes a great Christmas gift and a,
it's the best money you ever going to
spend. It's such a great thing to do.
Absolutely love doing this. And
I thank all the Comedians, um,
over the years that have done this and
we're just going to keep expanding it.
And I learned this year that I love that
Michael Che and Hannibal Burress are on
it because now we've got some younger
guys that were actually influenced by
Patrice has comedy. If you
don't know who he is. Um,
I'm actually jealous because now you're
going to get to discover the funniest
fucking guy I ever met. Elephant
in the room. Download that.
Please do all of this legally.
Uh,
so that the money goes to the
people he cares about. Um, is great,
wonderful. A CD, whatever
you kids call it now,
downloadable fucking CD
laser disc thing. Mr P, uh,
so funniest fucking guy I haven't met.
He's the best comedian I ever saw.
And uh,
if he was still alive,
I would have chased him my whole career
and I never would have caught up and he
would have just continued to widen the
gap. I mean, he just was the fucking man.
So please,
for the love of God,
we've got a couple hundred
tickets left and, uh,
makes a great stocking
stuffer. Um, all right,
let's get to the fucking corporate ones.
Were all Billy whore bag reads these
things? Oh my God, look what's back.
Everybody had Sherry's berries.
Oh,
it's gotta be a holiday coming up.
Don't get you tinsel in a tangle.
There's more than one way to get
your shopping for the holidays done.
So don't get your tensile in a tangle.
You already said that you don't have
to get burned out with the crowds.
Instead shop with the convenience right
from your home. Christmas is next week.
You'd dumb bastards with only in certain
number of days left until Christmas.
I got to do math now. There's 10
days left. Everybody does that.
Make him fucking nervous enough to
buy chocolate, strawberries, um,
rapid and deliver your, uh, 10
days left till wrap to shop,
wrap and deliver your gifts.
Give this incredible delicious gift and
skip the crowds all together by Sherry's
berries in seconds,
freshly dipped strawberries from
Sherry's berries starting at 1999.
That's over a 40% savings.
How the fuck would we know that as
that when you watch the stock market,
fucking ticker tape chocolate covered,
berries it down or double the
berries for just $10 more.
You just need my code to take advantage
of this deal. Burp. You are our,
I know I always make fun of these people,
but everybody I know who's ever gotten
these things say they're fucking
delicious. Um, additional copy points.
I'm not supposed to read
these types of things,
but I know you guys like behind
the scenes shit. All right. Uh,
describe the berries in your
own words. Decadent, fresh,
juicy, sweet and irresistible. I'm
supposed to use one of those. Oh my God.
These fresh, juicy, sweet,
decadent berries are irresistible.
Choose Barry's dipped in tempting
white milk chocolate or dark chocolate.
He goodness. Talked with Eagle or
you can go a, you get a little,
a little mix and match. Go a little
interracial with this fucking berries.
There are,
let's get to the Antioch.
Visit berries.com please spell out the
word berries. What do you think this is?
Stupid.
B E R R I e s.com.
Click on the microphone in the top right
hand corner and typing bur bur it's the
perfect gift without the hassle,
man. Go to Barry's dot com.
Click on the microphone and
type and burpee. You are
order them today. It's great.
It's quick. It's easy. Maybe
there's some chick down the hall.
You want to bang us some fucking
chocolate covered strawberries.
Get that nine and a half weeks, then
going, then you bang her in the kitchen.
You know as you pour buttermilk all over.
Um,
draftkings.com everybody,
the list of millionaires
crown@draftkings.com this
football season keeps on
growing and you know what?
You could be next but you're never going
to be next if you don't step up and
play draft kings as America's favorite
one week fantasy football site where you
can win instant cash every week.
And that beauty of the one week fantasy
is you can play whenever you want.
Every week.
Like is like a brand new season.
It takes watching football for that man
right there to take it to a whole new
level. You're a season long fantasy
team might be missing the playoffs,
but the excitement begins
again each week at draft kings.
Pick your team and minutes and enormous
cash prizes could be yours or you could
lose your shirt. I mean it
is gambling. True Story.
One player turned 10 bucks into five
grand and other turn two bucks into 10,000
another guy lost his rent money.
It's all how you play the game.
A new millionaire has been made nearly
every week this season@draftkings.com
you, uh, you got to get
in on this call to action.
Head over to draft kings.com right
now and use the Promo code defense.
There's no c in defense. Why, by the way,
you're dummies. It's d e f. E. N. S. E.
I was really talking to myself to play
free and the $10 million fantasy football
world championships, draftkings.com
bigger events, bigger winnings, bigger,
a million hands right there,
and a defense@draftkings.com
draftkings.com that's
draft kings done com.
All right. He voice. All right. I love
the flexibility that, oh, that, um,
of owning my own personal business.
Evidently, uh, look at me.
I've created an empire with this show.
But when it comes to handling business
calls, just stuck with the challenge.
Either you've got to hire a full time
receptionist is gonna be bitching,
moaning and complaining,
and then you need stuff to chair.
Do I get any benefits?
Or you can handle all your kills yourself.
It's a lose lose. And you
sound like a jackass, right?
That's why I love your voice. I love the
idea of it, man. This is great. Listen,
bikes is what they do.
They will set up your business with
a toll free number or a local number.
When your customers call, they're
greeted professionally, excuse me,
hiccups professionally by a virtual
receptionist that will route or route.
Depending on where you live,
all your calls to wherever you are.
There's even a dial by name directory.
You'll sound like a fortune 500 company,
and more importantly, you'll never
miss an important call ever again.
All 413 bucks a month. I wonder if
drug dealers ever use this shit.
I'm right now for a limited time.
My listeners can try.
He voice for free at six for 60 days.
Seriously,
my list is get an extended 60 day trial
to test drive this amazing business tool.
That's right, 60 days. Just for our
listeners to use this business tool,
go to [inaudible] dot com slash bill
now to sign up, set up your eve voice.
I'm 60 day extended free trial.
Now he voice.com/bill.
That's he voiced.com. Slash Bill.
What do we had a hearing? Um,
all right,
back to the podcast,
back to the fucking podcast where the
folks to fucking put kiss you scared were
include. Um, all right,
what am I going to talk about here?
Uh, where do we go? Where do we owe,
you know what? I had an acting Gig, uh,
this past week and on Friday I got to
work with an actor named Brad Carter,
who you guys have seen in a zillion
things. And I was actually imitating him,
uh, back in the day when true detective
came out and he played that inmate,
you know, when a Matthew mcconaughey
character goes into the guy,
went Reggie to do
regiment, do, do dat shit,
fucking unbelievable actor.
And next thing you know,
old freckles gets an acting gig.
And who am I sitting across
from this same fucking dude?
And he was so God damn funny
and scary at the same time,
all while eating Bologna sandwiches.
That's all I can tell you about it. Uh,
but my face still hurts from trying
not to fucking blow takes, uh,
you know, laughing cause he's such
an end. He always played like,
like character actors are amazing
to me. Like, uh, they just,
how they make a living and how much
they have to hustle and all that.
And he was talking about how excited he
was to do something that was, you know,
had a comedy background
and now he's always playing
these psychos and everything.
So we're on like whatever the 10th take.
He's on like his fucking ninth fucking
Bologna Sandwich cause he feels like he
has to eat it to get into this character,
which is totally fucking working. Right.
And I, we ended up
asking him, uh, he said,
he mentioned he had to be on set the
very next day at 7:00 AM and we're still
shooting it like fucking 10
at night trying to get this
fucking dog to walk into
the room, sit down and look over at the
camera. Right. And he says, hi. He goes,
I got to be on set tomorrow at
seven. I'm like, Jesus Christ,
I don't know how you'd do it. He
goes, no, I'm loving. I love it, man.
I'm happy to be working. So he's talking
about how, oh, we always play psychos.
I go, Whoa, what do you, what are
you playing tomorrow? And he goes,
I'm playing a rape.
Okay.
In
a independent movie called eat me.
Um,
that's what the debt is being made
right now. So look out for Brad Carter.
He shooting eat meat right now and a
watch true detective and look them up.
He also, um, had brain surgery and uh,
for this little thing that he had
going on, I'll let him explain it,
but this is unbelievable video
where he's playing guitar.
He's a musician while they're checking
out his brain to see if they put the
thing in the right place, it's
fucking unbelievable. We'll,
we'll upload it. But, uh,
you know,
if you really like character actors and
people just disappear into it to the
point you want you to go. And where
the fuck do I know this guy? Wait, no,
I fucked Dorthy and Brad Carter.
That shit man, right there. Um,
so anyways,
let's,
let's get onto some shit here
that I'm really excited about.
I know that I've been bitching.
I know that I've been moaning.
I know that I'd been bitch moaning and
complaining the whole time about this
construction downstairs. Guess
what? Everybody, it's fucking done.
The motherfucker is done.
There's a couple of little knickknacks.
They get a stick in these fucking, I
dunno, the plates over the light switches.
Little Bullshit,
like that little fucking bullshit
like that and it fucking awesome.
Absolutely beautiful. Absolutely
gorgeous. It costs me a fucking fortune.
I will never make my
money back in this house.
And I say go vegan right now
and try to live to be 106,
but I've just made the decision that I'm
not leaving. I'm not fucking leaving,
right.
Just all the cons.
I'm erasing all the fucking
cops who have lived here. Um,
exercise and the demons of every one
of these motherfuckers that went cheap.
You know, I got this ugly ass. Fuck. I
don't know. There's like, there's no,
I don't know what to tell you what the
color is of the rug and the bedroom that
I'm in right now. So
I'm thinking, you know,
there's hardwood floors
underneath this fucking thing.
So I started to pull back the rug,
you know,
for a future project and guess what's
under the rug? Fucking plywood.
And underneath the plywood is
the original hardwood floors.
What kind of a fucking animal?
You know what it was?
It was probably done in the 70s you know,
when wall to wall carpet was
just considered so fucking plush.
What it was is after years of
people just walking around on ward,
first it was dark, right? Was
probably stone or some shit, right?
He lived in a fucking cave and then you
just had stone in the fucking shit was
cold. Nobody could afford rugs,
right? It's expensive or whatever.
Your wife started net and one
by the time she finished it,
she had tuberculosis and she died.
And every time he looked at the rug,
he thought of her. She gave it to
somebody else. So people's feet,
they were sick of being
cold. They get, you know,
getting splinters and that type of
shit, which, you know, buy it back.
Then you got an infection,
then you fucking died or somebody
came in and saw your foot off. Right.
Is he had a fucking know you bit down on
a fucking angel, whatever that happened
because there was no anesthesia.
So after centuries of that bullshit wall
to wall carpeting seemed like a good
idea, you know? And uh,
it wasn't,
you know,
what's the most disgusting thing when it
comes to copywriting is carpeting in a
bathroom every once in a while.
Right? I like, you know, you,
when they have like an open house,
I'm one of those constant just walks into
your house and I'm not going to buy it
cause I just want to look at it and get
ideas and just see how's this fucking
douche limit. Right. It's like
when you go to Elvis's house,
he always felt like a creep.
You know,
you've got to Elvis's house and you
want to go in there and laugh at him.
Then you walk in and you
realize this was his home,
and I'm walking around looking for peanut
butter and banana sandwiches because I
want to laugh at this guy and it's
just like sky accomplished more than a
weekend than I ever did in my life.
And he's buried in the backyard and we
just won't give the guy at the piece that
he deserves that even spell his
fucking name right in the grave.
One of the most exploited stars of all
fucking time. He'd go across the street,
does it gift shop,
and they turned them into a cuckoo clock
and a fucking coffee strainer and every
fucking filter, every God damn fucking
thing you can think of with Elvis on it.
You know, this is an Elvis fan.
There's nothing Elvis about that.
Press the button. Ooh, Yay. Hi.
Just start singing a song.
They paid little mutton chops
on the fucking fan blades.
So anyways, every once in a while
you'd go and do an old house
and you know what's up?
My favorite thing that,
see when you walk into an old house and
you smell an old person, you know like,
oh my God,
this shit be going to see shit
in here from the 1950s right.
And you walk in there and you see like
the old kitchen and the old bathrooms and
all that,
and you just see all the errors of
styles that the house is fucking lived
through.
You know,
that fucking lime green toilet seat cover
or the plastic cracked fucking toilet
seat itself. You know, where they made it,
like that squishy shit that was supposed
to be comfortable and then it cracked
after a while and then they would
just have wall to wall carpeting.
And you just sit there looking at
it. Good. Oh my God. The fucking
health department.
Like how many restaurants?
I mean if you had that in any
restaurant, like, like the 10,
any restaurant within a fucking five mile
vicinity would be fucking shut down to
have carpeting in a fucking bathroom.
Absolutely disgusting. So anyways,
um,
so what I love about the downstairs
now is it's fucking, it's level,
it's clean,
everything works.
It's just fucking awesome and it's
right in time for the fucking holidays.
And I'm, I'm thrilled. I'm thrilled
with it. You know, it's funny,
as the guy who sold me this house, he
keeps calling me up every once in a while,
right? In know they do the call you
up like a fucking old girlfriend.
They can just feel you're
starting to love your house.
So they got to put that doubt in your
head day bill. Are you doing? Yeah.
Tell you it's a great time,
great time to get right back out there
and fucking start all over again.
You know,
the great thing is when you invest so
much in your house that you never going to
make any money off of it. You don't
give a fuck anymore. You're like, well,
I'm never leaving.
I'm gonna Redo this whole fucking thing.
Let me see if I can go broke on
this fucking thing. So, um, anyways,
you won't hear me bitching
about it anymore. Um,
it's done. And now that it's done,
it looks fucking gorgeous and, uh,
it was worth every,
every cent of it.
And your next question is going to be
built and we see pictures of it and no you
cannot. No you can't.
What are you an asshole?
Showing the pictures of the inside of my
fucking house isn't enough that I'm in
my house talking to you.
Fucking creep. Um, anyways.
Yay.
Look who she just walked
in all needy face.
Why don't you grab a, grab a
microphone, set up the old chord there.
Um, see what I wanted to talk
about. Anything here. Oh,
by the way,
as a new England Patriot Fan,
I am so fucking jealous of the
Seattle Seahawks defense man.
They just look fucking great.
And I'll tell you right,
I made fun of Pete Carroll for
years and uh, I was never more raw.
I mean, I, I never thought that he
was a bad coach or anything like that,
but that fucking guy is going to go.
He already,
he's,
he's one of two people who ever won a
Ncaa Division One championship in football
and also on the Superbowl. The other
guy was Barry Switzer, but you know,
no disrespect to Barry, he's a great
coach and all that type of shit. But he,
he won with Jimmy Johnson's team.
All right. Pete Carroll, you know,
you know what happened? The NCAA
was, the wolf was at the back door.
He got the fuck out of there.
And uh, he went up there.
What was Seattle at that point?
They were not thing. And uh,
he's turned it around and he's right now.
What's your watch you Pete Carroll Do,
is one of the hardest fucking things you
can ever do is to have a team that won
the championship the year before,
come out and,
and somehow the next season
motivate them where they're hungry,
not they want to win it again. They
always want to win it again, but they,
they have a hunger in them,
it seems when you're watching,
like they haven't won it yet.
Like they still have something to prove.
And earlier this season,
I really look at Pete Carol
and Bill Bella check this year,
who was kind of the same thing where the
first six, five, six games or whatever,
they had to figure out what their team
was because every year people leave,
people come in,
it's a little bit different.
And I'm watching Pete Carroll do some
bill Bellacheck shit where it's like he
knows what he has,
he knows how to work it now he knows
it's thick though I don't know as much as
my patriots or 11 and three.
I feel like I still feel like
the level of play in the NFC, uh,
is, it's on, it's another level. Um,
I would never bet against, uh, you know,
Bella check and Brady if anybody
could figure out how to fucking,
I dunno. Seattle looks like
fucking world beaters man.
So my money's on them at this point.
They just look like
they look fucking unstoppable and uh,
their QB there, Wilson, that guy is,
uh, is that even his fucking
name? I was so god damn old.
I can't remember names anymore. That
fucking guy is the real deal. I, you know,
and all you kids out there
who are starting to say verse,
he might've been right about Mark Sanchez.
I cannot help you.
I can't help you.
Firs even texted me that don't I,
you know I might've met rant about this
guy. It's like Paul, you watched the,
first of all,
Paul Versey is not right.
Whether the guy's great or
whether he sticks Paul verse,
he said after the first three games of
a quarterback's career, guy's a star.
Like based on what Paul,
based on what?
Sitting at home watching front of
fucking TV, never talking to him.
Never seen him in the locker room get you.
You threw a fucking Hail Mary.
This is the deal was Sanchez. Okay.
I think he's a good quarterback.
I think he could win
the Superbowl with them,
but the defense has to be unfucking
believable. We're talking some,
I'm not saying he's a Trent Dilfer
it, he's beyond that guy. Okay.
But to sit there and act like
this guy is like on a Brady level,
a Peyton manning level like Tom
Brady paint man and guys like that.
And I even think there's Wilson guy
like could could get to that level.
Like those guys are so fucking good.
Even if you suck,
even if everybody around them
suck, you know, as a wide receiver,
if you come in there and you kind of
stank and everyone around you stinks and
all of a sudden you're the number one
receiver because everybody's stinks.
You still know you're getting a thousand
yards because Tom Brady or Peyton
Manning's giving you the fucking ball.
Sanchez is not at that level, all right?
That guy, if he has a great team,
he's great, and other words,
he'll win the fucking game but
won't fuck it up, all right?
But when people start to leave and,
and, and the talent level dips,
it's but fumble time,
okay.
And I did not see that ever with somebody.
You know the higher guys,
the Damn Marino's, the fucking Peyton
Manning's the Tom Brady's, okay?
So enough with this shit,
okay,
stop watching fucking football
week to week and going,
this guy is this and now he's this,
now he's dead. Go fuck yourselves.
All of you guys,
you guys can all go listen to the
fucking fuzzy effect and fucking rob,
do a circle jerk and pat yourselves on
the back with your horrific predictions.
I love you Paul. All right, Nia. Hi. Hey,
what's going on? You're here
just in time for the, um, for,
for getting into the, uh, the
questions. Perfect. I told him, boy,
let me turn this up here. Uh, I told them
how the downstairs is finally, right.
Uh, what do you mean? I mean, there's
a couple of things. Yeah, I know.
I told I'm not,
I cannot muster this endless enthusiasm
that you seem to have until it's done,
until it's 100% fucking done.
I know till every single little
piece is, is done. And you know what?
I went down there and there was a
couple of fucking things. I'm like,
that's the thing.
That's why I don't keep going down there.
So you keep going down there every day
and I understand that it's important to
check on it, but like, you're like Judah
has zero, zero, zero was like every day.
And it's like,
I can't go downstairs every day because
I will see a hundred things wrong with
it and I'm just, I'm, I'm giving them time
to do their thing, you know, I'm like,
hey, we're done. Then I can
look and be like, are you done?
Are you really done? Hey, I'm
Billy. Big Eyes, really big ass
billboard bar. I still haven't
seen your billboard in real life.
What do you want to see it? You
know what I'm saying? Yay. Oh,
don't be so modest. Well
that's a well, yeah.
What am I going to bring up a fucking
billboard on my own fucking podcast.
Well you didn't bring it up. I did. Hey,
by the way, very proud of you. Thank you.
I'm very proud of shut up.
Um, by the way, for you guys, like I
somehow I just like, I sent a link.
Do you really want to get people going
send any sort of link about global
warming? Like the people who
were, I don't think it exists.
Like they always say the same thing. They
go like, oh, looks blue. Fuck a Polaroid.
He always talking about the
ice age is age of the ice caps.
Well, you had the ice age and then
it all melted, right? Right. Yeah,
the dinosaurs and then what the fucking
ice age came and they died. Whatever our,
our fucking or hit whatever
it fucking happen. Right?
But while you sit there and look at it,
somebody who's fucking got
a lazy eye flow history,
the fucking plans gone from periods
warming up and cooling, right?
You're talking to like a
dentist, Jake, and he, and I'm
arguing and I'm a comedian.
This is like, this is, this is okay.
What they're talking about is the rate,
the unprecedented rate of
how fast it is heating up.
All right, here's another thing I just
saw is that, that's what the argument is.
Not whether or not the planet heats up and
cools down. Well, it's fucking history.
It's the unprecedented rate that it is
doing. Any, any, any, any alarming. Great.
Um, I almost said get that word out and
like, Hey, what are you talking about?
Even nobody knows me.
I'm trying to fill a fucking hour here.
There's over 5 trillion pieces of fucking
plastic estimated estimated over 5
trillion in the ocean. Okay. Yes. It's
terrible. I know I'm not talking to you.
I'm talking to a few people.
Give me shit about it.
I'll sit there and act and think that
we don't have like an effect on this
fucking planet.
Like do you know those places in the
United States where you just can't live
there because of whatever we put
in the ground, nuclear waste,
whatever shit and it's just you can't
fucking live there or you will die.
Nothing that is alive can live
there. It's just dead zones. Name,
name one other fucking animal.
I mean Gypsy Moss, Caterpillar.
This is the closest thing I can come from.
What Gypsy moth caterpillars.
Gypsy moth caterpillars. They come up and
real thing. Yeah. They just want, want,
want, want, want, want more.
Come on up from the South Wall.
Doesn't help me envision and the,
and they would just sit there and they
would eat up all the trees and stuff and
people would have to put like a little
piece of plastic around the tree guy.
You are talking about five different
things. What are you saying?
You were saying that you,
there are places that you can't live and
then you said there's a Ma except for
the math gypsy. Like they're the only
ones that can survive in these areas. No,
I'm saying name another animal.
That fucking affects the planet
the way we do at firstly. I,
yeah, I don't, I don't know. I am not a,
I'm a specialist in that area. Oh yeah.
You're missing the whole
point of this spot.
You're missing will not speculate on it.
You're missing the whole point
of the podcast. The holes.
What honey? The point is,
you don't know what you're talking
about, but to, you know, I mean me. Oh,
I don't know what I'm talking about.
I've seen when you come on the podcast,
you don't know what you're talking about,
but that by no means stops
you from pontificating.
True and throwing out
facts
that are facts in your world of
science and your world alone. Hang on.
I got to read two more advertisements
here and then we'll do the, uh,
we're going to do the
questions for Louie guard,
stamps.com everybody with
the holidays almost here,
you don't have time to
go to the post officer,
to the post office with all the traffic
and the parking and the old ladies and
then that do, she shows up
with 20 packages in front
of you. You don't need it.
Okay.
It's going to be packed with everyone
mailing out the holiday gifts and packages
there.
So do what I do.
You stamps.com instead with stamps.com
you could avoid all the hassles, man,
of going to the post office
during the busy holiday season.
Everything you would do
with the post office,
you can do right at home from your
own desk. All right, well, your bed,
wherever the hell you put the buy and
print official us postage using your own
computer and printer,
print postage for any letter or
package the instant you need it.
Then the mailmen picks it up.
So easy and convenient.
I use stamps.com to send
out all my posters. Uh,
I'm thinking of making a poster by
the way, for that Australian tour.
That's not how the fuck,
fuck.
I'm going to ship it over instead
of the God the planet. I don't know.
Maybe I'll do that, but if I do, I'm
going to use stamps.com and you know what?
When you send out your shit, you
should use stamps.com too. Right now.
Get this special offer when used them.
You want to use my last name?
[inaudible] B. U. R. R.
It's a no risk trial plus a $110 bonus
offer that includes a digital scale and
up to $55 free postage. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
you click on the microphone at the top
of the homepage and type in Berbee.
You are our,
that's stamps.com enter bar and lastly,
but certainly not leastly, man. Great.
Everybody attention grill masters
this holiday season dooby dooby do.
There's only one gift that is an
absolute must have the man. Great.
What's a man great.
You might've asked,
man grates are American made high
quality a hundred percent cast iron grill
grates that sit right on
top of your existing greats
weighing in at eight pounds
a piece man grates and shows that juicy
tender meat with no flare ups and a
perfect cmack every time man.
Grades Patented Design Delivered
Steakhouse Quality Flavor right at home.
Take advantage of the Monday morning
podcast special and get the man great for
just 1999 just head over to [inaudible]
dot com and enter the coupon code burpee
you are are at checkout also for a
limited time or to four grades and get the
fourth one for absolutely free
time is running out. Order today.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and enter a
coupon code bur bur at checkout to take
advantage of this exclusive
offer. Um, once again,
there are 100% American made a hundred
percent cast island iron there.
1999 special is limited time.
You can order Forman man grades and
get the fourth one for absolutely free.
Make sure to go to man,
great.com and enter our coupon
code [inaudible] at checkout. Uh,
to get this exclusive offer,
and that's all other than if
you're going to go to amazon.com,
go to [inaudible] dot com click on the
podcast page, you click on the link,
it takes you over there,
it doesn't cost you any more money,
and they kick a little money over to my
podcasts if you want to. If you don't,
I totally understand it. All right,
let's get to the content for this week.
All right. Aren't you worried about the
wonderful Patrice O'Neal benefit? Um, AMG,
Mercedes, Mercedes, and Mercedes is,
you know what AMG stands for?
American made great
Mercedes isn't, isn't
American? No, it's German.
So the a and the m is the last name
of two German dudes and the g is the
hometown of the guy with the last name
that begins with an a according to my two
seconds of research. And it's the
top of the line. Okay. Fucking like,
they already have a sick ass German
car and then it's like, you know,
but if they take it to the chairman
gas monkey garage and they kick it up a
notch car called the MG as well.
Yes, my dad had one of those.
That's not,
that's not the same company or
same no factory or nobody ever,
uh, mg, uh, was a,
was English is what it was. And they, uh,
these little two seater racecars yes,
they were.
And a lot of the American soldiers
got exposed to European cars, uh,
sports cars to cedars and that type
of Shit. Italian stuff in English,
stuff in German. Shit when a, no offense
to German people, German stuff when, uh,
they were when they were fighting
over fighting over in Europe.
And um,
so when they came back,
those cars sold over here like a EMG,
TD and the fucking triumphs and all
that shit in the Italian stuff. Um,
so anyways,
these guys,
I don't know if they just make the
best fucking cars anyways. Hey Bill,
just listen to your podcast.
When you talked about how much you
enjoyed your test drive of the AMG wagon,
the station wagon, which you just,
yeah, yeah. Now I know you love it,
but I'm just, I had
fucking bad ass. He goes,
I'm totally with you on the
sleeper wagons being bad ass.
I just wanted to write you
to see if you've looked into
the CADILLAC CTS v Wagon
at all.
In my opinion,
it looks meaner than the Mercedes and
would cost you tens of thousand less.
Those Cadillacs are mean looking with
that vertical break light that they have.
They just look fucking angry.
And I loved it.
He loved Cadillacs and he always
looked bad ass driving them.
They're just bad ass cars.
Yeah, I absolutely, uh, if
I got a buddy of mine, uh,
has one, it's just a fucking great
car. Did Grandma I, you know,
I realized I'm a sedan guy. I really
am. I like, I'm Tom to social media.
Look at me.
I get that people in the backseat,
if you're gonna have a fucking two door
cards, don't, don't have a back seat.
That's so dumb.
Fucking staring at that station wagon.
I mean, I'm not like [inaudible] wrong
with station wagons, but they just,
I don't know. They carry that thing
about them that makes it just feel like,
I don't know,
just like, not that there's anything
wrong with having a family car, but like,
they're just not sexy. That's what it
is. A station wagon. It's not sexy.
Whether it's a Mercedes or a
Cadillac. I just, you know what it is.
It's because you guys, all you
guys know is nerd. If you had,
as you guys,
you and everybody else who trashes wagons,
if he knew anybody who played in bands,
guitar players, drummers, surfers,
all these cool bad ass people
drive fucking, yeah. Yeah,
because they should away like I
see a station wagon for a surfer.
That makes sense.
The shape or the boards and stuff.
Do you plan on putting surfboards in a
station wagon? I played drums. I say,
and you can't put drums in any other
kind of car, but a station wagon. Right?
All those vans that
van travel around them,
they don't try to van
the station wagon buddy.
All the baddest bands ever. Some
old, not saying, they all said, look,
anybody can take a yet.
Like I just think to look at a fucking
like a corvette or something like that.
[inaudible] it just for that thing
to go fast is designed to go fast.
I just, I'm so sick of arguing with this
point. When you look at a station wagon,
everything that everybody
thinks about a station wagon,
that's what makes it cool.
That's the thing.
Then fucking blows you away off the
fucking line. That's all I'm saying.
That's all I'm saying. I'm done. I'm
done talking about know Farron. Alright,
fireman.
Oh I asked for some firemen to a,
to a right in,
you know,
but some shit that they found in
a fire and they actually kept it.
They're not going to tell you what they
kept. The why. This is all anonymous.
How a big bed bill.
My father was a fireman for over 20 years.
One morning he came home and he handed
me a rent and Stimpy shirt. Oh my God.
That's funny cause he knew I liked,
to me you eat it.
It's debut 80th to be easy.
It they don't deserve to live.
I didn't put it together right away that
he had taken it from a job he couldn't
even buy as a kid. A simple ren and
Stimpy sir, you had to steal it from afar.
I'm sorry, I'm to steal when
I was a lovely man. I'm so,
I don't mean to diss your dad,
but that's as funny of all things
to give your kid a tee-shirt from a,
and now I feel like he
put his life on the line,
not like a bike that was managed to
be spared or something like that,
but a teacher is kind of weak,
you know,
it smelled like fucking suit,
probably at like little holes in it
from ambers linen on it. A go kit.
The loves you. He goes, I didn't put,
I didn't put it together right away.
He had taken it from a job.
But when I did,
I felt so horrible thinking that someone's
entire life disappeared in a fire.
And now I had one of their
only surviving possessions.
I had thought of that shirt a long
time until you brought that up on an
unrelated note.
Check out the book.
Meat is for pussies by John Joseph.
Uh,
you always make comments that sound
like you could be persuaded to try
vegetarian.
A lot of them.
Um,
I would,
if I could just get myself into like
learning how to cook it and I just,
I bought in like, you know how to cook
it, you know how to cook every vegetable.
You know how to Cook grinds,
you know how to cook beans and
rice and all that kind of stuff.
You know how to do it. So you
know, I'm a crabby old man.
I mean I know what to do with the pork
chop I don't have to do was fucking
eggplant. Now there are certain foods
you would like to cook more than others.
Like you like to make braised short ribs.
You like to make pie,
you like to make pumpkin bread.
So these are the things that you make.
It's not like you can't cook.
It was Anya.
I think this book might help you take the,
take the final step.
The author is a nut who has been singing
for a great punk band for the last 30
years,
but he's in killer shape and breaks it
down and all sorts of conversation on all.
I'm all over this conversational
English. It's not boring. Hippy dippy,
calm you a pamphlet.
It shows all sorts of
athletes and fighters who are
shredded without using any
animal products. I've been a vegetarian
for 23 years, so it didn't convert me,
but it served as a great
source for rebuttals.
When insecure meat eaters go after me
for eating rabbit food and say other dumb
things because my eating habits remind
them of how shitty their diet is,
it's worth checking out. Love the
podcast. Keep up the great work.
Go Fuck Yourself. Ps, stop
cutting yourself off short.
When you talk drums, music,
I sit through hours of you talking sports,
which I still find entertaining,
but I don't give a shit about, but
every time you get nerdy about drumming,
which I love, you say, Oh, this
is boring everyone and move on.
Please stop doing that.
I would rather hear you spend a half hour
talking about John Barnas, right foot.
Then some jerk off, overpaid
meatheads throwing our, oh my God.
Amazing. I suspect that there are others
who agree with me. That's a solid point.
Yeah. Guys in station wagons drive into
the fucking Gig who don't eat meat.
No, I think vegetarianism is, is
cool though. There's some really,
I would be completely satisfied.
You know what I love about f eight?
A total vegetarian. Me, I don't
choose to because I liked me,
but I wouldn't be mad if that's,
you know what's great about
eating vegetarian healthy
way of eating vegetarian
is you don't get, you can eat, you know,
get fat and then you don't have to worry.
Oh good. And again, still working
out like me right now. I got fucking,
but there are some fat vegetarians though.
Yeah.
Those are the ones who
don't read up on it.
They just stop eating meat
and they eat fucking chips,
cookies and Pasta and bread.
I'm a vegetarian. I can
eat that. It's like, dude,
which Chin just said that? So, um,
no, I would like to do that. Like, I would
like to try to, uh, just as you get older,
it's harder and harder
to fucking stay in shape.
And I just don't want to look
like a fucking, you know,
you start getting that fucking torso that
like the cops usually find floating in
a lake. Oh my God. Oh, bloated.
That's what that's been in a lake.
Yeah.
That's cause you know it
was because she had the dead
because you're dead in the bacteria,
your gut.
Oh God.
It's already there near the back.
When you die someday the bacteria that's
going to eat you up so more than it is
in this. Fascinating. No, it isn't. And
it sits in there your whole life. No,
it's nature. It's what the fuck
supposed to, it ranges the interests.
What's supposed to happen here.
Okay. The least fucking jerk off.
She'll get buried and you get stuck.
Don't blame them. They're dead.
And, and they, they get buried.
They get shoved in a drawer
in the basement of a church.
Those people,
it's the biggest fucking waste of stupid.
Your fertilizer does it put
you in the ground and said,
mom does Mazal I am the whole fucking
thing to circle it. Just go, okay,
you're alive.
Why do they decided to put people
in those instead of in the ground?
Cause it's like a fancier, and
you're better than the ground. Yeah.
You can't be,
you can't be warm food.
You have three like uh Nah man.
There's some cool about just fucking,
just being raw. Just rot
away to gone dust. Boom over.
Get out of here. Beat it. Yeah.
It's fucking sitting there with your
dumb headstone so people can come up to
with Jack Daniels and fucking
their arm around him. Man,
he's not there. She's not there. They're
fucking, they're there in the air.
You can stay at home and do that. Just
like crazy philosophical to the night.
Philosophical is stupid. Both. I know
one of the other, well, all right.
I'm
lying about medical school.
I've been lying about medical school to
my family and friends for the last two
years. I'm now, he's 23 this
is understandable. He was, wow.
I'm guest teen and lying about, you
know Jesus. All right. All right,
fine. Fine. Jesus.
Jesus. Can you give the,
can we get the kid a fun at 23 near like
if you saw how fucking introverted I
was at 23 you know why?
Compared to the Gloria Social
Butterfly that you are today,
you are on fire
person.
I like who I like. Okay.
I like, I don't like fuck.
Yeah, I don't like those big
parties. Got To stand there.
The fucking eyebrows up.
Is that what you tell
it did rain yesterday.
You're not good at small talk
is what it is. Pointless.
And then in little party conference
you've got to come up with some sort of
thing to just say and just when they
look and you feel the same thing,
just be like, dude, don't feel
you don't have to talk to me.
We don't have to do this.
That sounds like a great
way to make somebody feel
comfortable. No. If they know,
you know what I mean? These
fucking, we don't have to do this.
We can just sit here and the
quiet until our wives come over,
drag us back into that
and you just click your drinks.
Definitely worked with me, man.
That's so funny.
I would love to,
I used to do a bit of ice to talk
about you on stage when you come off
everything. Okay, I get it.
I always ended up drifting
into a corner at these parties.
You're the social butterfly going around.
Everybody fucking loves you.
And I'd just be standing in the corner
drinking a Miller and then you'd come
over and just be like, [inaudible]
okay, I just hear anything.
I feel like you're avoiding the party.
Like I am you.
In the beginning when I was getting
to know you and then I realized,
you know what? A wildly, you know,
dazzling personality that you can be at
social gatherings and I just let you do
your own thing and then I do my thing.
And then what happened?
You always say that I abandoned you, I
parties. No, that was early, early on.
That was weird to me that I would just
let you just say and you'd break off and
I'd be like, what the, I'm mean,
so someone beat on my hip and
they would just be an egg.
And it's also so first it weirded
me out and then I, then I was like,
wait a minute, this is
perfect. Yeah, you go Ryan,
you go round the room and be like,
oh look,
you do all, you find thinness. What
is in it? Oh my God, it's a Dylan
said I'm in the corner. Like, no, no,
I'll set. You find them. One of the guy,
the party that like spores and you guys
ended up talking all night. It's perfect.
It really is perfect. It's the
perfect. Usually I, you know,
nobody's feelings get hurt and we have,
we have very independent socialize.
I think that's important.
You know, I fucking,
I go, I find the room. Nobody's in.
I just stand there. I know you
always want to sit down. Yes.
What are we standing up for? But
you know what? I don't like this.
I don't like to stand
either during part anyway.
We'd have to get back to the question
watching all the fucking couples competing
with each other. Dumb Shit. Oh,
do you see the fucking woman jealous of
her bag and then you see how can it his
eye and then he sit and they go out.
God, now I get to buy a fucking bag.
Got to buy a fucking bag.
Cause Suzy q's got the fucking yellow one.
Fucking hate her. She's so, she's
skinny, right? She's getting, you know,
that's the nightmare chicken. Then
you drive home. You got to convince,
you got to convince the
woman you're with that.
You didn't want to fuck anybody
there at the party. Oh yeah.
She was too skinny for me.
Yes. She should've put,
she should have left
something to the imagination.
Thank God her tits were
hanging out fucking [inaudible]
and it was a great thing
to look at. And while I was in the
middle of that awful conversation,
now there example of why
having independence socialize
is so great because I
don't invite you to shit because I know
that you're not going to be into it.
So I don't even know if I
asked. You did forever. I did.
And then I sobbed and I was like,
yeah, you want to go to blah blah.
And I'd be like, no. And
then you would always go,
I died a thousand deaths than I not.
Can I take some,
give me a fucking break.
You've died a thousand deaths because I
invited you to parties because I want to
spend time with you. Oh, just hey
you up on that cross. It's so hard.
The things that you went to or what?
The fact that they were called parties
is an absolute insult around with you and
all your bone head comedian friends while
you insult each other for three hours.
That's like supposed to be something
amazing. Never called it a party.
Certainly not.
It is not a point when they say were you
and Joe de Rosa and Keith Robinson and
we're going to have dinner
and you're like, oh, you can
come if you want. See you.
And I said, who's going? It
was going on, I don't know,
smart,
this beautiful fucking great steakhouse,
hate this unbelievable food.
And all we did was sit there and
make fun of Keith's fucking sweater.
And then the waitress came over and
had the best insult because Keith was
defended the sweater and then she
comes over and we go, what do you,
excuse me miss it.
She already knew that were,
we were a jerk offs and we just said,
what do you think of when
you look at Keith sweater?
And she goes, Freddy Krueger.
And it was, and it was, and
it was such a Freddy Krueger,
it was their Thanksgiving colored thick
stripe fucking sweater. I was great.
And he had to just sit there and
take it and that, that made my meal.
And she said, do you want dessert? I said,
no, you just gave it to me sweetheart.
Sorry. Um, all right. So he says,
I've been lying about my medical school
and my family and friends for the last
two years.
I'm 23 I have aspired to be a doctor ever
since moving to the United States when
I was 10 I crushed it in high
school without really studying.
Graduated, graduated as, sorry.
I already go to salutary and I fucked.
Graduated as salutary.
I don't even know what that means.
Is that number one in the class to
Jesus Christ? Valedictorian is number
one. A salutorian is number two. What's,
what's the bronze?
I Dunno.
I'm still just the class
president or something.
They didn't miss them
that high academically,
but socially they were popular
enough to get [inaudible] president.
I was in the supplemental draft.
All right.
So I had an ego trip going into college
and decided to push myself in order to
get into the top tier medical
schools by junior year.
I was double majoring, working in
a research lab and teaching. Uh,
I say that word recitation. What the fuck
is that? A recitation session of my own.
Do you know what that is?
So how do you know that's how you say it,
but why don't you stand it out?
I do.
I have to like help you like a child
in school learning was sound out rats,
sealant, recitation or what
else would it be? I don't know.
I don't know what it is and either deal.
How do you know it's not recite Taishan
anyways, uh, on my own,
on, uh, a recitation
session of my own on top of volunteering
in the Er as an EMT during off hours,
ah, I'm gonna say this dude burned
himself up. To make a long story short,
I over extended myself, Mike,
but by graduation, my GPA,
Sax Solo that no United States
medical schools would ever consider my
application.
I was too ashamed to admit this to
my family and friends who have always
considered me as smart as
the smart one of the bunch.
For two years after graduation,
I had been lying about working fulltime
and applying to medical school,
but rarely but barely missing
the cut or at least sure.
Oh, you've been lying
that you have that. Oh,
about working fulltime and
applying to middle school. Oh,
so that's what's really going on.
You're working full time and you keep
missing the cut. In reality, I am working.
Oh, in reality. Oh that is what
you're doing. I'm sorry. In Rio.
Oh my God.
Hey,
that's the reason I'm a clown.
Oh, this is torture. How long it's
taken you to get through this.
In reality,
working parttime secretly taking
classes to improve my GPA and I've never
applied.
This lie has gotten so elaborate that
I have been making application size,
credit card payments to a credit card.
My parents don't know I own,
so if they review my bank statements,
it actually looks like I
have been applying what?
The burden of keeping the truth to my
self and it's gotten so bad that I'm
actually starting to feel a
disconnect from my family and friends.
First question,
should I come clean or should I just
keep up the lie until I get into medical
schools? Second question, is it even
worth pursuing this dream anymore?
By the time I improved my GPA,
I'll be 25 plus four years of medical
school plus three years of residency.
I'll be 32 by the time I have my first
day of work. That's still pretty young.
Dude,
I would love to take your advice to heart.
I think you're far more insightful
and to give us a no compliments here.
All he came out of it,
he goes,
I think you're far more insightful
than you give yourself credit for,
but you're still a balding ginger. Go
Fuck Yourself. God, I keep you honest.
Still over there. All right,
here's a good shit. Um hmm.
I would definitely come clean because
this is fucking eating away at you and
your brain and it's making you
live in a double life here.
I would definitely do it. And you if,
if it's still really is your dream,
who gives a fuck? Gives a fuck.
Who cares how long it takes.
But something tells me
that I didn't gradually,
regularly regular college until
25. Yeah, that's true. Um,
and it doesn't,
I don't know.
I get the feeling that he actually
doesn't want to be a doctor anymore.
What the hell? I didn't see that way.
What'd you mean? I don't know. I'm in,
what do you think? Um, cause I just,
I dunno, I just feel
like he or she is. Um,
probably he though I just feel
like the way it's written as a guy,
I have just feel like, yeah, maybe you
got burned out and really you don't,
maybe you don't want to do it anymore.
Is there a possibility that there's other
things that you to do? But either way,
I know you shouldn't lie anymore because,
and it's not so much about other people.
It's like you were saying,
it's about you.
It's how it's eating you up inside and
making you feel disconnected from your
family and friends. That's not
good. Like they, they love you.
You're only thing it really comes down
to they don't want you to be miserable.
Hopefully
this guy's academically George Foreman,
right before he fought up,
fought Isley where he just never lost,
never got knocked down.
And then when Ali knocked him down,
he said years later that
he could've got back up,
but he'd never been there before.
And I think this dude was crushing
it without fucking trying,
cause he was so smart. And then it got
a little hard and uh, he's dealing with,
um, like, uh, dealing
with a couple of losses.
You got to turn it around and do it.
It's not a,
you're not even fucking at 23 years old,
dude.
That's way too young to pack in.
You look at this way. This is how
I always looked at it. All right.
You're 23. All right. You're saying by the
time you get through all this bullshit,
you're going to be 32. What
would you rather be at? 32 32,
not a doctor or 32. Just became a
doctor. If that's what you want to do.
All right, because Sunday, dude,
you're going to look at 32 years of
age and be like, Jesus, I was a kid,
I was a fucking kid.
I still had it all ahead of me.
And you do so stop being
so hard on yourself.
Come clean because it
seems like it's your turn.
You're turning yourself into
a bit of a sociopath here.
Yeah.
Cause the two years is a long time.
And the fact that you're
making these payments,
you like the credit card and
stuff. That's a little much. Yeah.
So what are they doing?
Like buying flat screen TVs to be like,
oh that's for this. And then
you get that. That's a little,
that's taken it too far. I mean it takes
the TV and throws it over the backyard.
Yeah, there's really no
need to get this for that.
You let slip scale back before you do
anything. And here's this thing. Crazy
set. As your parents get at some point,
you guys are all gonna laugh at it.
You're going to laugh at lift the
shit that my parents laugh at,
the stuff that I fucking did. You know,
I got arrested for drinking and driving.
I've never seen my mother have a
more disappointed look on her face.
She still rolls her eyes,
but when I tell the story,
she laughs now she left still get over
it. All right. They'll get over it. Okay.
But uh, you know, I just, she's
still want to be a doctor dude.
The fact that you'd be a doctor
in 32 would be fucking amazing.
Yeah, of course. Being on becoming
a doctor is fucking amazing.
If you want to do it, if you
want to do it. Oh my God,
it is so hard. It's so hard.
You guys know.
What did he say?
I'm working part time and I'm secretly
do to improve and have never applied.
Um Hm.
Do you like working parttime though
and what are you working at? Cause I,
I feel like there's something else that
he's interested in doing. Well. Okay.
Maybe. Yeah. Like I know he wants,
he says he wants to be a doctor
and I don't doubt that, but I,
but what if there's something else that
might be even more interesting and I
don't know,
not make you turn into a person
that has to make up a second life.
I don't know. I don't know. The way I
read it, I don't think he ever had to,
I think you just put too much pressure
on himself. Oh yeah, that's true.
So I think his parents will be
fine with it. And if they're not,
then they're not your real parents.
That's right or not. You're really,
you know, they say if they don't agree
then you're not your real friends,
but you are.
But your mental,
like emotional wellbeing is way more
important than a medical school,
I feel like ultimately.
Right.
Uh, I wasn't listening to you. I was
already looking at the next question.
You know what?
Before I came in here,
I was reading about adult ADHD cause
you know I like to read it every couple
months and like make you take a quiz just
to confirm the facts. Bring it in here.
That's true are in fact, I'll take
the quiz right now. Have Adult Adhd.
Should I go get it?
Good.
I'll take it and I'll answer the next one.
I'm going to fucking destroy this test.
You know she's out of the room.
You know I'm going to destroy it.
I'm just going to fucking lie.
Never let the broad in your life
psycho fucking analyze you. All right?
Whether you wanted or not, they're already
gonna be running around in your head.
You don't need to fucking open the door.
You know what I'm saying?
When you get in a
relationship with a woman,
remember that star Trek one where they
fucking tied those guys hands behind
their back and they stuck that warm and
they're fucking helmets and then put it
on. They went in their ear. That's
what I'm talking about it all right.
Skating rink.
Dear Billy Bruins,
you've been talking a lot
about your home renovation,
but we never heard much about
the Yad, which leads me, uh,
leads to my suggestion of installing
some ice in your backyard. Dude,
I live in Los Angeles.
Surprise to me how few people have these
things going on regardless of whether
or not you could actually do it.
Is that something you would want to have
two out of the four seasons of the year?
Ps, maintain the ice would be the hardest
part. Oh Dude. Are you kidding me?
I would love to have
a rank of my backyard,
although would I want to go through living
in a place where I have to go through
winters? I did that for
40 years. I did my time.
I bought enough ice scrapers in
my life. Uh, I love the winter.
I like to visit it at this
point. And, um, you know,
and all you guys who say I'm a pussy now,
eve,
show me how it's done by standing back
there in the fucking goddamn winter.
Um, anyways. All right, that's the
podcast for this week. Everybody.
Thank you for listening. We're waiting.
Um, oh, by the way, by the way,
by the way, I finally got some
Boston dates coming your way. Uh,
rumor has it that all freckles is
coming to town sometime possibly
bleed,
possibly in May.
And I'm going to do a run of
dates at the Wilbur theater.
I'll let you know. I'll let you know,
definitely when a, when that's going down.
And also I'm going to be doing
another bus tour through the south.
And when I'll fucking around this
time we're going to go to, uh,
I want to try to avoid all major
cities in the south. I want to go to,
I don't want to go to Nashville. I just
was there. I want to go to Knoxville,
Memphis, shoo fly North
Carolina. Oh, mobile.
I already got a theater.
I'm picking out to go to Mississippi.
I've never done standup in Mississippi.
Um,
somebody showed me one inch and
I want to go to some cool venues,
some old theaters that have some history.
Somebody showed me one in Shreveport,
Louisiana that both Elvis and Johnny
Cash played at. It's pretty big.
I don't know if I could fill
it, but uh, that's what I'm,
that's what I'm looking to do.
And then after I booked the tour of phase
two is I want all you fucking southern
people to tell me where you eat in that
town. And I won't fucking tell anybody.
I won't blow up the spot.
You just let me know where to go
for some mom and pop fucking place.
Do not tell me about the apple bees or
the cracker barrel or wherever the fuck I
want to know where the fuck you
go. Uh, you know to eat. Okay.
That's the deal. Now let me take
this fucking test here. Here we go.
Alrighty. Ready? This is, hold on.
I have to study. The whole thing is,
the whole thing is never,
rarely, sometimes, often.
Okay. That's how you answer.
Is that the title? Oh No. That's how
you answer it. You're already failed.
That sounds like a fucking
the name of a book.
How often do you ever rarely tension
while doing something for work,
school hobby or fun activity? Eeg.
Remaining focused during lectures.
Links too many fucking things.
Hobby. I'm playing drums.
I could finish the question and
you're already cause it's vague.
Are you going to answer? Are you going
to do this and that? All right, good.
I'll just pretend you
have like power over me.
How often do you have
difficulty sustaining your
attention while doing something
for work? School, a hobby or fun activity?
Never.
If you already know the answers are
never, rarely. Sometimes. Often, often.
Okay. How often are you easily
distracted by external stimuli?
Like something in your
environment or unrelated thoughts?
What does that say it again?
Let's do it again. I was already thinking
about the joke in the middle of it.
I was going, can I imitate Barbarino what
people are going to get it? Oh my God,
I don't even need to.
I don't even need to ask you.
How often are you easily distracted?
You're not a doctor. Where's your in?
I'm not saying I'm a doc.
Was Bio psych central.com oh shit.
Fucking forget it then. Whatever they
say I am. How often do you avoid,
disliked or are reluctant to engage in
Taipei? People who spells psych? Yes.
Yes. Well, I'm psyched and they
spell it with an s. It's so gay.
How often do you avoid
dislike or reluctance?
Engage in stock. Dare you embarrass me
like this in my own fucking podcast.
Sustained mental effort.
Orthotic?
No, I actually didn't
hear the first part, but
you can not fucking paying
attention to see me.
Her fucking everything you read. No.
Cause it reminds me of other shit.
Exactly. What Adhd, Adhd as you can,
it doesn't mean to remind
you of other shit bill.
The like the second question was how often
are you easily distracted by internal
stimuli, like something in your
environment or unrelated thoughts?
That was question number two, Bill. Often.
Oh my God.
How often do you have trouble listening
to someone even when they are speaking
directly to you,
like your mind is somewhere else.
Often it's not somewhere else.
They're not interesting and then I just
start going and looking at their shoes.
Screw you. You're saying I'm not
interesting. No, don't fucking do.
Well I've got a fucking disease over here
often.
Then how often do you have difficulty or
in organizing a task or activity needed
to get done? Eg Poor time
management failed to meet deadlines,
difficulty managing sequential tasks.
Not One of those was good.
What? Oh, I thought those will do what
you said in the end with the options.
I told you at the beginning
that it's never, rarely,
sometimes or often.
That's how you answer.
Somewhere between rarely and
sometimes there's the I get shit done.
I'm a successful fucking God. That's true.
All. Well, why don't we say sometimes.
Okay, how's that? Well,
you're not supposed to say,
and I was supposed to say it when we,
well,
I apparently need to coach you through
this because you keep getting distracted.
Oh,
you are a devil woman.
And then how often do you fail to give
close attention to details or make
careless mistakes and things
such as schoolwork, at work,
during other activities?
Rarely take my work seriously. Okay. Sat
in that fucking writer's room. Six, seven,
eight hours a day. I didn't have to be
there. Could I showed up like the Douche,
hey, write me something. That's
true. I didn't. I sat there.
How often do you forget to do
something you do? All the time.
So just missing an appointment or
paying a bill all the fucking time.
Not Paying a bill though. I
pay bills. Yes, you do. Yeah,
but the 50 important shit
near the important shit. I'm
fucking locked and loaded.
I'll put sometimes all the dumb shit.
How often do you lose ms plays or damaged
something that's necessary in order to
get things done? Your phone,
eyeglasses, paperwork, wallet,
keys, et Cetera. Do I lose it or damage
it? Wouldn't mean damage it. Throw it.
How often do you lose ms plays
or damage? Either one. Oh,
fuck a time.
Yes.
How often do you have trouble following
through on instructions or failing to
finish school work chores or duties
in the workplace? Eg Syrah task.
We quickly lose focus and
are easily sidetracked.
Okay.
Sometimes, but not that much. I'm really
good with the work thing. Yeah. Yeah. No,
I would agree with that.
Obviously you are,
there's no doubt that you are successful.
What does,
what does the end game of this?
So then you find out here fucking Adhd,
fucking whatever,
and then what?
I lose the argument about the
fucking closet downstairs.
How often are you unable to play or
engage in leisurely activities? Quietly.
Okay.
How often are you unable to play
or engage in leisurely activities?
Quietly? Well, let me, cigar
smoking is pretty quiet.
I loved the one that sometimes.
Okay.
Rarely. Okay. Rarely. How often do
you have difficulty waiting your turn?
Such as while waiting in line.
Okay.
What would have of
course to stand in line?
No. If I see a long line, I just
like, I just think about what is,
is it really worth standing in line?
Is this,
you know, parative than my fucking
survival. I don't need it. I'm out often.
How often do you feel like you're on the
go acting as if you driven by a motor
or EEG you're unable to be
or uncomfortable being still
for an extended period.
All right. All right. I see where this
is going in a restaurant or a meeting.
Yeah.
I like going to restaurants at
bill at the end of a meal. Right.
While you're still finishing dessert,
you literally have your coat on
and you have your credit card.
How you're holding it on the table,
like looking around.
I know cause that's cause of the
fucking smalltalk throughout all of it.
Oh here's a story and people tell a story.
This is one,
you know his story bombing in
the middle of it. You have to go.
So damn
fuck isn't grabbing their coat.
Sometimes I'll put how often do you leave
your seat and how often do you leave
your seat in situations when
remaining seed is expected?
10 pens on whether I'm being entertained,
plays in the office or workplace.
If I'm being entertained sometimes.
Okay.
Yeah I have a hot fucking how often do
you blurt out an answer before a question
has been completed?
Eg completed another incense or
can't wait your turn and conversation
to an o?
An answer like I know the answer cause
that doesn't happen cause I've used don't
know the answer.
How often do you blurt out an answer
never happened or a question yesterday.
Fleeted jeopardy or wheel of fortune.
That never happens. That's I'm going to,
I'm putting off in and you know,
it's often can I put often
you do whatever you want.
This is fucking test isn't
gonna affect my life in any way.
I don't know what your point is.
How often do you feel restless?
Like you want to get out and do something?
Yeah,
like I get up and turn the data.
I want to do something. Yeah.
I don't want to lay around
like a dose. So yeah. Often.
How often do you fidget with our tap?
Your hands or feet or storming?
How many more?
It's the same fucking question
over and over and over again.
How often do you fidget
or tap or your seat?
I don't know. Sometimes. Okay.
How often do you find
yourself talking excessively?
Can I tap out often? Do you
find yourself talking yet
often? Sometimes I'm running
my mouth all the fuck at times.
Other times I clam up. Like when I'm at
a party I don't walk in and take over.
I see everybody Geekdad we'd
be talking about that bullshit.
I'm just saying this is awful. I don't
understand the corn. I don't say anything.
Okay. Sometimes. How often do you
interrupt or intrude on others?
I just butting into their conversation
and taking over what others are doing.
Well, I was with it until
the end. Taking over.
It's a little fucking hard letting in
or taking over. Yeah. The, the, these,
this is all the same fucking question
over and over again. See a patient,
non ADHD person would be able to take
this quiz and like, you know what,
this is just, I'm going to put some
time. All right. It's almost done. Uh,
were several of the symptoms
present, uh, prior to age 12? No.
You never felt this way as a little
boy. Okay. No, no I didn't. All right.
The fuck was I worried about,
do these symptoms appear in at
least two or more settings at home
and school or home and work or whatever?
Yeah. All right. Your
score, this is 20 questions.
You scored a total of 42 based upon
your responses to this adult add ADH
screening quiz.
Do you ever replied in a way similar
to peach people who have symptoms of
moderate to severe
attention deficit disorder,
moderate to severe, severe? That's
pretty much the entire gamut. Oh,
they it go psych.com.
You may have it a little bit or a severe.
All of that mental torture.
Do you see why I tap out half the time?
Symptoms typically worsened in situations
that requires you just send a up that
mentioned or mental
effort or that are boring.
You know,
that was written by boring people that
are tired of getting interrupted by
exciting kickball.
Me Burn everybody.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Don't fucking see what you just did.
You drag me through my own shit
that they go, but I love you. Hey,
let's look at this right here.
This is, this is the guy, uh,
I worked with the other day.
Brad Carter. All right there.
You remember him right?
Look at this picture right there.
Regular do. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. Reggie
Lewis who did that? She was awesome.
Yeah. I'm going to post
a video he had, he had,
he's got a video on the Internet,
says man plays guitar.
Well having brain surgery and it's him
blacks as they weren't, they weren't.
I'll let him tell the fucking story.
I already sound dumb enough. Is it is,
but a fucking a,
that's cool.
Okay.
Amazing. Fucking actor.
Funniest fucking hell.
And like can be scary if he wants to be.
So I'm really looking out for this
guy to do big shit, man. All right.
That's the Monday morning podcast.
Everybody.
Good luck with your holiday shopping and
good luck if you fucking wife comes in
and goes, hey, you want to take a,
because I can tell you right now,
she is a fucking axe to grind and
you're going to fail it. Alright?
Go Fuck yourself and talk to you next
week. That's next week. Next week,
10 days away. Oh my God. It's coming up.
It's coming so fast. All right. See you.