Hey,
what's going on is bill burr and it's
the Monday morning podcasts for Monday,
October 31st, 2016 what's
going on our, yeah,
it's Halloween. Everybody happy
Halloween. Oh, happy hollow. Fucking wean.
Happy all of Fucko read Datta,
Da.
You're a fucking teen. It's, you're
too fucking old for candy. Um,
what's the cutoff?
What's the cutoff tonight when the kids
come where you just want to be with some
of them just be like, dude, you're
too fucking old. Cleo. Get outta here.
I'll feed you in a minute.
Go on telling you my,
my cutoff is somewhere
around like fucking 12
you know,
even even brown 10 they just start saying
little wise ass conti fucking things.
You know?
That's the hardest thing about being an
adult around a kid is they think they're
so fucking smart and it's just
like, dude, I was, I was your age.
I've been 10 I've been 12.
Okay. Dan had been 2030,
40 almost up to 50. You're right. You'd
dump. Fuck. Do you think you think,
I don't know what you're doing. Do you
think you're playing with my mind, man?
I mean, just so you just want to say
it to you. Remember that your mode,
everybody's got to have that.
Do you ever have that fucking
adult that just fucking, you know,
when your parents weren't looking,
just look to you and just
told you to shut the fuck up.
Okay.
Probably doesn't happen nowadays because
of all the smart phones and everybody's
got a video camera and the kid
blogs about it. Next thing you know,
you get arrested for Ryder.
I Dunno. I Dunno what Cleo,
get outta here. Go on. Go on.
Um,
you know,
but back then, I mean, that's
the kind of Shit you could do.
I remember what we were talking in church,
me and my brother and this
dude fucking turnaround. He
goes, hey, he goes, shut up.
He said that. He goes, well, you shut up.
You know, it's just one of those things,
you know,
and my mother and I looked at my mother
and she fucking put her eyebrows up like
my, yeah, well, shut the fuck up. That
doesn't happen nowadays. Apparel my,
you don't talk.
You don't do that much emotional abuse.
Verbal abuse. No. You kid
needs to shut the fuck up.
So what our do you,
there's this, that shit,
that fucking hour where they just
stopped being cute. You know,
they just stopped being cute and they
get fucking annoying and then it get,
it goes over the hill where it just
becomes like, you know, they're coming up,
do your thing. And they got the
Shitty Grinch smirk on their face.
I'm telling you this fucking
year does fucking year.
Some kid comes up with a
smirk on his face. I go,
I'm not giving you any candy cause that
look on your face is what I want to say.
But you can't because of that.
Look on your face and if you do anything
to my mailbox or anything like that,
I'm going to fucking kill you.
All right? You fucking pussy.
You don't even know how to drive
yet. The Fuck Outta here. Right?
But you can't say, you know, he
can't, not, not today's America,
not in today's America. Well, you know
what, Trump's going to bring that back.
Um,
I've had such a bad experience,
like all my life, all my laugh ever there
was a bid. I've been waiting for the,
I couldn't wait to have a fucking house.
The kids came by to go trick or treating.
I mean I moved out and um,
the first time I lived like
in the up the attic of,
of a fucking old house that
they turned into an apartment.
It was fucking hilarious.
And you had to like walk down the center
of the apartments so your head head
wouldn't hit either side of
the fucking roof. And uh,
I told you guys this right now,
he didn't have a bed.
I slept in a sleeping bag
and I would sleep right by
the window because I didn't,
we didn't have any AC.
And then one night there was
like some torrential downpour.
I was sitting there dream and
I was on a boat or something,
some about water and I woke
up just soaking wet. Um,
and then he always funny ended up catching
a cold and like the next day it was
like July was like 89 degrees out
of something. And I had a cold,
like it was fucking November. Um, Oh God,
that fucking sucked.
Um,
then I moved back in with my parents,
get my shit together,
fucking finally graduated fucking college.
And then when I moved out I ended up
going to New York City and people don't go
trick or treating in New York City.
They have places where they go where all
the fucking candy is and they make sure
there's no fucking Weirdos there.
Um,
and then when I finally moved out to La,
I don't know,
people still didn't come to
my first apartment was when
I got my house, you know,
five years ago there was just like, all
right, now they're going to be coming.
And I was fucking loaded for bear
and I, you, I did the bid on,
I had the full size candy bars.
Jesus Christ.
Cleal you're driving me nuts. Get
over there and lay down. You keep,
there's no way to be mad at
a dog for longer than four.
Frustrated more than three
seconds. They'll can you
please lay down. Hey Buddy,
laid out,
down.
Go on,
lay down. There you go. And the
follow through. Thank you. Um,
I already can tell she's not going
to sit there cause she's laying down,
but she has her ears up and she's just
staring at me. You know what it is.
I had to get up early to do this fucking
podcast cause I've got a bunch of shit
that I need to do.
So anyways,
people finally started coming to the
fucking house and uh, that's what I found.
You know, soon as the sun goes down the
first, I know we always talk about this,
but you gotta admit it's true
the first like hour and a half.
It's the cutest fucking kids you've
ever seen. The parents are great,
you know, it's just like a great, it's
just, I dunno, it's fucking awesome.
The kids are adorable. And then somewhere
around, I don't know, two weeks,
seven and eight, it starts switching
over and there's just nothing,
but it's like after like
a quarter to nine, I mean,
just everybody see it's going
to be a bunch of fucking,
oh man,
you know something about rent in this
fucking house and it's got this crazy
driveway. I don't even think
anybody's going to come up here,
but next year I promise
you guys I have to fucking,
I want to open a door and be like,
ah Nah. You guys, you're too old.
You're too old. Look at, Hey, go buy
some candy. Get the fuck Outta here.
But then you got to worry.
They're going to fuck up your house.
Even if they don't do it that night,
they're going to do it another night.
Just be like, come on man, you guys are
too old. Maybe it'll just lie and be like,
oh, sorry. I might've candy. How
tall are you? Five Watt. Yeah,
I'm out of candy. What do
you got? Yeah, there's four.
You're not for 11. Fuck out of
here. You're five foot one bated.
Um Oh y'all are. You know what you do is,
is what's the worst kind of fucking candy?
Oh,
it's just a shitty old lady kind of candy.
That's what you do, you know with the,
the fucking fruit in the middle
of it. Like real fruit. Oh my God.
I don't know about you guys. I don't
know what grandmothers are like nowadays,
but when I was a kid, man, my grandma,
my grandparents had the
worst fucking candy,
at least one of them did.
And then like the fuck,
I had a paper route and then there was
like a bunch of old biddies and shit that,
you know, a couple that never got married
and shit or that fucking, they're dead.
They're fucking husband died and they'd
always have like this little candy.
I have a piece of candy. Right. And
I know he got a bite into, Ugh, God,
I didn't know what the fuck it was.
It was just, it was just horrible.
Just there, just, you know, he was like,
did they put your perfume in the
middle of this shit? I'm sorry. It was,
it was too. I'm just saying it was
disgusting. All right. So anyways, um,
I'm actually going to a
Halloween party tonight.
I was going to make some pumpkin bread
for the house straight. I was like, ah,
or the party in and neo's
going like I was, I got mad.
I got so much shit to do when I go
and I gotta make that Pumpkin bread.
And then she just goes like,
well, why don't you just
like not do that? Well just,
you know,
we'll go get a bottle of champagne.
She always does that. She always goes,
you make you life so fucking hard.
It's like, it's Pumpkin bread. It's
not that. It's just like, it's fucking,
it's going to take me like,
you know,
10 minutes to put it together and then
throw it in the fucking oven for an hour.
It's just a pain in the ass to do
it. She, why don't we just do this?
I could afford to fucking just being
another asshole shown up with a bottle of
wine as opposed to showing
up with Pumpkin bread.
Okay.
The fuck is, you know, I don't know.
I don't know. Sometimes. Sometimes,
I don't know. Sometimes we don't fucking,
we just don't see that out of like,
I want to make my own steam dumpling. She
goes, I just buy them at trader Joe's.
You know? Those are, those are
the times, you know what I mean?
Those are the times we just
want to kind of smile and nod,
just slowly back towards the front door,
get in the car and just never come
back again. Yeah. Then other words,
you'd lie to yourself that that's what
you're going to do for the next 20
minutes. As you drive around,
you know, talking to yourself,
it fucking red lights and you look over,
there's some beautiful
woman half year raise.
Go and look at that crazy bald old guy
and you just sit there and you got to be
like, wow, I'm the, I'm
the crazy bald old guy.
No, it's good. I'm worn me
out here. And then you'd give,
you go back home and then that's it.
That's how it works.
But every once in awhile,
not actually once in a while,
more people than not
can commit to that day.
They can back their way out the front
door and they can go through with,
it may take it all the way to the divorce,
you know,
they go up, they get
themselves a to pay, you know,
they painted orange, they get
a red tie, they run for office,
they start people up at truck stops.
Um,
this election is so fucked up that,
uh,
okay,
that's kind of really quieted down.
I have for the last fucking debate,
if that's what the fuck
you want to call it. Um,
okay.
My big thing this year is I want to know,
um,
I just fucking lose lose. It's fucking
lose lose at the, at the thing.
And you know, something, as much as
I've been sitting here fucking saying,
you know, Trump's a fucking
racist and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. It's just like,
well, you know, the Clintons
are from Arkansas, so, you know,
I don't think they're too fucking
enlightened down there either. You know,
if Wayne off, I know I'm just
fucking being stereotypical here,
but give me a break. Oh,
Bill and fucking I, Hillary,
they grew up in Arkansas
in like the fifties.
You might want to go back and look at
some of those fucking racist, you know,
the racist people
screaming at black people.
Kids go into school for the first time.
You might want to try to pick her
head out or something like that.
Give me a fucking break. You
from Arkansas. I love that shit.
Wear it just because you're a democrat.
That just means that you know that
you'd not homophobic, you're not racist.
Or I have a byway wear blue.
I just don't fucking or that public.
And then that automatically
means that you're, you know,
you want a berry babies in
the backyard and you know,
unless they're fucking blue eyed
white babies, you know what I mean?
Like that whole fucking deer in that,
the corporations and all that,
they're all fucking cunts.
And you know,
I know that cause I'm a condo
and I'm somewhere in the middle.
I like to think I definitely
lean more fucking left. But, uh,
I'm also contrarian and now I live
out here in Hollywood and I just can't
fucking deal with these people out
here and that it's, it's driving me.
I don't think it's driving
me to the right. It's,
it's driving me to say things on the
right just to fuck with these people.
Like I love trashing out here. It's one
of my favorite fucking things to do.
Okay.
You know,
I,
last night I was fucking around on
stage and I was talking about that and
talking about how, you know, well,
Hillary's from fucking Arkansas,
everybody and they all kind of
laughed. I go, you know, those,
those fucking fly over states that you
guys all shit on out here, you know?
Yeah.
And uh, you know, of course
it gets fucking whatever.
You know what the big thing isn't it
on this ballot is wherever the fuck you
live.
More important than what of that orange
headed fucking racist comment or that
devil woman with her fucking issues.
Right.
She lived in Arkansas in the 1950s.
Jesus Christ,
write me a fucking break.
Um,
okay.
Be a or her, you know what the
biggest fucking thing is, sorry,
I'm losing my train of thought
here is those is all the props,
the state propositions, you know,
and this is what pisses me off.
So I go to this website to try to
figure out California 17 ballot measure
propositions explained.
All right?
And uh,
all they do is they, they
sort of explained the thing,
but what they don't have,
what I cannot find is all the bullshit
that is attached to each one of these
propositions.
Like this shit is so fucked up
and I do not understand why.
Okay,
this is never addressed. Why? And all
these propositions like no means yes,
yes means no.
And then there's a little bit of maybe
in there and then if you vote for the
fucking Shit, there's some other
measure saying that, you know, yeah,
it's okay to a fucking stick, a baby
in a snowbank for fucking, you know,
13 hours until it freezes
to death or whatever our
fucking long would would take.
You know,
I just can't,
I can't find anything that says
all the shit that's attached to it.
Why can't the fucking ballot
just be fucking the proposition?
Just be written clearly. So regular
people understand it. Yes. Means yes.
No means no.
And there's nothing else attached to it,
you know, like they'll say,
all right. Ah, there we go.
Proposition 51 allows the
sales of 9 billion in bonds,
mmm.
To pay for,
for newK ,
kindergarten to 12th grade and
community college facilities.
The basics, roughly 6 million students
at 10 k two you don't have the fucking,
his proposition 51 wants to address the
needs by allowing the sale of 9 billion
in general obligation bonds to pay
for buildings in modernizing k 12 and
community college.
It's the first school bond measure on
the state ballot since 2006 it's unusual
because it's sponsored
by the building industry.
Okay.
Right there.
The fact that it's sponsored by the
building industry means they're going to
charge us up the fucking ass. And in
the end, even though they get 9 billion,
they're going to come in with the
fucking tab of about 15 billion and then
they'll be like,
well,
we already started against me going to
physically move from talking shit and
told Bluto.
Typically the legislator would be the
path for getting this kind of proposition
on the ballot, but it hasn't been
able to do so in recent years. Yeah.
The fact that the building
industry wants to do it,
you already know this is crooked is shit.
What you're voting on about 7
billion in nearly ADC like this shit.
7 billion would be allocated to the K
to 12 thing and in the another 2 billion
would feed it for the community college.
I got to read all of this shit.
Supporters include developers,
builders,
school board officials and business groups
and I want to get any of those people.
All right.
Yeah.
Supporters say,
all right.
Supporters say many of our schools need
repairs and upgrades to make them safe
for our children.
That's very vague.
Proposition 51 we'll will improve
education overall and help expand space
communicology so more students can attend.
Opponents say prop 54 would
add to the state debt,
which is already more than 400 billion.
How the fuck is California?
400 billion in debt.
Yeah.
Bond measures should be passed locally.
Giving communities control
of how the money is spent.
Yeah. Jesus. I mean,
did you feel any closer?
All right, so there's one comment. Close
the border. Eliminate anchor babies,
citizenship and re institute.
Yeah,
and re-institute of all provisions of
prop proposition one 87 the notes talk
about building more schools.
Sorry, I used to always vote yes.
And these now Sacramento
has changed my vote.
I always vote no on school bonds.
Quid pro quo baby.
What is quid pro quo me?
Where the fuck is it?
Quid pro quo meaning I love that
everybody else is dumb as me.
A favor or advantage granted or
expected in return for something.
Ah, that doesn't get me any closer
to understanding it. Quid pro quo.
Jesus fucking Christ. What it,
what am I on law and order here?
Quid pro quo means and
escape and exchange of goods,
goods or services where one transfer
is contingent upon the other English
speakers. Often is this tit for
tat? Yeah. Jesus fucking Christ.
English speakers often use the
term to me a favor for a favor.
Phrases with similar means would include
give and take tit for tat and you
scratch my back. I'll
scratch yours. Quid pro quo.
Agha sets the fucking snooty
way of saying that shit.
Let's go back to close the borders
here so I can try to figure out what is
fucking point is. Oh, I get it. Close the
fucking borders and then I'll fucking,
then I'll, I'll give money to this
side. I see what the guy saying.
I don't know if it's right or not.
Alright, fuck politics. All right.
You know what I try.
I fucking tried.
All freckles has flipped
out about technology and I
figured out how to watch the
NHL on my phone because so many in the
room knew how to do it and they walked me
through it and at one point I
started to get upset because they go,
it's not going on. He goes,
what do you mean it's not going?
And that's supposed to go on down.
And I go and then I started getting mad
about why would it go? Why, why, why,
why would it get on?
It's me if I'm fucking on edge.
Just brought it down and bring it down.
Bring it down. You know what I mean?
Like you ever see somebody like revving
up the engine ready to do a burnout.
Then I brought it all the way down,
you know,
before the tire stopped moving and I
realized that was not the tires I was
actually burning up the clutch.
It's one of the most disgusting things
you'll ever see is somebody trying to do
a fucking burnout. And I don't know what
happens. I still don't quite understand.
I've never done one. I just never
wanted to beat the shit out of my car.
I basically get it with a stick shift.
I don't know how you do
it with an automatic, I've
watched fucking the videos,
but it's basically you get your
premiums up, you let the clutch out,
and then you stomp on the fucking break.
See,
your tires are already fucking going.
But somehow if you fucked that up,
you let the clutch out. And you've
revving the engine and Jan, Jan, Jan,
Jan, your tires aren't fucking moving
and you burn out your clutch and it's,
I don't know what that smells like,
but the smoke is evil looking. Um,
all right, let's move on here. Oh,
did anybody watched the
Patriots game yesterday? Clear.
Get over there and lay down every always
and about you. Go on, go lay down,
go lay down.
I can't even fucking begin to
tell you how much I enjoyed that.
The fact that the fucking
patriots beat the pills yesterday.
I didn't say this because I take
off beforehand because I take a nod.
I get what bill Bellacheck does in
his press conferences where he's like,
I'm not going to say anything
negative about anybody.
I'm not going to give you any
advantages because you fucking fat.
Cats in the media are going to take this
and give bulletin board material for
the other team.
I got to tell you,
watching the fucking buffalo
bills and we played them,
we had a third string quarterback with
a broken fucking hand or whatever the
fuck was wrong with them.
How they got in his face before the game
with such a Bush League fucking move to
the point like I've always liked buffalo.
I might be done with that franchise.
Like I used to give a shit. Ah,
you know, they lost four in a row.
Now I'm just like, you know
what? Fuck them. You know,
it's like you're that insecure that
you're not going to win the fucking game.
That you got to try to pull some shit
like that. And I was just like that.
Then I was just thinking, you're like,
you know what? Two great things happen.
We lost.
So now we don't have to deal with the
pressure of the fucking undefeated season.
All of the extra media hype that comes.
If New England's going undefeated,
if you fucking Indianapolis with old
fucking, what the fuck's his name there,
Peyton Manning, you can be all the way
to 13 and owe nobody say nothing man.
They right down the street, them
cows. Right? So he took that away.
And then also I'm like the Patriots
are going to beat the shit out of this
fucking team the next time
because of that bullshit.
Cause I know in house they must
have talked about it and they go,
he get 41 fucking points. Whatever
the fuck we scored against.
You haven't said all that.
I'd like to say a lot of positive things
like tie Rod Taylor is like impossible
to fucking tackle.
I know the bills had a bunch of fucking
injuries and I'd make those excuses,
but they don't give a fuck
those fucking animals.
They don't give a shit.
They would talk at all kinds of
trash with third string quarterback.
Like they were coming out on the field
getting ready to lose another fucking
Superbowl. I love that. You fucking
ringless I love that you four three.
Hey Buffalo. We're on our way to the
playoffs. See you next year. Fuckos
wow,
I enjoyed
that.
I really fucking enjoyed that.
You know fucking Rex Ryan told
them to do it too. Oh God.
I've been waiting to go off on this.
You fucking get out there and you fucking
fucking fucking fucking cause we the
best fucking fucking in the
fucking EFC. Fucking east. Yeah.
Go have another fucking hero.
You're tub of shit.
If you want to talk about cheating, you
know we let a little air out of the ball.
He got fucking that dead stomach.
Gastric surgery.
He's not fees a fat fuck.
He cheated
letting air out of the ball.
He had a fucking choke out three quarters
of his stomach so you could actually
see his dick every once in
a while. Ah, sorry. Sorry.
Anyways, um, yeah, I and,
and I gotta tell you something else
to fucking watching this world series.
I've gone back and forth,
back and forth and back and forth about
who the fuck I'm rooting for. I mean,
how do you do it?
One team's waiting fucking
70 not quite 70 years, right?
68 years. Say what it
is yet. I'm 68 years.
The other team has even been the
fucker world series is 71 years.
And I know you guys think of a pill.
You're a fucking red sox fan.
How can we not for the cubs.
I was totally for the cubs until I saw
the 30 for 30 on on fucking apartment
and when I watched it, all of
their, hey, let's play too.
You know, hey, you know where the lovable
fucking losers. We always show up.
We just root for him.
All of that went out the window the way
that they fucking what the what they did
to their kid.
I just looked at that shit going like,
that's exactly what would have happened
if someone in Boston did that. New York,
Philly, Cleveland, these cubs fans
for all their fucking, you know,
Mr. Smith goes to watch Washington
fucking a apple pie and Chevrolet way that
they did. They're just like
us. They're fucking animals.
I'm not saying there is bad as bills.
Fans are that fucking franchise.
Those costs. The time I was wearing a
patriots hat, it was the bills, jets.
I was rooting for the bills.
I'm taking a piss in the bathroom and
pushed me from behind while I was taking
the piss.
What kind of a fucking coward?
Maybe there's a reason in the last
four and a fucking row, you know,
I used to think it was because a madly,
he was just too nice to win a fucking
Superbowl and he went up against Jimmy
Johnson. Let's get him some
hookers in a corvette. Right. Um,
and fucking whatever that other guy's
name is Jerry Jones with his real
housewife fucking looking face.
Good Lord.
The guy always looks like, you know, he,
she got like first degree burns on his
face or maybe like slightly like into the
second degrees, but he
was like, all right,
he refused medical treatment and he
just puts some savvy on his face. Um,
I know I'm going hard this week. I
don't know why. I have no idea why.
I'll tell you why. You know, why?
Cause last night I wanted to fucking
come home and do my God damn podcast,
but my wife, you know, wanting to
watch a scary movie. So I said,
okay, let's watch it. So we started
watching that, but they'll cut, took,
took whatever the fucking that thing is.
And I got about like,
I got about 40 minutes into their
movie and it's like, I mean,
I don't want to watch the rest of this.
All right.
I hate watching scary movies because I,
I buy in,
I fucking buy in and I'm just like,
I don't want to watch this
thing terrorizing this
woman in their kid for the
next fucking 90 God damn minutes.
Cause I know neither one of them is
going to die. And I'll eventually,
they're going to figure out how to put,
put Doka took back into the fucking thing
and then they're going to do something
with the book that lets me know that
there's going to be another one.
Cause they're always, you know, fucking
horror movies can never just fucking end.
You know what I mean?
Every one of them,
they got to get greedy like
Friday the 13th part fucking 97,
you know what I mean? Nightmare
on elm street. You know,
they did like 20 of those hell raiser,
15 evil dead parts six.
They just want to keep fucking going.
And, uh, I dunno, I just, I just don't
like fucking sitting there being,
having anxiety, you know?
And with each scene,
you think gradually going to
ramp it up the first time. Oh,
it's just a little bit of knocking and
then there's a shadow and then, you know,
I was just like,
this syncs going to,
I got a bad feeling this thing's going
to kill the dog and I don't want to
fucking see that.
All right.
They already foreshadowed in the book that
that's what's, what's going to happen.
You know, they kind of showed you
basically with the pop up book, fuck off.
If you think I'm ruining this, this,
it's this. It's like paint by numbers.
I every fucking one of them I get an
upset because I just hate, so I was like,
I don't want to watch the rest of this.
So she ends up shutting it off and
then she's like fucking pissed.
She's like fucking pissed at me. And
it's just like, I like Westworld.
My wife doesn't give a
fuck about Westworld.
I'm still on episode two cause I mean,
I didn't want to fucking watch it.
She's like,
Nah,
I want to watch the real housewives of
fucking saint or whatever the fuck it is.
So anyways,
let me get back to the cubs thing.
So right out of the gate,
not only is the country,
it seems for the,
for the Chicago cubs,
it's kind of having this vibe of this
foregone conclusion that they're kind of
going to win this thing.
So I have family or I had family
back in the day out in Ohio,
my grandmother worked for the
Cleveland Press, you know, and um,
way back in the day I had family, you
know, I just had family about their right.
And so growing up I kind of was,
you know,
I was always a red sox
fan, but, uh, you know,
I Kinda, you know, through my relatives
also kind of rooted for the Indians,
you know what I mean? Like, I
didn't, I didn't mind the Indians,
even though they were in our
division way back in the day, um,
that and the Tigers, you know what
I mean? Just cause of, of relatives,
cousins and all that shit.
So I was just like, you know,
I kinda like the fucking Indians
any now that Steve Bartman Shit,
like the level that they took that too.
That's exactly what would have happened
in Philly and all this shit if it,
if it happened out in la,
that poor kid he got killed.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
Or San Diego or Sacramento or Fresno
or one of these fucking lunatic fucking
cities out here where they take
sports Oakland way too seriously.
San Francisco, you know? Um,
so it made me just kind of
fucking sort of pull back.
And then also it's like I,
you know what,
I'm kind of over these fucking cities
that have two professional teams in one
sport.
It's like Chicago won a world series,
they won it in 2005 and that whole
fucking thing where it's like,
well that was just, there was for the
south side of the city, so, so what,
you need another one for the north side?
Fuck the white sox and the cubs at
this shit. If she, one of them wins,
just fucking jump on a subway or walk
three blocks downtown or uptown and join
the fucking parade already.
Same thing with the Yankees and the mets,
the Lakers and the clippers in everything
in fucking New York giants, jets,
Yankees meds, fucking rangers,
islanders, Nixon Nets.
Just fuck off with that shit already.
It's a New York team.
If they win by you championship hat and
go down there and just be happy that
especially in New York,
that you're so fucking filthy,
stinking fucking rich that you can have
eight teams or everybody else is doing,
doing back flips, that they just
have one in every sport. You know?
I know.
Isn't it amazing that New York has all
those fucking teams and they don't win
that much? You think that
Jesus Christ, you got eight,
eight at bats every fucking year.
The fucking Yankees,
I swear to God, I like the sugar daddy
of New York City. You know what I mean?
The giants are the son and everybody
else is getting read written out of the
will. That's basically how it
works with the sports in New York.
Do you know what New York should get
three teams in every fucking city.
Maybe they could fucking do something
other than the Yankees and the giants.
I have totally fucking respect for them.
But Jesus Christ the fucking next
should combine with the nets, you know,
make like a fucking dream team.
And those two shits shows,
same thing with the Rangers
in the islanders. You know,
I dunno the jets and the mets,
I don't know what they should do.
They should both retire and they
should start playing badminton. Um,
oh chase spelled. Um, so anyways,
so I'm really fucking sitting
there and I'm unloving,
seen Terry Francona killing it and it
gets all the way up to three games to one.
All right.
And I dunno, something happened.
Okay. My Cleveland friends,
Comedians,
one of them in particular just starts,
he's just talking all this shit in
Blahblahblahblahblah and he starts to got,
we won the basketball, now we're going
to win the baseball. Then you know,
you watch,
we're going on a fucking run,
your Yada with no fucking respect that
he's talking to a fan from Boston.
You know what I mean? It's just like, oh,
you're going to win two in one
fucking year. Yeah, we did that.
We did that a couple of times
and then we went every fucking,
we did all of this other shit. I'm not
fucking throwing that in your face.
I'm always the guy going like Anna.
Now they'll say they
don't know the team stuff.
I never believe we're going to do
it until we do it and then we do.
Then I'm fucking psyched.
And you'd go back to my podcast.
I wasn't even a country beach Seattle.
So these guys are acting like such
fucking cunts. You know what I mean?
Oh, we got Luke Brian. We're
going to fucking do it again
this year. All the Brown.
Oh, you mean the guy that you guys all
burned his Jersey and you're all done with
first. He called that one. Oh,
Paul Versey called that one.
Paul Versey fucking when he was in Miami
and he's Cleveland fans were saying,
fuck that guy. Blahblahblahblah
first. He said to him,
you guys are all going to be sucking
his dick when he comes back to town.
And they were like, no way. That's
never gonna happen while it's happening.
That whole city's on their fucking nice.
So anyways,
so at some point after they went up three
games to one, I went back to the cubs.
The reality is,
is I don't give a shit who wins this
fucking thing because it's going to be
great for one city. It's going to
be devastating for the other city.
Um, obviously. But so here's the deal.
This is what's at stake with this
world series. If the cubs win,
the Indians become the cubs.
They become the ones that have gone
the fucking longest. All right?
So they can't fucking lose.
All right? If Cleveland wins,
all right? Not only the
cubs, still the cubs,
as far as my quick research research
showed me the next people in line for
second place would be the cult 40 fives
slash Houston Astros that started in
in 1962 the Chicago cubs,
we're already 54 years into their drought.
Yeah.
Okay.
1962 is 54 years from where
the fuck we are right now.
Right.
So the Astros' are 54 years into their
drought where the cubs were in 1962 and
the cubs are now twice
that at one oh eight.
I don't know what the fuck that means.
Does that mean that you should
go play the lottery right now?
54 62 one zero eight.
I have no idea what that fucking means.
It's just, you know, one of those,
one of those number things.
Um,
I gotta tell you,
uh,
it's almost fitting that if
the cubs are gonna win it,
that they would torture their fucking
fans to this level and it's fitting that
if the Indians were going to lose it,
they would go up three to one to
lift their fucking teams hopes.
This is why I think
the cubs are gonna win.
If Terry Francona wasn't in the dug out
the master, by the way, he, he needs,
that guy needs a,
a nickname like the assassin.
He needs like a boxer nickname,
like lights out James Tony,
you know,
for the execution or Bernard Hopkins
that he needs a name like that.
It's just said he doesn't look like that.
But that's exactly what that guy is.
All right.
But what I'm saying is
because of what these teams
have done to their fans,
it would be fitting that the fucking
cubs wouldn't just go in and win the
fucking thing. So their fans could just
relax and finally enjoy. Oh series.
They would have to go down three
to one before they'd come back.
And then Cleveland couldn't
just lose the series.
They'd have to go up three games to one.
Okay?
So this is what's crazy about three gear
up, three games to one, and you're like,
holy fuck,
you're starting to take the wire off the
champagne bottle at that point. Right?
But then all of a sudden you fucking
lose game five and just instantly,
it's like, holy fuck, if we lose
the next one, it's all tied up.
So now the pressure is on
the Indians. I'll tell you,
the cubs are going in there.
They're playing loose.
They got nothing to lose other
than fucking 108 year drought.
Okay?
I don't know who's on the mound.
I don't know what. But, um,
I'm going to say the obvious
cubs gotta go. They gotta stick,
got a score early and make the
fucking Indians tighten up.
That's what the fuck they got to do.
Or a,
that's what's going to happen in game six.
Either the cubs are going to score early.
Indians fucking tighten up.
Okay.
And then lose a game and then we get a
game seven. Or if the Indians go up early,
it's going to be a bloodbath.
It's going to be a shit show. Um,
okay.
I'm hoping the first thing
happens because I want to see,
I want to see a game seven against a
team that hasn't won an hundred and eight
years in a team that hasn't won it.
Fucking, uh, what is it? 68 fucking years?
68. So adorable to a red sox fan.
That's fucking hilarious. I am,
I don't give a fuck. That's like this.
Whether we were there in like the 70s,
right? What was 68 for us?
I was at the met, let's see,
1918 to 1978.
That's 60 years,
right? Uh, yeah. 86.
I was 1986. So you're just didn't
bill Buckner go fuck yourselves.
You know,
you just did.
Bacter as far as where I'm coming from,
you got to go another fucking,
uh,
another 18 years to 2004.
So I guess I won't root for the Indians.
Nah, I can't. I fucking, I don't know.
My relatives got me into the Indians.
I don't know what to dope.
I don't know who to root for here.
You know,
I'm rooting for farm room for game seven
route for game seven and then they're
going to go up against each other and
one team is finally going to win that
critical game seven and get
the monkey off their back.
And then another one is just going to
add another giant cinder block right on
the fucking heart. So they've
fans, it's kind of, Oh God,
this one has trained right.
Written all over it. All right.
Let me read a little bit of
fucking average advertising
art. Jesus. The appeal.
You didn't fucking copy and paste them.
Um,
yeah.
I hope by the way you guys are
watching the series because it's,
it's been unbelievable. What a
fucking great series. It's bad. Um,
oh Christ, what am I doing? Come on
bill. Click here. Click there. All right.
How many do we got here? All right. Ah,
okay. Here we go. Oh, Lou crate everybody.
Gimme the loot. Are you
looking for gear, collectibles,
housewares and more and more,
um,
from your favorite pop culture franchise?
We've got you covered.
This is how like hipsters and I,
I guess nerds get laid, you know,
this is all about loot crates
should be like nerd crate, you know,
and just be like a pocket pussy in there
or something. Uh, we've got you covered.
Loot crate offers a range of Geek and
Gamer items for less than $20 a month.
Gamers are weird. They're either total
nerds or they are like fucking jocks.
Have you noticed that?
Okay.
Like video games kind of
transcend like the whole, uh,
what was it Matthew Broderick movie
war games sort of thing. You know,
we get the underwear on top
of your head and you're like
trying to make a woman
through your computer rather
than just fucking getting a
hooker. Like a normal kid who plays sports
with hand eye coordination. You just,
you know, cause what it is as nerds don't
know how to flag down a hooker like,
or an athlete, you know, sends the
signal to his athletic hand, you know,
and just brings him in. All right. You
want to bring your loop to the next level.
Get a bigger box with even
bigger loop with loot crate DX.
If you're more than the tie.
I would love to see the sizes of these
fucking tee shirts. What do they start at?
Um,
I just picture everybody
goes to comic con.
Looks like a young Burt
for Lanch Bruce for land.
She was at fucking guy
with the red glasses.
Who thinks he's fucking hilarious and
writes all the speeches for people.
Um, he's really the craft of writing
jokes and he has those Sally Jessy Raphael
glasses. Um, if you're more than,
than the type to where your Geeky,
he looks like, uh, like you
know where the wild things are,
like the way he has his hair and shit.
Um,
if you're more than the type to where
you're geeky heart on your sleeve than Lou
where,
sorry.
Our monthly wearables and accessory
subscription is the droids you're looking
for,
um,
that she'll running up your spine is
in your imagination. It's loot crates,
October theme horror.
We're taking over 40 years of creepy campy
bloody icons and putting them in this
month's loot crate,
channeling your best final girl with
items from the walking dead nightmare on
elm street.
Friday the 13th,
Texas chainsaw massacre and Halloween.
What's final girl?
I'm going to look that up.
You have until the 19th at 9:00
PM Pacific to subscribe. Well,
it's the fucking 31st and 19th of what?
Um,
that month's crate. And when the
cutoff happens, then it's over.
Make sure to head over to
www.lucrelukerate.com/burr
enter the code burr to save
$3 off any new subscription today.
Just go to the website.
I don't know what the
fuck they're offering now.
I'm sure there's some soda horror
movie that had a Turkey in it, right?
So then I'll take you into
November. Oh yeah. What's his face?
What's his face there? We did
reservoir dogs. Quintin Tarantino.
He did that movie facts you're giving
up. All right. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody. Um, guys, you know,
to go to dollar shave club for
a fantastic shave there. Uh,
what you probably don't know is that
they have other amazing products to the
quality is the best on the market.
Their bodywash is gray and
won't dry out your skin.
They're pre-shave and post shave
stuff keeps your skin soft and smooth.
Um, there's stuff we'll see. I have you
looking and smelling like 1 million bucks.
Oh, well it must have just came from the
men man, because money's pretty filthy,
right?
You don't want to put that anywhere near
you at dollar shave club's got stuff
for your hair, for your
face, for your underparts,
for everywhere you want to keep you and
to keep you feeling and looking fresh.
Once you're in the club,
you'll see they got the best grooming
products out there and they're affordable
right now.
Your is right now is your chance to see
for yourself why so many people love
dollar shave club. If you're not a
member yet and I've never joined,
now's the time. You'll get
your first month of razors
for free. Just pay shipping,
and that's only a few bucks.
Join today.
Go to dollar shave club.com/bird that's
dollar shave club.com/burn and it's
actually great shit.
You know what I mean?
You look and smell great when you
go on a date. You know what I mean?
That's good for the ladies.
You know,
maybe there'll be a little less upset
and you're going to make your move that
night. Um, all right, what
do I want to talk about now?
Let's go. Let's go to, uh,
oh. I went down to, um,
I went down to lago last night.
Been slugging through
my new fucking bullshit,
trying to see where the, uh, the
new hours going to come from.
And uh, I dunno. We'll see. We'll see.
All I know is I don't have any
fucking road gigs till February,
so I can just totally chill out.
I've been working out and eating
like a fucking animal though.
You know what made this Pumpkin
bread and shit? You know,
Rogan gave me some of the Elk Burger.
I made it late last night and then it
has slice of Pumpkin bread after it.
So it's weird. It's like I'm in really
good shape, but I also got this belly. Um,
but uh,
I dunno,
like I love the fucking holidays and
to me the holidays is your throat down,
your cook. You make stuff for your
friends. You know what I mean? Fuck that.
I'm not getting a fucking bottle
of champagne. You know what?
I'm going to finish this fucking podcast
and I'm going to go and make some
Goddamn pumpkin bread and
write and I'll show my wife.
I'll show her who's boss,
by the way,
you guys really enjoyed that
two hour podcast, Huh? Um,
I think we just went into a zone.
A two hour podcast is a long ass fucking
time and unless you hanging with Joe
Rogan, uh, who I hung out
within a, finally got him on
the podcast last Thursday.
If you missed it once again,
he has a new amazing standup
special called triggered. Um,
we talked about everything from hunting
elk and wild fucking bore to uh,
working out UFC shit, election
stuff, stand up comedy.
Um, just had a great fucking time. Um,
it's about his specialist on Netflix,
so definitely check it out if you
get a chance. And uh, all right,
let's get back to, um,
let's get back to the, uh,
the podcast here. Oh, F
one action in f one action.
I totally missed the fucking race, but I
read up on it. Lewis Hamilton wins again.
For those of you sort of keeping score,
now that I've been keeping score, um,
you get 25 points.
If you win 18th or second 15th.
The third then is 12, 10,
eight, six, four, two, one,
right? That's the top, bottom,
top, fucking 10 works. Um, Cleo,
you could not be more adorable right
now and what it is she wants fod.
I got up a little bit to do this podcast.
So now she's come over,
she sat down next to me,
her ears are down and she's rested her
head on my arm and she's just staring at
me like,
I don't know what's going on.
All right, today I've got another 20
minutes. Just fucking relax. No, no, no,
no. Not coming up on the couch. Go on.
Go lay down. Go lay down. Go lay down.
Up.
Get out of here please.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ. What the fuck
again? It get out of here. Cleo.
Get off of the couch. Way
down. Oh, now she's needy.
All right.
Anyways,
so Rosberg had a fucking league
and the last two fucking racist.
Hamilton is one boat.
So he's shaved 14 fucking
points off of the lead.
All fucking Nico had to do
is fucking win one more race.
I felt if he could have won it yesterday,
he could have wrap this thing up.
I'm kind of glad that he didn't cause I
want to see the person fucking wrap it
up. Um, so the next race
I believe is in Brazil,
which is not until November 13th.
And I apologize to a f one fans because
I know I got into this shit and then
I've just dropped the ball and like
the last four or five ones, but I,
I'm fucking living in this God damn
house. I fucked up. I forgot that,
that it was this week and that I actually
figured out through apple TV or some
shit that I patiently worked my way
through and actually figured out that I
could actually get, uh, was an NBC
sports. Is that the name of the channel?
And I could have watched the game.
She could watch the race.
So I got to go home today,
my house around the fucking
corner tape that fucking thing.
By the way, the kitchen is just come to a
grinding fucking halt. I don't know why,
but there's still telling us that they
gonna Finish on fucking time. So whatever,
whatever, I'm sure they will
fucking sure they will. All right,
let's get out of this. Let's, let's
do some, uh, can I talk about now?
Did you guys watch Clemson,
Florida? Fucking amazing
game. I also watched the, uh,
my Clemson, Florida, Florida state.
Then I also watched a Florida
fucking Georgia and, you know,
I was thinking when I first saw it, I was
just like, man, I got to go to that game.
I got to go to that game of Jacksonville.
The biggest outdoor cocktail party in
the world is they say, and I'm like,
I bet the fans are cool with each
other. They're fucking, you know,
cause it's a neutral site,
you know,
everybody's just psyched to be
away from their house. Sorry,
I'm fucking you on or near,
um,
Georgia scores first they cut to
the Georgia fans in the stands.
And I clearly see this guy turned around
not facing the field and just giving
the finger to the Florida fans
above them. And I'm just like, wow.
All right. It's at that level. Okay, it's
a dead fucking level. I die. You know,
I really had no interest in
going to that game. I'd want,
I want to go to the swamp.
And I've been to what Georgia home game
between the hedges and I've been to a
Jacksonville verse Bangles Games.
So I felt like I'd been to that stadium.
But after seeing it was like fuck when
it looks like fun and I always have a
great time at Jacksonville.
Everybody shits on Jacksonville.
It's a good fucking time. If you
take the stick out of your ass, um,
you can go to a gun range,
shoot guns with the without the fucking
silence around. All right, clear.
The only thing I'm going to do is just
sit here and pet you as I do the rest of
this. All right. All
right, Westwood Dear Bill.
Uh, glad you love Westworld.
For some reason he wrote
Westwood and the beginning.
Glad you love Westworld.
Uh,
I look forward to hearing your thoughts
and the rest of the season season. Um,
if you like that and you're
looking for a great movie to watch,
checkout the 13th floor.
It came out in the late nineties
and deals with similar themes.
Are you into reading fan theories?
A common one now that is a non spoiler
is that Ed Harris's character and the
nice guy who's new to the park or the
same person and other claims that it's
actually all on Mars. Oh, for Westworld.
Yeah. Well I got to get caught
up before people ruined shit.
I'll definitely check out
the 13th floor and I think I'm
going to watch an episode up.
So three of Westworld because I think
they're up to five at this point.
I'm going to watch that today and I'm
going to get caught up. And uh, you know,
cause my wife fucking cheated on
me with TV. You know what I mean?
When you guys have your shows,
right?
We watched that show below deck
with a yacht scan on their right.
And uh,
it's just,
it's a reality show that we can both watch
because they're always in the fucking
Mediterranean. They got a fucking yacht.
It's the Shit we always think, ah,
we should do that.
It'd be fucking awesome.
And then you look up the prices and it's
like the price of a house to rent one
of those fucking things.
You gotta be like Beyonce and Jay z,
like both of you can sell out the Rosebowl
on any given fucking night. You know,
you gotta be to that level
of wealth to fucking justify.
Do you realize that two of
them almost worth $1 billion.
So for then the blow 250 grand
on a fucking yacht is like,
let's say you're worth $100 million.
If you're with $100 million,
250 grand is like 0.25% of your money,
right?
Cause a million is like 1%, right?
So I don't know how to work that out.
It's like 25% of 1% whatever
the fuck that is of your money.
And there were 10 times set so
that that's like you and I go, hey,
you want a yacht for a week and you
take a penny out of your pocket and you
break it into four fucking pieces and
just hand it to them. Hey, you go,
there you go. Yeah, we'd like,
uh, all the amenities. Um,
anyways, I will definitely
be, uh, be checking that out.
Ed Harris is like,
as always,
as always one of the greatest
actors of all fucking time. Um,
I'll watch anything that that guy's,
and I swear to God,
the only thing I never saw his
when he was the one where, Oh God,
fuck,
I'm the only one I never saw was the one
when he played the painter and that got
nominated or he got nominated for an
Oscar. So I still haven't seen that once.
I got to check that out.
All right.
Old Toys a dear Billy potato head.
I love that.
That's a good one.
Cause that kind of shits on my Irish
heritage and then also makes fun of the
shape of my head. Um, if,
if, if you ever have kids,
will you try and expose them to
toys that you enjoyed as a child?
You strike me as a matchbox car kid.
I don't force the toys of my childhood,
all my kids,
but I've put a couple army men in their
general area to give them a chance to
play like I did. I am a huge, um, uh,
Greer of that proponent of that
opponent, of that proponent. Oh,
that's what proponent means you're pro,
right. I never knew what that meant.
I just kind of figured that
out. Oh, Ponant proponent.
Oh, pumpkin bread pro
pumpkin bread. I get it. Um,
yeah, absolutely. I absolutely,
I absolutely will do that.
Um,
my big thing is playing catch and uh,
you know,
I'm going to buy a fucking,
I'm going to buy a, uh,
a lefty glove for myself is what I'm
going to do because I can throw a little
bit with my left hand and rather than
just sitting there firing it into my kid,
I, I'd fucking a, I'm just gonna,
I'm gonna go with the left hand.
We were doing that yesterday.
We had a football, right.
He's placed in where we're renting
here has his fucking great pool.
So it was halftime of the Florida game.
We're out there smoking cigars and shit.
And we finished that up. We've got the
game turned up loud. So the game became,
there was four guys, right? So he
had two on one side of the pool too,
on the other side of the pool. So you
had to throw with your opposite hand,
first person that sent it into the pool
or if he had a catchable ball and it
fell into the pool was uh, I dunno,
whatever the fuck it was. It was,
was that thing,
that word you can't fucking say anymore
because everybody gets offended and it's
not a racial slur, but it is, you
know, you know, you know the word,
nobody said it, but we all knew we had,
you know, without saying, you know,
we're older guys, like that's what
it means. Um, so anyways, uh, yeah,
I would definitely do that. I
was, I was not a matchbox car kid.
I W I was Corgi cars.
We used to call them core g cause we
didn't know it was pronounced Corgi until
we got older.
And I'm so old that I remember when they
had rubber wheels on them and I had the
giant oil truck. I was big,
I had all the race cars,
I had the Johnny players special,
I had the Jackie Steward Elf car and
my mother doesn't throw out shit.
So I still have all of them. Um,
I had one of those, you know,
that kind of racing where the car
just looks like a giant doorstop.
Uh, it wasn't Formula One. It
wasn't, it's not an Indy car racing.
It's not open wheel. It, you know what
the car looks like, a water slide.
Like you could, you could slide from
the fin all the way down to the front.
I don't know what kind. I had a
white and red, one of those, uh,
Lincoln logs,
Lego Lego blocks.
Um,
okay.
You know, stuff like that. I think it's
big to not have to keep your kids. Okay.
You know,
I don't know the guy to get
them outside and you got to,
you got to keep them in their own. Like
I don't, I, I have such a hatred of,
of computers and iPads
and all of that shit. Um,
and kids just love them. I mean,
they go up to it like, you know,
liquid television type of shit.
You know, back in the day, the MTV,
I remember that graphic. I used to just
make me want to sit down and watch it. Um,
I dunno, Mr Potato head. I don't know
about that. Definitely like board games.
I think it'd be fun playing cards.
I think it's cool to expose
your kids to that, you know,
so they have like that old school shit.
Like it wasn't always the greatest.
Like when like for me,
if I met, uh, some woman,
I took her out on a date and she had,
she had some old school stuff about her,
you know what I mean? That, that
stuff that was sort of passed down.
I think that's really like a cool
thing. And I think, uh, like some shit,
like playing cards, playing
catch, like going outside,
it's just like, you know, riding bicycles,
just like all that shit is going away.
And um,
I'm not one of these old people that
I look at young kids and injury. Like,
you know, what are they
doing today? They're fucking
nuts. And these kids today,
they don't get it. And it's just like, um,
I totally get why they're doing it
because I had to tap out grand theft auto
three in like 2003 or 2004 Id.
I unplugged my playstation and
stick it in the back of the closet.
I literally just one day,
it was like the fifth day in a row,
I was just playing all day
long and I could not stop.
I had already beat the game, I got
the cheats, I did all of that shit.
And then I was just going on rampages
every night just shooting up to city.
And um,
I just,
you know,
I kinda just lost everything else in my
life that wasn't writing jokes and all
that shit.
So that was like 13 years ago.
So I can't imagine how
amazing the Games are.
And um,
like the virtual reality
goggles and all of that shit,
I can't even fucking imagine like how you
get your kid to go in the backyard and
just have a game of catch back. To me,
that's the greatest fucking thing ever.
I think it's a great to
communicate with your kid,
you know what I mean? Cause it's like you
don't, that's another activity going on,
so they're not really paying attention.
You can praise him when they're doing
well, you know, build up their confidence.
And then you just slide into how's
it going at school, you know,
and then you just read them third.
It's going great. All right,
so it's going good to be here. Same
kind of looked down and I, you know,
it's all right.
Oh,
it's a matter of what's going on
and they can kind of open up to you.
I think it's like a great way to,
uh,
I think it's really important
early on to be able to do that.
To have your kid be able to come to you
if they have a fucking problem is a,
a is a huge thing. But, um,
how you sit there with a
glove and a ball and uh,
how that competes with putting on
fucking reality glasses and you feel like
you're going to fucking base jump off of
a building or whatever the fuck they do.
I don't know what the fuck they do with
those six. Um, yeah, that's a, uh, that's,
that's a difficult, that's a difficult
one. I love Lincoln logs. I lie.
He didn't like Lego blocks.
She stepped on him and your bare feet,
they fucking hurt. Not the Lincoln logs.
Didn't, but like that plastic shit.
I wasn't into that as much as,
uh, the Lincoln logs are cool.
We used to fucking build those things.
We build houses and then we would,
you know what their Corgi Corgi car,
Corgi cars,
wherever the fuck are they called,
drive him around.
We'd have traffic jams and
all of that type of shit.
We had names for everybody
that drove the cars.
I remember I had all the
fucking race cars and in all my,
uh,
it's weird.
They drove like a formula one car to
work and then they drove the trucks.
I had trucks and racing cars.
Then my other brother,
who's a total fucking gearhead,
he actually liked like
the real looking cars,
like a Volkswagen bug,
like a station wagon.
Like he wanted to look like the cars that
you could actually fucking drive. Um,
I know my mother didn't throw all of
those out. Jesus Christ is fucking nuts.
They're all up in the attic
somewhere. All right. Election Bill.
The election is right around the
corner. A couple of weeks ago. You,
you'll eulogize the great barrier reef.
Any last words for this election?
Uh, not the country as a whole because
I don't think it will fall apart by an
imagined.
This has exposed the side of our country
that we've been able to keep under
wraps for awhile,
which is that no one ever pays attention
to anything unless it's an easy talking
point.
MMM.
Not everything is more fucked up
than we know or would like to admit.
What's the worst thing that will
happen if either candidate wins?
Uh,
well,
if Trump wins,
the worst thing is we're going to have
to listen to all these European countries
talk about how dumb Americans are,
especially people in England.
And I just want to say to them like,
you know what,
what if you threw out the
person every 48 years?
And I would love to see what the fuck
you end up with. You know what I mean?
Some years it's just not a
good draft. If fucking, uh,
whatever the fuck his is. Tony Blair,
that guy's been in there since Bush.
Not even saying that guy's good,
but you just get somebody in there and
they just stay there until they die.
Doesn't he have like Margaret Thatcher's
job? Oh, the original Hillary Clinton.
Hillary Clinton can't even
see her fucking name. Wow.
What's the worst that will happen?
Um,
I dunno if Trump wasn't such a fucking
jerk off if he wasn't such a jerk off.
It's really what the country needs.
You need somebody who isn't a part
of the fucking system. You don't,
but you just can't have
a guy like that in there.
And then Hillary is just going
to be more of the fucking same.
It's just going to keep driving
this country towards ruined.
Do none of them talked about
the population problem?
None of them talked about the
nationwide heroin epidemic.
None of them talked about
genetically altered food.
fucking global warming.
Maybe they touched on it for a second.
They haven't said Shit.
They're not going to do anything. None
of. I'm going to try to stop the banks,
put them in fucking line that building
another real estate bubble. I'll tell you,
it's fucking hilarious out here is
they are building up la like I've never
fucking seen.
They bought up the house of Blues right
across the street from the fucking, um,
from the fucking uh, uh, comedy store.
They play like $28 million for the thing.
They're going to put these,
these high rise fucking million dollar
multimillion dollar fucking condos in
there. It's like, who the fuck's going
to afford to buy those things? All right,
and this is the thing, after
2008, after we saw what happened,
they fucking gave the house.
None of the bankers went to jail.
They gave him the houses back so
they could do it all over again.
They're building another fucking bubble
and I'm already calling it right now by
fucking 20, 21, 20, 22 or some shit,
there is going to be a bunch
of empty fucking condo.
Fucking high rises going along
the sunset stripped and they have,
they've knocked down the rainbow room, the
Roxy, the wicks whiskey house of Blues,
maybe the comedy store. They're going
to wipe out all of these fucking things.
There's going to be
nobody in those buildings.
And even if they are in those buildings,
they going to have no fucking place to
go cause they knocked down all the cool
places to hang out on sunset strip.
It's so fucking stupid. You know,
I was getting gas the other day and
another place on the sunset strip and this
guy said, I said, hey, you
own the gas station. He goes,
I wish I did this property just sold
for 14 million bucks. And you know,
they're knocking down the two buildings
next to it and they're going to put up a
fucking, you know, 170
unit fucking, I dunno,
I just don't know where all these
people are going to becoming.
That can afford to pay. I just don't
know where they're going to come from.
Um, and from what I heard, you
know, at least the ones on Lassie,
Annika that was like oil money,
you know,
like Saudi Arabia and money came in
and they don't give a fuck. I mean,
they get money forever. Um, I dunno.
Uh, what's the worst thing
that will happen if either
candidate comes in is that
they're not going to stop
what's already going on.
And I gotta be honest with you, I
don't even think like, you know,
all the Bernie Sanders and
all those types of people,
you would literally need an army of
those people and then they would need
bulletproof vests to fucking,
that's how powerful corporations are.
And that's how off the
fucking rails we are.
MMM.
I Dunno.
Which is why I'm trying to focus on the
propositions and I wish if anybody can
find a fucking website out there that
not only lets me know what I'm voting for
but lets me know what is attached to it.
Like cause who doesn't want to
improve the schools, you know?
MMM.
But you know, whenever they
have stuff like that, like, hey,
let's clean up the drinking water,
then they attach all this
other evil shit underneath it.
Um,
I don't know.
I Dunno. It's, it's all very overwhelming.
So it's so fucking overwhelming that
you're asking extend up comedian,
what's going to happen or maybe you just
did cause you want to hear me make a
fucking ass of myself. Um, all
right, here we go. Cool guy.
Terrible in bed.
Okay.
Oh Jesus. All right. Uh,
dear Billy Bush bear.
Uh, I'm a 20 year old
female college student. Um,
I go to holy cross.
Oh, in, oh, he said is I
go to holy cross. Oh, okay.
I go to holy cross in Worcester.
Um,
I had a boyfriend for the first three
years of college and now I'm single.
I hooked up with a guy that I
didn't know was kind of an asshole.
He sort of popular in seem friendly.
One drunken night.
I did the worst thing I
could do. Fed his ego. Um,
had I known he was a moron in a pompous
Douche bag, I would not have done this.
I'll save you the reasons
why he's a Douchebag,
but just picture lame eighties preppy
bully who thinks he's God's gift.
Again, I didn't know this because
I never paid attention to them.
Well after we hooked up,
he told some people that I told them
he was the best fuck I ever had a this
found its way back to me and
bill. I was shocked. Why?
Because he was the worst fuck I ever had.
A,
he had no idea what he was doing.
He was, for lack of better words,
not present.
No rhythm and average at best.
I wasn't mad at this because it
was my choice to hook up with him,
but now he's putting words in my mouth.
I really just want to tell someone how
bad he was and wait for it to get back
around to him. What does my move here,
Bill and or Nia? Well, wait a minute.
Did you say he was all right?
Okay.
One drunk at night.
I did.
The worst thing I could
do feed is stupid ego.
Okay.
Does that mean that you slept with them?
I can't tell if you buy
feed his ego. Ew. Ew.
He was so bad. You felt like
you had to say something nice.
Now there's no fucking way. You said
there's no way. You said he was the best.
Fuck.
Yeah.
Um, I think you're saying, yeah. Yeah.
I think you're saying that you,
you fed his ego by hooking up with them.
Had I known he was a moron
in a pompous tooth. Okay,
so he's walking around
saying that you said,
and you're also saying it's
putting words in your mouth.
So I'm assuming that you never said that,
so fed his ego means that you
fucking hooked up with them.
That's what I'm guessing. I
don't fucking know. Christ,
they speak speaking riddles.
Um,
I wasn't mad at this because I'm,
yeah,
well, oh, this is a tough one.
I would,
I would call him up. Then
when he picked up, I be like,
why are you walking around saying that?
I said you were the best fuck I ever had.
I never said that.
Yeah.
Okay. I never said that. Okay.
And hear what he says and you know
something that might be a thing.
This is the thing, this fucking,
a lot of these guys like this,
a tremendously insecure, maybe he knows,
he doesn't know what the fuck he's doing.
So he's walking around saying that so
he can feel better about himself because
he feels that awful about himself and
he feels so fucking awful about himself
that not only does he got to go that big,
that the,
the fucking way he feels about himself
is such a big thing that it doesn't mean
that he doesn't even think that that's
going to get back to you or he doesn't
even consider your fucking feelings.
So you can either be the biggest
person and know that this person is,
I'm tremendously insecure and walks around
and probably doesn't like themselves,
which is a fucking horrible feeling
to have and just take peace with that.
Or
you can call a guy out,
which I kind of like, okay,
okay.
And I, and I, you know, and at
that point you got to listen. Uh,
if you were the best fuck I ever had,
I would've said that to you and just
leave it at that because you haven't sold
them that he's completely fucking inept.
You know what I mean?
But you're also kind of putting
the guy in check. Um, then,
then you have your final option,
which is you can go around saying that
he wasn't the best fuck I ever had.
He's fucking terrible
it better than anyone.
What happens is everybody just gets to
sit back and enjoy watching you guys
fucking do this shit.
I understand why you'd want to do it.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I don't do the revenge thing.
I kind of go to the person's that's doing
whatever they're doing that's fucking
annoying me. And I just kind of
chopped the head off there and, uh,
and then if somebody comes up to me
and says what they said, I would say a,
I would just say to him personally,
yeah, that isn't true. I never said that.
I Dunno. I Dunno what the fuck to do. I,
I'm sorry that this happened to you. Um,
and at 20 years of age,
it's probably hard to understand a lot
of the shit that I'm saying that of what
that guy feels about
himself. But, um, you know,
you can't have somebody walking around
saying shit like that about you.
So I would, first thing I would
do, I was confront the guy,
call him up. I'd be like, why are
you saying that? I never said that.
Yeah.
You know?
And uh,
if you continue to say that and if
he kind of goes around, just believe,
if you keep taking you to say that
you're leaving me in a position here,
that I have to tell them the truth.
Okay.
You're not the best fuck I ever
had. All right. I Dunno. It's just,
I don't know that sets, you know, guys,
if you listen to this thing
and you're a young person,
that's such a fucking asshole thing to do.
All right?
That's totally coming from your own
God damn insecurity. All right. And uh,
as an older, wiser fucking man, you know,
I wished that somebody older told me
that when you hook up with somebody,
you keep your fucking mouth
shut. Um, you know what I mean?
You're quiet about it. You know,
it happened. Who gives a fuck?
Who knows? You know what I mean? It's
an insecure fucking move. And, uh, just,
just sit there and then she did this
and then did dead. She fucked it.
Did this like, that's a really
fucking asshole thing to do.
Dumb in women.
If you'll hook up with the guy and he's
fucking terrible or he's got a little
Dick and all that type of shit. Right. Uh,
if he's not out there talking
shit for you to walk around,
fucking doing that too.
That's another fucking asshole move.
It's an asshole move either way. And
in this case, the guy see asshole. So,
um, I dunno, you know something,
if you can hang on until Thursday,
I'll run it by Nia version
again and I'll run it by her.
It's just that she's still
sleeping here, so. MMM.
All right. Let me go.
That's it for the questions.
Let me read the last two
advertisements here and then, uh,
I got some pumpkin bread to
make. All right. Uh, Geek, uh,
buying tickets online for
sports and concerts has been
a confusing process for a
long time.
It's always been hard to find the best
deal for that game or show you want to go
to. And none of those older
tickets sites want to change that,
but it Siki gets different.
They've come along and created an amazing
APP and website that makes it easier
than ever for fans to
buy and sell tickets.
Siki does all the price comparisons for
you by searching multiple tickets sites
and ensuring that you get
the best possible deal and
seek wants to help you get
the most bang for your buck.
That's why every ticket out and seek
is given a grade based on value.
You'll immediately see why any seats you
immediately see any underpriced seats
and be able to find the best
deals fit for your budget.
Best of all my listeners
get a $20 off rebate.
Their first SeatGeek purchase to get $20,
uh,
to get your $20 rebate on tickets,
download the [inaudible] APP,
go to the settings tab and
click add a promo code.
Enter Promo Code Burr seek equals send
you $20 and after you've made your first
ticket purchase, uh Oh after you've
made your first ticket purchase,
download the seat Geek App and
enter the Promo Code burr today.
Alright and stamps.com
now our old friends here,
some small businesses still thinking,
thinking expensive postage.
Meda is the only way to get postage
without having to go to the post office,
but they are
wrong. Wrong, wrong.
This stamps.com ah,
with stamps.com you can easily print
postage for any letter or package using
gesture, computer and printer. Uh,
no marks to hardware to
buy no longterm contracts.
stamps.com can save you at least
50% compared to a meter. Plus.
You could do more with stamps.com
that then you can with the meter,
like sent package tracking information
to recipients with one click the choices
clear stance.com offers more
features at a fraction of the costs.
I had been using stamps.com
for years for my show,
uh,
for my posters.
Actually it makes mailing and
shipping really convenient right now.
Sign up for stamps.com
use my last name burpee.
You are to get a four week trial plus
$110 bonus offer that includes postage and
a digital scale scale. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click on the microphone at the top of
the homepage and type in bur bur are all
right. That is it. That is the
podcast. Uh, let's go cubbies.
I want to see a game seven and then,
um,
it's an, I don't want to see that one.
Are you guys loose? You know what I mean?
You both waited long enough. But, uh,
I gotta root for the cubs in game
six cause I want to see a game seven.
All right. That's it. I got my app.
The NHL APP is working for me now.
I'll be watching Bruins games and that
type of shit and I was going to try to
watch that. A Formula One race, uh, for
all you fucking gearheads out there.
All right, go fuck yourselves.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.