Hey,
what's going on?
It's Bill Burger and it's time for
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
December 24th,
2018 oh it's the most
wonderful time of the year.
You went to your last fucking Christmas
party and you stopped your fat face and
now your wife is going to drag you
to midnight mass God for fucking bid.
You like me? God for fucking
bid. You just stay home one day,
24 hours.
Just fucking stay awake up.
You get fucking go down and get some
breakfast. You scratch your balls, right?
Then you Mosey on into
the fucking living room.
You turn on the heat
10 and build the right.
Nice toasty fucking house
God for fucking bid.
Okay.
God forbid you laze about two when fuck
off as they say across the fucking way
they're right God for fucking pit now.
There's always has to be some fucking
social event you have to go to.
It's unfucking believable. I'm literally
telling her go and like listen to,
this is my time off.
This is,
this is my time off and then it's
just getting immediately January,
second, third, whatever the
fuck it is. I'm on a plane.
The fly to the other side of the fucking
world to essentially do two shows a
night for 10 straight fucking
day. So freckles here. Hey,
no spring chicken anymore.
Can I fucking just,
just can I just stay
here for fucking one day,
one fucking tank fucking
at one fucking day.
I thought it would be nice.
Yeah.
You know what it is due at the end
of the day. They don't give a fuck.
And if they're not slowly killing you,
you're not still married.
That's what it is.
And all these broads out there bitch
moaning and complaining specifically the
white ladies about how difficult it is.
You know the number one stat,
how long you live.
You went in that one.
So go fuck yourself
with your fucking being,
counting whatever the hell they're doing
and show some ridiculous tweet there.
The other day they were talking about the
top 10 fucking gross and comedians and
this other comedian rights,
all male. And it's just like,
how is that guys fault?
How the fuck are you going to put that on
guys? You know, if you look at a census,
there's more women than there are guys.
So I mean, I don't know what to tell Ya.
I just don't know what to fucking tell
you. You know, write a better act.
You know,
ladies,
get out there and go see some female
comics supported better than you support
the wn Ba.
You know what I mean?
Fucking sitting there
yelling at us all the time.
You guys are not exactly team
players out there. Yeah. All right,
so why don't you look in your holiday
mirror? Takeoff is stupid antlers. Jesus.
What the fuck? It's just,
everything is just become that.
Why does it this like wide switch work?
A white male?
Yeah.
Um,
anyways,
this is the boohoo
generation. Um, anyways,
happy holidays, everybody. I thought
I would, this was guy was like, man,
this is fucking new you. This is
Christmas Eve. I don't have shit to do.
And there's just,
there's just always going to be something.
Just every fucking gets like,
how was there always something?
Even God,
every fucking six days he had one
fucking day or he didn't do shit and he
created the universe.
I'm a fucking aunt.
Oh No.
On a fucking the a universe
on top of a fucking pin,
whatever those fucking potheads say.
Okay,
there's a line I'm going to use to my
wife. Just out of curiosity, how do,
how am I working harder than the creator?
The creator of the universe gets
more days off a year than I do.
How the fuck does that work?
I think you're being a little dramatic.
I don't think I am.
Take out a calendar.
Okay.
Oh boy. This is what I do now. I
just, I just go out to the garage.
It's soundproof now cause it
got my drum kit hair and I just,
I lose my shit and then I come out and
I just fucking put a smile on my face.
Like fucking chuck Woolery.
That's what I do.
And I laugh and I rubbed my brow like,
Oh God, you're killing me though. That's,
that's fucking incredible.
Okay.
You know what I want. You don't
want, I want in the new year,
I want one day off a week. Okay. If God
needs a fucking one day, I should have to,
maybe that's why we only work
a five day work week, right?
Yeah.
Visit. We only took one day off. Then we
would say that we were on God's level.
Do you realize the amount of days off
that I don't have puts me that I'm
actually working harder than God and a
couple of hundred years ago or 26 years
ago in the south,
I would actually be killed for this.
What I would be doing was B could be
considered sack religious that I was
putting myself on a higher plane,
that I could actually sit down with God
and be like, Oh, what'd you do? Oh yeah.
Well that's pretty impressive there
a almighty maker of everything,
but let me ask you this.
What's that big goose egg on
on day number seven on Sunday.
What were you doing then?
Ah, yeah. You put your big
fucking creative feed up then.
Yeah.
You got your holy Hammock over there.
It didn't check. Well, guess what?
I kept going,
oh
look what happened to your creation.
You know,
you think if God could come down and
he'd have enough time to fucking bang a
virgin,
you know,
he could maybe fucking yell down my
chimney every once in a while and be like,
hey, hey sweetheart, ease
up. You know, ease up on it.
Maybe they could do that to all the
fucking married women out there.
How about you guys? How about you do
that in the fucking New Year, ladies?
I know we have all this
fucking work to do. God knows.
I've seen enough award shows this year
of women giving me lectures on how to be
a fucking man.
How funny is that?
Well, I get very good man, but you're a
bad man in the bad man. Shit did good.
Shut the fuck up and get your trophy.
Jesus fucking Christ the fucking lectures
and all these fucking guys with their
balls tucked behind there. PNID exercise
just sitting there in the crowd.
That Tuxedo. I don't want to
get in trouble. I'm telling you,
somebody's got to do it out here in
Hollywood. What are these award shows?
Somebody has to throw a dinner
roll. Just has to happen. I mean,
if it's happened to me, I
why? I mean equal rights.
Oh, righto. Ready? All right.
Anyways, you wouldn't know
this, but I was actually,
I was actually in a good mood 10 minutes
ago until I realized there was yet
another fucking thing. I got everything
done. Okay. The fucking trees decorated.
The fucking lights are up.
All the gifts are wrapped.
The last fucking gift that I was
getting my wife to the Cherry on top.
The Cherry Cherry on top.
All right.
You know, I just fucking, I, I, well,
let me just finish that thought.
I finally got that gift. I have
it. There it is. Here it is.
This is what you made to me.
All right.
Now can I have a 24 hour period period,
but I just stay in the house.
Okay.
I stay in the house.
Nobody's coming over.
Nobody's fixing anything.
I don't have to get in the car and
go down and go fucking get something.
I stay right here.
I don't read.
I watch TV. I fucking relax. I put,
I put,
I put my feet up
and for one day
I'm treated like a king is as a,
is that asking too much?
This is like one of those stupid topics.
So one of those fucking lady shows,
ladies, do we need to treat our
men like kings occasionally.
Yeah.
I'm not saying you're not a
queen and that saved the deputy.
Um, anyways, what are you
guys doing for Christmas?
I'm still in know this is my last podcast
holding my headphone Jack here. Like,
like a terrorist.
You don't want my thumb over the top.
MMM.
And uh, I dunno. Then I
guess my life gets easier.
I'm really playing the victim on
all this. I should just be like, no,
I'm not doing that. And
you know, it's funny.
My wife would have no problem with it.
So what does that go back to now?
Of course, back to the childhood.
That's what it goes back to.
I grew up with the sit
down and shut the fuck up.
Okay.
We had that carved into wood
and hung up on the wall.
Sit down and shut the fuck up.
But now I get it. Now I get it.
You gotta get,
you gotta get married and you have to have
a kid to truly understand your father.
Then you get it. It's like,
oh, I totally get them. No,
I totally get the guy I
know. Just coming home. What?
I don't know. Just Ah, get outta here.
Yeah.
MMM.
Anyway, speaking of broad,
Jessica Curson, everybody,
you know,
you want to talk about somebody who
you ladies should be out there fucking
supporting.
So there's not more people whining about
the tour money that people are getting
honestly out there. Um, Jessica Carson,
man or woman,
this is one of the fucking
funniest comedians out there
for a long fucking time.
All things comedy.
We're doing a special with our taping
January 11th at the highline ballroom in
New York City. I'm so
excited for this, uh,
telling you you watch or we're doing an
all things Cardi. Paul Versey special,
by the way,
streaming again on comedy central.
It's broken all their records
for streaming online and
it was named one of the
top 10 specials on Interrobang Bang of
2018 that's a congratulations to the
pride at Trenton, New Jersey,
Paul Versey. Uh, and then we got,
we got Ian Edwards coming out. We get
Jessica cursor with the, until we got,
I'm telling you, telling
you, uh, we got some fucking,
we got some, we got some, we got
some good specials coming up. Um,
in 2019. Can you believe
that's the end of this decade?
These last two decades have flown by
because they haven't really named him.
You know, where was the 60s? It was the
70s. It was the 80s. It was the 90s.
And then it was just nothing. It was
all about, oh my God. Y Two K is, is,
is my fucking flip
phone not going to work.
How will my refrigerator work
at one second past 12:00 AM?
Huh?
We'll uh,
we're gonna party like it's 1999
still be playing on my stereo.
That's what we worried about.
And then all of a sudden
nothing really fucking happened.
There was no arm. Again, I think
a couple people's like little, uh,
well,
those little handheld things with the
stylist that everybody loved to have him
back in the, I think a few of those
crashed, but everything else was fine.
Everything else was fine
and we were so relieved.
Okay,
dad. Uh, we never named the decade
and we just started invaded people.
Yeah.
I Dunno what Trump is doing right now,
but I love bringing troops back.
I'm all for that. You know,
considering all these fucking wars,
if effectively bankrupted this
company, company, this country. Well,
it's just a big corporation now, isn't
it? Yeah. We're gonna bring 'em all back.
Bring them all back. Legalize
weed, put up some solar panels,
put the Middle East dot of business.
Export the fucking we'd get everybody.
Hi Right. Pay off the debt.
Everybody thinks what? Shell again.
Okay.
That's what I would do.
All right?
In any country that still
has a problem with us.
We'll send up some free tee shirts,
couple of sex dolls, and it'll be all,
but whatever the fucking Trump did.
But that fucking fatty
over there in North Korea,
whatever the fuck he did with them,
they went over there, they sat down,
you know, they had some Jalapeno
poppers, right? He got hurt. He got,
he brought over a couple
of fucking blonde hair,
blue eyed who was okay.
They gave him the old sweet
and sour chicken there.
That's a hooker move. Um, anyways,
I don't know what to tell you.
I don't know what's going on in the world
of politics. Adult pretend to paint,
touch it. I just, you know, uh,
I'm a man of the people who doesn't
want to see the people. That's who I am.
I'm the man of people who just wants
to stay at home and his fucking house.
All right. That's all I want to do.
Do you know I like the regular people.
I like the regular guy in any country
just walking down the street and he's
excited because he has that
little moment to himself. Hey,
maybe I'll go into the pub here.
Have a quick little fucking
beer and a shot. All right?
Come on with this stupid look on my face.
My wife's talking to me.
I'm not listening.
I'll just kiss her on the forehead.
Pinch your cheek and face
plant under the couch.
Anybody who's doing that in any
culture, any race, any continent,
you're all right with me. I really
isn't that what most people are doing?
I'm most people you know
you've got a family. You just
want to fucking feel okay.
You know?
You know it'd be great if all the people
of the world just looked at the world
leaders and just said, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, relax,
relax,
settle down.
Everything's going to be fine. Okay.
You get when you're in a palace,
you were in a big White House. Okay?
Everything's fine. You have plenty.
You have your own jet.
Okay, fucking relax.
If you buddy, take it down a few, right?
Well that'd be nice if he could
just get everybody on the same page,
but you can't.
You can't.
You put up a fucking youtube video without
everybody's screaming and yelling at
each other.
Um,
I missed most of that Kansas City,
Seattle Seahawks game,
but I'm going to talk
about it nonetheless. All
right, I'll tie right down.
I would be a good start if I was a fan
of these kids are city chiefs from Kansas
City,
Missouri.
Okay.
That Kansas City, Kansas,
Kansas City, Missouri.
I would be very concerned.
Okay.
Cause Andy Reid is a great coach,
but when he goes up against
other great coaches,
he's got to come out of there with a win.
Andy Reid up against, so sneaky
Pete Carroll. Oh pistol Pete boom.
Out of USC. Right as the wolf was
at the door, ran out the back door.
Right up to Seattle.
Oh
sneaky Pete.
Do you know Pete Carroll?
How good that Guy Looks? You know he's
a year older than bill Bellacheck.
You wouldn't know
be Carol.
Looks like he's about 55.
The man's pushing 70.
Okay,
great shape. Full head of hair. You know,
not a line on his face.
Yeah.
Across the way.
You got Andy Reid,
the every man cause like he
drives a fucking snow plow.
Okay.
You know when you just knew,
you just knew Pete Carroll was going
to figure out a way to get it though.
You know what? Everybody is
slipping out about Patrick Mahoney.
You forgetting about Russell Wilson.
You know,
you just taking the guy
for fucking granted.
I would say that the Seattle
Seahawks or the seven seven and one,
whatever the fuck they record his dad
there, that team, nobody wants to play
a Jesus.
Who the fuck is that know I
know who the fuck that is.
I don't know some somebody over in Asia,
I've got my fucking cell
phone number and every day,
you know I don't pick it up.
And then I listened to the voicemail and
I hear this lady's voice just going now
your car man,
you got the bag for one 805 a pop up papa,
papa up like some sort of fucking,
I dunno what it is for,
but no idea. Maybe it's, it's Kim Jong,
US fucking secretary and the second
may making fun of him on the podcast.
What would you do with that guy called
in? You know, fucking scared. I would be,
even though he's in the other and then
the whole other fucking part of the world
to have a dictator call you up.
I think about the first syllable. That
word Dick, right? Telling me right now,
there's a reason why that guy's a dick.
Maybe that came from dictator. Did it?
Should I look that up? Would
that interest you? Um, anyways,
I missed most of that game, but
she just, you just fucking do.
You knew Pete Carroll wasn't going to
sit around and get his fucking ass fired
in Seattle.
No matter how many people he lost.
And I gotta commend that
owner for sticking with them.
They know what they got up there. Pete
Carroll's he's going to coach for like,
what do you think?
Another 10 years,
he's obviously hitting the elliptical
every day is eating the steam vegetables.
The guy's a beast.
What do you guys put him in
the coaching? Um, history.
I mean like you got to put them
in. I know he's got one. Oh,
we needed that second one. Oh. Oh, we
need to, you need that second ring,
you know, to get in the
conversation. Um, anyways,
you know something else.
I'm getting sick of this fucking Miami
dolphins every fucking year with this
undefeated thing in the 72 dolphins
still go on hit 1970 fucking toe.
Okay.
What are we going to quit glorify in that
they went undefeated in 1972 with two
white running backs so fucking long ago.
That was Jesus Christ.
1972 they barely invented the Frisbee.
The frisbee was like a decade old
and you haven't done shit since then.
Sort of the dolphins fans talking
shit about that. That's literally,
it would be like listening to them.
A Knicks fan or they,
that'd be ridiculous if they,
if they've started talking some shit they,
they have, I wanted since 73
they got a fucking year on you.
Um, anyways. Uh,
okay.
I don't think my patriots, I
don't know man. I don't know.
And then that dude we got from the Brown's
poor guy relapsed and now do you know,
you just hope he goes and he gets
okay.
You know, self taking care of their, um,
I hope they don't suspend them for good.
I'm hoping that guy has a full recovery
comes back and fucking has the career he
should have had.
But uh,
okay.
I Dunno. I Dunno. I'm looking at the
Patriots now that we have home field.
I figure we can win one.
I don't know about another one,
but you never know with Tom Brady
and bill Bellacheck. But uh,
if we're not going to win,
I want us to lose in the first round so
I could enjoy all these other teams that
I really want to see do. Well. I would
love to see Kansas city or a San Diego.
How about the Cleveland Browns?
How great would it see it?
Can they make the playoffs?
Like I said, I got the kid now,
so I watch as much as I can.
Um,
I saw Baker Mayfield staring
down his old fucking coach.
Bit of a classless fucking move,
you know,
to be in the prime of your physical life,
to be staring down somebody.
It looks like they take Geritol.
Um,
but you also got to love somebody dead.
Plays for the browns at the quarterback
position. Having a little bit of swagger.
Okay.
Um,
seeing happy Brown fans
see Brown fans with hope.
Okay.
You know
that late in the game. I mean, I haven't
seen that. I want to say since the 1980s
mmm.
When they played in municipal stadium,
so that's great to see.
I love seeing the Texans doing well
even though they lost to the eagles.
That was weird yesterday
having to root for the eagles.
I can't remember last time I was in a
position where it had to root for the
eagles.
I got to feel what it felt like to be
a fucking eagles fan yesterday. Uh,
no thanks. I'll pass on that fucking
cons. Can you just put somebody away?
MMM.
What else did I see?
And I think that was it.
I saw a little bit of that Steelers game.
I watched a little bit of the Bruins
play in the Hartford way. Liz,
did we lose that game by the way? We were
up like two to one and then, you know,
my kid woke up from her nap
Brolin's verse hurricanes.
Okay.
We lose that game. Ah, fuck me.
Yeah.
Oh,
we got smoked.
Okay.
And the second period,
three goals to one,
so that put them up four to three
and then they scored another one.
A you sons of bitches.
I love that they played the,
what was it called?
The brass something or other.
Okay.
They played that, uh, the old whale or
someone that they used to score a, yeah.
Papa. Papa. Papa. Papa. Papa, Papa.
Bye.
You guys remember that whalers goal
song was there was a brass something or
other brass bonanza.
They'd score a goal. Right.
And then they'd play this song
right here if I can unmute it.
That's, hold on. That's how old I am.
Okay.
The song was played in
national hockey league.
Yeah.
Buh Buh Buh Buh Buh Buh Papa.
And it was at the pro level.
I'll tell you was weird. I just
realized this. I tweeted about it.
Do you know the Hartford whalers have
been the Carolina hurricanes for one year
longer than they were ever? The
Hartford whalers? How sad is that?
Okay.
They were the Hartford whalers for a,
from 1979 to 1997.
So what is that? How many years is that?
That's 70 years. 17 years. 18 seasons.
And from 1997 on,
they've been the fucking,
the fucking Carolina hurricanes are y'all
kills me is I never went to a Hartford
whalers game. It was right down the
street. I could've got there in like,
I don't know how long, but it just
seems so far away to me back then.
Let's live in just outside of Boston.
I could've got there no traffic
in like 45 minutes, an hour.
And I never went. One time my buddy
had tickets and he's like, oh,
but I already asked this other guy and
then the other guy said he wanted to go
and I'm like, God, no worries. And it
was a Bruins verse. Hartford whalers,
the Hartford whalers.
Beh Beh Beh Beh Beh.
Um,
what about the Houston Oilers fight song?
Houston Oilers,
Houston Oilers. Now
Bob Won. Remember then?
Good.
Okay.
How much work did horn
players get back in the day?
Nah, that's not really true.
You've yet to win a Superbowl.
Oh wait,
here it is.
We're
the,
yeah,
there you go.
There you go. I was watching this
whole thing on fucking Earl Campbell.
I was like, I remember that song
and so easy it was back then.
That'd be songs started to say,
wait [inaudible] I get gap.
And then there's some horns came in and
then some guy in a tube was just going
boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
That's it. Then now, you know,
cause these fucking Djs,
they stripped all of that away.
And now all we're left with is
just the Tuba baseline. Basically.
Bom, Bom, Bom, Bom,
Bom, Bom, Bom, Bom Bob.
And then the Trump, it comes in by, by my
$2 trillion of national debt. Um, anyway,
I don't want, I'm talking about
here. Everybody that felt good,
the top of the podcast. It might've,
I might've came, came in a little hot,
but it felt good to get that out of me.
You know,
I'm going to fucking work out and
eat well. I haven't drank in 30 days.
That might be another part of the
problem. 30 fucking days. Three trees,
zero.
So Christmas tomorrow is going to
be a 31 and official, you know,
month. No Busan. And all I gotta do is
just get through that day. You know,
my wife is trying to convince me to
have a, you know, front of ours guy,
this does really nice bottle of
wine, but I'm just going to say no.
I'll be like, Yay, let's
drink it on Valentine's Day.
I'm just going to keep pushing it, pushing
it, pushing it, pushing the cause. Uh,
you know, I'm an old dad and
I got to fucking grow up.
I got a lot of growing up to do and a
lot of the yelling that I did and all the
bullshit I did at the top of the
podcast, you know, something, you know,
something that had more to
do with me than anybody else.
And that's what I'm realizing. I need to
learn to express what it is that I want,
what it is that I need. And I got to stop
acting like I'm fucking 22 years old.
All right, so over bill,
grow the fuck up. Who? Stan?
Oh, I lows but the pepper.
Pepper. Pepper. Pepper,
pepper this with the fuck up dude. 50
years old. This is what I look up online.
Oh, remember this game? That's what the
fuck I do. Just become this sad man.
Um, anyways, um,
my lovely wife is going to throw down my
lovely wife who deserves such a better
guy is uh,
throwing down.
She's making some lamb chops tomorrow,
which is going to be fucking
delicious. And um, I'm a,
I'm just drinking the club soda.
That's all I'm doing and I'm trying to
maybe play a little bit of drums early in
the day. That's it. All
right. And uh, I already know,
you know,
my kid's going to have a great Christmas.
She doesn't quite get what Santa
Claus this, but she loves the tree.
So next year it's going
to be on, you know, um,
it's gonna be a, it's going to
be a lot of fun. So anyways,
I'll let me read a little bit
of advertising here, by the way.
Thank you for listening. What are you
doing that you're listening to the shit.
You're not with your family, Huh?
And in between relationships.
A Dj just we use sent on an assignment.
I hope your work,
cause if you're worthy at the top of this
podcast was fucking Cathartic for you.
All Right,
John Wireless Shave Club Dough,
dollar shave club has everything you
need to look, feel and smell your best.
And you never have to go to a store.
By the way.
How the fuck is guys making all
this money and how is that sexist?
They're not forcing anybody
to go see their tours.
Yeah.
You know he had gray ears as comedians
that you just have to come in there and
he can fucking go out to
fucking write a great act.
People will come um,
on my wine and cause I wasn't on the list.
No redheads, a dollar shave
club, dollar Shave Club,
dollar Shave Club don't take forward.
Jolly Shave Club has
everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best and
yet have to go to this Stila.
That's because they deliver everything
you need right to you do a and they keep
you fully stocked on what
you use so you don't run out.
Here's how it dollar Shave Club has
everything you need to get ready no matter
what you're getting ready
for. All right. A dinner,
a Christmas party, a bank
robbery, you want to, you know,
he really scared me with the gun,
but I have to tell you,
he really smelled Great Jolly Shave Club.
They have you covered from head
to toe for your hair, your skin,
your face,
you name it,
they Abbott and they will automate and
they have this new program where they
automatically keep you stocked
up on the products you use.
So whatever you do, don't you know
something and that might save your life.
One day you hit your head on the tub
and people just see all this bathroom
products stocking up at your fucking door.
We should go in there and check on,
you know,
not catch you mid seizure.
You determine what you
want and when you want it.
And it shows up right to your door from
once a month to once every six months.
Plus with their handsome discount.
The more you buy, the more you save.
And Right now, dollar shave
club is a great thing to for uh,
for those doomsdayers.
You know what I mean?
The Armageddon prepares you gotta make
sure you have plenty of toiletry stuff.
Yeah, you could have all the
fucking super in the world,
but if he can't wipe your ash,
what do you do?
Peel the label off the
fucking chicken noodle soup.
Yeah,
you need some one wipe cherries
a plus with their home discount.
The more you buy,
the more you save.
And Right now dollar shave club has a
bunch of starters sets you could try for
just $5, like their oral
care kit. Ladies after that,
that the restart box ships regular
sized products at regular prices.
Get your status set for just $5 right
now@dollarshaveclub.com slash burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/burn Oh,
who's texting me?
Who was texting me?
Uh
Oh somebody, which shouldn't be a
merry Christmas. Isn't that nice?
That's the kind of thing that you like
around Christmas. You know what I mean?
Hey, how come only Santa
Claus Rides in the sleigh?
Why does his wife have to stay
home with those little people?
I think it's time for a
female Santa Claus. All right.
My bookie a I adore.
Hey Bull seasons here.
Oh, it's time to get into it
on the edge with my bookie. Uh,
there'll be a Gaba ghoul there.
Um,
don't be that guy with
no rooting interests.
As your relatives or friends
sit around watching the game.
A not this year when they're a record.
41 ball games.
Oh to bet on, including the national
championship game on January 7th.
It really is the most wonderful time
of the year to go gambling with your
children's college tuition.
Let's have a,
okay.
Make sure you're ready for the daily
action by signing up at my bookie today.
They pay fast.
When you,
when ownership really cares about good
customer service and they offer you the
crazy, his props. Um, where are you?
Bet is just important as,
uh, who you're betting on.
And if you want to make money, he wouldn't
be somebody during the ball season.
You got to go to my bookie. Oh, I trust
them evidently according to the copy.
But you don't have to take my word for it.
Check them out for yourself.
Join now at my bookie. Oh uh, my book.
He will offer you a 50% deposit bonus
to make sure you have a nice bank.
Will football season. All right,
get the fuck out of here. Uh,
use Promo code x, x, x, X.
I guess that's bur it
didn't put it in here.
When you deposit to activate the offer.
That's Promo Code.
[inaudible] I'm going to
guess it. My bookie. Oh,
I you're doing get the fuck out of you
as your mother. Uh, you play, you win.
You get paid. Try this. And I was trying
to sell us all right. There you go.
That's the, uh, let's see. Advertise
it. Let's get it on some questions here.
Can I go a little short here?
Can they go a little short?
Can I come up a little bit short?
Um,
Houston or alerts, Houston
Oilers, number one,
my ticket prices would have been higher,
but men came in and made him lower.
That's why I'm not on that list.
I would have played a bigger venue,
but men came and chased the crowd away.
That's sexism.
Uh,
name checked in a rap song,
a Billy goat gruff.
Just giving you a heads up that you are
mentioned by name and a new song iron
claw by czar face,
uh,
inspected deck from the Wu Tang Wu
Tang clan and seven l an esoteric from
Boston.
Ghost face killer is on the track,
but unfortunately the mention of got
the filter of bill burr obviously comes
from the white dude from Boston.
Well, what's wrong with that?
What are you ashamed to be in a crack?
Uh,
keep up the good work and maybe you'll
have better luck next time. Oh, Jesus.
Look at this. This, this poor bastard.
He doesn't like his fucking cream colored
skin that's gotten him his fucking
townhouse. Uh Huh. What's the matter?
Are you guilty with all your privilege?
You should go on tour of a deli.
You'll make more money than
the broads out there. Um,
I like,
are you totally just fucking completely
disregarded this guy as a musician just
because he was white. I mean, what?
I don't understand what's going
on in the world right now. Okay.
Can we just fucking, you know, if
somebody is good, just say they're good.
Can we do that? Can we stop
with the fucking bean count
and that shit. You know,
I love that. You know, this business
was like completely racist and sexist,
homophobic and all of that type of shit.
And now to correct it,
they now they're going to go the
other fucking direction and just,
it's just like they don't
know how to do it. It's like,
it's not about an algorithm. It's not
a formula. Just whoever's the best.
Just give it to them. Whoever
makes your heart sing. Hiram,
that's it. Um, named name. Okay.
Where am I in boys versus girls?
Dear Billy, wrong balls. Oh
God. My balls are Ron too.
I thought it was just my mouth now by
my fucking nuts are dragged into it.
An accessory to the crime. Uh, you
mentioned a few times out. Glad.
Okay.
Uh, how you're glad you
have a girl versus a boy.
I have one of each and I can tell you
for sure that is that it's not the case.
All right? So basically what
you're going to do is what I did.
I based the whole world on my
wonderful daughter severed,
evidently you don't have a good daughter.
So now my daughter's going to be bad.
Uh, not that boys are better,
they're just different.
Girls are very emotional and their
attitude is way more defiant in different
ways. Ironically, misuse
of the word parenthesis.
My four best friends all have one of each,
eh as well.
And we have had this talk a
bunch of times. All right,
now he has numbers on me.
All right,
now I'm losing.
Okay.
All right.
We're all different people and parents
and have different ethnic backgrounds.
He's got a great algorithm going here.
And one conclusion we came to
quickly was that it's a trade off.
Some things are way easier with boys.
Uh,
you're a man who's been around.
So you know that there are
major differences in the
ways boys and girls and men
and women process things do. Can you
just let me enjoy when she's a kid?
I don't need to know that she's
going to hate me when she's eight.
My daughter is very kind and very polite,
but at times she can be a bit,
how do I say, intense. Once again,
I'm not trying to convince
you that boys are better.
Just that you'll see when
girls can be a handful. No,
I didn't think it was
going to be an easy ride.
I'm just saying that boys are animals.
They're lunatics like the first 10 years
of their life. There are eight, seven,
eight years of their, they're,
they're, they're lunatics.
Can you give me that sir?
Now I've got to respect you because
you're further down the road than I am.
So you get the experience on me.
I'm still a rookie here.
I'm about ready to start the
sophomore jinx year number two. Uh,
oh no, I'm, I'm, I'm already two
years in, uh, next month. Again,
not a blanket statement. I'm sure your
daughter will continue to be an angel,
but she has yours and knee is
okay.
Spitfire jeans and she will surely show
it in a few years if she hasn't already
know. She has. She has. Um,
I'm happy you're glad you had a
daughter and not trying to convince you
otherwise. So No, call me a cunt. I
just think you're being a bit naive.
Go Fuck Yourself.
I hate just fucking call me naive.
You argue like a broad, what you, you've
see, this literally said, you know,
I'm going to tell you something,
but you have to promise
you're not going to get mad,
not trying to convince you otherwise.
So don't call me a cunt.
But now I'm going to call
you naive a food for thought.
Um, oh, go fuck yourself.
That whole fucking thing,
nick. I can go fuck himself.
Hey, not trying to be this,
not trying to be there,
just saying your way fucking wrong.
I'm not trying to convince you otherwise.
Just saying you fucking, you
know, you're a bit fucking naive.
That's some food for thought.
Hey, you some food for thought.
Why don't you go fuck yourself. All
right. Um, you are not me and I'm not.
You and I,
I'm,
I'm very happy for you and your United
Benetton colors of fucking friends that
you have. Do you guys can all
go fuck yourself. All right.
Okay.
Jesus fucking Christ. I mean,
I gotta be honest with you.
You didn't really tell me anything
that I didn't already know.
Women are more emotional. Gee, thank
you for that, Jim. I never noticed.
I never noticed that men and
women process things differently.
Now you know something. Now I'm going
to be a client. Let's go back to this.
I have one of each. Not that they're
better. They're just different.
You had like your hands up the whole time.
You know you fucking gun belt
around your ankle, so then you do,
you took a giant shit. All Lag.
Yeah. You made a really bugs me.
I like it better when people go,
hey bill, you don't know. You don't,
what the fuck you talking about?
All right,
this then at least I know where you stand.
Grain and I'll still get upset.
All right.
Shitty new bosses
I already know I'm going to handle
when my daughter gets upset with me.
I'll just be like, hey, oh
right. Oh right. I get it.
Yeah,
they'll talk to you mother. I
don't understand these things. Um,
hey there. Hey there. Billy no boss.
My company just got bought out by
have a boss. I worked for Netflix.
F is for family.
My company just got bought out and this
job I love will be majorly affected by
this corporate shit house.
I've had a lot of freedom to
be creative and innovative,
but that's all going to go away. Yes
it is. Kick comes the algorithms.
BOMP bomp Buh, Buh, Buh Buh Buh.
Don't have fun. The fuck each other.
We're a fucking cooperation for this shit.
And the drinking water,
who cares? It babies
had birth defects. Um,
I've been told that there will be a set
of guidelines put in place that it will
essentially rob me from all the joy I had.
It's really heartbreaking because I just
reached the point where I am able to
make good money.
The new bosses came in and started
talking to us like they were exists.
There were existing problems
that needed to be fixed.
This is of course ridiculous
because they bought
mmm.
They bought us because of how well we
were running out innovative. We've been,
should I just quit now so I don't have
to deal with everything that is to come.
I saved a lot of money,
but it's a unique job and I'm not sure
I'll be able to find anything like it in
the near future.
Well then I wouldn't quit it.
MMM.
I, uh, you know something,
God bless anybody in the corporate world
that deals with stuff like that and you
don't, don't could be like,
like when they come in,
you can't tell him to shut the fuck up.
Okay.
Cause what's going to happen is
they're going to ruin the company.
They're going to make it worse and no
one's ever going to step to them and say
that,
you know,
you guys took a great thing and you
made it less great slash fuck the whole
thing up.
No one ever tells him that because all
they do is look at the bottom line. Um,
I have to, you know,
I don't know. I, I've,
I've watched enough fucking documentaries
and shit and listened to enough people
like they have to just like corporations
the way they do business needs to be
fixed.
MMM.
Cause it's just a fucking runaway train.
It affects our foreign policy.
It affects people's quality of life.
Um, everything from how much money
they make to like the environment.
How polluted or not polluted it
is. And uh, until you get to,
I dunno because politicians have their
money pouring out of their pockets.
Like they've just fucking are treasonous.
Okay.
People that just, yeah, they exist without
fucking borders. That they're the worst.
They're the fucking worst.
We can agree on that boy's
first girls who gives a fuck?
Just the corporate mindset.
It's just fucking insane.
A Merry Christmas. Everybody. Uh,
my girlfriend, the aspiring model,
dear bill, same shit. Different toilet.
I'll rush through the generic intro,
updating the girl of my dreams.
You've been exclusive for three months,
but I've been dating for a total
of eight months. She's gorgeous.
She beauty has no boundaries. I've been
in other serious relationships before,
but none quite like this.
I'm truly in love with my best friend.
Like something Nicholas Sparks shit up.
Okay,
well who the fuck is that now? I gotta
look that up. He says Yada, Yada, Yada.
You get the gist. Who the fuck is
Nicholas Sparks that he shits out? Models.
All right, I gotta look
this up. You Stan. Oh,
alors Nicholas Sparks.
Yeah.
Bad movies. You fucking cunt. Oh God.
I fucking,
I fucking hate apple fucking cancer.
You want to talk about a corporation
that just infiltrated my whole life now?
Everything I have is
like run by those cons.
This stupid round building.
Okay.
He's a novelist.
What have I didn't want? I wouldn't have,
well, no wonder I didn't know who it was.
The guy writes books. All
right, hang on a second.
Merry Christmas to all my
friends and readers are crazy.
[inaudible] he writes books.
Nicholas Sparks,
one of the world's most
beloved storytellers.
All his books have been New York Times
best sellers. Jesus Christ. And I don't,
I back in the day I knew who the, okay,
I would know about a guy like this.
There's just no more bookstores.
Ah,
he's got a sweater over
a button down shirt.
These leaning up against
the fucking pole on a dock.
I mean this guy is a quality human being.
Nicholas Sparks is one of the
world's most beloved storytellers.
All of his books have been New York
Times bestsellers with over 105 million
copies sold worldwide and
more than 50 languages,
including 75 million in the
United States alone. Okay.
Sparks wrote one also a male sparks
wrote one of his best known stories.
The notebook. Oh, Jesus. Oh,
I get what you're saying.
You're like living a chick flick.
Okay. I get it though. All right. Um,
something. Nicholas Sparks
shit up. Okay. So I guess he,
he puts out a lot of product.
Anyway,
she's an aspiring model and
pretty good at her craft.
Her and the camera get along great.
Anyway, her lack of experience has,
there's still getting offers from unknown
photographers in particular, a guy,
she's done a few shoots within the past.
This time he wants to shoot nude
with and without pay. Fuck No.
Obviously you have a problem with this.
I want it. She doesn't need to be naked.
Don't do that. I want, I want
her to pursue her passion.
But this in particular,
does it sit right with me? I've never met
this guy. He's not paying her to shoot.
And what's her reasoning for
wanting naked pictures of my girl.
I've watched enough Jerry Springer
and forensic files not to trust it.
Definitely. She talked to me wanting
my blessing, which makes me feel worse.
I told her my unease about it,
but in the end I trust her and
we'll be okay if she goes ahead.
She wants to model so I'll have
to get over things like this. No,
you doubt the right now it's
a tough pill to swallow.
Any advice or comic relief you could
provide would be appreciated. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. No.
Fuck this piece of shit.
And then he's going to sell these fleas,
naked photos of her when she fucking gets
somewhere. This guy's a piece of shit.
He's not even given a cab
fare to get over there. No.
Fuck.
This guy with his artistic nude shots.
This guy's a fucking creep.
He's going over to her apartment.
That guy is a fucking creep,
so fucking creep.
He's gonna jerk off to the pictures.
Okay.
Any first year fucking cop
would tell you that. All right,
you got to go. Worst case scenario
here to fuck this guy all day long,
you'd have to tell you your, your, your,
your girlfriend that you know,
being a,
being a model doesn't mean getting naked.
You don't have to do that shit.
That's just fucking creepy shit.
There's no fucking reason ever
for them to do that shit ever.
Give me a scenario why they would have
to be naked there. A fucking model.
You're modeling clothes. You standing
next to her refrigerator being like, wow,
I'd lean, oh wait, what?
I really liked that refrigerator now
because that woman is so beautiful.
You don't have to fucking sit there
with your tits and your clam out.
What the fuck is that for?
Why?
Yeah.
Why does she have to be naked?
Jesus Christ.
A fucking two piece bathing suits
going to show pretty much everything.
No,
I would say no.
I would say I got a bad feeling
that this is going to come back.
I want you to have a great career.
This is going to come back and bite you
in the ass. Your bare ass. All right.
Did you go on over to
this guy's apartment?
He's not paying you and you have to get
naked and he's taking photos and this is
somehow going to further your career.
He's going to send these
fucking photos around.
Your parents are going to see him.
This is a bad fucking move.
Say what I just said, but about the
anchors in the f word. All right.
Worst dessert. Dear Billy Baker balls. Uh,
my aunt makes a peppermint cake every
year and every year I look at it like,
why would anyone want a cake
that tastes like toothpaste?
Was wondering if you had strong feelings
about any desserts that have crossed
your holiday table. Merry Christmas
to you and your two angels. Uh,
let's see here.
I don't like coffee,
so I don't like anything coffee flavored.
Um,
I don't like marshmallow.
I don't like smores.
Uh, yeah, I don't like anything
with marshmallows. I don't like, uh,
I don't like candy and my cookies like
m and m cookies or snicker bar crunches.
Like that's just this unholy
fuck. It's like, yeah,
you're already eating a cookie.
Do you got to jam a fucking,
I don't like any of that. I don't
like ice scoop ice cream with a co.
I mean they're gonna have ice cream.
We're gonna have a fucking cookie.
I'm really not going to have any of that
shit anymore cause I kind of got sugar
on in my life. Although the
holidays has come back a little bit.
And the first time you have something
with sugar after you haven't been eating,
you're like, dude, what the fuck is this?
It's terrible. It's terrible for you. Um,
okay.
But I,
I like pie.
I don't mind a little whipped cream
on my pi or remain an Allah mode,
you know, I don't mind shit like that.
Fuck. My wife told me to make a pie.
Yeah. Christ never ends. Does it?
When will it ever,
and when will it ever end?
Who,
who's at the Kingston?
Where have all the flowers gone?
Long time passing number that we have.
Oh,
there's something going on a long,
long time ago.
The Kingston trio. Yeah.
I'm not into marshmallows.
I'm not into fucking coffee flavor
in anything and I don't like,
I love the way cop if he smells
so, uh, and I don't like, uh,
okay.
Yeah, I don't, I don't like
incest. You was desserts
where the fucking cookie fucks the candy
and the candy gets inside the cookies.
It's just, I mean that's just for
super, super, super fat people. Uh,
that's like this speed ball.
Like it's not enough to do
heroin and just to coke you got,
if you've got to fucking do a speed
ball, you know, um, speaking of which,
how about that Aerosmith song
combination? Huh? Isn't that a great song?
Walk into Gucci wherein he seva raw,
barely stay on Carla Sam.
So God Damn God,
a dollar Shave Club, dollar shave club
has already talked about this, right?
Did I? I think I did. Yeah.
My book, he already did the,
I did both. The reads well.
That's right. I was doing the,
a shitty new boss. What are you,
what a way to start the year.
Yeah.
Where's dessert? Oh, that's
it. My done. I can't be done.
That's only, oh, 51 50 while,
but it was almost 51 50.
Um,
anyways.
You know what sucks is we didn't do
our holiday card until late this year.
You got to do it right on thanksgiving.
That's what my buddy told me last night.
The Great Al Madrigal. Let me know
that man does everything right. Um,
yeah.
All right. Let's see what I can bullshit
about for the next few minutes here.
Yeah.
Oh God. Yeah. I was at this
fucking party last night.
I can't say the comedian's name.
Yeah.
Oh, I'll tell it someday on
his podcast. So I'm at this,
I'm at this holiday party last night.
Last night was a great party by the way.
Um, I had a fucking awesome time
at that, you know, to the point.
I was one of the last
people to go. And, um,
okay.
Uh, there was a comic there and he had
lost like 20 pounds and he was already
skinny. So he's like, yeah, I lost
20 pounds and fucking site. Right.
And he's one of those people that he
then keeps tabs on everybody else.
So he sees me go over to the buffet and
I got like four shrimp and I got a bunch
of lettuce.
It's like salad or whatever.
And he's looking at me cause
that's all you're eating.
And I knew it was fucking with him
because he's one of those people,
like in order for him to feel
good about being in shape,
other people have to be a little out
of shape. You know, he's got to, I got,
I wish he would be laughing, right. I'm
not being addictive and he loves his shit,
right? So he goes, that's all
you're eating. And that was,
I knew what the fuck he was
doing. I was just like, yeah man,
I can't eat that other stuff, man. I'll
have to take a nap. So long story short,
we're there for like four hours and I
get fucking hungry. So my wife, you know,
fixed herself a nice plate and I saw
she had a slider. I'm like, Oh God,
I'd love one of those. So I
fucking go up and I go to the, uh,
this is like fucking two,
two and a half hours after I talked to
him about eating the lettuce and the
shrimp, right? And I grab a slider
and I'm reaching for a case of Dhea,
like a little triangle,
a case of dia.
And I just see this guy way
off across the room. Hey,
go day it go far. There you
go. Right. And I know it's him.
So I'm like, this mother
Fucker, this guy, right?
So I deliberately ignored him because I
wanted to see how fucking important it
was for him to rub it in that I was
eating bad and there was a bunch of people
talking and it was loud.
So I deliberately turned and walked
towards him and I was looking down at the
plate and he's going loud. They
had gall, there you go, party.
They had cow like that.
And I fucking looked up and I put my
hand on his shoulder. And I was like,
dude,
I heard you the first time.
I just wanted to see how
much joy you would get into
it. He was crying, laughing.
I was like,
what the fuck is wrong?
We had the funniest fucking
exchange last night, right?
I was talking to him and I said something,
he totally made this face,
he's cause whack.
And he kind of stepped towards me
when he said it and I said, dude,
don't get my fucking face.
And stuck it in argumentative.
I'm just making a fucking statement.
Get cont right. And then he goes,
I wasn't getting in your face or
whatever. Right? And then like,
it took me a half hour to
process and I was like, oh wait,
this guy's been to a zillion concerts.
He plays guitar. His hearing his shot.
And I walked over and I started
laughing. I was like, dude,
I didn't realize you were
a little harder hearing.
I thought you were being a dick.
And we were just laughing our asses off
that he was so fucking old that did.
Now he goes, why? When people talk to him.
And then I'm such a fucking defensive
con that I got in his grill,
like he was being an asshole to me. I'm
not even drinking. And that happened.
Oh my God, that made my night
day ago. They a golfer, they go,
hey, it goes stuff your face. So I
can feel good about being in shape.
Uh, I'll say if there's one
thing that I love in life,
it's a miserable concert and this guy is,
he's right.
He probably figured out who it is at
this point. Miserable Con Plays Guitar,
um, uh, is happy when
someone else's failing.
I might as well say his name at this point
and he's one of my favorite people in
this business. Um, anyways, uh,
l as I threatened,
as I threatened I,
I've been feeling like going
back to church and, uh,
I'm going to church today or
this evening, I should say, uh,
this is one of the things
I have to do today.
Then I'm actually looking forward to,
um,
I actually really enjoy going to church
with my whole family because that's
something I did when I was growing up.
I don't believe a lot of it, but the,
the underlying message before it goes,
takes a left turn and we have to go kill
some people is all religion seems to
lead to God loves you and you love him
and he just wants to love you and be
happy and these other
people we need to kill. Um,
I take it, just dislike the a, it just,
it's a nice reminder to be a
good person and I would like to,
I would like to start going again.
I'm trying to turn the
fucking ship around.
I lived a is it hedonistic?
I Dunno what the fuck it was,
but I am boozed way too much over
the last, through my forties.
And I said I was going
to slow down to my fit.
I was going to go stay in my
fifties. All right. You remember B?
What I'm doing,
Yoga pod yields a Bali,
a Navy did down dog lot left.
I want to fucking eat better and I
just want to stop fucking Bosun. Yeah.
Okay.
Oh God. Am I going to do that thing?
Am I going to be now that I'm a dad,
am I going to start pretending to
be who are, you know who I'm not.
Okay.
Oh, am I going to send an example?
I'm not going to lie to my kid.
God knows I can't get plenty of
fucking podcast to listen to dad.
Did you drink? Oh yeah.
Oh yeah. Oh yes I did.
Yes, yes, yes I did.
And I did it too much and I wish I didn't,
it was a mistake.
Uh, anyways, having said that, how long
has this booze, no booze run going to go?
If I get through tomorrow,
I feel like I can get through all of
January and then I'll be getting ready to
do with special somewhere. I got to figure
out where I'm going to tape it and um,
they didn't, won't drink. So I'll
probably go like to April and that'd be,
that'd be a good thing. Get my liver a
nice fucking break. You know what I mean?
Like what's his face? Urban Meyer. So
my livers, like every couple of years
it's going to take a break,
you know, for health reasons,
I'm actually go into the last game. That
legend is going to be coaching, man.
That's something else. Where do you
put him in the lexicon of Greg College?
Coaches of all time,
man.
You got to put that guy up there and
the fact that he was dealing with that
fucking cyst in his head there,
the point he had to like bend
over at the waist you like,
is that guy going to die?
And he plowed through that.
Can you imagine how much
shit his wife was giving him?
I just don't think he should coach
anymore. That's all I'm trying to say.
You're making it worse.
Okay.
Um,
anyways.
Okay,
so what are your goals? I've had
the same goal for fucking 30 years.
One of the goals, a drumming
goal and I'm fucking sick of it.
Am I ever going to be able to
play good times, bad times?
I'm once again trying. I,
I,
you know what it is.
I don't have this sticktuitiveness
even I keep playing drums.
I keep doing what the Fuck
I love playing them by,
just can't focus on anything
to get anything up to speed.
I get everything up to like 80%.
I could play good times,
bad times about 75 bps.
I'm fucking 25 fucking btms away.
Beads permitted for all, you know,
drum is out. Well, let's see.
I might be big fucking
find out what this is.
Okay.
I should promise you guys,
I'm going to do a drum cover.
That song dressed as John Bonam.
I'll put it on my patrion page when I
finally get it down. Let me see here.
Uh,
good times.
You cut bad times p m beats per minute.
BPM. Good Times, bad times, bpm.
What do you got? What do you got?
What do you say that,
what do you say?
They're clicky 94.
Oh fuck.
I am 19 bpms away.
I'm just going to keep playing
it at 75 until 75 is a joke.
And if I have to move up to 76 BPM,
if I just have to fucking
inch my way up like that,
that's what the fuck I'm going to do.
MMM
cause that,
that shoot little
kid there who played at this
year. I was just like, what
the, the, the, the, you know,
it's just that kid, that belief, that
kid, we should have what kills me too.
It's two minutes and 46 seconds long.
The Bass Drum Lick than I'm,
I that I want to play is literally,
you know,
I mean, what does that take?
A second and and a half.
Then at the end of the song,
it's Bumble,
but rob Robert Battle wrap
a rope bat. Bat Ball. Bob.
Bob Get right. What does that
four seconds, five seconds.
That is fucking help me
up for 30 goddamn years.
Um,
that's it.
I'm going to do a daily fucking
report, a weekly report. Make,
make sure I stick to this where I'm
at, but you know, suck somebody.
Get up to maybe 76 BP
fucking [inaudible] right?
And then I'm going to do this 10 fucking
day running Europe by a comeback.
My foot's going to feel like some old
lady. All right. That's it. Everybody.
Merry Christmas. Happy Hanukkah.
Happy Kwanzaa. God bless all IA.
IOP had a great year.
I hope next year is even better for you.
I hope you go after what you want in life
because you only live once. God dammit.
So what do you give a shit if you bomb,
these are going to be an old man saying
I wanted to do it and I tried it in a
life. Kicked me in the
nuts. Bowling's died.
Turn my scrotum into a speed bag,
but I kept coming back.
That'll be me someday on youtube.
90 year old finally gets good times,
bad times down.
Then I cry and Keel over and die.
All right, go fuck yourselves.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.
Ho Ho Ho.