HEY WHAT'S GOING ON.
IT'S BILL BYRNE It's time for the Monday
morning podcast from Monday July 17th
2017. What's going on. How are you.
July 17 2017 I'm going to go play that.
No.
No that shit.
Maybe you still do it.
Always remember that if all of a sudden
you know somebody's got something like a
receipt or something and there
was a couple the same numbers.
That's what I'm gonna play. I'm gonna go
down there and played on the megabucks.
That's what they had
Massachusetts megabucks.
My favorite one best name ever for any
lottery I thought was set for life.
That was just the perfect phrase
every blue collar working stiff.
That's what they want do just fucking
set for life just sitting there having a
fucking beer checks rolling in don't
gotta worry about nothing set for life.
All right kids if you're working class
you will you work paycheck to paycheck
and it becomes a fuckin grind
set for life.
Dude I could fucking sit right here right.
I COULD FUCKING SIT RIGHT HERE DO JUST
FUCKING stare into my fucking toes and I
still got that shit coming in every
month for the rest of my life.
You know why kid because I'm set for life.
You hear about Mikey Doty
hit the fuckin set for life.
He's fuckin set for life. Kid doesn't
have to do shit. Fuckin cock sucker.
God bless him.
Anyways I'm in a great goddamn mood.
Why.
Because I get eight hours sleep last
night despite the fact my daughter is
just waking up and she's trying
out her voice now where she sits.
Remember when Mariah Carey used
to hit those really high notes.
SHE'S DOING THAT AND EVERY TIME I LOOK
OVER LIKE OH MY GOD SHE'S JUST LOOKING AT
ME AND SHE HAS LIKE HER LEGS ARE
everything's like up in the air and she's
smiling at you. It's like impossible
to get upset. You just start laughing.
It's actually riffing about that
this weekend in Grand Rapids.
At one if that works as an adult.
You cut somebody off in traffic and they
look over you if you somehow flexible
enough we could just put both arms and
both legs in the air just give him that
fucking baby grin.
That might have been the creepiest image
I've ever seen. I've ever thought of.
There you go.
It would just creep them out.
Be like oh my god that
guy would be driving.
I think there's something wrong with
them in the mental department there.
So anyways I want to thank everybody that
came out to the shows at the Fountain
Street Church in Grand Rapids Michigan.
It is and it is continuing to be one
of my favorite gigs I've ever done.
I know I always say I'm going to put up
pictures like I didn't put up a picture
my drum kit.
Like I said I was going to and I'll tell
you why because you know I got these
cymbal stands and the ones that I want
I just wanted the single bracket ones I
don't like those double bracket like I'm
going to go play in a fucking hurricane.
They weigh nine thousand goddamn pounds.
I accidentally ordered those
instead of the ones I wanted.
So I had to return those and now today
I'm going to pick up the right ones I
just want to have it all set up when
you see it. I want you to see it right.
I want to have the fucking right look.
I'm not going to have it like you know
here's the car I bought and I don't have
this fucking.
The tie is on it so.
But speaking of drums my booking
agent my Reuben Kincaid is you know.
Tell them how much fun I
have when I go on the road.
If I find a place where I can go play
drums he goes you know we could put it in
your rider that you know any time you
do a couple nights at a theater they can
set up a drum kit there and
go get the fuck out of here.
That sounds like some diva shit
he goes in he goes. Do they.
They have music acts there all the time.
It's no big deal.
So I was like All right.
So I show up at the Fountain Street Church
and they had a fucking bear and this
Yamaha kit with this fucking horrific
white trash like leopard skin rap I don't
know what.
I don't know what to call it.
It was like somewhere between the
Stray Cats way back in the day and
poison maybe you know it actually looked
like the fuckin stretchy pants that the
slutty girls would wear at
the heavy metal concerts.
It was the same kind of print.
And I'm looking at those things
going like What the fuck are these.
And she goes Don't worry.
Everybody always says that sit down and
play him and the kick sounded amazing
and I was able to thanks
to my drum teacher.
You know I have a game plan when I try
to tune something up and I got this snare
to sound great and I went in
on those fucking hilarious.
I go in there on Saturday to play and
I'm like about an hour before the doors
open.
So I went in there and I
was fucking wailing on him
and when I got off the kid I
know what I was little.
I can like the place where the priest
dresses and shit you know puts on all the
fucking flowing ponchos and shit.
And I walked out and there was no one in
the church and I walked in the parking
lot there was like fucking six of the
security guys just standing out there.
It's like sorry sorry.
It was still it would've been great if
they actually had him out on the stage.
I would've left him there for the show
wouldn't a bug me but it would have
sounded fucking unbelievable.
This giant church and I didn't realize
because you know last time I played there
only played one night
it kind of came in town.
I did it I was like
What the hell was that.
That was fucking
incredible and then I left.
But this time I was there for like two
days three nights and I was able to read
up on the history of it.
Listen to this shit.
This is all the people that perform
there because there was no bigger venue.
That was the biggest venue in the
I guess Western Michigan or whatever.
Or at least in Grand Rapids.
So if anybody big came there
they went there everyone.
Winston Churchill spoke there.
Helen Keller spoke there blind and deaf
learned how to fucking read and write
and speak.
Somehow figure that one out.
Who else. Amelia Earhart. Malcolm X.
They say Winston Churchill.
Duke Ellington. Ella Fitzgerald.
Dave Brubeck.
Led Zeppelin Pink Floyd.
You two in like 1984 played there.
I think Zeppelin and Pink Floyd was
obviously on their first tours and that's
just that's just what I can
remember trying to picture
when I was looking at the
wall. Who else I saw there. I
mean it was fucking incredible.
Eleanor Roosevelt and they have like
pictures of him and their little thank you
notes and shit was fucking ridiculous.
B.B.
King and then make that.
I think I said that the video that I
took which I will actually post and I
promise you I'll give you a
picture my my drum kit this week.
So anyways we are on to episode two of
efforts for family we're recording the
first one.
Just remember this just
remember me telling this
recording the first one on July
18th 2017. You wait to see how long
it takes before you fuckin see it.
Fuckin animation it
takes forever.
But anyway let's let me talk about a
which I talk about here. How about this.
How about how great fucking Grand Rapids
is and it's one of my favorite cities.
I was there with Dean Del Rey and he was
fucking murdering all week and yet he
had a bunch of fans came out to people
flying in to see him and then he went on
to Detroit to go play some rock club
like after after our show Saturday night.
But there was this place a course
post forget the fucking name of it
but they had all these old video games
in there. The fuck was it called.
And why is my stomach still growling.
I had a bowl of cereal trying to starve
myself before the fucking acting gig.
Oh by the way thank you for all your guys
suggestions sack slash criticism of my
my dating or whatever guy goes Dude
you can't say you're crushing it.
You know you crushed it. If at night
you still haven't a drink or two.
It's like you fucking think I don't
realize that Mom. Yes I realize that
but anyways
what was it called Stella's is some shit
I can't fucking remember but we went
down there and they evidently they had
a great burger which I didn't have.
Went to this healthy place
and got this fuckin rap.
Right in a water water and then we went
over there because they had all these
pinball machines and shit.
Me and Deena fuckin all
shit and we walked in there.
They only had one pinball machine
but they had all these great
old video games and we showed up right
and we sounded like two fucking kids.
D just goes.
They got asteroids.
That we blew out and bugs play in that
I've never been one of those guys.
Never been a video game guy.
Just haven't been because
they're so fucking awesome.
They were like addicting
but that is something.
Remember back in the day when you would
watch MTV Cribs and then like these
fucking people would have these
video games in their in their houses.
And I saw a sink like I always feel
like you buy those and then you never
fucking use them like you use it for like
the first day and then it's just like
oh wait I gotta go to work you know I
have to work so I can pay for this big
giant stupid machine that I could've
just pumped a couple of quarters into and
let somebody else own and deal
with the fucking maintenance.
How if I was ever gonna buy one it would
be asteroids and my number two is a
game that not a lot of people know about.
And
I think for the most part
they've all disappeared.
It was a fucking great game at least.
I loved that it was called
elevators and it was basically.
I vaguely remember it.
It was like Spy Versus Spy kind of thing
you were dressed in white and all the
bad guys were dressed in black almost
kind of looking dark dressed like despite
a spy from Mad magazine and you had to
so you get in an elevator and on each
floor there were these bad guys and as
you passed the floor they'd be shooting
at you from the right or towards from the
left and you had to get all the way up
to the top of the building and get
something and then come back down again.
And the worst was when you were going
back down again and you'd be shooting at
the guy and the guy would duck and lay
down on the floor and as you went by when
you couldn't raise your gun up and it
was just your head at floor level he blow
your fuckin brains out.
I used to play that one I buy
either one of those I guess.
No I wouldn't I wouldn't fucking waste
of money but I'll go out we had a great
time and I got a killer picture of Dean
and his total fucking rock star pose
playing the game and I think
he already tweeted it out.
So if you look at Dean Del Ray's
Twitter thing you can find that shit.
So we did that and I want to thank people
that Dr. grins comedy club I went down
there and did a quick spot
you know went up did
some jokes or whatever.
And it was funny when Dean was up there
he fuckin started trashing this woman
who's sitting in the front row because
she wouldn't shut up and I said to the
other comics got they're gone.
I like one of those deals as a comedian
you'll be onstage and someone's talking
and commenting on your jokes and then
you don't realize most the crowd can't
hear it.
So if kind of supposed to ignore it I
guess even though it's driving you nuts so
he just fucking snaps and trashes her.
And I would sit in the back of the club
I said to the other comedians it's like
you know it's funny we could
even hear what she said.
You probably should've just kept going
I go I've made that mistake twenty
thousand fucking times.
Then I went up next and I did the
exact same thing exact same thing and I
fucking trashed her and then she got mad
you know said she was offended by for
some fucking joke I did about the troops
or some shit like that said no it isn't.
No it isn't I know when you got offended
you fucking ego maniac but I looked and
I said something to the effect of Why
would you think that you have anything
interesting to say. Was one of
those lines which was just really.
You know now that I've said it out
loud and I've kind of gotten out of the
emotion it was I was really mean
I went mean that's what I did.
I went fuck in me
so many ways.
Oh by the way somebody tried to scam me.
They tried to scam all Frankel
who you think are dealing with here are
some fucking rap bald Ralph Mal fucking
motherfucker what you are.
That doesn't mean you can scam
me though they almost did.
If I wasn't so fuckin paranoid
I'm hanging in the hotel and I get this
phone call and I pick it up and it's
just this computer going out that saying
that they were calling from Apple and
that there was a problem with my cloud
and somebody might be breaking into it.
They go you know call this number blah
blah blah blah blah and I'm like Oh you
gotta be fucking kidding me so I stole
it and they say that number twice I can't
remember it.
So I just start taking a guess and I
punched in like out of the you know 10
numbers you know 1 8 8 8 whatever I
got about 6 in and immediately starts
dialing and I somehow get
connected now right there.
That should have tipped me off that these
people are just fish and looking for
somebody to react to it. So I dialed like
six other fucking 10 digits I needed.
And then this guy's I low
but the Bubba and I was like Yeah.
You guys just call it what is this
referring to is like you fucking called me
spy my soundcloud or whatever and they go
oh yes yes you have a security problem.
But I go well whose fucking fault is that.
I go Why did you guys set up the cloud
if it wasn't going to be like safe.
Now you've exposed me all this
shit because what I fuckin.
Because I downloaded the Royal Blood
fucking album now all of a sudden some is
gonna drain my bank account you
computer cunts I wasn't cursed but I was
flipping out.
And then he goes so sir we can help you
we can help you over the phone we just
need to access your computer.
I go You mean access my computer
and the guy just started talking to.
I go I go I don't do that over the
phone he goes Sir this is a very.
So this is a secure fucker blah blah blah.
I go well how to.
How do I know I could because you say so.
Basically I wouldn't fucking do it.
Just because I was looking at I was
looking at them like they were legit but I
was just like well you already got hacked
why the fuck would I go with you again.
Why don't I just go to the store.
So little he got to the point he goes
Sir this is this is a secure but bubba
bubba bar. I just kept going like
Well I don't even know who you are.
You just for I know you're one of the
guys fucking trying to hack into my
computer dude.
I literally felt like I
was in the Bourne Identity.
You know when you don't know who to trust
you don't you just fucking yelling at
the other guy go you put your gun down.
You put your gun down first right.
So finally he gives up on me and he goes
So here's your case number and you know
I'll fucking you know.
He said some dumb shit you've
been to Turkey or Jordan recently
it's like No no I saw the 30 for 30 UNled
bias when he fucking went one on one
against Michael Jordan.
Do you call in Michigan
you fucking asshole.
So anyways he ends up transferring me
and it just fucking hangs up and then I'm
like flipping the fuck out.
So I called the guy produces my fucking
show and he just goes why he goes yeah.
Apple doesn't call anybody.
He goes now man that's just bullshit.
So thank God I'm a paranoid Jackass or I
might let something happen there so I'm
just putting that out there like you know
I'm sure all you young guys know what
it is and you feel so smart and you're
gonna shake your head and laugh your ass
off at me on Twitter.
Going like you fucking know
do you know like it's 2017.
I learned that back in 2010 did you.
What else did you learn how not to play
a guitar and then still call yourself a
musician. Oh Bill Bill. Come along
let's not be the old guy here huh.
I gotta be honest with you Del Ray played
me some of that Skrillex guy stuff and
I fuckin really liked it.
I thought it was way different than
anybody else and that's what I'm learning.
Whenever something new comes out as much
as your old ears listen to it and say
what the fuck is that.
You just have to know that there's
going to be the fucking Jimi Hendrix The
Richard Pryor the Tom Brady the James
Brown the fucking would is gonna be you
gotta find out who that person is of the
thing that you're listening to and then
you can judge it OK it goes but I swear
to God it goes right back to New York
pizza all these fucking dopes
get off the fuckin plane.
The first place that's his famous New
York pizza they eat it and then they go.
This pizza sucks here.
It's like now you did you
didn't go to the right place OK.
He didn't go the right place and deejays
are like New York's pizza in that
fucking everybody thinks they can do it
you know and everybody's claiming that
they're the real fucking
deal and everybody's saying
they're famous everybody's
famous Ray the fucking deejay and
I actually I really liked to shit.
I was like you know and I could
actually fucking get the car and drive.
Listen to this shit especially at night
like this great like drive and songs
like the whoo eminence front.
Do you ever wanna when a bunch
of fuckin money playing poker.
That's it. Just get your money leave. Get
in your car buy yourself the fuckin
window down and you listen to that song as
you drive out to the desert and tell
scream what the top five moments of your
life.
Oh fuck you I'm old
anyways what else.
When I saw I want to.
Oh did you guys watch all the Mayweather
McGregor pressers as they call them
overseas the press conferences.
It's kind of the same thing over and over
again with Conor McGregor he just kept
going like What the fuck
what the fuck is wrong with you.
He's got on a contract suit.
That form VOLTRON thing was dumb and I
loved when he trashed him on that but I
will tell you this.
Watching all of those people showing up
for a fucking press conference they sold
out the Barclays Center they sold out
were like the Maple Leafs play I believe
in Toronto.
The Staples Center people showing up
to watch a fucking press conference.
I can tell you this cynical Bill's
going to ruin the pay per view for you.
Those press conferences are
gonna be better than the fight.
You know and the fucking people that are
gonna order that goddamn fight are the
same fucking people that slow down on
the highway to watch somebody change of
fuckin tire
day.
It's like it's just beyond
it's beyond a spectacle.
I mean people go like you know I know
it's a spectacle but you know it didn't
just a word to fucking work.
Yeah I know getting fucked in the ass
but I want to see what it feels like.
Though that pay per
view can go fuck itself.
Do they ride in on the same
plane over the fucking London.
Get the fuck out of here and all
this shit McGregor gives Mayweather.
There's one topic he completely avoids
because it would fuck with ticket sales
which kind of makes him part of the
fucking bullshit of that whole thing.
You know what I mean it's
just get the fuck out.
I dunno I forget that I've given that guy
enough fucking goddamn money given him
enough fucking money.
I've gotten fucked enough
I've got fucked enough by that guy way
like it's professional boxers can't lay a
fucking hand on him and
I'm fucking not enough.
By the eighth round as he'd poo poo
poo poo point him to fucking death
now he's going to fight a guy who's
not even a bot who used to box.
I love they used to box. Yeah there's
a lot of people used to do stand up.
You want to see them do an HBO special.
Here's the bottom line if they ever met
each other in a bar and started swinging
McGregor would fucking kill him he'd
take him to the ground and then the
Mayweather would know what to do.
So they've eliminated all of that we know
Bill you've said that so I don't know.
Anyways. Maybe McGregor's
I mean Mayweather is ego
maybe tries to knock him out.
I'm just not I'm not going to
fucking watch it. I'm really not.
I think what I'm gonna do is I'm going
to get out on the highway when the fuckin
fight is on and just cruise
down the highway doing 90
miles an hour just looking
around going like this is
what it should be like.
Like if I was running shit this would
be the level of people that were in the
world.
I was joking on my own this weekend in
Grand Rapids saying you know what I would
do if I was running shit on the night
of the Mayweather McGregor fight I would
turn all the buffalo wild
wings into gas chambers.
All those fuckin mouth breathing morons
that were jerseys you know with other
men's names on the back all day all day.
So I call it.
All of those guys just just gone all of
them gone and you'd watch I bet I bet
the mean the level of meanness on
on on the Internet would go down.
You know these five by the way these
fucking people now who just sit there and
they watch CNN or Fox all day long and
then they show up to you and they just
start vomiting out all this fucking
fearful shit that they just watched.
And then after they do that and get you
all stirred up they don't even have the
decency to offer a fucking solution.
All these fucking morons it's just like
why would you sit there and watch Fox
News all day.
That's all you're gonna do.
Watch a little CNN balance out you
fucking lies keep yourself level
fucking what's his face.
My buddy was telling me this weekend you
know it's going global warming is going
to get so hot you know they're saying
they're not gonna be able to fly planes
onto LaGuardia
and I'm not I mean I'm thinking like
how the fuck am I going to be a comedian
anyway. And then that was it. He
didn't offer any fuckin solutions.
He just let me know. Like in the
future you know we will do your job.
Then I'm starting to fucking think about
you know me my family living out in the
street all I want to do is just say
he's going to play the last rites.
You know if you don't have
a fuckin solution don't
bring up the goddamn problem
okay. Like I brought the economy
Gregor Mayweather. All right.
I said it's a fuckin problem.
I gave you your solution.
You drive on a highway 90 miles an hour
and you turn the Buffalo Wild Wings into
a gas chamber.
See that.
See that I'm a good guy.
Everybody else is an idiot. In my world
I'm the smartest person in the room.
Sorry. Well we went for the
fuck do you want for me.
You know watching my kid all day today.
I waste fucking tired.
I can't take my goddamn pass where I'm
not watching now obviously while I'm doing
the podcast but that's only
because I curse so much.
I'm trying not to do that in front of
her which I know I'm gonna fail fuckin
miserably.
It takes up to being it
being a dad is this shit. It
really is. I fucking love it.
You know it's the best thing
about it is watching kids shows.
I don't know that I'm a fucking moron
or whatever but I am legitimately
entertained. We started watching
cars this morning. It's tremendous.
I mean you know it is I watch
cartoons it's so fucking long.
It's like the level of animation
on those things is crazy.
Like I think I saw one of those
toy stories one or two of them.
But you know when you when you don't have
a kid it's like you know why would you
go see one of those lets you smoke weed
like hey man let's get high and go see
fucking toys.
All right.
Or you know you're dating a woman they
always like seeing those they're cute.
I like to make foods and you end up
go in there and you just sit in there.
I just fucking I remember I saw one of
those toy stories like they were going
down something and they were all this
conveyor belt they went into a pit of
flames and the level of fucking anxiety
that it brought me I got like angry at
the movie like this is a fucking kid's
movie I shouldn't be feeling this way why
do I care so much about
these goddamn toys.
Which is one of the reasons why I
don't watch movies because I I take the
fucking ride.
When people watch scary movies
they go to that movie and scare me.
They all scare the fuck out of me
because I just I I take the fucking ride.
I never just I never
fucking pulled myself out.
Look around the theater
going and it's just a movie.
There's no reason I get this
fucking upset this is stupid.
That's just an actor and when he
takes they did. I don't do that.
I get sucked in and it's
fucking over it's fucking over.
And then I end up getting freaked
out and I walked to my car.
You know and I'm thinking of the
fuckin Blair witch is gonna get me
all right.
I think I think I
babbled long enough here.
Let's let's do a little bit of let's do
some advertising let's get to actually
the funniest part of the podcast
me trying to read out loud.
All right frame bridge everybody.
Oh you know what frame bridge evidently
is the easiest way to custom frame your
favorite art in photos is it.
We can't.
You know you're not the easiest
ways to give it to your partner.
Could you do me a huge favor and handle
this big pain in the ass fucking job.
But if you're actually cool and you don't
want to do that to your wife or your
husband or your fuckin transgendered
person whatever I'm trying to be
politically correct or whatever
the fuck you're living with.
Maybe you're a Gore phobic in
a sexual split personality.
Don't do it to the other person in you.
OK that I cover everybody without ever
leaving your house with their simple
online ordering process you can order
a fully customized piece in minutes.
Here's how it works.
Go to frame bridge dot com upload your
photo from your computer or directly from
your Instagram feed.
Have you been to Jordan lately or if
you have a physical item they'll provide
secure pre-paid packaging so
you can mail it in for free.
Preview your photo online
in any frame or style.
Choose your favorite or get help for free.
Free help from the talented designers
the expert team at frame bridge will
custom frame your item in days not weeks
or months and deliver your finished
piece directly to your door ready to hang.
Now now if this was me I and the copy
here honestly how much longer can you talk
about photos in a fucking frame by now.
Not these guys day
they're gonna keep going.
The best part you may not have asked
instead of the hundreds you pay at framing
stores their prices started just thirty
nine dollars thirty nine Sam cutting in
and all shipping is free.
Plus my listeners will get 50 percent
off their first ordered frame bridge dot
com when they use my code br.
All right guys guess he needs
to know how much it costs.
Frame bridge even offers a happiness
guarantee if for any reason you aren't 100
percent satisfied with your
order they'll make it right.
Well then you should have a
satisfaction guarantee not a happiness.
We have a happiness guarantee that
you're not 100 percent satisfied.
That doesn't make any sense. Do you
know how to percent happiness right.
Happiness guarantee if if you for any
reason aren't 100 percent happy with your
order they'll make it right.
Jesus gave you a personal experience
using framers. I never fucking used it.
I need you guys.
I never know what I don't have to every
fucking photo I took the last 20 years I
don't know where it is. It's on a
hard drive in the back of my closet.
And I took so many fucking pictures as
shit like a what do you even use it for
the site the ease of order and how
your peace turned out and how easy and
affordable it was.
Get started today framing your photos
are art do they should have a fucking
website.
Useless cell phone pics.
You know those ones you just have.
He took a screenshot of something because
you needed to remember a phone number
and then like months later
you're scrolling back trying
to find that picture you
when you got on the hang glider in one
of the photos you got to scroll past the
fucking 1 800 number for
the Smokey Robinson C.D..
You know
I don't would that be funny to sit there
and look at the top 10 worthless cell
phone photos of the day.
Then people do it on purpose so
probably be cool for like a month.
All right go to frame bridge
dot com and use promo code br.
You'll save an additional 15
percent off your first order.
Just go to frame bridge dot com promo code
br frame bridge dot com promo code br.
That's classic advertising read the last
time you do it you have that time frame
which dot com. Everything's gonna be
all right all right. He likes everybody.
You're unique.
You don't walk like everyone else.
Talk like everyone else show chat.
Sleep like everyone else so why is
your mattress why is your mattress.
One size fits all because
a truly customized mattress
will cost you five to ten
thousand bucks.
Until now I can't believe
that's a right number.
Go to hell Ixtoc com.
Answer a few simple
questions and they'll run.
Do you sleep on your back or you sleep
on your deck and they'll run a 3D
biomechanical model of your body through
their proprietary algorithms they've
developed with the help of the world's
leading Eragon nomics and biomechanics
experts.
The result a robot shows up to the door
punches you in the face through the
mattress that you ordered
and becomes you sorry.
The most comfortable
match is if ever slept on.
He likes customers report a 30 percent
improvement in overall sleep quality and
for couples they customize
each side of the mattress.
That's the end of the
relationship right there.
You're starting to build separate lives.
Your mattress arrives at your door in
about a week and shipping is 100 percent
free.
That's why everyone from GQ magazine to
Forbes are all talking about hell sleep.
You have 100 nights to try it out.
If you don't love it
they'll pick it up for free.
Ross and you have a 100 percent
refund no questions asked.
Go to Helix Sleep dot com slash burn
and get 50 dollars off your order.
That's how I sleep. Dot com slash bar
high. He looks sleek dot com slash burn.
One of those pronunciations is right.
Oh my God everybody it's dollar shave
club do doily shave club is the smart
choice why you might have asked you'll
get a great shave at a great price.
Conveniently delivered right to you.
Do you going to be set for life.
Kid you no longer have to schlep to this
store buy cheap disposable raises they
give you a cheap shave or spend a
fortune on races with gimmicky shaving
technology you don't even fucking need.
And when you use Dollar Shave Club's
Executive razor with their doctor carving
the blade gently glides
giving you a smooth shave as
you travel across your ball
bag Dr. carver shea butter is transparent
for a more precise shave helps prevent
ingrown hairs and fights razor bumps.
So in other words it works for white
people and black people make the smarter
choice by going into Dollar
Shave Club for a limited time.
New members get their first month of
the executive razor with a tube of their
doctor Carver's shea butter for only
five dollars with free shipping.
After that the raises are just
a few bucks a month. That's 15.
That's a 15 dollar value
for only five bucks.
There's no hidden fees and no
commitments cancelled anytime you like.
You can only get this offer exclusively
a Dollar Shave Club dot com slash burn
That's Dolly Shave Club dot com slash bra
I fucking love those guys just for the
simple fact that it's just one paragraph
they have empathy for me I feel all
right.
One more can you guys
handle me reading out loud.
Wink w i n c or is it wink it
is DWI and c whiskey India.
November Charlie when you have a great
clap when you have a great glass of wine
it enhances the moment
whether you're reflecting on the day
or with someone you love or just overly
explaining something to three people who
have been bored with you for 20 minutes
depending how drunk you are.
Wink understands this.
It's why they started their company to
give you access to exceptional wines from
around the world.
So you have more of those moments of
being drunk around your children not just
cake.
Nobody who drinks wine is a women.
Do women drink wine after they put the
kids down. Right. Then they pull it out
fucking bite the cork off
like a fucking pirate.
And you know what God bless them.
They deserve to do that. Just try.
Wink dotcom spelt t tr y w i n c dot com.
Try Wycombe.
Take a brief palette profile quiz
and wink will recommend distinct and
interesting interesting wines.
Actually customized to your palate to
be shipped directly to your door every
month. Isn't it hilarious that
you can do this with alcohol.
You can never do this
with like crack cocaine.
You know take a brief palette profile
quiz and we'll get you the crack pipe that
best fits your lips.
None of your time is wasted fitting in
a run to the store or on your way home
from work or on your way to an event or
gathering no more time spent guessing
what you might like.
That's actually great.
There's nothing worse as an adult when
you go over a couples you know should we
bring anything now.
We're all good.
You know you've got to bring a bottle of
wine and you got to stop at the fucking
door of the store to pain in the ass.
Just stock up on booze.
Would try Wycombe because wink bases the
wine states and they send you on your
taste preferences windfall even introduce
you to new rare and custom wines that
are not available anywhere else and
tell you the story behind each one.
Join for Free skip any month cancel any
time and at 100 percent satisfaction
guarantee. So you never have to
pay for a bottle you don't like.
And right now Wink is offering listeners
20 dollars off your first order when
you go to try Wycombe slash br.
They'll even cover the cost of shipping.
Let's try Whitcomb spelled tr y w ANC dot
com slash br to get twenty dollars off
your first order plus complimentary
shipping. Let's try with dot com slash br.
All right what are we up
to 34 fucking minutes.
Oh you don't even talk about the F1 race.
You guys watch it. Did you check it out.
Lewis Hamilton closing the
gap only down by one point.
Catching up on Sebastian Vettel.
What happened to the Ferrari's out
there in fucking great Britain.
What was it Kimi raking in whatever
his fucking name is. He's driving.
He's in third place He's loving life
for second place whatever he was in his
front tire fuckin blows out with like
fucking four or five laps to go and then
he fucking gets on the radio
the Townsville like over
the baby when he goes for
the fucking front tire.
All right so he's got to go in Vettel
moves up he's going to be on the podium as
much as fuckin
Lewis Hamilton is going to pick up
twenty five points he's gonna pick up at
least fuckin 15 if not
18. All right. Who knows.
You know and all of a sudden fucking
two laps to go his fucking tire goes up
front left one right and then all the
towns you like me all right fuckin vandals
all got damn pissed.
I think I have a I think I know who my
favorite fuckin driver is though I like
that. How have you seen
its first name Black Belt.
Val Terry Botha's that guy that guy can
fucking drive he went from ninth place
all the way to second place.
I know I've talked about Lewis Hamilton
and these guys going from fucking you
know night to like what's his face
yesterday the Australian fucker do they're
the happiest guy in fucking Formula One.
Jesus Christ babe I swear to God if
another fucking names in front of me know
what is that reckoning.
There's too many hours there's too
many fucking like crazy fuckin.
The nerve of these people to be put from
other cultures. It was a day is it Dave.
Dave. Fucking Jesus.
I only met the fucking guy. I've only
been rooting for him. Daniel Ricardo.
There we go.
The fuck would pop back into my head as
much as those guys have gone from like
19th to fucking you know 7th
grade the 15th to whatever it is.
I think it's harder to go from 9th all
the way up to 2nd because you get into
like the best of the best drivers to
fucking go past driver number five four
three to get all the way up to that start
where as far back as he did with the
Mercedes.
Once again having a gearbox issue that's
what happens with Mercedes stay forever
gearbox issue and they get a five spot
fucking penalty and evidently I don't
know who the fuck it is that's supposed
to be working on that fucking shock
absorber on the front left hand side of
the car or the fin or the fucking tire
whatever the fuck it is one of those guys
wearing the underarms with the helmet
on in the pit.
Somebody back there is getting a fucking
is get no pastor this week on the
Ferrari team.
So
what's his face.
Vettel was up by like I don't
know how many fuckin points
I forget what place he came in I think
he got like six or eight points and he
was up by like he was up by 20
points before the race started.
I can do the math here and by the end of
the race he was only up by 1 so like a
fucking math test.
So Lewis Hamilton got twenty five points
so he outscored in by fucking twenty
four.
So he come in tenth place he got one point
now they'll be twenty four he got four
points all right so he came in he came in
like eighth right and he came in eighth
All right whatever but why the fuck
would you care so they got one more
race before they take the break in the
summertime like they would like their
lives aren't fucking great enough they're
part of like like literally 20 people
who could do this in the fucking universe
all right they get to take
the fucking summer off.
I'm like these poor bastards I played
fuckin baseball who's going to pay like
fuckin six to seven games a goddamn week.
You know.
These guys get to take the summer off.
Granted they have to still diet you know.
But you know if they have like a shake
then they can they can fucking get rid of
it bang bangin a supermodel you
know fuck sweat it out of them.
I mean their lives are unbelievable.
Lewis Hamilton and fucking
what's his face. Both
times they both live in Monaco.
It's like it's not enough to get you
know he's got a private jet like these
fucking guys lives are unbelievable.
It's fucking tremendous. God bless him.
Hey what's going on with the fucking the
other Red Bull team that's not Red Bull
the blue ones the fuckin
with the hell and what the weather is
that the Totoro Rosa fucking team whatever
the fuck they're called.
Jesus Christ.
They were doing their impression of the
Force India team fucking slamming into
each other. I love when
that happens. I love that.
Reminds me that fuckin movie stepbrothers
they do doing like the Formula One
version of putting their balls
on Will Ferrell's drum kit.
No he put it on the other guy's drum
kit. That's right. I don't know.
Anyways let's get to the
fucking question this week.
Oh by the way all things comedy's own
Irish affairs new double Netflix special
airs Tuesday
July 18th.
Both double negative.
Both are both double negative
children and double negative.
Adulthood will be
available in 190 countries.
It's incredible how the reach
the sheer reach of Netflix.
All right feminism everybody.
Let's do some fucking reads here
for the goddamn week shall we.
I got 20 minutes left here
in this fucking podcast.
All right feminism Bill.
On a recent podcast when discussing
stewardesses and air travel you mentioned
that you sometimes thing the image they
think feminism is a way for ugly women
to get jobs that attractive
women used to have. I said that.
Why do you guys take anything I
say seriously. You understand.
I'm just riffing for a fucking hour and
I'm trying to make you laugh by saying
ridiculously over-the-top things.
So he's gonna write me in a few weeks.
Hey Bill a few weeks ago on your podcast
you suggested turning Buffalo Wild
Wings into gas chambers on the night of
the Mayweather McGregor fight just to
let you know I am a parent.
I am not a fight fan but I do enjoy the
fucking Halo Pino balls whatever the
fuck they're called
at Buffalo Wild Wings and
what if I was there anyways.
I wonder if you knew Ivan Emily I said
that feminism is a way for ugly women to
get jobs that attractive women used
to have. That's fucking hilarious.
I don't necessarily believe that but
there is an element of truth to that.
Like you know when they are
always bitching like you
know Hollywood creates this
impossible image of beauty.
It's like no you can't you can't.
Your fear of fucking ego maniac.
I don't think when I look at a Brad
Pitt whoever the fucking guy is now Brad
Pitt's like in his 50s now.
So we have the fucking shredded.
Who's the guy from Saved By The Bell.
Mario Lopez.
You know when I don't when I look at
him with his pigment and his fucking abs
and all that. I don't fucking go like
this is an impossible fucking town. Jesus.
This is an impossible standard for me to
talk standard for me to hold up to and
therefore Mario Lopez should
be on fucking TV anymore.
I just understand that. Yeah. You
know what on a good day maybe I'm a 6.
Okay. That's what I am. Not everybody
can bat cleanup in the order.
Okay if you're fucking bad Nate
quit your crying and get on base.
That's it.
Maybe I do believe that on some level.
Anyways I wonder if you know that this
is actually Rush Limbaugh's undeniable
truth of life.
Number 24 specifically that feminism was
established so as to allow unattractive
women to access access to
the mainstream of society.
Here's the thing I'd say in this
shit I'm like 90 percent joking.
There's always like an element of truth
that guy as far as I can tell because I
don't know what his act is.
It might all just be an act you know
so he can eat because he is in show
business.
So I have no idea it could just be an act
but if you actually truly believe that
I don't listen I don't believe that.
OK.
Feminism came about because men were not
allowing women to pursue their dreams.
OK but like any cause any cause for
whatever reason along the way a lot of the
times you end up becoming what
the fuck you were fighting. OK.
And that's not this unique thought.
I realize that's a hacky
thought but it's fucking true.
The level of bullying that goes on on
the internet and trying to get people to
get fired and trying to create firestorms
and trying to trying to show the power
of women by a lot of times attacking
people who you're deliberately and
knowingly taking what they said out of
context and causing them to not have a
fucking job is fucking reprehensible.
All right.
And they in a lot of ways
do the same reptilian.
If the ends justify the means corporate
fucking mentality just some of this shit
that that is set out there.
Yeah.
Look I don't think that it's actually
that but sometimes I think it's that you
know there are jobs that you should
only get if you're good looking.
You know I really believe that like like
when you get you know the first person
that they're going to fucking walk in
the top of your order you got to go with
Ricky Henderson. You know you gotta
get somebody who's gonna get on base.
You gotta put the fucking picture up.
You know and I feel like I can say this
because of how I look like if I ran a
company.
I'm not putting me on the front desk like
I'm the first person you're gonna say.
Why would you do that.
We're trying to make money here.
You know I know that high
schools over look in the mirror.
Love yourself but have a
sense of humor about yourself.
Know that you're not perfect
and just know that it's OK.
And you know what a lot of times if
you stare into that shit and you have a
sense of humor about yourself
you're fun to be around.
How many times I call myself a
pasty bald freckled fucking jackass
telling me you fucking stare into
it and you fucking age gracefully.
All right you start to lose your fucking
here. You just shave your fucking head.
Just be that guy and everybody's like
what the fuck and then. But you know what.
You deal with it.
Then people thought they respect you.
This guy came down the pike he didn't
even try to shake it off he took the pitch
right to the side and had
everybody stand it on first base.
Good for you you ugly bald son of
a bitch right. This is the thing.
So I know that they need ugly bald son
of a bitch as in movies and I'll just
audition for that at the end of
the fucking day I'm in a movie.
Am I really gonna complain.
You know I feel fucking.
Fucking bald freckled redhead should
be starring in more movies it's like oh
yeah you want to put your money
put your money where your mouth is.
You go finance that fuckin movie
yeah.
And a lot of ways.
That's one of those things which
everybody should get like a ribbon.
I mean I don't know what the solution
is but you like competition is a good
thing.
Okay.
And the best you know the
best should should win right.
Mike I'm I'm all with it
as far as everybody should
have the same opportunity.
But after that go fuck yourself.
Whoever's the best gets it.
You know.
Now like well we have enough of these
people are enough of those now who are the
fucking best.
Okay.
When we have to keep doing that because
at some point if the aliens aren't
already here they're coming here and we
need to have an all star fucking team
not a team that makes everybody feel
represented. All right. There we go.
I hope I explained myself or you know
I'll I'll know if I'm right if I don't get
a call from the Rush Limbaugh Show
asking me if I want to be a guest.
All right brother X feminine.
Dear Billy Boy boyo relative
relatively new fan here.
I loved Uma too. Love your material
help to see life one day. Thank you.
Before I start I want to say that
I don't care if my brother is gay.
To each his own is my motto. Okay
now for the back story. There you go.
That's what I do.
You've established you've given yourself
credibility because you said that
you're a good person. All right. I'm
17 about to be a senior in high school.
My brother is eleven and is
about to start middle school.
I feel like other kids will view him as
an easy target for a few reasons first.
He doesn't have many guy friends and he
hangs out with a lot of ladies second.
I do.
I try to do masculine things with them
I play baseball so I always ask him to
play catch with me and I even offered
to teach him how to place the sport.
He usually says no when I try to do
any sort of physical activity with him.
He rejects my requests and
just does his own thing.
Third his body language is quite feminine.
He sits like a girl talks like a
girl and moves his hands like a girl.
You know what I'm saying.
And the thing that ladies and
gay guys do with their hands.
You know I'm saying the thing that ladies
and gay guys do with their hands when
they talk.
My gut tells me to sit down and have a
talk with him but I don't want to come
off too blunt and hurt his feelings.
Then again that could be what he needs.
I think if I tell him what I'm thinking
he'll just blow it off just like me.
He's very hotheaded.
Sorry about the hyphen.
I personally blame his behavior on the
pacification of society over the past few
years and the very progressive
environment of modern day schooling.
He's a good kid and he's got a good
head on his shoulders so I'm not worried
about anything else.
I'm just looking out for him.
I don't want to dickheads
messing with him.
I used to get bullied so I know
how it feels. What do you think's.
Thanks for your help. Go
fuck yourself. All right.
I think you're 17 and I think you love
your brother and you're trying to protect
him.
Here's the deal dude.
I mean your brother is who your
brother is. You got to accept that.
And
I don't know how you handle the bullying
thing which is what I really think is
what you see when you look
at your brothers like this
kid's gonna get the shit
kicked out of them.
Which is you know sad to say.
You know hopefully not as
much as when I was coming up.
But yeah that is it.
That is it's a legit concern.
But
I don't think you listen people
are born how they're born.
OK. I don't know if this kid's
gay or not. I don't know what.
But if he does want to play catch
he doesn't want to play catch.
And if he's hardheaded you know e sound.
He said he's a smart kid he's hot
headed he knows what he wants.
So just let him be himself.
And you support him and there's no
reason why this kid he doesn't like to do
physical shit.
I wouldn't say take him down to a dojo.
Teach him how to fuck somebody up.
And the fact that he is effeminate.
If he goes and fucks somebody up that's
going to be humiliating for the other
person and then nobody else is going to
want to fuck with them because they want
to get beat up by Bruce Lee
used to do that Bruce Lee used.
I read this book used to walk around he
would act all effeminate and then these
guys would come up and fuck with him and
then he would kick the shit out of him.
People ask him well why would you do
that he said well if I just walked up.
Like a regular dude you know they got
their ass kicked they could get over it
but if they thought they got their ass
kicked by a sissy you know it stays with
them.
And unfortunately that is something with
guys if you know if people were more
progressive or whatever the fucking word
is they wouldn't think that and they'd
just be like well it doesn't
make a difference if you're
effeminate or masculine
if he can fucking throw hands
over there with a couple of feces.
I can I can accept the loss.
I listen I would just if anything I would
try to have a closer relationship with
my younger brother and
and I would ask him how his days are
going and I would just really ask him Is
anybody at school fucking
with you or whatever.
And if they are I don't know.
I would go down and have a fucking
talk I don't know if he could do that.
I don't know what to do. I don't
know what to do but that would do it.
As an older brother that would kill me
knowing that somebody could be fucking
with my younger brother. So I think you
come from a good place. Your ideas of
you know how to cure him of that are
understandable because you're 17.
I don't think it's society's fault.
I just think that's just how he's born.
And I think if you accept it he will
accept it and he'll keep a good feeling
about himself.
But unfortunately the bullying is going
to come and he's gonna have to learn how
to stick up for himself.
I mean that's just the truth of it.
And
there's all kinds of things that you could
do that I'm not allowed to say on the
podcast.
As far as what he could do in those
moments because somehow I become this
fucking bad person.
But I'm just going to
tell a random story here.
I remember the late Charlie
Murphy rest his soul.
He told me to do what to do if
you ever go to jail. And I just.
It was like you know not
that I could still survive.
He was like Yo this is what you do.
He goes the first motherfucker
that steps to you.
He goes you just turn into a wild animal
frothing at the mouth and you just
fucking swing for the fences and everybody
you know what I'm oversimplifying
what the fuck he said.
And
you know that's just a story he told me.
That has nothing to do with
what I just fuckin read.
Okay I want to do that
so I stay free and clear.
I don't know what to tell you buddy.
All right. Let him be who he is.
And you know I would watch some MDMA
events with them and maybe he'll want to
learn how to fucking do it.
I don't know.
I don't know because I've watched some
some cool videos of some kids that were
way out of their own weight class.
It's one fucking kid fucked his kid up
jumped up put him in a fucking arm by
this kid.
And what the fuck they do.
Maybe you can help him out with that but
yeah I would let go of all that other
shit that you're going to
fucking do I mean if like
you are being who you are.
I mean if somebody when you go out in the
driveway and it's to learn how to talk
a little bit time you just would still be
you but you'd know how to toilet baton.
I don't think it would change
how you walked or behaved
or who you hung out with.
You're wired how you wired. All right.
Girlfriend wants to move back to her home.
That's like those fucking people that you
know that would try to cure gay people
you know.
They think that they like it's like
they have the mumps or something.
Girlfriend wants to move
back to her home country.
All right.
Hey Bill Hill. If the guy took the woman's
last name in marriage. That's funny.
All right. Longtime listener first
time advice seeker I live in London.
I met my girlfriend online
a year and a half ago.
She's 25 and I'm 24.
She's from Switzerland.
See this what happens now to
all these fucking dating apps.
Fun fact about Switzerland.
They have enough nuclear bunkers to
accommodate their entire population.
Yeah that's because they're
so close to fucking Germany.
They moved here a few
years ago to get a music.
She moved here a few years ago to get
a music degree and graduated graduate.
Last year she was going to move in with
a friend a few months ago but her best
friend did a 180 at the last second.
So we decided to move in together
as we enjoy each other's company.
Here's the shit part.
She always said that she misses her
family and her friends a lot which is of
course understandable but recently she's
been mentioning that she wants to move
back to Switzerland once
our lease is up next year.
I completely get why she
would want to do this.
She doesn't have many friends here.
As many of her college
friends have moved back home.
The thing is I have established
an established career
here and I don't want to
leave my friends a job behind to go move
to a country where I don't speak the
language.
I've tried but there are hardly
any courses for Swiss slash German
and the market for my
skills is much smaller
I'm a magician an academic tutor.
Jesus is a fucking combo.
Whenever she brings it up I answer with
very variations of well we'll cross that
bridge when we come to it but I'm pretty
sure I'm never going to come around to
the idea.
She has made the point a couple of
times that this would be me choosing my
career and friends over her which
makes it sound worse than it is.
What should I tell her.
Thanks and go fuck yourself while she's
choosing her country and her family over
you.
So I would say nicely listen.
You keep saying that this
is me choosing my career
and you know what just when
she's saying my friends over her.
Do you know that feeling you have
when you live here in London.
That's what I'm going to feel
like when I'm in Switzerland.
Do you want me to feel that. No. Well
good. I don't want to feel that either.
So one of us has to make a sacrifice here.
Are you willing to live here.
And if she says no.
Then you have to be willing to live there.
And if you're not willing to do
that then you guys need to break up.
It's simple as that
simple as that.
I would I would fucking say
Do you know you got a fucking
goddamn kids today and fucking
swipe and left the next scene.
Oh yeah.
My girlfriend lives in fucking Bangladesh
and she's really missing some of the
food over there and I you know I fucking
you know whatever the fuck I do over
here.
I mean these are these are like modern
day relationship fuckin problems.
Yeah that's it. One of you guys has
to move but don't let her guilt you.
She's not choosing her friends
you're doing what she's doing.
You're living where you want to live
next to the people you love and you can't
get mad at her for wanting to do the
exact same thing all right but you know
she's trying to mind fuck you know for
me I feel like you're choosing this go
fuck yourself.
All right well go back home and send me
some chocolates will bang every once in
a while we'll meet in Paris summit that.
It that I want to tell you.
My girlfriend. You came to my
place not the other way around.
Girlfriends belly hangs past her tits.
Jesus
Hey there Bill.
Hey there billy will you freckled cheeks.
Love the podcast especially when you and
Nia do the podcast so that I know and I
gotta get her on here more but it's just
like when I do what she has to watch
secured and the other way around.
All right.
I've got a problem then I'm hoping you
and Neha may be able to help me with.
I love my wife of seven years dearly.
We have fun together.
Make each other laugh etc..
She's my best friend.
We're in an early thirties have no
children in our very affluent crushing it
except for the sex. The sex is bad
because we have become fatty fat Fats.
We've been together for a decade and
this has only become a problem over the
past six months. I'm 5 11 and to 40
with a lot of muscle and a lot of fat.
She's five four and two
hundred and has no muscle mass.
I'm ashamed to say that even though
I love her fiercely she's no longer
physically attractive to
me. Why me. What the fuck.
I'm just being honest.
I'm sure you're not as attracted to
her although you did give yourself some
props for having a little bit of muscle
you didn't quite say you was as big a
mess. I'm ashamed to say that.
Okay. She probably feels the same.
He said that she feels the same.
She used to be 140 tops and was
curvy in all the right places.
I used to be cut like a Greek
god our sex life was amazing.
She'd have one to three orgasms.
Jesus Christ every time we had sex one
two three times four weeks and now maybe
we have sex once a month. She can't
climax anymore because she gets too tired.
Jesus over the past six weeks I've cut
10 pounds and exercise six times a week.
I'm trying but I have a long way to go.
She isn't trying to eat right and is
not interested in exercising with me.
I know sex tends to dwindle over time
but I'd like for us to be in good enough
shape that we don't need a nitroglycerin
pill every time we try to do the dirt.
Any advice would be much appreciated.
Thanks and go fuck yourself.
You have to sit down and have
an honest conversation with her.
OK I would leave the sex life out of it.
It's just like she's
not going to live long.
All right it five for two hundred pounds
maybe you can start by going for quote
romantic walks and you hold her hand
and need you try to pick up the pace and
drag along.
I would just yeah I would talk to her
about it.
And if she chooses not to get in shape
then I I would not alter what you're
doing.
I would go back to being the Greek god
that you were and if she doesn't want to
get in shape then you know
what are you supposed to do.
Watch her eat herself into
an early fuckin grave.
You supposed to be with somebody that
you're not sexually attracted to anymore.
I mean that that's fair man.
If somebody puts on almost like.
She put on almost half her body weight
I mean that's not that's not fair.
It's not fair to yourself and it's
not fair to the person you're in.
You've got to be making an
effort to to still look good.
You know and people have a tendency men
and women to do that to become you know
you know just walking around fucking
shitty looking clothes just being a tub of
shit and it's just like that whole you
should accept me for whatever I am that
means I'm going to be the
least of who I could be.
Nobody ever says that when they're the
best. Yeah. I'd like to accept you.
Fucking going to the goddamn gym the same
way you'd like me to not fucking have
my belly hanging down past my junk.
Yeah I'd have a conversation with her.
Just sit down.
You know what maybe.
My beautiful daughter is asleep.
Maybe you could come in and help.
Hang on a second me a pause here.
She can't do it. She can't do it. Sorry.
Sorry to get your goddamn
hopes up so just know that
that you just got advice from a guy.
So what I would do is I would ask a woman
in your life not her advice on how to
how to drop in okay.
Cause this is one of these
relationship conversations.
It's like when a spaceship is re-entering
the atmosphere the space shuttle that
if it wasn't at the right fuckin angle
you know where you lost a couple of those
fucking shingles on the bottom you
could fucking burn up on reentry.
All right that I really have to bring
up that tragedy to make my point.
I don't know. Maybe I didn't. All
right. Girlfriend has severe halitosis.
Jesus Christ the women
are getting destroyed.
Ladies ladies you gotta write in next
week okay. You got to write it next week.
OK stop being sweethearts and tell me
what the problem is with the guys this is
this is not fair and
balanced like Fox News.
Or CNN.
I love that chick that cried on CNN the
one with the Mary Lou Retton haircut
when Trump got elected it's just like
there was one of those unprofessional
journalistic moments I've
ever seen in my fucking life.
How did we go from Walter Cronkite to
that. I literally know who you voted for.
You're not a journalist all right.
Hey there op ed piece. All right.
Girlfriend has severe halitosis.
Dear Billy Batts I saw you perform
and hilarity is in the land.
The worst fucking nickname
the land the land of what
Jesus Christ that's so fucking
bad and you had me in stitches.
Please come back the land their T-shirts
back there defend the land do you know
for half a second in Boston they split
they lose. People call it the bean.
Don't do that Beantown was bad enough.
We don't make beans there anymore anymore
than Port Chester still makes fucking
lifesavers. Although Grand
Rapids still makes furniture
anyways.
I'm 23 year old man and recently began
dating a girl I met on a dating app.
We've been on two dates and
she has bad breath dumper.
Jesus Christ over.
The fuck do you care.
It's not your problem.
Anyways you've been on two dates so
far and they both went great. We went.
To a couple of museums for how far away
we are standard from were you standing
there going in.
Is that her breadth of the artifacts.
Is that her breath of that fucking woolly
mammoth statue that they dug out of
the fucking ice two thousand years ago
and it was actually woolly mammoth from
fucking 4 billion B.C. go fuck yourself.
Right.
We have a good conversation in this great
chemistry overall but when she smiles
the sight and smell indicates
years of not brushing or flossing.
Dude I don't see any you know the
fact that you need advice on this.
There is thick dark yellow build up along
our gum line. Oh my God I'm gonna puke.
And she talks loud so her
breath travels a long way.
Kissing is difficult to enjoy.
Oh my God this is gross.
I almost just gag order.
I always just gag there. What kind of
fucking low self-esteem do you have.
What is my advice.
Either break up with her or take her to
one of those self power washes car wash
things and tell her to smile and fucking
blaster right in the fucking grill.
Jesus fucking Christ.
That's the most disgusting visual.
Oh my God.
What the fuck.
What is my advice.
I don't know what you know what my advice
is they say they should make a stamp
for you because you were a goddamn saint
Oh my God.
Kissing is difficult.
I think I gotta walk this one off buddy
does plenty of fucking
fish in the fucking sea.
Jesus Christ my God.
That's like heaven.
Speaking of fish it's like having a
goddamn eel going along your goddamn gum
lines. I'm sorry guys. I don't know
why you do it. I would just. That's it.
It's over there.
There should be no no
I mean how are you going to
hang in there with this one.
What the fuck do you say.
Hey what you doing Thursday night.
Nothing. You wanna go to the dentist.
Let's get his or her cleanings
Oh my God dude if if
if that looks like that.
What is what is the fucking
basement going to look like dude.
Oh my God.
God bless you.
Yeah I get it to a dentist however the
fuck you bring that up I don't know.
Some questions are beyond me all right.
Jesus Christ. All right. That's the.
I've never had to stop
reading an e-mail before.
I haven't done that.
I haven't them come that close to puking
since Opie and Anthony the baby bird
when I was in that fuckin room and I
still to this day can not tell that story
without fucking gagging and coughing and
if you puke easily do not fuck and go
look up Opie and Anthony baby bird. All
right that's it. That's the podcast.
Go fuck yourselves.
I will check in on you on Thursday.
I am back to watch it a little bit of
baseball I did miss the Yankees though I
was working the whole weekend I think the
Yankees got the better of us I know we
did win one game.
Yankees are in third and the fucking
devil rays are moving up there only half a
game out so I would try to watch we're
playing the fucking Toronto Blue Jays.
Bam bam bam bam bam bam fucking Toronto
Blue Jays there was my reference to
whatever their fucking song is by Rush.
That is the Morse code.
Y y z for Toronto's airport.
Somehow they came up with a
guitar riff for that. All right.
That's something Kevin Murphy would
try to do on efforts for family.
Harp season 2 on Netflix.
Look at that coming out of that disgusting
story promoting his show telling you
to go fuck yourselves.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.