Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burn his time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 28th,
2019 what's going on?
How's it going?
I'm doing this Sunday night cause
I'm a busy freckled Biba this week.
So I actually got a buddy over going
to smoke a cigar with him. I was like,
well why don't we kill two birds with
one stone and I'll just have you on the
fucking podcast. The uh,
the one and only Josh,
Adam Meyers.
Hello everybody. How I can't do it. How
I know the Voice of
Holland, Hank, Dj Helen,
Hank on emphasis of family going
to officially say that we're back.
We got some funny shit for you this
week. Season for everybody. Season Four.
You heard me on the radio.
I the feeling Dj Howland,
Hank will be making many, many
more appearances. I hope so.
I love that guy so much. It's not
really hard for me to play it this way.
A coke addict Dj. I mean that's, you know,
just think back into my past or worry.
I thought you were, will you? Oxy pills.
What were, I mean I kind of
did the whole smorgasbord. Uh,
let's get that. Where you from?
I'm from Germantown, Maryland,
right outside of Washington
DC. Okay. Sports affiliations.
My podcast listeners
have to, here we go, uh,
all crap teams except for one of them. A
Washington Redskins, Washington Wizards,
uh, and the Stanley Cup
champion. Washington capitals.
I can't believe I get to say that. It's
like the greatest feeling in the world.
And uh, no Orioles, no nationals. Norman
oils in a nationals fan of cut his splits.
I mean,
W I grew up in an Orioles fan,
but I loved Bryce Harper and I
really just root for the whole town.
So I'm,
I'm a diehard oriels fan,
but I'm also going to root for the nets.
I just want that. Are you old enough to,
to have been a Baltimore Colt fan before
they left or no, I was, I was alive,
but I was already red skins. I mean, I
didn't think they left it. What, 82 84,
something like that. Uh, something
like that. 83, 84, somewhere around.
I remember it. This is what sucks is
that I remember just my foot from like,
he's from like zero to 10 it was just
three Superbowls and then at like 11 I
think we got our last one,
which was in nine red one the red skins.
And then that was just like,
oh we're probably going to be in this all
the time and then nothing. Well that's,
that's what's going to happen
to like the Patriots and all,
all these kids who are lucky enough to
be born in the 1990s and remember 2000
was the first one or 2000 yeah,
2001 you know, it's going to
be like, you know, there was,
there was kids born when I
was born in 1968 and then, uh,
they got to watch Dan Marino.
I May,
but I'm just saying as far as like
just being good and competitive.
I was compared to Dan Marino cause that
guy was the best I ever saw man other
than Joe Montana. But even then, I
think Dan Marino with Bill Walsh,
she see definitely wins one.
I only remember,
I only remember bad knees Marino.
That's, that's where I was bad back.
Bad is bad. Everything. When I
got in, he was already in the,
in the down travels
him,
he came in and he was with
Don Shula and Don Shula like
was a man.
Sheila was a man
but, but by then everybody
had caught up with them,
stolen all his fucking
tricks and he was on like,
cause he was in the final 10 years of,
of going back to like,
like the 1950s I want to say.
He was on the giants at one point and he
was offensive and defensive coordinator
and the other guy was Tom Landry.
Okay. Those were the two guys.
If something like that one though,
I always forget who the hell it was.
But anyways, um, I just
remember, you know, we,
they went from Bob Greasy to
fucking Dan Marino and Sydney.
This kicked our ass
for like the first one.
One years of me watching the Patriots,
he just couldn't take it. And, and I,
I look at the dolphins fans
now, like this, still waiting.
I feel so for the next,
Dan Marino,
my cousin is the biggest dolphins fan.
He named his dog Marino.
Like he, he fucking,
everybody loves this team
so much and it was like,
I remember the beginning of the season,
I was like, dude, they're looking good.
The winning some games and he's like,
they're going to fuck it up and then boom.
It's just what they finished
like seven and nine.
There are seven and 19 but I mean,
I can't talk. The Redskins are what,
like six and 10 I gave up once,
I know once all four of our quarterbacks
broken leg. I was like, all right.
I was like, we deserve it.
Racist team name we can,
you can't be foreign 12
with the racist team name.
You gotta be 12 and four we can't help it.
I will say this too.
I still can't believe in all of this,
this fucking Hashtag and all this shit.
The fact that they still do
the Tomahawk chop all like,
I can't believe it. Then all of
that, fuck it. It's so fucking bad.
It's so fucking bad.
And they sit there like it does.
I love when white people justify, like
it's literally a people as saying don't
do where they're like,
but we're honoring a hand a is
cause we committed genocide.
Who's kidding?
Who against those?
That would be like if the Germans one
and then at the soccer game everyone was
chanting, oh Yay or nay.
And you know what's funny
two is that Whoa,
he's old school Hollywood imitating their
singing and all that thing on so many
fucking levels. It's just like, dude,
what can you just, and they just,
they'd fucking refuse. And I
don't know. Well that's why,
that's why there's this like a
backlash now on white privilege site.
There's people going out
there and uh, do, uh,
just there's white people saying
that white privilege doesn't exist,
which is fucking,
then he listened to their stories and
all their stories are as basically that
they weren't born rich. But at no
point was, hey, I was driving down the,
and because I was
white,
I got pulled over tased and then shot
to death and then the cop got free
comp was released.
There's none of that shit.
None of this is like,
look,
there's to sit there and act
like they're aren't privileges,
those privileges in everything.
There's all different levels to be in
white and this and there's shit that as if
you're just like a regular white guy,
shit that you see the private
school white kid doing. You know,
that pisses me off. Different levels,
different levels of black people.
You know there's a hawks for
sure. Yes, there's, I grew
up, I grew up middle class,
little note,
lower middle class and it's just like
I had that friend that just like, dude,
I had a friend who was like super rich.
His Dad worked for the FDA, right?
This kid always had money.
That family always had money.
His Dad went into a lone star,
remember that?
That steakhouse where they put like you
to give you peanuts and then you just
throw the shells on the floor. Right? His
Dad slipped on the floor, hurt his knee,
got like $10 million. They
were already rich. Like that's,
that's the kind of shit that shouldn't
happen to my dad cause he had shit to
happen to my dad. I just remember
when, uh, being in New York City,
what time and there was his publicist to
fucking snapped or something out on an,
and she was out like,
I want to say she was out in the Hamptons,
long island and h or something,
somewhere out there.
She snapped cause something about some
club or a restaurant and she backed into
like 17 fucking people under me. The last
lash drove away. Oh, that's horrible.
Drove the fuck away it,
they got her license plate.
They knew her. She was in,
the cop showed up and the
lawyer was in the driveway,
met the cops and said she'll
turn herself in tomorrow morning.
I remember reading that going like,
what the fuck? How is that possible?
Is that what it's that, yeah, but so
to sit there and act like, I dunno,
like I five, it's fucking hilarious.
It is hilarious. It's, it's ridiculous.
Everybody,
the thing is back with the red,
I used to work in a warehouse and
unloaded trucks. It's just like,
I know, but there was no point. Did
anybody ever look at you and like,
you have white skin get out
of this neighborhood? Yeah.
This thing is, let him be,
that's the thing with the Redskins
though, is that it's, it's uh, every,
every like six years a
senator or a congressman says
you got to change the name.
And I completely agree at this point
I'm like, just change the name.
I can't believe the owner wouldn't do it
considering I honestly don't notice now
because it's just been called
that for so fucking and now,
but you're looking at this, you got
to look at the owner is first of all,
we have broadly one of the worst owners
in football because he's like Jerry
Jones, just that doesn't
know anything about football.
So he's fucking the team up causing
all these problems, you know, and,
and he wants money so bad that you would
think that he would change the name to
get all the merchandising money. Like,
dude, that's like another, you know,
$100 million worth of shit. Like that
pays for a new, you know, parking lot.
And here's an argument that I've been,
something that I've been wondering
about for a long for a while now,
and I think I kind of understand it.
Where in every sport,
I like Major League baseball,
I thought they counted world
series titles back to the 18 needs,
but they kind of,
the first one that counters in 1903,
which I think was the Boston red sox.
I literally looked it up last week.
I already forget. But like they caught
though all the way back to fucking,
uh, 1903. All right. When
it was a segregated league,
all of this shit, right? Like, you know,
crazy Lake Johnson that was fucking 10
loved him. 10 teams or whatever, right.
Stanley Cup were about that far back.
NBA titles goes back to the 1940s.
And even the Lakers count an NBL title.
They somehow want an end
and a title in the NBL.
And that was counted as a fucking NBA
title was there when they were the
Minneapolis Lakers. Yeah.
They're first looking off of,
they want an NBL and then they
want for NBA titles in Minneapolis.
And, uh, but they, they for
some reason caught that one.
But Superbowls,
they only started in 1968
and what kills me, Oh,
I saw you post something about
this. Yeah, it's, he's just like,
so see it telling me and people
were saying, because it's,
I guess because they call it a merger,
but it was like the AFL came in,
it was like the Xfl of the USFL
or the world football league.
It was just this other competing
football league and the NFL laugh gone,
you're some fucking piece of shit league.
But it was early enough on I guess where
they, you know, and they made it up,
moves and had enough money or whatever.
And then with the style that they played
that they started to compete with them
and then they played them in the first
two games, super bowl one and two,
which were called Nfl
AFL championship game.
And they got the shit kicked out of them
because they weren't as good a league.
And then then the AFL one in Superbowl
three which was still not called the
Superbowl, it was still the AFL
NFL championship. All right.
So then after that they agreed to merge
all the owners agreed in the AFL to
merge with the NFL.
Al Davis was the only one.
He wanted to put the NFL out of business
because he was fucking Al Davis. Why?
Just why you away? You got
to love them. Right. So,
and then at that point they just go,
all right,
so those first three
games against the AFL NFL,
that's when we're going to start like
I guess cause they called it a merger
rather than, but I mean like the Aba
in a way merged with the NBA. Yeah.
And they still count all that shit back
to the 1940 days. They own the NHL teams.
They only took some teams from the
Aba. They didn't take everybody. Okay.
But still. Oh yeah. But still it was,
it was a competing league that was
fucking with their numbers and they had a
more exciting game just like the AFL.
And then in the end the NBA at, you know,
it was losing too many players too.
It same way with the NFL at some point
it's like can't beat them. Join them.
And then they came together,
but they still count all those Celtics
championships in the 60s and all that.
So it's like you, you're telling
me that Johnny Unite John Unitas.
I got to look at him in a
certain way or a, in all of the,
in half of those fucking teams, the
browns, the rams, the bears, the packers,
the giants, all of those fucking teams
were in the NFL playing each other.
There was, it was actually in
a way you could say, you know,
I just can't say it was more talent
than, but I'm just saying like, I don't,
I don't get why they just wipe that away.
They don't fucking talk about it at all.
And that the Steelers with six fucking
shit and 2018 six championships.
Yeah. Like it's so fucking ridiculous
that, that the Patriots, right.
If we win Sunday, which would be next
Sunday, which will be fucking awesome.
We would be tied for the
most championships won in
NFL history and we've got our
first one fucking 17 years ago. That
doesn't, that doesn't make sense. You're,
you're, that doesn't make any
fucking sense. That's still fun.
I see where you're coming
from, but at the same time, um,
you know, we're going by super
bowl one. I, I think, listen, I'm,
I'm not a patriots fan. I
think the, in the, in the,
since they started winning them and
what 2001 was that the first one? Yeah.
I mean they're, they're definitely
one season two definitely. You know,
one of the strongest thing,
but all the people that would want to
fight and put up the fight about saying
that, you know, well I saw that thing that
guy posted. The Green Bay has liked it.
We've got like 14 or whatever,
but he is green bay though.
Green based won four super bowls and
they won like fucking 11 NFL titles.
They've been winning the
entire fucking time. Yeah.
But there's Emma one in a minute.
I mean,
how long has it been says Green Bay's one.
What was that?
2005 something like that. And I was
like nine or 10 or something. Okay.
You're right. Yeah, but well I'm
not talking about that with that.
Well then why would you fucking count
the Broncos having won in 20 years?
So what those there's don't
count. No, they no, they count.
I'm just saying they count.
But I just thought you were getting mad
about somebody posting that Green Bay
had x amount because they were enclosed
and the earlier one. That's my argument.
They should keep those. Yeah.
But those should fucking count.
If the fucking Montreal Canadians can
count when they fucking beat somebody
playing on a pond. Oh, I didn't know which
angle you were going with. Oh, sorry.
I thought you were going against,
I thought you were saying door.
Octos gamble foray. Oh, okay. Then
I love the history of the game.
The NFL has been the NFL and a bunch
of fucking leagues have tried to to,
to compete with them. They've
never, they've never been able to,
the best you ever had was
the AFL merged with them,
but it was still called the NFL.
It wasn't called the AFL.
It wasn't called the NFL. Slash AFL,
like Sirius Xm or whatever. And right.
It was called the fucking
NFL. You joined the NFL. Yeah.
So those other championships
were NFL championships.
That's cause now you call it
the fucking super bowl. Sure.
It was still the two best teams and
those, you know, before the AFL existed,
those were the two fucking best teams
of who that fucking classic giants,
colts game played in fucking Yankee
Stadium. The winner of that, it can't,
can't fucking walk up to somebody
who super bowl four and said,
I know what that feels like.
They know exactly what it feels.
There's a lot of people are dying off
but yeah, they know what it feels like.
100%. That's a great point. They are
dying, dying but I dunno, I count them.
I that the Green Bay packers are the
fucking New York Yankees and I think the
giants and next, and that's the way
it should be. Did I think it was,
well the Redskins are up there. The
Redskins have, we have no, you've got,
you might get three.
And then we had,
I think we had like four other world
championship ones too. All right.
I'm going to give you some trivia.
Where did the rams first started? Um,
the city
St Louis.
No, cause then I knew it was
with Los Angeles. I don't
fucking know Jesus Christ.
You know, you just started like
me in math class a long time ago.
That's what I love about you is that for,
I know, I know sports, but dude, you know,
fucking sports like you,
like I can imagine.
Fair point.
Because I used,
I used to no fucking everybody in the
league and I just don't have time anymore,
so I don't know.
But they started off in Cleveland and
I've never understood why they were called
the rams. I don't know that there was
any rams in there. Um, all right, let's,
let's look up.
What am I looking at?
Washington red skins.
What's your fight song?
Hey,
hail to the Redskins.
Dory Braves on the war path.
Fight for Oh, daisy. Oh, there you go.
And then it goes into some weird thing.
Brandon doesn't jump in there.
And Lad Ball,
Steven Dapa Dupa led the point,
so,
all right.
Hey,
go NFL championships pre 1970 merger.
Uh, you got to five. Pretty good.
I'll take it. Yeah. So you got five.
So right now as far the way I look
at your tie with the Patriots,
we've got five super bowls. You
got, you got five champion. We have,
we have five championships and we should,
everybody thought like you cause a lot
of, you know, there's a lot of people,
you fucking people have ever said that.
No, I completely agree with
what you're saying. If he,
if the one before it was the official
Superbowl, it's still a championship.
Unfortunately a lot of
those people have died.
Yeah. Who would care, I guess.
Um, let's see. Yeah, yeah, Eh.
All right. Uh, Le League
championships. All right.
The NFL champ pre 1970s,
um,
the giants won four,
so they've won 40 NFL titles and
they won four super bowl ties.
Those you go to the stadiums, they
had no way to be found then. No,
they're not listed.
It's like it never fucking happened.
See the angle you're coming
with right now, and I respect
the, what you're saying,
dude, 100%. That's not fair.
I'm not saying it's not fair. Not
Fair. I'm just, I'm just asking why,
why won't you dude, lead
championships. Chicago bears. Okay.
They want fucking nine
19 2119 323340414346,
1963 and then he won a Superbowl in 1985
and all they have is one fucking banner
hallway hanging over their stadium.
Check one of the scores when they beat
the Redskins in one of those league
championships. It's like, it's
like crazy fucking lopsided.
70 to like 70 to eight from not mistaken.
So I don't know a lot about sports,
about facts, but I do know that,
that that is right. All right, let's
look up the uh, Los Angeles Rams.
All right. And your fire, you nervous? Are
you nervous about Sunday? Oh yeah, always.
I'll tell you what's the funniest thing.
My uh, verse, he texted me and he's like,
dude, Todd Gurley, is it Todd Gurley
tug earlier? Yeah. He goes, he's heard.
And in my head I'm like,
dude,
there's no way to stand up comedians
know the injury status of the key running
back for the rams if praise. I
got a guy on the inside. Yeah.
Who's your guy in the inside?
espn.com this is my, if,
if he was really fucking hurt, we wouldn't
know. They would keep that under wraps.
But he was hurt in the last game. I saw
them on the bike for a little bit. I know,
but here's the thing, what is
everybody's hurt this time of year?
They all said he's got to
fucking ruins of book cover.
He's going to fucking play.
If they are leaking it out that he's hurt,
that means that he's,
he's way better than they thought he was
going to be because that's just good.
Always hurt and like, but they know
Bella check is going to be like, well,
I guess we don't have to
prepare for Todd Gurley. Um,
but it's just funny that, oh no,
he showed up. Yeah. All right.
And it fell championships
pre 1970 the rams,
they wanted 45 and 51 and then they
won in 1999 and they were the y'all
Cleveland Rams from 1936 to 1942 they
took 43 off to finish off the Germans and
the Japanese 1944 1945 that was the
last year and then they moved to Los
Angeles.
They stayed there until 94 came back to
2016 which brings me to something I was
making fun of and let, did you see, do
you watch the saints ramps game? I did.
All right.
Everybody thought the worst fucking
thing in that was that fucking helmet to
helmet?
No pass interference call.
The worst thing in that game was when
they cut to the stands after the rams won
and you saw those guys in the rams
jerseys in their twenties maybe early
thirties crying. I saw that, yes. Yeah,
I did see the girlfriends
were trying to come for them.
It's just like buddy [inaudible].
You were fucking two years old
when they moved away. Like what?
What are you doing here?
You can waiting since 2016
it says that, listen, you're,
you're fucking pill. Ryan went belt
when you, cause if you remember how,
what happened when we watched,
because you watched the caps game with
me when they won the cup where you are on
my computer.
I was in London or in London than I was
facetiming you so you could watch the
game if you,
everybody was asleep
and I was a pitch black and I
was in the bathroom of my hotel.
My wife and daughter was sound
asleep and I was going to it.
I'm so happy for you just did.
And I was sitting there going like I did.
I was facetiming with you and you,
you had your fucking TV.
Congratulations Buddy. Like
your husband. I know it,
but my wife probably thought I was
in there talking to a hooker. Okay.
Everybody's asleep. Oh
man, it's so beautiful.
It's so beautiful.
But what was apple?
What was so funny is if
you would have seen me,
and I mean like I remember in
[inaudible] 91 with the Redskins won,
but I remember the day
after because my mom,
like I was watching the game and
then the uh, my mom made a bunch of,
of her famous Super Bowl Chili and I ate
a bunch of it and then I fell asleep in
a laundry basket.
Uh,
I was 11 and then I didn't get another
championship until this caps one.
And we were watching it together
and you were facing the screen.
And I remember I was just like cheering
as the clock run down and then the
member,
it stopped for a second,
there was like a stoppage of
play or like 0.06 seconds.
So I was screaming and then I got
quiet and then they win the game and
everybody's running on the ice and I'm
just dead silent. I thought, I was like,
am I dead inside?
Like what is wrong with me?
And then they brought
the cup out and dude,
I just started weeping,
just weeping dude.
Just like, I can't do it.
Why does it matter so much?
It's so soon. It's sky, it's everything.
It's just all the, it's all dude.
It's everything. It's all the, it's
all the, it's all the, you know,
the Times that they,
they,
they chunked it before when they were
supposed to win and all the times then,
you know, they, they did,
she put so much into it and to
finally get it just was so sweet,
man. And it was like, I started
thinking about like, this is great.
I'm going to go really like
John Cougar Mellencamp here.
But like I thought about all like the
middle class people that live in the
Washington DC area that worked these
dead end jobs and then they just,
they get that championship cause they
want it so bad and that, that team,
whether it's the Redskins
and the caps or whoever,
it's like that's what they have to, to
hold them escape. And so I, you know,
I wouldn't say spring senior team
raise the cup is just like, I, I,
I kind of was just like, I don't think
I'm ever going to see the Bruins steward.
And when they finally did it,
I watched him from 1980 to 2011.
That's how long it took me to,
what's that 10 2031 years? 30
ones I watched him. And um,
so from age 12 to a,
what does that 43 when they
finally they finally did it and uh,
I,
I was,
I told this to before I was at the Chicago
Theater on Jim Norton's tour with Jim
Breuer,
David telling myself from this tour called
the antisocial tour and I watched the
first period and a half.
Then I went on stage and then when I
got off stage I watched the final seven
minutes upstairs in one of those where
the green room is something like that.
And I remember being up there by myself
cause none of them cared because it
wasn't their team.
And the show ended and they went out to
do the meet and greet and I stayed up
there and there was like a three minutes
left and they scored a goal or it's
just not enough time for
the other team to come back.
Vancouver and I was by myself
and my eye went up like 900
because I was like,
and I
and all I wanted to see, they
were like, hey, like come on,
you got to come down from a
meet and greet people saying,
where the fuck are you calling you a
phony finance? I was like, wait, nice.
I just had to see him lifted
up and I told my wife to tape,
but I knew she was taping it and just
when I saw Zidane or just lifted,
I'm just going,
right
dude,
that was
one year is just coming out of here.
Just Ah,
all those years of not being able to be,
get past the keys,
not being able to win
in the forum. Yeah, man.
Fucking getting past the Canadians and
then run into those fucking Gretzky
Edmonton Oilers and the Mark Messy
Edmonton Oilers and just, and then just,
you know, Neil, he's getting his
fucking leg taken out, you know,
and bore Kevin and goes somewhere else
to when a cop and it's just fuck, fuck,
fuck, fuck, fuck the lockout. Oh yeah.
All of that thing. It did. It all just
goes through your head and then Bam,
thank you. Literally feel like they're
good. There's going to like look at,
look like at your television screen and
go or do you want to hold the pin up and
you can just like grab it.
It's just such an inquiry.
It was such an incredible feeling,
such respect for that trophy. I would
never touch it. I won't even touch it.
So I grabbed because I'm not a cause.
You should be, you should be on a team.
That fucking one players who play in the
League won't even touch it unless they
want it.
So me some fucking asshole
because there's was gone cause
that whew it up and drink that.
I'm going to let you lift it up dude. They
might let you get like a bottom on it,
but that's about it. I respect
that. I've seen pictures of guys,
I know that no players in shit and
they're like holding it with them.
Like what the fuck are you doing with
your hands on that? No, I respect that.
I respect that you,
you appreciate it.
Fax It back with a green
baret that cy action.
And you got your face all painted too.
Like you did something.
You paint balling when I
watched it with your paypal gun.
I watched you on CNN.
Um, anyways, I got a little bit of
advertising here like I have to read.
Let me see here. What did we get? Where
the fuck did this? This always happens,
Joe. Santa Maria is, why does
this always happen? Okay. Oh,
1-800-FLOWERS. Um, Valentine's
Day is coming up there,
buddy got weight by now.
Most of us have started racking our brains
about what Valentine's gift is truly
going to make her day
special. Dude. Fuck that.
It's any woman out there fucking racking
their brains about what kind of fucking
stupid thing they're going to get.
You know, you know, a guy should do,
we should get into some, what fucking
thing could you pressure them?
We'd be funny. Like ladies,
you know, Valentine's Day.
What kind of flat screen
TV as they get a bad,
some sows audio. Oh,
that's shiny shit. Uh,
with one 800 flowers.com.
It's really not that complicated.
Roses from 1-800-FLOWERS
are a no brainer right now.
When you order early 1-800-FLOWERS has
amazing deals on vibrant and Romantic
Valentine's rose bouquets.
Is it bouquet a bowl?
Who Says Bow k?
It's bouquet bouquet.
Oh my God, it's a bouquet bouquet.
I'm going to get a boom. Okay. Okay.
Tomato,
tomato.
It's like that arrangements and more
starting at 29 99 this is a great thing to
do though, to fucking
get this done. Oh yeah.
The order ahead of time to get this
fucking thing done and then you,
then you just,
then you just find some other stupid
bullshit thing that you can do.
You send a flowers to works.
Everybody,
she can fill in Yankee game first of
all of the fucking friends, you know,
and that's what it's all about. Oh
yeah. I'll send it to the house.
He get us centered to a public day.
People to see that stupid quote,
I love this woman.
That's what they want.
See my policies better than yours.
There are so many unbelievable
deals from 1-800-FLOWERS,
but you have to hurry a roses.
Roses are red roses from 1-800-FLOWERS
are picked at their peak and shipped
overnight to ensure freshness or maids
or just pictured the miserable bastard
picking those things. Gorgeous.
Does he have any love in his life?
Balance,
gorgeous valentines bouquets
and arrangements starting
at 29 99 is an amazing
deal, but it won't last long bouquets
prices will be going up soon,
so take advantage today.
Pick your delivery date and let
1-800-FLOWERS handle the rest.
When it comes to Valentines,
I don't settle for anything
less than my rose authority.
I guess it's supposed to be talking.
One 800 flowers.com to order Valentine's
Day bouquets arrangements and more.
Starting at 29 and Nan,
go to one 800 flowers.com.
Click on the radio icon and enter Berbee.
You are ordered today and
save@oneeighthundredflowers.com code bird.
I love how you slowly turned into Waylon
Jennings. Towards the end of that,
I just get a see Nana na.
I have to do anything.
I can't because I can't read
out loud anything to keep
it. Dude. I love the, the,
the bouquets. That's fantastic.
Hello? That's like I tell me
basement and there's no bouquets at the
Alamo. That's, that's my fucking shit,
dude. All right. Hymns. You know what
I'm saying? It wasn't us. It was them.
That's why I got him some,
that's from the warriors. It was,
I never seen the warriors. You never
seen the word. Never seen the warriors.
I started it and then I fell asleep.
I'd looked like two months ago.
I'll get into it one day. Okay. Hymns. Uh,
why did guys turn to weird solutions
or do nothing when they can turn to
medicine and science? What are they
talking about? Solution for hymns.com.
A one stop for hair loss.
Skincare. Sexual wellness.
Oh God. What the fuck was that? Oh,
I turned it on to make sure
I knew you were coming.
Oh fuck. I forgot to send that
fucking lady at check. All right,
what am I doing here? Um, for him, a
one stop shop for hair, less hair loss.
Skincare, sexual wellness for men.
This is the whole thing, dude.
You're going to clear up your skin.
You got to get your main bag and
he'd get to have a fucking blow job.
Motivate your audience. Talk about the,
your experience with the product. Well,
you know, I'll be talking about
that. I'm married. I'm fucking bald.
Is Getting looks great.
Cool. Yeah, that's right.
Choose one or two copy points
to rotate into your spot.
Why are they telling us thanks to
science bald? This can be optional.
Well fuck it. Thanks for telling
me hymns. Connect with your,
with connects you with real doctors
and met Al. Good, good real doctors.
This time and medical grade
solutions to treat hair loss.
Well known generic equivalents to name
brand prescriptions to help you keep your
hair. No snake oil pills or gas
station counter supplements.
A prescription solutions
backed by science. I like that.
Snake oil and gas station solution do
they said that was from like the 1930s.
They still do that.
Go to any like any like uh,
you know the gas station and you
can get those like, you know,
black Mambas or like just this like Dick
Pills, whatever dude. They sell them all.
Buy over the counter. Yeah. Dick pill.
That's a good name for a band. Uh,
no waiting room. No awkward
in person. Doctor visits.
Save hours by going to for hymns
for h I m s.com so easy answer.
A few quick questions.
Doctors will review and can just prescribe
you products are shipped direct to
your door. All right, uh,
order now by listeners.
Get a trial of four
hymns for just $5 today.
Right now while supplies last.
See website for full details.
This would cost hundreds if you
went to the doctor or a pharmacy,
go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bird that's for h I m s.com/burr for
hims.com/burr.
And lastly,
but certainly not leastly stamps.com
postage rates have gone up again.
Can you believe how many cents it costs
to send a fucking envelope from here to
fucking New York?
Thankfully stamps.com can ease the
pain with big discounts off post office
retail rates.
stamps.com makes it easy.
They'll send you a free digital scale.
Automatically calculates exact postage
stamps are co when we will help you
decide the best class of
mail based on your needs.
They'll even give you postage discount.
She can't get at the post office,
including 5 cents off
every class class stamp.
I stamps.com to send out all my posters.
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you right now
my slash our listeners,
my listeners get a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus free
postage and a digital scale.
See for yourself why over 700,000 small
businesses use stamps.com just go to
stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
that
derber.
Uh righty. Um, hey, you have a podcast?
They do. I, you know what was funny,
I was watching you read that and like
you just keep going when you make the
mistake. And like when I tried to
tape stuff like that, if I like,
if I fuck up at all, I just like,
I'm like, all right, God dammit.
And I just like to have to start over.
It's a seeing you do it so effortlessly
perfectionist where you're so
comfortable doing it. Well, I do.
I've established right out of the
gate that I'm a moron in front of it.
Yeah.
It's like an idiot.
Bill Clinton saw it happen and Gary Hart
and you just got out in front of it.
They would just like, did
you? He was like, I fucked
them all. And then he fucking,
you know,
but then he went back to his old ways.
I did not have sex with that woman.
That's a good Clinton did. And I,
if I say if I went,
I,
I do not have problems reading out loud.
Like that would be the end.
I would get impeached. Sure. That'd be a,
you know, I wouldn't leave just like him.
I need to leave my flaws in. That's
what it taught me to do. Yeah.
I do have a podcast. Uh, I love it. Bill,
I'm telling you I love
this and more than the 500,
the 500 it's about stock car race.
It is not about that.
It is about the 500
greatest albums of all time.
I'm going through rolling Stone
Magazine's list of the 500 greatest albums
starting at 500. Working
my way down to one. Uh,
each week I sit down with a
comic actor or musician now, uh,
you know,
and I give them a week with the record
and then I break the record down and we
sit down and talk about it is kiss cut.
One of them I just did,
I just did with Jeff Ross kiss
destroyer. I was going to say, you know,
you could've got Steven
Adler. Ah, I've got, he loses.
I would love to get Steven.
Dude,
I love this so much man.
Like cause it's not just being able to
sit down and talk with my buddies about
the album and ask them questions around
like the meanings of the songs and the
facts from the record. But Dude,
since I've started doing this,
like I have listened to music than I
thought I would never listen to who didn't
even know about and it's like touching me
and it's just so incredible. Right now.
I'm listening to Steve Earle Guitar town.
You ever heard of him?
This guy is fight. He's
like, he's like the key.
This is like his born in the USA,
but country record dude,
I never listened to country.
I fucking love this record dude.
When did it come off?
1985 and he has a song
called guitar town and it's,
it's just,
it's just incredible.
I mean especially once you
know the history of this
guy and like how he dropped
out of school and then went to
Nashville like you know, to,
to find Townes van Zandt and like
was writing songs for people.
And then the record company was like,
all right,
well we want you to make a record.
And he was like, all right. And He's,
he just sat down and wrote the first
song and the last song and then just the
whole album came together. But
it's like, that's what I love.
How many albums does he f well he's
got to shed load. How does he decide?
I would listen to anything else.
So he must be real quality cause I don't
know who he is. You know what I mean?
Cause I figured like if I know who
country person is for the most part,
they suck because it's going to be like,
you just know like the pop kind of,
here's the thing though. You don't
know. It's like, you know, like if, if,
if you were, I dunno if somebody
say name is speed battlement
metal band. Everybody would
know a motorcycle. That's
right. You would say motors.
Motors, sickle, our favorite band.
No, this is, this is the thing.
The guy could have been like enormous.
But then he developed like a drug
problem and then kind of fell off.
And now he actually still makes
music but a country, the country, uh,
fan base doesn't really fuck with him
anymore because he leans very left.
And I was actually watching
a documentary of his,
cause I'm getting ready to record the
episode with Tom Everett Scott from that
thing you do. Um, he played the drummer,
you remember when he came
and did it at the gym. Um,
and you look at the youtube comments, you
know, of this documentary. And it's like,
I used to like his music, but he's a
fucking stupid left as liberty card.
And it's just like, because they
can't accept that, you know,
you can play country music
but still lean towards yes.
Also, why I think, you know,
you shouldn't be constantly putting out
your political opinions. Like, listen,
I just completed, I didn't complete.
I make fun of people, you know,
the white privilege thing. I like
this. I make fun of feminists and shit.
I tried to be like even handed
or whatever, but uh, you know,
all you do is just like nobody.
All you do is get people who
agree with you to agree with you.
And then people who don't agree with you
too now hate you and not want to watch
something that you do because
they can't separate the two.
I can stay at a fucking Trump
hotel and not like Donald Trump.
And a lot of people can't get
past that because in their minds,
the people who run the Sheridan,
who were also billionaires for some reason
didn't vote for Donald Trump. I said,
they're all there. They're all the same
fucking pig. Get a hundred percent yeah,
by not dead to mention like it's just to
just painful his name outside the thing.
It's not like living and it's, I've been
in a Trump hotel. They're extremely nice.
They're incredible. They're
incredible. Yeah. I said Nice. I mean,
everybody knew what I meant. You didn't
have to one up me and say incredible.
It was incredible. I've only stayed at
one. It was fucking fantastic like this.
I want opinion. Incredible.
What this guy should be doing.
Fuck yeah, dude. Fizz to
stick to hotels. Residency.
Was he competent as his fucking
hotel? I made this, this, this.
We would be back.
He would make it great again if it's tax
cuts were as good as his bath towels.
I made Cobb the fuck. You know what? I
was bringing front of it the other day.
Somebody said like there was some, I guess
it was some sort of taxing out there.
If you make $11 million or more and
people would make $11 million or more.
We're complaining. Oh yeah. So, uh,
somebody had tweeted that, you know,
hey, you know, this is fucking bullshit.
Just pay your fair share so
it makes $11 million a year.
It doesn't work any harder than
somebody who makes 20 grand a year.
And I was fucking dying
laughing. I was like, oh yeah,
they do. Yeah, they do. Yeah,
they do.
You wonder why a guy make it $11 million.
He's getting a fucking divorce
is cause he never sees his wife.
That's why it's true. That's why
it doesn't see his kids has a pool,
never been in it. And it's just like,
yeah, there's this 24 fucking seven, I,
I've made 20 grand a year.
You always great.
It's the second the fucker whistle blows.
You don't even think about that job.
But once I think nobody calls
you up, hey bill, uh, tomorrow,
when you unload the boxes,
could you maybe do it?
Then we need to get to have a fucking
conference calling how you unload the
fucking truck.
It's just as people don't think that
people think of like when you think
somebody makes 20 million a year,
like we just know shit from
like Falcon Crest and dynasty,
all those shows and they're like,
they don't do anything. Yeah.
To hang out in country clubs and
they piss on us $20,000. Yeah.
And you have pay petty fights with
people within your family. Yeah.
That's all they do. Like nobody sees
them like, you know, in the office from,
you know, from 6:00 AM until like
3:00 AM and then they go home,
like walk into their kid's room,
the kid's sleeping,
they single teardrop falls and then they
go bang the maid and go to sleep. Yeah.
It's kind of what I, that's what
I assume happens. I have no idea.
I grew up lower middle
class, but I love, I,
what I love about this podcast is that
I would do this if nobody was listening
because I wanted to
listen to these albums.
And I started to, um, I was just
going, I want her to feel inspired.
I think I was just musically tapped
out and, and I was like, all right,
I'm going to listen to an album a day,
over 500 days.
And I started posting about it
and when I got to like four 98,
which was like on the third
day, Jim Jefferies reached
out to me. He's like, dude,
he's like, that stone roses record is one
of my favorite records. He's like, oh,
the stories that I think of when I hear
that music and then it like hit me.
And I was like, that's the podcast I've
been waiting to do. It was a great voice.
He can sing.
He's incredible voice.
Uh, but he came on and he
did and he did that episode.
And that's basically what
it is. It's like, you know,
we're going to go through these great
records and we're going to talk about,
and we're gonna,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna ask you to need more
than a day to listen to an album.
And then I give them a week. He
just pointed right at me. No. Oh we,
I give you a week. Oh yeah.
Well you did it. You did.
I thought you only took a day to listen
to it because you're so busy because
you're making $12 million.
So you're out. Um,
how can $1,000,001 11,000,001,
so that was the one who complained.
I could tell it was you, that was so,
but what it is is like I give every comic
or act or whoever it's going to be a
week with the record and then I break the
album down and like ask them questions
about their life using the meaning of
the songs, the facts from the record.
So,
so the album is really just like the
celery and the carrots and the onions have
the soup. But it's really just, you know,
the basis for me to have a really funny
or deep or whatever the fuck it is.
It's just a good conversation
when you run out of those albums.
And I already over that.
No, I know how you'd do it.
Do you do the 500 albums?
That should have been in the top 500.
That'll be 9.61 years.
And uh,
that's not a bad idea, but
I might just be, you know,
I think I'm going when I
retire it on May 31st, 2028.
Oh, that's what I was going to have it.
My goal is on the final episode to have,
uh, Oprah. I don't know why, but
it's just shits my white whale.
What's the number one sergeant
pepper's lonely hearts club band.
Then it's, then it goes a
number one album, number one,
and then number two is pet sounds.
And then number three,
I think his revolver,
uh, this is white rock.
The number one white rock in the top 10
know Marvin Gaye's in the top 10 Marvin
Gaye is number six. Marvin
Gaye, what's going on? But
it's, it's all over the place.
The album 500 was outcast,
Sequenom and I,
and then for lunch I'll be saying is
because the Beatles who really went rogue
and started their own Beatles where
essentially a boy band and then they,
that they took control of their,
Chris was a lot of people because the
Beatles now get a ton of shit by people
being like, you know, I like they,
there's like people who think they stink.
Like I've, I've listened to
two things to beetle stink.
Dumb people will their dumb. Yeah.
I'm not saying you can't be into them,
they don't move you or whatever. And
it's been a long time, but that, that's,
that's like Saint Count Basey steaks or
something like this. No, it's just a, hey,
no. Yeah, he don't leverage. That's
the thing is that somebody like my age,
I'm 39 like I, I, you know,
was born in 79 so I wasn't really
alive during the Beatles era.
And from what I've been told
and everything I've read,
like there will never be an artist
as big as the Beatles were like,
they were enormous. Like, well, this was,
they broke out of what usually binds you
and they took control of their career
and started their own label. And then
when they should have fizzled out,
they made this left turn
with a reinvented themselves,
you know,
when they started doing drugs and grew
their hair and all that shit and rubber
soul and then, yeah, in revolver
and all that stuff.
And then when that kind of went to,
they will now what the fuck do
we do? It's like, all right,
let's just play characters
now will be these, these guys.
How would these guys do that? So
during that time, Marvin Gaye,
I think he was stuck in the
Motown shit and he's got to sing,
but they're writing for him.
And by the 70s you know,
he was doing what they did as far
as he kind of broke ways like, well,
I want to sing about what I'm thinking
about rather than doing my version of,
she loves you. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Well he's doing like heard it through
the grape vine and all that stuff,
which I still love all those songs.
I mean,
but then he wanted to go like deeper
so maybe they think that that that's
because when sergeant
pepper I was actually,
what's going on is a better record
than that. Sergeant pepper. Yeah.
I mean it's Ellison.
All of these,
all of this whole list is completely,
you know. Yeah. All over them.
It's designed to do this. You got
like, because of the way they made it,
because I'm already had this
discussion with people. It's like
what is it? It's 20 years ago
today. It's such a bad job.
The bad and the play that are
going in and out of style. God,
mosquito larva down the down
to
ski but diva ski but do boot do.
Yup.
Something like that.
One of the best moments we've had on
the jam is when Jim Jefferies sang that
first time he did it,
he did sergeant pepper and then into
with a little help from my friends and he
was wearing a jacket that he bought at
John Barbados that the only reason he
bought it,
it's the gaudiest like most expensive,
weirdest Jackie you
ever seen in your life.
And it costs like $10,000 and he only
bought it because he was at this John
Varvatos like event and he
put it on to laugh about it.
And then Ringo Starr walked by and when
you look good in that, so he was like,
well, I gotta buy it now. I mean,
if a beetle tells you you look good
in something and it's like you got to
fucking get the fuck, I'm going to go,
star was there. Yeah. Yeah. I did bring,
it was always at like Barbados events.
He wears all that.
Like interview with the vampire
clothing was an event. It wasn't a,
it wasn't a store. Not
a did. No, no, it was,
I was an event. I spaced halfway through
them. Okay. How would, it's great.
It's great. So what I'm
saying is, is that, you know,
Sargent pepper was this huge thing for
the Beatles because what was the coat?
What did it have on it? Oh my God, I'll
send you a picture. Tell the story.
It was like an alligator gold style,
like,
like Rock Jack, I don't even know what
you'd call it. Just like a piece of that.
If he buys it. Was it a Beatles coat? No,
it was just a job. [inaudible] he was,
he was seriously saying he look good.
And that fucking code
was just saying to John.
He was saying to Jim that you look good
in it. And so he told him, you know,
he's like, you look good. So
Jim bought it. That's the story.
It was boring the second time. It was
interesting to find out, spaced out,
but everybody's laughing
at, you know, I'm not
fucking listening from,
we're not paying attention or whatever.
He didn't think that when
I sang a Johnny paycheck,
take this job
and shove it down,
I believe.
But dobber Debo,
what Josh has been trying to get me
to do, you're going to do it. Um,
he wants mother fucker.
You are Gunna do this to get brown curly
wig go out on stage is Don Henley and
then he wants me to play drums
and Sing Hotel California.
I'm a dad. Does it? Hauwei yeah,
I'm going to help you. I'm going to help
you in the crowd's going to help you.
So everybody knows because
bill's talked about it.
I do a show called the goddamn comedy
jam where Comedians do stand up,
they tell a story about a song and
then they sing it. Bill has done it.
You've done it more than fucking
like anybody. You're the,
nobody counts it cause it
was pre the NFL NFL merger.
They don't call back. Right. But, but uh,
we had my birthday coming up and,
and I asked you,
I was like, could you please do
that? And I was going to do it.
I said,
I'm about to do it.
And then you called me and you give
me one of your [inaudible]. This is,
I've gotten this call a few times
where it's like, Josh, dude,
I got too much shit going on.
I can't learn this fucking song.
Don't make me learn this,
play the song.
But the fact that they have to sing
along with it and I can't sing, but you,
you understand that's a song that's so
popular. The second you start playing it,
the whole audience is going to fucking
join in with you and then you can just
kind of mimic it.
And then I'll be singing
in the bass player will be
singing like all the fucking
lyrics in front of me. Like
it's just going to be a shit
show. I think I could do.
I think you know, I can make that
happen. We'd him, there's one in March.
I got one coming up
March 20th do we haven't done one in
awhile? Yeah, Dude. Like am I scheduled?
Doesn't open up again until fucking April.
Like I'm just straight. I'm straight.
I know what the fuck happened, dude.
I got in this business to not working.
Now we're doing, we're doing F is for
family, man. I gotta be cannot wait dude.
Right. And Shit, we're already up
to episode three. We're cruising.
That's great. Yeah, we're cruising. But I
mean, yeah, it takes a lot, a lot of time.
Uh, all right, let's get into some
point. I Will Sing Hotel California.
Oh,
where did my hair okay.
Does,
I just wanted you to do that
one part where it's like,
but what is the killer bees do?
Do, do, do, do. Yeah. On
the Tim Bali. All right.
Body shaming.
We got people write in and then they,
for some reason they want advice. I
know this goes down. Okay. Alright.
Body shaming. You'll Billy Brown shirt.
I don't know what Brown shipping.
So it wasn't that the people who
are sympathetic to fucking Hitler,
I have no idea what brown shirts went.
Brown shirts a wait a minute,
I gotta look that. How you got to Google
something political. Maybe they hear,
saw you in a picture that you posted
in a brown shirt and they are,
they're just rhyming in it.
Brown shirt did.
They said so many weird
things like Billy elbows or
Billy dangle down. Yeah.
So they just made it up.
No Brown shirts.
Political,
uh,
Nazi party original parliamentary did
played a significant role in Adolf
Hitler's rise to power. Ah, I guess
all he needed was brown shirts. St Cs.
What? The Internet stupid. Cause I just,
I just fucking grazed over all the
grays. Breezed. Graced. All right.
You're Billy Brown shirt.
I vomited a little my mouth halfway
through your tirade against fat cons when
you suggest,
I don't remember doing this.
Those who don't conform to your body
dysmorphic ideal should get therapy and
sorted out their lives.
Did I say that guys?
You have to understand something like I
have to do an hour usually by myself and
whatever topic comes up,
I have to destroy it because I'm
trying to make you laugh anyways.
I haven't heard anything less healthy
come out of your mouth for some time.
All right. You know something
to dude. First of all the,
I vomited a little bit in my life.
You're the fact that I'm
supposed to literally take
what you're saying seriously
and you're speaking in soundbites.
Let me get Stan,
did you shake your head before you rolled
on the floor? Laughing your ass off.
Anyways, if my partner thought
my weight was a deal breaker,
I'd thank her for the honest
glimpse into her vacant prisons,
soul and abandoned her in a
heartbeat. No, you wouldn't.
You overly sensitive jackass,
uh,
in a heartbeat to the Greyhound Hound
inspired Instagram influencers and
consumer program. Neil,
needless, you seem to champion,
diversity is not a mental illness,
but body shaming is ah,
God, wow. I gotta, I
gotta I gotta like that's,
that's worded so much in that speak that
I don't even believe that that's true.
No, they're just throwing
buzzwords together, Brown shirt,
all of that type of stuff.
I love,
now I see why they call it you Billy
Brown shirt. Like I'm a nine mad at you.
Yeah, they're mad at, you know,
cause what it was was there was
a guy who was with some chick,
she had a little meat on the
bones, whatever, and he was,
went into it thinking I should
probably fucking lose eventually.
I don't know why he thought that
people tend to just get fatter.
Yeah. People, people do
tend to age. That'd be like,
this guy has a little gray hair.
Maybe it's going to turn Brown. No,
it's going to flag it to get more
gray. Yes. So anyway, my age,
and if so what happens is,
but she was putting it on at what he
considered to be an alarming rate.
So he wanted to stay with her,
but he needed to know how to approach
to ask her in a polite way to stay in
shape.
Here's what all these not least gateway,
here's what all these proud fat people
are doing. They're killing themselves.
So if somebody does an intervention,
and then thing about fatties is they'll
fucking sit there and I'll talk about
how addiction, food addiction and all
that is no different than drug addiction.
I completely agree. Why you
ain't? You really agree with it.
You have an intervention
with people to be like,
you're killing yourself with this heroin.
So I don't know.
For some reason with big MACs,
you can't fucking be like, hey,
why don't you lay off your
fucking chicken tenders there?
So I have a friend that, that
just had a kid, uh, my buddy and,
uh, he, he was, he lost a little bit
of weight because he had prediabetes,
but he's putting it back on again. And
like, we had a thing tonight. And, uh,
and I was like, I was like, hey man,
like you, you know, you look at,
you're putting on more weight.
And he goes, yeah, you know,
it's just the stress and blah, blah,
blah. I'm like, I know, but you know,
we're celebrating your kid's
birthday. It's just, you
should just, you know, and he,
and he wants to it,
it's like that by saying that,
it's just that reality check just
to let him know I'm not shaming him.
And I don't think he's shaming his
girlfriend either, that the, you know,
that dude the Rohde. And so it's
just kind of like, hey, you know,
it's like you said, it's health, you know,
it's, you gotta you gotta Stop, you know?
Yeah. Fucking, just, you gotta
be exercise. If you want to live,
you got to exercise and take care
of yourself. What you eat is fuel.
It doesn't need to be doing,
hi, I'm not gonna say his name, but a
guy I knew a couple of years ago. Yeah.
The last time I saw him, I saw him sit
down and go, this guy does not look good.
And he was not eating healthy food
and he fucking dead a month later.
Fuck yeah, dude. And it's just like, but
you're not supposed to say something.
Someone who was addicted to heroin
but out and I got a temper and shit.
My wife can skin stepping on that. But
there's something about like, you know,
being fat. These people are just
like, no man, I'm a fucking eight.
You've just been convinced by sis.
Like they take it, like you're saying,
they're not beautiful
people. It's like, you know,
if I just saw you were just some
fat shit, you know, I don't know.
It wasn't my fucking idea
either, man. So yeah. Yeah.
You can go fuck yourself with all your
stupid like that, that, that, all,
all of that. So you want
about Brown shirt. The way
this whole thing is written,
this is the kind of person that
tries to make you lose your job.
1000000%. Yeah, they're
very active on Yelp.
Yeah. All right, and then
fell titles. Hey, pasty pig,
spin pigskin professor,
you've asked about super bowl
titles versus NFL champions
of what great or maybe
this person has the solution. The issue
here is not the answer, it's the question.
If someone asks which team
have never won a super bowl,
it has a different answer than if someone
asks which team has never won an NFL
championship.
Even a complicated more,
you could ask who's never
won a league championship,
which also includes AFL champion
chips and other leagues. All right,
I understand all of this.
For official NFL champions from 1920
to 1932 there was no championship game.
The championship champion was decided
by the best record only. Okay. Now,
none of this is answering my question.
That's like back in the day when baseball,
all those worlds series
that the county you winning,
the pennant was back in the year.
Back in the day,
you had the brand of the regular season.
If you had the best record in the
American league, you won the pennant,
there was no play off. Yeah. And
then you went to the championship,
you went to the world series.
So all those years the Yankees
won all those fucking titles.
They had one playoff series to win.
It wasn't this divisional,
it wasn't three rounds of playoffs, which
people have to do now where they doing?
Uh,
but were they doing,
when they got to their word series was
how many Games was it? Was it I was fine.
That was still seven games.
The early 19 hundreds where it
was best of best five out of nine.
That's five out of nine. Yeah. Fuck Dude.
That would go until like December. If they
did that now, like I think the Red Sox,
1903 we won that world series
five games to three man,
it's gay may come into
your house for game aid.
Anyways,
from 1933 to 1969,
there was a championship game and the
winner of that was the NFL champion from
1966 on that champion went on to play
in the Superbowl and then when it was
called the world champion,
that's not true. 66,
67 68 the end of those seasons
or whatever those are 66,
660760860 nine whatever it was.
Those first three against the AFL was
called the AFL NFL title was not called
the soup bowl.
Later on retroactively,
it was named the super bowl from
1960 to 69 AFL had champions.
That's true.
But they aren't counted as NFL history,
but they are counted as the
team's history. If you are
asking how many? Yes. Okay.
Uh, from 19 six, six 69, the NFL
AFL champions played the Superbowl.
I skies is telling me Shit,
they didn't play the super bowl.
It was renamed that does he know?
It should be called facts.
Just facts. Facts. Facts. Facts. Facts.
Okay. So in 1966 the AFL champions, the
Kansas City's chiefs, the NFL champions,
the Green Bay packers, this is the plus
one league championship for each team.
Chiefs lost when they played
in, in the first NFL. If so,
they didn't get a Superbowl win,
but they still the AFL champion.
I understand all of this.
None of that cleared anything up.
I'm saying why don't they count those?
Yeah.
It's like you go to the stadium,
like the AFL merge to be part of the NFL.
So you're saying that at
any most NFL stadiums,
there are no trophies to
represent the league championship.
If you look at the flow, I'm sure
in the, somewhere in the stadium,
maybe they'll have, they'll have
that, but it's just like, you know,
when you go to, uh, you know,
you go to fucking Red Sox,
Fenway park, I mean, we have our
banners right down the thing.
1903 to fucking 2018.
Yeah.
Everybody has all of their,
they're all, all of them count. No,
that that sir. I appreciate it
was to read all that history,
but that didn't answer my question.
Why aren't they counted?
Yeah.
I mean when it comes to the Superbowl man,
it's just if it's not in those words,
super embol aren't before them. They,
they just, they act like it didn't happen.
Act like it didn't happen.
Yeah. Well I mean it's,
it's just you could still say
dean championships, but I,
I completely see where you're saying
right now. It actually takes what we say,
we're kind of fucked up. Eagles,
they've never won a Superbowl.
They last thing they wanted was
an NFL title. It's like, yeah,
but that was the peak of fucking 1960
they were the best fucking football team
out there and you talking about it
like it would like they, they, they,
they lost the election.
Okay.
Yeah, I dunno. Anyways, living
in Wyoming. Hey Billy, silly.
It's silly city slicker.
I was listening to some older podcasts
episodes and came across a rant you had
about Wyoming. I like Wyoming. I
didn't remember what I said. Like these
tidbits I live in Wyoming. I got
to say, you are not too far off.
I listened to the podcast every
week while I feel my cows off,
feed my cows off the back of a flatbed
truck. Shut off. Find out of this guys.
Fuck with me.
Last week we killed the problem mountain
lion and it next weekend we'll be
entering into a competitive coyote hunt.
I live in the absolute middle of fucking
nowhere. This sounds amazing. This guy,
this guy listens to Steve Earle. Yeah,
but this guy is way more interesting.
Get a party than I am. I do
standup comedy. Oh yeah. What
did you do? Ah, you know, I,
I saved five of our sheep or you
know, from a mountain lion by, uh,
I came in, turn it off. I came in
third in the coyote hunting nationals.
I want to talk to that guy.
The nearest town population is 3000
miles and it's 40 miles away. Also,
just to clear the air,
most of the billionaire cons live up
in Jackson and the rest of why ohm.
Oh, that's what I was saying. I still
want to be the Douche in Hollywood.
That gets a place in Wyoming and the
rest of Wyoming pretty much discounts.
Jackson is being
part of the state anyway,
so I'll pretty much discount so to speak.
Part of state, partially unrelated.
I finished getting my pilot's license
last year and hope to start on my
helicopter rating within
the next year. Good. Phew.
My family has used a bell jet
ranger to hunt coyotes. Jesus.
How much more of an advantage do
you need for three generations now?
And I'm ready to start
for flying the heli.
Do you have like one of those fucking
Vietnam? Yeah, job do, do, do, do, do,
do today. How do you shoot a doe? Easy.
You just don't lead him as much. Uh,
am I ready to start flying
the heli to carry on the,
Oh and I'm ready to start flying and
they had to carry on the tradition.
So cheers to a fellow pilot.
That's cool as shit. Uh,
just wanted to let you know there's at
least one can listen to your podcasts and
Wyoming and love all the shit you put
out. Thanks. And Go fuck yourself.
That's cool man. I'm trying to get
eight hours a month, uh, flying.
And have you been flying a lot recently?
I got 7.9 for this month and
I'm flying tomorrow morning.
What are you going to take me up dude,
when I have three over 300 hours? Uh,
I'm going to do a little bit of instrument
training and just get better at it
and, and like do some full, I would,
I would do full downs and the
whole fucking thing before
I would ever take up my
first passenger. And I love you too
much to have you be my first passenger,
but there's a few people in my life that
I like, so I'll be taking them up first.
Okay. I believe that. And then, and
you know what I mean, it's just like,
do I want to kill this guy or this guy?
Wait,
dude wasn't like Sophie's choice with
a helicopter. How are we going to go?
We're going to go to see iron maiden in
Las Vegas and then that should be like
the time that we do that.
Does that,
sorry. Ps. If you want to try a new cigar,
checkout deadwood tobacco company
out of Deadwood, South Dakota.
The sweet Jane is is my favorite
cigar I have ever smoked. See you.
You see a, you're bald. Fuck.
Well I mean some guy out there in
the fucking range shooting coyotes.
I bet you know what a dead word. Yeah,
that sounds fucking pretty cool to me.
All right, we got to wrap this
thing up to, we get some gas.
Oscar's our three minutes. Perfect.
Alright, drone. Yo Billy up there. Uh,
you were talking about a drone last
week that would taxi people around.
Sounded like the one you mentioned
was unmanned. Check this thing out.
57 batteries. You have to, that is, I
was joking about that fucking thing dude.
They,
they're going to do this thing rather
than deal with the population problem.
The next thing they do is have
like, like, like a, it looks like a,
it looks like a helicopter
and you just get in it.
There's nobody in there and it'll just
take you across to La. Now. First of all,
I would think it would be super expensive
unless it's electric. Unless, yeah. Uh,
Elon Musk can make the thing, but dude,
you know, you fucking laptop crashes,
you phone craps out on you.
Oh y'all can like dude,
you're going to fly somebody like over a,
like the level of insurance.
Like how are you going to do that?
I was joking that you're going
to have some hipster come flying.
It was on his way to a pocket watch
convention out in fucking Venice beach or
something. And all we've found
was his handlebar mustache. Yeah,
he was on his way to this to meet
this food truck. Uh Yeah. Whatever.
I think it's there.
There is a,
so what I just want to get this
clear can show you something super.
Please show it to me. Boy. I remember
just trying to, cause I'm not,
I'm kind of confused.
You're saying there is going to be a
transportation that like he's a drone so
it's like you get into a tube and then
it just lifts the tube up and flies you
and it looks like a helicopter.
It looks fucking cool as shit.
I think it looks fucking cool. Show. And
is that what you're showing me now? No.
I want to show you this,
this app here for flight.
Um, and this is what I'm getting
better right here. So this, this here,
once I get good at,
you know,
confident enough in my abilities and
I take up a passenger so it just,
you don't have to know.
It's not like back in the fucking day,
we'd had to have like a
fucking sectional map on your
fucking thigh as you flying around.
This thing gives you all the, uh,
the airports,
all the M and e know Santa Barbara.
Where are we? Where are we? The, there's
Van Nuys, there is Burbank right there.
So it's pink. So that's a Charlie.
Uh, and then you go, well,
it's so great is you could just fucking
type in whatever you want to type in.
It gives you, the aid is, it
gives you the uh, contact tower.
It has a map,
runway aid.
This is probably what most time would
you land out there and why they slam on
the brakes because this is so fucking
short that it's a small ass landing strip.
Yeah. Uh, well I don't know how you
could tell it from the APP. I think,
cause I just told you it was um,
uh, being a cunt right now, uh,
there's Elma Burbank, there's El
Monte. That's one of my favorite ones,
but it has all,
but it has,
see what you see with this is so
boring for people here. BC right there.
That's a delta. So grounded 2,400. So
right here when you flying it on the,
the two 15, you know, I'm
going to be in the airspace.
I got to call them and they'll just
give you clearance all the way through.
And then once you learn how to read this
fucking thank you can kind of just fly
around out here.
Now the rest of the country,
they actually have to do
deal with weather. See,
I don't have to do it because people
like you just fly across the country.
It's like, ah, this is a dry climate
that I don't have to ever deal with. Hey,
everything's boo all and it all of
a sudden, yet I can't see anything.
There's a brutal fucking call of a guy
who like me is not instrument rated,
which means that the clouds
came in underneath me.
I don't know how to get back down other
than to just shut my eyes and go through
the closet. Hope I, yeah. Yeah.
So he's up there in the soup is
or whatever the fuck they call it.
And Dude this guy is free. I've
got a die. And then they fought,
the guy talked to him down and
then afterwards he fucking,
he lived. Yeah, but he called the
tower. He goes, oh yeah, thanks about,
and the guy says total ice go. Yeah.
He goes, what happened up there? Yeah,
you fucking pussy is basically saying
what happened up there is he got involved
in some shit that, that you know,
he wasn't in for. So that's,
that's the one weird thing about flying
is you learn by other people die are
doing the dumb shit cause he died.
So he showed me will be one,
one time this guy was doing a tour in the
44 Robinson 44 and he had three people
there when he took off. Right. Fucking
just did this really just, I dunno what,
he just didn't go like he just ignored
everything he's supposed to do.
He was loaded up with people he
had, I imagine, you know, a low,
heavy with fuel.
So what you want to do is you should
forward momentum to get going.
And he just pulled all this fucking power
and his low rpm horn comes on and now
the weird thing was the
chicken, the passenger sheet
was gone like right at this,
like the same fucking notes. So he didn't
hear it at first and all he had to do,
he was bank come out of the bank,
lower your collective and it'll go
off and then just gradually climb up.
And he did it for a second and then he
pulled it out again and it came on again.
And then he just started descending.
And your instinct is want to pull
because you want to go up. Yeah,
actually went up.
You actually want to bring you collected
down and he kept pulling power and he's
fuckers weren't in the ground. They
all fucking died. Oh fuck man. Yeah.
So I'll take you up. All right.
Girlfriend is pregnant. Hey, Billy sat.
It's um,
I'm uh,
I'm 28 years old and my 26 year old
girlfriend just found out she's pregnant.
Now you're saying this dude,
like you didn't blow the load dinner.
She found out she's pregnant. Like she
got fucking shingles of stuff. But uh,
this came as a big shot
because I previously had a
vasectomy when I was 22. Ah,
there's the answer.
Jesus Christ at 22. You,
they had nine kids by then
and he never wanted any,
he had him a sec 22 set and never wa
had never wanted kids after she told me,
I went to a urologist who told me I had
regained a sperm count, although rare,
it was not unheard of. When I met
this girl, she changed my life.
I had never trusted or loved
any woman the way I do her.
She's the light of my life. Who weren't
planning on this. We both have okay jobs,
but living in California is expensive
and adding a third mouth to feed and
paying for doctors visits
will crush us financially.
She doesn't have health insurance.
Do you have any advice for me?
My fear is losing the chance to have
kids with her as this may be a miracle
considering my vasectomy and considered
you waited a long time to have kids.
I want to know if you think this would
be a good for someone in my position to
go through this.
Thanks for taking the time to read this
poorly and probably not under understand
my situation. You old gray cont
uh, the old grey con t eight word.
He used to be love your
shows and I hope you here.
I hope to hear more
your ramblings from you.
Best to you the baby and go fuck
yourself and your gay ass patriots.
All right. Um, can I get any take this
cause I think he should do it. Yeah,
I think you do. Don't, don't wait on life
for your financial situation, man. If, if,
if you guys will make it work.
That's what you will make it work.
You'll figure it out.
You might not think that you'll
have enough money right now,
but something like life is constantly
changing and evolving and it's just like,
yeah, lay off the micro Bruce and have
the kid. Yeah, exactly. Like, yeah,
you'll make it work. Just I
think you should, you should.
You should consider it a miracle. Just
like you said, I think it's a great thing.
I'm actually really happy
for you and I think a, put it
this way, I wish, you know,
I wish I didn't wait as long as I did.
And the other day I was watching this,
I was watching this,
uh, this kid song. Um,
it's just as simple as like snow flakes,
Snow Flake,
well snow flake, snow
flakes, Snow Flake, Dadada.
And my daughter was trying to sing it and
she was throwing her head back because
doing the, I think wasn't
quite in Pitt, dude, I,
I had to fight off getting emotional,
just watching her do that,
get the most beautiful thing in the world.
And there's that thing. Up until then,
anything fucking I've done.
Madison Square Garden was not as good
as that 90 and not even remotely is he
like little man and his stroke.
I was like, wow, that's amazing.
But that moment with my daughter, I was
like, this is what life is all about.
100% this is what it's all about.
And then another great
thing is you become a dad.
And one of the greatest fucking things
ever and some sage advice I learned from
a good dad is he said, how awesome is
cause he goes, it's not about you anymore.
And at first I kind of took that as
like, you know, cause I'm a very like,
like don't tell me what the fuck to do
idiot sometimes. And then I, I realized,
uh, uh, how great that is.
Like the other day I finally had a day
off and my wife wanted to go on and go
get some breakfast. She goes,
you want to do that? I was
like, no, filing homeowners,
stay home. So then I was just like, I
fuck it. That's what she wants to do.
And we just went out and he
said, yeah, it's not about you.
They want to go out to breakfast,
take them out to fucking breakfast.
And I went out to breakfast and I had a
great fucking time and I had great time.
And it's weird when you're home,
you're a dad or whatever, blah blah.
But when you go out,
you kind of feel more like a dad.
Yeah.
Well No.
It's like you can take them out to dinner
and what out of the car you're walking,
she's holding your hand or
you're carrying her, you go in,
you get her in the little booster
seat, he'd get her whatever. And like,
it's usually like a Mac and cheese or
like a cut up hot dog or some shit.
And I assume that she's at
that age and you did, you just,
people are looking at the kid and look
how beautiful the kid is and you're like,
oh, I know. It's just like, dude,
you're in your element, man. Yeah,
no, it's awesome. I mean,
what's cool? She's really,
really beginning to talk now.
Yeah. So, uh, yeah,
it's getting the point where I can
actually convey to her and she will
understand how much I love her.
Which is going to be great
cause that's like doable. Yeah.
Cause I always say you
made how much I love you.
Do you understand that it should just
be looking at you smiling, whatever,
but I'll be, I'll actually be able to
say it. She'll be able to understand it.
Yeah. I can't wait. Can't wait
to fucking play catch with her.
I would teach her how to drive my
truck. Three in the tree. What?
What kid born in 2018 is going to know
how to work shitty 76 sorry. No, no,
I didn't forget about drivers stick five
three on the column. I took it today.
I took it over to a a Jiffy Lube,
which I know a lot of fucking car
people are going to give me shit for it.
That you went to Jiffy Lube.
Well, I would change it,
but the way they designed the,
the guy who have a fucking designed
the engine did not talk to the guy who
fucking design the frame on
that truck because the frame,
there's like literally a piece that
goes to one side or the other right
underneath the fucking plug for the
drain planet pants. So the only,
it's just a giant fucking mess.
Like when they do what they have to have
this giant thing underneath it and it
comes down and it splashes all over that,
that piece that goes across and then
they have like this spray thing and then
the air thing that they shoot all off.
It's like I'm going to do that in my
garage and have a fucking oil spill.
I can't do it. I hate it. I used
to love doing it when I was a kid.
I used to though, it's like my favorite
thing because I knew how to do it.
I would change the fuel filter.
I knew her to do a loop job
and he'll do the whole fucking,
all of that maintenance stuff.
But I never had the balls to start taking
apart the fucking engine or whatever.
But, uh, anyway, that's the podcast.
We've got a cigar to smoke. Uh, Hey,
your pick for the Superbowl patriot.
Yeah.
Um, I think it's going to be the
patriots. I really do think so. I, I do,
I can to be honest with you.
Like I kind of,
I love watching greatness and I didn't
know what people like to hate on the
Patriots. And I know I teased you
sometimes, but it's just like, dude, he's,
he's so good. The team is so good, man.
And it's like to be able to say that
I watched Michael Jordan wins six.
Like I know I was alive during that and
nobody else has matched that greatness
except for Tom Brady.
Well,
I think it's going to,
I'm going to die a thousand deaths as
always. And I really think that, uh,
I mean we're going up against what's
looking like the next bell a check. Uh,
[inaudible] he's like fucking 33 34 years
old. I mean, it's fucking ridiculous.
He was just skin dude.
He was our offensive coordinator
and we gave him up like he,
we have fucking one of the
Goddamn Gruden's you ain't
doing shit. I know Bella.
Check coached the browns at one point and
it happens too. It happens. All right.
Uh, that's the podcast.
I'm hoping my patriots win.
I have no idea what's going to happen.
The fucking rams look great
and I think their quarterback,
like they just don't make
quarterbacks the way they used to.
Like they don't come
into the league scared.
They just fucking come in like I whatever.
I Dunno what it is.
Maybe because they video games and shit.
They've already seen saying,
I remember that games to beat them
all the time and eighth grade,
now I'm playing him
now he's fucking older.
I'm not scared of any of these
people. All right, I'm rambling.
Can I give my final pitch on the
podcast? Yes guys. Everybody.
My podcast called the 500
with Josh Adam Meyers.
Join the record book club or going through
the 500 greatest albums of all time.
Bill's done at Jim Jefferies. We've got
to just table Wanda Sykes doing earth,
wind and fire. It's, it's cool. It's my
fucking favorite thing I've ever done.
Experience the greatest music of all
time and then here a me and a in a comic
talk shit about it. Not Shit.
We just could go through it.
I'll show how to find a great
toes. Listen, do it. Check
it out. Josh. Adam Meyers,
the 500 all right,
I'll see you on Thursday.