Hm.
Hey,
what's going on as bill burn?
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
March 27th, 2000. And uh,
was it 17,
2070 fucking decades flying by,
you know what? I'm the 2011, 1213.
Can somebody tell me that 14 was cool?
Vaguely remember 15 and
then 16. I, you know,
I want to thank everyone who
whined so much about it last year,
the worst year ever. I mean, that
one's pretty vivid. Lots of crying,
lots of crying.
And I don't mean for the right reasons
like David Bowie and prince passing,
but you know, you know Hillary losing in
that type of shit. A Lot, lot of crying,
a lot of whining. Um, anyways, I,
uh, I don't even know what the
fuck to tell you. I've been a,
there'd been fucking daddy daycare here.
You know what I did for the first time
we finally went out, right? Me and me,
we're going fucking crazy because you
have a baby. You have a little baby. Yeah,
but little lady, this is the
thing, if it's your first kid,
you fucking scared to death. You're
like, I can't take this thing outside.
It's going to get a bowler.
You can all fucking nervous,
you know,
and that has got to get his fucking immune
is there's Asians at all of that type
of shit. And he just let go and you
go, who do I fucking believe here?
Jesus Christ. I'll tell you those
fucking shots. This is what I actually,
I just sat down.
I was like,
nobody who's ever been in the
medical field told me not to do it.
I've had comedians,
high school friends,
a fucking actresses are a bunch
of non doctors have advised to go,
what am I not going to get her
fucking vaccinated for polio? No,
it's not that what it is it fish. Shut
the fuck. Do you even own a lab coat?
All you're doing is scaring
the shit out of me. So anyways,
um, so we were, you know, you
fucking afraid. So finally
we're just like, all right,
fuck this. We got a Stroller, you know.
So we started taking
walks around the block,
but my block has like the shittiest
sidewalk. It's like, uh, you know,
the grounds all shifted out here.
There's tree roots pushing it up.
You have no idea when you just
walk down the street, you know,
you start pushing the stroller and you're
trying to keep the kid quiet. You know,
cause she finally fell asleep. It's
like a push on my daughter up to street.
It's like fucking like liquid nitrogen.
I'm just trying to keep her,
I don't want to say I'm gonna start
crying in the middle of the street,
just going down the street,
waking everybody up and I
guess you're already awake.
I don't know. So, um, we finally
ended up going to the mall.
I had that experience.
I went to the mall with
my wife and my kid.
We pulled in, had to take out his
stroller, take her out of the car seat,
put her in and start walking around
the mall. And I got to tell you,
it was fucking awesome. I, for the
first time in my life, I get the mall,
I get it. You know, it's fucked.
Teenage kids when they're trying to
get away from their parents, like, mom,
just leave me alone.
What everyone friends,
that era before you have a license
really and you can't really go anywhere.
You just need some sense
of fucking freedom.
And it's for after you become a parent,
you have to get out of the fucking
house and do some sort of controlled
environment where there's enough God
damn people that you don't have to worry
about anybody snatching your
God Damn Kid, you know? Um,
so we walked around and uh,
just had a great fucking time.
It was like the perfect day and uh,
you know,
neo was all excited to be out because uh,
women just have Jesus the shit they
go through being being the guy.
It's the best. I swear to
God, it's why they fucking,
I think it's why they make our lives so
god damn miserable is they see how easy
it is.
And the thing is is we don't realize how
easy it is because we've only been us,
you know what I mean?
How long it takes them to get ready.
Do you know how long it takes me to get
ready now I've got to fucking shaved
head. I mean, I don't
even have to do anything.
You can literally hose me off in the
backyard and I, I could, you know,
I'd be ready in like seven
minutes, easy, seven minutes.
Cause I always got to run around and
find my cell phone for like five of those
minutes. But you know, if I, if I actually
was organized and newer, all my shit was,
I could be, I could be writing
like three minutes. Um,
anyways. Yeah, they got through all
of that shit. You know what I mean?
You got to breastfeed, they gotta, they
gotta they gotta pump all of that crap.
I don't have to do any of that.
You know what I mean?
So she was going fucking
nuts dealing with, um,
everything that nature put on her.
And she finally had to get out of the
house and now it's the happiest I've seen
her. We walked around and
had a great time. You know
what they have at malls now?
This is second mall I've been
to that they have like a Tesla.
Yeah.
Um, store like you can go and like who
the fuck just goes to the mall and buys a
car?
Okay.
You know what I mean? You got eat, buy
sunglasses, right. A fucking Hula Hoop,
whatever, whatever it is. You buy it. Buy
a car. So I, you know, I can't resist.
I got to go in there, right. And I'm
like, what's the deal with this thing?
Zero to 62.5 the guys
like 2.3 that's amazing.
I was up in San Jose,
the guy told me 2.5 he shaved off in
another two hundredths of a second
and I'm like, all right. So I get
four adults in there and he goes,
you can get five and I go and I'm still
going to go zero to 60 in 2.3 seconds.
Does make any sense. All that,
wait, what am I up to there?
Okay,
well 2.93 and he goes probably to six.
It's like,
what are you basing that on other
than the fact that you want to make a
commission?
What am I basing mine on? I don't
fucking know. So he goes, all right,
let's take a look at to Sylvia. I go,
dude, I just bought a car. I love it.
I'm not going to buy a car.
I'm gonna tell you right now.
But I just wanted to see,
you know,
if I got the car that I want and what
this thing's going to cost me, right?
So I go, I go, give me the one with
the motor. The all wheel drive.
All right.
I went black.
I didn't want to get the black interior
cause it's hot as shit out here, right?
So the guy goes, do you want the fucking,
the full moon roof and everything? I go,
dude, look at me. I'm almost an albino
and I have a shaved head, Dee Dee fucking.
And it goes down all the tents.
Crazy on it. I said, all right,
put it on the fucking car. What do I
care? I'm not buying this thing right.
Give me the best you know, best tires.
Best Rems, best, best fucking everything.
Then they had this thing over you in for
five grand. When you get on the highway,
it kind of drives. It kind of
helps you. And I was like, dude,
why would I buy a car like this and have
something else dry? I want to drive it.
I don't need that shit.
Right.
So that I didn't get everything else I
got in in the end, I took a picture of it.
I forget how much it costs. Ah Fuck. I
don't need the exact number in the end.
You know where to cost $152,000
okay.
Oh fuck.
And what kills me.
Someone's going to go to the mall and
buy one of those hundred 52,000 fucking
dollars.
I just wish they looked cooler.
I love the fucking tires and
everything and there's, you know,
if you get the right tires and rims
and shit really helped that car and the
front end definitely looks
better. I Dunno man. You don't,
it looks like it looks like
that four door Porsche.
That's ugly as shit at Panamera whatever
that you know, you don't think of that.
We started to do that and like the uh,
the car commercials will,
they have a two door car.
They have the dad,
then he has a baby and then he grabs the
bumper and he turns it into a four door
car. Like, Oh wow, this is like a
sports car, but it's a four door sedan.
No it isn't.
It's a four door sedan and it won.
But that's trying to be a sports
car and then it becomes ugly.
That's why I liked the Mercedes to BMW
in the jet and the Jaguars because they
still look like cars, like
four door sedan. Then you
step on the gas. It's like,
Oh shit, look at this. Who Knew I
even aren't talking about here? Um,
anyway, so we ended up having a, a a
great time and uh, I walked by the, um,
the fucking, what store is that thing?
Whatever. Whoever the one that looks,
it looks like the letter h,
it's not Nike or Adidas,
it's the other one is the one
that fucking Steph curry has.
And in the window there these
ugly ass basketball shoes.
And I looked in and said curry threes
dude, gun to your head.
What do you like better?
That the Colby eleven's or the
curry threes? I don't know dude.
The curry threes,
you know with a fucking Chris
pair of jeans and a Hoodie
over which it chain on the outside
male fashion. Niesters do Jordan threes.
All right. Jordan trees. Okay.
With the pair of Joe's
jeans. All right. And,
and a button down in a new Yankee doodle
new Yankee had two and a slice of pizza
that does it get any better
playing play station on the TV
at inside Dallas Cowboys Stadium.
Crazy ultimate bachelor party dude.
A pair of fucking Jordan nines
right genes cuffed creased with,
with an Abercrombie and
Fitch v Neck t shirt.
Extra soft.
Okay.
Play play station with a slice of
pizza and a fucking cowboy stadium.
Does it get any better than that?
Dude?
I'm sorry.
I don't know what it is.
I like sneakers and I've
actually been buying something.
I just like the old ones.
Like I got a pair of shell toes and I
got a pair of early eighties fucking
Adidas like high tops.
Like I like that shit.
Like I don't know what the One fucking
Picasso started designing these Goddamn
things. It's like, it
makes no sense. Um, yeah,
I'm going to get in trouble for this shit.
I'm going to say later on in this podcast,
I,
I didn't know what the fuck to tell you.
I get some shout outs to do.
I never give shout outs. Right. And um,
I just had a bunch that would
just piling up and I'm like,
I finally got to give out some
fucking shout outs and then,
but I just never get around to them.
It's extra work. I never give a fuck.
But then finally somebody
tipped me over the fucking edge.
Right Laura? I was like,
all right, I got it.
I got to give this person to shout
out. All right. So first of all, let's,
let's get the, let's get the opener
and the feature out of the way.
A shout out to Eric at Bose for
hooking me up with some of those Bose
headphones. I was bitching about, um,
people being loud and, uh, you know,
on the plane. It shouldn't, by the way,
this is not so I can get more free shit.
I don't want any more shit. I'm getting
rid of Shit. If you give me free shit,
I'm going to give it away or I'm going
to send it down to fucking goodwill and
it's going to end up in a truck that
sits in a warehouse and they're going to
dump it and then, Oh shit. So I don't
want any shit, you know, a nice email.
Hey Bill, like you stuff, that's just
fine. Okay. But if somebody did send me,
you got to say thank you. Right. All
right, shout out to Eric at Bose and then,
uh, James Shotwell. Um,
I did this thing this weekend,
um,
rock against ms where I got to give
an award to a Richard Pryor's widow,
Jennifer prior. And, uh, you know,
Richard suffer from that disease.
And of course he turned it into
comedy and set out the disease,
actually slowed him down so
he could live longer. Um,
which is really fascinating
that, that's probably true. Um,
and anyways, James Shotwell was
down there doing it, I don't know,
work in like the sound. I've got to
see all these fucking killer bands,
these amalgams like fucking Alison chains
with Nancy Wilson from heart coming
out, crushing it. And then she
brought her new a band out,
row case royal and they fucking killed
it too. She's a, she's still a beast.
I got to see Steven Adler
play with an all star band.
He played um, the hell did he
play? He played a, the Ramones.
I want to be sedated and then I got to
stand in like a 10 feet away from him.
I got to watch him play.
Welcome to the jungle and rocket
Queen and see all these subtle,
all these little subtle things that he's,
first of all,
I get to see all the genius drum parts
that fits so perfectly to that song.
And then just the different ways that
he played them. Um, you know that part,
you know, so Dona Ana, Ana Blah
Blah Blah, blah blah. It's really,
I always study was on both times.
He's just riding on the floor, Tom.
And on the second scenario
here comes over with the Flam.
That's that little shit when you
read drum nerd like me, I'm like,
that's how we fucking plays it. And I
got to, of course he was cool as shit,
you know, he's such a fucking
great guy. Man. Had, you know,
a couple people were there that had ms
he let him fucking sit like right behind
him while he played.
When he finished playing,
he came out and he high fives to
everybody in the front row do.
We were at the La Theater in
downtown La and it was, um,
I guess it was a theater was
designed by Charlie Chaplin.
Okay.
And when you walk in in the foyer,
there's a picture of Charlie Chaplin
walking in the night at first opened with
Albert Einstein.
And uh,
of course I missed that photo.
Somebody told me it was there,
but downstairs they have this kid's room
that's still has the original paint.
So they say don't touch the walls.
And of course it's all these
creepy fucking drawings.
Like being a kid was so fucking scary
back then. All these creepy drawings,
a clowns and horses and shit. And
um, someone was trying to claim,
and I refuse to believe that this is true,
that they,
that's where you brought your babies when
they cry. And if they got really loud,
they had these little like cabinets.
She just opened the door and you
put the baby in, you close the door.
It's like even downstairs
they could still hear it.
I refuse to believe that that's
true. But, um, I ended up co,
I call hosted it with Craig Gas,
who that Guy Impressions of fucking
unbelievable man is Sam Kinison is Gene
Simmons, Sebastian Bach. And he's
hung out with all of these guys.
So he has all these unreal stories
and he does dead on impressions of Jim
Florentine was there. Um, it was
an amazing fucking night. So,
um, thank you to a Nancy sale for putting
that whole thing on and I'll do it any
year that they want.
And then lastly,
but leastly um, got it. We got a,
actually I got a request from
somebody who says that she's a fan,
a lady fan of the podcast in my standup,
but a,
what she requested I
guess is already over. Uh,
she's trying to be,
uh,
in next year to sports
illustrated swimsuit,
Lisa Marie Jafta.
But the voting's already closed so I
dunno, I dunno if it was real or not.
I immediately didn't believe that it was
a real email and then she sent a video
gov. No, seriously. I know
you're a bald, middle aged cons,
but I actually like just stuff,
if you could send your listeners
over to vote for me, you know,
maybe I could get in the issue next year.
And uh,
I dunno, that's such a weird world. You
know what I mean? You don't need that.
Fuck me up about that world was one
time Nia had me watch this fucking thing
about it and they had this creep
that was like the Goto guy and
he called himself uncle Terry.
Anybody who's not your uncle ladies,
anybody who's not your uncle,
he just call me uncle so and so. Yeah,
he's trying to fuck you. He's a fucking,
this guy was one of the creepiest bucket
people I've ever seen in my God damn
life. Um, so anyways,
my apologies. The voting is
already fucking over, but
I don't even know if this,
I don't even know if it was real to
be honest with you. But you know what,
I'm a middle aged bald man and I
that's wanting to believe that.
That's true. Is it?
That's really all I have.
Okay.
Um, it, speaking of
swimsuit models, oh, lab,
Billy fat tits area has been fucking
doing great on the elliptical. Uh,
back in it, man. Oh, back at it. I fucked
up last night and had a glass of booze.
Oh the booze one last
night I just had a glass,
which is probably considered a triple
in any fucking hipster bar. But, um,
I was going to go to bed. I
wasn't going to have it, you know,
I've been doing good. I stopped
eating at five and 1130. You know,
Leah had come home, I was hanging out
with my daughter, the whole nightmare.
And she was a riot. She was
a right. Jesus Christ dude.
She had two apocalyptic fucking
diapers yesterday. That was just like,
it's just like really, I don't think,
I don't think I, I don't think I,
we bought enough provisions
to ever get this fixed.
Yes.
So, um, she came home late and uh,
and I was just going to go to bed
and I kept playing met mental tenant.
Should they have a glass?
Don't know glass,
try and lose weight should I have a glass,
don't have.
And finally the boots was just
looking like, come on, you don't, not.
The votes was like, it was
like Jimmy the gent, you know,
after they fucking did the lift,
one's a heist.
However you say bottle was just
over there and go, come here,
come here Yo. You know,
and Henry comes walking in.
So I had one, so I dunno. Um,
it like one 80, 1.2, and
I've just been in the 80s.
I hate being in the 80. [inaudible]
that's when, that's when I just,
and when I shift my weight around on the
couch just to go reach for the remote,
you just feel the roles going
hall on the side of you. You know,
I don't know how people do it.
I don't know how you just walk
around being a fucking fat body.
I don't know why you tolerate that.
You got one fucking life and you, you,
you know God damn well
in the back of your head.
You don't know where you go after that.
Okay. Let's say best case scenario,
you get reincarnated. All right?
Cause the whole heaven hell thing.
It's the same thing every
day. After a while, it's,
it's not even going to have any value
winning. You light me on fire again. Okay.
What does it, another perfect day. Oh boy.
You're going to be like those
teenagers at the mall. Oh God,
I'm so bored. Right? Um, best case
scenario, you get reincarnated.
The fucking odds that you're going to
come back again as a human being. I mean,
you know, if you can come
back as a fucking mouse or
some shit, like, you know,
fucking run around on was having a
heart attack is some reptile is slowly
tracking you getting eaten alive.
You know, this is the best she got.
So you can fucking sit here and
become a tub of shit. You know, you,
you all went to yourself.
This is what I've been doing.
This has been the breakfast.
Have a freckled champion.
Um, every morning I wake up,
go do to do dude, and I go
out to the garage and, um,
what do I do? I go to, um,
I go in the fucking elliptical as my,
um,
my rotator cuff is slowly getting better.
Today I did some lady pushups.
I was going to do 20. I was like, don't
push it. Stopped at 12, stopped the 12.
Just trying to keep the fucking man
tits from sagging down into my navel.
Um,
I do like a half hour on the,
uh, on the elliptical and then
it coming in for breakfast.
I have one of those little oranges
and I have a, a, a poached egg
and that's it. And then I have bumped
banana between there and lunch.
And then for lunch I have some
sort of protein. Well, you know,
maybe with a little bit of bread,
some sort of pen.
I know breads the enemy go fuck yourself.
Um, it's the only bread I have. And then
I don't know what the fuck it is.
Then they have a protein with the salad
at four protein with the salad at six
and then I'm done. Then I
just drink waters for the
rest of the night in theory,
unless the fucking Jimmy, the gent
moment happens and I get fucked over. Um,
anyways, uh, so I have to do this shit.
I gotta get my ass back down. I can't,
my birthday's coming up in June,
I'm going to be 49 fucking years old,
which I'm actually pretty,
I'm all right with it.
Once you have a kid,
you kind of are right with being an
old, you know, like other than that,
you're like, man, I'm
47 and I was a kid. Um,
just going to die alone,
um,
going to be 49 and there's no fucking
way I'm going to be in the one eight s
it's just not going to happen.
I am, I'm telling you right now,
I am going to be one 72 my fighting
weight where the hell I want to be.
My shoulder's going to be healed and a,
I have a bet with Paul Versey.
Then when I'm 70 years old, I'm going
to be able to do 10 pull ups and uh,
if I don't get this rotator cuff fixed,
uh,
I'm going to be fucked because all
I keep thinking about is Jordan,
when he came back on the wizards,
you know,
and that was the first time you really
saw a off in his playing level because
not only was he gone for three years,
he didn't really play.
And when you stop, that's when you're
fucked. That's what I've learned,
trying to get it back. It's, it's,
it's hard. It's really fucking hard.
Although,
although d del Rey who crushed it and
San Jose del Rey in San Jose told me he's
doing sets of 20 fucking pullups.
I've never done 20 pull ups in my life
straight. I think the most they have,
I was able to do is I just
can't get past like 16.
He's 51 years old. Could do 20 pull
ups, sets a 20. So there's hope.
There's always hope.
Is this like an inspirational podcasts?
Go use the shit on stuff. All right. I
will. Um, but I, and I can't, I can't,
I'm having, if I'm having,
you know, I've gotten such,
it's so little material out of having
a daughter, I thought like, Oh fuck,
here we go. My whole act is
going to fucking change, man.
And it's been so awesome. You
know, what am I going to do?
Talk about how great it is and somehow
get you, what I do is I actually,
I pretty much in my act that just shit
on people that talk about how difficult
parenting is. You know what I mean?
I'm not saying, you know, it's not,
I'm not walking around sleepy a shit all
the time, but you know, come on, you know,
go watch that fucking movie.
I tell. Told you to watch.
Will they taught you that
kid that plays the violin?
That guy from peaky blinders is in it.
Anthropoid go watch that fucking thing.
Watch what those people went through and
tell me that being a parent is hard. Um,
anyways, sorry. Plowing
ahead. Oh, what happened?
Where do I start? Do I talk f
One? Do I talk about the Celtics?
Do I talk about the Bruins
playing for their playoff,
fighting for their playoff lives.
Let's talk Bruins then I'll
do a little advertising care.
If the Bruins fucking 84 points.
We lost four fucking games in a row.
We just won one of those goddamn games.
We are now.
We will like all the way up to like,
I think a fourth seat at one point or a
fifth seat. We are now an eighth seat.
Toronto is ahead of us.
I heard the goaltender got hurt though.
MMM.
Where the fuck is it?
I had this God damn standing sweater.
I want to like deal with
it anyways. I Dunno. Well,
when we had a huge wing,
thank you to Riley Nash for those two
fucking huge goals against the island is
we got the prejudice on Tuesday and then
we played this status is a big fucking
Boston Teamweek dude. You're going
to watch bees versus the stats.
So I'm against the predators, dude. Um,
and I'm going to go out on a limb and
say we kind of have to win both of those
fucking games or hope everybody
beneath is just keeps losing.
Yeah,
unreal. Unreal. This is the
third year in a row. We're just,
the bottom's fallen out. But you know
what, I slowly see improvement though,
and I can see how this could
be a team that could, uh,
actually score a ton of goals
in the future. You know,
I saw on their website
today, the, you know, the,
the frozen four is happening and uh,
we got like,
we have four prospects in the frozen
four they share. So who knows.
I mean the frozen four versus get nhls
a big fucking leap. But who knows,
who knows? Maybe there's an, there's an
Austin, uh, what the fuck's his name?
Matthews in there. Who knows. Um, but
anyways, dude, speaking to that shit,
speaking to the frozen four,
what about the final four?
I barely paid attention Mack, cause
I've been running around, you know,
being a dad and everything, but I,
every time I would just like, you see,
you heard me go on Duke lost,
then my Kansas Lost Kentucky,
lost the final fours.
I remember [inaudible] telling me
was North Carolina understandable.
Okay.
South Carolina.
Okay,
good. Zagat and uh, I forget who the
other team is. Basically, there's no,
everybody's bracket is fucked at this
point. If you bracket isn't fucked,
if there's somebody out there
that actually picked this
year's final four in the
NCAA,
you either don't know shit about fucking
basketball and just guessed or your,
your dad's in the mob in something's
going down this year because just
everybody's out of it.
Um,
I dunno who I'm going to vote for.
Zagat South Carolina.
My teams would Duke or Kansas
and I was always like Ucla.
Yeah.
Um, and they all got, UCLA
got fucking knocked out.
You don't annoy me that day I was
walking down the street and you know,
cause all the bandwagon fucking Ucla fans
all of a sudden reads rabid out here.
You know what?
I was wearing a Bruins sweatshirt and
I'm walking down the street and this guy
goes, hey goes, hey, it's Ucla
Bruins, not Boston Bruins.
And I just laughed. I am mad. You guys are
good this year. He's like, yeah, we are.
And walked away. I was
like, well wait a minute.
And that was at the car wash and
I fucking looked it up. Mike,
who was the Bruins first and it was like
Ucla basketball team was around before
the Boston Bruins, but their first
year in like 1918 or something,
they were the UCLA cubs and then the
next year they switched to the Grizzlies
and in like 1928 they join.
I don't know what's there was the pack
something pack 10 pack 12 I don't know
what the fuck it was back then.
PAC eight I have no idea,
but like there was some team from
Montana that was already the grizzlies.
In 1928 they switched to the UCLA Bruins.
However,
the Boston Bruins were in 1924 all right,
so all due respect to coach wooden,
all due respect to the UCLA program. I
actually liked the school and everything,
but when it comes to that Bruin
Shit, go fuck yourself. All right.
We were there first. Okay,
CIF, stand the fuck down.
It's a different sport. It's
a pro sport. So relaxed,
you know,
you know bad.
I've been replaying that in my head that
I wished that I had that information.
You know, I wish they were in the
final four and I would actually,
I'm such an argumentative con.
I would actually fucking maybe drive
over to Westwood and gets some air quote
lunch and just walk around with that
shirt. It's like it'd be like, ah,
1924 you where the car then
you would be crazy. Hey,
know your history, know
your history. You know like,
like I'm the fucking the
sports guru like I did.
Just didn't look that shit up cause some
guy was a container. The car wash. Um,
all right,
let's do some reads here for this week.
Okay.
Youtube channel announcement. I
got to do that too. All right.
They Internet privacy.
Oh these are the reeds for this week.
This is the shit that people sent in.
Okay.
Oh, here we go. Wink. Everybody
W I n fucking see wink.
Finding a new wine is tough. Yeah.
Especially if it's shit faced.
That's why I've been telling you
all about our sponsored club.
Debbie had clubbed Debbie. I like getting
drunk. He can't, I'm not praising.
It doesn't count and how they make it
so easy to get wine personalized to your
palate and delivered right to your door.
And here's a little update for you.
Clump Debbie. Fight. Terrified.
Interi everywhere. They're
everywhere in the trees.
Man is now called Winc, spelled w. I n. C,
a new name and improved look.
But here's the important part.
It's the same amazing wine company
introducing you to new ones you love.
Wink works directly with wine makers
and offers and growers from all over the
world to create delicious wine
and deliver it right to your door.
Winks 100% satisfaction guarantee
means if you don't like a bottle,
they send you the real price it with the
bottle. You'll love no questions asked.
If I was a fucking alcoholic,
which I might be. That is
the loophole right there.
How much of the bottle do you get
to finish? Yeah, I didn't like it.
Send me another. Um, you don't
just get set random bottles. Wait.
Personalized wine membership
that recommends wine
specifically for you based on
the results of your
palate and profile quiz.
You can also rate the wine you receive
from Winc, so they learn about, yeah,
they'll basically figure out what you
like and then you always be having a great
bottle of wine. Then you start
boozing like fucking Ernest Hemingway.
The best part is Winc is offering
my listeners $20 off right now.
When you go to to try Winc,
W I N c.com/burr they'll even cover
the shipping. Think about that.
I get done. You'll get fine wine
personalized to your palate,
delivered right to your door.
Try Winc and get $20 off plus
complimentary shipping right now.
When you go to try winc.com that's try
winc.com try w I n c.com/bar oh look
who's back. Look who's back.
It's our old friends, old zip.
Are you hiring? Do you know
where to well, are you?
Do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your job on all the
top job sites and now you can with zip
bye.
Brewed up.com you can post your job to
200 plus job sites including social media
networks like Facebook and the Twitter,
all with a single click.
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your
qualified candidates roll into old zip.
It is easy to use interface, no
juggling emails or calls to your office.
Quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
Find out today why Ziprecruiter has
been used by fortune 100 companies,
not 500 fortune 100 this is the top 100
companies of all time and thousands of
small and medium size businesses.
Everybody's using it and right now my
listeners can try jobs on ZipRecruiter for
free by going to ziprecruiter.com/bird
that's ziprecruiter.com/bar one more
time.
Try It for free.
Go to zip.com/
[inaudible] all right, dollar shave club.
Dude. Do you like shaving your face?
Do you not want to cut it?
Apple I got to raise is for you.
There's no reason to use cheap disposable
razors or pay ridiculously high prices.
Kids were sent gimmicky thing.
They'd got a laser pointed
in 17 fucking blades there.
Make us smarter choice and joined
Dollar Shave Club. All right,
what are you doing? They're
overpriced. You always knew they were.
It's a piece of fucking plastic
was sharpened aluminum minute.
Should it be $90,000 wouldn't it be
great if they just delivered it right to
your fucking door or this thing offers
that service before dollar shave club?
It was either, I just settle that shit.
Okay? I said it my own way. All right.
Get a close commute,
shave every time and you can't beat the
convenience or the price of the club if
you haven't tried dollar shave club yet,
you're missing out.
It's an amazing shave and affordable at
an affordable price. There's no smart,
smarter choice in the market and right
now they're giving away a one month trial
of any razor for only a
dollar with free shipping.
And after that it's just
a few bucks a month.
There's no longterm comp commitments.
This is a one night stand.
No hidden fees. You get
the doorman, five bucks,
Shirin and you can cancel whenever you
want. You know you can go bar hopping.
Uh,
get one.
Get your $1
trial@dollarshaveclub.com slash bird.
That's dollar shave
club.com/bar. Um, all right,
he looks helux. This is the
last one. Oh God, I loved that.
They're making the copy shorter
and shorter for me. You're unique.
You're special.
You're your own snow flake.
You don't walk like anyone
else top like anyone else.
Shoe chat or I always throw it sounds
like that drill sergeant shit to make.
Remember that I'm going to teach you.
I'll have your mothers are not pair.
Oh,
I'm going to teach you how to
top chip, check, check my car.
Um, you don't want like anyone else.
You don't talk like anyone else,
her sleep like anyone else.
So why is your mattress one size fits all?
Because a truly customized mattress
will cost you five to $10,000.
Until now with $10,000
for a fucking mattress.
I just refuse to believe that that's true.
Yeah.
That should come with a lady giving you
a fucking hand job right before sleep.
Then go to helix.com helix answer a few
simple questions and they'll run a three
d biomechanical model of your body to
their proprietary algorithms they've
developed with the help of the world's
leading era Gomix and biomechanics
experts.
The results.
Why don't you stretch a little twisted up.
Count the fact that they got to sit there
and act like you're in the star wars.
The result, the most comfortable
mattress you've ever slept on.
You could also stretch everybody if
you stretch and then get one of these
mattresses. I think you're going to
be good. Go get a massage. You know,
drink some fucking water.
Yeah.
10 grand for a mattress.
Just have some fucking Asian lady
walk on your back a little bit.
Save some money.
He likes customers report
at 30 30% improvement in
overall sleep quality and it
has to be an Asian lady.
Okay? Cause the dainty,
you can't get one of those American. We
can't get some white woman, you know,
you can't get any other race.
They're going to be two finless there.
Then that could be old enough to
be in there. You know what I mean?
Yeah.
They get you going to be to God Deb dense.
They can be full of fucking
growth hormones and that
they're going to break it
back.
You don't.
That is an exclusive de de Asian lady.
I just thought about that.
I've never seen it.
Any footage of a white lady
walking on somebody's back.
You just feel like I write
around. Get off. All right.
Your mattress arrives at your door in
about a week and shipping is 100% free.
He looks, uh, and for couples that
customize each side of the mattress.
That's why everyone from GQ magazines to
Forbes or talking about he likes slash
headaches, sleep, customizing
both sides of your mattress.
I can't tell if that's going to make
your relationship happier or it's the
beginning of the end. Oh God, I
don't even like the way he sleeps.
It'll be great.
Then I just want to test out.
Would it be like to sleep a different bed
with them but still be in the same bed?
That's why everyone from Gq magazine to
Forbes are all talking about helix sleep.
Alex, uh, you have 100 nights to
try it out and if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free rouse
and it gave you 100% refund.
No questions asked. We don't even
want to know what that stain is.
We're not going to ask you go to hell.
He sleep.com/bar and
get $50 off your order.
That's helix sleep.com/bar Heloc,
sleep.com/ [inaudible] all right,
there you go. Just like that.
We're done with the advertising we've
done with the advertising and we're on the
other side of the half hours.
We're going to do traffic on the sixes.
Anybody out on the four oh five,
you might want to get yourself a hell
of capture. There's a lot of traffic.
Everybody slowing down and watching
somebody change a tire. Um,
anyways, let's talk some
F1 actually, did anybody,
did you watch the Australian grampy
grampy Grand Prix down in Melbourne,
Australia?
Uh,
it was a great fucking race and it
lived up to the hype that this year the
Ferrari's, we're going to be good. I've
only watched this sport for one season,
so I don't know shit about it.
All I know is last year it was all
about the Mercedes team, Lewis Hamilton,
Nico Rosberg, you know, they had
the whole days of thunder. You know,
I'm the guy who's been around
the block on the other fuck.
I'm on the Tom Cruise Guide,
somebody fucking Robert
Duvall and everybody else,
which is watching last year. And if
those two guys didn't hate each other,
it would have been fucking boring as
shit because basically every race was a
race to the first corner.
Whoever got there first was just driving
through clean air and the cars were so
equally matched,
nobody could catch up with somebody.
You basically had to fuck
up or your car died. Um,
so all the exciting racing was for
like for, for you know, fourth, fifth,
sixth place or whatever. Three psychos
going after it for the last, you know,
championship point is they say, you know,
back in 10th place that was exciting.
But up front it was just Lewis Hamilton
or Nico Rosberg just doing laps was,
you know,
kind of got a little boring.
So this year they were
talking about how um,
Ferrari was very quiet,
eerily quiet during the off season,
working on their deer there,
suspension and the engine and all that
type of shit with the new regulations,
whatever the fuck they are,
I don't know what they are and that they
were going to make a serious challenge
for, uh, against Mercedes issue.
So the fucking race starts and uh,
the Australian Dude,
I already forget his name. Uh, Rico
Rican Berg, I have no fucking idea.
And like eventually I'll, I'll, I'll get
these people's names down. Rikki rocket.
I forget. Okay. Everybody wanted
him to win the poor bastard.
He's down there and they'd taken like the,
the,
the warmup lap or whatever.
And uh,
not even the warmup lap.
They just going around,
getting ready to get into position just
to do the warmup lap and his car gets
stuck in sixth gear. We've all been
there, right the side of the highway,
except he's got 100,000
people in a fucking zillion
millions of fans around the
world watching this shit.
So they got to push his car and they got
to take out the fucking transmission in
like five minutes,
throw a new one in there and try and get
it back in the fucking car before the
race starts. That alone, if they just
showed that, that would have been amazing.
They kind of kept cutting back to it.
I wish they showed more of it.
A long story short, he wasn't able to
get out there until, uh, the second lap.
He was already two laps down.
So that kind of sucked for
all the Australian fans and
uh, then his car, his shit,
the bed halfway through the race,
however, so the race fucking starts.
All right.
I think Lewis Hamilton had the
pole and then Sebastian fettle um,
for Ferrari was in second place and uh,
Louis had a great start and he was out
front and I go, well I guess that's it.
I guess the Mercedes are going
to win it this year, right.
So they get about 20 laps
in and Lewis Hamilton pits,
it's one of these races.
It was like 57 laps and the announcers
were saying that they were going to pit
one time and it's all when you pit
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So all this shit is becoming fascinated
to me. So Lewis Hamilton goes into Pitt,
right? Sebastian Vettel was,
I don't know how far behind,
couple seconds behind he
decides to stay out there.
So the whole time when Louis
was out there in first place,
Sebastian's behind them. All right.
So Lewis has driving in the clean air.
It's like, you know, if you on a
fucking on a lake and you bring,
it's just still water.
You could,
you could go way faster and you boat as
opposed to if the water was all fucking
choppy, you got to go slower. That's
the same thing except the two it's with,
with the air.
I'm just saying this for everybody else
out there who's dumb like me and the
fact that air is invisible,
you don't understand it.
So no matter what this guy's doing,
Sebastian Vettel,
he can only get so close to,
uh,
to Lewis Hamilton because all
the air coming off of him,
and I guess the tire is a bigger this
year, which causes more turbulence.
It would actually,
it,
he's going to use more fuel and chew up
more of his tires if he gets too close
to them, which is really fucking, I dunno,
I don't know if that's
a good or a bad thing.
So Hamilton was having problems
with his tire. He pits early.
So the Ferrari team takes a
gamble and says, fuck this,
we're going to stay out there.
So Sebastian now is in first
place driving into clean air.
He's got the nice smooth lake.
He's bringing the boat across except it's
a car and it's going to air you still
with me. And he stays out
there for one lap and they go,
he's definitely going to come in
for the second lap. Meanwhile, um,
Lewis Hamilton came right back out
of the pits and then was, you know,
technically in fourth
place, but he's, you know,
but he already pitted the other two
guys in front of them have to pit and so
does the other guest. So technically
it's like he's still in first place,
but now he's driving in
dirty air back there.
So Sebastian's flying around the track,
he goes around a second time and you know,
the tires are getting chewed up.
He's driving like a fucking maniac and
then the deed comes around a third time
and they're like, he's not going to fees,
not going to fucking stay out there.
He stayed out there again and now
basically it was like this was the most
exciting part of it cause
this is the fucking race.
So basically what he's trying to,
he's trying to get out so far ahead
that he has time to pit when he goes in,
get his tires and get back out on
the track in front of fucking, uh,
Lewis Hamilton.
It was like a fucking movie.
He pulls in his fourth time around,
comes in,
they fucking take the tires.
You got to go so fucking slow too.
Now he got to slow down to like,
like you're driving a
Prius when you're in there.
And as he's slowing down this show,
and Lewis has coming around,
he's coming around, he's coming
around, he gets the tires,
fucking Sebastian's coming out.
It's like a fucking action movie.
And it was literally, he just
Sebastian, uh, for Ferrari,
just get out in front of Lewis Hamilton.
And then that was the Raci
southern Mercedes guy slammed
his hand down on in the
guy in the pits. Right? The
head fucking guy. Right.
The guy who goes to the eyes wide shut
illuminati parties at the end of the
fucking race. Right. The department
on some yacht that's like invisible,
like the air that they drive through.
Right.
He fucking slammed his hand down like
medium and then fucking slammed it down a
second time. Right. Then I was like,
this guy knows this fucking race is over.
And that was it. Ferrari won
the first race, you know,
backing up their lack of shit talk. They
were real quiet in the off season. So, uh,
I was actually really, you know, I
like the way my, I'm one of those guys,
I like both, both team
proceedings and Ferrari. I mean,
I don't know how you'd get mad at either
one of them. The fucking beautiful,
amazing cars that they've built all
this fucking, uh, over the years.
So I'm just happy that this seems like
there's going to be competition and if it
can be as exciting as that,
um, for the whole season, uh,
I think, um, maybe some more you
guys can get into it. Like I did,
I believe the next races in China,
in Indo India,
in China. That's going to be the next one.
But I was, I was thrilled with the race.
Uh, I don't know how many Effient
fans listen to this shit. Uh,
I'd love to hear your thoughts
on it. Um, all right. What else?
What else the Celtics won. The Celtics
are technically in first place right now,
but we got two games at hands.
We've one more,
one more game and lost one more
game then, um, the Cavaliers.
But uh,
I mean I don't,
I don't see them not the capital is
not getting the number one seed less.
They get real.
Uh,
I don't know if somebody gets fucking
hurt or some shit like that. All right,
last announcement and then
I'm going to read the, uh,
your fucking emails for the week are and
my youtube channel that I'm slowly but
surely building up. All
right. I'm going to, um,
um, gradually just transitioning
to the fucking Internet here.
My whole career is just going to
be on the Internet, the Internet,
other than my live dates and f is for
family because everything else is drying
up. So my youtube channel, which I'm, I'm,
I'm serious about building
up with content. Um,
I actually hired a, uh,
an animator and, um,
hired a couple of people to start making
videos and putting content up there.
I'm going to be doing tours
of every city that I go to.
Now I'm bringing those things
back. Uh, I'm actually considering,
uh, bring it on. This guy that does
drum covers that looks like me,
but you know, isn't me, but
maybe it's me. Um, so anyways,
what do we got here on Tuesday?
The first video from Alan Pailin,
pronounce Pailin on the
official podcast channel.
Alan Pale and is the
guy who edited together.
Remember that one when I
commentated basketball? Um,
he's the guy who did that. So,
um, we're going to have new videos
from him every single week. Um,
my, uh, youtube pages,
youtube.com/user/ it's backslash,
you know,
the one that starts further away and then
comes in towards you like a flare chop.
Um, youtube.com backslash user
backslash Monday morning podcast.
Please subscribe to the
channel, check it out, and um,
I'm going to start making some
videos and that type of shit.
I don't know that I'll have a video
tape the podcast because it's just been
laying here right now. I'm wearing a
tee shirt, pajama bottoms and slippers.
How interesting is that going
to be? And I, every time I,
whenever I saw a radio shows videotaped,
they just,
something happened where it was boring.
I liked the fact that like podcasts,
it's just like radio and the fact that
you, you, you're doing shit right now.
You're driving home from work, you're
on the fucking elliptical. You know,
you're pouring yourself a drink,
you cleaning the house whenever you're
doing whatever the fuck it is you do and
you can do other shit, right?
All of a sudden it's videotaped.
You feel like you've got to watch
somebody's talking into a microphone.
I don't get it. All right, here we
go. Internet privacy. Everybody.
Uh,
hey Billy thought you might like this.
A private Internet access provider
took out a full page ad in the New York
Times, calling out 50
senators who voted to monitor,
monitor the public's internet
activity for financial gain.
What people care a lot
about their public image.
And I think this should be done more
to combat assholes. Let me call,
let me click on this saying I can't click
on it because I'm not on the Internet.
Hang on, let me try and find this here.
I got to see who the contacts are.
Who are the cons that
scientists onto this? All right.
We are the cons. We don't give
a shit. All right. Hello world.
These are the 50 senators who monitored,
who voted to monitor your internet
activity. Uh, Jesus Christ.
I can't read on the too fucking small.
Okay.
All right. Oh Jesus. Jesus.
What are they all Republicans,
dude,
the way they vote,
man.
Cause it was probably something
else that was pro conservative.
That's the only reason why
the fucking Democrats didn't
so fucking and McCoys.
It's basically there. It's
all republicans. Okay.
Representative from Tennessee,
Alexander Representative from Wyoming.
Brasso blunt from Missouri.
Boozman from Arkansas
burn from North Carolina.
You fucking piece of shit
ruining the name.
Kaputo from West Virginia.
Cassie from Louisiana
Cochran from Mississippi.
Collins from Maine.
Corker from Tennessee. You
know what? I'm just going,
I'm going to just retweet this fucking
picture. Jesus Christ, Republicans,
all Republicans,
Cruz from Texas, Crappo from
Idaho, some hell of a names.
Dane's for Montana.
Okay.
Another one from Wyoming,
Nz from Wyoming,
Ernst from Iowa.
This is all of this shit.
All Rubio from Florida,
Perdue from Georgia,
Portman from Ohio. This is all like,
this is all the thing is fake news.
It's all fake news. Do you know
it's basically, um, you know,
whose kid new news. It's propaganda.
It's bullshit. It's bullshit.
But what they want is their bullshit
in your brain. That's what they want.
So what they want to do is gradually take
control of this shit and they're going
to make fake news.
Basically your opinion of what's going on.
They're going to make that
like a legal to do. Um,
and they're probably looking over
at China going like, Hey China,
how the fuck did you do this? And China's
going like, Hey, this is how we did it.
So they gradually do that. Much like the
Nazis were looking at us going like, hey,
how did you do that shit
to the native Americans?
Because we want to do that to the Jews.
Now we're going to do that.
Probably what looking, I bet. I
bet the fucking hire up 1% cons.
The people who make profit off
a war and everybody's misery.
I bet they are envious of the Internet in,
in Red China.
The way you know Uri is envious when
somebody drives down the street by in a
fucking Ferrari,
you know,
I dunno. All right, well I'm, I'm good
for that person that put that up there.
MMM.
That's fucking disgusting.
I wonder what was linked to it though.
You know what I mean?
Cause it's never just in defense
of all of those fucking people.
It's never just one thing,
which is another bullshit thing.
You know when they vote for something,
okay,
shouldn't it just be one thing?
Should we or show me not vote for
solar power and she just be about that.
But then they tag all this other shit
onto it, onto the bill, which is fucking,
that's how they get everything through.
And then it's always like, yeah, you know,
something completely fucked up. And then
when that person goes to run for office,
you know, they voted for the bill because
they're into solar power. But then the,
the, the, the thing that they, the
appendix that they put on to it,
they can be like, this guy
doesn't take kitchen advice. Wait,
he voted against that. It's like, no,
I voted for alternative sources
of energy to bankrupt the,
uh, the, the terrorists. Terrorists.
All right. Bullying manager,
dear bill,
about a month ago,
a lady dairy Queen Manager in Missouri
was charged for involuntary manslaughter.
What?
She gave the guy an ice cream headache.
They'll, she did keep eating
ice cream. Then I'll blow you.
The guy fell for it and he stuck his
hand under the fucking smoothie machine.
The soft serve there.
All right. Allegedly,
the dairy queen manager was a
dick to one of its employees,
uh, filled with name, calling
and belittling day after day.
Isn't it great to see women getting
like positions of power and just acting
exactly is fucking ridiculous
as men, you know, most,
most people cannot handle a
position of power. I mean,
look at me. Look at a power.
I have with this podcast.
I don't have the decency to put on pants.
I'm in pajamas and slippers.
I am part of the problem. Um,
one incident reportedly the
manager through a burger
on the floor after he made
it incorrectly and then made
the 17 year old clean it up.
The kid was also a victim of
bullying at school as well. Um,
none of this is going to justify this
kid harming this. This boss, you,
you quit the job,
uh,
but voiced most of the
bullying but foist most.
That doesn't make sense.
But most of the bullying happened,
happened at work.
What happened to this person
who wrote this sentence?
They wrote but voiced most of the
bullying happening at work and singling,
singling out his boss and his boss.
Okay,
well eventually the kid ended
up shooting himself in the head.
Oh boy. Did not see that
coming. Yes, I know.
It's a sad story that that
happens too often. Does it,
do a lot of people get bullied at dairy
queen and then blow their brains out?
I thought that was a happy place.
They got soft serve ice cream.
What could go wrong.
But the town wanted to hold
somebody responsible for suicide.
The authorities air quote,
investigated and interviewed people and
his stories of being teased and made fun
of where retold the cops ultimately came
to the conclusion that is dairy queen
boss was the reason the kid is dead
now by Jesus Christ. Wait a minute.
Hey,
it's a little bit of an overreach.
And she was charged with
secondary involuntary manslaughter
after me hearing this story is that
proper English shouldn't be after.
I heard this story after for me,
after hearing this story,
I'm waiting for somebody on TV to
state the obvious. This is bullshit.
How can you blame someone for
another person killing themselves?
It's not my fault.
How other people handled my insults.
You've been called belly fat
tits. How many times? Well,
first of all, I'm not 17.
All right.
Um,
I think enough bullying
can drive somebody to it.
It depends on how it is and how
fragile somebody is, but uh,
there's just so many fucking variables
involved. Like what ha the person,
let's say this person was a
bully at dairy Queen Lake.
What happened to them as a kid
that made them the way they are.
How old is this person?
Because, um, for me,
I just feel that, I honestly
believe that, you know,
people in their twenties for
the most part, it's just, it's
that is the most purest form of the
direct results of the parents that you had
is now you're out in the world. They're
not there to be like, hey, hey, hey, hey,
you know, knock it off. You know,
and you have to make decisions for
yourself and you go around. Like,
I know when I was in my twenties, I took,
without realizing it, I was taking my,
everybody takes the childhood out on
people in their twenties because you don't
know what the fuck you doing. Uh,
so hopefully you had a good one.
So you've taken it out on people. Is,
um, is you're actually a nice person.
Like Pete Holmes is character on crashing,
by the way. I fucking love that show. Um,
Tj Miller,
um,
Artie Lange and I believe the
guy's name is George Bazell. Uh,
I watched the first three fucking
episodes and they were killing me.
And their interaction with Pete's
character. He's great. And I can't wait.
I love Pete Holmes.
I cannot wait to break his balls about
his character on that show though.
I really going to break his balls like
Pete. Is that how you see yourself?
I'm just a nice guy who tries to
do nice things. It's like Pete,
you're a fucking lunatic.
Just like the rest of us.
Um, anyways, oh I can't wait to, I, they,
one of my favorite things in this business
is teasing him cause he can fucking
take it. But uh, you got check out
crashing a Judd Apatow, uh, Pete Holmes,
a Joey Rose's Joe to Rosa,
a road on the show to a Mike
Birbiglia I believe wrote on the show.
There's a bunch of people, uh, comics
and everything and the comics on it.
I saw agree of bonds, Dove David off
all these comics, a Marina Franklin.
It's just, it's fucking them.
It's just such an amazing show.
Cause I remember when he came to New York,
um,
as that wide eyed kid and I had
actually worked with him and, uh,
this comedy club in Peoria,
Illinois. That doesn't anymore.
I worked with him at Brewster's when
he was still married. I believe.
Maybe had just gotten divorced.
I can't fucking remember.
I've told this story before.
We went to go see the ring and we,
and we were the only two people in
the movie theater. And I hate that.
That's that. That is the
detail. Cause that sounds fake.
It's the only time it's ever happened.
We walked in,
it was a shitty movie theater.
We were two comedians.
It was the middle of the fucking,
it was like two in the afternoon and
we saw the ring on like a Thursday
afternoon and a shitty movie theater.
And I swear to God,
we are the only two fucking people there.
Um,
that movie stayed with me. Certain
certain one, Blair, which stayed with me.
That one stayed with me. Um,
some of them just to just,
they just fucking creep me
out and they stay with me. Um,
for whatever reason, Jordan peals movie
when that, that guy comes running, when,
you know,
when the kids smoking the cigarette and
then the guy comes fucking just running
up full speed. Adam, that fucked with me.
That's for whatever reason that
fucking stayed with me. Um, anyways,
did just like shit. I think about
when I go to my car at night,
even though I know it's not real,
I just think about what a fat fucking
dude just came from wanting to just like
that at the last second. Made a
right turn in front of me. Um,
anyways,
I had a fuck did I get on to all of that
shit talking about this poor kid who
killed himself. Um, anyways, he
can send that throwing a, okay.
What does he say?
You've been called Billy fat tits.
How many times and by how
many people you kill yourself,
over half of your listeners will
go to jail. How is this a law?
How many times can you call somebody fat
before it's against the law and can we
stop saying bullying? It's just being
teased and made fun of. That's not true,
man. That isn't, that's
not true. That's not true.
It depends on the level and
it depends on the intent. Um,
in all of this shit will be really hard
to prove. But like, you know, there's,
what it is, sir, is you have to have
empathy here. And what I'm guessing is,
is that you are more the person
teasing then getting teased.
Um,
and maybe you are a little bit more of
a stronger person the same way somebody
else might've just been better at math
than you. Um, I know looking back,
you know, in my high school, I
know that there was a, you know,
there was kids that got
it really fucking bad,
really bad and uh, you know, one of whom,
you know, killed himself a few years
later. And I remember thinking back,
I don't know what it was based on,
but certainly did not have
a good experience in high
school the last couple of
years.
And it's one of those things because
kids are kids and they don't,
they don't understand it.
Um,
it's a really complex thing.
But I would say at this kid
was also bullied at school.
And then if this person was a content
at dairy queen, I mean it's sorted of a,
an amalgam of all of that.
And then also the personalities people
they're born that just really sensitive,
shy people and, uh, they
don't know how to handle it.
And if you're prone to depression,
shit, I imagined that, you know,
that's sort of the perfect storm. So, um,
anyways, he goes, stay,
throw this bullying word around like
it's an epidemic sweeping all these
heartless millennials. Uh, we've
all been made fun of before.
We've all been called names ever
since we were little kids. Um,
you sound like an older person like
me and you're just doing the day.
These kids today, these
millennials, and they'll make God,
they're fragile little flowers and
they're not all like that. To this day.
He thinks it's still not the mean kid.
You still don't think there's, there's,
you know,
the big guy just fucking beaten on.
There's always going to be the bigger kid,
beaten on the younger kids,
the smaller kids or whatever.
Um, we need to let this continue.
It builds character.
If you were always given a trophy,
you're all over the map here.
Dude. It only told compliments you,
you wouldn't be a comedian. Um,
no. Now you speaking for me,
you would still be working in the carpeted
area discussing which I never worked
there. Your favorite route
to work in the morning.
All I'm saying is that we're all becoming
weak pussies because of laws like this
and nobody's addressing it.
But you can't bill with your
soon to be Emmy winning podcast.
You can champion this cause
for all our sake or whatever.
Hope to see important suit. Thanks.
I have to be honest with you sir.
All right. I think, uh,
the true sign of maturity,
aside from on one side,
being able to take a good ribbing and,
and learning how to have more of a sense
of humor by yourself and also learning
that whatever is happening today is
not the end of the fucking world.
And that, you know, it's probably kids
listening right now that get bullied.
This is the thing, all of that shit, it's,
you're not going to see any
of those fucking people ever
again after high school.
And your whole fucking life is going to
be determined by you and the decisions
you make, and you have
100% control over that. So,
um,
you know,
and I think a lot of times people get
bullied up aside from the fact that
they're, that they're just
smaller, weaker. They just
seem like targets. I think,
you know, sometimes when people
see somebody that's talented, um,
they'll go after him and,
uh,
so you got to make sure that you
kind of push all that shit away.
But the other side I think that really
shows that you're a mature is, uh,
is empathy. You know what
I mean? It certainly helps.
Like, uh, I can think it's easy
to do that. The rant that you did,
I understand there's a lot
of truth in some of the shit
that he's saying, but, um,
you know, it's not all just like,
ah, learn how to fucking take it.
You fucking pussy stop wearing a
helmet when you ride bicycles and shit.
And I'm guilty of saying stuff like that.
I understand where you're coming from.
Like, uh, you know, so
what, what is, what, what,
why do you think this kid killed himself?
You know what I mean?
Do you think if that shit
wasn't happening, the kids
still would have been made?
It's a possibility. I don't know if
that kid had clinical depression.
I have no idea. But I agree with
you to try from what you've written.
Okay.
For the sentences where the w
what was spelled correctly, uh, it
seems like that kid was just having
a miserable experience. I mean,
I can't imagine if you were getting
bullied all day at school and then you go,
okay,
well now I'm going to get a job.
This might be a ray of light to
what the future's going to be,
where I'll be at work and maybe people
are nicer and then it just becomes
somebody else screaming
at you. Um, you know,
when you're 17 years old,
if it's substance school and
sucks at the dairy queen,
you work at that is your world and uh,
you don't have an ability to step out
of it and you can downward spiral.
Like once again, I don't think that
they should put it all on this person,
but that's a a, it's a
fucking terrible story. Um,
but I, I don't think
there's backlash to the, to,
to political correctness to then go the
other fucking deep go deep all the way
back once again to what
caused political correctness.
All you fucking guys, hey, pull your
bootstraps up the top in a fucking pussy.
You fucking millennial flour.
It's guys like you that are fucking
ranting against fucking political
correctness. It's constant. Like you
that created a political correctness,
you know,
white guys that tell it like it is,
is there anything worse than
the white guy that I know.
I always say that I fucking, that's, that
is, to me that is the most boring. Yeah,
yeah.
Fucking mindset. You could
possibly have a, I'm a white guy.
Everything's set up for me.
Let me tell you who, you know,
just not have the advantages that I have.
Why you need to toughen up.
You know,
as I slept in my bunk bed and my Culdesac,
those were the years that I really
became a tough guy. Um, anyways, so,
yeah, I mean that's just
a terrible story. I, I, I,
I hope that something good could come
out of it cause that's, you know,
it's very rare that,
you know,
you bring up an ice cream store
and some like that happens.
That was all exciting. You know, I
love fucking dairy queen. You know,
my wife loves dairy queen. We are dairy
queen people, uh, cleaning up. All right,
dear bill, do your Billy red
face yet. Um, I'm 52 years old.
Congratulations.
Most people don't live that long or a
lot of people don't make it that far. Uh,
I'm 52 years old, but a life of
drinking has made me look 62.
I still drink and I smoke weed all day.
Jason Sky's going hard.
You drink and you smoke weed all day.
I wasn't there for my kids growing up.
They had to go through a lot because of
my mind and my wife's addiction problems.
JC, I imagine they did. Uh, let's say
Jesus is too depressing ones in a row.
What does this doctor, Phil, you
need to stop drinking, smoking,
Wade and pay attention to your children.
Crowd goes crazy.
Another episode in the can and he gets
more syndication money and then that
fucking drunk walks out the door,
continues to do what the fuck he's doing.
And Dr Phil Looks Great. Uh, let's
just say the fact that they turned out,
let's just face say the fact that they,
the way they turned out
has nothing to do with me.
I take no credit for the
people they are today. Well,
nor should you with the exception
of any lingering anxiety. I May,
I may have caused them.
I mean if you're the kind of dad
that you're saying you are, yeah.
You kind of owning up to it, which is good
I guess. Unless you're doing that like,
so everybody goes, no, no.
You were actually a good dad.
All depends on what your,
your reasoning is. Um,
I don't live close to my daughters,
but I am starting to miss them.
Um, I feel like they'd be better
without me at this point. Nah,
I'm at a fork in the road.
I can either clean up and
realized that my life isn't over.
Sent my phone buzzing.
Oh,
and he spills his first glass
of water or the day. All right,
I got to fucking call this back in a
minute. Um, all right, where am I? Um,
I can either clean up and realize that
my life isn't over and then I may have
the grandchildren one day that I want to
have a relationship with or just enjoy
my responsibility. Let's
life, uh, responsibility,
less life until I die.
That sounds morbid and the answer may
seem more obvious to someone else,
but there was a good chance my kids
won't care either way at this point.
And I don't want to disrupt
them by being the annoying, hey,
can I come back and do your life person
quitting won't be easy and I'm trying to
weigh my options. What should I do? A,
you should get clean and sober
and own up to everything.
Apologize to your kids and then understand
that it's your kids' choice whether
they want you back in their life or not.
And uh,
that's what they decide that they don't.
You have to be a man about it and I
wouldn't pout and go back to drinking and
smoking.
Um,
you can totally clean your life up and
you can put years back on the pedometer,
you know? Or you can be dead in 10
years. I mean, it's up to you. I mean,
it's pretty, uh, pretty easy, easy choice.
But I would say the first thing you
should do is try to get help and, um,
I dunno, I got to tell you, dude, not
drinking and all that type of stuff.
You feel like he feel like
1 million bucks, you know,
four days and not drinking alone.
When you wake up in the morning,
you're going to feel 20 years younger,
you know? So, uh, I don't know.
You want to keep feeling like shit.
It's going to,
that's going to be a
brutal death bed dude.
To sit in there waiting
for someone to show up,
hoping somebody is going to show up.
You don't want that man. You're only 52.
You know, you got a lot of years left. You
got a quarter of a century left, if you,
if you eat right in a exercise and all
of that type of stuff. So you know,
it's up to you, man. You're an adult.
I hope you make a positive choice.
Jesus Christ. All Right, yogurt.
Does anybody die in this one?
Um,
maybe it's more than you want to bother,
but it's really easy to make your own
yogurt. Uh, then you know what's in it.
I'm not going to down going
to load you down with links,
but this is a pretty decent start.
Yeah.
And they send me this fucking
video of this woman immediately.
I'm envious of her chin or kitchen
and the fact that she gets us,
she can speak more than one language
cause I think that's cool as shit. But uh,
she's making yogurt and one of the
things, one of the ingredients, she goes,
it's very simple yogurt.
One of the ingredients she makes,
one of the ingredients
to her yogurt is yogurt.
I'm going to show you how to make
chicken. All right, get salt and pepper,
put it in a ball and then go to
the store and buy some chicken.
Some already made chicken. I don't
get it. I don't get that video. Um,
I'm fine with just the Greek
yogurt, probiotic. It tastes
fucking weird as shit.
The plain stuff. And after a while you get
addicted to and you'll love it. So, um,
I appreciate it. I will post the
link. It's a great fucking steal.
I love about that stove.
It's got four burners and then it's got
the griddle in the middle. I love that.
Oh, I want that stove so fucking
bad. All right. Fun Car to drive.
Billy sports car.
Uh,
you were talking about cars on Thursday
and the most fun car I ever drove was a
1968 Alfa Romeo sedan,
not the spider. Google it.
Short throw, manual shift. My favorite
fucking thing ever handles. Great.
Um, yeah, I actually, um,
I actually looked up the car there
wa there was only youtube videos,
pictures of him. Nobody had the
sedan. I'll tell you, one of the best,
most fun shifting cars I ever
drove was my older brother had a,
had like a 1981 two door Toyota Tercel
for speed and that fucking thing,
it was so tight. It was do you
had to move that fucking thing?
Like I swear to God,
like an inch and a half and you
were in another gear and uh,
even though it was a four cylinder
by today's standards, you know,
it was a pretty goofy looking car,
San high up off in shit.
But it was fun as shit to drive.
We said these jobs with, you know,
we had paper routes from the time we
were in third grade right up til ninth
grade.
And then when we got our licenses we
just delivered bigger roots and we drove
around beating the shit out of our cars.
And that was the most fun car to drive
cause you could stack it the back seat up
with all the papers and um,
and dude,
it was a Toyota and that's when Toyota
was really competing with the American
shit. And I'm the only way
that they were going to get it.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Are you fucking kidding me too?
This is how fucked up my houses.
I just spilled water and I was just like,
you know what? On the hardwood floors,
I'm going to finish the podcast.
I'm almost done. I got to take the,
I can't believe this just happened and
I'm thinking that's a fucking water.
It's going to be on the floor.
It's just going to be a pump.
This is what just happened.
I just looked down at the floor.
I felt I spilled a full glass of water.
It's all gone.
It's not there anymore. Sorry.
I put the headphones back on
the fuck out.
He hit the floor isn't even wet.
Yeah.
This is what happens and this
is only one part of my house.
Okay.
The house is settled so much.
My house is 94 years old this year.
It's settled so much that I swear to God,
the water roll down the
hill and the base board.
This is space between the floorboards in
the base board and it just rolled into
the cracks. It disappeared.
This can't be fucking happen
on a fucking believable.
Oh, I've got it now. I'm
wondering where did that go?
Is this ceiling below now going
to have all watermarks on it?
I don't think that's enough water
to do it, dude. I'm telling you.
I'm telling you right fucking now.
Okay.
The next house I get
is going to be fucking,
if it's an old house,
it's going to be,
we looked at one this
weekend where it was,
should we just look at what would
bullshit? You know what I mean? Um,
but she's trying to see what's out there,
but the prices are,
and that type of shit did. We
looked at one, it was the turn key.
That's what I want. And for all
you people never bought a house.
That means the whole fucking
thing has been redone.
I don't give a fuck that
somebody is flipping it.
I don't give a shit that they're trying
to make fucking 500 fucking thousand
dollars in two months.
I don't care.
The fact that they're going
to strip it all the way down,
all the way down, all the
piping, the sewer line right
out to the fucking street.
Everything's brand new.
That's the house I'm getting.
That's the house I'm getting,
and that's the house I'm dying,
and when I die,
the fucking next person can deal
with whatever bullshit I did to it.
I just go to a full glass of fucking
water and it disappeared like a magic
trick. All right, that's the podcast.
Go fuck yourselves up in on
you on a on Thursday. Go, Bro.
It's.