Hey,
what's going on is Bill Byrd is time for
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
December 25th,
2017 Oh, it's Christmas morning. Ah,
merry Christmas to you.
Merry Christmas to you and
happy birthday to Geez,
a merry Christmas or
happy birthday to you.
Ooh.
Oh the lovely Nia.
My lovely daughter both
wearing Christmas pajamas.
This is my first question.
What in God's name are you doing?
Listening to a podcast on Christmas.
My class is already mad enough
at me for doing one. Hey,
gorgeous. How are you doing this?
How? I woke up in the morning,
I was laying in bed and I felt high.
I felt these little hands,
it's a little hand squeezing my finger.
So I thought she was just sleeping,
just sorta like squeezing
my hand or whatever.
So I took the pillow off my giant head
and I looked over and she was sitting up
and I looked at it and she just waved
at me. I loved the way she waves.
We were joking. My daughter waves
at you from like six inches away.
She waves like she's on a luxury
liner like cruise boat. And Yo,
you're a hundred yards away in the
dark. It's just giant wave. Like,
Hey man,
I'm right here.
You got blueberry all over
your face. Um, anyways,
merry Christmas to
everybody. Uh, you know,
I was going to tease everybody, but what
are you doing? You know, it's funny,
this is a tough time of year
to be allowed. Gee, Bill,
you really went in deep into your brain
to figure that one out, not only alone.
Then they got all these,
damn,
they got all these damn songs that just
make you feel worse about yourself.
You know, if your life stinks and
you're sitting there going, I'll go,
what have I done with my life? I
pushed everybody away. I'm all alone.
And as you're thinking that,
oh,
you hear in the background as you're
walking through the liquor stores,
just say it's the most
wonderful time of the year.
They got to update that. Right?
Unless you're a divorced dad,
you can't see your kids because
your wife is a cod ex wife. Sorry,
it's a boast one de full time.
Um, I do actually, you know,
I am envious. This is when,
you know, if you don't even care that
you're alone today, you are a true loner.
You Ready? First Ballot Hall of Famer.
What do all the, all the cliches,
you know, Mount Rushmore.
I remember one time I,
I spent a Thanksgiving alone and uh,
this is how, this is how deep and dark
my life was. I thought it was hilarious.
I was not, I wasn't sad for any moment
during the day. Thought it was hilarious.
I didn't have any Turkey, any, any
of the fixings, any of that stuff.
And I actually,
uh,
I called up this other comic,
I think it was Ryan Dalton,
one of my friends from Cleveland
and I believe he just came over to my
drab New York apartment and we just sat
there getting shit faced.
You know, I just, I was
in a point in my life,
I was just so excited that I wasn't in
a relationship. So there was no like,
cause at that point I didn't
even know how to be in one.
So the fact that I wasn't a one
and he obviously wasn't either,
we both would have had somewhere to go.
I just remembered,
I think that's why I was so happy because
so many years I was in a relationship
that I just, I dunno, I just
wasn't ready to be in one.
And then I was sitting there going,
Oh God,
I'm meeting their family and what am I
della I got to get out of anything rather
than just relaxing and
enjoying the moment.
So I was actually in my comfort
zone being all alone. Aw,
what happened? Bill? I'll
put, gives a shit. Um,
so Billy Bean town,
his back in Boston.
And you haven't seen any beans up here,
by the way.
So funny how that nickname just stuck.
I guess at some point they used to
fucking make baked beans, you know,
kind of how they used to go wailing
and, you know, I don't know what else.
Uh, I don't know. What else,
what else did you make?
Buckles for hats for the
pilgrims, but for some reason, uh,
making beans has stuck here.
Now. I don't know if you've,
if you've never been to Boston,
I just, I don't, spoiler alert.
You're not gonna find a lot of beans here.
All right.
I went to the big apple. New York City.
Never saw really any more apples there.
Why did they call it to this different
reason for that? Isn't there New York,
why do they call it? Yeah,
right. It is right there.
Why do they call it the big apple?
All these fucking chicks with the
big ass down there. Apple bottoms.
Is that what it is?
My big apple is a nickname for New York
City was first popularized in the 1920s
by Jay Fitzgerald.
What?
John Jay Fitzgerald. Okay. A sports
writer for New York when it's popular.
Since what the fuck?
Why is it called the Big Apple?
I don't give a fuck about John.
Jay Fitzgerald.
Yeah.
Origin of the name. Oh, somebody is
calling me. I'm not answering that.
Okay. Although the history of the
big apple was once thought a mystery,
a clearer picture of the
term history has emerged.
Do you do the work of amateur
etymologist Barry Popkin.
Okay.
And Gerald Cohen, who gives a fuck
about them? A number of false theories.
I don't care about those. Oh,
and clue. Okay. Why? Actually,
I like this one
theory previously existed including the
claim that the term derived from a woman
named Eve who ran a brothel in the city.
This was subsequently exposed as a hoax.
I love how they figure out that it's
a host. How do you figure that out?
Like where would you start?
You know, so she was,
they've been calling it that or that
was the lie for all these years.
How do you go back and fact check it?
New evidence suggests the earliest known
usage of the big apple in a book in the
book, the, the wayfarer in New York.
I mean in order to Wayfair is sounds
like a fat person that eats crackers.
Okay,
well it's wafers. Cookies. Wait, what is,
it is a literally a
whole fucking page here
in which ended another,
Duh.
Yeah.
William, if he considered in this
coinage, but where is he answer
Kansas is apt to see in New York City,
a gritty city.
It's inclined to think that the big apple
gets a disproportionate share of the
national SAP. Oh, so
that line from the book,
Kansas is apt to see in New York City,
Indian in New York are greedy city in
it inclines to think that the big apple
gets a disproportionate
share of the national Sapp.
I, I, you know, I, you know,
I don't feel like I'm any closer to
understanding why it's called that.
What the fuck does that mean?
So the way that's worded,
it seems like they were already
calling it the big apple or you know,
cause if you read like Tom Sawyer and
everything, they're like, hey, you know,
if you, if you're whitewashed my fence,
I'll give you an apple. And they're like,
boy, oh boy. You know, cause they
didn't have any snickers bars.
So an apple was like a tree.
It was a treat back then.
So maybe that was their big dessert.
I get the fuck out of people making pies.
Okay.
That's all women did back then. They
weren't allowed to vote. Right. You know,
if they just sat around making pies,
you know,
bitching that they weren't out in the
fields behind a fucking team. Oxygen.
Why do you get to go out there
and smell that og shit? Hey Lady,
you want to do this?
It's all yours
fucking sitting here kneading dough.
I'd rather do that to be outside
in the elements, but you know,
if that's what you want to
do, by all means. All right.
Speaking of apples, you
guys friend, you guys, uh,
are you guys fans I should say
of the, uh, the band primus?
Well, their drummer, uh, Tim Alexandra
has a cider called Herb Sida.
If you'd like to get boozed up,
go to ww dot herb cider.com.
Yeah,
and check that stuff out. I
actually had a little, oh,
I can't actually have a glassy pool of it.
He sent me something,
but I can't have a glass he pool
of it until I come off the wagon,
which is probably going to be
happen on the day of the Rose Bowl.
It's my 10th rose bowl in a row.
Me and Bart Nick are going to be there.
Maybe we'll have a little bit of
herb site or whatever. Check it out.
If you're into cider, if you like to get
hammered and also be like, yeah, but doc,
I'm also having an apples herb
site or resisting for you.
I'm gonna check out his website here.
Okay,
go to the page. Yes. That's what I want
to do, please. For the love of God,
for the love of God,
slowly opening,
I shouldn't have hotel internet.
I always pay for the extra amount.
Oh, it's got a great label.
I'll tell you right now,
if it's as good as that God damn label,
I'm going to be drinking
some of this stuff.
I love all these musicians now can like
branch out and actually have like other
businesses and stuff before.
It's like they had,
they hit songs and then some greedy
bastard would steal from them and now they
got like clothing label of clothing
lines and all of this shit.
This guy's making cider,
you know?
Do you know the smothers
brothers have their own vineyard?
That was like unheard of back in the day.
Maybe John Elway would have a couple of
car dealerships or something like that,
but usually the performance, when we
were done per forma, we were screwed.
You know, if we weren't out there
tap dance and we were fucked,
what can I come up with?
What should I make?
Okay.
Bill Burrs, big book of content and
like all the different ways to say it.
And I'll go around the world, you know,
find out, I'll find out the origins of it.
Back to j f Scott Fitzgerald,
you know,
people in Tupelo, Mississippi think
that the big con gets more of its share.
Okay.
Of just sat there. I'm sorry. Um,
um, anyways, I don't
know what to talk about.
I didn't know why the
fuck I'm doing this today.
You shouldn't even be listening to you.
You to be ashamed of yourself. Dammit.
Shit. My wife's going to give me, she
was saying he doing the podcast today.
Who I do the podcast. I go,
cause it's fucking hilarious.
Okay.
Then I'm podcasting, or Christmas morning.
Is there something funny about that?
Right.
We already had Christmas breakfast.
We're going to go out of my
parents' house for Christmas dinner.
I got a window here.
Snow one outside.
All the weather outside is frightful,
but your smile is so delightful.
That's really something that's serial
killer would be singing, right?
Just you're tied up in his cabin.
Oh,
the weather outside is frightful,
but your smile is so the legs
you sit in there all gag on,
sorry, I don't know what it
is about Christmas music,
but I always just think creepy shit.
There's something about it.
I think when I was growing up,
just watching it, you know,
passed a search in certain age and you
start to figure out adults a little more
and you just like, you know what? Nobody's
really that happy. This is all bullshit.
This is all part of the lie,
Huh? Full Christopher. Cringle
how about those patriots?
Huh? How bout those patriots?
How about those buffalo bills?
That's one of the best teams
I've seen them have both games,
even though we kind of kicked her ass
the first time. But I mean they're, uh,
when they were eight and
six when they came in,
they're looking at their ninth one.
They might be nine and seven this year.
You know when I say I say good for them,
good for them.
I don't know who the hell they are.
Safety wasn't that quarterback
who jumped out route,
timed it perfectly and got
a very rare interception.
Picked six off a Tom Brady.
But you knew we were going to win.
Anytime Tom Brady throws a pick six
weeks, that's when he's, he gets pissed.
All you did was pissed him off.
He's going to come back and just
blow the game wide open. Uh,
nobody knows that better than people
down in Atlanta. Merry Christmas.
Atlanta Falcon fence.
I love you guys so much.
I brought up the biggest show could
Superbowl history once again, I apologize.
Okay. And Happy Hanukkah too. If
you're a Jewish fan, happy Kwanzaa.
If you're an African American fan and uh,
I don't know what the transgendered
people celebrate these days,
but whatever that thing is,
I'm going to allow me to make
sure I know what that is.
So I don't cause a big
dust up on social media.
Um,
I'll watch the Bruins when,
and I went to the Celtics and
they want against the bulls.
We've got a great young team and a
buddy of mine has tickets right behind,
uh,
my Garmin and Tommy Heinsohn.
So for one quarter I got
to sit down there and, uh,
you know, heights since like six,
seven see sitting behind him,
he can barely see the damn game,
Lisa transition game when
they're bringing it up the court.
But I have to tell you, it was,
um, back in the day, I always,
I kind of wanted to be a sports
broadcaster. So actually watching them,
they both had a guy on
either side. Like, you know,
when they sit there and be like,
he's got 16 points, it's like,
how the hell did they know that?
It's like as they were scoring points,
whoever's scores,
their whole line of stats,
the player would light up and the points
is all the way to the right, I believe.
And um, I was just kind of watching
how they, they were able to do that.
I mean just there's so much stuff.
You got to know what's going on and
then understand like the importance of
what's going on. Like when you watch a
game at home, you know what's going on.
You're into the flow of the game and
then you're talking about the next day at
work and so much of that is because of
what the announcers are telling you.
This is a big play here.
They got to convert this dirt
down and then they don't.
Oh,
that was devastating.
You got to work like, no, it
was a big important cable.
Need you to protect her down
and you don't even know.
I realize you just, you just saying
what the fuck they already said.
What's when you go to the game by
yourself, you know, there's so much,
there's just so much crap going on.
Yeah,
good Lord. Every time there's a
stoppage of play, they had this, this,
this group of kids, little funk.
They always have these kids dancing.
Yeah,
I have a fun.
I hate it.
I hate seeing kids in show business that
young and it's like you should be up
building a god snowman going out
doing this whole dance routine.
How long did your work on that?
Just picture some mean fucking teacher.
We're not leaving till we get it
right from the top five tech seven.
Eight right?
Yeah,
they have that.
They got fucking Santa Claus coming up,
break dancing and spinning it on his head
and it really kills like feeling like
you're at the game.
Like I was heckling the bull's coach
Guy's name was Fred something or other,
you know we was sitting down low so he
kept standing up and those damn coaches,
they like block your view.
So I'm going,
hey Friday grabs him far.
Drag some pilot Frederick.
Okay.
Hey Freddy,
you know you could coach sitting down.
Okay.
Hey what? What his hands on
your hip beads. No defense.
Okay.
Friday just doing that shit. And everybody
was like looking around, you know,
my father in law was getting
embarrassed. I'm like, Mike, dude,
this is what people used to do. This
is what you say. This was big. But,
so there was also people laughing.
That's what used to happen when
there was a stoppage of play.
Okay.
Fans would yell out what they thought
should have been going on. Know,
hey Dee, why don't you let him
get to the fucking elbow again?
How many times he got hit dead shot
on you. And everybody would laugh.
Now the second that damn thinks up.
Are you Renee?
Gay, Gay, gay, gay, gay, gay,
gay, gay. All these fucking
kids run out on the court.
I'm trying to get drunk
and yell at people that,
I don't know why you
bringing kids into this. Um,
but I was stone sober.
Um, anyways, so we won't.
But either way that the
game was great and um,
okay.
Just seeing the Celtics live, how
young they are. Even I benches.
Great. I've keep forgetting
the name. What's the name
of our, our sort of center,
the big white guy.
He looks like a yoga instructor
that moonlights as a lumberjack.
You know, he's got the man
bun go and see, you know,
we spiritual these progressive
and then he's got the giant beard.
So he can't tell. Is this guy like a
hipster? Is He from the Pacific northwest?
Any in his grandfather used to get on
either end of an accident. Oh Wow. Oh Wow.
Right. You take a fucking tree down,
whatever the hell they did out there. Um,
what's his face?
Rosier had this month's to fucking dunked
towards the end of the game. Explosive.
Something you never used
to see on the Celtics.
We used to be a bunch of slow white guys.
Even our black guys was slow.
Just hanging out with the white
guys sitting and have to try it.
Try as hard and practice and then they,
they sort of became like a, you know,
almost not black anymore.
They were like mixed.
They had a little bit too much
white on them. Next thing you know,
they had developed an outside shot.
This is all true.
This is why we had a tough time
keeping up with the showtime Lakers.
Too many whities all right.
I'm just making up shit.
I don't have any reads this week,
you know?
Okay.
I Dunno. I guess when you, when
you piss off Sherry's berries,
then the dominoes just fall.
No,
I think people just like no
one's going to be listening,
nor is anybody can be podcasting
on fucking Christmas, you know?
And everybody thought that. And here you
are listening and you know else knew it.
Tim Alexander from Primus.
So that's my only read of this week.
Why don't you just sit down and ignore
your family and drink at nice jug of herb
cider.
If you'd like to drink some,
go to www dot [inaudible]
dot com her bs cider.com.
Um, all right, my wife's going
to kill me that I'm part.
There's going to be a shorter
podcast. Unusual. All right,
let's give me an a bridge person. Kids
want to open their gifts here. All right,
let's get to the reeds here.
Comedy bubble. Hey Billy.
Hey Billy burrata toes. I like
that one. I'm speaking of burrata.
I went to the north end and have a lovely,
lovely Italian meal.
I had a little burrata
and the appetizer there.
It was unbelievable that I went down
to a cigar bar. The bunch of relatives.
We smoked a couple.
This is fucking asshole.
I always go to that cigar
bar in the north end
and I always forget the name of it.
It's an Italian name.
The fuck is the name of it's Segarra is,
is the last thing,
let's see,
it's a garb are north and Boston.
What does it stands at?
Delsa Gary.
Oh, DC Gari. Um,
what'd they were having
a great frigging time.
And for some reason they have this bell.
They're like,
you would ring between rounds and
this fucking jerk off Boston guy.
He's got this hammer and he keeps hitting
the bell and I'm watching this dude in
this bowl and shard coming over,
you know,
with the Boston angry face with
his eyebrows up going, hey buddy,
knock it off. Stop
ringing the bell. Right.
And the kid keeps ringing
the bell and like, like, what
the fuck is with this kid?
And then I peeked over and I saw you had
like the earring in his ear. I'm like,
oh, that guy. Oh, that guy,
he's going to be that guy.
And the guy just would not stop ringing
in the fucking belt by appreciated the
fact that the fucking, the one dude
was trying to get them to stop.
But then the other dude,
they,
with the man bun in the fucking beard
kept laughing, thinking it was funny.
And I was like, right
there. There you go. That's,
there's the generation gap right there.
The millennial kid thinks it's funny.
The other dude, it was also kind of
young, but probably had an angry dad.
Did not think it was funny. So I
was rooting for him, but either way,
I had a great time and
I want to thank them.
They always treat me great when I go in
there. Um, cigars wasn't were amazing. Um,
that's sort of a tradition.
I always end up there at least one night,
if not seven. All right. Comedy
bubble. Hey Billy Baratos,
huge fan from Pakistan.
Saw you at the Atlanta punchline a
few months ago and it was amazing.
Thank you very much.
Recently I've noticed some as established
comedians on social media shitting on
open micros and newer comedians
for trying their luck at comedy.
Okay.
Yeah, that's not nobody
funny. He was doing that.
I get that there are a lot of comedians
around now and comedy in general is very
trendy, especially with Netflix
releasing a special every week this year.
But is it fair to say there
is a comedy bubble now?
Is it even worth it for an aspiring or
up and coming comic to try their hand at
it? Wanted to get your
take on this uh, love you.
Stand up the podcast and episode
family. Thanks and go love yourself. Um,
I'll at that for the holidays.
Great. Great. Great question.
Alright.
Um,
standup comedy is always
going through some sort of a
up or down as, as any business. Do
you know what I mean? Look at the NBA.
The NBA was through the roof,
popular, right to the Jordan
era. Then it made a dip,
but now it's starting to come back
and then Lebron and all those guys,
it brings it back up and
down, up and down. NFLS on a
little dip here. Tom Brady,
towards the end of his career, Peyton
Manning's gone. Andrew loves, heard Aaron.
Roger gets hard parity and all that.
They got to figure it out.
There's always ups and downs,
but that doesn't mean you
shouldn't go after your dream.
I started comedy March 2nd,
1992 after the big eighties,
bubbles burst and there was
a bunch of, uh, not a bunch,
but there was a number of older comics.
Okay.
Um,
when I started out,
that tried to discourage me from starting
none of the funny ones and they go
look at it so that it's crass.
It's plays like half full. Yeah.
It's like a two years ago there'd
be a line around the block.
He's lying around in the mud,
you know,
and they used to get me all
depressed in that type of stuff. Um,
any established comedians that shits on
an open miker and tries to discourage
them is not even worth your time.
But how pathetic is that?
What else are you going to do?
You're going to make fun of a
toddler learning how to walk.
Do you just give her a bath? Oh, um,
all right.
I need to get off this
because she's getting more
annoyed by the second that I'm
out here. What it was my Christmas
too. I enjoy podcasting. Um, yeah.
Okay.
Those people are not even worth your time.
And is there a comedy bubble
right now? Uh, yeah, absolutely.
You put out 50 to one network,
put out 52 hour long specials in a year.
You can't, you can't do that. It stops
being special. It becomes like all like a,
like a fucking logjam and you know,
you need to have space. It has
to breathe. It's like a song.
You can't have everybody doing
a tap on solo at the same time.
It just becomes noise. Um, but yeah,
know this is the,
uh,
I think it's gone up twice since I've
been doing it. You know, it, it dip, dip,
dip, dip, dip a bit, bit, bit peppy,
peppy, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
All in the beginning of my
first eight years of my career.
And then after nine 11, it went
up, it went up, it went up,
it went up and then it started to
come back down again. And then,
uh,
okay.
The ability for Comedians to shoot
their own specials and sell them,
made it go up, up, up, up, up, up, up,
up, up. And I would think that the,
the peak of this, it's like a
housing bubble was standup specials.
That one network has 52 of them.
But the thing about Netflix
is it's also global,
so it's not like,
mmm,
they're just doing it for
the United States, you know,
which would be insane if you
just did that for one country.
It's for everybody around the world.
So maybe that levels it out. I mean,
from what I've heard from Netflix,
they gonna try to have more
of an international flavor
next year when they do
it. I have no idea. I have no
idea. But I don't see that's,
it's beyond my control.
I'm not the one who decides,
nor should I be how much so many
specials get put out there or whatever.
But it's not going to discourage me
from trying to write my best hour.
MMM.
But it's definitely making me think about
how to release and when to release my
next one.
MMM.
Yeah. I hope I answered your question,
but dude, if you want to do stand up,
you got to do it. It's the
greatest fucking job ever.
If you're good at it. If not,
it's uh, you know, I'll tell you
it's a rough one. Okay. But yeah,
don't ever listen to any fucking ass.
Don't listen. Anybody in general,
whatever business you're in,
somebody's discourages you.
What kind of an asshole does that?
Hey, I want to do this. Ah, yeah,
I dunno why he want to do
that. Bad. I mean, lets you
talking about trying heroin,
you know,
other than that,
I think I want to start my own
business book be going to go under.
It's actually,
I will tell you,
it's actually good that
somebody is doing that to you,
that you're getting that this early in
this business because the key to success
is tuning those people out.
Okay.
And,
and being around positive people that say
things that make you feel better about
what you're going after.
Now,
I'm not saying that at some point
you won't have an idea that is,
you know, you need to think about again.
You know what I mean? So somebody be like,
hey man, you might want to watch out
because of blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I'm not saying that a negative response.
It's not even negative
constructive criticism.
There's always gotta be a place for that.
But you can't have people who are just
being negative just because you're going
out and doing something and you'll be able
to tell the difference. All right, Nia,
I'm almost done. No response. All right.
Rush, reaction video. Hey
there, Billy. Five, four time.
Love you. Love Nia. Love your freaking
podcast. And I thought you'd love this.
These guys review albums and apparently
listeners ask them to do a video on
Russia's Yyz.
They do a lot of rap albums,
but have reviewed metal bands.
Like I can't say that's Sepultura.
It's really fun listening to them. React
to the drumming and the guitar changes.
Merry Christmas. You beautiful
bastard. I actually, uh,
I didn't get to see this video until you,
uh, till right before I started this.
And as you can see, tensions are
building with my Christmas here. Um,
I watched a little bit of a,
um,
I'm definitely gonna Watch the whole
thing was cool to see that they liked it.
I knew that they're going to be like,
what the fuck is this? In the beginning,
as I mentioned before,
that's why y z is the, uh,
the call letters for Toronto
International Airport and,
and Yyz as the Morse code,
uh,
[inaudible] that, that,
that, uh, that, that,
that they're playing the Morse code of
y, Y, z. It's one of their, one of them.
And the band was flying a plane and they
heard it and they thought it sounded
cool, so they put it to music. Um,
there you go. That's what that is.
Anyways. So it's funny watching them,
listening to this shift going, yeah,
they haven't dropped into the groove yet,
which basically means it's not in yet.
Essentially for a lot of people,
if that's all you listen to. All
right, original six and nonsense.
Hi Bill. I want to know what your
thoughts are on the original six.
I call it the original,
who gives a fuck. Ah,
this sounds like somebody doesn't
have an original six team.
No other sports hold clubs
up on a pedestal above the
rest of the teams in the
league.
It's like all the other clubs in the NHL
are less than because they weren't from
the beginning. As it ducks fan now, Jesus,
you're not a ducks fan.
You're a mighty ducks. We,
you're named after a
Disney movie. I get it. No,
you can't win enough cups to try and get
some sort of fucking manly vibe on your
team. Um, as a ducks fan. I know you
hate them. I don't hate, I don't.
Uh,
I went out and supported them with
those gay uniforms and gay name.
It was always humiliating playing
the wings or Boston in those
eggplant fucked up green colors with
the cartoon duck on their jersey. Well,
it made sense. It was named
after a kids movie. Uh,
I think we've earned some respect for
going through the shit. You're dead.
You're dead.
TEEMU Salani and had all those
guys then angry bastard from uh,
what is, what is it from a Vancouver you
have down there, the hell's his name,
Ryan or some shit. Um,
cartoon duck and the Jersey.
I think we've earned some respect for
going through the, that shit. I was like,
it was like wearing a dress
to a biker bar. Every game.
I can't stand every time we
play the leafs or Montreal,
they always mentioned the
original six bullshit. Anyways,
I wanted to know what your take
is on the original six. Um,
well I love sports history,
so I like it.
And even if I didn't have a team
that was in the original six,
I like the expansion six.
Uh,
let's see if I can still name them.
That's the fly is
the penguins.
Oh boy.
The California Golden
Seals to St Louis Blues.
Nice to be able to rattle this off.
Every team has the Minnesota North Stars
and the Los Angeles kings oof by the
skin of my teeth. I did that. And
then for those who don't know,
the California Golden Seals move to
Cleveland became the Cleveland Barons.
And that went under and I believe
merged or something with Minnesota.
I can't remember. I don't remember
any. I used to know all that shit. Um,
I liked the original six. I wish that, uh,
more leagues would talk
about that type of stuff.
MMM.
You know, like the NFL and that
type of stuff. I just think,
I think it's interesting,
personally,
I wish the NFL actually acknowledged
NFL titles the way baseball,
basketball and hockey all count.
They all count titles to the
beginning of their leak. I mean,
the Montreal Canadians, they like,
they won Stanley cups against, uh,
the Montreal maroons in the Stanley Cup.
It was like the size of a shot glass.
I mean, it is the history. It probably
played the final game on a fucking pond.
But I mean,
that is the history of the league.
What I don't understand what the NFL
is,
how the Green Bay packers are
not the Yankees or the NFL there.
He's talking about the Pittsburgh
Steelers because they've,
they've won six Superbowls,
but the Pittsburgh Steelers were around
back in the early days of the NFL and
had an opportunity every year to
win an NFL title and they didn't.
And Green Bay did. And for
some reasons Bay's like, oh,
what are they going to green bay, you got
four titles. So it is four or five, four
for some reason they just
go, oh, they got for their,
the two behind the Steelers and they
have like 11 NFL titles plus four
Superbowl. So my world, they're
up around 1415 whatever it is.
And then you got the fucking
Lakers who count a Ba,
they went some league,
the Ba or something like that.
Okay.
And they want a title there.
They count that as an NBA title.
I mean that's one of the biggest
bullshit stats in fucking sports.
How the hell you win an NBA
title before there's an NBA,
the NFL, like look,
the Nhl, like you know,
when the WHL went down or the Ahl,
Dave absorb teams as did the NBA.
Right.
But it was still the NBA. Right. When
were they absorbed? Like the Aba?
Yeah.
You know,
those Aba teams went into the NBA.
The difference with the Lakers
is the NBA didn't even exist.
There was no NBA. It was like
wrestling before it got unified.
There was a little bullshit league here,
a little bullshit league there
and another bullshit league.
And the Lakers were in one
of those bullshit leagues.
And for some reason they get to count
that bullshit league title as an NBA title
because eventually all the
leagues combined the two
leaks or something combined
and it became a stronger league.
And that was an NBA title,
not your Bullshit League one.
You know,
that's like counting like
when they had the AFL,
like the San Diego chargers claiming that
they won like a fucking Superbowl Isam
Shit because they want to an AFL
title one year. Um, but whatever,
that's what it is. It's very la
to pad your fucking resume. So,
um, for some reason nobody
calls him on it. Um, so I
love, I love the original six.
Um, I think it's cool.
And it's also, you know,
there were more teams
then the depression hit.
And then they went down to six teams. That
was the deal. According to Bart, nick,
the Pittsburgh Penguins were around some
team from Pittsburgh and they had black
and gold. Cause the Bruins always said
the penguins took their colors. Um,
and he goes, no, we had that in the
20s. I the penguin steady. So no,
it was a different team.
It's like, all right,
well then you went belly up and at which
point you forfeit the colors and then
the Bruins gonna back. You don't
get to come back and be like, oh,
we can't do forever.
You don't.
They were already taken your best. It's
a great organization though. All right.
My daughter's boyfriend is
a loser. Oh boy. Dear Billy,
the kid first I want to say that I loved
the first two episodes of emphasis for
family and I can't wait. Oh,
the first two seasons, sorry.
And I can't wait for season three.
Thank you.
I don't like my daughter's boyfriend.
I like how this guy gets right to it
and I want to make or break up with him.
Let me tell you about my girl.
She's 28 years old. She has a job.
She's living in an
apartment with this guy.
The problem is is that she pays for
everything because he's air quote between
jobs and also sometimes she calls me to
fix some stuff for her and when I get
there I find this ass just playing
video games or watching a movie.
Oh my God.
He doesn't even put on a show for when
is the father of his girlfriend shows up.
Yeah, this guy's a bum.
He doesn't do shit.
I really don't understand
why she's still with them.
My greatest fear is if she marries,
she marries that guy.
Can you please give me your opinion
as a father? Oh my God, dude,
I'm brand new to this. You're like
a grizzled vet with a 28 year old.
I got an 11 month old.
I'm going to give you advice.
Can you please give me your opinion as a
father on how to deal with this problem?
Should I tell her to break up with them
or should I just keep my mouth shut?
And I would also love to hear what the
lovely Nia has to say about that switch,
about my situation. Thank
you. Keep up the good work.
Well unfortunately she's a little
pissed at me right now. So, uh,
I only got one more question here.
Um,
I think I probably would have given
him shit when I went over there.
Okay.
I would have just been like,
really?
You're just going to sit there playing
video games while the father of your
girlfriend comes over to this apartment
where she's paying for everything and
you don't even have a job. You just
going to sit there and play video games.
Who raised you?
Okay.
I probably, you know, Nah,
I'm not the smartest guy and I
also fly off the handle a lot.
I would have said something along those
lines and then if he mentioned it to
her, I just say, listen,
I probably shouldn't have said that. I
love you. I want the best for you. And
okay.
You know,
it,
it just as your dad had bothers me
that you're paying for everything.
And then I came over to the
fixed stuff in this guy.
Couldn't even start playing video
games. Um, you know something.
Don't say anything because then
you look like the asshole does.
That was bad advice. All right.
Swing and a miss strike one.
I would say that to her, just say, listen,
I'm going to just going to
say this and just say this.
I'm just going to say this one time.
I have to get this off my chest as your
dad because I love you and I want the
best for.
Okay.
I understand that the person you're with
right now is between jobs and really
tried to
fight the urge to do the giant air
quotes between jobs and just say,
listen, okay, I understand that you know,
people have ups and downs in life,
but
it was just kind of a red flag to me
that I went over to your apartment when
you're paying everything where
there's a man there. All right?
And he sees the father of the woman
that he's dating come walking in to fix
something that he's not fixing.
He didn't even help me.
He continued to play video games. I'm
just saying, I'm a little concerned
about the overall drive of the
man in your life and as men,
we can't give you children. All
right. What we do is provide.
Okay. So, uh,
okay.
He just looked like a giant 12 year
old to me. Don't say that last part,
but just say, I'm just a little concerned.
Are you, do you share those concerns?
And if she says no, just say fair
enough. Maybe I caught him on a bad day,
but just as your father,
I felt like I had to say something.
If you're okay with them, then I'm okay
with them. And then you, then you go,
cause now you put it out there.
All right.
But if he come at her and you just
say, listen, you need to dump this guy,
this guy's a Bombay guys,
I judge Joe,
then she's going to get a
backup and be are, you know,
and it'll become actually more
romantic to her that she's, you know,
it's us against the world, baby. Did you
hear what I said? The kids can be like,
Whoa, oh, sorry. Showing to
get to level seven. Uh, that's
the way I would handle it.
And then after that you just got to
wash if, oh God, that's difficult.
You got to wash your hands of it.
Um,
I dunno if I could do that.
I,
I mean I would just start, uh, at
some point if she stayed with them,
I would just start openly teasing of
cool.
Hey, what do you say? They're
there? They're couch face, huh?
Yeah,
whatever his name is.
Mike. Hey Mike. What's,
what's your favorite couch to sit on
when you're not looking for a job,
you know? Hey Mike, what you, what's your
favorite? What's your favorite movie? No,
let me guess.
Peter Pan,
right when you get to be 12 years old
for the rest of your fucking life.
MMM.
That's what I would just, I
would roast him. I would rose.
You sell progressive, you know. Hey
Mike, what do you want 41 for? Uh,
what do you want for Christmas? You
want an apron? Oh, that's right.
You don't even cook.
How about one of those inflatable donut
thinks that truckers where when they sit
on their ass all day getting hemorrhoids,
uh,
you want to stand up desks
to play your video games on?
I would just, I, yeah, maybe do that. I
would just start roasting him. Alright.
Bulletproof glass. Dear
Billy. Bullet head, uh,
writing to you from the great city
of Philadelphia. A brief background.
I am Korean. Oh Dude. I was just watching
a great movie last night on Netflix,
a home of 50 to standup specials
this year, including one from me, um,
called, uh, I think it was
called Big Bang. It was called.
It was about the guy just taste movie
starts. His wife's just like, yeah,
I'm fucking out of here.
And he's a really nice guy.
And he never breaks the rules
and he just sort of snaps, uh,
was watching the beginning of it.
A really good acting shot really well.
MMM.
I'm going to start what I'm trying to
fuck with my, uh, my main page here.
You know,
I'd like more shit on music and I
would like a wider variety of music of,
of uh,
movies rather than just the American
bullshit that I already know is out there.
And it probably already
saw what is killing me is
that Ryan Gosling movie and
the dude from fucking, um,
the gladiator,
20 odd foot of grunt lead singer there.
What the fuck's his name? The guy threw
the phone at the person downstairs,
which is one of my favorite stories ever.
He shouldn't have done it,
but I just can't imagine the satisfaction.
You're not helping me with the phone.
I'm not going to bring the device.
You're not helping me with it.
I'm going to throw it at the person that
didn't help me. It's all wrong, but like,
it's so right on so many
levels. Um, Russell Crowe,
the Nice guys too. One of my favorite
fucking comedies of the last few years.
A sort of a modern day midnight run.
I love it, but it's not on Netflix.
Some hoping it's going to get on
this soon. All right, dear Billy,
bullet head writing to you from the
great city of Philadelphia. Philly.
A brief background. I am Korean and
my father owns two convenience stores.
Both started by,
okay.
Grandfather and grandmother in the
mid Seventies. God am I that old,
but your grandparents started businesses
in the 70s and I was alive and wow.
Already watching football
and collecting cards. Okay.
They worked their asses off to provide for
their family. That's right. Old School.
I love it. And make sure my dad
and brothers had a good life. Uh,
one of the stores is in a very bad part
of town and in the mid eighties while
working, my grandfather was
shot at and robbed. Oh No.
The Bolo went over his head
and missed his head by inches.
This wasn't the first time
he'd been robbed at gunpoint,
but the first time you've been shot at
this obviously scared the shit out of my
grandmother. And eventually they
installed a bulletproof window.
Since installing it,
they've had zero robberies and my
grandmother's sleeps a bit better.
My grandfather is 78 looks 55 and still
works four days a week. I love this guy.
Uh, just this week a law passed saying
that bulletproof glass is illegal.
The reason a city council woman said
that it made customers feel uncomfortable
and pass legislation to make them illegal.
What is going on in this country
that has got to be that what fucking
neighborhood does this privileged asshole
live in?
For starters,
it's insanity that they can
dictate something big based
on feelings and emotions
that will have physical
repercussions on the store owners.
Not to mention that if we are taking off,
we're talking about these barriers.
Not to mention that if we're talking
about how these berries affect emotions,
they certainly keep my
family's emotions in check,
worrying about other working in the store,
the woman who passed the law
as a huge content, a grade.
I'm not a social justice warrior at all,
but this woman's legislation is racist.
Yeah, it sounds just like I live
in a safe white neighborhood.
I don't like going in being reminded
that people who don't look like me are
being shot. I mean it just, you know,
I just had a love today. It's also,
it don't,
it's only going to affect the pop,
the mom and Pop Asian and other emergent
grant owned stores and it won't have
any effect on the corporate change who
don't have any family working the counter
and won't feel the financial repercussions
of a robbery. None. The problem is, uh,
she's black and no one has the
balls to call her racist. Oh,
I assumed she was white so I
guess I'm racist. She is though.
She is though.
My question is,
I don't know how she's racist to you
is should I stand outside city hall,
City Hall?
I said silly hall with a sign stating
she's a racist or just a Twat.
Um,
no,
what I would do is I would try to contact
the local news people cause that's a
great story and if you still have the
bullet hole and all that stuff will get
dad on this guy grandfather
almost got killed.
MMM.
Is this Oprah? I mean, who said
this? This is crazy. Uh, she, uh,
Huxtable um,
is that racist for me to assume
that just because she's black,
that she had some point? Must have
lived in a tough neighborhood. Right?
Is that racist on my end or are there
not enough Huxtable black people.
Rapid. So my idea of, of what the
neighborhood's ally. I mean, who knows?
I mean this, this opens a giant can of
worms, but at the end of the fucking day,
I think that, uh, you should be able to,
I think that that should
be not the decision.
Okay.
Of the government. That should be the
decision of the person who got shot at,
are you comfortable with rolling the
dice that the next one also won't hit you
in the head?
MMM.
This is what I would do. I would not
take it down. I wouldn't take it down.
And if they force you to take
it down, I would, that's,
I would make a giant stink about it
is what I would do. And I wouldn't,
don't say she's racist. Don't say
she's a Twat. Don't do any of that.
Just what you want to do is you want
to keep the story about how the,
the bullet missed your grandfather by
inches and I'm much more comfortable,
your grandmother is now with the
bulletproof glass and just say,
and just you killed the, the, you
kill the other person with kindness.
I respect her opinion and blah,
blah blah. But we work here.
She does not work in these stores. Um, you
know, I'm sure she does wonderful work.
He just keep doing that.
And um,
and then,
uh,
I would to think that someone in the
State Department or whatever they are is
going to be looking at this story going,
okay,
now if we take down the bulletproof glass
and God forbid somebody in there and
get shot and killed,
what is the state's going to get sued?
MMM.
I would mention that. Just say, listen,
I'm not trying to cause a problem here,
but like if something happens
to anybody working in my store,
because you know, the bulletproof glass
is taken down, then I am going to hold,
you know,
whatever the,
the state of Pennsylvania or the
city of Philadelphia and that woman's
specifically,
I'm going to hold them responsible.
That has got to be the dumbest
thing I've ever heard of
who installs bulletproof glass.
Who does that?
Places where people
get robbed at gunpoint.
Okay.
Okay. And they still have the balls to
stand there the next day and you know,
so I can walk in to buy a
paper and fucking Kit Kat.
Don't they have the right
to feel comfortable.
Okay.
I mean, yeah, that's, that's,
that's fucked up.
I got to tell you as a white person,
I'm actually psyched that that was finally
not somebody white doing that. Hey,
finally it wasn't us. Um, so that's
the way I would go about that.
I'd kill them with kindness and a,
and then just sort of, you know,
vaguely put it out there. Maybe have a
lawyer down there. Just go on. Like I,
I can't see how this,
the city of Philadelphia would not be
held accountable if something like this
happens. I mean you, you need to
have some sort of stricter gun laws.
We need to solve a whole
bunch of other problems.
But before you have the hardworking,
honest citizens of this great city being
put into this level of peril because it
upsets one person in their mood that
they're reminded that there are bad people
in the world. Okay. Cause would you
have to remember everybody is you,
there's two things you,
this does the way you wish the world is
in the way it really is and you have to
act accordingly. All right. And that's
it. Merry Christmas. Happy New Year.
I'll check in on you on Thursday and a
hope you guys all have a great Christmas
hung out, but I don't know it was,
Hanukkah is still going. Yeah.
How many days are in Hanukkah?
I Dunno. I have no idea.
So now on the ninth day of Hanukkah,
my true love gave to me a kwanza.
Whenever that is,
I don't pretend to know. I don't
pretend to be informed. Okay.
But I hope all of you enjoy
your day. All right. That's it.
Okay. And if he got a gun,
leave it at home. Just going
to buy a fucking candy bar.
You content. All right, I'll,
I'll see you on Thursday.