Hey,
what's going on is bill burns time for
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
June 11th, 2018 what's
going on? How are you?
How's everybody doing?
I'm a fucking old man.
It's 50 year old.
Oh,
I remember when podcasting started back
in 2005 I just wanted to throw that out
there cause I know there's going to be
a bunch of fucking podcast people going.
It's been in Japan since 1968 and I
stood my poor care seats for use before
using [inaudible] steel.
We're mind is you get these many,
many kids as you wish judge on who
gives a fuck.com I actually look at the
numbers every week
and I feel that my podcast [inaudible]
you and change it. I'm, I'm providing
computer. We shut the
fuck up. I love people.
Look at their fucking podcast numbers.
If you noticed,
everybody seems to be in the type town,
everybody,
you know it's like five talked
about this before. It's like a,
it's like back when I
used to do college gigs,
every college I went to
somehow they figured out a
way to fudge the numbers that
they were number one in something.
You know the number one a
fucking school for mathematics,
the number one school for engineering's
doesn't that have mathematics and it,
I don't know.
Right.
And then we're just so you get down to
a community college and they'd be the,
the number one community
college, uh, you know,
with fucking the best deal with
triple a or some shit. I don't know.
Some other were number one or something.
You got to hang your hat on something.
If you're a college to try
and get people to go there.
If I, if I was a dean, did they have
deans at like community colleges?
I would just,
I would go on fucking TV and say,
listen,
why the fuck would you go for years
when you can only pay two years?
You know, you want to go to
Harvard, fine. All you have to go,
it's your junior and senior year.
Go your freshman and sophomore
year over us over us.
We are number one in being fucking
10 times less per year than Harvard.
You got the grades, you know
you're in. Come on down.
Teach us dummies,
my dumb students,
how to wear fucking
loafers with those socks,
whatever the fuck it
is you smart people do,
do your freshman and sophomore
year here translate, translate,
fucking transfer over to
Harvard and there you go.
And you can graduate from Harvard
wide, a dad, Yardi, judge, [inaudible],
JJ or whatever they're fucking
school song is what is this school?
So my dad is rich and AH,
did real bad in school
but he has money. So, um,
for gain here. Now let's say that's the
stereotype. That's not true. I knew,
I knew a I one kid in my high school,
he got into Harvard and he did it with
fucking grades and no social life.
He made the sacrifice. The rest of
us didn't want to do it. You know,
like that little fable there with the
fucking ants saving all the food and the
other animals like,
hey man,
I'm just jumping around and having
a good bucket time. You know,
you know who wrote that story?
I bet somebody who couldn't fucking,
who was really socially
awkward at a party.
So he was looking at the fucking,
was it a rabbit tortoise and the hare?
That's not the story. I don't know
what it is, but it's, you know,
you know people who are outgoing,
they get fucking annoyed
by people who are outgoing,
who are out there having a good time,
talking some shit, hooking up, right.
Singing songs.
They in the life of the party,
they stand on the side and the
fucking wall and they write scripts,
you know, so that's why now I don't know
what the fuck happened back in the day.
Used to have cool people and movies.
Now it'd be cool.
Person has this underlying insecurity
that they're trying to overcompensate for.
That's all right or shit, I
think, you know what I mean?
Some people just are
the life of the party.
So anyways,
now that I'm a senior citizen,
I banged out 54 pushups on my birthday,
a boy,
and then immediately just
fucking collapsed onto the
cap it and was like out of
breath. Like, I ran 54 flights of
stairs, but I did it, man. I did it.
I don't know what it means.
It's still means I'm 50,
but it made me feel pretty
good about myself. Um,
I had a great birthday. I want
to thank my lovely wife. Um,
she surprised me with tickets
to the French Open, Roland Gals,
Valenzuela Tulay mooned
um,
we fucking, we went there
and I got to see, uh,
what the fucks his is his name that he's
the only one left. He just won his 11th
Raphael Nay Dow. That's right. I'm
not the biggest fucking tennis guy.
And I knew that he had won
this thing a couple of times.
I didn't realize he'd already
won the fucking French Open.
He had already won it 10 times
and I saw him when his 11th.
And what's really interesting is that guy,
um,
he wanted oh five oh six, oh seven oh
eight and then federal one oh nine.
Then he went in in 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14.
So he wanted four years in a row,
Mr Year.
And then when it five years in a
row and then two years, 15 and 16,
he didn't win it. So people probably
all thought, all right, his run is over.
He's one of the greats of
all time, but now that he's
older, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And he fucking comes back last year
and this year to go back to back again,
winning 11 and I was talking
to somebody last night,
we were trying to say how, what, how,
what do you compare that
to in a different sport?
You know,
you can't really say it's like winning
an NBA championship because there's only
one of those where with tennis majors,
this is for,
so it's like they have
four sort of super bowls.
So we kind of said,
I guess you'd have to go to golf,
compare it to golfers were,
um,
you know, there's four majors in
that sport. I don't fucking know.
It was kind of saying, well, maybe it's
like Lebron going to the NBA finals eight,
nine years in a row.
And it's like, well, no,
because this guy actually won the thing.
Um,
I can't believe people give
Lebron's shit after losing to, they,
people forget so quickly.
You know how ridiculous it was that Kevin
Durant went to the warriors and then
the, you know, and then he wins a
championship. People like, what the fuck?
And then you just kind of say, oh,
this is how it is. It's just how it is.
Like when they first put a little fucking
TVs in the back of a cab and people
like get these things the fuck out
of there, then making me car sick,
then I got high and then later on
they just put them back in and get,
and nobody said, Oh yeah,
I guess this is just how,
I guess this is just how it is.
Right.
Um, all right. Uh,
I dunno what the fuck I was going with
that tennis golf major shit. But I mean,
just the fact that this guy won 11 in
a row and I basically got to see on my
birthday the greatest,
um,
I guess you'd have to say the greatest
player ever on clay. I got to see him.
I got to see the fucking Wayne Gretzky,
the Bobby will, uh, uh, tennis and uh,
he was playing this other kid and he
broke him his first game of both sets and
the kid had a bunch of unforced
errors and uh, you know,
you could see he kept back to the guy
lost it seemed like he was a kid and he
just had to go there, experience it, lose,
make a bunch of unforced errors for
the next time when he comes back.
And in the end right, an English dude
comes out of won the French Open.
Uh, I dunno that from the way he was
talking, it was like late fifties,
early sixties.
And he came out to say a bunch of great
shit about Raphael and they doubt.
And then when he talked about the other
kid, he was just like, go and, you know,
we would have liked to see more.
We would like to say more tennis said.
I'm sure he's a little disappointed in
his game today as with the rest of us.
And everybody's just sitting
there going like, dude,
you didn't need to fucking say that.
I couldn't tell if the guy was nervous.
He just sort of talked himself into
a corner and he meant to say, um,
he has nothing to be disappointed about.
I don't know what I'm trying to
give them the benefit of the doubt,
but everyone's just kind of sitting
there like, Eh, I kind of, uh,
kind put a fucking damper on things
[inaudible] done here. Right. Sorry,
I've got the bootleg recorded here,
um, which I have on my stomach too.
So if you start hearing
grumbling, I apologize. Um,
anyways, um, I was able to watch
gang,
uh,
was it game three of the NBA finals
when I was in London at about two in the
morning, I was able to watch and
I was able to watch, oh my God,
the fucking Washington capitals.
Okay.
Win The Stanley Cup through Josh.
Adam Meyers.
Cause I couldn't get it on my phone cause
I couldn't remember my password from
fucking, um, you know, my cable company.
I could have just gone on to NBC sports
and just sat there and watched it.
But my, my daughter and my
wife were sleeping so I was
laying a bed. What in bed?
Wide awake with the lights out.
Yeah,
just hitting refresh on my phone,
looking at the score.
And uh, when there was a few minutes
left, I text Josh Adam Meyers and he goes,
dude,
he goes for fuck it.
He was the one to tell me he
was just going to NBC sports.
And of course it didn't work out for me
cause I knew my password. And he goes,
well call me up. I'll answer my computer,
I'll facetime and Assam Shit. So I said,
all right,
but here's the thing,
I'm going to be in the dark and
I can't say anything because my,
okay,
my daughter's sleeping in the same room
and everything, so he goes, all right,
call me.
So I snuck into the bathroom light still
out because the only way to turn on the
lights in that fucking hotel room was
I had to have the bathroom door open,
which would have woke my kid up.
Some sitting in there,
they're like a dark in the dark,
like a creep.
The only thing that's lighting
me up is off of my fucking phone.
It looked like a horror movie and Josh
was just laughing at me and he's like,
can you see it? Can you see
that? Just put my pasty white,
the hand up to the screen,
given the thumbs up.
And I actually watched the final
three minutes of the Stanley Cup. Um,
and I have to tell you, uh, this
guy on the Internet put it best.
He said in talking about Alexander
Ovechkin, he goes, I don't,
can't remember the last time I was
this happy for a complete stranger. Um,
that was watching the capital's when
was everything that you fucking watch
sports for? It's everything
that I love about sports and um,
okay.
You know, anybody that says, you know,
Russian players don't give a
shit about the Stanley Cup.
Just all they need to do is just watch
him walking around with that thing in
Vegas.
And how cool is it?
Like they actually know it would have
been great if they want it at home,
obviously.
But like if you got a win it on the road,
Las Vegas has to be the place she wants
to be if you're going to go party. Right.
And,
um,
I say it every year at the Stanley Cup
is the greatest fucking championship
trophy and all this forge
simply because there's only one.
And you grew up as a kid watching all
your heroes hoisting that thing up.
And when you're in the
million to one odds,
whatever the fuck it is that you actually
win it. When you hoist that thing up,
you're holding the same cup. You
know, Maurice was Shard Gordie Howe,
Bobby or Wayne Gretzky,
Mark Messy, a Mario Lemieux,
all of these greats,
the same fucking cup
Eisenman all of those guys.
And you hoist that fucking thing
up, said, daddy know Ciara twice.
I had to throw one, the Braun in there.
Um, it's the coolest fucking thing ever,
you know, however, I
would not drink out of it.
I can tell you that right now because
there's been enough guys who've, uh,
you know, over the years, hockey,
former hockey players that
have told stories about some
of the shit that happens
to the Stanley Cup. Uh, he
goes, yeah, and one of them,
I vaguely remember somebody saying,
I would not drink out of that thing.
Okay.
This stories of strippers sitting in the
top of the fucking thing and bending it
or some shit like that. Um, I dunno.
And then each player gets it for
like a week. It's so fucking crazy,
so crazy.
And then there's this guy that's got to
be a fucking movie about that sometime.
The poor bastard who has to
follow the cup around all years.
Somebody must have done
a documentary on it.
Vaguely remember seeing some shit like
that when you get to follow, you know,
go to fucking a titty bar in Saskatoon,
whatever the fuck the companies
up for the week. Um, but anyways,
congratulations to the Washington
capitols in their first Stanley Cup
championship and, uh,
what is it, 44 years,
45 seasons. Um, and as I tweeted,
one other great thing is,
uh,
NHL has another great
hockey city in Las Vegas.
And after all those years of taking
these cities that just, you know,
there was the initial excitement and
then it just kind of fizzled. Um,
they kind of hit a home run in Nashville
and Los Vegas and I got a feeling that
Seattle is going to be huge just because
those fans are maniacs, you know?
And I'm sure they'll build a stadium
to make him sound even louder.
Okay.
Why
do I always give him shit? You know
why? Because it's fun because it's fun.
Oh, I heard Edelman got
busted for something pds or
something like that. And uh,
now they're going to Wa
he's going to appeal it.
And what I'm going to love about that is
now everybody's going to be like shoe.
That's why they beat
Atlanta and Dah, Dah, Dah,
and all this fucking shit
because they're the patriots.
That's how it works.
You'll just look the other way when 30%
of the Legion of boom tested positive
for fucking steroids. Ah,
that's all right. That's all
right. That's Seattle. And so,
okay. I had pee Dee sent to my house
in my wife's name did for my wife.
She was taking a pop tart out of the
toaster and she hurt her shoulder and she
needed a fucking steroids to get back
in shape again so she could make some
fucking lemon Marangu Pie.
Anyways, um, if I had to guess, you know,
we had that horrific injury and
he's doing the Andy Pettitte thing.
He's fucking trying to get back and he
took some fucking roids and he got caught.
It took something and got caught.
There's a lot I'm thinking. Um,
but I do know when, anytime anybody
seems to appeal these things,
I don't think that they ever had
ever goes back the other way.
But I'm glad that I'm not in the u s
to listen to ESPN and all these fucking
guys now say, Oh yeah, yeah,
they should take away all their titles
because they got caught.
They had a player get caught
doing what a player got caught on.
Every out of bucking team has
done. Um, so anyways, enough, uh,
enough with the sports
shit. I am in Patty. Amen.
Patty and I embalming with my French.
They didn't brush up as enough as I want
it to. And it's making me discouraged,
but I'm hanging in there. I
got my, uh, I got my fucking,
uh, what do you call it?
Rosetta stone and that Shit,
I'll do it when you, when you go to
the fucking French Open, all right?
And you have your ticket, you go in and
you got out of the fucking thing scanned.
And then after he gets scanned, you get
this little fucking, it's like a ticket.
The size of the knee, they putting
your fucking white. But when you,
when you pay for parking, all
right? And then everywhere you go,
you have to take that thing out and they
have to scan it to know where the fuck
you are at all times. You know, I
went into the goddamned gift shop,
bought a little fucking
2018 Roland Garros Mug,
and he goes, I need, you know, let me
scan your ticket. And that's just like,
I wish she just said, no, you're
not scanning my fucking ticket.
I'm paying for that.
So now what does that add?
Does that add to my whole
fucking information online.
He's into drums. He does this,
he drinks too much whisky and he,
he can't lay off of a mug when he's
in some touristy fucking place.
Now I'm going to get all these fucking
ads. Now I'm going to get all these ads,
the in the side when I go to fucking
porno sites and shit about mugs.
He funny if they had, why don't they
have a gift shop on online? Poor porn.
Why [inaudible] we're good food.
Um,
and actually they probably
do. Um, so anyways,
every fucking place you went you had to
keep taking it out and keep taking out
and putting it away, whatever. So
now, finally I'm going, you know,
I bought like a fucking still water in
a crepe for my wife and I had to get the
things scanned.
You know what?
I'm in another country somewhere on my
best behavior. Normally I would be like,
why the fuck do I have to scan this?
But the only reason why I didn't say
this is I didn't know what to say.
Why the fuck do I have to get
this thing scanned, you know,
in French on Francais, right?
So now I go to walk in,
it's five or three franch time and uh,
the match starts at three o'clock,
right?
So we go to go in and guess what I can't
find because they've had to take it out
of my pocket 58 fucking times.
I can't find a ticket.
I need to get into the goddamn match.
But I have that other thing and the
lady's like, I'm starting to see,
or you could not to get into the the,
but it's a doing. I was fucking shit.
I'm just like, are you serious? And then
she got mad at me. She's like, yes, yes.
I had to go all the way the fuck back,
wade through all of these goddamn people.
Then go to customer service.
Oh my God,
the fucking Tourette's that was going
on with me as I walked all the way back
past all of these fucking people. Um, I
got to give it up to the French people.
You know, you guys, you know, you
don't smell as bad as everybody says,
but I will say this when you do holy shit.
Then when we walked out of the stadium,
there was this guy like fucking,
he was probably a good six feet in
front of me and I said, Jesus Christ,
we actually made, he went left down the
stairs. After one flight, I went right.
And I tried to get away
from the guy I said,
and I had my shirt up over my nose so bad.
This guy smelled. I said to me, I could,
she's Christ. This guy smells like he
fucking played. How do you smell that bad?
Sitting,
watching people working out.
Maybe Casey was walking down the
stairs fast. Who's creating a breeze?
And it was passing through his
fucking French armpits. But Holy Shit.
Did that guy stick?
Not as bad as a homeless guy, but
like he smelled like he, you know,
freshly homeless, good.
Three, four days, you know,
maybe a tornado hit his fucking house and
Fema hadn't come over to help them get,
that's what this fucking guy
smelled like sitting, you know?
Okay.
And tennis is a really snobby
fucking rich person's sport,
especially down below, you know,
up top, it's a bunch of animals.
That's what we was sitting
in at the ever go. Uh,
we got front row in the upper deck,
get the second row upper deck because
front row they had this glass thing.
But you know, they chill
partition that you look through.
But on top of it they have this solid
thing that all holds it together.
And I was like, in America, this
would have been clear plastic.
So I had to look over and duck under it,
the whole fucking match,
which was still fine.
Um,
okay.
So anyways, but down low is
where all the fucking, you know,
the coaches are the super fucking rich
people and they go there and like fucking
outfits and they're big dumb
hats and all of that shit.
But all the animals were up top,
you know,
doing the wave and shit when nay dal had
some problem going on with his hand or
his arm. I don't know what
the fuck happened. And um,
but anyways, I always, it was,
it was an amazing fucking time.
So I had to go all the way
back and I got the ticket.
Then I came walking up and I,
you know,
after all that flipping out and
all of that fucking bullshit,
I still made it in the time
to see the match as always.
99% of the time I flip out
later on if there's a solution,
whatever I thought was going
to happen because he didn't,
convenience never
fucking happens. And, um,
I thought it was going to leave
all of that behind in my forties,
but evidently it's to continue. I started
strong the day I turned 50. It fucking,
it just continued on. So, um,
I'm going to rent a fucking bicycle
today and I'm going to ride around Paris
when my, uh, my daughter goes to
sleep and we just been having the, uh,
the best time here.
As always,
I'm going to take a well deserved
fucking little vacation here.
And,
um,
the hardest thing for me on vacation
is not to just playing a bunch of shit
every day. Um, you know,
and then it just becomes a
thrash. It's funny, like we, uh,
we drove by,
was it the Notre dam or some shit like
that and the guy driving us was going to
go, so you know, it's beautiful.
You got to go in there and Blah Blah and
I sweat it. I'm just not into that shit.
Those old churches and stuff. You walk in
and I just look around. It's just like,
yeah, you guys, you guys really decorated
the shit out of this place, didn't you?
You a no negative space in here.
It's all just filled up
with the most Gadi um,
you know, you don't think that,
you know, I like the Migos dress.
That's like the Church version of that
where you just can't have enough fucking
precious stones and or
like how those, you know,
the new thing where you get a Lamborghini,
then you do the fucking shiny wrap
that you put around it. That's like,
it wasn't enough that it was
a fucking Lamborghini. Those
old churches, it's like,
it's not enough that you have
90 foot fucking ceilings.
All right.
Then you got to have a bunch of sad
broken hearted people painted up there in
like real gold
and all of this crazy hocus pocus shit up.
They're like,
I don't have any desire to
do that, but um, you know,
if there's no line, I'll poke my
head in and be like, wow, wow,
this old church looks exactly like
every other old church. It's creepy.
I feel like I'm going to
catch tuberculosis because
it's cold and damp in here.
And uh,
the vibe in here is not the
vibe where good things happen.
So I'm going to leave now. Um, yeah.
So I'm going to, uh, I'm going to
fucking ride my bike around today. Uh,
like the big fucking Nancy boy that
I am maybe burn a few calories. Um,
I brought my little exercise
bands over here cause I'm old. Uh,
my shoulder feels fucking great.
Uh,
but I got a problem with my
fucking left foot. You know,
it's just always something. It's always
something. I'm an old, well not old
people. I'm 50. How the
fuck did that happen?
You know,
it's actually going to be kind to be
honest with six kind of a cool age to turn
in a lot of ways.
You know,
God knows I had a bunch of friends
that didn't make it this far.
So how the can I sit here and bitch and
I like a nice round number, you know,
30 sucked. 40 was like
Whoa, 50 has been cool. Um,
but I'll tell you 60 is going to crush me.
You know what's great about fifth? You
can lie to yourself through your forties.
I'm a young 40 something and blow blow 50
it's like not dude, you're fucking old.
So I am old and a I'm going to embrace it.
Maybe I'll start dressing a
little more dapper on stage,
giving myself a little pocket
square, hanging out of my
button down. Um, all right,
let's read a little bit of
advertising here. Oh look who's here.
These guys have been with me since
my 40 style is shave club, dude.
Few ever fucking shower or brush your
teeth or trying to make your hair look
presentable. I do most of those two.
What a 300 bed.
Here's some good news.
Dollar Shave Club has a lot of self bought
of stuff to help you out to all shape
club. Yes. That's dollar shave club
delivers everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best. You name
it. They got it. Shampoo. Got It.
Conditioner check. Bodywash. I said
we got everything. Toothpaste, hair,
Gel, even a wipe that will leave
your touch. Failing Tingley clean.
It's sort of the poor man's Butt Day.
You'll be a big fan of their amber and
lavender calming body cleanser after you
try it the first time.
Does that really work?
I wish I had some of that yesterday when
I couldn't find my tickets at a tennis
match. They should just have that in a
mess for someone angry bald shithead,
like make shows up and they just hit
me with the fucking amber and lavender.
We got an amber situation
over here. Amber alert, right?
Lavender, Louis, uh,
good luck finding a product
that's that great at the store.
All of dollar shave club's products are
made with top shelf ingredients that
won't break your budget.
You feel the difference.
Plus shipping is included
in your membership and is
a great way to try a bunch
of dollar shave club products,
but just five bucks you can get their
daily essential essential starter set.
It comes with a body cleanser,
one white shy,
they're amazing, but wipes.
They're world famous,
shaved butter and their best razor,
the six blade executive,
uh, and add in shampoo.
Oh executive, sorry.
Keep the blades coming for people.
More bucks a month and add in shampoo,
toothpaste or anything else you need.
Speaking of the next
month for a limited time,
only use the code [inaudible] at checkout
to get $5 off your second month of the
club. That's cold. Berbee you are,
are a dollar shave club.com to
save $5 on your second month.
Join the club today. Um, all right.
Couple more movement watches.
MVMT [inaudible] spring is right around
the corner. I think it is spring.
I think summer's right around the
corner and movement is dropping all new
sunglasses or a,
what does that Lou nets.
So now you say that Lunette.
So lay to get your,
to get you ready for the warmer weather.
Um,
okay.
Talk about individual styles and events
you have coming up that you want to look
good in shades for.
Uh,
or the next sporting event that I'm
going to as a 24 hours Le Mans and when I
inevitably lose my ticket,
yeah,
I would like to have some lavender,
miss a nice movement,
watch a pair of aviators and uh,
one wipe Charlie and then maybe I'll
be able to keep my cool over there.
Uh,
we just go,
what the fuck talk about individually
then it's just shades of a blah.
We just go to our goto
shades for who's we?
Why are they always doing this? If you
want the shit that they're selling, just,
you know,
for the goto shades that the guys,
that movement don't just make
great watches. Hello Nini. Hello.
Thank you for an awesome birthday.
Yay.
Thank you for the day.
After your birthday to you.
Happy Day every year of growth day to you.
Every day at New Year's Day,
the baby,
I'd be day after your birthday to you.
Yay. I tell you like I just pick the
one thing like I was in, was it Ron Dmc?
Is that how they used to do it? Sure.
I'd finish your sentence. Right.
You want to come up with a rap right now?
I wanna you supposed to say baguette.
Baguette. Okay. That's it.
That's the end of the rap. Um,
you didn't feel my flow there I was,
that's me rapping
is saying no. Jay Z scared
right now. We just go to it.
Just go to our shades for it. All the guys
that movement Pena, the guys that move,
but they just say,
just don't make great watches.
If you thought that was the
only good thing they did,
they also make awesome
sunglasses or Lunette Sunraysia.
So soy,
eggs,
ole solo and just reached a ton of
new styles. Are Friends that movement.
Yeah. To watch guys. They kind of felt
the same way. So they thought screw it.
Who they were feeling Sassy that
day. Sure. They didn't say fucking,
how about we make quality trendy
sunglasses at a fair price?
Why is screw it in quotes?
I think that's cause they said fuck it,
these things aren't plastic.
They acetate Acetate as,
oh they're acetate. Yeah,
I thought it was mine. Uh,
you can get them polarized and
they start at just $70 and acetate.
Acetate,
acetate
are seriously,
that's when you go to look it up to see
how you say these are seriously my goto
shades.
Talk about movements.
Various can these fucking assholes,
right?
The copy talk about varied
selections and styles.
Well there's aviators. There's
the one Tom Cruise war in, in uh,
was it losing in a risky business?
Why are you blaming them
with a bad that you can read?
There's nothing wrong with
this car bay when he talked.
I know they're not there
isn't talk about movements,
various selections and style.
Uh,
they keep doing that.
Okay.
I know I can't read talking about how
awesome we are talking about Mvmt is
various saves lives and in styles.
Finding the perfect parent, you know,
widely with free shipping and free
returns. I liked it. I like your ring.
I like that way and make it, I liked that
root cause then I don't have to do it.
Talk about movements.
Very selections and Style Week Matt Black
to really fun retro round shades and
how finding the perfect parents for free
with free shipping and free returns.
So you can't do it. Yeah, that
was good. That was good. Okay.
These are high quality premium Acetate,
Acetate, acetate frames,
no cheap plastic here.
You got to see these. They have lots of
styles to choose from. Classic, Trendy,
round 88.
A mirrored polarized for him and her.
They just talked about it.
You talk about it and show stuff.
You talk about it and tell
me what to talk about.
You're sure to find the perfect pair.
Uh,
get 15% off today with free shipping
and free returns by going to [inaudible]
dot com slash burr.
That's mvmt.com/bird joined the movement.
Nia,
did you have fun at the tennis
match yesterday? I know it was.
I know it was really hot.
How bad did that guy smell when we left
knee? There's think. Oh, all
right. You call me. Stinko. Um,
let me just read,
you said that was one smelly
motherfucker number. We,
we shot down the other stairs only
to meet him again down the bottom.
Um, stamps.com the u s postal service
is an important tool for any business.
stamps.com is the easiest way to access
all the amazing services of the post
office.
stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for letters or
packages at your own convenience. 24,
seven print postage for any male
class right from your own computer.
The exact amount of postage every time.
Never owned a payer. Overpay again.
I just mailed all of my
posters to Dublin and uh,
to London using stamps.com
it was very easy. However,
I mailed to many to Dublin.
It was an 8,000 Cedar. I was like,
what? What should I send there?
Like 500 stupid.
The magic number is 200.
There's 200 people, you'll sell 200. If
there's 200,000, you'll sell 200. I don't,
I can't understand it. So, uh,
by the way, people who the,
uh, the poster that I have,
it's only available at my shows because
I tried to sell stuff online and then I
have to fucking sit there and deal
with like I'm not from Swat, Hulu, um,
from Swahili. I didn't get my
fucking poster and then you know,
half the time people give you the
wrong God damn address and say,
what am I Amazon movie even not really.
Yeah.
That's a language to Safway.
I'm only pointing that I wish she just
stopped. That's a language that was great.
You just shut me down. I am just wearing
out because my name is Swahili, so,
okay. You don't leave. This whole
podcast is about, you know, is it,
can you make a Swahili dish? It's not
as where he leads as the language. Well,
I can make a French dish.
Okay. That's a language French.
It's also addressing,
I can mail any letter.
It's also a kiss.
It's all sort of type of fry.
What do you guys,
anything else?
It's also a, what is that old school?
They're your friends tech low.
Oh, it's also a tickler. It's also a
cuff on your shirt. You know I had,
this is good cause they just finished
watching Kanye west side family feuds.
I feel like I'm answering
family feud right now.
He was on town promoting his new album.
Now saying that he loves
Donald Trump and now, right.
Well that was controversial. What are
you going to new album or something?
Um, I think babies should be
illegal. Here's my new album.
Oh that sounds pretty catchy.
I use stamps.com I already did
all this and right now you too.
Can you enjoy the stamps.com service with
the special offer that includes a four
week trial plus postage
and a digital scale.
Go to stamps.com click on the microphone
up@thehomepageandtaperedboroughthatstamps.com
enter
burr.
Oh right near me. It's, you know what?
I love being here in Paris neither.
Whenever I see your beauty in Paris, I
always think when the moon hits your eye,
like a big pizza pie,
that's a tallier.
Why would I be seeing that here?
What's a good French song for Raj?
You have a classically beautiful place.
I've always told to you,
it's your cheek bones.
That's where the light hits.
When you go to look to the left,
it's the rate in the rate lit restaurant.
And I'm just like, there
it is. We had agreed,
that's how I ended the freedom of my
single life. But we had an awesome time.
Less so fun.
We ended up meeting up with friends who
ran into a friend at the royal and gals.
Uh Oh that was so fucking random.
So random.
There's about a hundred gift shops at
the Roland Garros and we just happened to
run into, but we went into the bad one.
The one that everybody goes into this.
Yeah, you want to go to the boutique
boutique once there's an Adidas store.
I saw that on the way out, but I
was trying to beat the crowd. Oh,
how funny was that?
We're like,
we gotta get away from the crowds
so we can get a fucking Uber and,
and I went right when everybody
else went left just to, you know,
get a few blocks over to, gives
somebody a chance. And, you know,
all the streets are blocked off.
And we ended up going from Roland
Garros and just walked past,
I thought it was a parking garage.
It was another stadium.
And I looked at soccer magic.
Yeah. It was like, oh fuck.
And then next door was another
soccer stadium. I'm like,
why the fuck this is like
stadium row over here. Um,
and of course we call the Uber and the
guy couldn't come down the street and it
just was a whatever it was. Yes, we did.
We went out to dinner and had a lovely
dinner and then we ended up meeting up
with the friends that we ran into at
Roland Garros plus another friend of yours
plus some friends of mine. Yeah.
We all met up and they, uh,
it was four couples and we just ended
up having this table at this cafe.
Late night. We shut it down when
you guys sang me happy birthday.
Got some champagne. Oh, it was awesome.
So much fun,
by the way.
Do you know it's one of the only times
anybody's ever sung happy birthday to me
and I haven't been embarrassed.
It's happened times in my life.
All right.
There it Royal Albert Hall.
So it was twice the same
birthday and then, uh,
last year when I was on stage in Montreal,
uh,
they all sang happy,
but I was one of the coolest
things that ever happened to me.
The crowd all saying it and the fact
that they sang it to a Bruins fan that we
could set aside our differences
to celebrate one bald heck yeah.
In that moment,
you know,
which gives me hope that when Donald
Trump goes to talk to all the, uh,
fatty fat face over there,
can you,
can you imagine like you'd be in that
fat when all your people are starving.
Now granted, I know as people are
starving because of our frigging embargo,
they tried to make it seem
like he's like a dictator.
So of course he's going to be like,
oh,
bad and eat lobster and Doug and drink
in the bathroom Hawaiian every night.
We're talking about Kim Jong. Right. Keep
going. You've got to have the own name.
That's still rob King John
and his dad was Kim Jong Il.
I was going to say,
imagine his wife Carmen for
dinner. Ill uh, yeah. Um,
Hey Kim. Jon. Hey Liz. I'm
trying to tell you something.
That picture that I posted of you
on my Instagram for your birthday.
He got over 5,000 lights. That's great.
You're really into that aren't yeah.
Retweets. Yes I do. I
am. I'm into all of that.
I'm an influencer.
So honestly I'm a doer.
But you want to tell the story why,
why you want to tell a story,
why you mock that whole influencer thing.
What is my story?
You don't remember when we
first heard the term influencer,
you were going to do something and
then you couldn't because they wanted
influencers. Oh yeah. I was asked to be
a part of the name. Any names I won't,
I was asked to be a part
of a storyteller shell. Um,
and what was it saying?
Yes.
And the theme was like cultural
diversity and families and stuff.
So it was like, oh sure. Right
up DOL we then, yeah, yeah.
We have an interracial relationship.
We have a biracial child is Kinda yeah
I can come up with something for that.
And then the person who asked me said
that they had to disinvite me because they
wanted more influencers.
So a network wanted more infant network,
wanted more influencers and you know,
so they got,
they replaced me with someone who had
apparently more quote unquote influence
and more friends and fit or whatever
the fuck it is. People on social media.
Um, and I didn't even really
dig into who this person was,
but apparently they were terrible and
the whole show was like kind of awkward
and not that great.
So it's fine.
But I was so offended that I wasn't
seen as an influencer when I have like,
you know,
I'd healthy following on Twitter and
Instagram that I just decided that I was
going to be an end of one of the greatest
influences ever. I am an influencer.
Like that's,
that's the bottom line.
Like I feel like at this point I don't
even need to keep telling people anymore.
It's just who you are
coming out of your pores.
Like naturally people want to be like me,
so
you know it's weird for some reason.
I don't know,
just looking for some reason I want
braids right now. Well that's the thing,
like if I have it, you want it and that's
what an influencer does and what it is.
You didn't even tell me to get it. You
just had it and I was like, I want that.
Could you see how good it looks
on me? And so you're like, wow,
can I look like that? There's only
way to find out. It's just to get it.
And then you're like,
oh I don't.
But I tried and it's like
that's really what it's about.
That's what an influencer does. Yeah,
exactly. You just exist in this space,
like your own site guys. Like you are your
own movement. You are your own moment.
Is this something could, could
you teach this to somebody
else? God, no, no, no, no.
You either have it or you don't.
So I,
if you want to become an influencer and
not really quite sure what to tell you
because it's like you already
have sensitivity calling.
Is it a, is it a gift?
How would you describe like, yeah,
it's just, it's, it's a state of being,
you know what I mean? It's like you're
just always influencing all the time,
so I can't teach it. I can't explain it.
Does that get taxing or tiring? It'll,
you know, it really doesn't, you
know, because it's like breathing.
You go people some inside tips on
how to be a fucking influencer.
Yup. I can't believe that people
walked away from a, you know,
you just influenced me to try to read
up more on influencers. All right.
Hey people, go me a send me
some parish tips here. Okay.
By the, did you read that
thing about the wine country?
The email that I forwarded you,
one of our listeners wrote in maybe.
When did you send that?
Evidently, I'm not an influencer.
Just an email from your husband's.
This is wine country.
You know you'd make that one,
wouldn't you? At least open.
I know you don't open the ones that I
send you that they have the subject.
Are You mad at me?
All right.
Paris chips. They still write
into the the junk box, right?
No fogging dredge or were there,
hey, thank you for the best birthday.
That was the best birthday I've,
I've ever had.
I've had two back to back.
Last year was the, uh,
was the selfish one where I was,
I was in Montreal and I went to an f one
race who I don't even know who won that
the Lewis Hamilton went. And again, I got
to look that up a little behind here. Um,
but this year was the best. Uh, all right.
You know what he's about
the song happy birthday.
It's really long and it almost
sounds like people making fun of you.
Happy bird days as a year,
red douche bag.
And then in the end it's always
speech speech. So I actually,
I thought what I said at Royal Albert
Hall was really nice and I was like,
I did it, I got through it, knocked it
out, thanked everybody and I'm done.
And then as I'm walking away, people
would go speech, speech and I know,
and then I go to, like I
said, just fucking gave one.
I still didn't get angry.
Let me love God I Paris chips.
Hey Bill,
I am a fan from Perry or you
were visiting our lovely city.
This is my French accent.
Uh,
make sure that you start by
Lik comp twice in Sasha Ma,
uh, Metro Audi on as we
get off for a nice meal.
Then take your lovely lady to the cafe
Laurel in Rue dauphine for a late drink
and some jazzy entertainment.
It sounds good.
They have a nice garden where you can
smoke a cigar and sip on some scotch.
Slash. Wine. Also, don't learn French.
It's useless. Better learn Chinese as fed.
Uh, enjoy your stay and go fuck
yourself. Let's go do that. All right.
Thank you. Thank you for that
tip. Now I want to try it.
Was that gay an influencer?
He's more an informative informer.
Can we please label everybody that
fucking, he's a suggestion. Uh,
it wasn't yesterday. That'd be
funny if that was an no, I am not.
I am not a suggestion. I
was mute. I am a presenter.
I was presenting information that
you can do. You know, I mean,
it was a suggestion. That's really what
it was. Not Bad. It does adjust things.
But here's a, even in
this age of me too. Hey,
I suggest you come over here,
your honor.
It was just a suggestion. My sausage, um,
crazy lawsuit co crazy war suit.
All right.
Hey there Billy birthday cake.
Wondering if your friends in the comic
community pass this onto you. Oh,
please don't be performed getting
sued and, Oh, oh, this is the one.
You know what? I'm going to go
take a shower, take a shower.
I say take a shower and something do.
Shh.
Um,
all right.
Wondering if your,
uh,
friends in the comic community
of Wa of why influence our,
uh,
wondering if your friends in the comic
community past this Auntie backstory,
this guy, oh my God, he touched
my hair and then you hit a,
this gay Maddix like the TV show who
started a page in the 90s called the best
page in the universe.
Um,
he became famous for calling out
Christopher Reeves for not caring about
paraplegics till he became one himself.
Well,
I mean, Jesus Christ, if that, of all
the things to call people out on, uh,
basically lambasted him for
being a selfish piece of shit.
Jesus Christ,
I don't understand.
He never sold me on the aggressive
manner of heating Reeves.
The only way he kick, he does this
without looking like an asshole.
It's as if he was also in a wheelchair,
you know,
and lived at the top of a flight of stairs
or shit and nobody never made a ramp
for him. Then I could see him
being mad at Christopher Reeves,
but even then it would
still be misdirected.
It's still should be aimed at people
like myself that didn't go over there and
help build them a fucking ramp anyways,
but I appreciate it.
A different point of view on topics.
No one questioned and so I had,
okay, I, but I appreciate a
different point of view on topics.
No one questioned and so I
had some respect for this.
He also had a post called something like
I can draw better than your kids and
then posted pictures kids made
and trash them. All right.
I like this guy now because this guy is
just being a cunt. Um, he's just this guy.
Maybe he's the original troller I like
it. He goes, that was like 15 years ago.
I hadn't heard of him since college
until I read about this lawsuit.
Apparently this same guy who made a
career trolling the people on a personal
level across the Internet became offended
by a comic who decided to troll him.
Oh No, no. We had no sense
of humor about himself.
Or is this more trolling? Is this
gay? The Andy Kaufman of the Internet.
He sued the comic for $20 million,
which is basically way to bankrupt the
comic for whatever little he had the
judge essentially throughout the case.
Um,
on the advent of your 50th birthday,
I just want to thank you for not turning
into a huge hypocrite like Maddix I'll
do it.
I'm one of the most hypocritical people
you're ever gonna meet him doing yoga,
meditating and then flipping out.
Cause I, cause I lost my ticket.
Okay.
Saying this whole system is
fucking stupid. You teach,
really build this system that makes
sure that when you get to your seats,
some mother fucking assholes not sitting
in it. You fucked up, take your medicine.
And I didn't act like a big fucking baby.
Um,
even if he thought he was being wrong,
he should have taken it like a
man realized that he had to come.
And after years doing
the same thing to others,
you don't feel like this is the
final act of his performance.
And now he's gotten you up in arms.
Uh,
you're a fewer years older than me and
I've definitely taken a page on your book
in terms of allowing myself
to stay true to who I am,
but also allowing myself to grow
into a more well rounded person.
I'm an ONA saying, oh
hey, from back in the day,
and it's my favorite content ever.
But when I see comments
online that sounded like they
came from the crowd at the
virus tour,
I just feel bad for these miserable cunts.
Thanks for everything and happy birthday.
All right.
That went a little left there.
But I know what you mean about the,
that happens with everything by the way,
not just fans of the OB.
And Anthony showed this,
I mean go on Youtube,
there's always going to be then the
initial thing that you like and then you
look at the comments and I forget what
comic did that bit, but he was just like,
you know,
yeah.
You scroll down like three
or four comments before it
spins into like somebody
dropping the n word or some,
you know, thanks a lot. Oh Bama.
Like somehow that'll be
watching like slap fights.
At least that's the shit that I watched,
which I do not understand those
for the life of me. First of all.
MMM.
The fact that if they hit your ear,
what that's gonna do to your hearing,
you know? Do you know that was a thing
that like, I got to look this up.
Moms used to do that. That was like a
disciplinarian thing back in the day.
You've blocked she mothers box.
Yeah.
Boxing
their children's.
This is too specific. I don't think I'll
get anything. Ears. They would just,
you know, it was like killer con how he
used to do that. That scream well Ha.
Oh Man. Just hit your
boxing the ears. Okay.
Boston hears the other Victorians.
Uh,
Anthony.
Joshua says there's nothing wrong with
parents giving them which one should I
click on here?
World champion boxer answer.
You just said there's nothing wrong with
parents giving their children a clip
around the ear.
Boxing child's ears can cause deafness.
Yes it can.
MMM.
That's, look, this one up here.
Okay.
Oh, unable to open this because
of legal. The fuck does that mean
all right. Boxing ears. Let's see if
this one will open up. Come on, come on.
Come on. There we go.
All right. A phrase sick,
confused me while reading Alice's
adventures in wonderland was the rabbits
explanation of why the Queen Order the
Dutch is to be executed in chapter eight.
Okay.
What of I've never seen Alice
in wonderland is a queen
in Dutchess and all this
shit. People get an executed. I,
you know some, do you know why?
I think there's so much death in
old fairy tales, the original ones,
because so many people just
fucking died back then anyway.
So it really was a part of
life. Um, the rabbit, it,
I mean it's still a part of life,
but it's way down the fucking road.
But everybody had like a brother
who died of like a fucking appendix,
ruptured appendix or some Shit, get
some sort of flu. Ah, all right.
The rabbit explains to Alice,
she boxed the Queen's ears.
The actions of boxing is,
is something I had never heard of.
So I decided to look into
the meaning of the term.
I found that boxing of ears is a hard
simultaneous slap of both of yours.
Yeah.
The violent act was a popular form of
child punishment during the Victorian era.
Oh my God.
In an 1878 issue of the London
reader of literature, science, art,
and general information,
the punishment of boxing ears is debated.
The article warms is 1878 people like,
dude, what the fuck are we doing here? Uh,
for not only his deafness caused by boxes,
which ruptures as they continually do.
The drum of the ear,
but the inflammation of the internal
cavity, which is so frequent,
a result maybe followed by disease of the
bone giving rise to absent two abscess
of the brain and having
a fatal termination.
I liked how they took pick the euphemism.
They're around the same.
Your Kid's gonna fucking die.
The article explains its school is
suffering from the chastisement by school
masters and fears as noted above, that
the effects of the slabs may be longterm.
I swear to fucking God,
if my,
if I ever had a teacher
that boxed my ears.
Okay.
Oh my God. I mean, how angry
were children back then?
Oh my God. Like I literally have
to walk away from this article.
Okay.
Oh Man. I wish there was, you
know, some fucking kid back then,
just fucking snapped was
just big enough. You know,
it just beat the shit out of his teacher
and boxed is years, like nine times.
Made him a deaf fucking bastard. Um, yeah.
So whenever I watch, she'll slap fights.
It's just like,
you're going to make somebody deaf.
They put something in their ear.
Forget about just taking a concussion
for no goddamn reason. I mean,
well they'll slap fight competitions
like what is the fucking prize money?
Um,
anyways,
continuing on a Bayer and Monsanto.
Whoa.
Jesus didn't, uh, I guess see what time
I've done here. 53 minutes. All right.
It didn't, Monsanto changes her name
like Jefferson airplane or some shit. Um,
bear and Monsanto. Hey there,
you over the counter cunt.
So bare and Monsanto are merging and
reminded me of the time you mentioned an
article where bare admitted to knowing
and allowing the distribution of some
aids infected shit found the article full.
This sounds official.
First of all came from me and
then you just drive the Arctic.
The subject of the article
as aids infected shit.
Well let's check out the link.
It is from CBS news.com.
So all right.
Bear admits he had paid millions and
HIV infection cases just not in English.
Oh my God,
dude,
I swear to God.
At what point,
how much money do you have to pay
politicians where they feel like they have
enough money and they don't
need the corporate dollar
and that they can actually
start to dismantle or a restructure.
Okay,
these corporations,
these corporations are going to kill us.
Not Isis, not fuck it. The Russians.
None of this fucking shit.
All right. When I say kill us,
I mean no human beings left are
going to be the result of because of
corporations. All right, and
what, how they view people,
how they view the environment, how
they view money in their whole idea of,
of what is a is worth.
I mean,
I know I've just never heard a corporation
ever been like, you know what the, the,
the,
the costs to innocent people or the
environment is too high for us to do that.
Maybe they do.
It'd be refreshing if you have an article
like that that wasn't actually written
by someone from that corporation
that's aligned. All right.
Turn to the read the
English speaking media.
You'd never know that bear just paid tens
of millions of dollars to end a three
decade long scandal in which the company
sold HIV contaminated blood products to
hemophilia x thousands of
whom later died of AIDS.
They just killed thousands of
fucking people or admitted to it.
But that doesn't mean they actually
said that they did it. You know,
that fucking legal thing.
Um,
ironically bears new hemophilia who feel
your iPhone app got some coverage ads.
Did bears hemophilia research grant,
are they covering their tracks?
So the University of Florida go gators,
but you have to pick through the French
and Italian news media to find out that
bear is finally writing
checks to people who got aids.
I've got HIV that turned into aids
in the 1980s the cutter biological
unit of bear ignored
federal law to recruit
prisoners, intravenous
drug users, and high risk.
Amen. As donors, all they
ignored that of the blood.
Carter then use to make factor eight
and nine the clotting product that
hemophilia x need to order,
need in order to not bleed to death.
Oh. So they pulled the Bella check
whether they were like, all right,
you guys are all filming.
Need the team on the sidelines.
You can no longer do that.
And they just ignored it.
MMM.
All right.
The German group bear in three other labs
will pay tens of billions of euros to
hemophilia.
Ooh.
Accuse them of having sold in the 1980s
blood products contaminated with HIV.
A source close to deal told him.
So did it.
Was it that they knew that it had HIV
in it or did they just went to high risk
people to get blood?
The figure of tens of billions of euros
and compensation is not totally wrong.
She had a bear in the U S company.
Baxter are the two main
parties to the agreement.
She said accompanies folks versus said,
however,
the company accepts no responsibility
in this case and continues to insist and
it always acted responsibly and ethically.
That's how they get out of it.
It's like, all right, we'll
admit that we did that shit.
If you say it wasn't our fault and
that we always behaved above board.
You know what that's like?
That's like when they send somebody to
jail and innocent person to jail and then
they're like, all right,
we're going to let you out.
But the only way we can let you out as
if you sign this paper saying you won't
sue us because we fucked up.
MMM.
Anyways, found the article. I just read
some of it. They're still in business.
Sell is still in business. Can't
bring down bear. That's our medicine.
But maybe our food supply.
Nope. Then you got,
I don't know what this
guy's talking about now.
MMM.
Then you've got Monsanto who can't be
sued because Obama signed that laws saying
that you can't soup and Santo now there
were super team corporations are like
NBA teams. Huh? You got
room in the chopper for me.
Bill just goes all over the place.
All right.
And why did Obama sue that sign that,
so that, why did he sign that bill?
Everybody?
Is it because he's a Ultibro targe snow
flake or whatever people getting wears a
blue tie or is it because he's grossly
underpaid for his fucking job and is,
and I bet those guys
funded is fucking campaign,
so then he had to do them a solid,
it's all the same shit.
They all make 500 grand a year and then
come out of office worth hundreds of
millions of whatever, fucking
70 80 million bucks. How
does that happen, everybody?
Although recently I saw Bill Clinton when
that fucking piece of shit brought up
the me too thing. You know
Monica Lewinsky, I let all,
they tried to make that a me too thing.
You know what I mean?
It's like she was in her twenties
she was a college graduate.
She never learned that she,
she is what I was saying on stage.
She never learned that you shouldn't
blow a married guy in his house with his
wife and kid down the fucking hall.
She didn't know that.
Now she's coming back being influenced
by his power and it was UPI pool people.
We get the fuck Outta here.
You are a driven young adults who somehow
in your 20s got a job in the fucking
White House. Okay. You weren't some dope.
He founded a bus station I near um,
some of them Monica Lewinsky thing where
now that she's trying to like turn it
around that he used his
power and influence.
It's like you are a college graduate
working in the White House. Right.
I don't know. I thought we had dealt
with all of that. All right. I know.
And he got punished for it, but in
that thing he said Clinton was like,
I left the White House. I was $16
million in debt. You know what I mean?
He's a if that's true. I think he's the
only fucking president ever did that.
Oh Geez. She's, she's getting
ready for nap time. All right.
Um,
big band drumming,
tear belt. I'm 17 years old and I
played drums every day. That's awesome.
It's my life and I'm in every band,
jazz concert and marching. Good man.
And I play percussion for the
chorus and for the school place.
Kenny Aronoff is my hair.
Well that I was going to say that
sounds like his autobiography. Uh,
how he started out.
Thank you for that dream interview.
I have it on a playlist with music. That's
how much I listened to it. Oh, let's go.
I'm glad you liked it.
You know Nia not for nothing.
People say actually do a good interview.
Oh yeah.
Kenny Aronoff to Danica Patrick
to my lovely wife. You know,
I set you guys up. No, no,
let you guys, you know,
I love it over the plate.
I learned that by going on [inaudible].
That's what he does. He mean Andrew, they,
they just, they just lob
it over to you. All right.
Andy Richter,
my day was telling me about,
my dad was telling me about
the scar movement in the
90s I just watched swingers
and discovered this band,
squirrel nut zippers.
Oh my God.
It takes you back to your college days.
It's really takes me back to my early
thirties and I was in my late twenties.
It's really different
than anything I've heard.
I discovered that I don't like all Scott,
but I like these guys cause it's more
big band. And Scott, I really think you,
uh,
enjoy the drumming.
It's really a cool mix between big Ben
drumming punk in almost some primus type
drumming stuff because of the time work.
Uh,
did you get ever get into any of that?
I remember that big bad voodoo
daddy and that type of stuff.
I liked it a little bit,
but I was a little too old at that point.
That was actually kids music to me.
Um,
this is what our lovely daughter does.
Before afternoon nap,
she screamed bloody murder.
Um, and then falls asleep.
No one talks to herself when she calms
down and then falls asleep. Anyways,
I doubt this will get read
because it's too nerdy,
but maybe just maybe thanks for
the laughs. Oh, Billy rim shot. Um,
no, I like all that stuff. I mean,
I liked when Robert Plant was Jesus.
I liked when Robert Plant did that. The
honeyed represent with Paul Shaffer. Um,
I've always liked big bands and that
type of stuff and I really liked the way
all of that music is the squirrel
nut zippers and all that.
I just liked the way it was produced.
It sounded really live.
And um, and also, you know,
when you get that many people in a
band and they can all play, it's,
it's always sounds great.
So was awesome. Oh,
big diversity today. He was also in
swingers. Okay. I did not know that. Um,
where Mike and Jon Favreau goes, Oh
yeah. Dancing with Heather Graham.
Oh yeah, they were, uh, they were great.
They are great, I should say. Right. What
did they forget how to play? All right.
Being rude to wait staff.
All right. Hey there.
Billy bath salts.
Your receipt.
Talking about Nia being slightly
rude to wait staff and it made me
a hit of word got cut off something,
a podcast.
I've heard years back about raising kids.
Essentially a group of economists gave
their opinions on what you can and can't
change in children's supported
with studies and evidence.
One person suggests with evidence that
there are only a small number of habits
that kids pick up from their parents.
Those adverts are drinking, alcohol,
smoking and how we treat others,
waitstaff, family, et cetera.
Well,
those are kind of big things.
As a former bartender who's dealt
with incredibly rude patrons,
I would love to hear you and Nia debate
if she is actually being rude or not.
If she feels she's not being rude,
would she be okay if she saw her daughter
treating a family member the way she
treats waitstaff? Absolutely. She would
love the can't wait to hear her thoughts.
Here's a link to a podcast as a new dad.
I think you'll dig it.
Have a great summer and I hope you
get sunburned. You some of them bitch.
Um,
Nia,
do you feel as an influencer,
why can't you just influence them to make
better, better service? I am not rude.
I just,
and something goes wrong.
I just let them know and I'm direct
about it. I'm not like, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry
I don't do that.
Cause what am I apologizing for?
Unlike no out of this.
Can you change it? Thank you.
That's it. What do I had to,
I had to do with like,
do you want me to fucking blow the
waiter because he did something wrong?
Like he's blowing me.
No,
I'm just saying control
a little sugar on it.
In the end I feel like I'm
very sugary. I'm not, no,
don't take it badly right now. Like, no,
it's quite that you did one
time it was cold and you said,
can you have them go back and heat to
Stephanie's? You, Oh my God, I'm so sorry.
You and you like, yeah.
Cause it's like, yeah.
As they went to take it away
and I was just like, Jesus.
You remember everybody was at the
table like God to have Nia? No.
Everybody who was everybody
at the table was, I got Dan.
Dan would have been family.
No, that didn't happen. Nope,
I don't mean, yeah, I don't remember
it. So maybe it did happen, but like,
I don't remember it. Maybe it
did happen. That was hilarious.
What the fuck was that? That didn't
happen. I don't remember that.
Yeah. Maybe it did happen.
I don't recall ever being,
behaving in such a manner that it
would be like, so was so freaked out.
You're adorable. And
even when you lied. Um,
okay.
Yeah. Um, I, I go the other way.
I'm too nice and we'll eat fucking
whatever the fuck they send me.
You don't see you when they
send me the wrong thing,
I still eat it because I don't want,
because I don't want them to throw it out.
Oh, who's this? I'm going to throw it out.
They might put it to the side and maybe
somebody lunch and the kitchen later on.
Oh No.
Yeah.
You're telling me if somebody brought a
plate of food out into public and they
said that's not what I wanted and
brought it back, he'd be like, oh,
fucking eat it. Somebody might, well,
how do you know they haven't put their
fucking mouth on? It was like, oh,
this isn't Ravioli. This is French
toast. I thought it looked weird.
And then you go over there and
you get the old breakfast. Herpes.
Um, all right. That's the podcast.
I get to find out why my lovely little
boob bears a crying downstairs. Oh,
she's phones. Oh, shoot. In the bedroom.
Yeah.
Okay. All right. Well I gotta get
off my day here of what? To Lamont.
She on the belly on.