Yeah.
Hey,
what's going on?
Is Bill burn his time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
April 10th, 2017 what's
going on? How is Yah,
how's it going everybody?
You're doing good. I apologize
that the podcast is late.
I apologize that it's laid I a,
he was flying back from San Antonio.
I meant to do it yesterday,
but I was doing a tour of San Antonio
and the day got away from me, you know,
I was going all around San Antonio,
went out to Jeff Wright drum shop.
I got some Mexican food around the
corner that was fucking delicious.
Um, I forget the name of that place,
but it's going to be on the video.
Then it went down to the river,
walk it over to the stupid fucking Alamo.
Jesus Christ, just crawling
with fucking tourist reenactors,
all kinds of magnets and shit.
And I just was like the, you know,
every time I go to San Antonio I was like,
I'm going to fucking go in there and I
want to read up on all these guys who
fought to the last guy
I'm going to read up on.
Every time I get there there's like
9,000 people in Jean shorts is a fucking
gift shop and I just say forget
it. I felt bad about it. Like, Hey,
what do you know? What do
you not patriotic? Then
Bill,
you know?
Then I ran into somebody from San Antonio,
you ever go into this thing and they go,
no, we live here. And I was like, oh,
I get it.
No,
The Alamo is your time square. If like
nobody in New York goes to Times Square.
Okay.
Nobody in La goes to fucking Disneyland
or fucking universal unless you have
kids.
But I mean just as an adult you're not
going to do now is just going to fucking
go there. You know you don't stand in
line in your own fucking town. Okay.
One of the advantages of it being your
own fucking town is you don't have to
stand in line with everybody else.
Cause you know all the spots.
You know where to go,
you know where not to go.
And when you're in San Antonio,
where not to go is the fucking Alamo,
unless you're a goddamn tourist.
Then you'd go in there and then you're
going to go over to the river walk,
which is actually for a touristy thing,
was very nice. That man made river.
I got to tell you something.
That's the first time I walked down and I,
I liked it.
I really enjoyed it.
There was a bunch of people standing
outside getting a little hustle going on,
trying to get you to go in
and drink a Margarita. Right?
All kinds of wacky
people wearing the hats.
People driving by on the little gondolas,
you know, it was like he went Venice,
but it was Texas right there.
Little slice of fucking Italy,
you know. And then right around
the corner was the majestic.
Yeah,
very ornate. The word only use to
describe a theater. Very ornate. Hey,
my buddy redid his garage. Oh, it's,
it's beautiful. It's so ornate.
Nobody ever says that, right? To say they
call it a fucking man cave. It was. Okay.
So the man caves for fucking,
you know, the twinkle toes there.
The Broadway stars are these theaters
and this thing had like a, I mean,
it had like fucking houses and she
looks on Peter Pan Stuff was amazing.
And evidently while I was on stage,
it was a flying around.
They went past me and aside
the fact that it was a bat,
like nobody even reacted. They're so used
to bats down there. Evidently they, uh,
they kill all the fucking mosquitoes are
enough of them. You know what I mean?
So people in San Antonio
evidently cool with bats. I Dunno.
But I had two great shows,
the first show when awesome in the
second show was just fucking next level.
And I actually texted my agent, I was
like, the hours ready, and he was like,
really? And I'm like, yes. So let's fill
up the calendar. They have, fuck, oh no,
that's not how I talk to my agent. Um,
I go, let's fill up the full, you know,
let's fill up the fucking calendar.
So his mission should,
he chooses to accept that he's going to
fill up my calendar and then in I gave
him the list of the eight teams that
I have left that I need to go see.
All right,
so if you're on this list,
I'll be doing a show at some point within
the next fucking year cause I'm not
these out in the next year before my
daughter starts walking and talking and
doing all that stuff.
I got to knock this out.
So I need the Toronto Raptors,
the Auto Isac
playing my Boston Bruins and
the first round of the playoffs.
Congratulations to both teams making
the playoffs. It's a big deal. Playoffs.
I'll wait. No, no, no. Wait. Are we
playing them? I think we are playing on,
which makes no fucking sense to me.
Fucking hockey.
If we'd like the aid seat,
should we play the capital's?
Shouldn't the capital's be rewarded that
they won their fucking division rather
than having to play the fucking penguins
and then they knock one another out and
all we got to do is try to get
past the senators. No disrespect,
but disrespect intended. I'm
just being honest. All right,
let's check this shit out right now.
Okay? You know this isn't going to work.
You know it's not I, you know I'm
going to be on the wrong fucking one.
The Boston Celtics or a second seed.
They're a fucking second seed
there. All right. Hang on a second.
And H L playoff
bracket. All right,
here we go. And it fail.
Nhl fucking playoff
bracket. All right. Yes,
this is what the fuck I want.
You gonna make me click on it again.
I typed what I wanted and then he like,
is this what you want? Yes, this is,
this is what I want. All right.
The ranges of verse Canadians,
the Bruins. Get the senators. I don't get
it. Capital's get the maple leafs. Okay.
All right. All right. All
right. I thought. And then
coal, there's a good one.
Columbus first of penguins that
[inaudible] Nashville predators made the
playoffs playing the black hawks,
Minnesota wild versus the St Louis Blues.
And I'm ducks first. The Calgary
flames in the San Jose shacks first.
Edmonton Oilers, Eh, we go,
Brad Marshawn is back and all
of that shit. So anyways, yeah,
I got to get the Toronto Raptors
auto senators. I got to get a,
the Brooklyn Nets.
I've already seen the New Jersey Nets,
but my rule is if you get a new stadium,
I don't give a fuck.
I'll eventually see it. But if you
move to a new city, especially a state,
you know,
then yeah, I got to go fucking
see you again. All right.
I need the Carolina Hurricanes,
Orlando Magic,
Tampa Bay Buccaneers,
the Memphis Grizzlies and
the New Orleans Pelicans.
So there you go. So I'm going
to try to get, you know,
I probably do the Canadian ones at the
same trip and I'll try to do the fucking,
um,
Orlando Tampa at the same time.
Then I think I'm going to do a bus
trip to knock out those fucking three
Carolina fucking Memphis and New Orleans.
I think that that's what I'm
gonna do and then it'll be done.
And then what we do build,
well you know what I'll do is I'll
move on to fucking college. All right.
Cause the day I go out on the road and
I don't have something to fucking look
forward to and I just sit in the God damn
hotel waiting for the show. That's it.
I'm going to dry up.
You hear me dry?
So anyways,
I got Boise coming up and I just got an
email from the CEO via my agent saying,
Hey, we've been watching these videos,
seen a bill, likes to play the drums.
What if we rented a drum kit and put
it in the theater during the day and if
Phil wants to play during the day,
he can come in and play for like an hour.
How fucking great is that? It's the
coolest thing ever. I made, I'm a put my,
put that on my fucking writer.
I don't give a shit how much
it costs because this is
the thing that we say, hey,
we'll do that for you. And then they
just, you know, they pay me less money.
That's how it works now. God Damn
it. This isn't in fucking stereo.
I just realized that,
wait a sec, wait a second.
She let me see something. There we go. Oh,
you fucking son of a bitch.
That's not it.
How do I get this thing in stereo?
You know,
this is just one of these
fucking days, isn't it? Isn't it?
It's just one of these days.
Now I'm just going to push buttons.
What's going on there it is.
Now it's in Stereo.
Oh, Jesus Christ. I thought there
was something wrong with the wire.
My fault. Well, you had to suffer
for seven 53. I'll let you know.
I'll just say that it isn't, you
know this, he know something.
You know what's great about it? It'll
give you something to complain about.
You know, unless the Great Andrew
Feminist fixes the fucking thing. I Dunno.
Anyways, plowing ahead here. Um,
so what else? Okay. So I went
down there and I saw, uh,
I saw a lot of San Antonio this time.
Like I said, I had great fucking shows.
You know what? Who's kidding, who? I lost.
I completely lost my train of thought
cause now I'm fucking mad at myself.
Why didn't I think that?
Just fucking push that button.
I immediately thought it was the wire.
I troubleshooted I never
knowingly lied about the wire.
Um, all right, so now I know what you
guys are thinking. Hey Bill, you know,
you said that you were going to watch
some alternative sports this weekend.
You said you were going
to watch the masters,
the Moto GP fucking Formula One.
Well,
all fucking Billy freckled the Fed tinted,
no glued,
haven't fucking cunt.
I did two out of three.
I watched the moto GP.
You know what's hilarious?
I didn't realize that there was two
undercard motorcycle races and I'm sitting
there going like this fucking race. It
was only 20 laps. What's going on here,
right? The first one was the GP three
then or something. The Moto three,
then the moto two. And then,
uh, then there was the last one.
So I kind of fast forward
through the first two. And
then I watched the whole, um,
I watched the whole a moto GP,
uh, the real fucking one. And,
uh,
congratulations to a,
I don't even have to say this
guy's named maverick finales.
You know, I saw that mark, mark and
Berg, whatever his fucking name is,
he was cruising around and all of a sudden
he just didn't make this turn and he
was very upset with himself.
That's his name. Mark Menendez.
That's old is this again, I'll kill
this fucking did he kill his parents?
I don't know what happened. And then, uh,
Valentino Rossi came in
second and both of them,
they seem very excited about that. You
know what I mean? They got some points,
they felt good about themselves and,
uh, I gotta tell you something, man,
those fucking guys and you
gotta check out the Moto Gp.
Okay.
It's unfuckable the amount of crashes
that I saw too in all three of those
races. There was one guy who
was going through the turn.
He started to accelerate in the backend,
kind of kicked a little bit.
So he got off it,
then he got back on it and the fucking
the God damn bike had I had a seizure,
fucking did a couple little ss then just
like started slipping over and then the
guy of course fee flies off
the damn thing. It hits him
in the back of the head.
It amazes me that they get back up again.
Those suits they have are incredible.
They got little air bags in them and shit,
but still they always end up fucking up
their hands or their ankles or something
like that. But this Guy Kinda high sided
on it, which is basically, you know,
if you're a novice like me when they
just sort of lay it down and the bikes
starts sliding and then you just Kinda,
you just touch the ground and slide
with the fucking thing hi sightings.
When it hits the ground and you
fucking catapult over the top of it,
the high side of it.
And that's when you get,
seems to me that's when you get
fucking hurt. Um, it's ridiculous.
They're going like 200 miles an hour in
something that you can just fall off of.
Um,
but I enjoyed the race immensely.
I enjoyed that race as much as you guys
probably didn't enjoy the first seven
minutes.
53 seconds of fucking no stereo
on this m I n I then I watched,
I watched the masters too and I could
not be happier for Varage Sergio Garcia.
I man, I just, you know,
it's one of the things about being at
his level when you go that long without
winning is that gives you,
it gives every mouth breathing Haagen
daas eating fucking Douche bag who never
achieved anything.
The right to walk up to you and start
telling you about how you can't get it
done. You know what I mean? Sitting
there wearing a wife beater with you.
Flabby Grandmother fucking arms.
You know,
just given this Guy Shit, when he missed
that one on 18 I was like, oh God.
Oh boy, here we go. Here we
go. Shades and Kenny Perry,
is this what we're going to see again?
And actually every year when I
watched the masters, you know,
I don't watch it every year. I shouldn't
say that, but every time I watch it,
somebody always folds in the back nine
and I actually get mad at the tournament.
I always ended up, you know,
I was actually texting my,
I was texting that court
who did the live um,
final day of the masters
and I was just like, dude,
can somebody just win this fucking event?
Does anybody ever just when the masters,
no one ever wins the masters.
Somebody fucking loses it every year
and you just have to watch somebody.
Like a buddy of mine tested me, uh,
texted me test it, texted me and said,
uh, it, Sergio doesn't win this playoff.
He said that punt Wa
that pot will haunt him.
Okay.
It's like, no it won't. It will.
But you know what's going to haunt him
is every cheesecake factory and Douche
bag walking up to him,
Hey, remember that time,
you know, giving him shit, right.
Not Realizing that that ms pot is a
fucking metaphor for the other person's
entire goddamn existence. This guys played
in over 70 something major. So anyway,
it's just like watching Phil Mickelson
when it way back in the day and like,
oh four was so great to watch
him get the monkey off his back.
So congratulations to him.
Um,
winning the most difficult activity known
to men playing the non sport that is
golf.
Okay.
You know, I still had to give
a shit. Right? It's such,
um, I know it's such a dude.
It's so hard. It's such a
fucking mind. Fuck, I get it.
I get it. But I would rather have to do
that than face a fucking roided up. Uh,
uh, oh, he never got convicted.
So Cardiac remens right.
Roger Lemons. Right. I wouldn't want
that guy thrown half a fucking bad at me.
You know, just muttering inexplicatives
as I walk up to the plate,
like I would much rather have to
try to sync a fucking three foot,
then some fucking roided up maniac on
the goddamn mount who can't admit that
it's fucking career's over.
So he's got to go out and take
some fucking horse tranquilizers.
Not saying that he did it. And you
know what if he did? God bless him.
God bless him that he did. I am. I am
so fucking, I told you I'm pro steroids,
dude. I'm fucking pretty.
Everybody should get on him.
You know I want every fucking
athlete on steroids. Okay.
And then the doctors can look at you and
see what the side effects are and they
can gradually make them better and better
and better and better till it's like
vaporized. We'd, you know,
you just have like a steroid mist
and meet with my fucked up shoulder.
You know what I mean? I'll just come in
and just walk into the doctor's office.
You know,
they'll put a fucking hot towel over head,
like I have hay fever and then they'll
just have be breathing steroids.
I'll walk out,
I'll have glutes again after 20 years of
sitting on my ass and planes and rental
cars, my fucking glutes will come
back. They're just like nonexistent.
I don't know what happened. I just
fucking like, you know, like a,
when you're going to make something
and you got to pound out like a fucking
chicken breast.
Yeah.
That's what my fucking ass is like
after years of being on a plane. So, um,
I actually made my way across to the
gym when I was in San Antonio to their
sister property sister
property mean the other hotel
fucking Weirdos. Anyways,
and I went in there,
I did the elliptical for about 40 minutes
and then I just did a fucking for me,
for me, I did a savage fucking
leg workout and now I, you know,
I know you guys are all thinking,
well, what did you do bill? All right,
this is what I did.
I add the exercise ball,
I put it on the fucking wall between me
and my back and then I would just roll
down with that, you know, so I can
keep my back nice and straight and my,
my weight on my heels,
pushing through my heels to engage my,
my veal fucking buttocks.
Uh, there, what did I do? I did
hip thrusts after that, you know,
then I did a some calf raises,
then I did the classic,
you know,
the things you sit down when you do the
front parts of your quads and then the
other one, the stick them in your fucking
go the other way. You do the back party,
your legs.
And then I got on the squat machine.
I don't like the old thing you stand up
on like the one that you sit down on.
I feel you can go deeper. You don't have
to worry about your fucking back. And uh,
and I did that.
I did fucking three sets of all of that
shit and a this morning my legs were
definitely killing me. Um, so
that's a new part of my workout.
Okay.
That's what I'm doing.
But I don't have all those leg machines
when I'm here, you know what I mean?
And my shoulder's fucked up so I'm not
putting a bar bell on my back with a
bunch of fucking weight.
Okay. I will just,
I will choose to do more squats without
any weight because I am an old man,
but I swear to God.
Okay.
I swear to God,
man,
that's fucking athletes manner that he
got to keep taking steroids. You know,
just like the singer, she know a singer
can't sing a song. What do they do?
Give her, give her a little bit of
fucking steroids right in the throat.
Give her throat. The old right there,
Fred. And what happens? She fucking,
she goes out there and start
singing a song. She makes it simple.
And you know what, in the last,
the whole night launch, sorry. Um,
and then lastly for alternative sports
are I thought I'd take the fucking
Formula One race in Shanghai, China,
and I didn't fucking pisses me off.
So all I did was I just
watched the highlights.
So a congratulations to Lewis
Hamilton, him and the, uh,
the guy won the Australia.
They could, you know,
they came in one and two and now they
just flipped. So the tide was 43 points.
The fuck's his name. I should know his
name. He only want a goddamn race. Right.
That's all right.
Sebastian Vettel for the Ferrari team did
tied at 43 and Max Verstappen is 25th,
25 points.
I'm sorry.
In third place at a fucking Rikki rocket
isn't fits place Kimi Raikkonen now
he's not the guy called who's a
guy called fucking Rikki rocket.
Nico Rosberg is that it? No, Nico Rosberg
fucker. Yeah. I don't fucking know.
There's too many God damn sports
going around my head now. Anyways,
the play in Nhl Stat would play in Ottawa.
I like her goddamn chances.
I heard that defense is a little banged
up according to Joe Barton, a gun,
the puck off podcast. I'll be watching
all of those. I'll be tweeting.
I'll be fucking Facebook and I won't be
doing any of that ship and maybe I will.
Um, so anyways, eight pretty good when I
was on the road now. So he kind of bed,
you know, I had that Mexican food
and was just fucking, you know,
I used to always make fun and the tour,
I was making fun of like Mexican
food as far as like, you know,
the re fried green beans and the
rice that they put on the plate.
And I was just like,
you know what this shit is.
This is Mexico's version of Coleslaw.
You know what Coleslaw,
like most people don't take it seriously
and it's basically, it's a plate filler.
You know, you got your piece
of meat, he got your vegetable,
and then they just throw that
shit. They're just so, the
plate doesn't look naked.
You know what I mean? Yo, wow. Look at
this big plate of food. I got not, I not,
that's Mike. More than 60% rice
and beans. I didn't get it.
All right then. One sentence stands.
No, you mix all that shit in together.
He grabbed one of those little
fucking round pieces of bread,
whatever the fuck you call it.
You put it on there,
you know a little bit of hot sauce.
It's delicious.
You got a little bean and rice. Fucking
a fucking thing there. Thingamajig sorry,
I'm white. I don't know. I'll learn it.
I've only been out in La for 10 years.
At some point I'll, I'll, I'll
learn it. Was that a Tostada? Um,
I know what an Enchilada is.
I know what a crispy Taco is.
She said crispy or puffy.
Puffy before.
Um, I always go crispy, you know
what I mean? But the crispy Tacos,
it's, it's a, it's only
good on the first bike,
cause then the whole fucking thing
falls apart. You know what I mean?
It's like an old person's Hipaa.
You barely touch it in the whole thing.
Just cracks and it doesn't work anymore.
So you kinda got to go soft Taco, right?
The flash at TACO. All right, I'm sorry.
But then if you mix the beans and rice
in there is all I can say. It was a,
this was God damn delicious. Let me, yeah,
let me do a little bit advertising here.
A little ads here for the,
for the, for the week here.
MMM.
What am I doing here? Come on. Come on. I
want you, I want this computer work right?
For now, from okay. Oh, here we
go. Out. We're all friends here.
First read a week old zip,
right?
Are you hiring?
Do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
Do you want to find the perfect hire?
If you want that perfect person
to walk through that Goddamn door,
you need to post your job on all the
top job sites and now you can with
ziprecruiter.com you can post
your job to 200 plus job sites,
including social media networks
like the Facebook and the Twitter,
like the Facebook and the Twitter.
All with a single click.
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your fucking
candidates roll right into old zip.
Okay.
[inaudible] is easy to use. Interface, no
juggling emails or calls to your office.
Quickly screen the candidates,
sex offender, right then.
Get the fuck out and hire the right person
fast. Look at the rack on that batch.
Uh, no juggling emails or calls to
your office. Did I already say that?
Find out today why olds?
Yup.
Has been used by fortune 100 companies
and thousands of small and medium size
businesses.
And right now my listeners can post
on Ziprecruiter for free by going to
ziprecruiter.com/bird that's
zip recruiter.com/bar one
more time to try it for
free.
Go to Jose.
Okay.
Dot Com slash burp sorry, the last one
was creepy. All right. Dollar Shave Club.
Duke buying a fucking raises a lot
like buying a car to get a smooth,
to get smooth luxury quality kid,
you have to pay huge fucking price and
that means you're paying mostly for
splashy marketing and features.
Features you don't actually need switched
to dollar shave club.com it's the
smarter choice.
Luxury quality at an economy price.
Dollar Shave Club's razors are
amazing quality. They got uh,
the shave tech you need and none
of the overprice gimmicks should,
don't have you seen the ad for the razors,
monopolies newest razor thing.
It's got like 24 blades. Swivel, pivot,
Robo razor with the laser pointer.
You know the whole thing.
You don't need any of that shit.
Once they go and beyond two
blades, it was stupid. Okay?
Every year they make a tiny change to
the razor and then the new blades don't
fit the old fucking handle.
It's the Steve jobs thing.
The new phone doesn't fit the old charger.
It's the same goddamn thing
and all the other ones,
they end up in the ocean and they try
to convince you it's totally new and you
need to spend even more affordance.
Bullshit. Joined the dollars,
join dollar shave club and
just be done with all of that.
There's never been a better
time to give them a shot.
Right now you can get off your fucking
ass and for the first month sign up,
you can get any of their
amazing raises for only a buck,
including free shipping and after that,
it's just a few bucks a month.
That's all is,
there's no long term commitments.
No hidden fees knows where's
this relationship going?
We need to connect more.
None of that.
You're a fuck buddy with these people.
You can cancel whenever you want.
Get your first month for, for just a
bobBuck@dollarshaveclubdotcomithoughtitwouldbeforfreeatdollarshaveclub.com
slash
burp that's dollar club.com/bar.
All right, two more. And they're,
they're short just hanging here.
M the m t watches,
Michael Vincent, Michael
Tango, watches movement,
watches start at just $95
at a department store.
You look at it,
four to 500 bucks,
move and figured out
that by selling online,
they were able to cut out the
middleman and retail mock up,
providing the best possible price.
Classic design,
quality construction and styled minimalism
over 1 million goddamn watches sold
in over 160 countries,
but not including North Korea.
You know why they couldn't find a strap
big enough to get around that fatties
risk.
What do you say to pork belly? Um,
call to action. Must read. Hey,
easy, easy fucking
relax. I want to read it.
Get 15% off today with free shipping
and free returns by going to MVMT
watches.com/burr.
This watch has a really clean design.
Seriously. I've been getting
compliments ever since I put it on.
I'm not wearing one.
I don't know what they're talking about.
Now is the time to step up your game.
Go to movement,
watches.com/burr join the movement.
Once again,
it's Mvmt Mike Victor,
Mike Tango,
speaking of which,
I flew a helicopter for the first
time since October 31st of last year,
and although I'll tell you it was
a rough one, I was fucking rusty.
I'll tell you that story in a second,
right after our old friends here,
stamps.com oh stamps.com come on. Shake
the colt off high. You Bet. All right.
I've used, I use stamps.com anytime I'm
selling my posters, you know I'm a moron.
If I could figure out how to use the
scale on the postage meters, so can you,
okay.
Stamps save you time and money,
which you can use to grow your business
or maybe just sit there scratching your
ass. Anything's better than going down to
the post office. You can mail a letter,
any package using gesture
computer and your printer,
and the mailman comes and picks it up
the mail, man. All right. Not that lady.
He got to drive down and
fucking give it to her.
Avoid the hassle of the post office
man and mail everything from the post,
from postcards to envelopes to packages,
domestic or international stamps.com will
help you to decide out of the fucking
the best class of mail
based on your needs.
No need to lease an expensive postage
meter right now. You can enjoy this.
You can join these stamps service with a
special offer that includes a four week
trial plus postage and a digital
scale without longterm commitments.
Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone at the top of the homepage.
Type it bar that stamps.com
enter burr one more time.
stamps.com never go to the post office
again unless you're one of those Weirdos
that collect stamps. Okay? Yeah,
I flew for the first time I went up
with an instructor and a holy shit.
Anybody out there with flies
helicopters? I mean, Gees,
I missed the fucking pad
when I was coming in.
I mean I missed it by probably 60 yards,
just coming in way too fast.
I was like, I gotta a guy
settling with power. Fuck this.
I just kind of continued on past it.
Like you supposed to came back
around the next time. You know,
I came up a little short. It
took me about, I don't know,
26 goes around till I was starting to
feel it again. And uh, it was funny,
like my fourth time I just
flew the traffic pattern
down there at long beach and
um,
my fourth time around I was turning to
go downwind and I just started laughing
and my instructor started laughing too,
cause he knew I was laughing.
It was just like, this is fucking
awesome. It's just fucking,
it's fucking awesome.
And it just totally re lit the fire in
me to go do it and I'm going to try and
fly again before the end of the month.
So if I can just kind of fly like once
every 10 days or something while I'm
getting a little one going, you know,
um, I would be very happy with that.
It's such a,
it was such an accomplishment in
my life to get my pilot's license.
I would hate to just not do
it and forget how to do it.
It's so much fucking fun and it's
really safe, you know what I mean?
If you just do what they say,
the way they maintain them.
I know everybody always tries
to freak out, but you know,
they always freaking and know
what was freaking me out.
Like he'll be careful out there.
Be careful. Oh yeah. Okay. I can,
I was going to fly with a blindfold, you
know, but I get it. I get it. Anyway,
so let's, um, let's plow ahead here. Um,
oh yeah. So I ended up, uh, you know what,
I can't plow ahead here cause I was gonna
start doing the reads and I'm only at
28 minutes, so I need to run my
yap a little bit longer. So, um,
yeah,
yeah, I think we flew the
tab traffic pattern for like
just like a little over an
hour.
I got a 1.1 in the Hobbs meter and um,
didn't do any autos. It was just all
low approach, you know, normal approach.
Steve Approach. That's
all I was doing. And um,
it was fun flying the 22, which
is my, that's my favorite one.
Even on the 44 is cool.
You know, it's a nicer one.
I just thought the 22 is like driving
an old sports car with no power windows,
no power steering, fucking drum
brakes. I always just put that one.
It's just like whatever it's doing,
I'm actually doing it.
I heard on some of those
high end helicopters if you
want, if you want to hover,
you just push a button and
it just does it for you.
That's the one you get when you get older.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
I don't want to shut out, draw it on
a dime. Um, all right. You know what?
I'm just going to start
reading these fucking,
I'm going to start doing
the reeds here for the week.
Okay.
Oh, by the way, what,
what's the deal with all the
haunted houses in San Antonio?
You know, it was the
usual stuff as far as, uh,
as far as you know,
Texas goes,
Texas is the king of the shiny four
door pickup truck that's never seen a
construction site or off road.
Okay.
In Texas.
That's a four
door sedan. Then I'll tell you,
they got some fucking nice ones.
I saw a guy pull up in
a Ford F one 54 door.
It's got giant tires on it. This old
fucking guy, big white cowboy hat,
big fucking belt buckle in white
cowboy boots. I was just like, ah,
this is just, you know,
as a tourist. It's like,
that's what the fuck I wanted to see.
Now I could say I went to Texas.
You know what I mean?
I don't want to see somebody
looking at their fucking iPhone.
I can do that out here. All right.
Update Psycho from yogurt shop video.
All right, Bill. Turns out that
Nutjob I don't even remember this.
Who was it costing? The couple.
All, all, oh, that's right.
This goes back to like
a couple podcasts to go,
whether it was this woman who was trashing
these two people kissing in public
saying that it was sexual harassment
and all of that type of stuff. And uh,
I kind of agreed with her
on on a level is I just,
I hate watching people kiss in public,
you know what I mean?
Give each other a quick peck, you know,
going for one real one if you want to,
but then just keep it moving.
You know what I mean?
To literally sit there and take it to
the point where her policies getting wet
and your Dick Start standing up.
It's like,
what are you don't get the
fuck out of here. It's gross.
[inaudible] all over each other.
I fucking can't stand it.
I don't like it in movies, you know,
I've put disgusting. Um, anyways,
so here's an update for this lady flipped
out and was yelling at them and you
know, I dunno, I'm going to call the cops.
I couldn't get through the whole thing
because she looked like she was a little,
uh, you know, had some
mental issues going on.
Some was going on and she was extremely
lonely or somebody filled her up with
Jesus. I don't know what happened.
Anyways, Bill turns out then that nut job,
who was a costing, the couple of the
yogurt shop is an amateur porn actress,
Eh,
boy and witnesses say that the guy only
kissed his girlfriend on the forehead.
No lip service. Oh, all right. My fault.
And it wasn't the first time
she's yelled at people in public.
It took the interland like half a
day to get to the bottom of it. Ah,
well that's too bad.
Yeah.
Aww. That's too bad. You know what I mean?
You know what's weird about watching
porn as much as you watch it, you know,
nobody wants to do it. No, but
that was not a fucking job.
All right, let me read
this here. Go to the page,
go to the page.
That's what I sage.
All right, here we go. Is
it going to come up for me?
Okay.
Viral video of meltdown over for how
exactly did they figure out who she was?
How does the Internet get to
the bottom of all of this stuff?
All right, here we go. Uh, recently,
a viral video video went viral.
Having a meltdown over a forehead kiss.
Yeah.
Yeah. This all happened at a
Santa Monica or restaurant.
Okay.
Go so far to believe that the women, a
woman is something, something that seems,
oh Jesus Christ. Yeah. Come
on man. It's not enough.
It's not enough. She made an ass
of herself. We've got to take it.
I don't want to fucking know about
this person. Feel bad for him.
She turns a life around.
All right. Update.
Great Barrier Reef is
time for another update.
Sounds like your skepticism of the
reports that it ain't all that bad was
warranted. All right. The Great
Barrier Reef. Yeah. This is more shit.
I don't want to read about fucking people
have gone crazy doing porn and I don't
read about the fucking great barrier
reef died. What are you guys doing to me?
I got another fucking 27 minutes to go.
Oh my God.
Is this the Holy Shit. Okay, great.
Barrier Reef at terminal stage scientists
despair at latest coral bleaching data
Australia's politicians has betrayed the
reef and only the people can save it.
Oh I should read this cause maybe I dunno,
maybe they can turn it around.
Cause there are uplifting stories
about nature out there. You know,
where certain species are making a big
comeback, you know what I mean? All right.
Back to back.
Severe bleaching events have affected
two thirds of Australia's Great Barrier
Reef. A new aerial survey
have found the founding.
The findings have caused alarm amongst
scientists to say the proximity of the
2016 and 2017 bleaching event is
unprecedented for the reef and we'll give
damage, coral little chance
to recover. Um, all right.
What side is this? This is called the
Guardian. Now what? What is their agenda?
Yeah. I mean you never know
what the fuck. Believe here,
scientists with the Australian
Research Council, Center of Excellence,
Jesus Christ, take it
down a little bit, Huh?
Fucking arrogant bastards for
coral reef studies. Last week,
compiled aerial surveys of the world's
largest living structures, scoring,
bleaching at 800 individual coral
reefs across 8,000 kilometers.
The results show the two consecutive
mass bleaching events have effected 1500
kilometer stretch, leaving only
the rates southern third unscathed.
Oh boy.
Okay.
Oh,
there you go.
Okay.
You know what the deal is? We have to go.
A significant portion of us have to go.
You know,
maybe it's good that the robots come.
Are they going to be electric robots?
Are they going to require oil also?
But you know something.
All these fucking electric cars,
you know when you go to just split
that Tesla, that giant Tesla battery.
Now what do they do with that?
When you're done with the car,
what happens to that battery?
I know that car constantly has updates.
Does that also include the battery?
Can you make the battery better?
Let's look that up.
I bet there's a bunch of fucking
oil companies putting some shit out.
True or otherwise about this. Um, Tesla.
Okay.
Car.
Footprint.
Okay.
Let's
see. The carbon footprint of
Tesla manufacturing Teslas.
Electric cars aren't as green as you might
think. The electric cars aren't green.
Yeah, nothing is green.
Nothing is green. Okay.
Then Doug Stanhope, Doug
Stam. Nope. Had a great joke.
He said the greatest thing
you can do is kill yourself.
And I would go further
if he didn't just say,
and then add yourself buried in the
topsoil so you'll get fucking give it some
nutrients.
Um,
actually we're also full of fucking
God knows what Mcdonald's and shit.
You'd probably cause the tree
next to your body to die. Um,
does the Tesla model s electric
car pollute more than an SUV?
This is the green car
report. All right, let's see.
Okay,
let's see
who's kidding?
Who the Tesla is not about being green.
That's about going zero
to 60 in 2.3 seconds.
Does that supposedly clean green test?
Somara s really pollute more than a
gas guzzling jeep grand Cherokee sports
utility vehicle.
That's what one analyst has claimed.
Now what I love about this is
everybody has a dog in the fight.
Obviously the oil guys don't want you
to switch over to the fucking electrical
shit and all the electric people,
they are so convinced at batteries.
You know? Did Michael Jordan do
a commercial a long time ago,
but recycling your batteries
to need do that. You know?
That's how I know about it. Right,
because an athlete told me not to do it,
but what about that giant battery
at the bottom of the Tesla?
What do you do with that thing?
What do you do with that when it's done?
All right.
In an exhaustive 6,500 word article on
the financial websites seeking alpha
analysts,
Nathan Weiss lays out a case model
s that the case model s actually.
Okay. Okay. We know what he
said. He said it was worse
as an owner. I was shocked. For
me, I just felt this is crazy.
Although the carbon emissions, we're not
a big factor in my decision. Blah, blah,
blah, blah. Okay.
Okay.
Weiss has been advising his clients to
short the stock of Tesla and it's good.
Okay.
All right. Not so fast. Power
plant emissions counter. All right.
I'm not reading all this fucking shit.
You know what this is.
This is just a media war right now going
on and I don't know where the fuck to
get the facts and I'm not going to just
look at the up the first goddamn thing
and read it. I have no idea. You know?
But I can tell you this. All right.
I know that guy that had a Tesla has
like ridiculous security roundup because
remember that Gao came up with the car
that could drive across the country just
on water and then he went
around and told people about it.
His last words when he walked out of the
diner was they poisoned me and then he
died and then his car disappeared.
Um, I know that sounds crazy,
but that's a true fucking story. It's
a true story according to the Internet.
All right, follow up girl. Who gave,
we'd ultimatum. I love the followups.
Everybody. This is like our own
little mini series here on podcast.
This is tremendous. I'll give you that
guy's name too if you guys can look it up.
But you guys let me know if you think
this is fucking, yeah. All right. Uh,
water power.
Car
inventor vanishes. What is
his name? What's his name?
What's the name of the fog and
water guy? Yes. Stanley Myers.
Water fuel cell.
There you go.
Look that guy up. Go down that
fucking Rad. Hope rabbit hole.
M e y e r I think is how you spell it,
right?
Stanley Stanley's are always
fucking honest, aren't there?
Um, one of my favorite promoters around
the country, that's his first name,
Stanley, right. Is fucking rain. Um,
all right, follow up to the girl who
gave me the weed ultimatum. All right,
for those of you missed the podcast a
couple times ago, there was a, this woman,
this guy was dating,
you know,
he's always smoking weed around her as
she had problems with alcohol and shit.
And then one day,
I don't know,
she cleaned up and she just lashed out
at him and said he needs to just totally
quit smoking weed or you know, it's
either her or the wheat. All right,
so here we go. It says, Yo
brother bill on four, three.
You responded to my email about the
ultimate and my girlfriend gave me, uh,
her versus wheat. Uh, my fucking
computer's going to die. Hang on.
I got to hit pause.
I can't keep fucking yammered expect you
guys to listen to this shit. Hold on.
All right, I'm back. I'm back. I'm powered
here. I'm powered up here. All right.
On four, three, he responded to
my email about the ultimatum.
My girlfriend gave me her versus we'd
be the choose her or the weed man.
Uh,
she has sense admitted that she was being
a cunt by giving me the ultimatum and
no longer cares if I smoke. She has
since been smoking more weed than me.
And two days after she
gave me the ultimatum, the
following happens yet, dude,
I don't even need to read this. See, this
woman is unstable. She needs to get help.
And if I was you,
I'd get out of this relationship,
but I'll read it for the
entertainment value here. Uh,
she stumbled into our apartments
so drunk that she couldn't stand.
She was accompanied by another
man. Oh, bonus. Here we go.
The guy she was with happened to be the
one guy that she swore she'd never talk
to again because a couple months ago he
sent her a 10 page email professing his
love for her and trying to convince her
that I'm an asshole and she should be
with them. Up until that point, they
were friends that hung out on occasion,
which I was okay with, oh Jesus.
But after he sent the love letter,
which she read to me, she told me
she would never speak to him again.
Why did she read this to you? You
didn't need to hear all of that. Okay.
Anyways,
back to the cup a couple of days ago,
we got in a fight and I said I was
going to leave because of the bullshit.
We'd ultimatum,
but instead she left.
What?
Anyways, back to a couple of days ago.
So wait, when did she stumble into,
this is like a fucking Tarantino movie.
Two days after she gave me.
All right,
so I guess before this bullshit happened,
you said you were going to leave
due to the fucking weed ultimatum.
Is that what you're telling me?
But instead she left claiming she was
spending the night at her sisters and said
she went straight to this dude's place,
got shit faced drunk,
went to a bar with him, then came
back to our apartment, both of them.
She did not expect me to be home.
When she saw that I was there,
he immediately walked out.
Oh Jesus. She was so drunk.
She was unresponsible.
So the fight didn't come until the next
morning when she claimed that the only
reason he walked in was probably because
he was just making sure she got home
safely. Oh boy. Um,
I told her that I'm done and then
I'm moving back to my home state,
seeing as she's the only reason I no
longer live in my home state. Good,
good move. Good move.
Sir. Since this incident,
she has been crying and begging for
me to stay and wants to get married,
et cetera.
I get the fuck Outta here.
She claims that she has no interest in
him and she was just mad at me and was
under the impression that I had already
packed my things and left and she just
needed a friend.
At the moment,
those are all lies and this is the
tip of the fucking iceberg, sir.
That goes all the way down to the
fucking ocean floor. Personally,
I don't think I can forgive
her on her or trust her,
but I need to make a decision and
fast get the fuck out of there, sir,
because I'm either going to tough
this out and stay here. Oh Jesus.
Hoping this shit doesn't happen again or
I'm going to get the fuck out of dodge
and moved back home and start over.
Help me out, brother. Should it,
should I stay or should I go your
thoughts? Thanks. And Go fuck my life.
No, not fuck your life. If
you stay, you're fucking,
you'll have to get out of there now that
you just heard what you wrote out loud
back by me reading it out loud,
which probably made no sense. Um,
okay.
You realize how insane that is.
How insane it would be for you to do that.
Um, I'm almost thinking it as much
as she needs to get her life to get,
you need to look at yourself as to why
you would stay with a person like this.
Okay?
Yeah. You need to get the fuck
out of it, dude. All right.
You still got your
whole life ahead of you.
Okay.
All right. And as far as
like marrying somebody, you
basically get one draft pick.
All right?
Cause when you get divorce,
your franchise gets cut in half and then
you start drafting in the later rounds.
You know you're getting older and shit.
This is your number one draft pick.
This is what you're going to pick this
person with all the fucking problems that
happen at the college level.
I'm telling you.
Get the fuck out of it. Right
it dude. I mean Jesus Christ.
If you don't believe me, go, go as
tell 20 strangers that fucking story.
I swear to God they're all
going to say the same thing.
Get the fuck out of there.
Okay,
go on Doctor Phil Hill.
Do you need to get the fuck out of dodge?
He'd say the same thing.
Actually, he probably wouldn't
be because she's a woman.
His audience is female. So he
probably got, well maybe if you
smoked a little less weed and she tried
to fuck a little less other people,
maybe y'all could find a middle ground.
Now we're going to be like, Woo.
I inserted myself into that situation.
All right.
Men going their own way. You can't go. Oh.
Um,
all right.
This is a fucking amazing bouquet.
Hey Yo Billy boy.
I was wondering if you are secretly behind
this movement. This is fucking crazy.
This right here is,
um,
there's some movement
evidently down in Australia,
down in all Aussie down in all
is whatever the fuck they say.
I don't know if the fuck they say, I've
only been there a couple of times. Oh,
the plug came, I'd done.
Was there a reason why they
turn the plug into a magnet?
You know, back when it plugged in, it did
much better. I guess it's easy to find,
you know, it's got navigation kind
of, and you can find the fucking hole.
But it won't stay in there. All right. Uh,
there's a growing movement of men in
Australia called men going their own way.
I just paused for all the guys listen to
this with their girls so she could have
time to roll the rise and be
like, oh God. All right. M,
g t o w Mega Sao.
Um,
it's an offshoot of the
men's rights movement,
but rather than getting stuck in and
tack stuck in and tackling issues,
okay.
Now, rather than getting
stuck at tackling issues,
these guys have vowed
to stay away from women,
stop dating and not have children.
Jesus.
Essentially m g t o w was a statement
about living your life rather than trying
to make a woman happy. Sorry, happy.
Sorry, screamed all my jokes last night.
Or being a slave to cultural expectations.
One sw members says,
um,
this isn't about a specific rule book.
More a mindset.
Although there are purists in the movement
who are the most extreme and avoid
women entirely. There's a growing
number of men who've had enough,
enough of the feminism and enough of
being told they have to work for a greater
good,
which doesn't actually exist.
Start looking into this manosphere and
it's like going down a rabbit hole.
This person says,
happiness here is supposedly freedom and
shutting relationships is now sweeping
through the younger generations.
Is it or is this just a very
interesting article? Okay,
Tom 15 from NSW north,
south west, whatever the fuck
that is is what you call it,
what you would call the growing
number of teens going their own way.
Jesus kid never even got off the
ground. He goes, it's probably not.
It's probably not true. But I got to
Philly and women are actually dangerous.
Maybe the men around me have
just had bad experiences.
He tells the news woman.
Um,
you said it's scary being a teenage boy.
I'm not sure how it all,
it's all meant to fit together
in the future. Says Tom,
last year my uncle lost everything
because his wife of 40 years decided she
didn't love him anymore. Just like
that. She randomly got up and left.
It got nasty and he lost everything.
His house, cars and loads of money.
There's no way I'm ever getting
married. Well they, I mean Shit,
you saw a very traumatic thing.
Of course,
teenage boys look at other males in
their life together. Some perspective.
I'm just going to read quotes cause
I'm not gonna read all this. Uh,
my older brother who's 20,
was dating a girl for a few months.
She turned real nasty in the breakup
and made a string of allegations to the
police. That made me suspicious of women
to my mother. My brother's a good guy.
Okay.
Okay. Why should she be able
to just say what she wants,
accuse him of anything and then
get on with her life like that?
It doesn't seem fair to me. I'm not
sure what rights I have. Maybe none.
Yeah.
Okay. Both sex is okay. It's crucial
that we encourage our children,
find a mentor or a teacher of some
blah, blah, blah. Someone who supports,
communicate the, yeah. About skills
of getting a healthy relationship.
That's exactly what I was going to say.
Yeah.
What do you get? You just going
to walk away from women, you know,
you're never gonna Bang another one.
Maybe just go on Tinder.
Look, you can get a lot done not being
in a relationship, male or female.
Just focus it on your fucking
career buddy. And you know,
if you want to be alone,
that's fucking cool. But uh, to do
it because of fear reasons is wrong,
but you need to learn how to do is set
up your relationship and how you set up a
relationship is you have to,
you don't pretend to be something.
You're not.
Just tell him what the fuck you want
from day one when she's going like, do
you watch sports all the time? Be like,
yeah,
I love them.
Okay,
love it. Do you know what I
like doing most when I do that?
Like drinking a beer and then going
out smoking a cigar. That's what I do.
Hey Sweetheart, what do you do? Don't lie.
Just tell me what you do and let's
see if what you do mixes. What's what,
what I do. Because if we both start
pretending that we don't do it,
we go and pitch a minute, go
back to go. Well, we don't know.
We all make God you changed.
No, I didn't change. I just,
I just started being myself
for the first time around you.
Okay.
I didn't mention that I was
into a dog sleds. Yeah. Uh,
well I just figured during
the first three months,
like I'd make you fall in love with me
and then I would bring my 18 huskies into
the fucking house. Um, all right.
You're talking about a guy who's made
every fucking possible mistake that you
can make in a relationship.
I've fucked up more goddamn
relationships with great women.
I got to taste something. Okay. You know?
Yeah.
I, I, I dated some great and I,
I fucked him all up. All right.
And it wasn't until I met my now wife,
not saying I did make a bunch
of fucking mistakes after that,
but I just met somebody, dad. Uh, I dunno.
I was in that part of my life where
I could just be like, all right,
this is what I do. Is that what
you do yet? I never get, no,
that's the one thing I am,
you own a few things.
I am proud of all the relationships I've
had with women as I've never liked a,
I never judged him as far as like
whatever the fuck they were into.
I didn't give a shit. You
know, whatever you want to do,
just just fucking do it.
Because I just looked at it like
if I give you that sort of freedom,
then you'll give it back to me.
And if you don't then I'm,
I'm fucking out of here.
And what are you going to say?
What are you going to say? That's
the thing that's my, you know,
my friends come over there.
Jesus Christ fail.
You always fucking
cleaning up the kitchen.
You fucking doing all this type of shit
around the house. It's, I can't exactly,
it's the genius.
I earn a great living and then I
come home when I fucking crush it.
Yup.
So then when I want to go out and go
see my buddy played drums tonight,
what's my wife going to say? No. Why?
Because you have a daughter.
Ah Shit. You're right. Okay.
She got the daughter car now.
So what am I going to do?
Plus I fucking love my daughter. So break
coming off there. Not Match the best.
It's the greatest thing ever.
Greatest thing ever. She's not,
she's slept through the
night for the first time. Um,
of course the day I had to get
up early, you know, and fly out.
So I missed the last
three hours. She, she,
I think she slept that she slept from
like 10 to like seven in the morning.
It was fucking unbelievable.
And um,
she's such a cute, happy, chill kid.
I'm so happy about that. You know,
cause I am a fucking lunatic and I,
she's not home right now.
That's why I'm doing the
podcast a little late too.
So she's out with her
mother and that is my goal.
You know, I don't know if we'll
have another one. I have no idea.
But whatever kid or kids that I ended
up having, I want them to be happy,
relaxed. I want them to feel like they
can approach me. They can ask questions.
I am by no means going to be a pushover.
I'm not going to buy him a bunch of Shit.
I'm already against that by and kids
fucking toys before they're like three
years old or two and a half is stupid.
They don't even know what toys are. Okay.
They want to go out in the kitchen,
they want to play with pots and pans.
You know, they want to play with you
shoes. They want to play with everything.
But toys, toys actually bore them.
Okay. You get them some pots and pans.
It's over. They love him. They like
the noise, they liked the handles.
They like make it a fucking
mess. It's great. Um,
but you know, I'm not going to be
that fucking person by, you know,
78 fucking iPad.
Be Funny by daughter's pissed at me in
the future and she goes back and listens
to this episode is now playing it to me
sometime in the future. You know, Jesus.
Oh, that'd be a rough one. Anyways. Uh,
let's plow ahead. Let's get, um, yes.
I would say like that whole, like men
going their own way. I don't know. It's,
that's silly. Why would you
do that? You're 15 years old.
You're in the prime of your life.
You don't,
don't want to be in a relationship to
just be that Gail finger banks checks on
the weekends, you know? And then on Monday
when you go to school and they're like,
hey, you know, like we going to
do that again and be, I, you know,
if you want to hang out, I
mean, I'm kind of doing so,
and then when they fucking go and like,
so what should deal you just going to
finger me? And it's just like, what?
You didn't enjoy it.
Okay.
Yeah. And like, I did
something bad, you know, just,
I just don't want to be in a relationship
right now. I'm young, you know?
And they called it finger banging,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo.
I'm Eric girlfriends.
Spiked my drink.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ. You know what's funny?
If I said that in front of a crowd,
everyone would laugh. It's the
other way around. Everybody gasps.
What she do is spike your drink
and fucking take your wallet.
Okay.
That's a woman raped some man.
Um, all right. Uh, hey bill.
A couple of months ago,
I went to a party,
went to a garden party to reminisce
with my old France a couple months ago.
That was Ricky Nelson. Everybody
if you didn't recognize it. Um,
a couple of months ago,
I went to a party with a few friends.
Among them was the girl that would become
my current girlfriend and a few drinks,
but was shocked to see
just how drunk they got me.
I don't remember the entire night
because I was so drunk, you know,
some of these is so fucking over the top.
I just can't believe.
Don't even tell me.
Then you ended up with this person.
I'm supposed to believe this.
I went to the bathroom twice because I
felt that was going to throw up. Today.
My girlfriend confessed to me that she
and her friends had spiked my beer with
shots of vodka.
That's not so bad at some college shit.
He didn't taste it.
She thought it was a funny prank until
I clearly expressed how fucked up that I
was. She apologized and all that
saying she never wanted to hurt me.
But I'm thinking this is break upworthy.
Most of my friends and
family agree I should leave.
This isn't the only issue
in our relationship.
And I'm thinking red flags at this
caliber are too large to ignore.
Should I walk away?
We'll dude,
you only gave me one
piece of the puzzle there.
Okay.
You know,
if she was drunk and she was in a silly
mood with their friends and they fucking
did that.
MMM.
I Dunno.
But like it seems like there's a bunch
of other shit that she's doing and uh,
you already seem convinced
that you should fucking walk.
So I don't know what the other stuff is,
so I can't give you advice on that one.
Sir. I don't have in that you,
you, I'm a hung jury on this one.
I need, I need more information
and I don't know what to tell you.
MMM.
So I dunno if that's the only one that
you were going to tell me and that's not
a great way to start a relationship.
Okay.
It is kind of funny though.
I Dunno. I'm kind of an LTE,
so in a way that's my dream girl.
Do you know at some point you also got
to admit that she knows she did buy a
couple of shots that night, didn't she?
You just didn't know it. Um, all right.
I'm taking a lot of shit on me.
TV for me.
TV taping,
a couple episodes of 'em.
Oh,
with what the fuck's,
his name of that show was he was
show Valerie Bertinelli was in
with the red headed lady.
Okay.
And then the other chick and
then Schneider next door.
The fuck was the name of that show.
Not The apartment.
Not The odd couple.
Not Three chicks in a janitor of,
what the fuck was the name of that?
Shut God.
S C H Snyder.
Sit Calm.
Let's see what we got.
What do we get one day at a time.
One day at a time. I take a
couple episodes of that and
then an episode of Alice.
I didn't remember how those
fucking theme songs went.
Do you guys remember those
ones day in a day at a time
theme?
It's called this,
is it the fuck out of here?
What happened to my memory?
See if I remember this.
Okay.
Oh yeah,
I used to have such good
crush and Valerie Bertinelli, but
the, they were so fucking broke.
That's what all these fucking
70 sitcoms were about.
They were just fucking broke ass people.
I guess it was a reflecting the
economy at the time, you know,
like Alice was like,
you know,
divorce driving this piece of shit
to Phoenix Ford Ltd station wagon.
What is it that cannot
be the real fucking song
that was fucking horrible singer.
That's what happens when we let
the star of the show sing it.
Did she sing that fucking thing?
You know what?
I can actually block out the sing and
to listen to the old studio musicians.
That's what I missed because now
it's just some asshole. What?
The fucking laptop and the keyboard.
Those are all individual people
playing all those instruments.
Oh
Jeez.
God
got divorced,
got the station wagon and
I'm in a new neighbor hood.
Remember that kid who played Tommy?
He was fucking adorable.
And then in between like
season five and season six,
he grew like three feet and
that includes his teeth.
All of a sudden you had these fucking
horse teeth. He was fucking gigantic.
He looked like he went from fucking being
her kid to be in the a walk on for the
Phoenix Suns. Um, anyways,
that's the podcast for this. Uh,
for this Monday, I want to thank
everybody that came out. Um,
two shows at the majestic theater
on a Sunday night. And Noah,
you guys had to go to work the next day.
I had such a great time.
San Antonio is great. I didn't talk
about it. I went to the spurs game,
went to the spark as far as fucking,
uh,
against the La Clippers. Great
game. Fucking amazing fans. Very,
very knowledgeable of the game. I got
to see their five championship trophies.
They got him right out
there where you can see him,
took a picture and all that
shit was great. And um,
but I gotta tell you something.
If you want to win some free shit,
go to a spurs game. I've never seen so
much free shit given out of my life.
First of all,
they had this coyote and a mask and a
up a guy in a coyote mascot costume and
like 19 times during the game he stoled
the vendor's cotton candy and they would
play the Benny Hill Song.
Yeah.
And the vendor would sort of mock
chase them around is a thing,
was fucking throwing free
cotton candy all over the place.
They did that like 10 fucking times,
which made me immediately think like
they ordered too much cotton candy this
month.
It's going bad.
Let's just get rid of the shit
so we don't have to throw it out.
And we'll also look like, you know,
like we're good guys for giving it away.
They had cookies coming down
from the ceiling in parachutes.
You know, they would just float down.
People jumping up for fucking cookies.
They dragged some guy out of
the fucking crowd and put us,
put a couch that you could recline
it and they put it at the foul line.
They're like, if you could sit down and
you can fucking sink this file shot,
we're going to give you this couch.
And next thing you know,
I geeky like you forget about the game.
There's so much shit going on.
I'm rooting for this fucking couch potato
to when a new fucking couch to slowly
die on, you know, shoots the
first one. Oh, the next one,
rems out. Oh. And then he hits
it and it was like freaking out.
He's jumping up and down his man tits
flopping all over the place and then they
just drag this leather porn couch off guy.
You're fucking water and your water.
All right. And then you're looking up at
the scoreboard like, oh, wait a minute,
I'm watching the fucking sparse.
They're playing the clippers.
That's what's happening here.
This is a critical part of the game.
There's a timeout.
Now I'm watching Awkward Dad's dancing.
Who's the Best Awkward Dad Dancing?
Other than that, it was fucking great.
I really enjoyed it. And um, that was
franchise number 118 that I've seen.
I know I'm getting like
the rain man with this.
I got eight left and
until the next season,
you know when the La chargers
in the Vegas Knights start.
But I plan on knocking
those guys out early, early.
I might even go to that first charges
game just for them having the audacity to
fucking move on me. You
know, as of right now,
in this moment,
I've seen every team fucking west of the
Mississippi from fucking as far south
as San Antonio is far north is Edmonton
and these two consequent to come along
and fuck the whole thing up for me.
I will not tolerate that.
I will avoid my family. I will take a
trip and I will go see both of these.
Fuck why? I'll take a trip to San
Diego. I sound like a crazy person.
Go fuck yourselves.
Thank you for listening and I'll
check in on you on Thursday.