Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it's time for a another
special edition of the Monday morning
podcast. If you new to my podcast, you
probably say, Hey, what's his special,
what's a special one? Usually I'm here
by myself laying in my fucking underwear,
running my yap, but every once in a while
I have a special guest and uh, this,
this person will not let you down.
This is one of my great friends in this
business is one of the funniest bastards
I haven't met in my life.
He has a new special coming out on
Netflix called mouthful of shame on a,
that's already funny on March 14th
please welcome the legendary Jim Norton.
Thank you bill.
That's a nice intro.
I don't know how to handle nice
things being said about me. I know.
Does it make you
uncomfortable with people?
I was going as big as I could
go through when you score me.
One of my great friends, one of the
best comics I ever saw. Just listen,
just watching you squirm over there. I
can handle personal things are a Gar away.
We are from one another.
It is odd.
My manager's kind of saying they're
uncomfortable with this fucking giant cock
bulge in the middle.
It looks like a retired figure skater.
Sorry. All right. Anyways,
I can handle personal like,
because we are great friends,
but any type of compliments of
work, I can't. It makes me so like,
do you like watching clips of yourself?
I'm going to torture you for this.
Drives me nuts, dude. I watched he,
we get to watch a clip of yourself when
they bring you back and then the people
in the room like, ah, Yay. That was
good. It's so fucking [inaudible].
If you ever do a talk show
and then they're light and
they play either something
you've already done or whatever you're
promoting, I literally will, uh, you know,
if they cut to it and I actually look to
monitor to see if the crowd's watching
it at home and then I just literally,
I'll put my fingers in my ears if I have
to. I'll start humming now. Humiliating.
It's horrific.
Do it man.
I can't watch because then they
feel like they're fake laughing.
Like they don't really like it.
They're just playing along to me polite.
I feel like they're just kind of
being nice to little Jimmy Norton.
They just being polite to me.
The only way I can watch
myself as if I filmed myself at
a club and I'm just watching it.
But the second that I would,
if I knew it was going to be uploaded or
broadcasted and I know that everybody's
going to see it immediately, I'm like, oh
my God, why did I do that with my hand?
What did this fucking sell?
Everything immediately. It's horrific.
But having said that,
I uh,
I actually made sure my last
special that I sat through it.
I sat through a couple of times to make
sure that at least I had like the look
of it,
the look of it right now.
Did you do that with your new special
mouthful of shame that comes out in March?
I'm going to hype the shit out of this.
It's funny. Yeah, I did it obsessive.
I probably seen it about 60 times,
but just in editing,
like I don't mind watching it to edit.
Like I go point by point over both shows.
I want, I know exactly what I want from
the late show Polish from the early show.
I'm really anal about it. That's
good. That's good to have. Yeah.
Cause I don't trust that
like anyone else it,
Netflix is easier cause
there's no commercials you
have to worry about and they
don't give a shit if it's 56 minutes for
promos it can be an hour and two hour
and three. So I was very comfortable
doing that. But like you said,
as soon as somebody else in the room,
I want to hang myself but
I can do it alone all day.
Cause I know I'm doing it as part of,
it's still part of the work.
But once it's done I'm like
I can never watch it again.
Oh I walk out of the room second
other people in to watch it.
Oh Hey can I see a thing here?
And absolutely.
And then they sit down and I
closed the door and walk out.
Could you watch it with Nia? Could
you watch it with someone you really,
really close to if like it's not like
somebody you need to impress her.
I just don't have to be standing up and
would be standing up with my fucking
hands on top of my head like that.
Like, Eh, is it good? Is it suck?
I'd be doing that the whole time.
And she literally gets mad going shut.
She knows that this point, Nia
knows to be like, you know,
she'll just come up and say, Hey, I
watched your special, it was good.
Or I watched this, it was good and blah
blah. And I go, okay, good. You know,
like if some, if a parts coming
up that you don't like legal, I,
and I hated the way I did this
thing like right before it happens.
Cause you like,
you don't want them to watch
it and pretend to like it
when you know it's not it,
it's fucking psycho. Have that thought
buttons. It comes out like this. I just,
I just go, ah, it's just a noise.
I just yell over over and it just,
it will bother her.
But I've also learned
that, uh, yeah, it just,
that you're going to think it's way,
way worse than it fucking is.
But don't you find the comedians who are
so comfortable watching themselves saw
something wrong with that? Man, I can't,
I keep your eye back could literally
watch a fucking marathon of their entire
career and be oh yeah, I love that
sport coat. I loved when I wore that.
The way I roll those sleeves up.
I absolutely love this one.
It was a dog and cat thing.
Oh you're gonna love this.
You know I've been a loop.
I've, I'm not a loop a tear watching
Robert Klein videos cause I,
we are having him coming in and I,
and he's one of my idols and I'm watching
like Robert Klein from the tonight
show in 81 82 83 watch them on
74 on soul train or whatever.
He was fucking great man.
Robert Klein is a guy that most people
don't mention like no one talks about
Robert Klein anymore.
As much as I mentioned prior and Carl and,
and Robert Client is the most
underrated guy I think to ever.
Seinfeld always gives him a bunch of
props and was talking like how he, he was,
I think that was one of his guys.
He liked Cosby and Robert Klein I believe.
And um, I forget how he put it,
but he was like sort of their age,
like when he was still in those things
in the 70s and he was going to colleges,
like he was like that age part of that
generation. So he was kind of there.
Thank keep like Carlin
was more of a sixties guy,
even though he blew up
in the 70s. I think, um,
people from that generation
remembered them, but it's,
it's weird how some people,
despite their contributions will kind
of slip through the cracks like that.
It's, I find with most people
that when that are like,
that they're not into self promotion.
So if you're not spoon feeding it,
like the amount of fucking journalists out
there, if you just tell them, you know,
like, uh, I'm one of the edgiest
guys on the set, like, oh,
well what not that's tuned to stripe.
But if you're, you're like the, um, uh,
I would always like to, I dunno, I would,
I would equate it to Detroit
that calls itself hockey town.
Like they gave themselves a fucking
nickname. Like why are you a hockey town?
Wouldn't it at least be Montreal,
Montreal Canadians.
They have the most fucking uh,
you know,
championships they've got the fans will
literally drive out of town. I mean,
why, because you're that, well no
one Michael Jackson the king of Pop,
not saying he wasn't good,
but he kind of gave himself
that like right that nickname.
But like have a lot of hacks do that and
nobody thinks that somebody will be a
big enough asshole to give
themselves a nickname.
So people just kind of go with it.
Like people must have called him the
king of pop cause nobody can be that
fucking narcissistic to give himself
the nickname, the king of pop.
But he probably did.
And the press loves them because
they write the story for them.
That's why they'll love a Rex Ryan.
But hate bill Belicheck like Bella
check is smart enough to be like,
you constantly going to take any little
thing that I say and turn it into bolts
and board material. That's why he
stands that gun, you know they're good.
And I think next week's going to
be a tough game and just taking a,
why don't we get time and then they
want a guy like Rex Ryan go look,
oh gonna win the Super Bowl.
Then they love him.
I didn't come here to kiss the ring.
The I'm going to go in there,
we're going to shove it right up
their ass. And they're just like,
like before he's done talking,
their article is written. Yeah.
Milania go foreign 12 yeah.
I Love Rex Ryan.
I love what a priority is. I live
with that. He loves his wife's feet.
He's the best one. He
loves his wife too. Yeah,
he does know his wife keeps him
on the rails. I swear to God,
if he didn't have that guy
would ate himself to death.
I see it like all that
shit talk and he does.
You see like that's why I love that guy.
When I watch him,
like he's his flaws. I'm
like, Oh my God, this guy,
he's a shit show.
This guy is a shit show.
And he loves his wife to
death because she saved them.
You totally see the whole thing. Yeah.
He's a disaster. He's a disaster.
I was trying to say it in a
nice way. Yeah, but he is.
But there's something endearing
about that and not, you know,
I just started watching football again.
I can't care about it. Uh, I'm like, wow,
you're the biggest one. We
would come up. You were huge.
Campbell's always fan and then you were
huge Yankee Fan. I just, I stopped,
I started going on the road more and more.
I just stopped caring
as much and I'm like,
I'm putting in so much effort to these
guys and I meet them and they don't give
a shit that I'm alive. I had a couple
of bad experiences with athletes on,
I remember done. Yeah, I was wrong
about the Jeter thing. I was a baby.
I really act like a little douchebag.
I was fucking rat.
He was a deck to nighttime,
but I way overreacted on the air.
I'm embarrassed by that.
Well, if you, if you,
if you go to the psychology
of the way you overreacted,
it wasn't really just your love
for the guys and the team. Yes.
You are a jilted lovers.
Patrice used to always say absolute lover.
That's exactly what it is. I
mean, you know, uh, the, the,
the husband that becomes a stalker is
the guy that was obsessed with his white,
like, you know, that's what I
was, I was obsessed with them.
And then they didn't love me more than
my biggest meltdowns was gene Simmons
because he hurt my feelings.
He blew me off and I wanted a photo and
he was kind of a dick about it and it
just ruined me and I fucking
killed him on the radio about it.
And I kind of felt bad because he was
nice to me. The next time I saw him,
I met him one time. He was teasing
me about losing my hair and shit.
I just so wanted to be like,
dude,
do you think of anybody's buying that
fucking Darth Vader helmet wearing a walk
in your fucking head?
That's terrible that he
as Chewbacca his hairline
dude. It is like shoe Polish, black.
I mean you can you talk to the guy
and your kids kid not even look at.
But what I love about him is he would
sit here and laugh right along with you
and not give a fuck and then just scribble
down Chewbacca with hair and the next
day they'd be a picture of him dressed
as Chewbacca with some his shit written
on it and he would make $1 million on
unreal unapologetically go make $1 million
off of it. He really doesn't care. You
don't. One thing I like about Gina,
and this is one thing that Dee Dee,
Dan rather interviewed him and he
talked about his, he's a patriotic guy.
Like nobody loves America more than
Gene Simmons because his mother was in a
concentration camp and she came here and
when he was a kid and he remembers he
did. I think he was Iranian are the
biggest kiss fan. Yeah. Yeah. No,
you're way off. This is about
as far off. Yeah, he was.
He's a Brazilian. I thought he
was Irish. Yeah, he's a, he's a,
he was born in his name.
His real name is hime whites I think.
And he was born in Israel and he said his
mother's Zig high old when she came to
Ellis Island.
And he tells that story to Dan Rather
about how moving it was to have them tell
her to put her arm to it.
So you watch that and it's like,
that's the gene he should be showing
people. Wait, what did she do that,
cause she was,
she didn't know any better.
She came to America and she had to
pledge allegiance to America to get in.
That's what you did. So she's [inaudible]
and the guy put his, put her arm down.
It's like, no, you don't have to do that.
So if that made gene
come incredible patriot,
those people were so lucky back then
that there was no youtube that would have
ruined her life. She'll never run for
office. Never even opened a bakery.
You know the seek high,
a little girl is now coming of age
to make some pastries. Fuck you.
You Hitler love and pitch all of that
picture of her with the statue behind her.
Say Hi. Yeah, you're right.
There's no live in a town now.
Do you have any clips about you? I think
there's so many things on me that I,
that could ruin my life that I,
I think that it's almost,
there's so many that they can't at this
point. Things I've said or you know,
things I've admitted. Is it the things
in your life that you're like, fuck,
I wish I didn't talk about that way back.
Weddings.
I didn't realize that it could me
on me or do you not care? Yeah,
I mean I just,
I mean it's going happen.
It's inevitably going to happen to
everybody. They're going to go like, oh,
you said this in 2006 and be
like, oh, did I? All right,
well why don't you get into your
time machine and have me apologize.
The 2006 version of me.
You know what a lot of it is,
is I would equate it to the the Eddie
Murphy thing where Eddie Murphy delirious
and he did all that,
that material about gay people and
everybody laughed and nobody said, Shit,
I'm sort of gay. People
didn't, but mainstream did not.
And then when mainstream catches
up and starts to learn that, oh,
that's really hurtful and
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah
to gape, then all of a sudden,
and he's just like, you know, they talk
about, oh my God, they look the other way.
Bob, you know when you, when they talk
about that part of the special, they act,
it's like,
well where were you during that year?
I know you saw it and you sat there and
laughed at the same way I did. I did.
I didn't know that. I didn't know
what the Sh that it was to that level.
So I think you could do that
with anybody. Well, I think what?
Let's any off the hook, especially with
that type of material is the whole,
you know, I was giving her a ride. Excuse
me for that special young lady boy,
if that didn't make me
love Eddie, nothing. Well,
but like you have to that you're like,
Eh, all right, we get it. We get it.
Who knows he could for him. Who
knows? I get involved in people's
personal lives. I don't give a, I don't
either. And not in a judgmental way.
I love the fact when when things about
let's say any celebrity come out,
they could or could not be true.
It makes me like the more like,
it makes me understand like, yeah,
this, this is a public persona.
Like I feel bad for,
there's one major actor in particular
who miss male massage therapists said he
was doing stuff and I feel so bad
for this guy. I'm like, he said,
what did torture it is to live your life.
Being afraid you're going to get caught
or being for being who you are. Yes.
Oh God.
That's gotta be fun.
It's going to affect how much money you
make because of the, yeah, that's all.
It's all, you know, some,
a lot of that personal life shit that
kind of drove me away from ESPN because it
used to just be the games and they'd
show highlights and just seemed like a
bunch of people, you know,
broadcasting, it just loves sports.
But when they started to just keep like
delving into these people's lives and
trying to like do like the
controversy shit, I just, um, I dunno,
I just Kinda,
I got away from it after a while.
That's why I love the sports packages
and I just taped the games that I want to
watch.
I S I blow through the pregame and I,
and I never watched any
postgame analysis or anything.
I just watched the fucking
game and that's it. You know,
the Knicks recently handled
Hannibal Burress retreated
this thing where they did
the first half with,
uh,
you went to the game and there wasn't a
bunch of people running around shooting
tee shirts at you every time
there was a stoppage of play,
not a bunch of music playing.
And all I would have loved to
have gone to that game. Yeah,
it is distracting and they think we need
constant stimulation and constant noise.
Like no, we're at the game. I'm
okay just watching the game.
I'm okay if it's the
third inning and it's a,
you know it two in one and
this one I don't need I
fucking manic stop it.
Basketball's the worst.
Basketball is the worst just because they
run out into the court and it could be
like a really critical part of the game.
One Oh three one oh three timeout did.
It's like time for like one more shot
and these fucking assholes guy comes out
in a gorilla suit, tee shirts at
you and shit and it's just kind of,
it becomes like a Chucky cheese.
You supposed to be teaching
your kid the game here,
like this is really important and there's
all these people at that extra excited
look on their faces. They're
holding the tee shirt. I always,
I sit through all of that hoping
that I'm going to, you know,
nobody ever sits with me,
but I have this,
this is my little fucking dream is that
I'll sit and everyone else would just
stare at fucking daggers at them
and they won't do it anymore.
I don't give a fuck about a bunch of
con smiling, jumping off trampolines,
dunking the ball. It's actually
embarrassing. The white people like,
look how little we can jump.
It's humility. We need this here.
I saw that at a suns game. I had a great
time at the game, but that bullshit.
They're like, yeah, that calm look
crazy trampoline fucking guys.
And it's like fucking nine
white guys coming out there.
We don't need gymnastics.
Yeah. There's nobody blocking them
either. And there's Matt Paul.
It's like a nerf hoop,
like taken to the next level.
I'm sure someone's going to tweet me.
Oh,
actually it's really hard combining
those sports. But um, I hate mascots.
I think they're unnecessary
and they're stupid and they, they, they,
they child up the game. Like the, I,
we interviewed the Philly fanatic in 2001.
There's one I like to Philly fanatic.
Oh he's smells. Those
uniforms stink. I too.
I remember about being next to the
affiliate for night. The stench.
I'm sure they all smell like that,
but they all smell guess man than you
know you're out there wearing some for
fucking outfit. It's
horrendous. And to me they just,
they do nothing to make me enjoy the game.
That's what I kind of always liked about
like I hated the mets cause fucking Mr
met and that big store.
I love the lack of
imagination of that one.
It's just a guy with
a baseball for a head.
Yeah, Mister. And then they named them
after the team. I literally is stupid.
Really comes off as the first idea. What
are you going to, how about Mister Matt?
Go ahead. He's got a
baseball head. He's a guy.
Call him mister. We played
during Valentine's Day. Maybe
we going to miss his men.
I actually love a mascot standing on a
street corner holding up a tax tax thing
and doing a stupid dance.
When I'm sitting at a red light.
It makes me laugh my fucking ass off.
I don't know what it is.
I think they should have them.
Just mascot should be like in
traffic like every 200 yards.
It's just somebody doing a stupid
dance just to entertain you.
That's what I need.
Entertainment,
not when I'm fucking attic
at an entertainment thing.
I don't need entertainment during the,
in between the moments of entertainment,
you don't need extra entertainment
and it's not even entertaining.
Mascot should not entertaining.
I never watched a mascot and like,
oh that was kind of funny or cute.
It's insulting and it's related.
I would say the Philly freak,
the San Diego chicken,
there's a couple of classic ones
where they were actually funny. Um,
that's about it. I always feel
bad for the truck when they slide,
when they run in to take the big slide,
go ah, the little guy couldn't do it. No,
I like when like the Philly frequent walk
up and fuck with the umpires and mess
with people on the other other team and
stuff like that. It's, it's, I dunno,
like that's one of the classic ones,
but I forget the red sox they
tried to have on a long time ago,
it was called the Fenway freak
and he lasted like seven games.
People would just pelting
him with shit ain't,
you know what was like the 70s this is
when you could actually go there and be a
fucking alcoholic scare and children.
And then they brought this guy
out in a fucking, you know,
muppet outfit and he just got the
Philly freak. But now they have a,
Oh this is just the green monster one.
Yeah. And it's called Wally Wally, right?
Oh, it's like a pun. It's
a mascot with a pond name,
Pun for what the park is known
for. And then, then, yeah.
And then they swing sweet Caroline
during these seven things stretch.
Just when I thought your YMC horseshit
at the Yankees game, trust me, it's bad.
But at least the, you know, was the
grounds crew that kind of looked like,
all right,
like they took this boring thing and
made it entertaining a little bit.
Like that was kind of interesting to
watch people still spell out why MCA was
just, yeah, that, that's, that
was always tough to watch.
I don't need to wash the grounds crew
was singing what was probably the gay
anthem for 19,
for the 70s.
I don't need to see them fucking
saying that every seventh inning. Yeah.
That might've been the, uh, like,
like they were so gay than the
shift that they were doing,
I think would actually be
offensive to gay people.
I'm a construction worker and I have
the big mustache and I'm a leather guy.
We like, dude, like literally now
gay groups would be like, you know,
you're perpetuating stereotypes.
We go to work in gray suits just
like you do or whatever. But um,
that's fucking hilarious. Do you
remember Victor Willis the lead say,
did you know they were, I didn't know
they were gay. I was a big village.
My father took me in to
see them when I was a kid.
It was them in sister sledge was the
opening band and I didn't know legendary,
you know, disco show are absolutely,
that was like for the mighty.
If it was either them or kiss was the
first one and I didn't know they were gay,
but I found out like I didn't know what
the village was. Greenwich village thing.
I had no idea what any of that meant. I
didn't either. I thought it was cool to,
oh that's the construction worker
got YZ construction worker. Yeah.
I didn't know where musicians,
why is he just a bass player or the Indian
Phillippi rose. He's still, he's still,
he's still my favorite. I thought he
was awesome. I loved this head dress.
I really did. I actually liked
the one who looked like a,
somebody who hit on Al Pachino and crews
and Glenn Glenn was the one I liked.
I thought he was bad ass like that's
why I never saw a rob Halford from a
million miles away because I'm part
of that last generation of way.
If you wore a bunch of
leather and had a mustache,
you would like some bad ass bad ass cycle.
I didn't understand that.
There was a whole other side to that.
I had no idea.
But now you look back
on old Helford video.
I'll go back on Youtube and watch
old Judas priest from like a,
from that domain was that contract.
They didn't like 83 and Philly.
There was that. That was the, that
just live aid or whatever it was.
Do you watch priest from that and
you're like, oh, how did we not know?
It was so obvious and I love the fact
that he came out and nobody gives a fuck.
It's just how offered, you know, he's
like a big power top, you know, he just,
he's fucking ramrod. I, I've just
loved the guy. Nobody gives a shit. Oh.
I think he grew into that role.
He looked like a bottom early on.
I think as he got older, you know, he got
a little more comfortable with himself.
There's a story that he has a big Dick
and he puts some guy in the hospital,
Florence, he told me his story,
anything, if you put a guy in Ohio,
he didn't put any person in the hospital
with your Dick. You're a legend.
And I heard that there was some,
some hairdresser who for years one and
half or to find finding it's consensual.
Let's put that out there before that
clip gets you in and they're over 18.
I mean, I'm talking, you know,
the asterisk is that it's an adult in
a consensual relationship or consensual
encounter and you willingly allow him
to put your Dick and you line up in the
hospital.
That guy's a legend.
I'm just picturing the
interview afterwards with
the fucking another person.
At what moment did you realize you were
in over your head? When I was, when I,
when I told him he has to pull it out
and I realized it was still four more
interesting.
Yeah.
There was some moment where he
realized this was a bad decision,
but I heard he was bugging Alford to
fuck him and he was a hairdresser or
whatever he was. It was odd. The
whoever the guy is that how for oh,
fucked intend to the hospital and a
health word finally did it. And uh, he,
the Guy Wound, oh, you hate
fucked them. All right, fine.
I'll give you the rock star Dick. Yeah,
I hear he's packing like an animal.
So there's nothing but good, good thing
you think you did it right before a show.
So he's wearing all that
fucking awful studied shit.
It's just the sound of your screaming
in his fucking milky thighs rubbing
together leather pants. I'm sorry
everybody. Sorry. Just paint that visual.
He smells good too.
I interviewed him before a show one time.
Me and this guy Troy from
the show went to the,
I guess it was a garden or wherever they
were were the metal and he smells so
fucking good.
So I bought the same Cologne.
A lot of times I'll smell Cologne that
British rock stars have on and I'll buy
it. And it's very specific. It
never, because they smell gay.
British rock stars are just British
rock stars. No Ozzy's not gay.
Ozzie's Ozzie's the best
smelling guy in music.
Ozzie smells better than anybody
a rob Halford smells great.
You would never guess that with Aussie
ass. Not saying that. You know, just,
you wouldn't think that he smelled.
You wouldn't,
you wouldn't associate him with like
a really rich guy smell. But Ozzy,
you can smell from down the hall and he,
he has it,
I think in his hair or whatever.
It's this British Cologne and he fucking,
he smells fucking amazing.
He smells amazing.
How food also smelled good,
but it never smells good on me.
I buy it and I just smell like garbage.
How do you know I can,
I smell it on myself and I'm like,
it stinks.
I thought you can't really smell
yourself. Oh yeah, the Cologne. You can,
I put it on and it's great
for a minute. And I put like,
sure. I'm like, oh, suck it.
I said, yeah, but that's self
hatred. No, but I, I don't,
I never get compliments on it. And no
one's ever said, hey, you smell great.
And that like, you know, when Ozzie
walks you, people like you fucking smell.
That's the first thing I noticed about,
first time I met him was with Jim
Florentine in [inaudible] 97 and the first
thing that struck me is this guy smells
amazing. They're not getting enough ass.
You know what I mean?
They've got a shell like Jesus Christ.
That's where you got to fucking send
your wife into the next room. Yeah,
go get some.
You host that shit off of you police
so I can still be married at the end of
this. How funny is it
that he just, you know,
he had the whole thing with shower where
you get caught having the affair and
he's not, I loved the damage control.
Ozzie does it in an interview. He's like,
well, I'm a fucking, I'm in a fucking
band. Or No, like that's his reasoning.
Like what do you expect now
that that was the greatest?
That's something you say
to your friends though.
You don't say that in an
interview after you play.
My fucking said that I am too for if it
doesn't get them divorced, I'm happy.
He said, look, I fucking,
do you mind if fucking people that aren't
in his position that can easily sit
back, you know you'll fucking
life is, you're not in a band.
You don't have all these women fucking
throwing themselves at you. You're like,
what the fuck is he supposed to do?
I know. I know. But you how to use,
you're like a grounded guy. Like I
really mean that. Like I look at you,
you're married,
you have a baby and like you,
you're a fucking booze gym that's in
the green room until everybody leaves.
And I boost theory.
Really? Yeah, I admire,
I sit there and I just
tell stories with people.
They bring a bottle in and I'm
with like four or five of them.
I did it the last night. I was
just in a, what the fuck was,
I stand up live in Phoenix and they
brought it to have this bottle for us and
for three days we just would,
you know, taking a third,
a third and a third and by last night,
you know, we'd just sitting in there,
I go to cigar bars. I just
basically go. But dude,
I always used to look like
fucking Ralph mouth too.
So it was never really a problem.
You know what I mean?
That wasn't like a fucking
like Geraldo rest his soul.
I mean that guy was like a fucking great
in those, those guys, if you're funny.
And he had a, he had like a, I also
always had like a really, you know,
angry fucking energy.
So like most women who had even remotely
had a decent father or maybe an uncle
that they spoke to had a nice conversation
once would be running for the hills.
And I would get these absolute fucking
lunatics that would come up to me.
And um, you know, so it kind of took
care of itself to be honest with you.
It is scary when you meet women and like
to girls you dated first or for awhile
when you realize I represent something
to her. Like I'm an average looking God.
And there's some girls
I've dated who are better,
lot better looking than I deserved.
And I knew that there were
mental things and I'm like,
I represent something weird to her.
It's a father, a mouthful of shame.
I would say that, you know, it's a
monster rain. I mean the names of your,
it's very, uh, I think you've carved out
quite a niche for you. Yeah. You know,
I got,
I figured,
I gotta be honest because I once
other girl tried to blackmail me,
I had to go and try to blackmail me
one time. She had no idea who I was.
And we had hooked up a few times. Yeah.
It was a money thing, not a big expense.
We had texts, a lot of dirty fantasies,
and then she wanted me to send her money.
She's tried to blackmail me and I'm like,
well,
I'll send you money to help you with this,
but I'm not doing it that.
And she goes,
well,
maybe all your friends would want to see
your fantasies played out on Facebook.
And I'm like, you really don't know who
you're talking to. And I, and I, I texted,
I said, I don't give a fuck. Everybody who
I know knows what I'm liking what I do.
Uh, at that moment I was grateful
to be me. Yeah. You gotta be what,
when you put it all out there and
you know, they can't catch it.
It's nothing funny.
You're one of the fun,
I wish that was a scene in a movie
watching somebody's thinking that they can
blackmail somebody and they just
completely don't give a shit. Do that.
How am I going to say the guy's name?
But that happened to a hockey player.
He was like in his forties
and he, um, Oh yes. Yeah.
He hooked up with some like 1,989 it was
legal at everything and she's just like,
I'm going to tweet this out,
you know, if you don't, blah,
blah, blah. He goes, what?
Then I slept with a smoking hot chick.
Half my age. He goes, God and do it.
I don't give a fuck. And she
did. Sometimes they will.
They will at times do it. She said she was
gonna. He said he didn't care. She did.
And he didn't give a fuck and
nobody else did. Oh my God,
this guy did something illegal. Yeah. She
really didn't have like a leg to stand.
He did what we'd all love to do.
Shame on him. Good for him. But,
but if you're married, if
you got killed, you know,
there's so many guys that they like,
I heard a lot of rappers get like
girls will, you know a special ladies,
a lot of rappers you know are,
are,
are a little on the DL as they
say about certain things and uh,
they get blackmailed a lot.
Like I've heard a lot.
A lot of times the girls will go,
yeah,
I want a $30,000 I'm going to start
fucking screaming in the lobby.
And there's been times of that stuff
has worked. It's a shame Jesus.
He can't just go, go ahead, go screaming
the lobby's stupid. Well you know what,
if everyone was like me,
you could and you like I wouldn't,
I wouldn't give a shit. I was like
that's what kills me. Like whenever a,
a controversy like that comes out,
like I like you were talking about that
guy with the massage therapist and all
that stuff.
I always just think like I cannot fucking
wait to go to his next movie just to
make type of shit go away
cause right to support it.
Yeah.
Cause even the worst case scenario is
they did something where they just fucked
up. They fucked up. What am I saying? The
guy goes on the road, he banks, you know,
fucks around and his wife
every that's between them.
Does that mean I don't
like that song any better?
I those fucking people who do that shit.
Well they just go like, Oh fuck that guy.
I'm done with this movie.
Rarely get done with those movies.
I'm done with this movie's when
his movies suck. You know, if he's,
if he's not out there,
you know, they'll say,
fucking people will still going to
mass every Sunday. The Catholic church,
it wasn't everybody. It's like, is
that really what you're thinking?
That's just your fear of dying and not
knowing where you go when you die and you
don't want to piss off the
invisible guy. Right. My buddy,
my brother said it the best. He goes,
it's talking about the Catholic Church.
He goes, dude, if that was any other
fucking business, they would be shut down.
Fucking shut down. I'm, I, I'm
still on, and I think of this a lot,
but the fact that you don't believe in
name calling, I've thought that a lot,
like how negative it is and bad it is.
And it's something,
and not that I've had cause to,
cause I'm single at this point,
but can an interrelationship
with the woman.
I've never done the Europe
fucking bitch and blah,
and I would never have thought. And,
but hearing you say that it's the, yeah,
I guess it really is a
damaging thing to just do it.
I can't kick because it builds up,
it builds up resentment because
people don't forget, like, uh,
I got this weird thing. If my wife goes,
you know, you're a fucking asshole.
I don't care. I know other guys
that would be like, you know,
you like that would actually, it would
hurt him in a way that they will as a man.
They wouldn't want to admit I don't
give a shit. Um, but like I, I,
I saw enough guys growing up doing that
you fucking bitch thing and everything
like that. And I just, I
just, I saw what that did. Uh,
I was a little kid and just saw it. I
just saw it. It just, it didn't look,
you know, this big deep voice yelling at,
you know, it just was not, it just, I,
I dunno. So I just made a vow is
just one of those things. I was like,
you know what,
I'm not doing that.
But then there was other stupid behavior
that I guess I didn't recognize them
then I repeated that, but that was the one
that, that I, I didn't do. So what we do,
she calls you an asshole.
You just tell me about what she's
doing is if I go real mature,
I wish I had the presence
of mind ice. I, uh, what,
what do I do? I, you know, I definitely
say the f word a lot, but I don't, um,
you know what, now that I have a daughter,
so I really, I just, I don't do that.
I'm not gonna fucking sit there
and screaming. You can't. Yeah.
When there's a baby in the room,
change that we can stay on.
My radio partner just had a baby and it's,
see everybody I know is having kids,
it gets, it changes the way
you do shit. Right? Yeah.
Because then there's that whole,
uh,
I think for the first time in your life,
you're actually aware of your behavior
affecting other people. Right.
With, you know, with your girlfriend or
your wife. It's an adult to adult thing.
So you really don't, you're like, oh, this
person is an adult. They can drive a car.
You know, I can say this stuff, this
isn't going to affect them, you know,
but it's when you have the kid
and, and it's just like, you know,
that this could actually affect
who they marry, right? Oh yeah.
This guy that literally, you
know, if I do what I'm, you know,
if I flip out right now
and I consistently do this,
this could literally drive my daughter to
a trailer park someday. Right. You know,
and,
and be one thing,
if I was just completely oblivious
that I could just sit at a bar, Go,
now she's a fucking loser. Get Out. She
grew up in a house. Now she said a thing,
but I am kind of aware of the effect
of it now and then I would have to sit
there and take on that kind of guilt. So,
um, plus, I don't know. I, I don't, um,
uh, just growing up there was a
lot of just the era when I grew up,
like every authority authority person
was just so not approachable as I said
this and this is what it is and you
shut the fuck up. And it was that just,
you know, that's kind of what
stoke the whole fire in me,
I think. So I try to, uh,
you know,
I think you go one of two ways.
You either repeated or you just
remember that. So like, um,
I actually got a really good comment
from somebody one time. It's like,
you know what? He goes, Mike, you should
got to come by. Come by my house. He goes,
my kids love you. And I was like,
really? He goes, yeah. He goes, they,
you talk to them like they're adults.
I wasn't even aware I was doing it.
Like I would be talking to like
is a 10 year old, right. Do you,
what grade are you in? Are you
getting homework now? Ah, that sucked.
The hated that.
Like I wasn't thinking that I was and
they kind of liked it that they were
talking to adult like,
oh this is,
this is somebody older who they think
knows everything he's saying how he hated
it. Kinda gave him making it. It made
it okay to be like, oh this sucks man.
I hope that did make them not do their
fucking homework but I would just,
you know, I would address it rather than
being like, no, you need to sit down,
you need to learn it. This is what life
is. It's sitting there doing shit get,
don't want to do like that's so much
that you learn that, that you like,
you don't think that you can actually
go out and achieve shit and like life
becomes like fuck,
when is this over just staring at an
cock and people saying that,
I think hepatitis don't even mean it.
They just think it should. An adult
as supposed to stay, like to say like,
you know what I mean? Can you sit out,
you buckled down your throat, you lie.
If I said that to anybody,
I would entirely be on shut up.
You don't fucking believe that I cannot
wait to tell my daughter. I don't know.
I cannot wait to tell it. Why is this
blah blah blah. And I'll just, I dunno.
I Dunno. Why be like, well you
know, cause I don't read. Why?
I don't know cause it makes me sleepy.
I'm just going to fuck brutal honesty.
I'm just gonna own up to it.
There's a lot of stuff.
Your dad isn't good at sweetheart.
Do you want some ice cream? Yeah.
Cause you want [inaudible] I'm
in the middle. Like I, you know,
I'm in a point where I'm 48 no wife,
no girlfriend. Like I, you know,
I don't know if I'm,
if I'm the best boyfriend candidate by,
I'm tired of being single. Like
I'm, I'm kind of, oh, there you go.
That's where I think of it.
You got it
sick of it, right? Yeah. I got a no,
you know what I did was I finally,
I just looked at like what I was doing
and then, you know, we have to like,
I used to joke about that on stage.
I feel like the 90th fucking person
that doesn't go well and there's only so
long you been doing these chicks are
fucking psychos after a while. It's like,
what am I doing?
Okay
dude,
I chase him away in tech.
I've had some updated literally
for I lose in text message.
Oh, I'm so, I'm so like I want
to either talk dirty or I just,
I just want to keep pushing the envelope
and the next thing you know, um,
they stopped talking to me so I
know I'm doing something wrong.
It's not that then him not talk it over.
I'm just creeping them out on some level.
I don't know why.
That just reminded me this
last night I was watching, uh,
what does that fucking show
with Andy Cohen when he does
the wrap ups of the, uh,
the real housewives. Oh, I'm not a his
talk shows. Look what happens live. Yes.
That show that one.
So my wife always watches that show.
That's one of those crossovers
shows I have to watch what they're,
so we don't battle over the TV.
Right, right, right. So I'm watching,
it was Jennifer Lopez and I'm, oh Jesus
Christ, and just went blank on his, uh,
Ray Liotta Dude,
ray Liotta was fucking hilarious.
He just answers eight doesn't give a shit.
He just answered everything straight
up, straight up. They were like, what?
So for cocaine, like in
Goodfellas, like what did they use?
And it was like cocaine just to say that.
And they would be like, who's the most,
they played this thing, you can plead
the fifth. And He, oh yeah, he never,
he never pleaded. The fifth would
ask him. They asked him like, uh,
Oh, who's the worst kisser of, of anybody?
Easy you've been with this person.
But I suppose first and you know,
Andy's doing all the things.
So who was the worst kisser? Like this was
going to be the thing. He goes, uh, well,
I don't think I kissed any of them. And
he goes, well then who would you guess?
And he goes, oh, Sigourney weaver. Just
setting. They go, who's the worst actor,
most overrated actor or the 90s? And
he goes, most overrated. He goes bad.
I'd probably say Clint Eastwood. And then
somebody mumbled, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. But he's shown, he turns around,
he goes, I don't know, give a shit.
It's just like
he is kind of untouchable at this point.
He Israeli Yoda, he gets no, but it was
real. It wasn't found to be dangerous.
He literally goes, I don't give a shit.
I don't give a shit. I don't give a shit.
I'm fucking, I'm Ray Liotta.
And by the way, I, I am,
I don't give a shit what
a brilliant game that is.
Plead the fifth on one of these
three questions. Then what it'll do,
it was then it would then pass it over
to you and then you got to, you know,
and it's all this, this, uh, you know,
he does all the squirming questions. He
was asking like Jennifer Lopez. Okay.
When you, you know, how many, you've
been proposed to five times, did you?
Who did you say no to? And she's a
nice person. Doesn't want to say it.
And Ray Liotta was just sitting there
going, just plead the fifth on this.
I'll answer something like
he just completely didn't
give a shit or two of them
together. Yeah. Cause they're on that cop
show together. Oh, you know, it's fine.
I auditioned for that.
Uh, I did. Yeah, I did.
Doug Davidoff got the part and he lazy.
He,
I think he's better for that than I
am anyway. Not just acting ability,
but you know,
he looked more of the part of uh,
a kind of a slick like internal
affairs guy if that's what you got.
I didn't know Doug was on that shit.
Hey. Yeah, he's got a good party part.
Radioed into the comedy cellar
one night. Um, but you know,
if I'm not going to get it,
I'd rather see somebody I like yet.
That's great. Seen a glimpse of
what your life would have been cool.
Hanging on Ray Liotta that would have been
fun. How it had been kind of Nice. Jim,
you're are next. What should they say
about you? Yeah. You know, she'd going up,
sorry, was my bad STM. Like, like
she announces you before you go on,
but I understood what you're saying. Oh
look, as bad as that joke was everybody,
uh,
Chuck Norris and special is going to be
the opposite of that mouthful of shame.
I, it's so stupid. I keep going back to
this. When people listen to a podcast,
it's not like they can, there's no right,
there's no commercials coming in front,
but I just feel like I have to keep going
back to March 14th in case you forget,
because then they got to rewind
and try to remember where and when.
Of course we'll probably tweet it out.
And I did love Netflix too.
I've never done anything with them before.
I know you've done a bunch of stuff with
them, but they're so easy. They're like,
all right, just put it together. I mean,
Robbie had a couple of minor suggestions.
They don't overly manage you. It was like
fucking great. It was so nice to do it.
And I'm actually happy with it. Like, you
know, you shoot something, you this one,
I actually feel it's dirtier than I kind
of intended and wait to next time you
go to Australia, now that it's on
Netflix, like you'll sell tickets.
You can help someone.
I'm going to a you.
I told you you inspire
me completely to to do,
I'm only doing this stuff because you
got in my head and I hear bill burn my
fucking head all the time. God, what
are you waiting for it? And I'm like,
I got to do it. I really do. It's
like, but you are right now. Watch.
I'll stop selling tickets
and then I'll be like,
you're watching David off coming into a
place. I'll be watching you sell it out.
The fucking, what does that thing in
Sydney, the Opera House and I'll be like,
I used to do that. I, I, you know
it's funny, I did one show there.
It was a TV taping. No, was, it
was a TV taping and something else.
And I enjoyed city. Melbourne was good,
but Sydney was really good and I'm like,
like Melbourne and a little
bit better. You did? Yeah,
I got that park was fun cause I landed
there and was Australia day and everybody
was just fucking getting hammered
and shit. So I was like, hey this,
this country is, I didn't
go to Perth. I didn't go.
What was your first time through is
great in Perth is the Bon Scott. Oh,
buried there. They got the stats. Show
you pictures of that. Yeah, we did it.
We went to the Bond
Scott Wall and Melbourne.
It was like in one of the things someone
painted a tribute while in the bond.
Scott, you know it's Bon
Scott because it says ac DC.
But if it didn't you'd be like, you
know, or say say acadeca down there.
I don't know why. Oh, do they
really? Yeah. And then what does,
what does burger can call down there?
I don't remember a fucking
cheese. Yeah. No, it's something.
No,
cause somebody down there actually had
already had a burger king and he sued the
corporation and the, what the fuck is
it? You're looking it up, Jonathan.
Um, did you sell tickets when you
first went through the first time?
No. No, I think I did. Uh, the
first time I went out there,
it was like an old four and
I did something for comedy
central and we flew in
from New York,
so it was like six hours to five and a
half to la and then lay over and then 14
hours and uh, you land, they let you
sleep a little bit and then it's like,
it's already the next day and then
we taped it and then the next day you
supposed to go back was so fucking nuts.
So I was just like, well fuck that.
I'm going to stay here for a few days.
Hungry, Hungry Jacks. That's right.
Hungry Jacks. Okay. That means
nothing to anybody listening to this.
But I thought it was cool.
Um,
and I just hung out there and I bought
all these ACDC albums on CD that,
you know, the original like, like was t
and t. I used to know the names of the,
like t and t was the original album
that then became high voltage,
but their version had like dirty deeds
on it, which later became its own album,
became an EAP over here. So we went, you
know, I bought like all these, you know,
cause I got a big family so I just
bought them for my brothers and sisters.
Oh that's cool. Yeah. And uh,
drove around and saw the apostles and
just driving on the other side of the road
was really fucked up.
And anytime I went to take a turn,
like the joke was I would just pretend
that I wanted to kill myself and then I
would actually make the right decision.
Cause everything else,
it doesn't even make sense. You like,
what the fuck? This makes no sense.
Especially when you're,
um,
when you make a right turn and
you're sitting, you're sitting on,
on the passenger's side and
you got to go wide. You like,
what the fuck can you
just picture like a semi.
But late at night when I came out,
I didn't know where the fuck I was at.
I was with this other comic,
one of those comics,
I was from like Scotland or some shit,
an ex patriot and I just met him
and I never saw him again. But uh,
we got on the road with no street
lights and drove probably maybe eight,
900 feet and the same time we both went
like, oh shit. Oh Shit. And got over it.
But there was nobody coming. Right. We
definitely was starting to go up a hill.
So yeah, I'm sure people get car service
when you're out there. And Jimmy,
that's what I'm trying ubered when
I was there and the openers there,
it was great.
But I'm also going to Norway and I think
I'm doing something to Scandinavian and
I've never been to any of these places.
I'm doing all of them.
That whole run through,
uh, Oslow Helsinki,
Stockholm dude the best. But they said
those are just places that, you know,
as an American to actually go there.
I mean I think he got to be like,
either you're either in the Illuminati
or you'll like a downhill skier or some
shit. Cause other than that, you're
not going to go there as far as,
it's just not on our radar to go there.
Beautiful countries and the people are,
the people are great.
Do you fly in and out the [inaudible]
can I have sleep apnea and I fucking,
I take Dramamine to fly. Like I came
this morning from Portland, so I'm like,
I'm very loopy and I'm tired and you just
do a show that night and then fly out
the next morning. I can't, there
was a, um, I'm panicking about that.
What I do is I turn it into
like a paid vacation. So, um,
what I do is I fly over there and I
either do the tour and then I meet my wife
afterwards or other times I've done it
like just because of our schedules that
work out. Like, all right,
let's do the vacation first. Um,
and then not only will I be
rested, I'll be, you know,
talking about to acclimate at
that time and that type of thing.
So I've done both. But uh, you know,
there's all, you know, I build a window,
it build a of shit around
sporting events and stuff. Like,
you know what I wanted to go to this year.
I,
I don't think it's going to work out
though, but I was going to go to that.
There's this motorcycle
race on the Isle of Man,
which is an island between Britain
and Ireland home saying that, right?
A fucking whales, whatever the
fuck you want to call it. Um,
and it's just this fucking
motorcycle race that's just like,
I mean more people have died than years.
They've had it.
It's just they go on like fucking 200
miles an hour down these country roads and
shit and they go, go. I
come blazing through town.
I mean it's like if you love the
beginning of the last mad max,
this is like the closest you're going to
see to the real version of it. I mean,
these guys are fucking lunatics.
Like they know that going so fast and
it's his little ass country roads and this
like stone walls and shit
and trees like you're dead.
And pedestrians are getting
killed once in a while too.
I'm actually surprised that so many
people stand so close that my only
nervousness about it as how can I get
high up enough to see a little bit more of
it. Right. Because I'm worried that
it's just going to be like, you know,
I'm going to stay fly halfway
around the world. Just see
and then stand there for like another
fucking 20 minutes because they go by that
fucking fat and that's it.
Yeah.
I went to the Daytona 500 we
were on the infield on like,
like this little building so I could
actually stand and kind of watch them go
all the way around. Um,
but like if you just stand,
the first time I went to
the Indy 500 I was just,
you're just in a corner and it just
becomes this drinking game and everybody's
bed on like four different cars and you
just pray to God there's going to be an
accident or some shit in front of you.
Right. Just something interesting. Yeah.
And it's actually really amazing the first
time you see it and you actually hear
this tire skid like a real accident.
You're like, oh yeah, I guess it is a car.
For some reason I never thought
it would sound like that.
But the thing is that going so fast as
they'll hit the wall in front of you and
then the debris just they fly down.
We've seen the accident. Yeah,
I saw like I hit a wall in front
of me one time, but it's like it's,
he hits it in front of you and by the
time your brain reacts to what that is is
he's already a quarter mile away.
It's not like they hit it and just stop.
Do you watch like boxing and MMA cause
you such as sports care, do you watch uh,
combat sports or no? Yeah, I
keep going in and out of MMA. It,
it's like to pencil my road
schedule where it's like, you know,
I work a lot on Saturday night and if a
couple months goes by and I keep missing
the fights, I hate it. But it's a
big thing that me and my wife too,
like she fucking loves it. The
shit like UFC dude, she's old.
She's almost embarrassing. Like she
gets up and yells at the TV. Oh Great.
She totally gets into it.
When Anderson Silver,
like had the compound fracture of his
leg. I was like, oh my God, look in a way,
and she has this weird thing where
maybe she should have gotten the medical
field because she was,
it wasn't like she was happy it happened.
She was just more fascinated by what it
looked like and was just like, good Lord.
Oh, I was called. That's like the, uh,
when they break that fucking thing,
that's like,
you ever see like a little kid put on
like his dad's rain boot straps on the
side and just folds up. Like I can't, I
cannot look at it. I was at that fight.
That was their second fight. That
was a, nobody knew what happened.
Like until the replay,
you just saw him fall and then the replay
played the whole place was like, oh,
it was her. That was a horrible, but he's
still kicking. He's still using that leg.
He just thought I heard when you break
the bone or it doesn't come back stronger,
some weird reason, they might
have strengthened it with metal.
I heard it was a pretty clean break.
Here we go. We're going into the best.
We don't have to make it stronger.
How you heard they did metal
[inaudible] we don't know,
but he's able to fight with it,
but it's just give
answers chuck,
why it happened.
I remember over hearing somebody say
that and I never did any background check
on them and had gone to one
of the fights. Yes. Yes I did.
What does that, oh, is that the picture
of him going by on the stretcher?
Jesus Christ. Jim, you look like you're in
a fucking band. Dude. I got to tell you,
this guy took this weight off. What? Two,
three years ago? And you've kept it off.
What are you doing? I just just eating
in the gym. Just that. That really is it.
But when did you find that? Because you
were a, you weren't those up and down.
It was awful. It's just that
moment of clarity. I was like, Ugh,
just so much fucking self disgust.
What were you eating and
where were you when you,
when you finally were just like,
I can't do this anymore? You know,
I really don't remember. I do remember
is going to the gym and going,
I am going to go.
I was fucking,
I was just sick of like when you
feel it in your back above your belt,
that little bit of fucking fat.
It's just soft. Like a little lamb.
I started getting the uh, the
effort noises, putting on socks.
I was just like, Oh God. And becoming
that guy. So I just like, uh,
this last trip I just had, I got off the
road two days ago now I've just been,
it's so funny.
I literally just two days of not eating
burger king or steak and shake and I
never,
I just kind of fell into this.
I think it was just because of the lack
of sleep I've been getting and just
going out on the road and then having
to do the shows and the pressure putting
together the new hour.
I just spent under a lot of stress and
I've just been like last second, Oh fuck,
I'm hungry. Let's go
here. I don't give a shit.
Just stuff this in me and fill up
the hole. And it just was a, yeah.
So La is dangerous for me because I go,
this is what a fucking fruit I'm turning
into Jonathan and I will word it is a
great one. Fucking fruit. We eat.
Uh, I like eating Sushi here,
but then we go to the
yogurt stop on Santa Monica.
But I didn't go on that for years.
They think we're a complex.
My favorite place in the world is the
fucking yogurt stop on Santa Monica.
I love where is that? It's on Santa
Monica by rage West Hollywood. Get get,
get, get a Mike. I know you're
just talking to Jonathan.
Forgot. God. Put it on.
Put It on the fucking head. Can you
just speak into thinner at Brownstein?
Everybody. Oh, hello? Yeah, Jonathan.
Well who was very instrumental when we
first started doing the Patrice O'Neal
benefit.
That's right.
Please help me get in touch with all the
guys and everything like that. And uh,
it's an amazing thing. It's still
going on. It's incredible. Yeah.
Just like she knew how much Nah, no, no.
It was Maureen Taren Morin's flooring.
Taryn deals with all the
infrastructure and uh,
the herd of add that is booking
a bunch of comedians through it.
It's like literally,
it's like you got 12 cows just fucking,
I guess what,
what runs cows don't run.
You got 10 you got 10 fucking things
that run there will go in a different
direction and things that run all
going in different directions.
But February 21st that normally would
and this right? Yeah we kind of,
we kind of know it's going
to be in February now. Yeah.
Now she lets us know in enough advanced
and that's why we do it Tuesday cause
sometimes fans go, why the fuck is this
on a Tuesday night? It's cause guys
are working for free. And this is what,
that's the day when comedians are, uh,
are in town. So, uh, next year, uh,
I already know like one of
the guys out here every year,
we try to like maybe
fly somebody in and uh,
we got an idea of possibly who are going
to try to use it next year. But, uh,
it's been a great thing because
I just hate like, you know,
like when someone passes away,
like with unfortunately we're at that age,
you know, and where you had that one
time benefit and you're like, okay,
here's your sack of cash, good luck
for the next 40 years. And it's, um,
you know, he was taking care
of those people. So it's,
it's definitely been a great
thing. So, and the thing
about it, I said, here's the,
and I think of there's too this year
is that it's the fifth annual one.
I've officially done this four more
times and Patrice would've done it for me
this year,
I think might've been this shoe.
I thought it was the perfect
combination of a great mix of people.
The ball breaking was on a whole
other fucking level. And then, uh,
when Leslie Jones told that portray story,
oh my God,
it was just fucking know dude.
The shit that you said when to Keith
and Keith Robinson, Keith Robinson,
Keith unfortunately, uh,
suffered a mild stroke, uh,
wasn't moment coming up on two years ago,
was it? No, I'll say less than a year.
Yeah, a year and a year ago. And um,
he's of course now he's doing like
someone funniest shit or whatever. So Jim,
when he out-tro to me it goes,
keep it going for Keith Robinson.
He should had a stroke 15 years ago.
The place fucking dies laughing and
then your other one was like a, well,
it's funny is even after a stroke, Keith
is easier to understand than rich vos.
How is it, I don't know how you followed
it with the rest of your jokes, but yeah,
people like the attacks on each other
that, that's always a crowd favorite.
You had one way, you said,
I think Colin came after you
and you said, uh, he's here,
he's a,
has to be back at men's Wearhouse soon.
He was wearing a suit that night and
it was bosses awful hat this year.
And Pete Davidson kept telling him the
truth going to look awful. I'm like, Pete,
that's not how this game works.
Tell them it looks good and you wait
till it goes out on stage. Yeah.
You don't try to discourage them.
You wait until he's on and then you
fucking attack them in front of the entire
theater. Was another, another one.
That's the first time we had him and he
came out and he was trashing Voss has
had, I think they actually may make
fun of us as the old guys. Um, I,
yeah, I think that, but
then vos leveled him.
Pete Pete Talks about his dad died on
that 11 and voice had the one good thing
is that of uh,
uh,
the Pete's dad didn't have to seem in
that blouse and he's saying he would have
thrown himself in another
fire. Oh yeah. That, fuck.
Oh my God. They're terrible. Sweater,
head artsy golden girl's sweater
that was going to wear. Yeah,
that was really bad. It was really,
really shitty. I wanted to make fun of it,
but I knew I didn't like it. I'm
like, you're on a TV show. You're,
you're fucking good looking young guy
and if you dress slightly of feminine,
it's like you're not getting enough pussy.
So I knew that that's what I was
going to come out. And I was like,
I can't come at him. You know,
the potential was wrong. I
knew that I was just, uh,
an old man
getting jealous, you know, now I had
to, Rosa just showed up and that then I,
I would've, I mean, the sweater on
by itself should have been burned.
It was brutal. It was,
it was bad. But you know,
you knew the reasons for attacking
it would have been more. Yeah.
It's not one of those
fucking guys remember those,
those all those people that Madonna used
to fucking sell Ho in New York City,
those Charlie Bean Beneatha's, those
artists. Yeah. He looked like he fucking,
when he dies his artwork, it was going to
be worth something. Yeah. Like a young,
uh, I can't, I haven't got bused
yachts. Yeah, the young guy of age.
It's all I'm thinking of.
Yeah.
I don't like any of those guys because
it always makes me feel foolish because
everybody looks at this shit like it's
fucking amazing. And like one of the, uh,
I dunno,
like the two ways when I always know
that I'm a dope was when I tried to read
out loud bat and when I go to a museum,
because I mean, you want to just talk
about flatlining emotionally and it just,
it means not dude. I went,
when I went to Paris,
I went into a little lube.
I could not get out of there fast enough.
I was like literally almost shouting
at people. Like, where is it?
Where is the fucking,
where's the Mona Lisa so I can look
at it and get the fuck out of here.
And you get out of it. And there's
all these people just, you know,
just creating like a ledge with their
other hand and then fucking holding their
chin out with the other one.
And I was, I just sort of,
I peered over like it was the presidential
motorcade driving by and I saw that
was it.
Did it move you and give a fuck.
The only thing that was cool as it's
been recreated so many times and be like,
that's the actual one. And
Dude, I saw the Sistine Chapel,
I couldn't be off fucking small. It
was, I think the guy was dogging it.
I mean it's saint. It took
them that fucking long walked
in. I literally was like,
this is it. And somebody went
shoo, shoo, like shushed me.
I'll tell you what would be on inspiring.
And they recently dug up Christ's
tomb and the church and they had to do
something that they know where
he's buried. They know where the,
suppose the tomb of Christ. They
do know. Yeah. She just fucking,
Al Capone's vault is shroud of Turin.
It probably is bullshit,
but I mean it is in Catholicism.
They do kind of Riviera,
it's somewhere in Jerusalem I guess.
But these guys had to go down and they
were doing some kind of maintenance work
on it, which they had to be done on
the lid over the tomb. But I'm like,
that would probably get me like, Ooh,
this is a pretty important place.
But the art museums do nothing for me.
I did see the Washington crossing the
Delaware painting. It's fucking massive.
It's probably the size of this room and
I always in the Metropolitan Museum of
art, that was kind of always the,
well, I would rather look at that shit.
Then something like
abstract. Yeah, me too.
It looked like you rolled a baby and
paint and just fucking threw it. Yeah.
Canvas.
I liked,
I went to the van Gogh one when wherever
were the fuck whatever country that's
an,
I went to that and I actually liked that
one and it's not because he's a fellow
fucking red head. It was just, I actually
would like with Netherlands. Yeah.
How about uh, I like a Norman
Rockwell. You sure it's not in Denmark?
Copenhagen?
I thought it was Amsterdam,
but maybe it could be the
whole way. You're addressing
me, lets me know. I know,
I know that you're right.
Initials on his shirt.
He gives like the air of authority,
but half of the times he knows what he's
talking about. Half the times he does.
Oh, this is that what you have
your initials right there?
Yeah. That's very unique.
And the Taylor's, is that
near your run, your pancreas?
Is that why you put it there? I thought
you did it on the cuff link on the cuffs.
There's two styles. You can do it.
The cuff. You can do it here. You can.
What is that and what does that style?
I don't know.
I've always had it here
though, so I dunno. The Taylor
that I got this made yet.
He did it there. Yeah. This is a
true gentleman. Yeah, the train.
I can tell how difficult you are as a
client because I know when you're not
around, his shirt is untucked. Yeah.
He said he's getting a little rock
and roll because I'm in town. He's,
there's chicks to talk to get
them to the Greek. All right,
well coming up on an hour
here at Jim, I'm, you know,
I'm such a fucking huge fan of you
and I always tell you this dude,
I owe so much of the tickets that I sell
to on the road that you were generous
when you got a lot of guys would have
got that opie and Anthony Gig and they
would've kept the fucking door closed
and you let us all run in. So, uh,
I want to thank you. Well, you know,
you can see I'm blowing all my money
on footlocker tee shirts here now,
but you do do it well.
Deservedly like you're a great comic
and I don't mean it's not like, yeah,
I just taught my compliment
with a compliment. You,
it is nice to see like a mouthful
of shame on Netflix March 14th.
I love you to death Jimmy. Uh, all
the success in the world to you.
I will definitely be tweeting this out.
If you want to talk to Jimmy Norton,
you can get him on Twitter at, at Jim
Norton, Instagram at Jim Norton Facebook.
Just type in Jim Norton and Jim norton.com
and you can hear me and Sam in the
morning. I have to plug
most Sam Roberts. Uh,
we are now doing the show
together Monday through Friday,
eight to 11 on Channel One oh three.
I have satellite radio now and I've looked
at the list and you guys all the time.
It's great.
It's really finally get caught up.
I can't believe how long I did
satellite radio before I got it.
It's fucking tremendous. You
just got it. I just got it.
I never had it in my
car and I finally just,
I finally never bought myself a nice car.
I'm one of those frugal
fucking Douche bag.
So I finally just said up buying a nice
car. I was just like, whatever. They said,
you want this? I was like, yes. Do
you want that? Yes. Treating yourself.
Climate control. Yes. I
just said yes to everything.
That's why it gets shitty gas miles. Just
so fucking heavy with all the options.
Thanks for having me, man. I'm sorry I
was late to Oh, you weren't late. Jimmy.
Appreciate we're building
anticipation and I'll see you guys.