Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
August 14th, 2017. What's
going on? How, why?
Yeah. How's it going? Oh my God.
Paul [inaudible]
fucking destroyed last night on
his standup special and Tarrytown,
New York.
And uh, I want to thank everybody
that came out for the, uh,
for the two shows that we had
there. And uh, we just, I dunno,
it just went as good as it
could have gone, I felt and uh,
I was really proud of him. You
know that first one's always, yeah,
you got to figure it out.
How'd it go up there and try and be
relaxed as you're like, Holy Shit,
I'm shooting a special
look at those TV cameras.
Look at the chip camera swinging
by my damn face. You know,
you got to block all of that.
No,
that the crowd's going to be
looking at that shit. You know,
you learn that they have to turn off the
fucking air conditioning because most
of those old venues, the AC so frigging
loud, it messes with the audio.
So you're then going to go out there
under hot lights with HD makeup on with no
AC and progressively through your set,
it's going to get hotter.
So he learned all of that and
you know something. God dammit,
he saw the fire any fucking
walked through it. And um,
okay.
He just, uh, I dunno, it just
couldn't have gone any better.
And uh,
there you go.
So we're going to edit that thing down
and hopefully sell it to one of the
goddamn networks. That's
the guy, that's the goal.
So congratulations to Paul
Versey. Uh, that's it.
And put them to bed. I told
him that before he went out.
That was just like, dude,
just look at it this way.
Okay, you're putting all these
jokes to bed. This is it.
Okay.
Go out there and give them the sendoff
day deserve because the second you're
special comes out, everyone's seen that
material, then you can't do it again.
And everybody will be like,
dude, you already did that.
You did that on your last fucking special.
No, your last special
called chuckles. Like,
what the fuck is wrong
with my goddamn computer?
Okay.
I'd been having all my God,
I even having like the worse
technology experiences.
What is going on? Why is the
screen just all black? Then I got,
then I go to touch it and it does that,
what does that make it a hit escape.
Can I hit escape? Why don't they
have an escape button for your life?
Um, oh, it worked. It worked to, Oh,
the old escape button.
Okay.
You know, there's somebody could turn
that into a little lead, like in a mood,
like turning into a movie.
A big time Hollywood movie.
Yeah. The, the escape button movie. Yeah.
Go in there and you can pitch it.
Hey,
you know that escape button on your
keyboard or you on your laptop?
And they'd be like, Yup,
Yup. Uh Huh. Uh, just
to [inaudible] guy. He fucking
the, he pushes it, you know.
Okay.
And uh, he disappears and all
of a sudden his wife was like,
wait a minute, I thought I told you
cold and start where? Where'd he go?
And then whenever he fucking comes to,
he's always a,
okay,
let's flush this.
Let's flush out this fucking off a movie.
He was always in some
someplace better at first.
Okay.
But then there's, you know, he goes to a
baseball game, he's like, this is amazing.
And then he,
you know,
no one believes that it's true
except for his dump fat best friend.
Okay.
You know, they hit escape again, then
they're at a steak house, you know,
and they just keep hitting escape that
eventually they, uh, they're some fucking,
I don't know where the hell did they go?
They had escaped and they end up
in fucking Syria and North Korea.
That's where you get a note from the
industry. Can it not be North Korea?
Could it be, could it be like Canada? Like
Winnipeg? What if they went to Winnipeg?
That's funny.
Right?
I just feel like with today's
political climate to say North Korea,
I just think that,
you know,
then they're starving and we
like the fat friend fat is funny.
Fat As nonthreatening.
Okay.
Um, I don't know. You guys can finish the
rest of the fucking movie. Uh, anyways.
Um, so I was very proud of Paul
and all that type of stuff and uh,
going to try to keep the
podcast light, uh, despite the,
despite all that fucking
just horrible shit.
Okay.
That happened down in Charlottesville.
It's just fucking four.
I don't think I don't want to go.
I know.
I did hear one fucking funny
thing about it. I mentioned,
I'm going to say who I mentioned it to.
I mentioned it to somebody
else or go Jesus Christ to,
can you fucking believe that shit down
there in Charlottesville? They, he goes,
he goes, no, what happened?
I mean, I don't know. I
don't know if that is like,
I don't,
I don't know how you missed it,
but I mean there literally is that much
information coming out at you that you
could miss all that shit that
went down there. And uh, I mean,
I don't even need to comment on
what the fuck went on down there.
If you're any sort of a
human being, uh, you know
that dude in that fucking car,
I swear to God,
like I'm trying to think of a proper
punishment for that guy. And I,
I can't think nothing is like enough.
Okay.
To fucking drive. Just do that. You know,
you know what's funny about
that guy as I bet that guy,
he's talked about Isis and how cowardly
terrorism is and then he gets in a car
and does what the fuck he did.
It's just like, it's like, I dunno.
Hey, there must have been,
I mean, obviously beyond
joining that fucking group,
there's something wrong
with that guy mentally. Um,
anyways. Um, see that's why
I didn't want to bring it up.
Where do you go from there and then
fucking Trump, I'm done with that guy.
The guy's just no longer
funny or anything ease. Uh,
I've just done with that fucking guy.
Yeah.
The fact that he wouldn't
just straight up denounce it.
The fact that he's going to go, oh, you
know, there's hatred on both sides. Hey,
turn on both sides and he's doing
like that. You know what came first?
The chicken or the egg got
slavery. Slavery came first.
You fucking dope. It's,
it's documented.
It's just so fun.
Like he's been catering to that racist
fan base cause he needed their votes.
I'm not saying everybody
voted for Trump is racist,
but like for that fucking guy to do that,
it's absolutely fucking reprehensible.
It's sickening.
Fucking sickening. Okay.
And I'm not a fucking,
you know,
I'm not one of these guys that thought
the sky was falling because this guy got
in the office,
you know,
everybody freaking the fuck out like
what the fuck was going to happen.
But I will just say his track record
on the Klan, you know, to be just
not even commenting on it and being,
do you know, if I was doing standup and
people in the Klan started showing up,
I would be looking at what the fuck am
I saying that's making these people be
like, oh yeah, this guy,
he approves of what we do.
Okay.
At the very least I'd be
like, Hey, not for nothing.
You guys over there with the
Hudson, I fucking, you know,
I'm not down with you guys like
fucking kids. So you're morons.
You fucking morons. He never
does it. Never does it.
You know?
And I think he was just trying
to make a joke with the cops,
but the don't push the heads up, but just
a while, the shit that you've seen that,
that all that police brutality that's
been going out to make that fucking joke,
the guy, it's unbelievable.
And now I'm hearing like,
this is what, see, I'm not even a name
fucking names, but like all these Fito,
it's like fucking Taylor swift that
was gonna run for Senate people.
We can't go down this fucking road.
The very least.
Can we at least stick with
career fucking politicians?
Can we at least do that? Can we, you know,
which would you want? Like you want
me to be your fucking accountant?
You want to comedian to be an accountant?
Why would you want an actor or a musician?
Fucking God knows what else.
I, I just, I don't know.
I don't even know what the
fuck we're doing now. I just,
I don't even know what the fuck
we're doing. So, um, anyways,
that happened. And uh, you know,
fortunately it wasn't a big rally.
You know,
they're Nazis is still a little, a
little mom. And Pop fucking group, which,
you know, that's about the only good
thing that I took away from it. But, uh,
I dunno, you know what's fucked up
about the whole thing though, as I said,
I wasn't going to talk about it.
Okay.
Is when people started texting me
like, dude, you watch in this shit.
So I go online,
you know,
to watch a video of the rally and all
the bullshit to see what's going on.
And I go on and when I click on it,
I immediately see Bobby flay and he's
selling me something from Lipton ice tea.
So what's so fucked up is, uh,
and I think it was actually,
I was actually on the Huffington
post and I fucking hate those guys.
Okay.
You know, and they're all liberal is
how can you fucking believe it's a blog?
It's like, dude, you're making money off
of it. You're making money off of it.
So there's something you would think
on just something like this is so
reprehensible. We shouldn't
even put a fucking ad in
front of it. Other than that,
I understand you've got to make you money.
I have advertising on my fucking podcast,
but there was just something fucked up,
like this is the most
horrible, blah, blah, blah,
whatever the fuck they have as a headline.
And then you click it on and it's fucking
Bobby flay set selling me fucking ice
tea.
Yeah.
But you know, and that's how the
game's played, I guess. Anyway,
so let's get the fuck out of
that. All right, Boo Nazis,
uh, boot Donald Trump being a
fucking pussy. That guy such a fuck.
I'm so sick of him and that fucking guy
from North Korea acting like the tough
guys acting like the tough, you know what
I mean? You know what they shouldn't.
You know they should,
they should fight the fucking undercard
on a McGregor Mayweather. All right,
why don't you guys
settle your fucking beef?
I'd love to see the two
of them put on fucking
okay.
The whole fucking get up the
box, insurance, the mouth
guard, the gloves, the boots,
and go out there and you just really see
what a couple of pants he's, you know,
that Fatty Donald Trump with his fucking
wig flopping around it probably one of
the fun.
It'd be funnier than all the standup
specials that came out this year combined.
It would have been tremendous.
Like that's,
that's the way I think that that's the
way they should solve world problems.
Although, you know what's his
face is like a black belt in judo,
Vladimir Putin at fucking, that dude
looks like a bad guy. And like, you know,
little spy movies right now I'm in over
my head. Why do I try to talk politics?
Because that's what everybody's fucking
talking about and asking me about I
guess.
But how about those red sox take it to
on a tree from the New York Yankees.
He had 100 bucks on each game. You know,
I get 50 with version 50 with my agent,
right? They're both Yankee fans. So, uh,
you know, we fucking blew that, that,
that first one bell, middle reliever.
I don't know what happened to him.
By the way, did you see that guy in
the mets made, he swung his leg around,
made that weird pitching motion and he
fucking slammed his balls between his
thighs. And then after that is
fucking pitching hand went numb.
Figure that one out.
Okay.
Why the fuck are guys wired like
that? Why if he get, he could,
how the design fall of men that you
could throw an object in somehow,
basically kick yourself in the,
and then you're throwing hand goes numb.
Okay.
It's unreal. You know what it is? The
men are like the death star, right?
We got that one little shaft.
All you do is you just fucking throw
something down and then the whole fucking
thing blows up and that would be on nuts,
you know?
Okay.
I don't know what the women want is
women.
You just tell me look older and then
that's it. The whole fucking plant,
it explodes.
Uh, Shit. Um, anyways,
I've been in it,
so I remember what was going to talk
about and I've been having like the worst
technology fucking weekend here.
Um,
I'm about to buy my, uh, my second
cell phone charger of the weekend.
I brought one,
I left it at the theater and then the
next day I woke up and I bought one.
I bought one.
And uh,
yeah,
drove from fucking, well,
there was a red bank,
New Jersey up to Tarrytown, New York.
And then I don't know what happened.
I don't know where the why or when, but
I fucking lost that one, so I got to go.
Bye. Fuck another one. It's just my phone.
My fucking computer
just keeps cutting out,
I guess now that I hit the escape button,
I'm fine. I don't know. I'm, I'm uh,
I'm just not meant to live in this
fucking era of all of this shit.
I need to go back to when there
was just like rotary phones,
which was impossible to lose because
you wouldn't take it with you.
It was just in your house.
The only way you lost it as it fills it
in fucking sink hole your house and you
lost all your house. So there was
a fire in your house, you know,
or somebody came to Maria with the black
gloves and they would fucking cut the
phone wire. Then you lost your
phone and you lost your life.
But you say you didn't care.
Right. Was this sent, wait,
I'm trying to say was it
was a simpler time. Um,
I gotta tell you, dude, I'm fucking
sold on the Jersey shore by the way.
All these years,
all these years of Paul Versey great.
Paul Versey fucking crushed
his special last night.
It's been shitting on New
Jersey. I fucking five. Finally,
the same way goes like to Yara. I know
what your deal is with this fucking state.
I don't know why you think, you know
there's more animals that live here.
The New York, there
are, I'll give him that.
It's a little dirty or
animal in New Jersey,
but there weren't there the under dogs.
So I was going around Terry town and
I was just taking pictures of people,
all the fucking animals that are up here.
What it is about this part
of this neck of the woods,
like fucking West Chester.
Um,
is it so fucking beautiful up here?
It could cleans up the animal.
You don't see it,
but if you really do,
if you fucking block out the trees and
the beautiful houses and buildings behind
these people and you really look at them,
you know it's a bunch of animal.
I want it to Terry town and there
was bunch of people like had all the,
all the new rage now be seen like those
does their motorcycles but they're
really small.
We call a mini bikes but they look like
it's like somebody took a Ninja and they
just made it smaller.
Like this whole group of them.
Okay.
Was riding through like a motorcycle gang?
I don't if they were marketing
motorcycle gangs, I have no idea.
I don't know if they were more likely
to beat the shit out of you because
they're insecure about the size
of their motorcycles. I don't,
I don't get how it fucking works,
but there was like 40 of them we'd,
I'll ride through town and I was
laughing my ass off going, here I am.
Here I am in fucking, you know,
if I'm not in West Chester,
I'm Oberson West Justice.
Look at these fucking animals
and I already learned up
here. There's already is,
there's always this snooty thing in
all the fucking real estate, you know,
are you above the boulevard
or you're below the boulevard?
Are you in the flat lands?
Are you in the hills?
Are you on this side of the
tracks or that side of the tracks?
This side of the river,
other side of the bridge up here,
I already found out that there was,
there's this snooty,
if you live on the other side of the
Tappan Zee bridge or the Tappan Zee Bridge
is there's my fucking Google Map lady
was saying when I was driving up there
making right to go onto exit
one c four a Tapan zee bridge.
Yeah,
you're less than you live on
the other side of the river.
Stuff is cheaper over there.
It's more expensive to live here.
Therefore you are less than me.
You are less than God likes you less.
God loves everyone,
but he loves you less because you live
on the other side of the fucking river.
Actually cornered this woman last
night who was in real estate, right?
She's up at the Bar,
right?
And I'm going up there to go get a couple
of rounds of drinks or whatever people,
you know,
cause I'm a hell of a guy.
Okay.
And she's like, Hey, you know,
first he special yet. And I
said, it's great. You know,
I do the tip accomplishing. What are
you doing? She goes, I'm in real estate.
I said, wonderful. I got
some questions for you.
And I fucking grilled her up up. Uh,
uh, uh, went law and order on her.
Yeah.
And I fucking was breaking it down to
find out what's the deal with all of these
luxury apartment buildings?
They're going up like fucking
like luxury apartment buildings.
That's how many luxury apartment buildings
they're building in New York and Los
Angeles. The only reference is what
they are. And I'm like, what is the,
what's the deal with these fucking
luxury apartments? Who is building them?
Why are they building them?
What kind of a fucking moron pays rent
in a luxury apartment when they could
actually just go buy
something and live in it.
That was less than the luxury apartment,
but at least they would own that.
Who makes that dumb decision? First
of all, who's paying for these?
And she said, it's a lot of
foreign money. Uh, China,
Russia and Middle East money,
right. Then I go, all right,
and then who the fuck's in them? And
she said, she basically said, I got,
when I said, who's dumb enough to
throw money in the toilet like that?
She said, about 15% of
the population. I go,
all right, so you're banking on, I got,
how do you put your head on the
pillow every night? She goes,
this isn't my passion. I go, but you
are selling them. How do you do that?
How do you fucking go?
All right,
come on the lower 15% dummies,
please walk into my office today.
Long story short, I go, when does it
burst? When she goes, well, you know the,
you know of people seem to be, they keep
building them, they keep filling it.
When does it burst? Well, you
know, but, but when does it burst?
She goes two years dead serious.
She goes, two years, two years.
It's going to be fucking
overseas. What you do? I go,
you sit on your fucking money.
All right.
If you need to buy something now,
because the fucking, this is me.
I'm like that fucking ball guy who screams
about taxes. I mean, uh, the stocks,
I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about.
Both from a little fucking conversation
that I had about three 30 in the morning
as we were closing down this fucking bar.
Um,
celebrate and Paul Versey
crushing his special.
Okay.
Uh, I, I'm telling you right now, just
sit on your fucking money. Like, oh,
I don't know. What the fuck
did I say initially? I guess
I said, yeah, if you, if,
if you're getting killed in taxes
and you got to buy something, no,
just don't rent a function,
a fucking luxury apartment.
It's got to be the dumbest
fucking thing you could ever do.
Look at the luxury of this all.
Look at all those luxury than I'm
paying for that. I don't fucking out
just hanging in there in two years,
you'd be able to buy the fucking building.
Of course you won't cause it will
still cost millions of dollars.
But you know what I'm saying?
Don't be a fucking SAP. Alright.
All those buildings that do
doing is killing everybody's
fucking view. You know,
they're all going to be fucking
empty within two years down.
I'm calling it right.
They're all going to be,
people are gonna be jumping out of those
fucking tags and two years we're taking
college.
MMM.
I don't know. I don't fucking know.
All I know is I haven't been home.
And too many days I miss my daughter,
my wife and I can't wait to get back.
And um, and that's it. I
got a nice 10 days off,
but I had the best fucking
time down on the Jersey shore.
The fucking food was amazing. I
went down to this place, juniors,
I don't even know where I was at.
All right? Like I was pretty cool.
I had a different opener every night
versus he opened the first night,
fucking killed it.
I went to bed like a God damn angel,
like a fucking angel. All right. I'm
already white as a fucking angel,
you know, at least to ghost went right
home, went to sleep, woke up the next day,
worked out,
fucking crushed it.
Right next day I had fucking Bret Ernst
came up who absolutely fucking murdered,
who you have to go see. Uh,
I hadn't seen him in years.
It's weird how we seam the comedy store,
but he that just went up
or I'm going up or what?
I'm going up and he's
going up in the other room.
I just hadn't seen him in a few years.
That dude grown by leaps and bounds.
Absolute fucking monster destroyed.
He had me pacing a little bit
before I was going up or not,
fuck Brett's killing breads, Kellen
Shit, what am I opening with? Right.
And then later on that night he took me
down to wherever the fuck he was took
went down and this place juniors
someplace on the Jersey shore and we got a
tomato pie, which I had never
heard of, which is basically,
it's like a South Jersey Philly thing
where according to them they put the
cheese on first.
Then the tomato sauce,
but the one that I had looked more like
a swirl of looked like tomato, cheese,
tomato, cheese, like a big
fucking circular thing.
Like when you fucking through computers,
refreshing that. A little pinwheel thing.
That's what it looked like.
Fucking I might've been,
might've been one of the top five pizza
slices of pizzas of it had in a while.
Okay.
And I'm going to tell you why,
because I live in Los Angeles and
all the pizza out there sucks.
Even the stuff that they say is
good, you know, it all fucking sucks.
Every fucking last place in
la absolutely fucking sucks.
I don't know why you just can't.
Anything that involves doe sucks.
The bread sucks. The
pizza sucks, Bagel suck.
All of that sucks. However,
you know, other than that,
they got a tremendous fuck.
Pasta sucks. But you know,
amazing steakhouses, Burgers,
Thai food, Mexican food. That's what you
do out in La. But you do not get pizza.
You don't get bread. You don't
do any of that shit. Um, and I,
and I was coming from that,
eating that shit to go into this.
It was fucking unbelievable.
That in the fucking muscles,
the bread with the fucking sauce. It was
unbelievable. Like an asshole. I mean,
this shit at like fucking
two in the morning. Um,
and then I kept going to this place,
lcs in red bank to get
a sandwich and just,
I would pay for just the bread alone,
by the way.
I went with the Turkey with the cranberry
sauce over there, fucking delicious.
And I made the mistake of getting a large,
by the way,
which was the size of my fucking leg.
So the next day I went back and I
got the Italian, which was amazing,
but I still like the
Turkey a little bit better.
So I was eating as my stomach growls here.
I was been eating like a
fucking king out here and um,
I dunno, I, I kind of fell in
love with the Jersey shore.
Always wanting to see Asbury park.
Went down there, check that out.
Went into the uh,
I dunno all those play every place down.
There's like Bruce Springsteen
or Jon Bon Jovi played here.
I know the place is not
called the fucking stone pony.
That's a fucking bar I used to drink
and in the fucking village that is no
longer there.
That was my fucking spot name.
He used to drink in there back when
I had my drinking under control.
Then I was hanging out with all the
comics that hung out with back then.
Didn't drink and uh,
we'd go in there.
We used to play fucking video games and
shoot pool and just give each other shit
like we always did for like four or
five till four or five in the fucking
morning. Um, whatever that fucking pony
places called. I know it's sac religious.
Tell you jerk. I got to look. You know
why I'll get the name of it right now.
Cause I bought my daughter
a onesy from that place,
which I think she'll only be able to
wear for one week because it looks at the
side, it looks like it's the, uh, the
size that she is now. What's it cost?
My wife had to say, oh, what
is this stone pony? I'll wait.
The stone crow is the bar I
used to hang out at. All right.
So I was saying it right.
I sent the picture of the ones he didn't,
my wife and she knew that it goes like,
what size is that?
Cause she's currently wearing, you know,
this month to this month. It's just like,
can't Jesus, can you just, you know,
can I do one fucking thing right over?
He just fucking one thing. Can I do that?
Um, so last night I hung out
until four in the morning,
but I only had a couple of fucking
drinks cause I kind of realized,
MMM,
I'm not an ally.
I'm not going to undiagnosed an
undiagnosed string of alcoholics.
You know, where, uh, I'm the classic
alcoholic where I can't just have one,
like I'm doing it, I'm fucking
doing it. That's it. All right.
But the next day I could just be
like, all right, but now, you know,
now I'm not drinking and I walk around
like, I need it, man. I fucking need it.
I don't wake up like missing a tooth
and all of that fucking shit. Like,
um,
but uh,
you know,
I have way too many that night when I
went down to juniors and had that great
food and everything. And I also noticed
too, I was throwing them back like,
like fucking water
and,
uh,
and it's just not a good thing. I'm just
sick of being fucking hung over. So,
you know, last night I
only had a couple, um,
I'm kind of, I think I'm done. I'm
just done with it. I like waking up,
not fucking hung over. I like
getting up, going to the fucking gym.
I like doing that shit. And uh, yeah,
I'm not saying I'm done for fucking good,
but I'm just kinda just, yeah, I'm done.
I had a hell of a run.
All right. Started at fucking
17. Drank until about,
I dunno, 22. And then it went like a
10 year period where I didn't drink.
I barely drank.
Yeah.
Barely fucking drank. And then, uh,
then a guy named Joe to Rosa came down.
It's my life.
It's not fair for me to put it on him.
All right.
But what does it say?
We were not good for each other and uh,
that was probably 2004.
So I'm talking like a nice,
I been on like a 13 year sort of a,
although I took a year off one
time from 2010, 2011 a year.
I went a year and two
days without drinking.
I've gone a couple of
stretches of 75 days,
50 some days here or there or whatever.
But uh,
mmm.
Yeah. I mean, I'm always, you know, if you
get a nice cold bottle of fucking wine,
this is a good meal. Maybe I'll have
a glass, but I just don't feel like,
but then it's like, I'm going, I'm
going to finish the fucking bottle.
Yeah.
I mean, what are we doing here?
Right. Uh, so I don't know.
I don't feel like I'm mature enough
at this point in my life to, uh,
handle shit like that.
And I'm at the point to where it,
I don't think I even
enjoy it anymore. So, uh,
for the 90th time on this fucking podcast,
I'm going to try to stop drinking.
So I was a social drinker.
I think I want to go to Aa just
cause I like crowds, you know,
just go up there and just
fucking make them laugh and shit.
MMM.
Anyways, what am I talking about
here? How many minutes in it?
We're 27 minutes in here and I get
to vacate this fucking hotel room.
I'm staying at this stupid ass fucking
yeah.
Fancy fucking wanted to share it in,
right?
People are just going to stay at
the fucking Sheridan, these kinds,
I swear to God,
you order the Internet at 1201 it goes
off and you've got to buy it again.
MMM.
Oh wait, maybe it's free. All I had
was an access code. I, you know,
I take that back. They're not fucking
cool. All right, let's, let's,
let's read a little bit of a,
let's read a little bit of, um,
uh, Eric. Oh, by the way,
then the other thing too,
you know what I don't like about Trump
supporters is when they compartmentalize
that racist shit when they
go like, you know, hey, I,
that stuff where he doesn't
condone, you know, he doesn't know,
uh, chastise the Klansmen that
not neo Nazi said like him.
I don't like that. I don't like
that part, but I'll tell ya,
I think the way he's handling it
had been Hilary. You know? Well,
why can't fucking stand either, but
at some point, you know what I mean?
It's like if you had a friend,
right? He's a good friend of yours,
but he was also in the clan.
Yeah.
Dude, he's such a great host.
You have them all over again.
All we fucking, he's really polite,
but he drops the gun board. I mean,
at some point you don't,
you have to have some sort of a standard.
You can't tell me that there's
not a better republican. Okay.
They're all right.
Please tell me.
Please tell me there's something
somebody better than this guy. All right.
Oh, here we go. Oh, it's old zip
accrued up.
Are you hiring? We'll are you, do you
think the clan uses ZipRecruiter? Uh,
do you know where your post, where to
post your job to find the best candidates?
Talk about the best qualities your
employees have. Well, my employees, me,
and I couldn't tell you. When I look
in the mirror, when I brush my teeth,
I'm like,
God dammit,
there's a fucking hung over guy
that really gets the job done. Uh,
with Ziprecruiter,
you can post your job to 100 plus
job sites with just one click.
Then their powerful technology efficiently
matches the right people to your job
better than anyone else.
That's why zip.
Yeah.
Up is different.
Unlike other job sites,
ZipRecruiter doesn't depend on candidates
finding you. It finds them. In fact,
over 80% of jobs posted on.
Now there's no more sentence
on there. Ziprecruiter and
fucking, I guess, you know,
if they find the right person. No
juggling emails or calls to your office.
Simply screen rate and manage
candidates all in one place with zip
I own is easy to use.
Dashboard.
Find out today why ZipRecruiter has been
used by businesses of all sizes to find
the most qualified job candidates
with immediate results.
And right now my listeners can
post jobs on Ziprecruiter for free.
That's right for free. Just
go to ziprecruiter.com/spark
that's zip recruiter to
us-ziprecruiter.com/bar one more time.
Try It for free.
Go to zip.com/bar all right.
Oh look,
everybody Jolly Shave Club.
Okay.
Dollar Shave Club is the smarter choice.
She get a great shape at a great price.
Conveniently delivered
right to your front Doula.
You no longer have to Schlep to
this store like other than the,
and then go into Yiddish. You know, the
one gay have to Schlep to the steel.
Susan Bloomstein calling a buy
a buy a cheap disposable razor.
Uh,
they give you a cheap shave or spend a
fucking fortune on razors with gimmicky
shaving a technology that you don't need.
And when you use dollar Shave Club's
executive razor with the doc to cabbies
easy shape,
uh,
the blade just gently glides
giving you a smooth shave.
Dr Carver's shave butter is
transparent for a more precise shave,
helps prevent ingrown hairs and fights.
Razor bumps.
Make the smarter choice by joining
the Dollar Shave club revolution.
For a limited time,
new members can get their first month of
the executive razor with a tube of talk
to Covey's executive chef for
only $5 with free shipping.
Then that and that. After that, sorry,
raisers are just a few bucks a month.
That's fifth to a $15
value for only five bucks.
There's no hidden fees and no
commitments cancel any time you like.
You can only,
you can only get this offer
exclusively@dollarshaveclub.com
slash bird that's
dollar shave club.com/bar.
All right. Yeah. You know,
what I watched the other day did I really
enjoyed was I watched this whole thing
on John Daly. That guy has to be
one of the most honest human beings,
one of the most honest human beings ever.
You know, it's kind of hard watching the
guy, what he does to himself. But like
I swear to God, like when we're in scar
face, when that guy goes, I like you Tony.
There is no lying and you,
you know fizzling lying and everybody.
But John Daly, I think he
kicked Gif, they should recast,
they should fucking green
screened him in there. You know,
can somebody Photoshop that in? Somebody
just says, I like you John Daly.
There's no lying in you.
They just be like,
you know how much should the Heidi, you're
drinking when you're drinking a day.
Cause I drink like a case of beer some
days up to maybe 35 40 and they go 35 40
he's like, oh yeah. And then
they go, then one he goes,
I know I probably switched to whiskey
and then he just started laughing. Like,
just be like,
I know it's fucked up.
Talked about how he played his best
golf when he was a little drunk. He was,
you know the balls, you know, you just hit
the ball better, you know, you're looser,
the body relaxes.
And uh,
I really wish I watched golf
more when he was playing,
cause he didn't take all that fucking
time. When he went up to address the ball,
he just went up and he
just fucking hit the thing.
Crushed it like seriously.
Watching that guy swing is one of the most
incredible things I've
ever seen in my life.
I actually saw some fucking idiot did
that thing where he put the tea in his
mouth with the ball.
He let John Daly do a John Daly Swain
and we daily didn't fuck up. Thank
God. But I gotta tell you something.
If you ever took that to this day,
he would've killed him.
He literally would have killed that guy.
He would have gone to jail.
You know what? That guy from the
fucking New Jersey Nets, right?
Shut that limo driver I need.
You would be in that role.
They have a row of cells of uh,
athletes who accidentally killed somebody.
He would have been right there. You know,
what did you do? I shot my limo drive.
What'd you do?
And you know,
I tried to hit a golf ball
out of this guy's mouth and I,
I missed an eye kitty's head.
How far do you think John Daly could
have hit a human head that was still
attached to a body?
So he has to rip it off the body.
I could say you get hit at least 17 feet.
That's the level of Torque and power
in that man swing to check out John a
videos if you get a chance at work. Um, I,
it's crazy. It's so fucking like
it's an overly used expression,
but refreshing when you watched the guy,
he's not trying to hide anything.
It's just like, I know
that's why he's still, yeah,
one time it was a rain delay and uh,
you know,
just went in there and made these two
golfers and yeah, we just got hammered,
just got absolutely hammered.
And then the next day we came out in the
same clothes hung over and we actually
will play.
Great.
All right.
More advertising upside.
There is upside down.
Boy,
you turn me,
there's a better way.
A upside down.com you're turning me.
I wish it wasn't one.
I was just say it was one less
civil in that syllable in this.
So I could fuck her. Really
make that song happen. Um,
there's a better way for you to
buy business travel. You know,
one thing I've learned about these
fucking people that advertise,
evidently they all have a
better way of doing something.
It's called upside.com.
Boy,
you turn me every time
you buy a trip at upside,
you'll save your company a ton of money.
Um,
and they give you an Amazon gift
card worth hundreds of dollars.
Amazon gift card worth $100 a upsides
able to do this because they bundle your
flights and sticky one to the
plane with the luggage. No,
and I'll hotel together.
They bundle your flights and the hotel
together for one low price bundling
prices saves money.
If you're a frequent business traveler,
you're company saves a ton of money and
you can get thousands a year and gift
cards chest for buying your air
and hotel together upside. Uh,
plus you'll get all your miles. Jesus
Christ as a hand job coming next. I mean,
what, what, what more do you guys
need here? If you're shopping per se,
I just got rid of all the females.
Is there a free pair of
pumps coming to ladies?
If you're shopping for business travel,
you'd be fucking crazy not
to checkout upside.com boy,
you turn me Amazon Gift Card. I'll
work it out. I'm working it. Okay.
Believe me,
everybody does it solve the greats.
This is how they write their songs.
It just,
it takes just three minutes to see how
much you can save by buying your flights
and hotel together for one low price.
And right now we use my name Bur B r are
you are guaranteed to get at least why
$100 Amazon gift card.
Your first trip.
That's my name bar to get at least
$100 Amazon Gift Card for free.
Okay.
Think of how many widgets you can get
for that hundred dollars or one of those
fucking fidget wheels,
whatever the fuck they call it.
Save big on travel and get
a big gift card every trip.
Evidently I loved the upside.com
according to this copy,
upside.com minimum purchase required.
See Site for complete details.
All right, the last one.
This is the last worthless re simply safe.
Sorry,
my voice is enough to fucking three shows.
It's a little fucking messed up here.
Um, summaries, primetime for burglary.
Oh my God. Cheese. I'm scared. So
now is the time to protect your home.
For a limited time.
You can take a whopping $100 of simply
safe's especial thumber package.
This is simply saves the biggest ever
summer sale and has everything you need to
protect your home and arsenal
of security sensors. Whoa.
An arsenal security
sense to secure each door and window.
Are you a static ana?
You're simply safe.
System comes with the panic button.
Jesus Christ down.
I'm thinking about the chick from fucking
silence of the lambs. Jodie Foster,
a blaring extra siren and a wireless
connection to authorities and police
dispatch, your family, your
home and everything in it.
Stay safe around the
clock with simply safe.
There are no longterm contracts,
installation costs and no hidden fees
and 24 seven professional monitoring is
just 1499 a month.
Get a hundred dollars off the summer
security package@simplysafebird.com if you
guys knew what was going
through my head right now,
this sale ends September 3rd that simply
safe bird.com to get your $100 off
simply safe bird.com do you
remember in the panic room
when she had to go out of the panic chroma
that she went back in and as she went
to go back in,
there was like some issue where maybe she
would've caught her fucking arm in the
door
and I was just thinking,
what if she fucking did and it closed
and then she had to make the decision?
Do I reopen the door,
expose my kid to the bad guy or do I
just sit here while my arms slowly just
fucking dies? And then, then
I'll die in here. You know?
See, this is why I don't write movie
scripts because that would fucking happen.
And every like, oh my
God, it was terrible.
Then she fucking died and the kids saw
it and then he couldn't figure out the
code and then everybody died.
Right. It was a double feature.
After that we showed the local news,
um, white people, this is, Oh God,
we're going to get into the ration.
Are we really going to get into the
ratio here? Okay. White people. Oh,
Billy ambassador.
I'm unsure.
I'm sure you address the current events
at the top of the Po, this podcast.
I skipped over most of it.
As you may have heard.
I just thought of trashed Trump for not
having the fucking humanity to trash,
you know, some of the dumbest
people on the planet, you know,
and actually blaming the
people that they attack
also. I just don't
fucking get it. He goes,
I'm pretty moderate and have the same
Ron Paul ideas about government is,
you seem to have a, sorry
about the generations trying
to keep a tight yet. Dude,
I don't even know what the fuck
I believe anymore. He said,
I watched my Facebook feed all
day. Denounce White people.
All right. First of all,
why would you go on a Facebook feed?
Are you trying to depress yourself?
Are you trying to make yourself upset?
Why would you go on there?
What did you do next?
Did you go on Twitter and look up Hashtag
white people so you could infuriate
yourself more and get an even more,
um,
like delusional view of
what the population is like?
You know,
I dunno.
I mean, if you watched all
that shit about the Klansmen,
you'd think that every white person was
in the Klan. I mean, it's just, I dunno.
Anyways, plowing ahead here.
Uh, he says, uh, I look white,
but I'm first generation American
with my parents coming from Italy.
Okay. Yeah. You're, you're telling
you, okay. I get it. All right.
My policy on making general statements
about entire races is I don't,
and stereotypes.
Sure.
Why people love things like
jarred jam's budding criticism.
I never say white people or black
people because if history has taught us
anything,
it's the dumbest thing you period.
I think you meant to say the
dumbest thing you can do. He goes,
I'm tired of it all day white people.
There's white people that I voted for
Barack the first time I ate Nazis.
And it's fucking pathetic that
I have to say that out loud.
I think Trump is a con. I hated Hillary.
I don't wish for the south to rise again.
I'm not offended as a white person.
I'm just tired of the laziness
of an am I way off here.
Uh, look, I know what you're
saying, but dude, it's like,
is this the worst thing
you have to deal with?
You got to expect people in a
highly emotional state. All right?
Such as this.
You know,
when you're in a highly emotional state,
you,
you're going to say stuff in a way that
you wouldn't if you were a little more
relaxed.
And then secondly,
if you're going to fucking go on
a Facebook feed and get upset,
I don't have any sympathy
for you. Like, it's,
you know, it's, it's,
it's a Facebook feed.
There's no,
the qualifications to comment on Facebook
is you have to be smart enough to sign
up for Facebook. That's it. So
that's what g it's not a think tank.
It's not a ted talk,
which even those things,
I'm starting to think of just a
fucking bunch of snake oil salesmen.
Everybody acting like some fucking
amazing is happening, you know,
cause somebody is up there with a laser
pointer talking about the future. Um,
yeah, I mean, all right. I understand
what you're saying. Like I'm not,
I'm not going to lie to you.
There are times where I'll see like these
people being applauded for shit that
they're saying.
And when I'm listening to what I'm saying,
it's like if you took out white people
there and then you inserted black people
like that and that person was white,
they would be in trouble. However,
however you do have to take it with a
grain of fucking salt because of the great
fucking life that you
have. All right. And, um,
I dunno, I, I think he should maybe try.
I would try to listen more
to what the overall point is,
rather than wasting time being offended.
You know,
I'm a white guy, I'm a fucking,
life is great, you know,
I can pretty much go wherever the fuck
I want to go. I go down to the mall,
I buy a tee shirt, nobody fucks with
me. Right. I'm not saying it's easy,
but I mean,
compared to what other people compared
to what other people fucking out of,
I guess this is the best, you
know, this is the inside lane,
you know,
I could fucking look the other way,
but there's definitely days I'll,
I'll say this is definitely days that,
you know,
nonwhite people say some shit or like,
women will say stuff about men being like,
that's so fucking overtly fucking sexist
and not only not being called out on it,
you're being applauded for it.
Like you're brave.
And what you're saying is just as fucking
ignorant is what the fuck you're doing.
However, at the end of it, I,
you kinda gotta be like, well,
okay,
because of what's happening
that's so fucking pissed.
Like I give it a little bit,
like,
I just thought I'd give it a little bit
depending on my mood. Um, I do that, but,
um, all right. You don't,
what the honest thing is,
is if I'm sitting there and the
person who isn't white says it,
I'll get into a debate with them.
All right.
But if I'm with all white people
and they're complaining about it,
I'll tell him to shut the fuck up. I think
I'm just a contrarian and all depends.
Um, I don't fucking know, but all I do,
all I know is after watching all
that fucking horrible shit. Yeah.
I just think, you know, there's,
there's a certain level of empathy
that, uh, he should try to tap into,
try to put yourself in other
people's positions a little bit more.
And um,
I dunno,
I guess to try to compensate
for the astounding level of
fucking ignorance that's out there.
I guess she got to try to make yourself
an even better person or somehow,
I don't know.
I don't know what to tell you because
I'll be honest with you is when our people
go, Hey, I'm not in a fucking
mmm,
oh, not in the clan. I'm not
a Nazi guy. I'm not, I don't
belong a hate group, blah,
blah, blah. And Bernard Shit,
everybody has their fucking issues.
And when you're a comedian,
it's like you're running for office.
It's like you run this campaign that
never fucking stops and you're meeting
people. Like, I was just in Red Bank,
New Jersey, now I'm in Tarrytown,
now I'm going to go to fucking La,
you know,
the end of the month I'm going to
be in Boston, in New Hampshire,
then I'm going to be in
Mississippi and Alabama. Um,
am I really promoting my upcoming dates,
talking about racism. Look amazing.
Next thing, I should have
Bobby flay reading this. Um,
but the point is as I'm going to
meet all these fucking people and um,
I dunno, I gotta be honest with you.
Everywhere I go, no matter where I'm at,
when I'm in a room and it's just
all white guys of a certain age,
my generation and older,
you can literally take a fucking,
I swear to God,
like one of those sands of
time timers and just go, okay,
when is the n word common?
I'm trying to remember.
I'm trying to remember the last time that,
you know, it doesn't happen every time,
but I go in there and I literally started
having anxiety going, Oh God, you know,
I look around and what I'm doing
is I'm judging too. And I'm like,
when's it coming?
Someone's going to fucking say it or
someone's going to say something a little
borderline.
Yeah.
MMM.
And it's depressing.
Like I was hanging,
yeah.
Uh,
recently on a row gig and it was all
white dudes in there and Mayweather
accused. Mcgregor is saying something
racist and Mcgregor's going, I, you know,
I didn't fucking say anything
racist, but blah, blah, blah,
Blah and all this type of shit.
Right.
And then this random white guy is watching
it. He goes, yeah, what's a big deal?
He's like, this guy's an n word, net
guy's Whitey. I mean, it's a fight.
Who gives a fuck what you say? And I'm
just, I'm just thinking in my head like,
dude, they're not saying
he said that like, like,
but that is like,
that's how his fucking brain
process that information.
And it's, it's, I dunno,
it's, it's so fun.
It's depressing
cause you know what it is.
Everybody thinks they're as smart and
everybody thinks they have it figured out.
You know what I mean? Think about
when is the last time you, I mean,
sometimes your conscious gets to you,
but does your brain really ever say like,
uh,
I mean, it takes a lot to
fucking admit that you're wrong,
regardless of color, sex or anything.
They'd be like, you know what,
I shouldn't have done that.
I was wrong. I, you know,
I now realize how fucking ignorant
that takes a look into truly mean it.
Not to just get on the good side of
your wife against the, she'll bang here,
right? To truly fucking sincerely
mean it and then try to make a change.
It takes a fucking lot.
And, uh, for anybody.
So I dunno. So I've gone
through things like,
you know, if somebody does says that,
what do I do? Do I fucking confront them?
Okay.
Do I get into the fucking debate?
I've tried every fucking technique.
Do I get up and walk out every
fucking tactic? Nothing works.
Not that fucking works.
Um,
that is depressing.
So I try to avoid that social situation.
Maybe that's what I'll do in the future.
Uh,
anyways,
that was like a time over the f I don't
remember what the fuck I was when I was
in, I was in Durham, North Carolina, and
that fucking guy goes, you know, Bill,
I like you, you know, you're a good
person. You know, you don't bill. He goes,
I like meet good people. And I
was like, Oh God, here it comes.
I like meeting good people.
He sees testing the waters,
he sticking his toe and you know,
Christian Good Christian people,
white people, and then boom,
the fucking Edward comes.
So that guy who headed off at
the pass is that you don't buy a,
I like being good people and I was
just like, Oh yeah, do you, you know,
I like meeting bad people who the
fuck doesn't like making good people.
And then he, then he shut up. Then you
shut up. And then he got really mad at me,
you know, when I was
talking about, you know,
I dunno like the Middle East or something
like that. And I was just going like,
dude, they in another lane
us. You know what I mean?
They've got a couple of crazy fucking
leaders and then everybody else is a bunch
of you and me walking around, they're
trying to get a sandwich, you know,
you and I were trying to get the fucking,
uh,
the NBA package and they're
trying to whatever fucking sport.
But what sports are they into
over there? Soccer. Right.
Everybody's into the fucking soccer.
Um, anyways, so, yeah, I dunno.
I understand. You know, but, uh, I dunno.
I, I don't, I don't, I don't have any
fucking answers. I don't fucking know.
All right. Younger girlfriend,
not ready for marriage.
Okay.
Okay. Hi Bill. I'm a big fan of
yours and would like your advice.
I'm a 35 year old guy.
Okay.
From the Bronx dating a 20 year
old Japanese girl in Japan.
I love her a lot and want to marry her,
but she tells me she's not ready for
marriage and children yet and can't really
say if or when she'll be ready.
Yeah, it's cause she's 20
okay.
It was, I love her, but getting
married and having children,
it's very important to me. If I were
younger I would say, okay, no problem.
And just keep dating and
see if anything changes.
But at 35 I'm starting to feel pressure
to get married sooner rather than later.
That societal pressure. But I worry that
I'm getting too old to be a father. Well,
I just had one at 48, so, um,
Alec Baldwin's fucking knocking them out
in his 50s. He said, I'm okay right now,
but in five or 10 years I feel I might
not have enough energy to run around
chasing little ones. And if she's
still not ready in a few years,
that would put me in a very difficult
position. You just think it's smart, sir.
I'm happier than I've ever been with her.
And happiness can be so fleeting that I
don't want to ruin it with what I have
with her, but at the same time, I can't
wait forever. What would I do? Um,
I would,
I would listen to a,
I would listen to logic.
All right.
I, I really think, you know,
most of the time, you know, if who's
dragging their feet to the altar,
it's usually the guy. Okay,
not the woman. Why would they?
For the most part,
generally speaking,
they're marrying somebody that
makes more money than them.
So there's no fear financially.
If you fucking,
you know,
they're not going to lose half the house.
They're going to get the whole house
and they're going to get a fucking check
from you. That's basically what
the fuck happens. You know,
it's like the showcase showdown
at the end of the price is right.
And you're the guy that they go, hey,
thanks for playing and you just walk off.
And then everybody crowds
around the person that one,
that's usually the woman in marriage.
Okay.
And I don't hear any shit from women
because all you guys do is bitch that you
don't make as much money as men.
So what I'm saying,
cause if you're just going to say that's
not the fucking case than what he had
bitching about fucking equal pay for.
All right? Either you're making less a,
you're not.
All right.
So for you to sit there have been saying,
I love you.
I want to spend my life with you and
fucking have children with you and start a
family and live happily ever after for
her to say I'm not ready for that yet.
And I can't really say if or
when I will be ready. Yeah, Dude,
she's 20 years old. She has no idea
who the fuck she is. You're, you're,
you're fucking 15 years down the road,
you know who you are,
you know what you want,
and uh,
I don't think she's going to
figure that out with you. You know,
you're taking their best years away from
her when she should be out fucking seen,
figuring out what the
fuck she wants and you,
and your best years of cause.
Now you're ready.
So you need to go out and meet a fucking
mature woman. Who was it not mature.
I'm not saying this woman's immature,
she's not in, but she's fucking 20.
Okay.
All right. This is what happens.
This is what happens when you, when,
when there's that level of an age
difference at this age. Okay. Look,
if you were 45 and she was 35, she'd
be fucking, you know, pressure and you,
mmm,
I dunno dude. I would just hate for
her to at 23 to be like, you know, uh,
I don't, this isn't like what I want
and now you're 38 you push in for,
you don't want it. Then I think I
would, uh, pull the rip cord now,
you know,
that's what I would do. I
don't fucking know. I mean,
it's hard for me to tell you to fucking
break up with somebody over a paragraph
of information on a podcast as I sit
in a bed in the hotel room, isn't it?
So take all of that with a grain of salt.
All right. You know what I would do, sir?
I would ask you.
Good friends.
Ask you good friends with the fuck
they think because they know you.
And like she'd have to have a nice long
fucking distance phone call with you.
I guess you're in Japan right
now. I would do that. You know,
maybe you get some friends into Japan.
I don't fucking know.
That's a big decision, but just
from that little information. Yeah,
I get out of it,
you know?
And I'm also saying don't do that cause
I don't fucking know you. All right?
Okay.
Jason's Christ bill. Could your waffle
anymore than that one? All right.
I dumped my girlfriend
and now I regret it.
Yeah.
Is this the followup song too? I kissed
a girl and I liked it. Um, hi bill.
I started watching your
podcast watching my podcast.
I don't know how you're doing that.
You mean listening to my iPod?
Kaz. Oh, this person is not from this
country or it doesn't speak English.
And he was, I'm going to read this right,
is the same way this person wrote it.
I started watching your podcasts since
few months because the best Romanian
standup comedians always said that they
listened to yours in their podcasts.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Romanian comics.
Listen to this podcast.
Shout out to Romania.
Huh?
Is that where all the Gypsies Come?
The Richard Pryor's and George
Carlin's of fucking pickpocket hers.
I gotta tell you, man, they're fucking
amazing. They're pains in the asses,
but Jesus Christ can those fucking people
pick your pocket you almost like and
they leave. You can't find your
passport. You almost fucking applaud him.
I don't know where you are, but that was
good. I had no idea. God bless you. Um,
I dunno if they come from Romania, the
Gypsies, Transylvania, that Gypsy stay.
Move around. Now about the
story, me and this girls,
we had a complicated too.
You've got a threesome.
He couldn't broke up with two girls.
I had a complicated story and I tried
six months to be what they are until I
finally succeeded.
So after one year and a half,
a very nice relationship, he
was giving it to her, of course,
with ups and downs before I
leaved to Germany to study,
I decided alone that will be
better for her if we split up.
So I dumped her and said to her
that we should remain friends.
My decision was because
I got scared of her love.
She would leave all of her
dreams and stuff only did
come with me and be with me.
And T to hear that at
19 years old is scary.
It's scary as shit. Uh, now after
nine months when the moving out,
euphoria has vanish, I now know that
I made a big mistake and I realized
how cunt I was to her.
I think you mean country,
uh, in the past month. So she moved
on, but we still kind of talk,
but I cannot sleep anymore.
I developed a little problem with
drinking alone and trying not to feel
something. A little advice
would be nice. Thank you.
And all good for you and your family.
First of all,
fuck can you did great with your English.
I knew exactly what the fuck you were
talking about. I could never do that.
Well I don't even know what you guys,
what do you speak over there is it
gives a Calder Romanian tap pansy.
Um,
okay
dude, you're 19. You're going to
meet somebody else. I mean, um,
on your way to finding the
person you're going to,
you're going to be with you fuck up.
Like anything, any success story.
You make mistakes and you learn
from them along the way. All right?
If you really love her,
I mean this is what you could do.
Call her up one time and just say,
listen,
I just want you to know
that breaking up with you.
What's the biggest mistake I've ever made?
I've had a problem sleeping. I've been,
I've developed, I've been drinking,
trying to forget and just
tell her why you did it.
It just totally communicate with her and
see what, see what she says. All right?
And you know, if she doesn't take you
back, you can live with that. Okay?
The bottom line, dude, you fucking 19
years old, okay. Don't start drinking.
Don't do, don't make the
mistakes I made. All right?
You're in the prime of your fucking life.
Turning around. Wake up every morning.
Have some positive thing that
you say to yourself. All right?
It's simple as today's going
to be a great day. Alright?
Fucked up that relationship
with so and so.
But I forgive myself and I'm going to
go out that door and I'm going to be a
fucking rail. Like, you know when
you can attract somebody else too.
You go out there,
have a good time and when you
meet a woman right that you like,
just, just fucking be straight
up on. It's how you doing, man?
I'm trying to be positive, trying to
be positive. I went through some shit.
I'm trying to get over it and
I'm trying to be positive.
What's going on with you there,
Cutie Pie. Start doing that.
Don't fucking start drinking and being
a sad sack, you know, drinking again.
Oh baby, I'm drinking again. All
right, that's it. But this is a good,
this is going to be
good experience for you.
You can learn how to
fucking open up as a guy,
communicate your feelings and learn how
to fucking get closure with the woman
that you broke up with or who knows.
It opens back up. Who knows? Right?
And then also you learn how to not
make self-distribute learn how to pick
yourself up off the fucking Mac.
Cause I'm a tell you right now,
you're 19 years old.
If you think this is the first time
you're going to get knocked on your ass in
life, um, you're, you're
sadly mistaken. All right?
You got to learn how to get back up again.
So this is a great opportunity no
matter what. All right? So there you go.
Grasshopper, take those positive words
and go help yourself a great fucking day.
All right. How do you make friends
after turning 25 Oh, Jesus Christ.
What do you mean? Just, I don't know.
Buy a round of drinks. He says, my man,
double be no fun, Dude. That,
that dead, uh, old Billy.
No fun is complete bullshit. I've been
having too much fun. I happen all right.
And I've been having a problem
turning off the fun faucet,
if you know what I mean. Um,
I'm struggling here. All right.
There's always a reason.
There's always a reason. Oh,
he just shut his special bump. Oh,
written fucking tomato pies. Bang.
Oh, I'm on a fucking flight. And the guy
asked me if I want to drink, but Sally,
all right, big fan. You may
have had this question before,
but I've moved into a new town and I've
learned that I have no guy friends.
I mean,
I'm plowing like crazy through these apps,
but I miss just going to the bars with
the fellas. Okay. So, um, yeah, I'm an,
I'm an old guy. So you're, you're on
these dating apps and you fucking,
you motherfuckers,
man.
Yeah.
Good Lord. How fucking easy is it
to get laid? Jesus Christ. He goes,
I keep trying to arrange to
go out with guys some work,
but they all commute in from
another town and have girlfriends.
They need to tend to,
I find myself going back to my hometown
a lot on the weekends to see my buds are
laying pipe with miscellaneous
chicks where I live now.
So my very sad question is, how
does a guy make friends, chairs,
uh, you poor baby, you just don't
their bag and all these chicks.
You know what I would do?
I'd fucking hang out with them.
Okay.
I just started hanging out with
them. The fuck. Do you care?
You can always find a fucking cruel
dopes to go watch a fucking game with.
Um, you know what I would do? I don't,
I don't know. He said cheers so much.
It's the assuming gifts fucking
somewhere over there and Great Britain.
What do they say in Australia too?
I don't fucking know. Anyways.
Um,
do you play sports?
Go play some pickup hockey.
He'd go play some fucking softball.
Go places to pick up soccer, football,
whatever the fuck you call it.
I would do that. I would get
involved in some sort of an activity,
a sports related. Um, if
you're into like, I don't know,
you don't sound like you're in to a
comic con shit considering all the women.
You seem to be fucking so,
yeah, I would, I would, I dunno.
I would do something like that.
Is there an APP for that?
I have no idea. All right. What
time is it here? All right.
Time for me to wrap this up. Uh, my
girlfriend doesn't appreciate me.
Aw,
but go for it.
Doesn't appreciate me.
Ooh.
Um,
hey Billy back fat.
I liked that one.
Um, I'm a 21 year old guy. Currently
unemployed. Well, why the fuck? Yeah,
you're a guy without a job.
It's like being a woman without tits
and we went the fuck or a vagina.
Yes. Women. That's what we look
at. You like. I'm sorry. We are,
we're fucking animals blamed God. That's
how we're wired. I'm a 21 year old guy,
currently unemployed and I live with my
girlfriend and we've been together for a
year and I'm, and I'm s oh,
a year and seven months now.
Uh, recently, it seems like she
doesn't appreciate me anymore.
Yesterday when she was at work, I made
her coffee, did the laundry for her,
bought her some pizza,
and then picked her up.
And all you heard that night was how I
didn't rinse the dishes enough before
putting them in the dishwasher.
She doesn't act like this.
Uh,
she doesn't act this way to anyone else.
And I feel like I can't do
anything right around her.
Would love to hear your feedback and go
fuck yourself. Yeah, here's the deal.
Here's the deal.
All right?
And you'll never get a woman
to admit this, all right?
But one of the great things
about them having a boyfriend,
he said he's going to pay for shit.
He's going to take him out.
He's going to buy or buyers stuff,
right?
He's going to fucking, you know,
your job as a man is to provide,
okay. A woman, you know, after you give,
you push her off the dock with you Johnson
there, she can make a fucking baby,
all right?
And then immediately just be the greatest
fucking mom and it's fucking magical
to watch.
What can we do?
We pick up heavy shit that they can't
pick up and we go out and we earn a
living. Now here's the thing, as a man,
the second you're sitting there and you
don't have a fucking job, and she does,
and now she gets to feel
what it's like to be a man,
which is you fucking come home,
right?
You've busted your ass all day.
You know, if you're fucking young,
you don't have your dream job yet unless
you Justin Bieber or somebody like that
or you made it for professional
sports. Generally speaking, your 20s,
just the struggle of the dream Pope.
And it comes true at some point in your
it thirties so she's coming home and
she's seeing you sitting there
like a little fucking homemaker.
And you know every guy sometimes you know
when you come home and you look at you,
you know,
if your wife stays at home,
your girlfriend stays at
home and you just look at us.
But she would not have any kids. It's
like, what the fuck did you do all day?
Yeah,
it's like every Saturday for Yo,
what the fuck?
You know? But at the end of the day,
like getting up and look at me, she's,
you know, she's, she's fucking
beautiful. She's bagging me, you know,
all that shit that guys, I
think of reporting. But for
women, you got to provide,
dude, you got to get a
fucking job. You want,
you want your girlfriend to
fucking respect you again.
You got to get a fucking job.
Okay,
you got to start bringing home money.
That's it.
See what I do is I actually,
I bring home money and I do
the fucking dishes, you know?
So then whenever my wife gives me shit, I
could be like, what? What is the problem?
Okay. I'm like, fucking Babe Ruth here.
I'm hitting home runs and
I'm pitching a no hitter.
What the fuck else do you want?
What is the problem?
So you that you know why I can say that?
Because I have a fucking job.
You don't have a job, sir.
So no matter what the fuck
you do, her problem with you.
It's not that he didn't
rinse the shit off.
It's not that you did this wrong or
you would drive it too fucking fast.
It's the fact that when you guys
go out to get a meatball sub,
she has to pay for it, you know? Yeah.
You want to see the all their feminism
go right out the fucking window.
You stay home.
You'd be Mr Mom.
That's what happened here,
sir. What happened here, sir,
is you stopped being a man to her.
The second you don't have a job,
when you're with a woman, you immediately
become like this fucking 20, 25, 30,
35 40 year old fucking teenager.
They look at you like you're a child.
MMM.
That's it. So you need to get
a fucking job. Am I might,
uh, ladies, I, am I wrong? I'm
speaking for you here. Okay.
If you think of fucking run just right
into the podcast and I read your opinions
and then I'll make fun of
myself. All right? Okay.
I got to get out of this fucking hotel.
MMM.
That's a podcast. Go fuck
yourselves. I'll check in on you.
And,
uh,
a dark day and uh, you
know, I'm a, you know,
after all that fucking depressing
shit I saw in Charlottesville,
I'm going to try to be, and I'm going to,
I'm be fucking nice to everybody today.
All right.
I'm going to try to go on a nice
little run up being nice to everybody.
Go out of my fucking way to not be a cunt,
okay.
To be a little more empathetic as I just
trashed women and spoke about them in a
nice big generalized way.
I'm basically a fucking hypocrite and I'm
for life can stand why you guys listen
to me. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll see you Thursday.