Hey,
what's going on?
Is Bill burn his time for the Monday
morning podcast from Monday, uh,
June 25th, 2018 what's
going on? I whoa. Yo,
how you doing? How you doing with the,
the summer, the summer's here, right?
We're in the,
we're in the twenties of June.
Somewhere along the lines of first day
of summer. You know, back in the day,
used to know it right?
Because there wasn't as many channels
and you would watch the local news and
they'd bring it up. Tonight is the
first day of summer. Tell us, Jack,
what can people look forward to weather
wise? While I'll tell you a bike.
We got a low pressure.
Says, look, Google it.
It's so don't inflate those fucking
above ground pools. Yes. Yep.
Um,
and then they'd laugh for no reason.
Your weekend's going to suck. Um, anyways,
uh, it's gotta be a summertime,
right? The fucking son's out.
There you go right there.
Global warming. Um,
what'd you do this weekend?
I have a couple, of course,
like that's his generation's Budweiser,
Coors light. They're crushing it.
You know,
Peyton Manning's fucked up.
You notice the second Peyton
manning fucking bought Budweiser.
Now it's second place. You
know, you didn't buy it.
He bought into it the
second he fucking God.
And I bet he started pointing fingers
at everybody. You know, we, we, we got,
we had some hops issues,
right? And all of a sudden,
nobody's getting along over there and
of course lights now cause lights ahead.
Right? I Bet Tom Brady
invested in concourse lite.
Sorry. Why would I do this?
I like Peyton manning now
that he's retired. You know,
I could look back and be like,
you know what,
that fellow was sat quite quarterback,
but when they're playing against your
team, you hate him. It's stupid. You know,
you don't hate them. You
just, hey, it's weird. Um,
anyways,
uh,
the summers here I am back
from vacay shawl and a,
I'm getting ready this weekend. Oh,
freckles. Shaking off the cobwebs.
I'm going to be in Minneapolis,
Minnesota, in Detroit,
Michigan. Okay. A couple, uh,
Joe, six pack towns, you know,
where they put their pet to
one leg at a thought. Uh,
looking forward to that and a,
so I'm going to be around La doing a
bunch of spots, shaking off the dust.
I'm on the elliptical,
working off the cholesterol panel.
Shock a lot. I never had
any of those, you know,
my wife's into those
fucking things I liked.
I like the plain old
boring white guy croissant.
I don't need any flavor.
Uh,
anyways. Oh my God. Um,
I don't want to talk about this early on,
but I have to out of respect, uh, to sad,
sad, sad, sad day. Uh, the passing of V,
the Great Vinnie Paul,
um,
drummer of obviously Pantera damaged
blend and hell yeah, good Lord.
What a, what a loss. Can't even,
can't even put it into words.
And I was lucky enough to meet him.
He was a big comedy fan and I
remember the first time I met him,
I was opening for the
late Great Charlie Murphy.
This is what happens when you get older.
Like half your stories is like half
the people in a more like fucking dead.
It's sucks. Um, but anyways, yeah, me,
Charlie and Danelle or on tour.
And we did the Addison Improv
and, uh, I remember that that was one of
those shows, one of the few times I ever,
I went over without even realizing it.
I always knew when I was going over,
but I did like 40 minutes and
I was supposed to be like 25.
It just one of those that just let,
there was talking and I don't
know what happened. And, um,
Charlie was cool with it, but I was
in Paris because I never do that shit.
And it's a real country thing to do
and it's something, you know, mixed.
The headline is job more difficult
because you ate up all of that extra time
wearing them out and all
of that shit. So, uh,
I do remember that from that weekend,
but one of those shows,
it wasn't the show and I went over,
but, uh, I was standing after the show,
selling my cds. This is how long ago
this was. It was right around, uh,
it was 2004. His brother
was still alive. Um,
and I was just standing there
and I just looked up and he,
and he was standing right there,
Finney fucking Paul. And you know,
it wasn't like he was Vinnie Paul
offstage. He just was Vinnie Paul.
He had the fucking cowboy hat on,
you know,
this shirt with flames on it and shit,
these crazy cowboy boots and he's just
standing of the big smile on his face.
And I was just like, oh, I
mean, this guy, he's like,
guys saw on the cover of modern drummer.
I couldn't believe it. I was like,
I was like,
Holy Shit in fucking Vinny Foley.
You started laughing and you know,
it was super complimentary
about the show and all that.
And then he invited us out. Uh,
he had his own club out there,
gentleman's club,
then we all went out there
and he was nice enough,
I actually sat with him in
his club for like 45 minutes,
like a total drum nerd and asked
them all of these questions about,
um, Trump parts that he did. And, and, um,
like, who were the guys that he
listened to? And, uh, and, you know,
I asked and I said,
you know,
who do you think only one
of the underrated drummers
out there? And he was like,
Oh, Alex van Halen, you know,
and we went on and on about him.
It's kind of ironic because I really
feel that Vinnie and dime bag where the
Eddie and Alex, I should say Alex and
Eddie of their generation. And um,
it just sucks man. He was just such
a nice guy. And then after that, uh,
he probably came out to two or three
other shows and he always was smiling,
always was just the greatest,
nicest guy. And, um,
it's,
I dunno,
one of the reasons why I never got into
double bass playing was because so many
people, I just felt like once,
like they all have fills,
everything was just their fucking feet
and their hands stunk and it didn't
groove. It just was going nine
zillion miles an hour. And, you know,
it was impressive to look at, but it
didn't, it didn't give me the chills.
It didn't make me want to do it.
And he was a guy that changed that.
And I, I, when I listened to him play, um,
my younger brothers who were independent,
Tara, I fucked up. I never saw him a,
I remember one of my
brothers went to go see him,
was telling me how amazing the show is.
But to be honest with you, like I, I just,
you know,
conscious with different,
back then you could get fucked up at
a concert and there was no cell phone
footage. She just got fucked up and that
was it. And there was like mosh pits.
Like it just, it changed.
And I got a little bit older.
I was in my mid twenties,
basically when they came around and I had
already started doing standup and shit.
And um, you know, I remember
going to a couple of, uh,
you know, concerts like ACDC and shit
and people were doing blow and it was,
you know, it was a little
fucking, you know, there was you,
you had to be like a certain level of
fucked up just so you could stay relaxed
so you could kind of navigate it,
you know what I mean?
You couldn't be sitting there looking
fucking nervous. And I, you know,
and that was just it like ACDC,
which was always like a fun show.
So like put this pant,
Tara came in.
It was a new level of aggression and anger
certainly, you know, with Phil singing,
I had never heard anything like that.
And um,
you know, just the way I was just,
I just had this feeling of my house.
I was too afraid I was, I'm going
to fucking going to go down there,
my fucking orange hair trying to grow it
out and it just gets bigger and bigger
and it looked like Bernie from
room to 22 and there's a mosh pit.
I'm going to get the Sh,
you know how I always got over with
people was making them laugh and the show
was going to be too fucking loud.
So if they would just going to look at
me the way I looked, I mean I would,
I just felt like it
wasn't going to go well.
So I was a fan from afar and I really
fucked up by not seeing those guys.
And, um, I remember when Vinny came down
on the show, he said, hey, you know,
I got this, this new, uh, this new
band. I think it was. Yeah, it was,
it was damaged plan. He said, we play
in New York. He said, he goes, he goes,
I'll hook you up. I said,
really? He said, dude, he goes,
you can fucking stand right
behind me while I play the
whole show. And of course,
um, I had some fucking road
gig when they came to town.
I think Florentine went,
cause I remember talking to him about
it and I was so fucking envious that he
got to go and I, I didn't get to go,
so I never saw him play live. But, um,
you know,
since doing that Dean del Ray's show
or I had to learn how to play a much,
I butcher the sun,
but I tried to learn how to play
that song by Motley Crue live wire,
which had the double bass, you know,
basic thing in there. Since then,
I've just kinda gotten addicted to it.
And I was listening to all of the
Pantera stuff in a whole nother level.
And um, you know, cowboys
from Hell and fucking,
uh, um, broken and this love,
just loving the drum parts are just
so fucking perfect in all of those.
And I was just talking,
I was talking to my drum teacher
literally that day of how great, um,
Finney Paul was, um, with
his work in that band and,
and then like it fuck,
it was so weird that night.
Then all of a sudden I got that text,
I couldn't fucking believe it.
And I'm Super Sad. But, um,
I don't know.
Like the only good thing I could say is
that got the mark that the guy left his,
he, he won't be forgotten and obviously
his brother hasn't been. So anyways,
that's my little,
my little point of view on a truly one
of the great artists that I ever heard of
or got to, I dunno, listen to whatever
hang out with or anything. So,
so that sucks. And that's sad. So I don't
know where the fuck did go from here.
How do you, how do you turn it
back to being funny? You know,
can I talk about the Germans playing the
Swedes and the fucking, uh, do they play?
Sweden is out or was it by the, the, the
shirts for the same colors, their flags.
So, um, I always fucked that up. Sweden,
it's Switzerland because I'm
an American and we never,
they never taught us geography like that.
And I remember one time I did a
Gig in Sweden and I said, hey,
it's great to be here in Switzerland.
And they all laughed thinking I was
joking and I honestly fucked it up and I
just rolled with it. I was just
like, Hey, just fucking with you.
They both start with sw, but I, I did
that the whole, thank you Cleveland.
Whatever the fuck it
was a spinal tap thing.
I got to get back there.
I haven't done, um,
what would you call that? Hitler's ranch
up there. Norway, Sweden and Finland.
All those places. When he used to look
across the, was it the Baltic Sea?
I don't know what the fuck it is.
It's just look across that water.
They're all desserts is what
people should look like. Yeah.
Frolicking in the grass.
Um,
anyways, um, tello swing,
did you know, they,
they, they were noncommittal a World War
II ended up being a great fucking move.
Not socially. It wasn't a good move, but
it was a great fucking move financially.
Cause just for the fact that they were
still standing after World War II never
got bombed. You know, let the, let the,
let the crowds fucking use a
train to go to Norway. MMM.
They stood there. They're fucking apple
piece was still open at the end of it,
you know. So I mean, I, if I guess
you can learn something from Sweden.
Okay.
When Shit is hitting the fan and
you to stand up and make a stand,
don't let other people do it. Just kind
of sit back and see who wins it. Ed, uh,
carry on
anyways, so the Swedes or
play in Germany. All right.
I'm mostly German,
so I usually root for Germany.
MMM.
Or whatever. Or I just root
for an underdog. Like Iceland.
I mean high enough fucking roof, Iceland
and Poland and shit like that. You know,
I'm rooting for all any anybody other
than the powerhouses that always seem to
be in an, I don't know shit
about soccer. So this is, boy,
it's going to make it funny.
But anyway,
so I'm watching this fucking game
and this Swedish dude, right? Yeah.
He's on a fucking break away
going, God, he's all all alone.
Right? And then this Joe Guy in
the German team, a black dude,
which is hilarious. You know what I mean?
I was always just sitting there like,
like how conflicted would Hitler
be Germany one. But what's,
what does the whole foods,
is that outside,
he comes down and goes to not
only went to like trip the guy,
he also cut,
like just pushed him from behind and like,
oh,
fucking referee and the WWE,
somehow this guy didn't see it.
Okay.
I mean, I think it happened in
the box, in the painted area,
whatever the fuck they
call it in that sport.
And I think that that should have just
been one of those fucking penalty kicks
with a goalie.
Just dives and guesses one side.
Um, but anyways, the Swedes ended up going
up one, nothing that Germans tied it up.
And then this guy,
he did the old bend it like Beckham
did the old fucking a roundabout there.
I don't know how to talk about the sport.
Uh, but I got to tell you something.
I actually,
okay,
I love making fun of soccer but I have
to watch it in order to make fun of it.
And now having watched it,
I'm actually,
I kind of love it now and I kind of
understand the beauty of the game.
Finally.
I'm starting to get it and it is really
cool that it is so hard to score that
when it happens that people
absolutely lose their fucking minds.
So I am on board.
I'm going to continue to make fun of it.
I had it on in the
background and you know,
I had like fucking two weeks of male
here that I was going through and um,
okay.
And the amount of times that I just kept
looking over at the TV cause he knows
he'd be like,
oh,
he's going to be sick.
Yeah.
So I was sitting at the table
going like, oh my God. Oh,
something almost happened. That's
what it just seemed like. Um,
okay.
But it really is a great game. Uh, GI
bill. Yeah. You really, uh, you know, you,
the rest of the world is right, Bill.
And you might be wrong on this one. Um,
but I missed it today.
A good friend of mine wrote in a Protean
sent me a text and I'm in podcast mode.
She sent me a text message and
asked me if I had saw the, um,
England play today.
I guess they played a great game.
And I heard Mexico had a pretty scrappy
game with the Koreans heard it was
getting a little nasty. They're like,
the Koreans would desperate like, oh,
we don't give a fuck. You know, we
can't score unless we have the ball. Uh,
you know, I guess Mexico's
fast. That's what I know.
And I promise you this week I'm going to
neglect all my responsibilities and I'm
going to try to watch some of this
shit cause uh, it is, it is fun.
Go once every four years,
the entire world gets together to play
for an actual world championship is
pretty, that's pretty sick. You know,
I just wish I could use their hands.
You just see that one Connie
fucking jumped over the
guy and accidentally kicked
him in the face.
I mean that's gotta be like,
okay.
Kicking a guy on the ground in the face,
in the realm of like losing
your man card forever.
Like, who fuck who does that with your
shoes on leash, you can be barefoot.
So maybe make you foot sting a little bit.
Um,
I would be so disappointed
if I had a fucking son and
he ended up playing soccer.
First of all, I'd be happy for his brain,
but you know, if that's what he did,
you're going to frolic down the field
and jump in the air like some baby deer
and then kick somebody in the face.
Um,
knowing like the guy does,
he takes out a yellow card.
I hate the way they take it out in the
guy just stands up in front of the guy,
the stupid thing up in the air, like
he's bidding on a fucking Shelby. Um,
anyways, congratulations to anybody
you want. Uh, I got to get into it.
Sorry. I did watch the, uh,
the one finally I was in town.
I got to watch her watch the French GP.
Congratulations to Lewis Hamilton.
Max Verstappen was fucking hilarious
in the press conference afterwards. Uh,
cause federal slammed into botox back.
She was going, you know, I think he needs,
you guys should tell him he needs to
adjust his style because they were given
Max Shit, you know, beginning of the
year. I forget. He took out his own teeth,
took out a, what's his face there? Um,
Daniel Ricardo and they
gave him all this shit does,
does he need to adjust his style?
All these fucking assholes
who don't drive for a living.
So he was trashing all of them go
and you should tell Vettel. Yeah,
you should tell him he needs to do it
justice style and then he shouldn't
adjusted at all the way
I didn't adjust my style.
And now here I sit three races in a row,
whatever on the fucking podium.
You fucking cunt Kimmy ragged.
They kept bringing up the,
this is his 25th,
the 26th podium without winning a race.
It's like this guy's fucking
Lewis Hamilton went because
of Louis samples at my
kid's sleeping. It's cause fucking Lewis
Hamilton wins every God damn week. Okay.
That's like giving somebody shit who
played when Michael Jordan was at the
height of his powers.
Yeah.
He never got a ring. Nobody
got a ring. You know,
I've got to ring Olijahwaun would fucking,
Jordan was playing basketball and then
when he was a little out of shape the
next year, other than that,
everybody got shut the fuck down.
All right. That's what
happens. So what Ha, what, what
needs to happen is the next,
uh, the next Drake great
driver has to come around.
And also for one,
my,
what I little know about the sport is
they got to fucking get with either
Mercedes and Ferrari. Basically. Mercedes,
it seems to have the fastest car out
there cause I think, what's this?
I think Daniel Ricardo was gonna fucking,
he's going to jump somewhere, right?
That's what they say. Um, by like both
those drives and I'll put the eggs,
how the Americans will be coming,
like six to seventh.
We've got some points and our gray cars
or overcast cars. Um,
what else did I do here?
Oh, I got back on my fucking
diet. This has been tough.
It's been tough to get back on the Diet.
I fell the capes I fucking
hate over in France, you know,
and a couple of slip ups, but
at back to the keen one, um,
hitting the elliptical.
Oh God.
The first two minutes of getting on
the elliptical, my age, Jesus Christ.
After that I just kind of
go numb and then it's fine.
I listed my fucking songs
and then it's over. But, um,
I finally got the shoulder thing B and uh,
I have,
I think I have to join a
gym though because in order
to rehab my shoulder where
I can do pull ups again,
I got to do those,
those fucking lat pull downs with like
20 pounds and then 30 and work my way up
to my body weight and then I can attempt
to do like a pull up because what I did
last time when I rehabbed it was I then
got these like those help or bands,
you know, that you stand on and make the
pull up easier. But I was still, you know,
trying to pull up,
you know,
90 a hundred pounds with the weight
and I fucking Jack my shoulder against,
so I got to do what I don't want to do.
I've got to go join a fucking gym,
so I got to find a local
gym, not a fucking, uh,
a chain. What? Cause those are the ones,
they get your credit card and then
you can't fucking get out of it.
I've been tell you that
time I went to Bally's,
I joined Bally's and there was
like trying to fucking leave AOL.
You just couldn't do it.
They'd be,
oh okay Cindy in a hundred
dollar cancellation fee.
And then I sent it in and then they
go, oh yeah, yeah, but there's another,
there's another gym within
like a five mile radius.
So you can't cancel like, oh and
I was to put the fuck, he just,
he just took $100 from me. I should have
sued the fucking shit out of him. And I,
and I didn't. So I just didn't
pay him. I just, you know, I did,
I cancelled the credit card.
That was the only way out and it was,
it was quiet for months.
I didn't hear from anybody.
And then all of a sudden this
collection agency called me up,
the only anti he was William burned the
hair please. And I'm like this, hey.
They're like, Hey, this is showing show
from the show and show collection agency.
We bought your dead from Bally's total
fitness and would like to discuss it with
you. And I was just like, well, I don't
know what the hell you did that for.
You know, I didn't pay them. What,
what the hell, but why would I pay you?
I don't even know you,
you know,
this is your business.
You actually earn a living doing this
shit by debt that other people can't
fucking collect. And so she was
like, you know, giving me Shit,
telling me I had to click or I'm
not doing it. You know, I go, I go,
I have perfect credit.
I've paid everything. Okay.
I really don't think that someday in
the future when I go to buy a house,
they're going to be like, you know
what? We really want to let you know,
give you a couple hundred
thousand dollars a loan here,
but you owe $300 to a gym.
And she's like, oh my God.
You know what? We just had
a client who just called us
up and said, please, please,
please, I have to pay off. You know,
this $400 that I owe you
because I'm trying to buy a
house and they won't let me.
And I was like, wow. I
go, that's incredible.
That's almost the exact same scenario
that I just presented to you.
It's almost like you made it up.
Right.
And then she got fucking mad at me and
then I just started hitting on her and
she started saying it was harassment and
I just gay. How old are you? You know,
you live around here, you know, you got a
boyfriend or anything. And she ended up,
she got so mad, she
hung up on me. You know,
I'll probably get me to get over that.
And ever since then I been afraid
of the phone. Every time it rings,
I shake.
Okay,
please tell.
Phone's always on styling.
Um,
anyways,
what are we got 22 minutes in here?
Is it time to fucking say?
And you know what I got to met? They
just kept harassing me, harassing me.
I just got sick of it. It was only
300 bucks. So I just fucking pay them
and um,
I shouldn't have, there's a couple people
that I shouldn't have paid and I did,
but I just, I didn't like
the, uh, the stress, you know,
I couldn't put it into perspective and I
just got sick of them calling me and I,
you know, I had fun with them. Shit.
Okay.
Hitting on them or are saying that I
had gotten into some horrible accident.
That was another big one that I just said.
I don't know how many times I have to
tell you I lost my leg in a car accident.
What kind of Pete went? Oh my God, sir.
I'm so sorry to hear that. Well, are you,
this is like the third time.
I'm literally sitting here right now with
my stump elevated so I don't bleed out
because the sutures have come loose
again and here you are harassing.
This is what you do. And then they
would, you know, it was that thing. Um,
and I just ran out of ways
to have fun with them.
Uh,
and then I, I think I just
finally fucking paid him. Yeah,
I've done that a couple of times.
I had a fucking landlord that's stole
from my apartment managers stove,
my pubs on the road. And I came back and,
uh, it was on the road for three weeks.
I was on the road for so
long when I came back,
like most of the water had
evaporated out of the toilet
and they had this check the smoke alarm.
So legally they could go into my
apartment when I wasn't there without my
consent, because if there was a fire,
it could affect the other units.
That's what they said.
And uh,
all of a sudden I noticed
there was a camera missing.
They'd picked through my cds.
It was a hip hop fan. And, um,
so I went down and I talked to the guy
about it thinking that the manager was
going to be like,
oh my God started where we got to get
to the bottom of this age, who says,
I don't appreciate you coming
down to excuse you, accusing me.
And he started saying all this shit,
I have the power.
He kept saying I have the power. So it
was like, Oh yeah, you've got the power.
I buddy and I just stood outside the
office and anytime anybody new came,
I stood out to for two hours. I was
like, yeah, don't run from these paypal.
They uh, they stole from my apartment
and all that. That's like, dude,
I'm a comedian.
I can do this all day.
I will be down here
every single fucking day.
And it was bullshit because the next
day I went on the road and I just,
I just didn't have it in me and um,
I shouldn't get,
hey, hey, come on in here.
The lovely Nia, everybody,
can we hear
what's going on?
I was just talking to them
about collection agencies and all of
that type of stuff and all the crap I've
gone through. Um, I haven't had a lot of
that stuff, but you know, David's side.
Then I, the time that woman
called me up, I know it was bally,
total fitness and they, and I just started
hitting on her and she got mad at me,
said it was harassment.
I ended up,
I ended up getting her to hang up those
up on me. That was like the highlight.
What's a matter with you?
Oh you do. Um, all right,
well I gotta knock
another 35 minutes here.
I'm just going to read some advertising
and I got some great questions from
people this week.
All right.
You want to go get some floss instead
of just staring at me with the lick your
fingers in your mouth.
You know what sexy to me. You
know, it's sexy to me at my age.
Eight hours sleep that, that turns me
on. All right. All right. Listen to me.
I'd love to talk to you
while you pick your teeth.
I got to keep the momentum going here.
We have floss.
You can get your fingers between
your teeth. Get out of here.
There you go. Tenacity. Yeah.
Alright,
let me go.
He says they always want to go somewhere.
You know what I mean?
Only once a fucking house and then you
get a one and then only want to do is
leave. Yeah. Boy.
Fucking believable. I, when is the,
when is the guy me too thing going to
fucking happen. You know what I mean?
The reverse. Me Too. You know,
I take a lot of these feminists
a little more seriously.
If they ever bitched about something
that didn't affect their life,
you know what I mean? Yeah. I'll
see. Need to fix. Let me guess.
Something that affects you.
You're self centered. Fucking,
um, all right. Let's, uh,
let's move on here. Oh,
and then I'm going to tell you about this,
this music festival I went to yesterday.
Definitely feeling my
age at a music festival.
Just having to stand standing too long.
Throws out my back at this
point. I know. It's my posture.
I don't need you all Yunan
doctors out there. Just save me.
You're fucking remedies.
All right. All right. Oh,
here's something from a friend
of mine. Um, a buddy of mine,
he actually died a couple
of years ago and uh,
his widow is trying to finish
a project that he started,
which is a really great idea. It's called
the, uh, the untold legends of hip hop.
And my buddy Pete coming rest his soul.
He was out there interviewing all of
these legends from the early days of a rap
music. Curtis blow, Russell
Simmons spliff starved.
And I say that right. Um, and he,
they would do these two minute little
stories talking about the early days of
hip hop and then they were animating it
and I saw some of the clips in it looked
fucking incredible and they
want to finish this thing. Um,
so they have a startup.
If you're a fan of hip hop music,
animation and all that stuff,
just cool stuff.
You like to learn about music the way
I do. Uh, the website is halo boost,
h a l o B o s t.com.
And uh,
the project is the untold legends of hip
hop people go to halo boosts and click
on the featured project and then you
go to the untold legends of hip hop
campaign, need, donate a dollar, whatever
you can do to try to get this thing made.
It's a really, really
cool project. And, um,
from one of the great people that
I've met in this business. Um, I'll,
I'll definitely retweet the link and all
that type of stuff, so I appreciate it.
You know, if you're a, if you're into it,
I'm not, it's no pressure here. All right.
All right, here we go. Ah,
butcher box. Everybody, uh,
these guys, these guys, these
guys know what they're doing yet.
Put your box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
free range,
organic chicken
and heritage breed pork bread,
Brie Porchia.
The incredible quality of butcher box
meets starts with the commitment of
raising animals humanely before they
killed him and free of antibiotics and
hormones.
I've got to tell you something.
I cannot say enough about
their heritage breed pork.
You got to get it all right.
You've got to do it.
The skill it sear it on both sides.
[inaudible] finish to the other.
Come out a little fucking
garlic butter bath.
I don't give a fuck where your
wife wants to go the next day.
You're gonna have a smile on your face.
It is fucking delish.
Each box comes with at least
nine to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individual size meals.
You can choose from five different box
types. I swear to God this was around,
there'd be, you know, back in the day that
there would've been no Jeffrey Dahmer,
all beef beef and chicken, beef
and pork, mixed pork custom box.
I'm just saying cause there's so
much of it, you know, I'm sorry.
You know way I'd use that
circular reference and I
know they're going to give me
shit about it was I was
thinking 24 pounds of meat.
Oh 2011 pounds of meat. I was
just thinking like, you know,
you're double up the order.
You get one of those meat freezers
in your fucking garage, you know,
you know Lezama getting people so they
got all that meat you'd have, you know,
everybody else is starving to death and
you're just sitting there going like,
yeah, I don't know when helps coming.
And they're looking at you like,
well how come you're not getting
skinny like us? Right. They're like,
he's got food.
But by then that two week and you've
got all that fucking heritage breed pork
and you're all that protein, you
fucking knock their asses out. Right?
I Dunno. And then they just, whenever
you think of a giant meat freezer,
you just always think of a fee.
I don't know.
You just think of somebody
chopping up a body.
Custom box lets you choose your own cuts.
Antibiotic slash hormone,
hormone free butcher box believes in a
healthier food system where everyone has
access to meet the way nature intended.
Free of antibiotics and hormones
and humanely raised on open passion.
I guess it's fucking delicious.
Um,
butcher box carefully curates the
finest selection and cuts. Oh,
look at us that went over
there and makes it a breeze.
To customize your own delivery, build
your own box to exactly what you want,
a whatever you want and
what your family will love.
Choose your delivery
frequency with customization.
Customizable subscription recipes
are available on the butcher box.
Website and videos are available
to follow along on the butcher box,
youtube channel. Um, which is great.
And it says personal experience.
I told you, I already told you.
I already told you I love
the fucking portrait. Uh,
anyways, to receive free bacon
for life plus $10 off your order.
Go to butcher bought.
What? Free Bacon for life.
Go to butcher box.car.
They probably give you a thick slices
helping you can have a heart attack.
So they got to keep giving you fucking
bacon for the next five decades. Uh,
10% off your order. Go to
butcher box stocks. Calm.
Click on the big bacon banner
on the homepage and use burpee.
You are are at checkout. Go now.
Limited time offer. Holy Shit.
That's next level. Free Bacon for life.
Tell me that's not going to be a home run.
Um, me undies, everybody.
Oh,
Bodo though to beyond days me undies.
Free Bacon for your life to do to,
to me on days beyond these.
It's just for you and not your wife.
Tell that bitch together around
you're making some bacon.
Now leave me alone.
I wanted fair and fucking square.
We got to bake and fucking prenup and
my balls of feeling nice and soft in my
nice tight Greg Louganis
pair of underwear is um,
you definitely heard me
talk about me and he's, hey,
you guys have to be singing about it.
You know the fun comfy undies
that feel as good as they look to.
Those of you haven't tried them yet.
Listen Up.
There's a reason your balls are crying
because all the other balls are walking
around bragging about it.
You can get incredible underwear sent
to your door with me undies meaning no
more hunting around for perfect,
for a perfect pair at a crowded store
and eventually settling for good enough.
I guess these don't make
my balls to achieve me.
Undies are made with sustainably
sourced material from beechwood trees.
How they make their underwear on of trees.
I have no idea. They're naturally soft.
Fiber makes a fabric that won't Sag.
You know,
we and your balls hanging there like
the beginning of an action movie.
Sebesta Salone trying to reach down
and grab him or they don't write up,
you know, like in some claustrophobic
relationship where you're killing me.
My biological clock is ticking. He
twisted my nuts there. Trust me.
Once you put on a pair,
you'll get it.
Me undies is so sure you'll love the
first pair that if you're not happy,
well fuck, they'll do whatever
they can. Hey guys, don't get look,
don't get desperate here.
They can to get it right. Uh,
get you into the right pair. And if they
can't keep them and they'll refund you.
So it really is risk free to
tell your best underwear ever.
And if you're already part
of the and his family,
tell your friends about it to get
there in their referral program.
This is like Scientology,
but with fucking your balls.
They'll get a discount and you'll
get a store credit. It's a win win.
Still not sure it, well me undies
has a deal for my listeners.
First Time purchases get 15% off
their first pair of me undies and free
shipping. That's 50% off. Okay.
She didn't hear me two seconds ago,
plus free shipping and a guarantee
that you and your me undies,
we'll be happy to get there.
I can't see by balls in any
other underwear except me undies.
Get you right over to me and
he's dark a treat yourself. Paul.
Sing into each other, right?
Me and you and you in me.
No matter how we're in the SEC.
Willow,
we see each other's fucking purple
face. What color are you? Paul's.
I always picture they were purple.
I guess they're red, right? Um,
to get you 15% off your
first pair of shipping,
a 100% satisfaction guarantee,
go to me undies.com/ [inaudible] that's
[inaudible] dot com slash part I just
realize how stupid that fucking
song with me and you and you and me.
Um, oh my God, I've got
a lot of reads this week.
I got a lot of singing and do
here. Oh, dollar shave club, dude.
If you ever shower,
brush your teeth to try to make,
try to make your hair look presentable.
Here's some good news.
Dollar Shave Club has a lot of stuff to
help you on. Do you guys know much money?
I saved a year on shampoo
because I shaved my fucking head.
Dollar Shave Club. Yes. Yes. That Dallas,
that dollar shave club delivers
everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best. You name
it. Shampoo, conditioner, body wash,
toothpaste, Hair Gel. Even a wipe that
will leave your tush feeling tingling,
clean.
Uh,
you'll be a big fan of their amber and
lavender calming body cleanser cleanser.
After the first time you use it.
You know those one wipe Charlies are
basically the poor man's per day.
And having used a bad
day, it's, it's fuck mean.
The fact that we still use toilet
paper over here, it's, it's, you know,
do you know why those Frenchies I have
and all those menage a trois is over
there. It's because they're fucking
assholes are so God damn clean.
It's what it is. Good luck finding
a product like that. It is store.
All of dollar shave club products are
made with top shelf ingredients that won't
break your budget.
You'll feel the difference.
Plus shipping is included
with your membership and is
a great way to try a bunch
of dollar shave club's
products for just five bucks.
You can get their daily essential
starter set. It comes with body cleanser,
one wave GRE. They're amazing, but wipes.
They're world famous shave
butter and their best razor.
The six blade executive,
you know, shave a gorilla,
six blades.
Keep the blades coming for a few more
bucks a month and add in shampoo,
toothpaste or anything else you fucking
need. Speaking of your next month, uh,
for a limited time,
only use the code [inaudible] at checkout
to get $5 off your second month of the
club. That's Code burr@dollarshaveclub.com
to save $5 on your second month.
Join the club today. All right.
I said I got two more reads,
but I'm going to give you guys a break.
All right.
Yesterday I went to a music festival.
I went to go see the pretenders
when I was in England.
Um, the great Chrissy hine came
down with some of her friends,
some of the band members and
stuff that came down to my show.
That's the second time she's come to one
of my shows over there. So I was like,
next time you come to the u s I'm
going to your show, you got me going.
And she said, cool, guess what?
I'm going to be there a few days after
he come back. So I was like, all right,
done don Dale.
So I figure they're going to be playing
like some theater Assam shit out here.
You know, I'm an old band. I'll sit down
in his seat, get myself assessed Barilla.
That'd be once in a while,
stand up and wave my fist and feel
like I've as an audience member.
But now they were doing a music festival
and I get the email from our manager
and there's a map and it's
to the rose bowl. I'm like,
Holy Shit. Who the fuck is
on this bill? And it was,
it was Neil Young, Jack White,
the pretenders, the smiths,
and a bunch of other people
that I'm sure I missed.
And that will fucking amazing, right?
So I'm like, wow, this is going to be,
I never saw a concert at, uh, at the
fucking Rosebowl is going to be amazing.
So, you know, I walk in there, I
walked right where it's, you know,
the Rosebowl logo.
I'm having all of these flashbacks of how
many times have been they're hammered.
Going to the rose bowl game kind of
struck me as funny to be walking the golf
course. It's a big golf course
outside the stadium, by the way.
I'm finally doing it sober.
So I'm walking in there and the first
thing I tried to go into the main entrance
into the, uh, the Rose Bowl
stadium. They're like, Nah, Nah,
you got to go around and you got
to go around. And I'm like, well,
of course she got to go around.
They always make eco the longest fucking
possible way. Why do I got to go around?
Why the fuck do I got to do that?
You fucking assholes.
And then I go in there and then we
got to make a left turn and then a,
right now I'm going to cut across the
bridge, the stadiums right fucking there.
And I go to go across bitch gun.
Sorry sir. This is one way. It's a,
it's one way for walking.
Are you worried there's going to be a
head on collision when a fuck do I have to
gut guy and got to go up
dairy and I'm losing my shit.
And then I'm looking around,
there's all these tents and all this shit
and all of a sudden he finally fucking
dawns on me that the concert
is not in the Roseville.
It's all over this giant golf course.
So the whole time I'm
trying to go in the stadium,
there's nothing going on in the
stadium. Fucking moron. Right. And uh,
and also I'm trying to keep
my cool because somebody
told me the other day said
like, dude, you, you do
not handle stress well.
And that of course hurt my ego. I'm
like, what are you talking about?
I don't handle stress. Well,
I'm a stand up comedian.
I've performed at Madison Square Garden.
I dealt with doing five
minutes of stand up on,
on the Dave Letterman show when it was
like 30 below with the air conditioner.
Okay.
One of the most intimidating things ever.
And I was able to set aside that fucking
stress and get through it. And uh,
then the person's like, all
right, all right, Geez. You
know, just saying, you know,
and then I realized, it's like, you know,
thinking about it the next day actually
snapping again over something fucking
stupid. That of course, five
minutes later I figured out,
probably three minutes later I actually
realized that this person was right.
That I,
it's not,
I don't handle inconvenience.
Well, and then I turn it into like,
what's going on in Hawaii right now with
the lava pouring out and all his shit.
So
yeah.
I don't know. I've done this so many
times. The last couple of days, you know,
except for at the festival when they,
I was doing well with the stress until
they told me the bridge where people were
walking was one way.
Yeah.
You know, I just, all right.
I mean if I even taught,
say that one more time you guys, I'm
going to lose my shit again. So anyways,
I drove in traffic yesterday.
I was completely relaxed,
but I've done this a
million fucking times.
1 million times is somebody
says something to me about it.
It makes me want to change. And
then for two, three days I'm okay.
And then gradually I just go
back to the way I was, you know,
flipping the fuck out.
So I think I'm going to start talking
about it on the podcast the way I do with
my boozing,
cause I keeps my booze and,
and check to tell you guys if I'm
on the wagon, I'm off or whatever.
And then you guys give me shit,
a Billy booze bag,
a Billy fucking fat tits and all that
Shit. It makes me hard. Fuck these people.
I'm going back to crushing
waters. Um, so anyways, I'm just,
I finally,
I figured out that this festival is uh,
outside and now,
you know,
I don't know where the fuck I'm going
and the pretenders are going to be on.
They were on in the afternoon,
five 25. Right. Right.
At dusk or should have been
dusk. Different time of
year would have been dusk.
Right.
And um,
okay.
I was looking like, what, what the fuck
do I do here? I've got to get some booze.
Right. So, you know, they're doing
these little fucking, you know,
they're not pulling at home port.
So I got like two whiskeys and I'm walking
around, you know, my stupid Little Cup.
Right. And I see this fucking
guy even older than me.
He must've been like 63.
It's actually still in pretty good shape.
But he had the long gray hair. He had
his shirt off, you know, just that guy.
He's been going to concerts forever,
you know, and the pretenders startup.
And I'm trying to find
where the, uh, you know,
the best place where I could watch it.
And he starts doing like that, you know,
that like that,
that fucking hippie surfer,
spiritual white guy dancing.
It was a touch of Tai Chi in there.
You know,
he's still in that fucking dance
and you know,
it's the same dance he does to all music.
I don't even know what it is. And they
always have like this look on their face.
When you look in this smiling,
they always look at you like they have
life figured out. Like they know what,
what makes they like,
hey man, like you know,
they're going to say all this spiritual
bullshit to you that you could find on
the side of a fucking
Dixie Cup. You know? Um,
then whoever that guy is, I
want to thank you. I fuck it.
It was laughing my ass off.
Uh,
just a faggy had his shirt off. I
get to sit. He was still doing the,
I got him [inaudible] he was still doing
the pushups so he didn't have the man
boobs. But still, it's like, come
on man, these young people here,
if they don't want to see that,
cover yourself up.
This whole fucking pride in your
age and everything, you know,
or how you look is all well and
good, but you know, you know what?
It's kind of disappeared is common
fucking courtesy for your fellow man.
Good Lord. You know, I just, it just
blows my mind. It really doesn't. It does.
Doesn't cause you know what?
I think that guy was a baby boomer,
you know, and there's never, you know, you
know, right before the baby boomer, sorry,
gotta plug my headphones back in right
before the baby boomers was the greatest
generation. According to Tom Broker,
they're the greatest generation. Like,
I think the baby boomers
resilink like the most selfish,
like maybe because there's so many of
them that they had such an influence on
the culture and they think every fucking
thing that happened during that time
was just so God damn important.
That just, I dunno, I think,
and I think that there would just so up
their own ass about themselves that now
that they're old and all wrinkly,
they just can't, they can't,
they just can't let it go. Can't
let it go. You know? I mean,
I'm not gonna lie to you.
I'm fighting aging by trying to work out
and stay in shape and eat right and all
that type of stuff. But
yeah, I stayed covered up.
I have empathy for people in their 20s.
They, they, they don't want to see it.
So anyways,
um,
I go by the spiritual dancing guy and I
wore my way up as close to the stage as
I possibly can. And I have to tell
you something, man, have Chrissy Hine,
the paternity is fucking murdered.
She sounded like she once
again, two weeks in a row.
I've seen great concerts.
She sounded as great as the albums that I,
I grew up listening to.
And um,
the song she opened with was on her,
her new album.
It was just about being a loner and liking
not being in a relationship and shit.
And, uh, the lyrics are hilarious and I,
I'm almost a little ashamed at
like how much I relate to the song.
I told her afterwards, I was
like, I fucking love this.
Okay.
Um,
but they just fucking murder and
she's such a bad ass total rock star.
Like the real deal, paid her dues, all
that shit. You just see all of that.
When you watch her perform.
It was tremendous.
And she gets off stage and
then next up was Jack White,
Jack fucking white,
right?
I get to see him come out with this
new lineup, the new sound that he has,
he was fucking unbelievable day.
You know, there's another guy,
if you go see him,
it's like,
when have you ever seen that guy even
remotely take a show of like half a second
off during a show?
Forget about a show.
That guy never is the
intense of phoning it in.
Whenever I see that guy perform live,
I always get inspired as a comedian.
Like I could be working a little harder.
Okay,
I can be trying to give people
a better show here. So, um,
his said ended and um,
I walked over
to go see the smiths who I run my,
one of my brothers listen to them.
Everybody I knew listened to better
music than I listened to in the 80s.
I just was listening to like, I
mean, I listened to some good shit,
but I was listening to a lot of
fucking hair metal, you know,
which is why I missed out on Pantera and
fucking all those bands that came out.
Like I was, I was, I was too far
the other direction. Like, Hey,
every rose has its door, you
know? Then also I was like,
Pauly Paul Shad, right? I'm just like,
what the fuck is this? This is, you know,
I'm as cynical as the next guy, but
Jesus Christ, that's another thing.
I started listening to that Iowa album,
that slipknot shit and like,
okay.
I always liked the, uh, the heretic
thing. People equal shit. I was,
that was kind of funny.
Um,
but I never like,
I dunno,
it was just too much going on and now
I'm listening to a fucking 20 years after
it came out going like, this
fucking album is unbelievable. Um,
but I mean, have, you know, there's
only so much fucking music he can lead.
You're going to miss something, right?
I've got to forgive myself on some level.
So anyways, uh, I went over and I saw
the smiths and I remember that one,
that one song that crossed over that even
like a fucking mainstream Charlie like
me heard where it was a, that
stopped the meds. You know, rab, uh,
stop. It's up to your
future. Right. Anyways,
I watched those guys that band fucking
murdered and did the impossible.
I felt it had like 10,000 white people
all dancing for their entire fucking set.
It was ridiculous. Um, how hard they
killed and then they ended this, this set.
Yeah.
Such a cool way they had
the crowd do was sing along.
Okay.
As a band we started playing a little
more quiet, a little more quiet,
a little more quiet.
And,
and the lead singer was like roasting
people in the crowd go, great job.
Great job. You don't sound that good.
You feel like you got bronchitis
and everybody's laughing.
And then the band just sorta,
just gradually stopped playing
and the crowd one more time sang,
uh, or does it the chorus. And then
they said, thanks a lot. Good night.
It was so fucking cool. And, um,
and then Neil young starts playing.
Now you got to walk across
the golf course again.
And my back was fucking killing me and
I was jet lagged and all of that shit.
And I just, I hate to say this, I've
never seen Neil young and concert. I just,
I couldn't make it, you know,
and I had to get home, you know,
I got a kids getting up and
shit and it's just like,
I don't want to fucking see Neil young
standing outside with my backbone fucking
okay.
You know,
it's talking to me next to some fucking
60 year old guy doing his Tai Chi
fucking hey man, dance. I want
to see this guy in a theater.
So I, I stood there and I
watched him play one song.
Um, so I could say, or at least most
of the first sock, he didn't even sing.
It was just like him playing guitar and
Shit. I think his experience was like,
I got to get all those people that would
just over at the Smith's time to come
over. Sure. People's feet hurt
and their backs hurt. I mean,
he's probably doing me a favor,
but I just, you know, I dunno.
I just said to my friends, I was
like, guys, I gotta I gotta go home.
I can't and I ubered here and it's just
going to be a thousand fucking people to,
and I just know how I'm wired.
I have to find that one way bridge
that's going to allow me to get the fuck
outta here. And I actually left, um,
during one of my favorite singers of
all time during his fucking set. Um,
but anyways, it's a great show
and all that. If you're younger,
definitely check it out. If you're
older, definitely stretch, you know,
try to keep your shirt on. Um, I
saw these two people. Oh my God,
these two fucking Wales,
he's too fat people like one of those
fat couples and they were just asleep on
their picnic blanket.
Like both in like the spooning position,
but faced opposite.
It was like a fat ying Yang.
They would just lay in there. You
know what they look like, you know,
like at the zoo when they
tranquilize like, uh,
one of those big cats when those predators
and then it's just like, all right,
now that we knocked it out,
we need to bring a fucking machine
over here to pick this thing up.
It weighs like 600 fucking pounds.
Um,
and I dunno, they were,
they were oddly adorable.
Like I was like, it must be
fun. You know what I mean?
Like you like those commercials
come out and you see like
Domino's or like Papa Ginos we'll
have like a fucking some deal,
like get two pizzas for seven
bucks and if you get that,
we'll throw in the fucking chocolate chip
cookie pie with the whipped cream and
ice cream.
Right.
And I always make fun of that Shit and I
always make fun of it because this is a
big part of me that just wants to
order that and take the ride, you know,
have the salt fucking take me down to
the ground. Right. And that the is,
I think I'm going to fucking, you know,
sink into the rug like that. Dude.
And trade spotting.
Then he started eating the fucking
cookie pie and you start coming back like
Hulk Hogan.
You know when he,
when they went to drop his hand that last
time and it didn't go down and all of
a sudden you eat the cookie thing
and you start shaking your Yag,
he starts strutting around.
Right. But you don't,
you don't. And they get,
they get to live that life.
They get to sit there and like I bet
they got one of those, you know those,
you know those big fucking couches that
on either side there's the recliner but
it's still like a sofa. I bet
they got one of those, right.
And then in the middle the thing comes
down. Remember that it was basically,
it was a fat fuck couch.
These to make this thing before,
like the biggest loser
and everything came out.
It was like catering for people
who were fat fucks or were,
their goal in life was to become a fat
fuck because on either side of this big
couch like cute, you could pull a
lever and you've feet could go up.
And then in the middle
this thing would come down.
There's a place for your drinks and like
a fucking pizza and he just sit there
with you, with the girlfriend, you know,
watching the TV you feed up,
get the AC cranked can just destroy,
like just destroying the fucking
planet and your absolute like Utopia.
I mean,
I don't know if you guys believe in an
afterlife and which I've thought about a
lot when Vinnie past,
you know,
there was all that talk
about now he's reunited,
reunited with his brother and I
was definitely thinking, you know,
I really hope that that
happens, you know? Um,
so let's say that it does okay.
If you're a fat couple and you have one
of those couches and you'll watch it,
one of your favorite shows on Netflix
or Hulu, whatever the fuck you do,
and you're sitting there with your feet
reclined eating a pizza and he got that
cookie fucking pizza thing coming next,
drinking your favorite drink.
It's just like,
what could the afterlife offer you that's
going to be any better than that if
you truly love one another, you know,
when you got the AC going, you know,
you get your toes out. I mean, I dunno,
I think I'm selling a lifestyle right now
here. I think I'm selling some couches.
Um, anyways, but I had a great
time and uh, if you get a chance,
you know,
like I said,
definitely check out that festival and I
feel really bad that I had to leave to,
I left during Neil Young. The
fuck is wrong with me. I have to,
I have to fix that in the future
by seeing him. But like, you know,
I want to see that guy.
Like,
did you have a scene when he
did that film was at the Ryman.
That's what you want to see fucking
deal young. Yeah. You see him at this,
I'm not trying to not sell this festival,
but I'm just saying, look, I'm old.
I need a chair. Okay.
There I said it all right.
I used to be able to stand.
Evidently I can't any longer.
I was able to kind of work, but
work my way out of it. I know it's,
it's my fucking posture.
Posture stinks, you know,
it's all those years from fucking
hating yourself, you know,
fucking slinking down.
I'm an albino stop looking at me.
Alright.
Indochino indocin or talk about how
every man looks better in a suit.
Well, you know, when I'm
out there trolling for cock,
you know, it's just like,
I hate to be picky,
but guys,
the sweatpants and the lazy look
isn't doing it for me. All right?
If I'm going to give it up,
I want a nice meal. Okay.
So when a guy in a suit comes along,
Indochino is the world's largest made to
measure men's wear company and has been
featured in many publications
including Gq, Forbes,
and fast company.
Okay.
Fast company sounds like a bad sitcom.
They are old,
but they're still fucking snappy.
Uh,
they make suits and shirts made your
exact measurements for a great fit.
Guys. Love the whole wide selection of
high quality fabrics and the option to
personalize all details including your
lapel lining and monogram. All. That's,
that's, that was, that was the side
of a bad ass dude. When I was a kid.
If you had your initials on your sleeve
of your suit, you know, had a company car,
you know, came home, your wife looked at
the ground, she knew who was running shit.
I mean that, that was success. Here's
how it looks, how it works. Sorry.
Visit a show room or shop
online@indochino.com pick your fabric.
Choose your customizations,
submit your measurements.
Wait for your cus custom suit
to arrive at just a few weeks.
This week my listeners can get any
Primo indochine oh suit for just $379.
That's indochino.com I,
N, D. O. C. H. I. N. O.
It's like China, but with an l and it's
like India with an l, right? No, it isn't.
It's like Indonesia,
but you don't say the needs your part
and then it's like China will we know.
MMM.
When entering [inaudible] at checkout,
that's 50% off the regular price
for a made to measure premium suit.
How many times they can
say made to measure.
MMM,
isn't it made to measurement?
Okay.
Plus shipping is free.
That's indochino.com Promo
Code Bar, and any print,
eh, for any premium suit for
just 379 bucks and free shipping.
Incredible deal for a suit that will fit
you better than anything off the rack
ever could,
you know,
and it gives you incentive to
stay in shape once you submit it.
It's like I can't get fatter.
I gotta maintain stamps.com everybody,
the u s postal service is an
important tool for any business.
stamps.com is the easiest way to access
all the amazing services of the post
office.
stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for any letters or
packages at your convenience. 24,
seven print postage for any male,
uh,
class right from your own computer.
The exact amount of postage every time.
Never underpay or overpay again.
I'm stamps.com saves you time and money.
There you go.
Um,
which you can use to grow your business.
Buy and print official US postage for any
letter, any package, any class of mail.
Using your own computer and printer.
They'll send you a digital scale that
automatically calculates exact postage
stamps.com we'll even help you decide the
best class of mail based on your needs.
No need to lease the lease.
An expensive postage meter and there
are no long term commitments are use
stamps.com I've gotta
use them this weekend.
Hopefully if my posters get
back from Ireland to pluck it,
send these things to Minneapolis
and Detroit. My exclusive.
Okay.
Tour posters, 50 for
my age, not my effort.
All right,
good to give you 100% effort at 50 years
of age and you can only get them if you
go out to the show cause I'm not shipping
them out. Again, dealing with, hey man,
like I fucking Yag thinking
ain't can't find it right now.
You too can enjoy the stamps.com servers
with a special order that includes a
four week trial plus postage and a digital
scale. Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburdenthatstamps.com
enter
burr.
All right. We got some great emails
this week. The first one, Vinnie, Paul.
Hey Bill.
By now,
I'm sure that you're heard that Vinnie
Paul passed away last Friday. Uh,
much like you talked about
Malcolm Young after his death.
I feel like Vinny was another one
who just lived an amazing life.
One of the great drummers to ever get
behind the kid. I got to tell you,
like all everything that I saw on Twitter
from all these big time rockstars over
and over and over again, other than
stating the obvious what a monster,
amazing drummer he was.
Everybody's just talked about what a,
what a nice guy he was. Um, anyways,
he said I was too young when Panthera
was leaving their mark on the metal scene
through the 90s. So I never got to see
Pantera played live before they disbanded.
However, I did get to see Vinny play
with hell yeah, back in the day, uh,
back in 2016 at a Rockfield
festival in Jacksonville, Florida.
He was quite simply incredible. Oh, this
is a cool story. I read this before, um,
the podcast, something I never
do, but I saw it said, Vinnie.
Paul said I wanted to read it.
I said,
I remember being pretty close to the front
of the stage and Vinnie was the first
band member to come out
before the show started.
When he stood up behind the drum kit,
he had this smile on his face.
Like he was just really happy to be there.
He twirled his drum
stick at the whole crowd.
A crowd saluted by putting his fist
in the air and then the madness begin.
But for most of the show,
I couldn't take my eyes off of him because
of how good he was. Oh, that's awesome.
And even though he was that good,
the biggest memory I have of him was
that he was smiling the whole show.
Like he just loved playing in c,
seeing people enjoy themselves as much
as he was. He will be missed by more.
You will be missed by more than we know.
I don't know if that sentence
makes sense. Um, if you remember,
please cranked a Panthera song up as
loud as she can. Today. I'm sure Vinnie,
we'll hear it. Best
switches, Eh, um, a I um,
best which is incompetent. It said, um,
the hours already listened to the fucking
shit every day anyways. You know what,
you know, it's a great album. Great
live album. Is there 101 proof?
I'm such a bad ass Alba and my,
one of my favorite things is when they
play unbroken and fill as Phil's doing
the intro video. Vinnie's already counting
in the song. Just how tight they were.
Always our world shore. We Bernard's
called our broker. No Maverick of course.
Jab Brown al Bag.
Alright, coco the gorilla.
Oh,
I saw this too at fucking
sweetheart of a gorilla.
Okay.
Um, did I did the bit
above. Hey Bill, I saw you.
You live last year and I love you special.
We talk about teaching gorillas,
sign language.
I was watching clips of cocoa interacting
with people like with flee from the
Chili peppers and Robin Williams.
I watched those.
I was still nervous and I just saw a flea
laying down and there's like a fucking
gorilla right next to them. Um, I dunno,
I get you're shooting the shit with
it. You can kind of, I dunno. Um, um,
it made me nervous,
you know,
I wonder if it made me nervous just
because I'm such a big fan of flee and I
didn't want to see anything happen to him.
Like it was a bass player from a band I
didn't give a shit about. And they go,
look at this guy, this could get
interesting. Um, anyways, it was,
it was charming as hell. I was wondering
if you ever sat down with cocoa,
if ever given a chance. Well, no, not
after the bid. I did. They probably,
this guy's a fucking asshole.
Uh,
you could have asked him why the chicken
cross the road and wait for a chuckle
or try to explain humor to him.
MMM.
Five. Or sat down with that gorilla
I, and that thing, actually,
if that wasn't a party trick, if it
actually knew how to do sign language,
I imagine it would sign to me.
You seem nervous.
Yeah.
At our and back. Yeah. Well,
you're a fucking gorilla.
Um, anyways, kid show recommendation.
Um, hey there, Billy
Barnicle balls. I want to,
I want, if you want a show to watch
with your girlfriend, checkout.
Okay.
I thought it said octo nuts
like something with eight balls.
Octonauts is it an octopus in outer space?
I watched it with my girls and kids and
I actually learned some stuff. All right,
well that was about as vague as the,
uh,
what was it that was that movie way back
in the game, the silent game or the,
okay.
There's something game or
the something or other.
David spade had that joke.
I'm going to tell the,
so I'm going to tell you guys the
secret of the crying game and he goes
overrated.
Okay.
All right. Hair, transplant, depression.
Oh No. Hey old freckled Dick.
I'm a 21 year old man. I recently
got a hair transplant surgery. Well,
you must be a hairy motherfucker,
man. You went bald that are soon. Um,
the surgery went great.
Good, good for you.
But I now hate that I have a
huge scar in the back of my head.
I don't they do it now where
they just vacuum the shit out.
So you don't have to have that smile
on the back of your head. You Go.
So every time I cut my hair, you can
see it. Could you give me some advice?
So what I should do?
Well yeah,
don't cut your hair so fucking short
now that you got of back on top of your
head. Grow your hair out. You'll
be fine. That was an easy one.
What are you doing? You got hair plugs
yet? I'm hacked the back of your head.
Then you got fucking hair plugs and now
you're shaving your head down to the
point where you can fucking see it
anyways. What was the point? Um,
I dunno. I would just, I guess I would
just grow my hair out a little bit.
I don't think it has to be
that long to cover the scar.
As long as it's long enough
that you can't see your scalp,
I think he should be all
right. Right. Anyways,
pit bull problems.
Dear [inaudible].
Oh Billy. Easy shave butter. Oh,
fussy Ellie's face right now.
That's easy for Seeley's. Easy.
I Dunno, I have no idea. I suck at
that shit. As he former pit bull owner,
I'd like to ask your advice on a problem
I'm having. My wife comes home from,
my wife comes from a large family and
they get together at her parents every
month for Sunday dinner and family
hang out. It's the last two times.
My brother in law has brought,
his recently is recently adopted pit bull.
It's a rescue dog and he doesn't take,
it was abused or used to fight
because it's so good with kids.
According to him it's a large family.
So there,
there are about 50 kids ages three to
11 running around and my four year old
daughters, one of them, she loves
dogs and likes this one in particular,
but both times he's brought my dog.
My daughter has come running to me in
tears because it got over excited and
jumped onto her too rough.
Well that's the thing about pities man.
They just a big fucking
awesome ball of muscle.
And when I used to wrestle with my dog,
I used to have to lay my
neck over the top of neck.
He had to get inside because she was
lightening quick and she would turn around
and her head was like a wrecking ball.
God,
I miss that fucking dog. I still get to
see her every couple of months. But I,
I really miss that. Um, anyways, he goes,
I don't hate dogs, but I don't love them
either and I don't trust pitbulls. Well,
you have to validate all of
that. Okay. To be quite honest,
I'm kind of afraid of them.
I never forget myself as
something happened to my daughter.
If I say something to my inlaws,
I looked like a kill joy asshole.
But I'm too stressed out to enjoy the
family gathering because I'm hovering over
a constantly.
So my wife's response has been to treat
me like I'm overreacting and dismiss my
concerns.
It's bothering me so much.
I've considered just keeping
my daughter home next time.
But am I making too big a deal about this?
I think it's a recipe for disaster.
I don't feel like it's my place to tell
my brother in law to keep it at home and
my wife's not supporting me.
Please tell him.
Please let me know if you have any ideas.
Uh,
may I see a Vod Vod to fair for two.
Thank you.
Thank you. And I imagine
that's saying go fuck yourself.
Um,
I know ed and go to is you fit all right.
Anyways. Um, I would say this dude,
you have to like,
if that's what you're feeling,
you don't have to tell anybody,
leave a dog home and you just have to
communicate this to people. All right?
Say you don't hate dogs,
you don't love him either and you don't,
I don't trust pit bulls.
Okay.
And just tell them that rather than be
like he did fucking lunatic. Good. No,
just tell them that.
All right.
And I would sit down with
your wife and say that,
you know,
I don't feel like you're
hearing me all right.
She's my daughter and I'm concerned
and I have to be honest, you know,
if you had these concerns,
I would listen to them and you're not
validating what I'm feeling and it's
really bothering me and I can't
enjoy when I go over there.
I don't want to be this kill joy,
but I'm hovering over our kid and I just,
you know, it's bothering me.
You married me, you love me,
I'm telling you something's bothering me.
We need to talk.
If I say you can't go
there because I'd be,
and you fucking talk to me about this,
that's what I would do.
Keep it in the register.
I was just in all right.
And don't stop having the conversation
until there's a solution that you're
satisfied with. It should
daughter. Okay. And uh,
you know, dogs are abused. All right?
And if a dog snaps, you know,
it's a bad thing around a kid.
And then when you have a pit bull, the
thing about a pit bull is its capability.
You know what I mean?
Some dogs,
they like a little water pistol and other
dogs or like a fucking bazooka at that
dog is a bazooka.
So not saying the breed is bad,
I'm just saying if somebody fuck
that dog up and it does snap,
the results are,
you know,
going to be really bad. So, and you have
to address that. That's being a real,
being a responsible parent and these
people need to listen to you and a,
you need to speak up. You gotta stand
up for yourself there, buddy. Boy,
that's my advice. All
right, good luck. Okay.
Lay De lady manager crossing the line.
Dear bill or William below will you
call yourself but a little below wall.
I'm a 23 or 23 year old lady who just
started working in an office for,
I love when women write in. It's always
guys, God bless you for writing it.
Who just started working in an office
for a big company. It's a boring job,
but while I figure out what to do with
my life after graduating, it's all right.
Well there you go. That's not bad. He's
23. He gets your whole life ahead of you.
Uh, I got promoted with the recommendation
from my former manager at this 40
something year old woman who
I thought was quite nice. Uh,
now she's not my manager anymore,
although she's still senior to me.
She has been a little inappropriate
with me after an office Christmas party.
Me and my colleagues went to a club.
Uh,
I came out of the club
bathrooms and she was waiting.
She didn't even come with
us. Well, that's weird.
She waved me over to sit next to her
and asked me if I was gay. I said, no,
I'm not. And she went fine and it didn't
speak to me for the rest of the night.
All right, well she needs a better
opening line that she's a little blunt.
You know, she's in business. She
got right down to brass tacks. Uh,
she said I was a bit uncomfortable with
the question because what business is it
of hers.
Okay.
Oh, I thought she was gay. She
wanted to hook up with you.
Yeah,
because what business is it of her?
So I told one of my work
pals what had happened. Uh,
they had been at the company longer than
me went, wow, you're her new one then.
Oh boy.
Oh Gee.
I asked them what they meant.
And a guy said, well, I
mean, look at her right now.
She's filming you and
she, Sarah enough. What?
And sure enough she was. She
was, when I turned around,
she hid her phone as I was a little
bit too drunk and under the influence.
I was already paranoid, so I decided
to leave because I felt so gross.
Since then,
she's pulled me aside to say that
I looked delicious and scrumptious.
Oh, what a crape. Whenever she
sees me at the end of the day,
she taps her cheek and demands that kiss.
Okay.
Oh yeah. What the fuck is this
part? She Ain't, oh, that's,
that's like a gross relative.
She asked a girl who works for me to take
pictures of me and to send it to her.
When we're at a pub.
I consider myself an assertive girl,
but there's something about
how public about her actions,
which makes me so timid,
so I go along with it. No,
I'll do that.
You think you would think that
because she's not my manager anymore.
Now that I've been promoted,
it wouldn't be a problem,
but it is because my new
manager is their best friend.
I don't want to cause a riff in this new
job, but it's really stressing me out.
Am I within my rights to tell her to stop?
Absolutely. You are. I do. I tell it.
Is that no,
I don't want to kiss her on her cheek
every time I see you without looking like
a bitch.
Listen,
the way you're looking
at this is fucking crazy.
Yeah.
You're, you're sitting here looking at
like how like your being an asshole.
You're not,
this person is completely out of line.
She said a few of my friends thinks
it's a funny situation, but I don't,
and if you don't then it isn't.
You've got to validate that if this
was a male manager, he'd be reported.
I your stuff so much and I
wish I could come back to,
you'd come back to Glasgow someday
from a fellow fellow pasty redhead.
Um, all right. Dev
Fellow fucking pasty. Um,
okay.
This is what you gotta do. She
asked for a kiss. You tell her no.
Okay.
And I just stare at, I mean, listen,
you have all the fucking power in the
world or if you just want to go to the
manager and say,
listen,
I don't want to cause some me
to scandal or any of that shit.
Can You keep this weird old fucking
bag away from me and tell her to be
professional? I mean, that's
the proper way to do it.
Those are the proper channels,
but I have to
do it that way. Do it that way. Okay.
Do it that way. And, and, and
document that this has been happening.
You have all these witnesses about them
filming her and all of this type of shit.
If they ever tried to fire you, I
mean, you don't have a problem at this.
This kind of thing needs to stop and uh,
you know,
in a perfect world you'd go to her
because I don't like that whole telling on
her thing. But that's how the
business world works. Um, you know,
in a perfect world when she fucking goes,
like pointed to were cheeky.
That's right where you should punch her
fucking blast or right
in the fucking face.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean if you were ever at a
bar again and she's doing that Shit,
I would fucking dump a drink
right over her fucking head.
Like that's just creepy
behavior. I would just, MMM,
okay.
You got to stop this Timothy. Cause if
you're timid someone like that, it's,
it's gonna. It's like a magnet.
They're going to go right towards you.
You got to step up to her and tell
her what a fucking creep she is.
And if I catch you take
a video of our, our, uh,
pictures of me or any of this
other fucking creepy sexual
shit that you're doing,
I'm going to report you.
Okay.
And you think you're going to get
together with your fucking manager friend.
Okay. All I gotta do is go on social media
and you're fucking world is over with.
The fuck is my phone.
What the fuck is mine anyways, but
don't do that. That's all anger. Listen,
but you know,
you are,
you seem like a really like overly
nice people pleasing person at 23,
which I was where you're like, is
it me? That the way I'm dressing,
that's attracting this, it's
not you, it's that person. Okay?
So whatever the fuck I said
before I got upset, uh,
just go, listen, I got an
issue and don't be icing.
I didn't want to come as a family.
They go in there fucking flat footed
and look right at that person and say,
listen,
I got an issue with her.
She's coming at me in weird sexual ways
and I'm getting sick of it and I'm sick
of it. I want to come here and go to work
and do a great job. I don't need, okay.
I would like to file an official
report on her harassing me.
Okay?
Okay. And that's the deal. And I
want it to stop. It stops right now.
Are we clear?
That's it.
Okay.
That's it. There's no, don't go
in there fucking hat in hand.
You don't have to be a content.
Just go in and just say, look,
this is happening and it
needs to stop immediately.
Okay. Well, I mean,
what if she just slammed?
She's your kitchen. I mean,
what the fuck's he going to say? You can't
say that it's over. Right. All right.
Good luck to you.
Okay.
Stay out of the sun and the rest of you
where go fuck yourselves and I'll check
in on you on Thursday
rested piece for any Paul.