Are you filming? You just
taking a picture? What are
we doing? Why are you doing?
Oh, picture. Okay. I always get paranoid.
All right. We're going. All right. Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast from Monday,
December 11th, 2017
what's going on? How I,
yeah. Um, it's the
Christmas season. Everybody.
Merry Christmas to everybody. Um, I know
you're not supposed to say that any more.
I don't know why somebody
said Happy Hanukkah to me. I
wouldn't be like, you know,
go fuck yourself. I'm Christian. I'm not
even Christian. I don't go to church.
I just like say merry
Christmas. [inaudible] he puts
a little song in my heart,
but in this gift giving time of the year,
the gift that we have today is a,
as very special guests came
in all the way from New York,
the wonderfully talented with a brand
new special called naive innocence that
you can get on iTunes. Google
play, Amazon. You Porn,
right? You Porn? No. No. Okay.
Please welcome Harris Stanton.
Everybody to the program. Hey, what's up?
Yeah, they should have have laws there,
but we don't have the sound effects.
I have porn in minds mine album.
Do you know what I'm trying to go? Uh,
I'm trying to go to the month of December.
No porn. No boots. Why no nothing.
Because I think it fucks you up.
It does. It does. I, if I didn't have to,
if I didn't get up so late
and had to be here at one,
I would have jerked up before I came here.
But I realized I didn't have enough time
to get into it in the way I want it to.
Jesus, what are you fucking
become a character or something?
I'll watch that flare documentary was
talking about and the guy asked him,
how many times a day do you jerk
off? He goes twice. I was like,
that's about what I do.
Rick Flair said that? Yeah.
You saw the documentary you told?
I don't remember that part. Yeah,
he's went to a sports
psychologist and the guy was like,
so how many times a day you drink off?
He goes twice a, how much do you drink?
He goes, I have 10 beers and and five of
Buckos. That part I remembered it. Yeah.
Well he said that before. He said to a
jerking off stuff before that. Oh okay.
He goes everyday everyday. How long you
been doing that? Oh it was nice. Me Too.
I started in 72 boom.
Going back about 20 years.
That's impossible. He said
it's been a week with me. Yeah.
I liked when they said they
were like your first wife,
how long you faithful to her and
he was like, Eh, about a day.
And they go, really? Cause I
couldn't do it. Couldn't do it.
I came home and he goes, I was
bored. I just want like to see a guy.
It was great to actually just say how
fucking board he is being married.
Cause you know anytime you have a thought
of just any sort of like resentment of
your situation that you fucking created.
Right, exactly. I'd have to say I do.
You didn't have to do all that,
but you created it. You have that,
that feeling of like, fuck I want to
do this. You have like that guilt.
I loved his complete lack of guilt or
honesty. Honesty. Yeah. Honesty. Well,
why don't, why don't you tell the girls,
why do you say scream at your hotel? Eh,
no. Why don't you wear
your ring and uh, you know,
no one ever comes to the old tale.
Hey, y'all come to the hotel.
I like that one when he was in the middle
of nowhere and there was no party when
he went back to the hotel he created
when he just created one spot,
like a hundred kamikaze. He's dancing
on the bar. It's just like, whew. Yeah.
Told you. Just blew out my fucking
years. Jesus. Let me turn this down here.
I'm speaking of woe flare impression.
Yeah, man, you got to go. There you go.
Speaking of honesty, tell me
about Shira. You're special.
And I also like how you're doing it.
Like you're a,
you basically went where all
the specials end up anyways.
And so he just bypassed all the networks.
It's just like someone's going to
steal this and rip it in any ways.
So whatever the kids say. Um, what
did you just shot it yourself? No,
it's a bill for the fifth time was the
album, what is it? Oh, it's an album.
Oh, it's a CD. Yeah. Well it's not
a CD. It's just digital I guess.
And I have drop cars. Did I sell it after
my shows and stuff? Oh, all right. Yeah.
Sorry man. I don't do a lot of
interviews and I'm not a good listener.
There we go, Bill, for the last
time. I'm here about a benefit
when just special come out.
I just assume it's a comedian.
It's gotta be a special film.
Good at Gotham comedy club.
Uh, Memorial Day weekend.
Well, how do you film
an album? Well, right.
I recorded it at Gotham comedy
club one more day weekend, and I'm,
it's on all the little media platforms.
All right.
45 minute album. I have to ask
you the white guy question here.
You're wearing a Phillies hat. All right.
Now I've learned this with black people.
That doesn't mean you're a fan.
Do you have on Maroon sneakers or
do you really like the Phillies?
I just liked the hat. Oh, he
just liked the hat. I Buy,
I'm a Toronto Blue Jays Fan.
You might see me wearing a few
different Toronto Blue Jays ads.
And you have a baseball background,
correct? Yes. Chicago cubs. That's right.
You were right fielder,
I believe in the 56 round,
which they don't have that round anymore.
You would draft in the 56 round in the
scouting report on you as you could go
deep, but you couldn't hit a curve ball.
Yes. So what did you do to try to work on,
other than just guessing,
what did you do when you stepped
up to plate to try to get,
because there's no fucking
way I could ever hit a curb.
I was always hunting a fastball,
which is probably not a great,
well that's what a lot of hitters
do equal to adjust. But I just,
I think it was mental.
I though, wow, I wish,
I wish I knew about sports
psychology when I was playing.
I would have went to one because it
was totally mental. You had a mental,
like Charles Barkley's golf swing where
you guys to stop and then like Jon
Lester who can't throw to first base,
but he could throw a pinpoint fastball
and inside corner to a hitter,
but he can't throw it to first
base with those somebody up. Yeah.
He will not throw. It can throw.
You ever say, I'll just take, take,
take fucking throw.
Like,
like I dunno what like a God damn gorilla
on the lounge and the second they got
to throw it, they throw like
a little girl like, oh right.
Are you all know if you remember
chuck Knoblauch he played for,
he was a gold glove second basement.
All of a sudden he couldn't catch
anything and we couldn't throw,
you couldn't throw. What's
the yeah, he threw it.
He threw it was like hitting people fifth
row. Yeah. Steve Sax was the first guy.
Was that the guy? Yeah, the Yips.
Yeah. It's what they call it mental.
Because you was doing
it your whole life until now.
So did you ever hit the curve ball
hit a few curve balls. Bad ones.
The ones that don't break that
much. Oh, okay. But a good one.
And too many people get a good one anyway.
You're not going to hit if it,
Clayton Kershaw puts a good one on that.
You're not touching it. What's, uh,
anybody you ever go up against made it in
the big leagues? Yeah. Lando Hudson. Um,
he used to, he used the only show against
him. Well, he didn't, he didn't? No,
he didn't pitch. He was a player.
Oh, okay. Yeah, he was playing night.
Jacob Shumake uh, he got drafted first
round by the Toronto by Atlanta Braves.
And um, he didn't make it, he
got to $500,000 signing bonus.
And um, so you did all that Bull Durham
Shit riding around in buses and all that?
No, I didn't make it that far. I
released extreme training. Wait,
so when you get drafted by the cubs,
they saw you at high school. Like, wait,
what did he saw me in high school?
And then they, uh, they actually can,
scouts can actually get help.
You get into schools,
they call other schools and go, we
liked this guy. Um, matter of fact,
I got recruited by NC state from a scout.
They call schools and they, hey, get
this guy, we're going to look at them.
And then you go to the school
and then after your first season,
they either pick you up or they,
cause I was a drafting follows.
It's just nonstop pressure.
Yes. It's every time.
So then it's already bad enough if you're
in your head, if you're in a slump. Yes.
Now it's just like, fuck, I'm not
going to get picked up next year.
My dream is going to die.
So all of these other kids
that are walking around
going to keg parties, going,
mom, send more money and you're, and
you're literally going, my dreams.
Fucking dying. Right, right,
exactly. It, most people don't.
Most people that we don't know,
baseball is extremely
competitive and hard to play.
That's why there's a minor leagues.
There's no minor leagues for,
but it is a little bit for football now,
but that's not my,
at least with basketball and football,
he would just go right to the pros.
But baseball, you need constant
work from rookie ball or way to AAA.
Rookie ball is not even able yet.
Is that because it's the games that hard?
It's really that hard yet.
You mean you haven't tried?
You ever seen a 97 mile an
hour fast ball coming at you?
I like those people that go down to the
batting cages and they just sat it on 90
and they know what the pitches and they
keep going. Dude, I was hitting it.
Just catching up with this. It's
like, okay, yeah. All right.
Now let's actually put a brain behind
that fucking machine that has two other
pitches. Exams. There's a
million people watching.
A fastball was actually easy to hit.
It's the other stuff. Slider, curve ball.
You don't know what's coming. Sometime
it's if the you, he's what is what?
What exactly is a slider?
It's a [inaudible].
It's a Baltic slides to the left or
slides to the right. That's it and yeah,
that's not a curve ball. Curve ball drops
off the curve ball drops off the table.
Yeah. That's a slider.
They call it 12 to six,
where it really drops from 12 to six.
A bad Kershaw has a 12 to six.
Some people just have a little loop,
but a slider is a,
an a cutter is a fast ball that at the
last minute darks to the left at which
goes into your, uh, the handle
part and you break your back.
Like Marianna had greatest
cutter and it was just like,
can't they just guess and just going,
I know he's coming with the
cutter and just gasp because even
just little left
out of the way.
I met a guy one time who you
got split second too to play
giants,
any own fucking Tim Wakefield who was
a knuckleball pitcher and he goes,
I, this is a visual here. But
basically he go like, well,
basically his pitch did this and he
would make all these crazy were with his
hand and then go either
went here or there,
your knuckle ball is crazy.
He would just guess he would go hide,
I'm going to just swing here on this
one or I'm going to swing there.
And I'm ignoring all of this
bullshit between me and him.
And he actually was successful doing that.
Yeah, I remember the Yankees won years,
we're just looking at tape
against Wakefield and they
realized that most of his
knuckle balls were balls. So they got
well just don't fucking swing at it.
And then he started getting
behind in the count.
I think that's when he had to like every
once in a while throw like his idea of
like a fast ball.
Right.
But I always felt if I was
going to get to the big leagues,
like that's the way to, you know, if you
could somehow develop a knuckle ball,
cause then you're not
going to blow out your arm.
You can throw like 26 pitches like, you
know, crazy like Johnson 60 19 hundreds.
Yeah. What do you think? I know we're
not, I love sports. Who gives a fuck?
We know you're funny. Let's just, let's
talk sports here. What if, what if, uh,
what do you, how do you look at
those early 19 hundreds you know,
specials on that specialists, the
fucking records that people and baseball.
Yeah. Like when somebody, you know,
pitch 93 innings in two days,
that'll never be broken.
The Home Depot League is what I call it.
Well,
today's date is, uh, baseball
is different because, uh, it's,
the training is the proper preparation.
Those guys, they just, they just,
they just played like now did coddle
the, uh, the players, the pitchers,
like they only go six innings now.
Really good. They're like veal. Yeah.
Like back in the day they planned
to go nine and right now he'd go,
you go six in some five. I don't, that
means your bullpen has to be very good.
You know, if you don't have
a great bullpen. I remember
her talk over which, uh,
which was, which is a blast for
me and I hope they never do it.
That just tried to, okay, you go
three and as you go through, no,
you let Clayton Kershaw our goal,
as long as he can go.
And then you bring in the bullpen,
you don't let them go three and then
let your other guy go three, I guess.
What do you coach any baseball when
you're not doing stand up? No, no,
I'm going to put my son in the league.
Um, probably next summer. That's good.
You're going to keep him out of
football. Lacey, she didn't pick soccer.
I mean I was, soccer is gradually taking
over. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Sorry. No,
you can't do, cause he
said, you know what?
She was basically saying the Joe Jackson,
him in baseball.
You're saying you're saying I
want my son to be a flopper.
That's basically I want it.
I think you have to,
you got to take like a drama class before
you play soccer or whatever the fuck
they call it. Overseas
football. My favorite one ever
is, you know, people say,
you know, what do you call it football?
Talking about American football.
There's somebody, I forget what
comedian said. This is like, well,
why do you call it football? Why
don't you call it feet ball, right.
Using both feet. Right.
You want to be a clever
because you're clever joke
right back at Ya. Right, right.
I actually would rather watch women's
soccer than men's soccer with just because
they just play,
they don't do all that fucking
flopping around and it's embarrassing.
I would literally, if that was my
son, I would walk out of the stadium.
I would stand up all dramatic,
like Glenn close in the natural.
I'd have myself backlit.
And so he saw me up in the stands and
he'd be all excited that he drew a fucking
yellow card and I would turn
my back on him. That'd be it.
That'd be the modern day version of
that story where the guy bricked up the,
the room that the kid
was in. Oh yeah, that,
no, no. But I, I watch the ID channel
Song. I mean, he, he, he locked his son.
He bricked up his son.
His son was supposed to go to
battle and he fucking chicken doubt.
So the guys came there and they were
like, yeah, you know, uh, your son,
and you said that it was like
the king or some shit. They go,
your son who you said was
brave, a fucking, you know,
he chickened out. And he said, bullshit.
No son of mine would do that. And they go,
yeah, he's right in that room. He goes,
I refuse to believe that
and to demonstrate it,
I will now have this room sealed off.
And he started bricking the room up and
he got all the way up to the last brick
and then the pussy was on the other side.
He went though,
I don't want this and
that. Oh, this happened.
And to Honga Orange County or something.
And uh,
he goes brick it up now.
It was that to put the last brick in.
And that was at the dude done. They
found skeletons with powder bunk to it.
It wasn't. Now it's a, it's a
fable. I wasn't a real Jesus.
How crazy do you think white people
are? Crap. [inaudible] think we are the,
we can break our kids up in a
famine worse. We actually have
she, um, anyways, Jesus Christ.
Let's get out of slavery.
What else do you want to talk about
the tree? So Neil benefits coming up.
Yes. Yes ma'am. Yeah.
Um, I'm sorry about that.
I'll always like seeing
Georgia. Yeah. Yeah.
I was actually spoke to
her before I came here.
What's your favorite Patrice
O'neil story that you had?
You went on the road with him?
He did Amsterdam,
man, man, we come back from Charlie
goodnight's, Raleigh Durham. Oh yeah.
And you guys five crackers is
illegal in Boston, right? Fireworks.
The fireworks go up to New
Hampshire. Yeah. So Patricia, yeah,
you're in a hurry to get back
in New York. I go, uh, no, no,
we'll sell it because I never really
use fireworks. And I go, okay,
well we stopped by, he spent like
three with the fireworks and duty.
Yes.
He just,
just put them all in one bag and
just wrapping it up and he goes,
oh, I want to, I want to set some of
this off. So I go, yeah, I'm from dying.
He was in North Carolina,
I'm from here so we can just find one of
these blue abandoned fields. So we did,
but it was, uh, it was hot and
the grass was dry. Oh, Jesus.
We started a forest fire.
Uh, no. Oh, we lit it up.
We had just came back from
eating. So Patrice had t he
shouldn't have had to. Uh,
and I had a big glass of water or
tea and the fire getting bigger,
but before it got bigger, we
tried to put it, stomp it out.
So it was just two black dudes
like ti would. I know we did that.
We did the feet first. You both had
new sneakers on. I sneakers were black.
When we were done.
He was trying to stop this fire out and
then we went and grabbed the t and we
both put our team on the
fire that did nothing did.
I said, let's get Outta here. You Go.
No, no. We got to the ambulance came,
fire truck came,
the owner of the land came in 10 minutes.
I'll Patrice you said, let's get out
here. You're on the state. You were like,
fuck this place in New York. Yeah,
yeah. Let's get out here. What happened?
They put it out, they put it out and that
will really cool. Uh, Patrice was honest.
It goes, let me do all the
talking stupid. And um,
and when they got, when they got
there, he's like, ah, I'm from Boston.
I know pop firecrackers before. So we just
started to be like, oh, it's okay man.
Don't worry about it. I just, I just, uh,
put some pesticide on this crops and
everything is dry or whatever and they let
us go. Wow. It took our statement.
Let us go. There you go. Look at that.
But we almost started a forest fire.
That shit was going to cook.
The field is here and the,
uh,
the forest was like maybe
10 feet from a five.
Slide it off in a parking lot. There
was no booze and was in North Carolina.
There's a parking lot. Yeah, there is.
I lived there. W will not will ruin it.
We were like off the highway,
off the beaten path in the rest area.
Scare a couple of pedophiles out of
the bathroom here. We didn't do that.
Let's put it in this fucking a pile
of hay. Oh Dude. It was hilarious.
Our feet were both,
our shoes are black from trying to
stomp fire report out to you on it.
Where are you going? Where are you
working these days? Um, everywhere, um,
in the city. Um, I'm actually pretty
busy in January. I'm going to Denver,
Colorado, Dino. Which, and
um, um, Dana headboards man,
I haven't run into him in
a minute. Yeah. Yeah. Um,
and where were you guys playing
it out there on the Improv?
Was that I was like a funny bone to
Denver. Comedy works? No, no, no.
It's the Improv I think. Oh, the
Improv. Okay. And then, um, after that,
I am an um, Dan, where am I?
I'm in Myrtle beach where I
started at a comedy Cabana.
How close is that to the forest fire?
Myrtle beach.
What forest fire as far as far as in South
Carolina one that you fucking started
two minutes ago. Oh, I'm
trying to do a call back here.
That was on fucking help me out
here. That was enough. Carolina. Oh,
North Carolina beach. South South
Carolina. Yeah. Fucking same down there.
That's what I'm saying.
I've been in the south,
the chain of waffle house. Oh
yeah. I used to work in Warren,
the signage to what this sign,
the font is so not exciting and then
it's like piss yellow with like the most
basic thing and you get in there
and it's just, I don't know,
there's always like a, either a fight's
about to happen or just happened.
It's just really like, I worked there
three years and when I was in high school,
people go there. They seem
like they're hiding out. Like,
you know, I can't go home
because of such and such situation.
Yeah, it's, it's, it's, it's uh,
I didn't enjoy working ahead.
How long did you work there
for? Three years. Off and on.
How many clients did you see? I didn't
see any fights but someone at the end,
after I work third shifts on time
and it club and the club let out,
these drunk people will come in and one
person went in the bathroom and shit
everywhere on the walls. So
the waitress comes out, she
goes, hey, I'm cooking food.
She goes, Harris, I need you to clean the
bathroom. I go, well, what's going on?
Somebody made an accident. I went in there
and it was just, it wasn't on purpose.
I don't know. It looked like a crime
scene, which shit. Uh, and I said, no,
I'm not cleaning out.
I don't get paid to clean shit off walls.
And they don't make a mop for that.
No,
they don't cause call a fucking Hazmat
group. Exactly. Exactly. I refuse.
And one of them did it and one lady came
in and she wanted a cheeseburger and I
said to Jesus, 50 cent
extra, she goes, 50 set,
can't you just put it on there at
coop? No Lady, I can't just do it.
You have to pay for it. And she
didn't get the cheese the next day,
the next night she came in, she had her
own cheese and the plastic and she said,
put that on my burger.
Like using a nightclub.
This cheeses in your glove compartment,
two hours, you left your house,
you've got your purse, your perfume,
and your high heels and your cheese.
So when you get to the waffle house to
cook can put it on your burger because
you don't want to pay 50% wow.
Hilarious.
That's that is, that is, that is a level
of fun. Cheekness cause that is cheapness.
If you're going out to a club and you're
going to pay a cover and you're going
to do some shit like that,
I fucking hate cheap people like that.
And also dumb with money. Yes. I
don't have any sympathy for that.
My white guilt only goes so far.
You know what I mean?
I'll white guilt all fucking day long
until I watched you get a deal and buy a
bunch of dumb shit. Then it was like
I'd forget it. Right, right, right.
You know all kinds of shiny shit.
Remember that?
Remember the member the age of the
deals and Montreal comedy festival and
everyone would go up
there and he'd be like,
oh my dad was crazy and my brother was
crazy and every was like, that's a show.
And then you'd go out and
you get a six figure deal.
Remember all those fucking idiots that
went out and they buy flat screen TV
title. They ain't got a bunch of money.
Todd land rest and peace literally did.
And I refuse to believe it
until Dean Edwards fucking, uh,
confirmed it.
Did the coming to America thing where
he fixed up a place he was renting.
He even redid the fucking floors.
He, he showed his landlord,
she raised the rent and he
had to leave after a while.
Yeah. Yup, Yup. He bought a bunch.
He, well, two cars. He, uh, he
bought that Gold Lexus. He had the Jesus,
it was, it was an infinity, infinity,
infinity. And he, he had a, he had a
waist length mink with a hoodie on it,
zip up and he would be on stage
talking about white people. Right.
You could be as white as,
you know,
you're never going to keep
money if you do that. Right.
He must have spent 20 grand on a horse.
It was hilarious. I feel bad to go and do,
we can't go that far.
It's not alive to defend himself.
But if it was less than it was,
say the spirit of him. Yeah.
Do you think
in the afterlife, both his
arms worked doing and he says,
Jesus, Oh God, you know, it's funny.
Tie wouldn't have their arm and
people were still afraid of him. Like,
what the fuck are you afraid? Because
he had that. He had the mean mug.
I used to always tease
him about this Roman nose.
He had like a Julius Caesar fucking
knows. Yeah, he was, I don't know.
He kind of looked like a male missy
Elliot. When I really think back,
you know what, she needs to
lose weight. You know, write,
write right that size missy,
whatever happened to her. Um,
I think she took her money and left.
I think Napster, which blew up comedy.
I'm convinced to that. I'm smart
with my money. Did it when I,
after the accident I was,
I only did all he only bowl.
Can I get any credit here
for going this far and,
and not making you fucking relive
that again. Oh, that's fine.
We can talk about it. It was okay.
Yeah. Harris was one of the people,
unfortunately, uh, who was on the bus
with Tracy Morgan when that Walmart truck,
not the bus. I'm sorry. It
was one of those little,
those Mercedes like say the band thing,
Limo party bus without the polling.
Rest in peace. A uncle Jimmy.
Jimmy Mack. Yeah. Oh Man.
I remember bombing with him
at fucking Labar bat one night
and I remember he was alarmed a
little barbaric to, oh everybody,
that fucking room that was talents from,
I never figured that roam up. Never.
If that room was like this really
cool bar and it had an upstairs and a
downstairs and it was
Tuesday's the after work crowd,
you know they never
called any white people.
I remember that specifically.
All black crowd after work crowd
and the only time I went there,
I think I must've killed first because
I went back. Right, right, right.
So I killed the first time,
then I bombed,
then I killed and I bombed every other
fucking time. It was unbelievable.
He only did it twice and a bomb.
Both terms.
I remember one night when I was
new anyway, so I probably go bad.
You never bombed so bad that the next
guy's bombing off your bomb. Like,
that's like an aftershock
of what the fuck I did.
Uncle Jimmy went up there and was bombing
and he was bombing so bad and it was
so fucking quiet. He was just that guy,
man, fuck y'all. [inaudible] he goes,
I in this woman was giving him shit
and uh, he said something about like,
what happened? You know,
something about his career, right.
You still got my fucking Korea. And
she was like, Edward, what career?
And everybody, that was the biggest
laugh. Everyone laughed at him.
He was trying to talk about being
on bet. Dude, you remember raw?
What's his face? Uh, Gerald
Kelly. Joe Kelly and I abandoned,
I did one of his rooms out in Jersey.
He was one of these places.
It was a dance club.
And like the next week it
was closed because someone
shot off guns or some shit.
And I fucking went in there and it was
me and Ross g and I forget who else.
And he was supposed, he was supposed
to host it. It was his Roman.
He was like fucking two hours
late. And uh, he came on stage.
Oh yeah. And it just was
like, he's like, Yo, what up?
You just got back from Atlanta [inaudible]
kind of sound and he goes doing comic
view. He goes, made
six g's,
I'd say made six grand doing comics.
If you're not people not in the business
comic view, you got paid like 600 bucks.
I got thousand dollars one time.
Did you think that was actually after
everybody I remember was in the hundreds.
It was like 700 bucks.
MMM.
All inclusive. Like you lost
money. You lost money. Yeah. Yeah.
Got It to one of your hotel, you
gotta pay for your flight. So he shit,
nobody knows that. So he showed up,
told the crowd that had waited for him,
like fucking axl rose back in the day
that he was late because he was doing a TV
show and he made six grand. Hilarious.
That's how we start. Every was like,
what the fuck? And I remember Ross went
up and she had such a tough set that uh,
she ended her set and she goes, damn. She
goes, I don't know who's coming up next,
but he better be funny cause
you motherfuckers ain't
laughing at shit and walked
off. And then they brought me up
and of course the second I talked,
everybody did the white guy
voicemail. Hell yeah, I ate it.
Uh, Jimmy, I tell you a funny story
with Jimmy because Jimmy Hill had,
I guess he was away for
comedy for a little while.
So Tracy brought them on the roads
and it was on tour with us. Um,
but before I got on the tour,
uh,
mark field both said that Jimmy would
go up and open and be bombing. So uh,
Tracy said a chimney,
you go up,
warm the crowd up and just will go up
at Jimmy started bombing and then a
already comes back and goes,
you'll Tracy Jimmy's bomb.
You want me to get them off
the, she was like, no, no,
let them simmer for a little bit.
Goes back out.
Yo Jimmy stretch. It's to me
turns the Broncos. Oh, okay.
They want me to stay out here and he
just bombed for five more minutes.
Like Tracy,
you were an asshole for just letting him
sit in this bomb for five more minutes,
let them out off the hook man.
And before then,
so the next night he goes, Jimmy,
you're up against, you're up.
Sounded like that dude in pulp fiction.
Let them simmer a little bit.
It's similar little bit. And then so
the next night, Jimmy Tracy goes, Jim,
you're on again tonight night.
And Jimmy literally went in the corner
and started rehearsing his lines like new
comics do.
And he went out bombed again.
What an asshole. Tracy.
I had a
bunch of those. There was a guy, I
remember when I was in Boston, this guy,
this guy, Dick Doherty, he still has rums.
He had all of these fucking rooms, right?
Right. He was like the godfather of
the outside the satellite rooms. Right.
You had the,
the main clubs in Boston.
And then he had all of these
places in like fucking Drake,
it and all these places in Massachusetts
and uh, which are all great towns,
but you know,
not the best place sometimes to do comedy.
So he finally did want it.
He finally got one in Boston.
I guess he always had the, uh, he
had the comedy ball for a while,
but he opened this other
one in Kenmore Square,
right in the college area and they
called it comedy comedy campus. So this,
this journeymen guy, finally, he gives
him the room, like your book in this room,
your host it, and he's
fucking psyched, man.
I'm finally fucking making something
in this business. And um, he fucking,
the first night of it,
I'm on it with Greg Fitz Simmons.
And the dude goes up and it's just really
small crowd. 10, 15 people on through.
When I tell you he didn't get a
fucking laugh. He got nothing.
Brings up the first act. The first
act immediately starts killing crowd.
Fucking livens up. Everything's
going great. Dude finishes
his set. Thanks a lot.
Back to your house. So, and so host
comes back up immediately bombing again
bombing. That's always funny when
the host is bombing also bombs again,
brings up, uh, the woman that
Greg was dating at the time.
Fucking she kills back to him bombing.
So finally brings up one more
person. That person's killing, right?
So fucking Simmons looks at him and he
just goes, hey buddy. He goes, dude,
you know, if, if it's not happening for
you, just bring acts up. You know, we, we,
we got plenty of show here. We've got
plenty of showing, like piss this guy off.
So he got on stage and he fucking
immediately just starts bombing again.
So finally, dead silence. He just looks
at the crowd. He's like, you know what?
What the fuck? What the fuck the fucking
jokes do you fucking people want?
Exactly. And this guy and the crowd
goes, how about some funny jokes?
And he goes, he goes, funny how like
things going in and out of your anus.
Oh, that's that. Does that kill it?
Killed me and Greg. That's hilarious.
He said it was such
fucking bile in his voice.
You actually pictured this guy's an
asshole. Pucker and up. That's your key.
Me and Greg were, it was the funniest joke
of the night. He will cry and Larry's,
and the crowd was just like,
Whoa, what the fuck? Oh, well,
you remember Kevin Hart's sweet cheeks
in Atlantic city? I never did that one.
But I remember they throw chicken
at big J. Oh, it was awful.
They love heavy bar it.
No,
it was a sweet cheeks and
it sounds like a gay bar.
Teres worked at gay bar called
fiddlesticks. I did one.
It was called Queen of hearts.
Oh Man. No, it wasn't a gay bar.
It's actually the opposite.
Gangsters hung out.
There was fights all the time
and they love little Kevin and,
but when everybody else we'll
come back on, they would just,
they do like the little plastic that
you put the menu in on the table.
They threw that at Jimique.
Uh, they just, they were awful,
but they loved Kev.
I was like,
well that guy is funny tools. Oh, I
didn't do rooms like that after a while.
Like there was a weapon if
enough people that last bag,
if enough people came back with stories.
Yeah. He was trying to get me to do that.
Roman. I remember I was far
enough in my career to do it.
I don't need to drive to Philly to bomb
like I can. I can do that. I'll do drew,
drew, Frazier's, rum, Manhattan
proper. I'll take the e to the end.
That just finally closed to take my,
I love that room.
I remember one time doing
that air all the time too.
I remember doing that one time and I
remember one entourage chasing another
entourage out of the club and then the
next week there was like a metal detector.
Yeah, wait, but yeah,
that's two parking gangsters used to
hang out in these cases just to hang out.
They're like real live drug
dealers. Yeah. That was the vibe,
but then this really cool after
work thing was there like supreme.
He, he, he was on American gangster.
He, they used to hang out there.
It was not a guy there named supreme WWI.
You probably didn't know
when your whiteness,
you had no idea that it makes the why we
thought it was a cut. People used to do.
When I got off the fucking, when I
took the EDA, Jamaica Queens get up,
they would look at me like they would
just be like, people would try to help me.
Jamaica, queens don't like,
they'll get back on you want to go.
He wanted to go the other way.
Want to go the other way? Yup. Yup.
You know, use, use, performing
in front of killers. Digi. Uh,
no. I, I knew that there was definitely
some shit going on that wasn't legal,
but I mean, I thought it was kind of
like a, do you ever think about that?
How many, how many like people
that killed somebody at this point,
how long you've been doing standup?
How many people in the crowd who have
killed somebody that people just don't
even know yet? All right. All
right. I just think that on
the subway, right. Well, in,
in Manhattan, probably, you definitely
had it. Some clientele and it kills him.
Might I add somebody killed some,
some future stars are for the first
48 yes. Let me make him some appetite.
How far into the Samurai?
Half. Half Hour. Okay, cool.
Look at me since still can fill a half.
Huh? I got typed in my God damn password.
What's your name? Your special again,
so people know to look for my name,
my special city. Uh, sorry,
got deck that naive innocence
and that's the thing,
cause I moved from South Carolina
and I was naive, innocent.
Then I got up here and it got wrong. You
guys and I became fucking terrible. Yeah,
we're going to blame us like that demon
wasn't in you. You're right. You're right.
Yeah,
it was in there.
But you guys haven't even talked about
half the fucking shit that I heard.
You did lubricated it out. You guys
lubricated it out. No, you are. You are.
You are on your own.
You will.
I remember you didn't help
fucking night overnight.
You would just went from like, hey, how's
it going? Everybody to Harris did what?
Harris did. What? Yeah,
it was pretty well. Yeah,
and I'm just leaving this open.
You want to tell you fucking stories
you tell them, but other than that,
I keep my mouth shut. No, Hey, you go, eh,
goes into falsetto.
Go sideways there.
All right, let me do a, let me do a
little read here real quickly. Uh Oh,
look who's back for the holiday season.
That is Sherry's berries.
Christmas is a week away.
Talk about last minute shopping nightmares
or do you want me to talk about it
going to the mall at midnight. Okay.
Fuck you. Everybody knows us. No,
it's actually not that bad this year cause
everybody's shopping online. Hey. Yeah.
Like you're just there with like fucking
people as old as me. Um, all right.
How shopping was Sherry's berries
has been a lifesaver. Oh yeah dude,
I'm so sick of these people who
are clearly stocking stuffers,
acting like you're buying somebody
a fucking Lexus like, like this.
Oh I don't want to go to the stores.
I'll just get somebody,
some chocolate covered strawberries and
that. I'm going to get those to my wife.
I'll just get those only and
see all my fucking holidays.
Go See all 2018 is anyways,
no matter how matter who you're
shopping for this holiday season,
share these berries has the perfect gift
for everyone on your list. This holiday,
my listeners can get fresh and delicious.
Sherry's berries dipped in white
milk and dark chocolate. Goodness.
Why didn't white come first? Harris
starting at, Oh that's right.
Cause it's pure starting at 1999
plus shipping and handling
or check this out. Uh,
when you double the berries,
double the berries for just $10 more.
Your gift will include a free
keepsake dessert platter A. However,
the white chocolate is still
the same price. I'm kidding.
I just want to see your face mark and
Rick left. That's two gifts in one.
You know the white ones come
with little clan hood on it.
If you get the Grand Dragon fucking ones,
uh,
there's only one way to get this amazing.
Somebody in the south is going to order.
Oh, that'd be fucking perfect mark. Uh,
there's only one way. Uh, you know,
that's a made up name cause it wasn't
two names, right? Mark, mark, Bobby.
There's only one Billy Joe would love
one of them. Claire, you know, ask.
I keep the hood. I'll keep the
hood. I put it on [inaudible]. Um,
there's only one way to get these
amazing 1999 deal this holiday.
Visit berries.com. Click on the
microphone in the upper right hand corner.
Enter my code burr checkout.
Remember when you double the
berries for just $10 more,
your gift will include a free keepsake
dinner, dessert platter platter.
Christmas is a week away order today.
That's berries.com code birth.
Um,
which white hate groups,
supremacy group of friends
you to least clan neo Nazis
or just the average Douche on Youtube?
That was a good question.
Probably the clan
even though they're out there
and that just kind of saying it,
I would think the youtube, cause it's all,
you know, you might even run into that,
you might even know that guy,
but they don't have the balls to put on
a uniform to say what they're thinking.
Okay. Yeah, that's,
that's better. But, uh,
the clan is just like funny
to me now. Like, you know,
I see it all on.
Somebody
shows you we wouldn't take the claim.
That's the only place they are.
The plan is only a, I'm as white as it
gets. I've never been asked to join,
I don't know any fucking members.
Right.
I mean all through the South [inaudible]
I've been in Connecticut and evidently
they got, they had a good
following around Connecticut. Yeah.
Not as prominent as they used to be.
I guess they kind of fell off.
It's like the mob. They're all doing like
identity theft now in the fucking whip.
Yup. All right. He looks everybody helix.
There are a ton of online mattress
retailers popping up these days.
All with a one size fits all solution
for better sleep to a better sleep.
Guess what? One size fits all doesn't
work when it comes to mattresses.
He likes sleep offers something that
doesn't exist anywhere. Anywhere else.
A mattress personalize to your unique
preference and sleeping style that won't
set you back. Thousands of dollars.
That's true. Like even not,
not just your height,
like if you sleep face down,
they take a plaster mold or your junk
so it the contours to the mattress.
That's true. Are you
serious? No, no. I was like,
you don't need that.
Go to helix,
sleep.com/burr and take their
two to three minutes sleep quiz.
They'll build a custom mattress.
That will will be the best thing
you've ever slept on for couples.
They even personalize each side of
the mattress, which we both know.
That's the beginning of the
end of the relationship.
You're starting to live separate lives.
You can't even sleep next to the
person you need your own space.
Everyone from Gq to cosmopolitan to
the New York Times or talking to vibe
magazine, reaching out to
your people if they still do,
they still have vibe magazine? No, I
just, it was the last black magazine.
I remember Ebony Ebony jet TV guide,
uh,
are all talking about
he likes and once you try it out,
you'll know why your customer masters
arrives direct to your door in a week and
shipping is completely free. Try it for
a hundred nights. If you don't love it,
they'll pick it up, gross and
refund you in full. Uh, all right,
go to helix, sleep.com/bar right now and
get to get $50 off your custom mattress.
That's helic sleep.com/birth for $50
off your order as he likes sleep.com/
[inaudible] all right, we
got two more here. Oh, here
we go. Me undies, everybody.
But out Bob. Bob, me, undies, me undies.
They'll take a mold of your junk to
do, to dupe me undies, me undies,
flip over and they measure your trunk
if I'm sorry, not [inaudible] everyone,
every year millions of people receive at
least the least like gift of all time.
Underwear. Harris, what if someone
gave you underwear for Christmas?
I will love it cause most loan over have
holes in it because I'm one of those
guys who just,
I won't buy new underwear until
someone's a former baseball player.
You're superstitious. You hit your last
curve ball with that pair of underwear,
you're still gonna wear it. Right? Um,
well listen to this. [inaudible] okay.
They'll give I love socks.
Now I'm trying to do a segue back into
this fucking copy and I can't do it. Uh,
anyways,
but we still give it to our family
and our loved ones who just don't want
underwear. But maybe it's not
that underwears the problem.
Maybe it's the kind of underwear.
Harris and Harris.
Can I take a moment here to
tell you about me undies?
The only underwear that makes for
an amazing gift. The only underwear,
even though you'd probably take a
three pack of some shit at Marshall's.
Me undies made underwear.
The perfect gift that everyone
is going to love you for.
It's a Goddamn holiday miracle. This
ha this year. Don't give underwear.
Give me undies this holiday season to
get your exclusive 20% off the softest
underwear and socks you'll ever wear.
Free Shipping and 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] that's
[inaudible] dot com slash bar
they used to have all this shit in
there that they were softer than cotton.
Sorry, I meant last. Last but not
least. All right. stamps.com Paris.
Do you go to the post office ever and not
recently? No. How do you get your mail?
I don't mail shitting. Oh, Di do di?
Do you do it online?
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah. You're comfortable with
that. Do you bank online? Yeah.
Do you jerk off online and when you
do, do you cover the camera? No,
I don't drink off on why
you don't jerk off online,
but you have VHS while I'm online.
Plus what? I mean you use online porn?
Yes,
yes.
Yeah.
The porn on Washington,
you don't cover the camera does.
There's not a camera is a camera
right here. Yeah, but now what?
I'm watching porn hub. There's
no right that, that's a camera.
See the tape I got over there,
but you know what I found out now.
Now when you click on a point of all
of a sudden like the whole screen to go
like they just took a picture
of you go and look on the video.
No, this is the thing. I use my phone most
of the time. Do you use your phone? Well,
where are you home?
Put my phone.
You got debt?
Go to eyesight and you can't hit a
fucking curve ball snapped the ball.
That's unfucking believable. Well the
phone's not moving right? It's like golf.
All right.
stamps.com everybody stamps.com brings
all this service of the US post office
right to your fingertips.
All right.
Buy and print official US postage
for any letter, any package,
any class of mail using your
own computer and printer.
Then the mailman comes and picks that
shit up. stamps.com makes it easy.
You don't have to use your brain.
They'll send you a digital scale.
Automat that automatically
calculates the exact postage.
stamps.com we'll even help you decide
the best class of mail every time.
Print postage, any day, any
time. stamps.com is always open.
I use stamps.com whenever
I'm fucking sending out my
posters. I'm a moron, Harris.
You know that. If I can
figure it out. So can you,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com service
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus postage
and a digital scale without longterm
commitments.
Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeatypeinburburarethatstamps.com
enter
burr.
Okay. All right. How far in are we?
And you have 40 okay. 10
minutes of bullshit there.
Sorry. You have a tape vote.
That's it.
The camera.
Just so people don't want you to drink or
does that really well? I just feed. No,
I'm just like, what if you're banging
your wife and you just have your thing on?
Like these fucking nerds, you know,
they're not getting any pussy.
They just watch you. They actually
caught people like they, they want the,
you buy a TV, they watch you
watching TV. Oh fuck yeah.
And for some reason that's not illegal.
And now all these fucking morons
who are ah, they got that,
that little thing there in the
house being being like, Alexa,
what's the Capitol of South America
or whatever. I mean, sorry, Brazil,
South America in the morning. Um,
yeah, you just bugged your own house.
I mean you already have with all these
devices and now you've got this other
thing, right. That's like a excellent,
I'm not all have locks of my house. No,
it's like inviting a vampire into
your house. You got to put a thing,
a garlic around his fucking fuck.
Alexa.
Fuck out my house, Bitch. That's
exactly what I said. Okay,
here we go.
It was bad timing. We both took a sip.
All right. Uh, here's some questions.
All right, now I tried to get
some ethnically diverse. Once,
so I can show you that I'm woke.
How annoying is that to hear a
white person say that by the way,
are you married to a black
woman? Huh? Yeah. But you know,
once you're married that long,
just a woman,
you know it's the same file cultural
fight. It's not like the little,
you'll hold the fork like this
and I hold it like that. Wow.
There really is a difference.
It's the same shit.
Like can I finish up here in the bathroom
before you try to steal the sink?
Brushing your teeth. It's
the exact same shit. Right?
It's only when you go out in
public and everybody's like,
what the fuck are you doing together?
You fucking race trader. Yup. Um,
but when you're in the House,
Huh? I low ball. You can
have mine. You can have mine.
Whatever one I was supposed to be
with and I took yours. There you go.
And then one day we'll go on a double
date like those too. Freaky fucking,
was it the Yankees and the Indians near
here? The button that they swapped wives?
No, there was two teammates.
They went on a double date.
By the end of the end of the date,
they fucking realized, hey man,
we're like sorta like, you know, they
probably sat at a four top boy, girl, boy,
girl.
And I think they just sort of uh,
the dude stop talking to
each other and chicks up top.
You should have by the end of
it some they agreed to switch.
Swap wives like to just
go forever like yeah.
And I think one of them made it and the
other ones didn't. That's hilarious.
The other one didn't.
That'd be the funniest fight.
I should have stayed with that right.
Feel there.
Well I know he's getting a better blow job
than I am old. Be Brutal. Um, all right,
here we go. So I tried to have
some ethnically diverse. Okay,
so you want to start,
this is a nice one that I feel like
anybody have any sort of background?
Transgendered? Anybody? Uh,
this one's called favorite
Ozzy Osborne guitarist.
So this is right in your wheel house.
This is a fast ball.
I feel like you can jump on this one.
Why is this in my wheel house isn't
being an asshole. You are breaking bad.
I'm watching a documentary on Ozzie
that's four hours long and booze and while
the girlfriend is out with her
peers doing sex in the city,
shit a while,
Randy Rhoads always gets to me,
especially during Mr Crowley,
that none of this means anything to you.
My favorite is always been Jakey Lee.
I grew up on bark at the moon when I was
a kid and still listen now and again to
the last furious rips of Jake and the
last minute of the song I always felt he
was under appreciated. Could not
agree more. Zack Wylde is all good,
but it feels like he's using five pedals
instead of showing pure skill. Well,
you should've seen Zack wild when
he played with the almond brothers.
That would have cured all of that shit
for you. A more style than substance.
I don't agree with that.
Uh,
what do you think Drumma boy ps was great
to see you Montreal last summer when
it was your birthday. Um, all
right. What do you think Harris?
Just by the names alone.
Who would you think is the best guitars?
Would you go with Randy
Rhoads, Jake Jakey Lee or, or,
uh,
Zack wild.
Probably Zack Wylde Zack
wild by because it's wild.
It goes crazy.
You can jump on that Janky leave.
What does that sound like to you? Jakey
lease. I was like borderline Asian,
mixed Asian trying to fit
into the culture. Okay.
And Randy Rhoads. Randy
Rhodes, uh, as a racist.
And um, he died in a plane crash by
the way. Oh yes. She'd go easier.
This is like making fun of
Tupac for a lot of white.
Right? Right. Oh, sorry. I don't know
any of these people, uh, listeners.
I don't know any of these people. I
would never say that if I don't know him.
Well, he did play in an all white
bands. So I mean your theory does work.
Fucking racist. Uh, no,
no. Is it brutal story is he
was on tour with the Ozzy,
Ozzy left black sabbath. Right. And that
would be no doubt. That would be what,
whatever they had a fallen out.
It'd be like one of the one on how
do we relate to, you hear, well,
it'd be like something
in the Wu Tang clan,
they leave and then they put out a solo
album. That's, that's critical there.
Right. But Blue Tang never
really broke up, right? No,
not religious. Haven't made,
no. Okay. Well just say they broke up
and then all of a sudden, uh, you know,
one of those guys that's not old,
dirty pastor and method man,
ghost face killer decides
I'm going to fucking put one
out. You know, uh, you know,
it's a very, it's a very
precarious point in your career.
Like you, you don't get a second
solo album if the first one bombed,
especially if, you know,
came out in a supergroup. So
black Sabbath thing was over.
He was coming out on his fucking own
and he ended up meeting Randy Rhoads and
Randy Rhoads basically saved
his fucking career. Hey,
so they go out on tour, he's destroying,
he's like the new guy and everything.
And they, uh, were in Florida and
they pulled in and the bus driver,
wherever they were going to gas up the
bus, that was also a little plane there.
And this guy had a pilot's license and
he fucking got in the plane with Randy
Rhodes and he was fucking buzz in the
bus doing all of that shit in his last
pass,
clip the bus,
and either flew into the house or
into the barn to one of the other.
And then that was, it does
crazy. And that was it.
And you just said he sounded
like a racist. I hope you're
happy. No Man. You know,
maybe if she shouldn't be
googling all your fucking porn,
you could look up Randy Rhoads before you
soiled his name. All right, here we go.
Here. Here's, here's one that
we can both jump on here at.
Girlfriend isn't very attractive
and I want to cheat. All right. Um,
I've been dating my girl for a year
now and I love the shit out of her,
but God damn, if she isn't on the
wrong side of the 10 point scale,
God, what an asshole.
You don't love her? No.
And why would you date her if she's
ugly? If you think she's ugly? Yeah,
yeah, yeah. You don't love this
woman. All right, we got it. It's not,
there's anything wrong with their face.
She's just not really my type physically,
personally, personally
wise. Does he eat, flight,
physically personal.
Personally,
we jive what he says personally
wise, personality wise. Sorry.
We jive like crazy jive.
This guy's to be like 50 it's
like, dude, what are you look like?
Does he eat food or he doesn't like to,
and let's say she's really pretty
when I'm laying on top or next suffer,
but any other position,
and I can't help but be disappointed
in how overweight she is. She says,
this guy's a fucking monster.
On one hand,
the sensation of being with thick girls
really appeals to me on the other.
My male gaze does not
agree because of this.
I've found my thoughts wandering to other
women have started flirting with them
for seemingly no reason.
I'm afraid I'm going to cheat,
but I really think all things
considered that I could marry this girl.
This guy's all over the fucking map is
breaking up with her for something so
shallow would absolutely kill me
and it hurt. The woman I love,
loves heart for no reason. What
should I do? Go see a therapist. Yeah.
He's like
oddly like brutally honest.
He's being brutally honest here, but
what? He's all like, it makes no sense.
I like purple but I don't like
purple, which is it? Pick,
pick the pros and cons and you know,
he went on it is,
he made a very mature move where he
actually fell in love with the person and
now I think that that's
getting old. Yeah. You know,
there's no more surprises now he's just
looking at her and I think that that's
what's going on and exactly what
was going on. All right, now,
how can he for Christmas,
what gift can he give her that in
a funny loving way can be like,
you need to lose some weight
or I'm going to cheat on you.
Sherry's berries.
Oh,
there is no way. There is no way. Like,
you know the end of an action movie
where it's which wire do I clip and they
fucking take a guess. Yeah, both of
them blow up. Yeah. Alright Harris,
I gotta to put you on the spot.
How would you do it?
How would you tell the woman
you love personality wise,
you guys jive is this guy says,
how the fuck would you tell her?
You putting on too much weight.
Well, if you know someone that
long, when you go bitch, you fat,
you need to lose some weight.
So you just,
so you rip the bandaid off. Go listen,
you're getting a little overweight.
I had a boy,
a friend of mine who dumped his girl.
He wander before doing it while they
were dating. He said, if you get big,
I'm outta here. She got big. He
was out of there. She tested him.
She ate two bucks. She,
she tested the brand.
He said that they said that
to her and he left her crying.
I told you exactly what did I say?
Look in the mirror.
Look,
what did I say?
You're a hundred pounds bigger
than you was when I said that shit.
But he has the thing
though.
I actually think there is like a complete
lack of respect for your partner if,
if you let yourself go. Absolutely.
There is. Now here's the thing,
unless you know you Sikhism, oh or she,
you know, she got what? She was pregnant,
she had a kid talking about all of that.
But before having kids or if
you're not having kids, all right,
if you sit in a man or a woman,
if you're just sitting there just
becoming a fucking lard ass. Exactly.
What are they supposed to do? Exactly.
That you putting a lot of pressure,
like Patrice said, whenever you,
how will you look to get him?
You have to somewhat maintain it all.
Otherwise he's going to venture,
we're animals.
We're ma like we were.
And what I loved about Patrice as he
could be that overweight in the crowd,
they would never even think to say like,
well, what about you? Right, right, right.
He would just be like, bitch, I've
always been this size. Um, yeah.
I don't know what, what should he do? Um,
talk to her like you're talking to
you on these. I would just say this,
I would put it on me.
This is what I would do and this is this.
If you really loved her, I'd put on 20
pounds myself and then just be like,
listen man, I got to get this weight
off and get diabetes. If I loved her,
I would put on 20 pounds
myself and just say, listen,
I got to get this weight off but I
can't do it on my own. I need you. Okay.
I mean week lately,
I need you to know,
oh and she'll be there for you and your
take around and walks and this is what
you do. You buy, I wouldn't do that. No,
I wouldn't. I'd dumper. No, I wouldn't.
You buy his and her fucking matching
workout fucking outfits walk.
Just steer right into it. Just walking.
Be that couple that dresses the same. Oh,
I know. That's one of the, it's just like,
that's either like whenever I see that
that's like either they literally are
soul mates if you believe in
that or there's one person
that needs to be rescued
from that relationship
because the other person,
like who was that guy in the NBA when you
ric flair do, what would Rick flair do?
Yeah. Oh Jeez. Well he wouldn't be
around long enough for her to get fat
when he came over on the road when she
fucking put on all that way and he'd do
the flare flop right in front of it
and just turn around.
Oh you do the Henry Hill.
He just do that laugh member that and
he'd go walk turns right back around and
he gets, he gets back in the,
got that fuck kind of people.
Are they getting back in the car with the
Joe Pesci I think that's what he would
do. Um, this guy, I think
he was trying to be,
sometimes people try to be
funny by being really blunt.
I actually think this guy does
really like this girl, but like, uh,
yeah cause I think if they start
getting that fat before you had kids,
you just start thinking like, oh
my God, I don't want to be with a,
well no one wants to be with the,
no one wants to be a whale and no one
wants to be with a whale. Well some,
some guys like big women.
Okay. All right. Okay.
But he doesn't know. He
likes it. Will Thicken and
sunken obese.
My had a best friend
who wanted his woman as
fast as she could be.
Oh he did? Yeah. He had a best friend. She
was, his wife was a fat motherfucker too.
What is that about? I don't,
I think they liked it.
This is what's so weird. You know, maybe
they want them to just look adorable.
You know,
the durable a baby looks with all those
roles of like a roll of fat in the mid
forearm. He just looking at like,
what is that? Right? What is that?
That they didn't want a big, a big
giant baby. I think there's a lot of,
they like a lot of woman,
but I like a lot of one
but far as like not fat,
but like let's say six, five,
11 that's a lot of women too.
Yes, I understand what you're saying,
but it's not fat, not fat. What's,
what's the biggest she would
go give me height and weight.
Let's break down your draft
picks and in the foot.
Then the first round of the big
girl draft terrorists, Staten picks,
picks 185 pound,
six foot. Nope, five tall. How tall
are you? I'm six. Two and a half.
Six, two and a half. All
right. Yeah, so she has to,
if you're going to weigh 200 pounds,
you'd have to be five 11 and better.
Otherwise you're just a fat bitch.
Let's consider an insensitive,
but it's actually,
there's an endearing thing where
you're just being brutally honest.
I mean that's, that's what
your heart is saying. Yes.
It's saying you're a fat bitch. It's
not being like listen. Um, right.
Your heart's doing all the
work. Yeah, I would, I would go,
uh, whatever. Cause I'm like, I'm
five, nine, three quarters. I'm,
I'm exactly Doug Flutie height, not
quite five 10 big woman with curves are,
are, have a chance. Like if you
still, you don't have the fat woman,
they are really fat, but you can
still see the curve. Yeah. Curvy.
Like it was like a skinny woman, but fat.
Yeah. Like a deck, a hot chick giant.
Just sacrifice that.
Ah, right. I would say,
I would say one 65 cause I'm about one
75 I don't want to throw me around the
fucking room height.
Is it like five,
five [inaudible] six as big. Yeah. That's
not that big. Depends on the, you know,
depends. Five, five 160 pounds.
She, she's got a nice ass on her.
I don't like those. Cankles would
ankles or went into the, to the foot.
You know what's weird is when he got,
they got fat feet and skinny. Oh yeah.
It's like, it's like someone was
at, you know the carnival, right.
We slam the hammer down and trying to
win that prize and the hit a mid feet.
Right.
You've heard Corey Holcomb's
fucking underrated comedian.
Absolutely underrated in my fucking head.
But uh, he, he felt welcome.
You have a fuck the fat girl.
We're regular people legs, but God
damn, I just fucked the hamburger.
That's usually an alcoholic body.
There was a guy that I used to work
with who I found out recently died,
which wasn't a surprise.
He was like the biggest booze hound coke.
He was like six, five. It was funny,
man. He was just big, just like, dude,
his legs were skinny as mine and he
would push his jeans down and just up top
was all,
was just all booze and burgers
and he said hello and uh,
and he had the little skinny hit, but
he had like his arms and legs was like,
he never worked out in his life was just
skinny as shit and he just kept all of
that stuff there again. Well, I
think he died of a heart attack.
That's it right there. Which is why
going back to this guy, it's just like,
that's another thing you have to look at.
Going to be like,
I'm going to be a
widower in my mid fifties
there's gotta be an exercise video just
to get rid of your flat feet or at least
to fatten up your toes, right?
You should get like, no,
you should get like the acid injections
in your toes just to fucking even it out,
you know? Um, all right, here
we go. Ladies. Get deprived to,
how are we doing on time? Oh, good.
Killing it. We're right on schedule here.
All right ladies,
get deprived to dear bill.
I am a lady in my late twenties and I
need a male perspective on something
that's too embarrassing to bring up with
my friends. All right. On a good day,
one might consider me quite easy
on the eyes. I exercise every day.
I have a natural look, I. E. Not
trashy, 20 layers of makeup kind of Gal.
However, I always make a case of
looking well put together even at home.
See, she gets it. However, my
husband's a fat fuck anyways,
but for some reason in the last
year of my five year marriage,
my husband denies me sex.
Even if I only want to service him.
He knows I like to do it. Geez. He's like,
don't you want a job? Yeah, this is bad.
Uh, yeah. This is bad.
This is when you're not going to start
taking off the police tape and getting
out the blanket too to take
a blow job from another dude.
I Dunno about that. All right. On
any given evening he will be a,
it's not the mouth,
dude. It's the stubble.
I think that that's what
you couldn't get past.
I almost got need to do a spit
take on any given evening.
He will be sitting on his desk working
late and if I try to initiate things by
touching him and kissing his
neck, he will say, sorry babe,
it's too late and I'm tired.
Same goes for when we are in bed.
It has gotten to the point where I just,
you know what,
I got this paranoid thing just
cheating like a month ago. Huh?
Either that or he got replaced by a robot
and the days they haven't worked out
the genitals yet. Sorry Babe.
It's too late and I'm tired
and we're throwing their voice. Um,
same goes for when we are in bed.
It's gotten to the point where I
will try to approach him in lingerie,
sit on his lap and even go as far
as begging for just five minutes.
All any success.
Uh Oh, this is like, this
is one of these things.
If it was a new story,
I would shut it off cause I don't want
to see the fucking ending. Here we go.
What baffles me is that
during normal day to day life,
he will frequently grab my
ass or tell me I'm hot. Wow.
I also do the same for him as I know men
like to feel manly around their lady.
This woman is like a dream.
I don't know what's this guy's problem
is the possibility of NFL. Okay.
The possibility. She said she's,
you know, she's easy on the eyes.
She takes care of herself. Yeah. I
Dunno, I got a nice picture in my head.
Um, anyways, the possibility
of an affair is very unlikely.
Seeing as we both work on the same male
dominated company that's not good and go
home together. Um, also he doesn't
have a password in his phone.
I think maybe he's gay male dominated.
I know something wrong with him also.
He doesn't have a password in his phone,
which is another huge
indication of nothing to hide.
We have a very nice interaction.
I never nag him. If anything,
he nags me and we do cool stuff like
play ball together or watch some Netflix.
It was Dick don't work no more. You
don't want to tell her yet. Yeah.
You need to sit down and talk to him.
He's a very loving husband except
for the actual physical loving part.
I've tried to ask, but
everything is fine. Uh,
everything is fine isn't
as it appears a bill.
Could you please let me know
what the Hell's going on?
Aren't men supposed to be always in
the mood? Uh, that's not true. But, uh,
generally speaking,
yes,
I am going crazy and I'm starting to get
aroused from the most ridiculous thing
like men's smiling at
me or opening the door.
Jesus,
thank you.
I really enjoy everything you're
doing contrary to what you think.
You are very balanced and insightful
in your opinions. Look at this.
I got to read that to my wife.
Happy fucking holidays and
go fucking fuck yourself.
One itching lady itching
to get fucked. Uh, listen,
I think you've been nice for long enough.
Exactly where you need to sit down and
be like, look or leave him. No, no, no.
You've got to have the conversation
before first I said, yeah, of course.
What is going on?
Because you know I'm about ready to
get jumped on a rolling pin. Exactly.
What the fuck are you doing it you need,
you need, you guys need to have a talk.
Need to go on.
And I wouldn't,
I would go nice because just in case
it is some physical thing you got to go
nice first year. But now maybe, maybe,
maybe he's addicted to
online porn as a problem man.
But that definitely can't
continue what they're doing.
They seem like they're around
each other the whole time.
I don't know what's going on.
You get a lot of,
you have a lot of weird stuff. Yeah. All
right. Need Advice? Quitting drinking.
So I wouldn't, I guess our advices, I
w I would sit down and talk to them.
Absolutely. You're not being
a nag at all. If anything,
you've been too nice and uh,
I would just go easy just in case it's
something fucking a problem. Yeah.
Like he got molested as a kid and it
finally came out and now he doesn't like,
did they ever used to go at it
like bunny rabbits? I don't know.
That's a good question.
Did y'all ever used to have like a
real healthy sexual relationship then?
It just fell off a cliff? I,
oh, was it gradual or, yeah.
I think once you have a kid though,
that that just happened,
like the appeal of going to sleep
is just fucking unbelievable.
It's unbelief and it's something if you
do it together, like that's your sex.
Gosh,
we're going to get eight hours.
This is fucking awesome. All right.
Needed vice quitting
drinking. Uh, I know you're,
I know you're at 100 something odd
days now of no drinking 116 days of not
drinking.
I'm at a whopping day three and this is
my third attempt in the last two months.
Take some serious time off.
Most of my attempt only last three or
four days max because every Friday rolls
around and I can't help
but buy some booze.
I want to quit because
my problem is serious,
not serious enough that I experienced
minor withdrawals like minor shakes,
LG. Oh Wow. If I haven't had a
drink in like 12 to 16 hours,
meaning I'm physically dependent. Yeah.
Dude, this is a great reason to stop.
It's not serious to the point where
people notice I'm able to keep it under
control, but drinking
everyday needs to stop. Yeah.
Your what's known as the
intelligent are alcoholics,
so you can fucking what I call you.
You're a smart guy and your booze and
so you can play shit off and nobody
notices where they're just
a fucking moron. Everyone's
going to notice. Exactly.
My question for you is how did you go
about filling up the boredom that comes
with being sober? Oh, what
a great fucking question.
I feel like I'm drinking a,
when I'm drinking anything.
It's fun sitting on the couch for hours.
It's so true on end
watching youtube videos.
But when I'm sober I've got like 20
minutes tops before on board with whatever
I'm doing. Also. What was your prop?
Was your problem ever bad enough
that you felt withdrawals? Uh,
I know how to tape her
pretty well at this point,
but I have failed so many times that
if you know of any tapering tips,
basically how to Wean your way off, I
guess. Uh, I'd love to hear them. Ps,
I've always missed the old overrated
underrated segment you used to do circuit
2009 ish on the podcast. You should bring
that back or actually bringing it back.
Um, all right. This week we'll bring
it back. Uh, we'll keep doing it.
And if you guys want to send an
an overrated, underrated. Um,
I find when I stopped drinking,
like when I stop, it's,
it's tough for like the first,
uh,
like six to 10 days and what
it is I'm more habit addicted.
Like I just like if, if I'm eating
well, like I'm addicted to go,
I'm going to get a salad.
If I'm eating like shit.
Like if I eat McDonald's the
next day I'm craving McDonald's.
If I'm drinking then I want to drink.
So it's basically,
I tried to be conscious of those
thoughts in my head and just be like,
try to get to the next morning,
going tomorrow morning,
what's going to make me happier that I
had a drink right now or that I didn't
and it was always that I didn't. So
I would choose that. That's a good,
that's a good word.
I used to do that at the Boston comedy
club when we never really know what she
had. Like I never really seen you drunk
ever back in the day. Uh, yeah, I,
in the last like, uh, like 15 years,
I gradually just drank more and
more and more and more important.
And then I, uh, I just, I'm
not an alcoholic but I, but
at the amount that I drink,
I absolutely am,
but I'm one of those guys that can shut
it off and like this guy just sit there
and be like, shows you don't, I can do
it. If I'm not performing arts, I can,
I'll have a drink.
But if I'm performing I need one or two,
but I'm not an alcoholic but far,
but I have all the problems. I,
my thing is like, I, uh, if I'm
doing something, I'm doing it.
So the first thing I do when I sit down
at a bar is I always order a double
because I'm assuming that they're poor
is you go to the Bart destination,
leaving your house is the bar or like,
how's this Nigga ours after shows?
Oh by the sumps this this summer it was
becoming like going to the liquor store,
buying a bottle and always like I was on
the road doing an acting gig and I made
sure I had a bond and I just close
it and I knew I was shutting it down.
So it's just like this is where
it is. Bill, this is bad. Um,
yeah, it got, it got way, way,
way worse than it ever went as
far as like, what am I doing?
I remember coming home from the set one
night and being excited that the bar was
still open and before I went in there's
no road debt to where where I was
staying.
I was by myself and I ordered a double,
sucked it down and said give me another
double cause I was sort of addicted to
that, that crazy buzz and
then going asleep. I think,
um,
I like the tube and then the whole time
wanting to stop or wanting to not do it
as much. And that was the only
time there's was first time ever.
My wife brought it up going on, you know,
you're really drinking a lot and hey,
you're going to snore
and blah blah blah blah.
And then one night I came down to set
up good wife, meet all I can see you.
I know I'm so embarrassed by this.
I came downstairs and I
actually was hiding the glass
of booze on the other side
when I was coming down the
stairs and I was just like Whoa,
I'm that guy now how soon before the
bottles in the back of the toilet. But
I kind of too much of a control freak
to make it happen like that. So,
but I find like once I go 10 days,
the way I'm wired,
I could go, it gets easier. In
theory, I could go forever. Okay.
Cause now it's just something I don't do.
I'm just like audit the whatever
it is that would, that had its,
it's fucking claws in me.
It only takes 10 days for how I'm
chemically made up to just be like, yeah.
Like right now I'm 116 days in,
I could easily go a year,
I could go two years.
I could,
I could like never drink
again for the rest of my life.
I don't think about it
anymore after the shows. No,
there's certain things that like makes
me just wish I was still drinking. Eh.
I'm like, what did I see the other
day that was just like, aw man,
I love to do that. Like, uh,
I saw some cool looking bar
and it was just like, man,
I would love to go there at two in the
afternoon and just get fucking drinking
till six get fucking hammered.
But then,
but now the way it plays out
is renewable flare though.
I know I would jump into Uber and I would
come home drunk to my daughter and I
was like, ah, can't
have that on the resume.
So that's over.
So my life also kind of, I'm not
telling this guy needs to have a kid.
So I would just say what you need to do
is you got to push through that boredom
and uh,
I put the,
there's so much fun shit that you can
actually fill that time up with that.
It's stuff that you wanted to get good at.
Like,
like I've always been in the music,
like playing drums and playing guitar.
If you do that instead or
working out like if at night.
Yeah.
If at night you go out for a jog
instead and then this is nothing,
this is nothing to about not drinking
is the fucking pounds just fall off.
You really, you know, as long as
you don't substitute it with them.
Like I'm going to eat ice cream
so I can get like a sugar rush.
If you actually eat well and you don't
booze, yeah. It just falls off. Yeah.
It's got nowhere to hide. So, um, I dunno
man, but it sounds like, you know, the,
the shakes and stuff, you're on another
level than I was. So I'm, I, if I was you,
I might even go to a meeting
as borderline intervention TV show.
What'd you get to shake?
Yeah, a little bit. I
would go to a meeting,
just check out a meeting just to go down
there, check it out, sit in the back,
have a fucking doughnut,
whatever the hell they do there.
And just listen to these people's insane
stories that actually make you feel
better about himself. Self. Exactly. Um,
all right. Okay. Here we go. Overrated.
Underrated. Bringing this back because
this is something that's, this guy said,
so we actually were going
to do when this week,
this is something he used to do way
back in the day. 2090 [inaudible] too.
Overrated. Underrated. It
was the thing of the week.
Whatever you thought was over eight
and whatever was underrated. All right.
Overrated. Texas hold'em. Underrated.
Five Card Stud.
Now here's the deal.
I don't know shit about
cards. Um, I, I don't know.
You got to give me the explanation.
All right. That was a bad,
that was a soft open. I don't know
anything about cars and don't play cards.
All right.
What do you think is overrated right now?
Oh,
this, this topic. No, no.
What I think is overreading right now,
hip hop.
Rarely. Yeah. Like th th th th
the not having any words in your song
and it being a quote unquote a classic.
Ours a hot a song for this time and it,
but 10 years down the road just
guy said nothing. It was just be,
be in sounds. I was just beaten
then like mumble rap. They don't,
they don't say anything.
Oh everybody. Yeah. Everybody sounds like
they're kind of like half in the bag.
Yeah.
And there's no originality anymore,
but people are still celebrating something
that is less original than it used to
be.
Do you know how old you sound right now?
The people in your
generation has gangster rap.
Originality is not old at arrest.
Universal and they don't have any original
that their name's not even different.
How many little rappers do we have?
Little this little, that little,
you can't even name yourself
and the original name. All
right. When did they live?
When did it hip hop lose you? Hmm. Uh,
probably mid 2000.
No,
late 2000 late 2000
maybe 2011 12 on and up.
But not all you want. You hung in
there. Yeah. But not all hip hop night.
You got artists like m and M and nozzle
was still doing what they're supposed to
do with God.
You're doing like,
that's like me going Yo Zeppelin
and ac DC going back like 20 years.
But those guys are still wrapping those
chaos and it's still relevant and it's
the words like you got, you can't
have a song. It's instrumental.
What about the WHO? Who's it?
They got all the awards. Migos.
The meek is at the Migos. I don't even
know him. He throw listened to him.
I don't even know.
I heard of him,
but I know a lot of rappers name got
little in it and that bugs me little Uzi
Vert and they could just change
your name to original name.
Little Wayne was first and then
everybody else's little bit.
My Tupac and Biggie, they had their
own names. Not that it's original name.
Yeah, he went there. He went
little because there was
already a too short who is,
who is the, uh, the little
person there and uh, uh,
that fucking guy was that, fuck. I don't
know anybody. There was a guy, Bushwick,
Bill Bush. Yeah, he was, no, he
didn't even say little. No, he was,
he was bleeding with bill several
years from, well, you know,
these millennials are sensitive.
Okay. I would say overrated.
Being informed is overrated.
Absolutely.
I am off social media is, I don't read
the shit anymore. I post my shit on there,
but I'm done. Like, oh, I fucking
took a picture of this thing today.
This is the classic classic is going
to take forever to turn my phone on.
Somethings gotta keep going.
Classic fucking like a joke.
When you forgot the punchline, you just
keep repeating and set up. Oh yeah.
Shit is crazy. She is crazy
shit. It's crazy. We used to say,
we used to say when when comic
white comics will lost in their act,
they'd look down and be like, yeah,
yeah, so uh, what else is going on?
And that shit is crazy.
She just crazy out here.
But you're a good looking crowd. Applause.
But let me now, tonight for the ladies,
ladies, all the strong women in
the crowd, they're always strong.
Women are always wrong.
Do that. So I wouldn't bomb
early, like in black rooms.
Like I'll just go give
it up for the ladies and,
and compliment the crowd of milk.
So they'd give me at least 30
more seconds not to Boomi. Okay.
What's the hardest room you ever did?
Sweet.
She's sweet cheeks back to sweet cheeks.
It's not even, I don't think it's like,
it's just a fucking place to go get
pick up $200. Well the two 50 back then.
Oh yeah. That was literally like fighting
might like Mike Tyson. It's just like,
all right, if I can survive around I
get, I get my fucking purse. All right.
This is something that somebody tweeted
today about that pipe bomb that went off
on in the uh, the port
authority has happened.
Yeah. Am I mean, fortunately nobody
died. They said there was non,
I like non life threatening injuries but
that doesn't mean somebody didn't lose
an eye or fucking hearing or something.
Bomb went off on 23rd street right by
Gotham comedy club and they closed the
street off. I, you going to do a
joke? No. And so just got off stage.
When I got there, they was, the street
was closed off and I actually asked a cop,
but, but I have told because I have a
spot I didn't give a fuck about. Oh Man,
I just want to do much spot.
Well this is what,
this is what this fucking jerk off tweets
about the port authority bum. He goes,
I have no idea what's going
on at the port authority,
but it was chaotic and I did
state of find out
so you have no idea what's going on.
But we had to find out how you felt
about what you did know was happening.
Who gives a fuck what you did? People
down there hurt you fucking asshole.
This is what I can't stand. I, I'll be
an old man here about young people now.
Nobody cares,
right about every fucking thought
and your stupid fucking headaches.
When you there, did you see what
happened? Do you have any information?
Okay.
Oh my gosh, I have no idea what's
going on at port authority,
but it was chaotic and I
didn't stay to find out,
and then there's going to be a thousand
fucking people going. So happy.
You're okay. Yeah, exactly. People
just want them. I didn't know.
So many people want it to be known.
Oh No.
All these fucking people.
The reason why at least
fucking people on social media,
it's like they have their own TV show
and they're acting like celebrities,
self-involved fucking celebrities
as opposed to cool ones like us.
The one who that skill, sorry. Sorry.
All right, last one. Here we go.
How do I tell the truth?
Uh, Hey, bill. Well,
I've been thinking with my
Dick, I recently downloaded
the popular hookup app,
Tinder,
and I've been using it to fish for some
action with some college chicks in my
area. I'm pretty good looking
and I'm not bad with chicks,
so I've had moderate success.
I recently found this one
chick in my area who is,
oh, premed. Is that all
one word? P? R? E? M. E?
D? No, there'd be. Okay, thank you. All
right. That was like, I knew I was dumb.
I didn't think I was that fucking
dumb. Um, you know what's funny,
that fucking guy who said, the guy who
I was telling this story about it, like,
you know, funny how like things
going in and out of your ass.
He just sent me a text.
I'll fucking random sec. Um,
I recently found this check
in my area who's premed.
I really like spending time with her
and we have the same sense of humor and
political beliefs and she has an
excellent body and face in short.
She's pretty close to my ideal
girl. However, there's one problem.
I'm in high school
and she has no idea. Fuck, fuck this guy.
Fuck this guy, dude. You Dude, you are a
legend. I, you should be giving me advice.
I have dodged most of our questions
about the classes I take and where I
couldn't dodge. I lied. Jesus. We
haven't done anything physically,
but she made it cleared. She is
interested in me. I'm in deep bill.
How do I tell her without her hating
me? Uh, do I have to tell her?
I just fucking tell her. Just say, listen,
I don't want to go to a physical level
without fucking telling you the truth.
I'm still in high school. I really
liked you. I would have told you sooner,
but I was afraid you weren't gonna like
me. Just do that. Put it out on the table.
If she tells you to go fuck yourself,
fine.
But you've learned a very
valuable lesson with women,
which I wish somebody taught me way
back on my teen years, teen years.
Just tell him the truth. What
are we doing? I wanna fuck you.
I have no intention to having
a relationship with you.
Okay? Most will walk away.
Some won't.
But you can literally leave your fucking
car out in the front of your house and
it will never be keyed.
None of your shit will be lid on.
Yes. That's why when I see
guys who, who, uh, um, um,
damn,
I forgot my train of thought.
But honesty is always the best policy
because you don't have to worry about
people getting mad and doing crazy
shit to you. Dude. It works with cops.
Two cops and women. Nobody lies,
gets lied two more than those two.
And when you actually come with the truth,
even if they don't like the truth,
it kind of like, yeah, you might not get
a ticket. That's probably why Patrice,
the fire that no one, no one,
we didn't get in trouble. Yeah.
Cause he was fucking
honest about what happened.
The only time I fucking bang this, you
turn right. And on Fridays I did it.
Just fucking cop got out of his car and
I'm, as I'm pulling up and thinking, wow,
maybe he didn't see it.
He's just coincidentally getting out and
he walks right up to my window. He goes,
let me see your driver's
license and registration. I
was like, yeah, fuck. He goes,
uh, he goes, you know why I'm asking for
that? And I was like, yeah. He goes, why?
I go, because I just made an
illegal uturn. And he goes,
why did you do that? I go,
because I'm impatient and I didn't
want to wait in that line in there.
And he just laughed and he goes,
do you want me to give you,
what do you want me to give
you a ticket? And I said, no,
but I'm not going to lie to you. Right.
And he laughed again. He goes, all right,
get out of here. I said, you're
awesome. Right. That was it.
Then other times I've told the truth
and like all the way to the point,
is this your current address?
And I said No.
And the guy wrote me up for everything
and my fucking address and I was like,
this motherfucker.
He trying to get
fucking cop of the month. Like I did
that in western New York. All right.
We're out of time.
Um,
Harris. Yes. So great to see
you once again, your album,
my comedy album is coming out.
It's out already.
It's out right now on iTunes,
Amazon and Google play in anywhere else
that you can get comedy anywhere else in
the name of the album is naive innocence.
Okay.
I almost said Google alert
is where you can get it.
Like I don't know what the
fuck anything is. All right.
Thank you so much for stopping by. Thank
you for being on the podcast. Everybody.
Uh, I forgot to mention
here, we've got a couple
of, uh, benefits stuff
here. Uh, Santa Steve,
the Great Steve Simone and regular hero
are raising money again this year for
children fighting cancer
and their families. Um,
that's worded really weird.
They're fighting cancer and the families
of the children fighting cancer.
Isn't that weird?
The raising money again this year for
children fighting cancer and there
these kids are fighting cancer
and their own families, um,
the children and their
families fighting cancer.
A Monday morning podcast listeners helped
raise 15 grand last month and it had a
huge impact on a lot of families. The
stories are brutal and every bit helps.
We're going to save you the
fucking stories. Okay. Uh,
the goal this year is to raise 50 grand.
We're going to tweet a link.
Thank you so much in, um, ahead of
time if you've got anything to give.
And also,
here's some dates I've got coming up.
I'm going to be at the hard rock live
in Hollywood, Florida. December 14th,
December 16th, the Bob Carr
Theater in Atlanta, Florida.
February 2nd to Reno ballroom,
Reno, Nevada. February 20th,
the Patrice O'neal comedy event benefit.
The sixth annual,
makes a great Christmas gift.
Get a pair of tickets to that.
Tickets have been going fast. Um, it's
a great benefit raising money for, um,
Patrice has mom and loved ones.
Thank you guys so much.
Go fuck yourselves and I'll
check in on you on a Thursday.