Hmm.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is time for the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
January 30th, 2017 what's
going on? How are Ya?
Um, as you can tell by my, my
little slightly more relaxed tone,
my kid's asleep downstairs so
I, I can't scream. I can't yell,
I can't rant and rave.
Oh, I can do those things,
but I have to do it in
a controlled manner. Um,
that's what I have to
do, you know, cause the,
the dynamics of the house changed a little
bit and I know what you think is so,
Bill, does that mean the dynamic
is you'll probably catch,
is going to change a little bit? Yeah,
just a little bit, but nothing crazy.
You know,
like listen to me right now,
you would have no idea that right before
I got on this podcast, I just meditated.
I meditated for 10 minutes,
I shut it down.
Let's focus on the sounds in the room now.
Gently let those go away and focus on
your breathing. I did that 10 minutes.
I guess it's helping me out.
Um, you know, I had one,
one meltdown this week.
I was trying to figure out how to put
the fucking car seat into the car and I
swear to God, dude, like the level,
the level that they have overdesigned
those things is insane. I swear to God,
I hope auto racing,
they should put those fucking drivers
and car seats and then nothing would ever
happen to them. I couldn't figure out
how to get this effing thing in there.
And I did I just say Effient. Yeah.
I'm trying to learn how to, uh,
the kids influence.
It's coming in.
I've been cracking me up
by doing it going, hey,
quit talking s and just, you know,
abbreviate incarceration to her.
It's hilarious because all she's
ever heard we do is just, you know,
curse my brains out.
And I was making a laugh last night
because we were laying in bed when we
watching wheel of fortune with
a beautiful baby between us.
And I was just doing what I always do.
I was trashing all the contestants
and all and everything on there.
Read, uh, you know,
I to say about the wheel of fortune,
man,
dead dare fucking some
stingy cons on that show.
When I give it comes down to the,
to the Dang whoever that one of the three,
that one when they go over and then you
try to win some big money to get him for
one big hit for like 50 or 60
grand, those puzzles, they,
they're practically impossible.
And the clues throw you off.
Okay.
They had one,
they said a phrase,
okay,
they go, this is a phrase, we'll give you
these letters. And of course, you know,
none of them show up. Right? Then you
pick some in a few of those show up.
This was the phrase,
our first voyage.
Okay.
That's a phrase.
I mean technically it's a phrase,
but if you're going to say it's a
phrase that should be something like,
like to me a phrase,
it's somewhere between,
you know, an expression and a, you know,
just some random shit.
Right? That's a phrase.
Yeah.
Does that make any sense? Like
an expression, a, a, you know,
fucking stitch in time saves nine. Is
that an expression? Instead of Soliloquy.
I don't know what that is. Okay.
But I know that's not a phrase,
that's something else, but I don't know
what that is. But a phrase is Jared,
some calm eight check please.
Yeah.
You know, don't fucking touch that. I
don't know. I can't think of a good one.
But you know what I mean?
Our first voyage is afraid.
Technically it's a phrase Pat Sajak.
I never realized they,
they always fuck the person over.
They tried to limit the r s and t's in
it because they know everybody's gonna.
Okay.
Gonna guess those ones, I don't know.
And he always pulls the car down so,
and they give you like eight seconds
to solve it. You don't get it in.
Then he always pulls out some
ridiculous amount of money. Oh,
that was for going to be for 90 grand.
Very stingy.
But what do you expect?
Cause I remember back in the day they are,
when they had the shittiest
prizes on that show,
it's almost like they didn't want
you to be happy when you left.
So as much as I'm a joy in that show,
I don't know.
I'm starting to just getting ready
to move on to a new game show.
Um,
Jesus Christ in my fucking tired.
I don't know how the hell I'm
going to get through this hour. Um,
cause then I got to run over.
I'm doing Conan O'brien tonight.
Everybody please tune in to hide my
standup special that comes out tomorrow on
Netflix, my fifth one called walk your
way up. I know what you think of bill.
Why don't you call it walk your way
out. Well, if you'll watch the show,
you'll understand how about
that. But if you guys could,
um, you know, social media,
the whole thing up and uh,
just let people know to check the
thing out so the dream continues. Um,
I would really appreciate it. Um,
I'm very proud of this one. I hope,
I hope you guys like it too.
I had a great time doing it and we shot
at this beautiful venue called the Ryman,
which is the original place where
they shut the grand ole Opry.
Then a couple of floorboards
left from the original,
um, stage. So when you walk on those,
those are the same ones that
Elvis Johnny Cash. Yeah.
You know a bunch of other white guys and
fucking Minnie Pearl who walked down.
Hank Williams,
Hank Williams jr I acquire
you have Jeremy and jr
um, I told you guys I've got
satellite radio finally in my car,
if they're all those years of being on it,
on the opie and Anthony show way
back in the day, XM satellite radio,
way back in the day. I never had it and
I didn't realize how fucking great it is.
And I've actually gotten a little bit
into country music, but it's sad. Um,
Willie Nelson roadhouse channel.
I like the old stuff and the new shit.
I just don't fucking, I
just don't, I don't get it.
I'm not into it at all.
It's gotta be somebody.
There's no fucking way you can have
an entire genre of music and not have
anybody today doing it. Well, um,
but who knows. So I haven't
done shit this week. People,
I don't have any jokes. I don't even
know what the fuck to talk to you about.
Been watching Celtics and Bruins Shit.
I was so tired the other day,
my daughter was crying.
Um, my wife was holding my,
my daughter and I walked over
with the pacifier to try to
quiet the kid. And I literally walked up
and tried to put it in my, my, my, uh,
my wife's mouth. She laughed thinking
I was fucking around when I was like,
oh sorry.
Sorry.
Because when I walked over she was
talking and I'll always thinking was make
that noise stop. And I tried
to stick it in her mouth. Um,
so anyways,
so I'm starting to understand why
so many parents are so are so conti.
Yeah.
To people who either don't have kids
or they're about to have kids and they,
they, I dunno if they're not
nice people, they really aren't.
And I'm gonna try not to be that person.
I'm not going to resent someone who,
who doesn't have kids because they
have free time that I no longer have.
That's such a fucking,
I dunno,
it's a weird thing,
you know,
when you have a kid cause you get to
experience this new level of love and then
you also get to see this other
side of people just like, ah,
they would just fucking,
I dunno. I don't know.
I ran into yet another person. I'm like,
dude, you can have no free time either.
I have no freak type of pocket door.
I went to a drum lessons Saturday and I
went to the Nhl all star game on Sunday.
You know what the rest of my time was
fucking, you know, daily with the kid,
but I'm still doing shit.
Yeah.
You know what's up?
I think a lot of fucking people,
they didn't do shit before they had a kid.
They don't have a fucking hobby.
They don't have anything that they're
passionate about. I don't know what it is,
but they're miserable. Cons.
I got to get away from him.
You know, I just had a buddy of
mine say, hey, congratulations. I,
I'm thinking about having
a kid, you know, next year.
I just said, that's great. It's your
experience. Don't talk to parents.
They're not saying people,
myself included, just, you
know, it's going to be great.
Have a good time. Be Nice if people did
that. Huh? But why would you do that?
Why would you do that when you can't get
somebody you're fucking resentment out
on a completely innocent person.
When I'm going to start bitching about
this shit, uh, I think I've made my point.
So anyways, I'm selling more
shit. Oh, I'm selling more shit.
Everything's on the chopping block.
Um,
okay.
I got that John Bonham drum kit that
I have that 71 Ludwig green sparkle.
And I'm actually toying with the idea
of selling that fucking thing because I,
um,
okay.
It's just too fucking big for me. It's
not comfortable playing it. The symbols.
I don't even like the sound of
them. It's not my sound. And I did,
I did the stupid fucking thing that every
weekend warrior want to be hobbyists
musician does.
I'm going to buy Eddie van Halen Guitar.
Then I'll play like Eddie
van Halen. No, you won't.
You'll just be a dose with an Eddie
Halen Guitar who is an Eddie van Halen.
So I made that mistake. So I'm
actually thinking about, um,
actually I toyed with the idea,
but then I,
I went in and I looked at the
drums and it's so beautiful.
I don't know if I can fucking
do it, but, um, I dunno.
I would rather get a drum kit that may
be set up for fucking how I'm built.
I swear to God,
I played that thing out on the comedy jam
twice and I to go from the rack Tom to
the floor,
Tom said 26 inch bass drum.
It's so you gotta take like a taxi to go
from the rack or just the way I'm built.
So to get to the fucking,
from the rack to the floor,
I always go via the snare just to give
me that extra split second just to get
over the fucking thing.
I don't know how this Barnum guy did it,
but you know, it's not working for me. So,
um, I'm thinking of
getting rid of that and uh,
and going out and buy maybe like a Gretsch
or something like that with like a 22
inch kick instead of a 26 and have a 14
inch floor Thomas that I have and that
has a rack.
Tom,
I think that I always like the 14th floor
I noticed is some fucking nerdy drum
shit.
But um,
yeah I think I want to do that and
get them out of the fucking house.
I'll fuck a final fucking studio space
for like a couple hundred bucks a month.
Now I just have a brand new kit cause
that's the only thing that stops me from
setting that thing up cause it's
a vintage kid. I'm like Oh my God,
when somebody steals it,
it's irreplaceable. But
if I buy a brand new one,
brand new symbols, get a little bit
insurance, you know, 50 bucks a month,
I walk in there one day somebody steals
it adds just fucking get another one.
Cause there's still making them,
I'm trying to get out of their disease
of like an old shit. I love old shit.
But then you get it and it just becomes
this fucking thing when it breaks.
Oh my God, how the fuck am I going
to try and find the parts for it?
They come up on my body guard
and the big dude from, uh,
from m power.
What is your major malfunction with the
fuck was that called full metal jacket?
Remember that guy? He played the, uh,
the dude who protect the kid
from meatballs anyways, he
had a fucking motorcycle.
There was some little piece of the
carburetor, they couldn't fucking fight.
So of course because it's a
Hollywood movie, you know,
because it's a Hollywood movie,
you know,
they go into a junk yard and the
little nerdy kid finds it, you know,
and then that's they're
the little bonding moment.
I would tell you guys how much
I hate that when I watch, um,
TVs and movies, TVS, TV shows and movies.
I hate the fucking convenience of
how everything fucking works out.
Um,
I also,
like two nights ago I was doing stand
up at the comedy store and I was talking
shit about being a white dude.
You know,
cause it's funny cause you're
not allowed to do it. You know,
every other group of people could
be proud of their accomplishments.
But we can't wait to this camp because
of all the horrific shit that we've done.
Wipes out any sort of accomplishment.
So jokingly saying like, you know,
we did this as a dad, we went to the
moon and then this woman yells out here,
figures go see hidden figures.
I'm just saying,
you know,
I cannot stand people that go see a
Hollywood movie and think that they just
read a history book.
It's, it's just fucking like, and
then they think they're informed.
It's like you're not informed. You watched
a movie. I told you guys that shit.
Do you know their movie sully?
When that thing came out,
they wanted to make the copilot
an alcoholic just to raise the stakes.
And the real guy who's really alive and
still flies had to like threatened to
sue or something. It'd be like, guys, he
can't fucking put that out there about me.
I'm not an alcoholic.
I have a career in commercial aviation.
You can't start floating it out to the
world, then I'm a fucking alcoholic.
And then they were like, oh, all right.
So that's all I'm saying.
Okay.
I'm not saying that there weren't some
people doing some math and all that.
Just don't fucking, my only thing
about that, this is myself included,
don't fucking come after
me when you've never,
you never heard of those people and
all you did was go out and go see the
fucking movie and start
coming to me like you,
like you went to fucking graduate school.
So I had formed with that.
I probably went too hard. You know, I
brought up that guy who fucking, you know,
that dude who figured out that
when you're out in outer space,
then if you perspire that your,
your sweat would boil and you would
literally boil and your own sweat.
So that his space suit was
literally like a giant radiator.
Some dude figured out
that that would happen.
Figured out that that would fucking
happen before we even went out there.
You know? Where's that guy's movie? Huh?
Well,
where is it?
Oh, Jesus Christ. What else? Um, so
yes, I went to the NHL All star game.
Um,
three on three is crazy format.
I think you know that going in the right
direction because everybody knows that
all star games are mind numbingly boring.
The baseball ones pretty good.
Basically I would say baseball's
the best all star game.
The NBA All star Game I guess
is sort of fun cause everyone,
nobody is going to play d and
everybody's going to dunk.
So it's a little interesting.
But I'd say the baseball wants the best.
So the NHL is trying to figure out,
you know, a format on how to make,
there's competitive and
people to give a shit.
So they take like all four
divisions and I can only,
I didn't even understand the format.
He played like five minutes,
then you played another five minutes and
then two other divisions came out and
you played five and five
and then the winter,
those two then played in the finals.
I don't know how to fucking thing worked.
Um, where'd you play?
Two 10 minute periods.
I was at the game and I couldn't figure
out what was going on. And it was,
it was unbelievably quiet
when he was in there.
They should have played the
first five minutes, five on five
and then the next one, you know
something. There's no way to make an all
star game exciting. That's just
basically it. Cause you know what though,
they just have too much to loose back.
I'd be no sub at Ben when they
all start games are great.
We're back in the day when professional
athletes also had like off season,
day jobs.
Yeah.
Like he played for the Cleveland browns
from September till the end of December.
And then the rest of the year
you were like pouring concrete.
Like those lunatics, they
gotten shaped by, you know,
being the Jackhammer guy on a road crew.
Um,
I bet then then they had some good games
because then there was probably the
pride of like our conferences better
than your conference and Blah Blah Blah
Blah Blah. But uh, there's just
too much money at stake. But, um,
it was still fun to go down there and
see all that type of stuff. But, um,
and that's was part of my nerd,
you know,
fandom thing that I have.
I've now been to every all star
game except for the baseball one.
So now of course with my fucking OCD,
I have to,
I don't even know what I'm going for.
Okay.
Going to all of these fucking games
at this point. But um, I dunno,
you know what's cool about it is it
keeps me going to different places.
Okay.
You know, cause at some point
I want to go to that. Uh,
I've been to one golfing major in,
in order to go to all four.
The first three are not difficult. Well
the US Open and the PGA or not difficult.
You can get fucking Texas. The fucking us
open at golf. I mean they just animals.
Yeah. When you watch that golf tournament
and you hear those people screaming and
yelling,
it sounds like the third show.
It's some shit fucking comedy
club on a Saturday night,
just a bunch of drunks and then I can a
police anybody cause they want to make
their money off selling a booze.
Um,
the masters is the hard one
because they don't sell tickets.
And here's a heads up on that.
The first time I did it, you have,
you get like these badges that are given
to the members and they're not supposed
to sell them, but they all
do. And everybody kind of
looks the other way, right?
So then you go to these
brokers that have these badges,
you pay way too much fucking money
for them and you show up at somebody's
fucking house.
This is what happened to me.
Okay.
And, uh, the first time I did it,
I went with two people and we,
we lucked out and we got the
badges mean Versie we went in 2010.
Then a few years later we went to go
again and I brought five fucking people to
the same people's house and they said,
ah,
there was a mix up with the badges and
then the lady who was going to pay us
just fucking goes, I'll be right back to
go get them. And She just fucking left.
And that's the last time we saw.
And then the husband just waited
us out on the front yard and uh,
and I was just out the money and
they completely fucked us over
and I lost a ton of money as
did a number of other people.
And we were talking
about trying to remember,
we were standing outside the
house just waiting for them.
The neighbors came walking by going like,
God or they screw you out of the badges.
Yeah, they did that a few before. And,
um,
you know,
just started having fantasies
about burning down their
fucking house and all of
that type of shit. And then, um, I dunno,
I just Kinda let it go. And you know,
it's funny
is every time I let it go,
like fully just let it go
and just be like, you know
what, I did get to go to it.
Part of buying scalp tickets is every
once a while you get fucked over.
It happened me at a ravens game one time.
Um,
I ended up buying some tickets that were
stolen season tickets and they kicked
me out of the fucking stadium and then
I had to buy another pair of scalp
tickets to get back in.
I mean it's, it happens,
but what's funny about that?
Um,
okay,
the one I get fucked over at the,
uh, the masters and I bought,
I bought five of those fucking things.
So I was out a lot of money.
What was funny about that is every time
I go to let it go,
cause I remember him saying, the guy said,
dude, if you don't give him money back,
I'm going to suit. I'm going to sue you
and blah, blah, said all this stuff.
And then the guy, little
Elmer Fudd looking fucking
dude, just get who you are.
You near Gichon mood
back in with his fucking,
there's other fucking
fat. Fuck. I was going,
well,
well how much money you got your pocket
from the other ones give me that money
and he gives you ain't give me that money.
Come get it. Let's see. You try, right?
It was like one of those moments and
there was like five of us and we could all
beat the shit out of the guy.
But you know what's gonna Happen?
You're gonna beat the shit out of him.
Okay,
then we're not going to get them money.
We're going to go to jail.
They're going to sue us for assault.
There's just no way to win.
The only way to win a fight,
once she passed like high scorch,
once you become an adult,
the only way to win a fucking fight is
you have no money and you have nothing to
lose and you're homeless.
That's the only way to win it because
then you're going to get arrested and
you're going to go to jail and at least
now you've got a place to stay for the
night,
get some meals.
You don't have to beg for food other
than that you're going to fucking loose.
Cause I sat there and kept trying
to do the math going how the fuck,
you know,
having those violent things and you know,
I'm sure there's a fucking
tire iron in the car.
If I smashed both these guys over
the fucking heads. What's APP,
which I'm not going to do. I've never
done anything even remotely that violent,
but you're so fucking mad.
Where are you getting fucked out of money?
You start having these fantasies and
just cause it makes you feel better.
I'm just thinking of caving in
the side of their fucking heads.
I just kept trying to do the math on how
we would get away and you just can't do
it anymore. You know, back
in the day you could do that.
You could jump on your horse and fucking
right away it was over. You know,
it wasn't some minor with the cell phone
fucking camera and you've horse had a
license plate on his fucking tail and
you were screwed. You had done, um,
you know,
somebody following you what the fucking
drone and there was just no way. Um,
there was no to do it other than
just take my loss and then I
was going to cook, quadruple it.
And um, and God knows what else, you know,
and the kind of people that would do
to us what they did to us. I was like,
what would they do in a court of law if
I was actually guilty of doing something
to them? You know what I mean? So
I let go of it. I said, fuck it.
It's a loss. Who gives a
shit? We'll make it up.
We'll come back at some other
time. We'll go, go again. Fuck it.
And every time I would go to let go
of it, you know, start to let go of,
would start to let go of it.
Fucking Paul Versey. Okay.
The half Sicilian part of him who can
never forget anything like that would call
me up.
And just get me fucking off.
He kept me all riled up
again. I'd be like, Paul,
you've got to stop doing.
Then he would sit there calling
me up like he's Sammy the bull.
If Sammy didn't fucking sell out
and I'm fucking the other guy there,
what does it, what are the Teflon
don there almost sit Giuliani,
um, Gotti, John Gotti,
and he would call me up just telling me
what he was going to do to that guy's
house.
And of course he did door, hey, he's
not going to do it. He's married,
he's got two kids.
But he would call it a call me up
and I would get me going again.
He did this for fucking years
now it's just a joke now.
It's just like once a year he'll
call me up and be like, hey dude,
not for nothing. But I thought about
this again the other day. I was thinking,
not even fucking saying anything to you
and just going down there and then just
calling you up and being like, hey bill,
it's done. It's done. And I go, yeah.
And right there,
right.
That you'd call me up and then
you'd say something over the phone.
And because it's not illegal now to listen
to people's phone calls right there,
we would get caught. You have to
weed, you would have to do, Paul is,
you would have to go down and do it.
Know that you did it
and then not say anything to me ever
until one day maybe we were out to fucking
see in international waters.
And then even then we'd have to go to
back to the back of the boat when the
engines were on. You'd have to put
your hand over your fucking mouth,
like fucking Joe Pesci and Deniro and
casino. And then you could tell me,
oh by the way, I burned down that
guy's fucking house. MMM. So many.
I mean, how the fuck I
got onto that, that store.
I don't think I ever told you guys that
story cause I was so fucking mad about
it for years. Um, oh,
I know what I'm talking about is just
talking about going to all these different
games. Um, so be beware of that.
If you ever go to the masters,
unless you have a really good hook up,
if you just going to buy from a a
regular person, try to keep it at two.
Because what happened,
because we were a group of five and
they didn't have enough badges, uh,
they decided like,
we're going to have one group fucking
pissed at us rather than having,
you know, you know, three groups
of two fucking pissed off guy.
I forget how many we had. It was just
like, all right, we're just gonna have,
this is one group of people that will
bitch as opposed to having like, oh yeah,
they fucked me over. They fucked
my group. They thought my groups.
I was just just as complainant. Actually,
I think there was one other couple to,
I dunno,
I got to stop talking about it cause
it's gonna give me fucking mad again.
Those goddamn cuts
you nail.
You murdered.
Oh God. Oh, fucking elbow fund.
Any other the fat fuck redneck,
this stupid orange shirt.
I still remember these big guy.
He has his big fucking beer belly.
Oh my God.
Uh,
the beautiful sound of a bat
hitting all that flesh. Oh,
that would have been to heaven.
But you know,
that's not what you're supposed to
do as an adult. And who's can, no,
I've never done that to anybody.
And I would have been like,
I would have alligator armed it and
I just would have made them mad.
Then he would have smothered
me with all that fucking
hillbilly fat and I would've lost
and it would have been out the money
that I'd be leaving with grass stains all
over myself. Uh, it would have been
horrible. All right. Sherry's berries.
Barry
gifts like no other for love,
for your love, like no other.
Oh, that's right. Valentine's Day's coming
up. I'm so fucking sleepy to my kid.
Last night got up, uh, I started
to fall asleep around midnight.
She got up at, I get up at 1257, one 10,
two [inaudible] three or something.
Then she went to four 30,
which was unbelievable.
Just get that extra 30 minutes.
Then she went to six
and for whatever reason,
she sleeps from like 6:00 AM
to like nine or like nine 30.
And I just know at that six o'clock one
that when I change their diaper and I
get her all settled down again, that I
can actually just think it's, it's fine.
That's where the podcast is.
A little late here.
I thank God I'm a standup comedian.
Okay, you people that actually have jobs,
we have to fucking get up at eight
30 in the God damn morning to go dry.
I don't know how you just don't,
not off in traffic and drive
into a fucking guard rail.
So my hat's off to you.
All right.
Gifts like no other for
your love like no other.
There's no one like your Valentine.
Oh Jesus Christ.
There's plenty of people like your
Valentine. Everybody has two arms,
two legs and a head this year.
Treat them to an unforgettable
gift that's as unique as they are.
Chocolate covered strawberries.
A tell a personal fuck off.
Tell a personal Valentine's Day story.
What makes your sweetheart unique?
You know why? Because we have
a kid who was eight days old.
She still let me go to the NHL All
star game. How about like that?
What quirks do you love?
Um, oh, I don't know.
Talk about your personal experience
sending Sherry's berries. Have you,
have you already ordered Sherry's? No, I
haven't. You guys given to me for free,
for free cause I talk about
on your podcast berries. Um,
how did your Valentine react?
Do Am I applying for a fucking job here?
Do some analysis
on me or I get from Sherry's berries.
Shows her,
you put your thought into
finding the perfect gift.
People.
How am I supposed to get through this
copy when they just make such outrageous
statements like that?
There's no fucking thought.
This is the perfect fucking thing.
When you hear,
you guys had totally
selling this the wrong way.
Sherry's berries is the
perfect fucking thing.
When you're running out of time and
you'll only want to spend 20 bucks and get
cheese,
at least show that you made an effort
and maybe you'll get one more blow job
before she kicks you out the door.
Freshly stripped drops
strawberries from Sherry.
Barry's starting at just 1999 plus
shipping or double the berries.
Double the berries, right? Maybe you play
with the Bulls to you for just $10 more.
Just go to Barry's dot
com and use my code.
Burr helps support our show by supporting
our sponsors. Use My code burr.
Uh, these berries are decorated. They
are fresh. They are juice, sweet,
shareable and irresistible.
Shareables gross.
I always hated that fucking nine and a
half weeks when he was fucking taking all
the food or the fridge and putting
it on her. It's like, well, Mickey,
what do you do? What do they eat the
food of? Fuck your woman. You don't,
you don't do both. It's gross. It's
like eating, eating, eating Teddy Barr.
You want some chicken fingers
now? I don't, I don't,
I didn't want to see some titties or
go to a place that fucks with chicken.
I don't want you guys pick one.
You read them in the sex industry or the
food industry. Top with chocolate chips,
decorative swizzles and chopped nuts.
Surprise her at the office. Slash.
Workplace.
Her coworkers are sure and be just a
little jealous and she'll be overjoyed.
Yeah, bitches. Who else got to
everybody's getting Sherry's berries.
Choose a gift from Sherry's berries.
Incredible collection of gifts.
Your gifts will be a perfectly packaged,
perfectly packaged in a gift with
all the details taken care of.
Sherry's berries will deliver
your gift to fresh shit on time,
guaranteed or your money back.
We all know this with Valentine's Day,
right around the corner. There's
only one way to get Sherry's berries
starting@nineteenninetyninejustvisitberriesdotcomberries.com.
Click on the microphone in the top
right hand corner and type in Burr.
That's berries.com.
Use My code.
Burr helps support our show by
supporting our sponsors. Use My code.
Burr are right. Okay. Now here's
the next one is the next one.
It's fucking pro flowers.
Proflowers everybody.
Aren't you tired of guessing what
she wants for Valentine's Day?
When you love an easy fail
proof way to look like a pro?
Why don't you just ask her?
God knows.
She'll tell you I want a diamond bracelet.
Oh, is that what you want?
What are you gonna get me?
You're going to give me new flat
screen? Yeah, I didn't think so.
So here's some strawberries
and some flowers.
You want a peanut butter and Jelly
Sandwich this year? Pro Flowers.
It's making it easier than ever,
ever by taking all of the guesswork
out on top of their already low prices.
Right now you can get two dozen assorted
roses with free with a free glass vase
for 29 99 plus shipping and handling a
or upgrade in for nine 99 you can get two
dozen long stem assorted roses
with premium vase and chocolate.
Just go to proflowers.com and use my
code burr helps support our show by
supporting our sponsors.
Use My Code Bar,
pick your flowers and then
check out in two minutes.
Why do they all say that now helps support
our show by supporting our sponsors.
I'm not putting that kind of pressure
on you. If this appeals to you,
fucking buy it.
Order now and have it
delivered on Valentine's Day
right to your home or work.
When coworkers gush over the Gif, you'll
know you did Valentine's Day, right?
Pro Flower bouquets or
bouquets are guaranteed to
last seven days or your money
back. You can't beat the price and
convenience proflowers takes care of.
I was just thinking like if you got rid
of the flowers, you know what I mean?
Seven days is a long time.
You could actually have a big enough
fight that you break up before the flowers
die. Okay? Those are some fresh flowers.
You can't beat the price and convenience.
Proflowers takes care of the details.
She can just sit back
and look. Awesome. Um,
here's the only way to get two dozen
assorted roses with free glass vase
starting at 29 99.
Just go to proflowers.com and use my
promo code [inaudible] help support, uh,
that's proflowers.com click on the
microphone and type in my code. Bird.
Don't wait. Order today. This
deal expires soon. All right.
He looks everybody Hallux.
What is it about buying a mattress
that leaves you feeling violated?
Yeah,
I mean, come on people. Why would you do
that? You're talking about mattresses,
you're saying violated this.
This is,
why would you put this sexual
assault undertone in this?
Okay.
I Dunno. Where do you buy your
mattress in a fucking alley.
Is it the pushy salespeople?
Is it being held down by the back of
your neck that you feel your belt being
undone? Oh, this is going to
be the last one for these guys.
The fake President Day sale or the fact
that you know you'll regret that you
bought as you do the walk of shame
out of the mattress store. Yeah,
this is on them violated walk of shame.
They're putting all this out there,
not me. Those days are over. Thanks
to Helix Hallux a sleep well.
You can buy a mattress online customized
for you for hundreds of dollars instead
of a thousand gotta Healy sleep.com
answer a few simple questions and Helen's
creates your custom sleep profile
to build you your perfect mattress.
The results, our customers report at 30%
improvement in overall sleep quality.
Your mattress will arrive at your door
and about a week in shipping is 100% for
free.
You,
you have a hundred nights to try
it out and if you don't like it,
they'll pick it up for,
for gross.
They'll pick it up for free and give
you 100% refund. No questions asked.
What does this stain set up questions.
It's like it happened.
If you do love your new helux mattress,
keep it and your dignity.
That's why every, yeah,
cause they don't want it.
You don't want to see
your fucking DNA all over.
That's why everyone from
Gq magazine and Forbes,
we're all talking about and
he likes sleep. Go to a Heloc,
sleep.com/burn and get $50 off your order.
That's helix sleep.com/borrow
heavily asleep.com/barb.
All right, last one lastly,
but certainly not leastly.
MMM.
stamps.com everybody, um,
I use stamps.com anytime.
I feel like whoring myself out at the
end of my shows and I want to sell merch.
So I'll send my posters out
using stamps.com I'm a moron
if I can figure it out.
So can you. Evidently postage
rates have gone up again.
That means trips to the post office
aren't even bigger hassle, man,
it's so crowded, but thanks to stamps.com
you don't have to worry about it.
Just use stamps.com to automatically
calculate and print the correct amount of
postage for every letter
of package is sin.
stamps.com brings all the surfaces of
the US Postal Service right to your
fingertips minus the long lines.
They'll send you a digital
scale automatically.
Calculate exact postage stamps.com we'll
even help you decide out of the fucking
blue,
the best class of mail based on your
needs they give you postage just counts.
She can't get it to post office, including
3 cents off every first class stamp.
Anything you can do at the post
office you could do from your desk.
You'll never have to go to the post
office again. Right now my coat,
use my code [inaudible]
for this special offer,
a four week trial and includes a Po
postage and a digital scale. Don't wait.
Go to stamps.com.
Click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburgerthatstamps.com
enter
burns. Sign up today with
stamps.com you'll know that
they have to go to the post
office again. All right, there we go.
Thank Christ. Thank Christ. It's over.
It's over. Um, all right,
let's get into some of
the reads for this week.
I might come up a little short for my
usual hour everybody cause I got the cars
coming at noon. No, Billy has
not fucking done anything yet.
I got to get ready to do this
fucking show. Um, all right.
Oh, you know what? I didn't bring
up. I've been watching of course,
been watching him.
The Celtics and the Bruins and all that
Bruins had a big victory against the
penguins before the all star break.
Granted,
Malkin wasn't playing, but it was still,
we had played a great game and uh,
I have to go down to nothing,
if I remember correctly.
And then the Celtics had been playing
great and a big win against the bucks.
Um,
the fuck did they beat right before that?
I watched like every one
of them I really enjoy.
I can't believe I'm back into NBA
hoop. Um, okay, let me get to, um,
let's get to some of the reeds
here for this week. Uh, oh,
Superbowls celebrations there.
Billy bloodhound after.
Don't ever tell you guys how
much I love a bloodhound. Ah,
the fuck that amount of dogs
that I fucking love. But
I love that dog. You know,
they just got that chilling out vibe.
Any you gotta love a house cause all
you have to do is go and they do it with
you. That's it. That's all I need.
That's all I was looking for this
Valentine's Day. Okay ladies,
if you really love your husband or
your boyfriend, right? Just get,
get them a bloodhound.
Do you know?
And then you can be as crazy
as you want to fucking be.
And all he has to do is just every once
in a while be hanging out with his dog
when you're not around, you know, he
just looks over him. Hey Buddy, buddy.
Right.
It does it with them and it
just makes you feel good.
Maybe it's just me. I don't know. I heard
you mentioned bloodhounds last week.
I know you're not looking
to get a dog anytime soon,
but when you do definitely
consider a bloodhound.
They're unbelievably unbelievable
with real young kids.
I've had to, uh, with
both my kids. Anyways,
my question is if you ever have been to
a Superbowl that's they're great with
kids. That's good to know. Um, by the
way, I keep getting updates with cleo.
She's doing great. She's loving her new
family and everything's awesome with her.
And uh,
I might do a show at some point in the
vicinity of the new people that have the
dog just to visit and say hello.
I Dunno if I should do that or not.
I don't know if it'll
fuck the dog up or a,
I feel just make me sad all over
again. I don't know what, but I still,
you know what the fuck
I just look at like,
that's one of my kids and she's gone off
to college and every once in a while I
check in. How about that?
Anyways, my question is,
have you ever been to a super bowl
or hung around for the week before?
Seeing what all the action is like?
Uh,
my friend asked me if I wanted to go this
year, but I'd rather watch it at home.
I like to watch sports alone. Loved
you. One cowherd. Go pats. Um,
all right, here's the deal.
Uh, I have been to two bowls.
I went to the, uh, the Patriots when
we played the Green Bay packers.
Remember that?
And Brett fat
fucking through that touchdown pass and
then took his helmet off and ran like
half the fucking football field.
Cause his agent told him to do that and
give us a big astronauts smile when you
do it right.
MMM.
That was cool. Just to be like the
first time you go to a super bowl,
if you ever lucky enough to go to one,
there is that thing that you
can't believe you're right.
The thing that basically
most of the United States is
watching that you're there.
Um, and I remember going
down there, it was,
uh,
it was in New Orleans and,
uh, and it was just all the patriots
fans were a bunch of drunks.
And then of course the Wisconsin fans
who are the same level of drunks,
but there's just something about
Wisconsin, like the Midwest,
there's a certain level of common decency,
decency,
I don't know what it is.
I Dunno if they just don't go as hard.
It's weird times you see him though,
then they're more animals than east
coast people. But you know, it's, it's a,
it's an ugly thing, you know? Uh,
east coast sports fans were lunatics.
So we're all up there screaming and
yelling on one of those balconies.
Fucking hammered down on
Bourbon Street. Right. And, uh,
John Kerry walked by
and everybody was yelling that John Kay,
John Kay, what do you think about
the pages? Blah, blah, blah.
And he just looked up and he had
this big phony smile. Like, I,
this is like an act out. You're
not going to get it. But you know,
you know that stupid like old school,
like, you know, let's go get him.
And you liked sort of like do
the, the, you make a fist, right?
And You Kinda, you kinda
act like youth, you know,
maybe throwing a baseball to
home plate. You're like, yeah,
they kind of do one of those, well he
did it. He did it like slow motion.
He made the fist,
he paused and he just went and they
kind of throw it like that really slow.
It was so fucking weird.
He was so detached from his own body
and I'm convinced now after I saw Bill
Clinton do it, that they
just know people are, uh,
taking pictures of them so that they
don't even give a fuck about interacting
with you. It's all about what you look
like in the paper. That was that time.
I told you a long story,
but I ended up Bill Clinton
when he was still president.
This is pre getting impeached and all
that shit. He came down to Boston and uh,
one of my friends wanted to
go down and see the motorcade.
I didn't want to fucking go.
My buddy didn't want to go.
He convinces us to fucking go.
He's going to buy lunch three guy,
five fucking right. So we fucking
go down there. He's all excited.
He just wants to see the motorcade go
by cause he'd saw swatch so much of that
JFK shit. Um, you know,
he just wanted to see a motorcade
and that's like a big deal to see the
presidential motorcade. I can admit
that was pretty exciting to see.
So they start coming down the street and
right before they get to us, we're like,
finally,
here it comes.
He's going to see the motorcade drive
by then we get all fucking go home.
You can buy us lunch. Right.
Right before they got to us,
they made a right turn to go into this
alley right before they got to us,
like, you know, probably
like 50 yards up and like,
oh you gotta be fucking kidding me.
And this dude was so into like no
one politics. He was just going like,
oh don't worry, he's just going to
go in there. It's a woman's college.
He usually speaks on average
from 50 to 65 minutes.
I'll go run and get us some, you know,
a couple slices of pizza, whatever.
So we go fine.
So he fucking takes off and we're standing
there and all of a sudden the secret
service starts walking down the street
telling everybody we were up against
those little police little sorts things.
Sounds get your hands up.
He ends up in the morning.
Kade starts driving w who's
walking down the street?
Fucking Bill Clinton with Ted Kennedy
and somebody else. Ted Kennedy was first.
I think I already told this story dude.
His fucking head,
I swear to God was the size
of like a fucking safe.
I've never seen a head that big of my
life. Like I literally went to like, yeah,
both your hands up so the secret service
could see your hand and it was just
sorta high fiving people.
Um,
can I say walk by remembering that Bill
Clinton comes by and every time like,
oh to President Bill Clinton
and he wasn't saying anything.
He just had both his hands up.
He was slowly walking and just
imagine smiling with your mouth open.
Like yeah, like you were doing
that. But your face was just frozen.
He was just walking past all of us doing
that and everybody was yelling to him.
Everybody was saying stuff and he
did not say anything to anybody.
He just had that Ah, fucking look
on this face with both his hands up.
He looked like a fucking crazy person.
But then the next day,
the front page of the paper,
you see the guy and he's on the
front page of paper like Ah,
and it looked like we were
all having a great time.
I thought there was something wrong with
them. Also, I will tell you right now,
dude, these softest fucking
hands of any guy ever,
ever, he has not done a fucking days
work of manual labor in his life,
baby stuff. Now that I have a
daughter, baby soft fucking hands.
That's how it gets the ladies.
That's what it is.
He puts one of those soft
baby hands on your shoulders.
It takes out a cigar and it
is game set match. So anyways,
he fucking does this shit.
Then they jumped in the car
and then they fucking leave.
Everybody's freaking out and then then
it's just over and people just start to
walk away and leave.
Okay.
All of this took less
than like 38 seconds.
Okay.
Because the secret service was not going
to have to present and exposed to the
public for that long. Um, so anyways,
he jumps in the car, they
leave everybody's like,
like high off of, Oh my God,
I shook the president's hand.
Hoe Pig was Ted Kennedy's head.
That takes about a minute for
people to be like, what the fuck?
And then people just start walking away
and then like 15 seconds after that,
my buddy comes walking up,
the dude who wanted to see all of it
and he just sees everybody has left.
I remember he was biting into a slice
of pizza and he kind of stopped his bike
and he just looks over and he
goes, I missed it, didn't I?
And I just looked at him and I felt bad.
I was like,
I shook his hand and he
goes, no, you didn't.
And then my buddy was a total pothead,
was galloping around sideways,
like in a circle, just screaming. I said,
ah, that was such a fucking
sad quiet ride home.
And we would try not to fucking laugh.
We just started laughing after awhile
and he just refused to believe it.
But the details we had,
he knew that it was fucking true.
And then the next day in the paper
he saw, cause we saying like, dude,
he wasn't saying anything. I'll
never forget that. He just was like,
ah,
but without like that said noise
he should have been making,
but he wasn't making that noise.
He just had his mouth open with his
fucking hands up in the next day.
In the paper though, he looked like
a champ. The man looked like a champ.
All right. Um, Jesus,
I was a long way to go.
What was I talking about the first
time I went to Superbowl? Yeah.
So we went to it and uh,
Bill Parcells fucked us over that year
cause that was his whole fucking stupid
thing like you will be cooked to do you
get a little bit below the groceries
because what's his face?
Robert Kraft overruled him and
said you should take Terry Glenn.
Okay.
And fucking bill Parcells ego
couldn't fucking handle that. Right.
And then he proceeds to tell the team
that he's leaving and then he put his
fucking house up for sale before we even
played the Goddamn game was one of the
most selfish things. If
that's true, that's the no,
that's the room of what the fuck happened.
And then, you know what kills me?
He fucking goes to coach every place else.
He goes to coach.
Who does he bring along with them?
Terry Glenn.
Okay.
Unreal. Unreal. But whatever. Um,
let's plow ahead here. Uh Oh.
And then the second time I went,
I went to the Patriots versus the
ramps and we won that game obviously.
And uh, when it last second and
then I was just like, you know what,
every time the Patriots go,
I'm going to go to the super bowl.
So the next time we played, which was
either against the panthers or the eagles,
I can't remember. I
think the panthers, um,
I was going to go, but the next day, um,
I had like a six or 7:00 AM call
time to do that Chappelle show,
sketch a world series at dice
as the first time I met Charlene
Murphy and all those guys.
And so there was no way I could go and
I was, you know, it was all upset like,
Oh man, I'm going to miss the game and
blah blah blah. But I got to tell you
that Sunday night when the game was
over and in, the Patriots won, you know,
and I was sitting on my futon and my
fucking poor excuse for a one bedroom in
New York City.
I remember when the game was over.
I've watched it with a couple of
friends and they were leaving,
the game was over and I still had like
two grand in my pocket cause that's
basically back then what you were
looking at drop and like if you could get
tickets,
we'd like 1500 bucks plus the hotel and
all the travel and everything was gonna
be another 500 bucks.
The end of the game when I still had
two grand in my pocket, I was just like,
yeah, you know what? This is
better. I went, I saw him lose.
I know what that feels like.
I went,
I saw him when I saw him when
their first one in the last play.
It's never going to get better than that.
I'll go again some day when I have a kid.
So some day my daughter,
if she wants to go, I'll take her.
But um, um, if you've never been,
I would definitely go to, it's
worth going one time. But you know,
I was kind of all set back.
This is back when I still just
had the regular square TV.
Forget about the flat screen now with
the surround sound and all that shit.
I don't know. Plus, I don't know.
I just like watching the game rather
than a, you know, I don't like everybody.
All that shit talk and when
your team loses or if you win,
watching your fans talking
shit to other people,
it's just like we didn't have anything
to fuck it. Do it, do with it, right? We,
they got lucky or we get fucked.
What are you going to do? All right.
Paranoia or legit worry. Um, okay.
Uh, hey. Hey, Bill. Birla check.
Uh, congratulations on your new
baby. Huge fan of the podcast.
I'm a 30 year old naturalized citizen who
immigrated from South Korea when I was
10 as an immigrant and
now a proud American. Um,
I'm writing to you in regards to the
current state of messy affairs going on at
the White House. Why do you
guys ask me this shit? You know,
I'm just a comedian, or am I,
I'm going to solve this problem.
Do you still think that hill dog would
have been just as bad as our current
president? Uh, with Trump's reaction?
I'm not so sure anymore.
Hillary might've been corrupt,
as you mentioned in your previous podcast,
but I believe she would not
have taken such a radical,
brash action based on
intolerance and hatred.
Yeah.
I'm not to that level,
but they're going to keep the war's going.
You haven't noticed cycle.
Obama said he was going to end the wars.
He was going to shut down Guantanamo.
None of them did it.
Yeah.
They're not going to do it or I can't
get into this type of shit. I look,
if you believe that,
that this government,
the governments act on what
is right for people, you know,
rather than money.
Everybody,
everybody passed a certain
level moves on money. That's it.
Same thing in my business. Okay.
Why don't they make better movies?
Because they want to make money.
Why? There's so many cliches,
whether there's so many shitty wants.
It's the same fucking thing. Um,
do I think Hillary would do
something like that? No, I do not.
I don't think that she would
do something like that,
which you do a bunch of other evil things.
My point in all of that shit, okay.
When the amount of shit that Trump got
during the election about being evil in a
horrible fucking person,
I never disputed any of that.
But everybody was acting like
Hillary was a good person.
I say to that she wasn't,
and I was trying to get people
to look at other options,
which nobody's going to do
because they just go, oh,
that's a waste of a vote because
you're not going to win anyway.
So my thing with the American voters
is you get exactly what you fucking
deserve. If you don't have the
balls to not fucking to do,
not vote for the,
the,
the representative of the Republican and
the Democrats who've been fucking you
over since the day you've been born.
And try to get outside of this and try
to pick somebody from a different fucking
party that actually wants to call
out bankers and calls out a corporate
corruption and deregulation and
pharmaceutical companies and fucking,
uh,
genetically altered food.
All of that shit that never gets
fucking brought up with the fucking,
the two guys who were,
you know,
the man or the woman or the two guys
usually that are in the fucking, the,
the showdown between the
Republican and Democrat.
You get what you fucking deserve.
So this whole fucking thing now,
because Trump's such a colossal fuck up,
which everybody already knew.
Okay. Um, for you now look at
Hillary being like, well, you know,
it's like you're looking two serial
killers and Hilary Barry's the bodies,
you know, fucking under a house and Trump
leaves him out in the fucking street.
Therefore you'd rather have Hillary.
I mean, if that's, I don't know.
Okay.
But I, I can honestly tell you, you know,
just my own feelings that
she's not a good person.
Trump is not a good person there too,
horribly selfish fucking people.
And I think a lot of people got caught
up in the fact that with Hillary's
fucking genitalia and the
whole thought of, Oh my God,
if there's a woman president,
what does that mean for fucking women?
It's just like every president
in my lifetime has been a guy.
What does that meant for me
as a guy? Nothing. It doesn't
mean anything like that.
That's like that disease in my business.
When you're a struggling artist and
then all of a sudden you get a manager,
an agent, you start thinking,
when I could put my feet up,
I don't have to work anymore. Yeah, you
do. You're always gonna have to work.
You know why?
Because nobody gives a fuck about you.
And I hate to be so fucking bleak, but
it's the truth. Nobody gives a shit.
What Trump is doing is fucking
horrible. It's not surprising. It isn't.
In a weird way.
It's actually causing a bunch of people
to rally and push back against him.
He's so fucking radical that I
don't think he's going to survive.
He's going to do a bunch of fucked up
shit to like the midterm elections and
he's going to be so fucking on a hand
that people just going to run all the way
to the other side of the boat.
That's what always happens the same
way after eight years of Bush, oh,
let's all now let's all run over to the
guys with the blue ties and the Blue
Bras and you still get fucked, and then
everybody runs over to the other side.
So whatever.
I'm trying not to be preachy here,
but like you kind of get what you deserve.
If you're going to go through the insanity
of continuing to vote for whoever the
Democrats or the Republicans are
going to give you at that level,
and you're not gonna,
you're not gonna start at least voting
for these other people to encourage more
people to run outside of those two
fucking parties. Other than that,
I don't know what to tell you. All right.
I'm done ranting here. Anyways. He said,
I remember on Conan you said everything
will be the same under Trump.
I really hope to God that you are
right, dude. You know something.
I'm getting so much shit for that
Conan thing. You know something.
Next time there's an election like that,
you go on the day after the fucking thing
and try to find some sort of a fucking
angle,
you know,
like it's my fault the day after
the election that I say that,
that Trump gets in. Okay. Everything
has been the same under Trump.
For a guy like me and for most fucking
people, if you're Muslim, yeah,
you're fucked. That absolutely
fucking changed. Okay.
But they were not showing those people.
They were showing a bunch
of white women crying.
That's what the fuck they were showing.
You know? And then they go, oh,
the fucking planned parenthood and all
of that type of shit. I mean, I don't,
I don't fucking know.
I mean like,
I think people fucking hate Trump and for
whatever reason they want to yell at a
comedian. So continue
to yell at me. You know,
I told you they were both pieces of
shit, but you know, after the election,
I don't know.
I just thought a lot of the screaming
and yelling and fucking crying was,
was a little much.
Yeah,
it was a little fucking much.
I understand you disappoint but crying.
It's just one so fucking pathetic.
All right.
Okay.
You don't like the guy do what the
fuck he can to fight back against them.
You don't just fucking breakdown crying
like somebody took your toy away.
I Dunno.
Maybe I'm too fucking not on a cynical.
MMM.
But I've gotten so many tweets
you really don't get, yeah,
you get a bug to shit
change when Obama came in,
but did it really fucking change,
you know what I mean?
Cause I guess for me actually true
change what they would tell me.
Where exactly do my
federal income taxes go?
Where does that go? If it goes to
the fucking IRS and they are not,
they are a private corporation of bankers.
They are not connected to the government.
Where does that fucking money go?
Do the people at the upper echelon
of the fucking Federal Reserve,
do they actually even bother paying taxes
considering they're paying themselves?
There's a nationwide heroin epidemic
that people are saying was created by the
pharmaceutical companies,
was not even fucking brought up.
Okay?
They genetically altered our food,
which is evidently so fucked up.
They got to try to force other countries
to do it and they're fighting back
against them because they don't want it.
Inevitably,
it's so fucked up that these people,
they don't even want to be forced to
label food is genetically altered cause
they know people aren't going to buy it.
There's all of that shit,
all of that shit.
Not only did not change under a
president with a blue fucking tie,
it continued to get worse.
So now when a guy like Trump
does something so, so obvious,
now everybody's all, oh my God,
this guy's out of his fucking mind.
Like this last guy.
I mean,
I'm not saying Obama is a bad fucking guy,
but like it wasn't he just continuing
on with the fucking warmongering and all
of that shit. Am I out of my mind? Maybe
I'm out of my mind. I don't know. See,
I don't know bill. Maybe
I'm paranoid, overreacting,
just like those crazy liberal fucks out
there, but I really do feel worried.
It's one of those gut feelings that
simmer deep down into your soul. I mean,
come on. Even Gorbachev just said
the world is preparing for war.
Okay?
Yeah, absolutely. But I don't think
that's because of Donald Trump.
Okay.
I just think he's yet another guy.
And if
they say the world,
okay,
the world is not Donald Trump.
It's a bunch of fucking people.
Okay?
You know what it really is? I don't.
I don't give into fucking hissy fits.
You don't think clearly.
You're breaking down crying and just
screaming that the fucking sky is falling,
falling. Then you're not going
to make any rational decisions.
There's a of groups that
are going to help out those people's at
the airport that you can give money too.
You can do shit like that and you can
give money to them and you can pray to God
that they're actually gonna use it on
him and not use expense accounts and go
out and buy themselves a fucking corvette.
So I don't have any answers,
but I will say this to people.
You got to stop looking,
you know?
Okay.
I Dunno. I Dunno. I Dunno what it
is about standup Comedians, but we,
for some reason,
our get our feet held to the fire more
so than people who are actually in the
governmental positions.
Um,
okay.
You know,
you want to get mad at me because of
what the fuck I said on the day after the
fucking election on Conan, by
all means do that. But, you know,
I bet there was how many of those fucking
women at that women's fucking rally,
how many of them you think actually voted?
You know what I mean?
All it is fucking outrage.
Where were you on election day?
I mean, there's been, there's been people
who've got busted bitching about Trump.
They didn't even fucking vote,
you know, but, uh, whatever,
give me shit because I joked around when
it was like a fucking funeral out here
in Hollywood.
I was just trying to calm people down.
I just see, you know, you see a bunch
of adults crying on television. Yeah,
it's unsettling.
Okay,
this is what it thinks that it happened.
I think this guy is going to go fucking
sideways and then he's going to go
sideways. The midterm elections,
what's going to happen? He says,
just going to get a bunch of fucking
Democrats in there to maybe level this guy
out. But in the meantime
they'll keep deregulate,
deregulating the banks and all of that
other shit. And in the end of the day,
guys like Trump will be able to build a
golf course in a fucking pipeline under
and over any native American
land that they want to.
That's what the fuck they want
to do. Peep, they're so rich,
they find the government to be in
nuisance. That's what the fuck
you're dealing with. And um,
I don't know if that's what I think. All
right, so there you go. And once again,
I don't read or pay
attention, so fuck off. Uh,
and God bless the United
States of America. All right,
advice from a new fellow dead.
Hey Billy boy, congrats to you.
And the lovely Nia on the new baby.
My wife and I welcomed our
first son about five weeks ago.
People would try to give you
too much advice early on,
but I've discovered the only secret,
uh,
you need to know about babies
is that snap suck in zippers.
Rule baby's shit all damn day a.
See you're taking onesies
on and off all day.
He don't need the added frustration of
fumbling with dozens of snaps to get a
one C's. So get onesies with zippers
and that's all you really need to know.
Congrats. And go again and go
fuck yourself. That's a great one.
That's actually great.
I'm going to use that because I dealt
with snaps all last night. Um, all right,
selfish girl friend advice.
Hey Bill, you're gruff.
Okay.
Hey Bill,
you gruff ginger Bollix
I love the podcast. Brutally honest.
It's great. You're like, whoa. Anyway,
I got a girl who most
of the time is great.
Uh, she's really hard, really smart,
really fun. They always start this way,
but every so often she just seems totally
fucking selfish. Most of the time.
I totally mile her Meyer, her ethics
slash morals important. Right? Yeah.
So she's human.
Most of the time she's cool and every
once in a while she's just got this thing
you don't like. Well, we celebrated our
third anniversary yesterday, by the way.
I'm 28, she's 27. We went out to a Sushi
restaurant for a bit of a celebration.
It gets time to pay the bill.
And I say,
I'll pay in cash if she
transfers me her half.
Oh God, Dude. He goes,
from that moment on,
on the night was all silent
treatment till we started arguing.
Then it went back to silence
till we went to sleep. Yeah.
Cause that's that weird thing where
it's like you're celebrating your
anniversary, but for some
reason you have to pay. Um,
yeah. That's where all the feminism
goes out the fucking window right there.
That's always a great sleep when
there's an unresolved issue.
Uh, I'm not even a big believer
in the guy just paying,
I'm not a big believer in the guy
just paying the bill, but okay.
On special occasions it's done. It's the
done thing. So I'll go along with it.
But I didn't this time because the week
before my laptop fucked up and I had to
sacrifice my TV,
my camera's stuff and media center stuff.
I love to make enough cash to get a decent
replacement so I can work slash keep
applying for new jobs.
Also,
I've been between jobs and money's
a bit tight right now. In short,
it's not been a great week.
You'd think she'd be a bit understanding
about it given the circumstances,
but no. Hey, you'll make an all
decent points here. Anyways,
we had a fight about it.
Um, when quiet again,
then we did what we do sometimes and
just let it go rather than either ups or
either of us having to
apologize. Oh, that's not good.
She says the argument was me not
treating her like a lady. I see.
This is his fucking, I dunno, this is
this thing that you can't win as a guy,
you know,
they want to be treated just like a guy
when it's something good is at stake.
But when a bill comes, like
I'm a lady, I say it was about,
it was not about me paying for everything.
I'm up til the bill.
We were having a great time.
I was psyched about a call for a
great job I had gotten earlier.
She was psyched for me.
Then she throws a fucking moody,
like a fucking infant who's toys been
taken away because I want to split the
bill. I don't know, maybe I'm insane.
My friend says it was a school boy error.
I don't think we're kids in a bit,
in a bit of grownup consideration
called for this situation. But anyways,
have at me, if I'm being a
moron, give me both barrels. Um,
dude, uh, all of this shit
that you said to me, you
need to say to her. I mean,
minus the fuck's in some of the
other stuff. Culinary child.
I wouldn't do any of that,
but um,
okay.
You know,
your relationship is going to be a lot
easier if you start communicating. So, um,
yeah,
maybe you could a preface
it with, hey, you know,
I know we're celebrating our anniversary.
I know I'm supposed to pay as a guy,
but I'm kinda tight. Can you blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. I Dunno.
Okay.
I know I just,
okay.
I don't, I don't get all of that
shit wear. Why the guy has to pay.
It's your relationship and the
woman never pays. You know,
if you notice all the advertising,
hey, Valentine's Day's coming up.
It's all about what the
guy has to get the woman.
MMM.
That's something you don't hear
what the fucking woman's March.
Just basically how the male
female relationship is set
up is that the guy should
just be constantly showering her with
money and gifts because she had the
decency to, uh, you know,
spend her time with you.
It's like her time has value.
Yours does not, you know, I
don't get it. It's like, Hey,
I can be fucking doing other things too,
rather than the ones you've
talking about your day.
Same as you've got to listen to me.
It's not our works. Anyways,
cigar recommendation. Hey,
they're a freckle tits.
I had been sober and more importantly
off the cigarettes for over a month now.
Graduations to celebrate this,
I decided to treat myself to a nice
cigar while I watched your new stand up
special on the 31st. Any
recommendations on a good smoke? Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself.
Um,
okay.
Well if you're off cigarettes,
I don't know why he'd smoke a cigar,
but if you're going to, then you don't
have access to a Cuban cigar. Um,
okay.
I like those.
Okay.
The Aurora emeralds.
And I like, uh, this, um,
the Davidoff Nicaraguan adverse,
he turned me on to and the Casa Magna,
the, uh, the torpedo one's got the two
bands, I forget which one it's called.
I like those ones, but I kind of
quit smoking to be honest with you.
I think I'm done with it. I might have
the occasional fucking cigar, but uh,
you know, now that I'm getting life
insurance and it's just like, all right,
I got to get this
nicotine out of my system.
So I can pass the fucking
test and everything.
When I saw the difference in rates,
just even being a passive smoker,
I was just like, wow. Uh,
they obviously know that this means
this shit's gonna fucking kill you.
So it was kind of like, who am I fooling
here if I just cleaned myself up?
So I think I'm kind of done. Like,
I'll smoke a cigar. I'm okay.
Okay.
I don't know. I'll smoke a cigar. What
you suppose towards an actual moment
as opposed to just being like, ah, man,
I always smoked cigars and now I'm kind
of feeling that itch to smoke when saw
smoke one. But anyways, I got to get
running here. I gotta go do Conan.
I'll say some more shit
probably about politics.
And then you guys can now give me shit.
Like I'm the one fucking running things.
I told you a long time ago.
I don't read a that's it.
Go fuck yourselves and I'll
check in on you on Thursday. Bye.