Hey, what's going on is bill burn? It's
time for the Monday morning podcast from
um,
December 17th.
Okay.
2017 all my God.
Only seven more days
till the fucking baby.
Jesus comes down the chimney there.
Whatever the fucking story
is, right. What was the story?
All calm,
all ye beard guys into this fucking barn.
Look at this lid.
Obey.
Be she was Nana ever banged.
Oh,
poor Joseph. What's going
on everybody? How are you?
How did you enjoy your
weekend? That Jab, a good one.
My patriots lost again.
I think they're only going to
win 10 or 11 games this year.
Is it time to hit the panic button?
Um,
yeah.
What are you going to do?
You know,
we had a great run. We had a great
run. This is a trend. Normally this,
this type of play would not,
would not worry me. I, you know,
cause I remember when we lost,
you know,
Romeo chromal and Charlie Weiss and we
lost Thai law lawyer Malloy and fucking
Teddy Bruschi retire and we lost all of
those guys and we built it back up again.
So you know, this time, what do we lose?
We lose, we who'd we lose? We lost a,
you know,
Matt,
Patricia left to go coach the fucking
lines running back to wide receivers,
quarterback left tackle all of that
shit and adds up one year. You know,
two years. That's a lot of people to
lose. But back in the day you'd be like,
all right, you know, all the
draft picks they got for them,
they're going to build this
fucking thing back up again. Right.
Which they always did and they continue
to win and people kept saying the
Patriots had done and they kept
proving them wrong. But now,
I mean Tom is what, 41? Almost 42 is
that what it is or is he 40, almost 41?
Um,
yeah,
it's like do they have time for one more
champion chip run for ring number six
on precedent. I, by the way,
I'm so fucking sick of every time they
show the fucking steal are still like
they got six Superbowls more than
anyone else and they never bring up the
packers.
It's,
the packers have four and they have like
11 NFL titles that for whatever reason,
they don't count NFL titles.
I've been asking this question
cause I'm, I'm big on that. All
right. I'm not saying the Steelers,
not one of the great franchises
or the Super Bowl era. They are,
but what kind of fucking league is around
since the 1920s in 1930s and doesn't
count championships until 1968.
You know, as, as I've stayed
before the Montreal Canadians,
they fucking count championships,
won the Stanley Cup was the size of a
fucking shot glass and the, and you know,
and they beat the fucking Montreal
maroons playing pond hockey.
The fucking Philadelphia Phillies,
one of their world series titles
is from the fucking 1880s.
I didn't think they had baseball gloves.
I don't know what they fuck
they were using as a ball.
Okay.
You know?
Probably like a fucking human skull.
It was so god damn long ago. Um,
those championships are all counted.
I don't understand why,
how nice are people in Wisconsin that
they don't speak up and be like, hey,
not for nothing. Uh, back when
you could, when NFL titles,
the Pittsburgh Steelers were playing.
So,
okay.
We basically been playing the
same amount of time and uh,
as far as I could tell we're,
we're almost like 10
championships ahead of him.
Okay.
Why do they always get all the
glory? I have no fucking idea. I do.
I just don't understand
why NFL titles don't count.
Why don't I Google that? Why
don't I look it up? By the way,
congratulations to the Steelers. Jesus
Christ. That wind was a long time common.
Should've want it fucking last year when
that guy caught the ball and scored a
touchdown and then they said he didn't.
Yeah.
After further review what
she just saw didn't happen.
Replay the down. Alright, there we go.
Let's write this out here.
Why
starts with a w bill?
Why doesn't the NFL count
and F l champ be an ships?
BOMP bomp bomp.
Bomp dude,
why do people ignore pre
Superbowl championships?
Okay,
here we go.
Okay.
Or a team's dark ages.
I don't know what dark age assessed
to do with any of this stuff. Okay.
So this guy goes, I rarely post
on here, but this always irks me.
I'm a fan of the packers,
but I live in the middle of steel,
his country and I get this thrown in my
face all the time that the Steelers have
one six Superbowls.
I throw out the fact that the
packers have one 13 championships.
Okay.
With four of them being super bowls.
Yeah. So they have more than twice then.
Okay.
I get all the time saying no,
they don't count in.
This bothers the crap out of
me. Yeah, it absolutely does.
You basically saying that like all the
champions that came before Superbowl
champions, they're not champions even
though they won a championship. Um,
as a person who was a history major
and who loves the history of the sport,
especially for some Steeler fans,
um,
that NFL history doesn't start at 1970.
It actually store the first two super
bowls were called NFL title Games and AFL
AFL championship games or something.
And then later they were,
they were renamed Superbowl champions.
Um,
Superbowl won a Superbowl too,
I should say.
But the first one that actually was
called a Superbowl as it was happening was
Superbowl three. Uh, anyways, they
ignore or the third AFL NFL title.
Jesus felt we get it.
And he was,
they ignore the fact that the Steelers
were terrible until 1970 also known as
the dark ages of the Steelers.
Uh,
I think they have actually terrible
until about 72 or 73 till they had that
incredible draft. I acknowledged
most of the packers dark ages,
the 50s and posts,
Lombardi and home grim. Uh,
I know it's not all Steeler fans,
but it still bothers the crap out of me.
The question I ponder is in the title.
All right.
So this guy writes,
it's kind of funky since most NBA fans
will count championships before the 76
and be a merger. Oh Dude, you can go big
and go back further than that. With a,
with the Los Angeles Lakers count like
a fucking Ba championship has an NBA
championship.
It was the BA in the NBL and those two
things merge to form the NBA and like the
Minneapolis Lakers, I think one
the first like four NBA titles,
but the year before that they want to a
Ba championship and for some reason that
is counted as an NBA championship.
The Lakers won an NBA title
before the NBA existed.
Explain how that works anyways.
Um,
this isn't going to be a good name.
I wanted something to somebody
who fucking knows something
green bay as much more historical.
I think if someone wants to argue that
the league is totally different now than
the real point of reference isn't 1970,
it's 1994 in the salary
cap was introduced. Yeah.
Why don't you turn it into
your fucking argument.
MMM,
okay.
Mass swarm of lines, browns and
eagles fans. But in all honestly,
it's really frustrating.
Flat out inaccurate when they say the
eagles have never won anything. Yeah.
That's bullshit. Well, this
is from four years ago.
You can't Cherry pick which championship
titles count and which don't.
The name of the trophy is arbitrary.
Uh,
it's not arbitrary at all.
It's,
it has a very specific line in the sand
and it's one that the league itself drew
not friends fans trying to hold
down the eagles and other teams.
The NFL decided nothing pre Superbowl
matters. Yeah. Well that's my question.
Why?
Okay.
Cherry picking would be saying the
eagles are packers pre Superbowl
championships camp but the browns don't.
Arbitrary would be saying
the package packers,
NFL championships count but the eagles
don't just because the NFL only counting
stats and championships and super
bowl one may or may not be fair,
but it's definitely not arbitrary
or cherry picking. All right.
That's all good points but it doesn't
explain why they decided not to decide it.
Why people count. Why do people do, I see
there's a bunch of articles on it.
There's a bunch of articles.
I all these are all chat rooms.
I'm not going to get anywhere with this
next time I do one of these fucking
I, I don't know who. Who would you ask?
Okay.
Is somebody that has got to be somebody
that you asked because this fucking
bullshit that they act like,
you know,
the fucking league is like 70 goddamn
years old and they're acting like the top
of the heap is six measly
fucking championships.
It doesn't make sense at all.
And then, you know something,
if they actually counted NFL titles,
I know the giants won a couple
two and they got four super bowls.
Okay.
And the only thing that I'm
basing this on is that the NBA,
the Nhl and certainly major league
baseball all go back to the 1920s and MLB
goes back to like 1889.
Um,
I dunno,
it's weird.
It's just a weird fucking thing that like
the Patriots have bullied, been good,
you know,
winning championships and 18 for the last
18 years and we're one championship a
wave in 18 years.
We somehow are only one championship
away from being the most successful tied
for the most successful champ NFL team
of all time. That makes no fucking sense.
It makes no fucking sense.
People. Um, anyways,
I miss most of the Patriots Steelers
game. I caught, uh, the first quarter,
first half I basically caught and then,
you know,
I'm a dad now so I had to go to a kid
birthday party and uh, once again,
every time I go to one
of these parties I am so,
feel so blessed that I had a
daughter and not a son. Jesus Christ,
they're fucking lunatics.
Lunatics. I was just like,
I used to be like that.
You go in there with your daughter and
the first thing you're doing you're just
fucking,
you know,
you become like the Dave some Manco and
your kid's like fucking Wayne Gretzky.
Cause you know somebody
is going to do something.
You know somebody is going to throw
a ball, comes flying off a slide,
they have their fucking lunatic.
She was the funniest thing.
I was watching this kid who
has like a little Bobby Hurley.
He's playing this game,
you know,
hitting the ball like using is like both
his arms like intellect in his, his,
his fingers. It'd be bounced the ball
and then use his forearms like a bat,
smash it against the wall and
then stop it with his hand.
And throw it back between his legs,
you know,
all point guards style and you
look like a little Bobby Hurley.
So I was getting a kick out of this kid
who, this kid, this kid, this kid's got,
yeah, he had it, you know what I mean?
Like he had like that competitive thing.
And then at one point he ran over to go
pick up the ball and there was like a
couple of, um, the almost
like, do you know those,
those yoga blocks that help you
if you do not stretchy enough,
they would like that but
were more like cushions.
And someone had made a little seed out
of them and I had kind of been sitting
there like,
oh this is nice.
Some parent did that cause they
didn't want to sit on the hard floor.
And I was standing up when the kid came
over and he picks up the ball and just
sees like two blocks with a bigger block
on top of it and he just kicks it over.
There was no reason to do it,
you know?
And I was really just looking at
that thinking like, like, wow,
did I just see right there in
that moment? Why, why there's war?
Why,
why the world is so fucked up.
Why we don't get along because we're
like literally wired to just fucking
destroy stuff.
And I'll tell you something else.
With all these fucking people out there
who are trying to say that like gender
mmm.
Gender roles are,
are basically taught to kids.
Uh, yeah. From what I
see when I've seen it,
these kid birthday parties that he's just
not, it's not even remotely the case.
Okay.
Boys are fucking lunatics.
Anything they can pick up,
they're going to throw anything.
They can just knock over and break.
They're going to do it.
The girls are like sitting
down like behaving themselves.
I can't necessarily say shake
sharing after a certain age.
They're not really sharing.
But there definitely like
their interactions with boys. It's just
kind of like, what the fuck was that?
Like they just kind of this sitting there
with a toy and a boy just runs up and
rips it out of their hands and you
just see them looking at it like, like,
you know, if you asked me for
it, you know, I, I would've
given it to you, you know?
Okay.
So it's going to be interesting with
all of these families out here that are
trying to prove, I might be wrong,
but as far as me just sitting there,
it's just boys are absolute
fucking lunatics loaded taste.
I'll tell you last year,
and we had my daughter's a birthday party,
they came over and immediately it'll
pick it up, gravel in the yard,
throwing it down on,
thrown in at fucking cars,
climbing up on shit every two
seconds. Hey, get down from there,
get down from there.
You know,
girls would just go into like the doll
house or pick up a toy and they would
just sit there and play
with it. Um, beyond,
beyond, more mature than the
boys. The boys, I swear to
God, it's like, it's like, uh,
I can't say puppies still like,
um,
do you know after a dog is just afterwards
a dog and it knows how to run their
like that age, you know where they're
going to go get sprayed by a skunk.
Um, yeah, fucking hilarious. But um,
we had a great time and they had like all,
like we went out to this place of good
friends of ours and it was at one of
those parties. It wasn't at the
house, it was like an a destination.
So there was one room that had all these
games and after you're done with that
game,
then you go into another place with a
bunch of other games and then in the end,
you know, all the kids get food, you know,
and they're sitting there eating pizza
and shit. All of a sudden the cakes,
comedy and you know, you
know, just the meltdowns. A
common, everybody's like going,
all right, all right. Trying
to time it, they had the cake.
We sang happy birthday
to starting to whine.
I feel look like if we leave now,
the meltdowns only going to happen
like halfway, uh, on the way back.
But fortunately my daughter
loves music, so, uh,
whenever we drive home, whenever
she starts like flipping out, uh,
me and Nia just starts singing to her,
you know, he just stuck. Ah, wait. Oh,
the itsy bitsy spider or
the, we'll say, um, uh,
what's the other one?
Uh,
the wheels on the bus go round and
round that when she likes Jesus Christ.
Who's calling already? It's, it's early
in the morning. People who cook at this B,
who could this costs off? Fuck, I
got to take this, hang on. Hello.
I'm back. I just said hello, like I
just clicked back to you guys. Um, yeah.
Anyways,
we just sing all these frigging songs
and then she wants to sing along with us
in themes is shows, you know, par, par,
par puppy dog pals. She loves
that Shit. I'll tell you the show.
I've been talking about it.
I just don't fucking like it.
I just don't like that fancy Nancy.
I just don't like every,
every show.
She's like being a Douche in self
involved and like totally shallow.
And then she allegedly learns a lesson
and then the next show she's just a jerk
again.
There's like no growth
whatsoever in this person.
You know what I mean? I mean, Van Porino
always wants to go back to Transylvania,
but she's not hurting anybody.
She just gets a little bummed out every
once in a while that the other kids
aren't blue light car. Right?
But fucking fancy Nancy,
this little ginger broad over there,
dude,
she's hanging out with a girlfriend,
right? And they're sitting there,
they're going to do a fucking dance.
And she's like,
I'm going to be the sun and
you'll be a wrong to be a rainbow.
You be the son and a friend Zach. I want
to be a peacock. She goes, yeah, but yeah,
you can't because it's a rainbow and
a peacock doesn't make any sense.
It's gotta be the sun and the rainbow. And
she goes, well, I want to be a peacock.
And she's like, look, you gotta
be, you gotta be right, Jen.
Say that. But that's the subtext. So then
they have this big fucking falling out,
you know, cause she's being a cunt again,
like she has every fucking episode,
every episode she's into like,
like,
what's the fanciest stuff coming up
with a clubhouse that's just her and
exclusively her own, you know,
she, I swear to God, Dude, God,
I'll tell you this right
now in the animated world,
God blessed the animated man
that marries her someday.
Fucking lunatic. Fucking, that's going
to be one of those fucking chicks, right?
He just buy him everything under the
every designer keeping up with the car
Dashi and fucking love
bracelet you could possibly do.
And then in a fucking end
when she's leaving, yeah.
And you're sitting there going, but I
bought you all this stuff. She'll be like,
I never wanted that.
I just wanted to kidnap action.
Uh,
I swear to God,
this is going to be a first 48
with an adult fucking fancy dancy.
If she doesn't get her act together,
she is.
She's going to drive somebody to do
something crazy because she doesn't learn
any fucking lessons. And she's
really shallow. You know,
she's a little sociopath. I just,
I just don't like sending the end.
She does some fucking dance to
apologize to a friend. And once again,
a friend's going to be friends with her
again rather than just being like, hey,
you know something, I've been on
this ride before you little red cunt.
I'm not fucking doing this again.
But it's like literally teaching
somebody how to stay in a dysfunctional
relationship every fucking episode.
At least the ones on paying attention to,
I just don't like it,
you know,
I don't be that person just sitting
there say they don't have your kid watch
step, but like, you know,
I don't put my foot down too much
as a parent with my wife. Um, well,
who's kidding?
Who would I put it down?
But it's not listened to because it's
the dad foot and nobody gives a shit.
Nobody gives a shit about the debt.
It's all about the mom foot.
The mom says it ain't happened in anymore.
It ain't happening anymore.
The Dad says that they,
people just, they just, yes,
them to death and then the next
day it's like, why is she watching?
Why is she watching carrot top here again.
Huh?
Okay.
Why is she watching this stuff bill?
It's fine. It's just a cartoon.
It's just, it's just what you
wanted. It's just what you wanted.
I don't like that show. Um,
anyways. Puppy dog pals,
that's where it's at. Okay.
There are a couple of pals.
They're trying to help out somebody
in need, you know what I mean?
And you know something and yeah,
Bob goes through a lot of little problems,
but he's, he's not hurting anybody
salted. The Earth Guy, you know,
probably could do some squats.
It owes shoulder's a little too broad
for this little skinny legs. I don't,
I don't know what's going on there,
but other than that,
I don't have a problem with it, you
know? So anyways, plowing ahead.
I watched Liverpool versus man United.
I did watch that game.
I saw a little bit of the
dolphins, Vikings. Um,
how about the browns?
About the fucking Cleveland Brown's
got a chance to make the playoffs.
This is really going to be a fun year if
my patriots are not going to win it to
share. Okay. What's
looking like that? Not,
I just hope they lose the fucking first
round just so I can enjoy all these
other goddamn teams that are going
to be in it. It's going to be a,
okay,
it's really going to be exciting.
And all of a sudden, you know,
the rams have lost a couple this
showing that they're not invincible,
that fucking challenges are coming on.
You know, there's a fucking chance someone
was saying to me yesterday that, that,
that they could actually be the NFC and
AFC championship games could both be
played in Los Angeles.
I Dunno about that.
Cause the charges get
home field advantage.
I don't know if they could do that
mathematically at this point. Uh, by,
I apologize, I'm music better, better up
on the sports, but uh, I just, you know,
I got the kid now, so, you
know, it's only a kid once,
something has to give and it's
not going to be her. So, um,
I did watch Liverpool versus Man United
Liverpool scored the first goal and was
really carrying the play.
And then all of a sudden,
man United just really had possession
of the ball, um, in Liverpool's and,
and, uh, kind of seem like basketball
or it's like, you know, to game a runs,
you know.
And uh,
at one point I said something
when I was just like,
we got to get the fucking ball back.
I said, we, and I was like, ah, Shit.
It's just something else I care about.
I don't totally care about it,
but I do find it interesting
to watch and I'm actually
starting to get into the game.
And I remember back in the day when I
would hear the crowd applaud when no goal
was scored, but they would just applauding
the pressure you were putting on.
I started like, without thinking about
it, doing that yesterday, I was like,
I fuck,
here we go again.
I'm gonna start giving a shit
about something else. Um, anyways,
but I'm actually going to go on,
I should go online now and see
if Liverpool has a fucking game.
I know I'm going to be
out there at some point.
That would be sick if I went out
there and no, I'm not going to sing.
You're never going to be alone or
whatever the fuck they sync beads.
Some douchey watch three games and all
of a sudden we're going to go buy a scarf
and stand there. Like I fucking bled
there colors. I'm not doing that.
I'm just a fucking,
let's see here.
Just a fucking Newbie fan here. All
right. What do we get? billboard.com oh,
by the way,
did I mention I'm going to be
in Europe January 4th through?
Where are we? January 4th
through the 13th uh, alright,
Liverpool. I'm there on the 26 now here's
the interesting thing. That's the first.
That is the first date on that tour,
which means if they have a
fucking game on the 25th at home,
there's a chance there is a chance I
could actually go to that fucking game,
right?
Liverpool fucking schedule.
All right.
What do we got here?
Okay,
come on. Come on one fucking
time. Work out for me.
One 19 to 14 to 27 it looks
like it's an away game,
right? Where the fuck did they just
play? Yeah, they just played man,
man, man United. Right. Oh
wait, no, they got a home game.
12:00 PM the day of my show,
the fuck Gotti.
I'm going Liverpool Verse Watford.
I'm going to fucking go.
They got one verse, man.
You not all their ad in
Manchester on the 24th.
All right. Don't get greedy built.
Don't get greedy. You know what I mean?
Don't get greedy.
I'm,
I'm going to see if I can go to that
one on the 27th it says 12:00 PM though.
Wait, is, but it's probably going to
be at night. I'm thinking 12:00 PM uh,
Liverpool time, but it's not going to
be, is it? It's going to be my time.
They're eight hours ahead.
That doesn't make any fucking sense.
The games at 10 at night,
maybe that's an east coast
time and it's at seven.
I don't know if that would be at five.
I don't fucking know.
I'll figure something out. Jesus Christ
is going to be nobody at my fucking show.
We would love to have gone
bill. Um, all right. No booze,
everybody. Oh, both freckles came close.
He fucking came close a couple of times.
He's 22 days in. Can he make the
entire month? I'm right there, man.
I'm right fucking there by just
make it through Christmas Day.
All have gone 31 days and I'll have my
own sober October from November 21st
through a
December 25th. That'll be,
yeah, that's six days, right?
25 and six is 31. So longest.
God Damn. Once you can have, uh,
tell you it's going pretty good. It's
going pretty great. What's wild night?
And I have really looked at the bottles.
I was like,
do I really want to
start doing that again?
I don't want to fucking do that again.
I got to stay in shape.
I'm going to be taping a special next
year. Right. I got stay in fucking shape.
All right, let's, let's read,
uh, only a couple of fucking
ad reads this week. Okay.
Ah.
[inaudible] the Patriots
fuck aid loads to do to,
to be ids. Mia. These don't
turn to the fuck aid bows.
They had a great run Brady years old,
but he's not the fault.
That's what I'm told. It's the
other cons, not doing their job.
He's still throwing for 300 yards a
game even though he's 41 years old.
Tom Brady is still the shit.
He's the human version of me undies.
All right.
Um,
me undies uses the coveted
micro modal modal fabric,
which is three times softer than cotton.
If you never felt this fabric,
get ready to experience pure
bliss in underwear forum,
you can also get a style that is
perfectly suited for you or that special.
Someone seriously,
these fun undies would be
a great stocking stuffer.
But why stop at undies?
Me undies has cozy lounge pants and
onesies in that same super soft fabric,
perfect for wearing Christmas morning.
Me undies has a great offer for my
listeners for first time purchasers.
When you purchase any me undies,
you get 50% off and free shipping order
by 1216 for free shipping in time for
Christmas crunched for time. You can't
go wrong with the [inaudible] gift card.
This is a no brainer. Get, uh,
get 50% off a pair of the most comfortable
undies you will ever put on to get
your 50% off your first pair of free
shipping and 100% satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr.
That's me undies Dotcom.
Slash. Burr. Ah, right. Oh,
stamps dot. You know what?
I don't have any stocking
stuffer from my wife. Huh?
How do I take the stalking and I
stuffed it in her mouth? The Oh,
Jesus stamps.com. As you
know, the holiday season,
Dolby dooby do,
um,
are the busiest time of the fucking year,
especially at the post office.
stamps.com brings all the service of the
US post office right to your desktop.
Buy and print official US postage
from any letter, any package,
any class of mail using your
own computer and printer,
then mail and the mail carrier picks it
up. Print postage anytime of day, anytime,
any day, any time. stamps.com is always
open. stamps.com not only saves you time,
it saves you money.
Stamps Dot Khan come and help you print
the right amount of postage every time.
Never overpay again.
Ooh,
yeah.
Remember that?
Is that little Asian girl acting like
she's a black woman on a 70 sitcom? Okay.
Okay.
Um,
how does she not get in trouble?
A stamps.com helps you print the
right amount of postage every time.
Never overpay again. With stamps.com
you get discounts on posted.
She can't even get at the post office
with all the time and money you'll save.
stamps.com is the best gift you can
give yourself this holiday season.
I use stamps.com because, uh, you know,
I don't like going to the post
office either. If I don't have to.
I send out all my posters.
Um,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com service
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus postage
and a digital scale without longterm
commitments.
Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburrthatstamps.com
[inaudible]
a righty.
Um, oh, you know what I made for
the first time? I was second time.
First Time I fucked him up.
I made some chocolate chip cookies.
I'm not good at making the cookies. And
this time they finally came out. Right.
Cause they made three different batches
where I just, uh, often the same batch.
I did three different cooks of them.
I only had like one cookie sheet
and I had to like, you know,
my recipe called for only
half a tablespoon of a, of
a dollop. And I was like,
that seems really small.
I didn't get how much they spread out.
It's like reverse bacon or bacon,
like all shrivels up,
like the cookie dough spreads out. So, um,
my first one that I made it like the
whole sheet looked like a giant cookie and
I was like, all right,
that's not the way to do it.
And then the next one will like medium
size and then I coat sign it kinda had
like the smaller ones, but
um, they were damn good.
And I use my little kitchen aid
thing, you know, second pair of hands,
not free advertising.
I just love that fucking thing.
I love when that thing's turning and
I'm over in the counter doing something
else. Um, but I learned
from the expert. My mother,
she told me, uh, you know, she's like,
well how did you do it? You know,
I'm like, well, you know, I put
them in the kitchen out. She's like,
you got to fold the flower
and you can't use that.
He can't use the kitchen aid thing. You
want to fold it. And she's trying to say,
cause it, uh, you get some
air in there. I don't know.
Somebody else was saying
it has to do with gluten.
I have no idea because my cookies
seemed a little bit runny yet crispy.
And every oven is the diff is
different. So I used the classic, um,
our version, my family's version
of the classic toll house
recipe and chocolate chip cookies
were invented by a couple of ladies in
Massachusetts at this place,
this like toll house tavern
or something like that.
And they would use like a
semisweet chocolate chip.
And that's what I always use.
But I got, you know, my wife told me that
she likes milk chocolate. So I said, fine.
So I put the milk chocolate ones in
there and everybody said they didn't say
they were good.
They were like,
this is the best goddamn chocolate
chip cookie I ever tasted.
So maybe I'll do a cooking
video on that shit,
but I can't give away my family recipe
so I don't know how to fucking do it.
And having said that,
I fired up my big green egg for
the first time in a long time,
and it had these two fucking rib
eyes with like literally the fucking,
uh,
the rib bone sticking out.
You could have fucking brain somebody
with that when they were frozen. And, um,
I got impatient with my green egg.
I was told to 50 with indirect heat.
It went up to like three 10.
So I was like, all right,
I'll leave it in there for like 40,
45 minutes instead of doing the full hour.
And I then I reverse seared
it when I was on the stove.
I should only done that for a minute
and ended up being under salted and
overcooked. Two beautiful pieces
of meat and I fucked it up. Um,
it just really fucking,
it just,
it made me sick cause those things
where my freezer for a while,
but I still ate it and a, I will
not waste it. I'm going to eat,
I'm going to remember next
time to be more patient.
That's the biggest thing
with the big green egg.
You gotta be fucking patient and I'm
just not cause that thing is the PR,
it was the shit it, we'll just stay at
the temperature you want. And I just,
you know, it was getting late. We
were coming back from the party.
I just wanted to put them on here that,
you know,
when you put it on and uh,
ended up fucking him up.
So anyways, you, you, you know,
I think Alannis Morissette said it best
when she said, uh, what, did she say?
Something at pot of being ironic?
No, she said you live, you learn
use update. You let, um,
why did she ever have a
really good follow up to that,
that jagged little pills that,
cause she got it all out.
It's almost like she should have saved
some of the anger for like the next album,
you know, like, yeah, but like you,
when you were watching a baseball playoff
and your team scores 11 runs, you know,
when's like 11, two, and as it scoring
like runs now by eight, nine, 10,
there's always some baseball fan be like,
save it for tomorrow night.
Why you scored all of them now
maybe she should have done that.
I don't know baby bill.
Maybe you ought to put out a hit fucking
album before you criticize somebody
else's fucking, uh, one of the albums of
the decade. Right? Jagged little pill.
Fucking rich. Yeah. Balls. Huh?
His scrotum there, whatever the
fuck it's, I don't know how it goes.
I don't even know.
The anatomy aren't your
balls and you scroll down the
same thing. I have no idea.
You know what I mean? And
it's like, it's a snare drum,
but the things underneath
it to call this the snares,
it's very confusing
sa with path,
you know, can you imagine a guy if
you wrote a fucking song like that,
I remember every breath you take
they will like to sunk. It's,
it's this guy's a stalker.
She puts out a sign.
Ha ha ha.
Sounded like a flood.
She's looking in the guy's fucking house.
Terrifying fucking song.
And of course when women do it isn't,
she's strong and brave.
Ha Ha.
Poisoned your morning tea.
Anyways,
plowing ahead here. Guess what
I'm doing today at 12 noon. Uh,
I'm going to go fly a helicopter there.
I flew Saturday for the first
time since the end of October.
Uh, and I had the best fucking time.
Flew great pickups and set downs.
We'll fucking is great
as they've ever been. Um,
and I had taken a lot of time off.
Dare I say I'm getting fucking good at it.
I landed on top of a building,
which I've never done before.
Just fucking awesome man.
I felt like I was in some like
fucking copper procedural show,
you know, where is the patient
always coming? And now, you know,
the beginning is to play in the opening
credit poem by, by Dubai and was
a fucking freckled pilot. Right. But
he's almost fucking see you through.
Um,
it was always really intimidating because
I felt like it would always be like
really windy and stuff like that, but uh,
I'm a chump. Sure. It could have been,
but it was kind of perfect. Conditions
came in, there was plenty of room,
there wasn't anything sticking up. I
always felt like when you would go there,
it was just sort of like,
um, you know, I've, I've had,
I've had to land those things on a,
I don't even know what you them,
it's like, rather than just
setting it down on the ground,
there's like a Little Square Hella pad
that you land that's actually sitting on
the ground and you have
to be way more accurate.
Then you start getting in your head, you
stirring the pot, you get a little wind,
what the fuck's going on?
And then the ski instructor has to come
on the controls with you and then your
friends in the back don't respect you as
much. You know, it's one of those deals.
Speaking of friends in the back,
I'm going to be flying with my instructor
and uh, and Joe Rogan's coming along.
Uh, I've been trying to figure out some
time when we could actually do that.
We finally have a little bit of time and
our schedules could have fly with him.
And then on Wednesday I'm going to be
doing the Joe Rogan experience podcast and
we'll be talking about the flight.
Maybe you have some video hopefully or
whatever. It's going to be a great time.
So please tune into that.
And I will be promoting a season three
if f is for family and of course the uh,
the Patrice O'neil standup comedy benefit,
which is happening February
19th, 2019. Trying to get last,
the rid of the last couple of
hundred tickets on Joe's podcast.
I'm all right with that.
I've already read the, uh,
the advertising. Let's, let's read
a little bit of the questions here.
Let's read some of the questions. I got
to get back to the fucking gym, man.
I've been being Mr Mom, you know,
now that I've been off the road,
you know, cause I, I, you know, want to
be with my kid and every morning I just,
you know, there's always
a reason, you know,
not to go to the gym where I'm just like,
or I could sit here and read her a book,
you know,
or we could go to the playground
or I could take her for a walk,
you know, or I could watch a driver, a
little electric car around and then, oh,
cleo audio is in town and my
trainer who now owns the dog,
you know, whenever he comes into
town, he brings her. And uh,
it was awesome going on.
A couple of hikes with her and stuff.
I've fucked in love that dog, but she
looks great if anybody's concerned.
And she has a dog friend now,
which I didn't have the skill set to
make her comfortable around another dog.
So she's like a,
she's living her best life.
So she really is like an amazing
story where she was abandoned,
you know, by the La River.
She had all these issues.
My one of my wife's friends found her,
my wife took her in,
we kept her for eight years.
She lived in the lap of luxury.
It got too crazy, you know, she
bit, one of my friends, you know,
all of this stuff usually ends with a
pit bull getting put down and this dog
just keeps going to an even better
situation and now it has like,
you know the dog is like 10 years
old now. So I mean it's in, you know,
probably the final four or five years
of its life and its going to live,
you know, now has a best friend
you know to hang out with.
It's really awesome.
And I still get to see her once
every couple of months and um,
you know, so I'm happy because I felt
like when I got that dog I felt like a
responsibility. Like this thing
is, is going to live a full life.
It's not going to get put down. I didn't
anticipate that. I'd have to, you know,
give her away to somebody else.
But I made sure that when I did,
she had a good home, so I feel like I
did the right thing, you know? All right.
Anyways, that's my little
Rni a great guy. You know,
talking about myself. Very
Instagram influenced, uh,
Bosnia show come to Bosnia.
You lying ginger. Fuck all.
I thought I was going there. You're
fucking dose. Um, I'm fuck kee kid.
Jump on a fucking train.
Let me know.
I'm going to find out how long have
these fucking assholes over there.
I'm literally going to Estonia and Latvia.
Like,
how much more do I have to fucking
do for you guys? Come to Bosnia.
All right, well, it was Bosnia.
It's find out, isn't it?
Just south east of, of, of
have a prog. It's not
that far, is it? Isn't it?
Just like a fucking train ride away?
Let's see here.
Okay,
let's see how close.
I mean,
I'm only flying from the
other side of the globe.
You can't get on a plane for a
couple of fucking hours. All right,
so there's Bosnia.
Okay.
All right. That's what Jesus that, so
it's a hell of a fucking ride. My fault.
Where else am I going to be?
Okay.
I'm going to be in Vienna. All right,
let's see. Let me see. Something.
Bosnia to Vienna.
Yeah.
Travel. Uh, just say distance, right?
I'm the worst with Google and shit.
Bosnia to to be in a distance.
Okay.
Eight hours and 32 minutes.
Holy Shit. That's a fucking
drive. All right, my fault.
I'm starting to understand your argument.
Uh,
okay.
Plane ride.
Let's see how long this is.
Okay.
It's an hour and 15 minutes by plane.
Jesus Christ. Like how much can that cost?
That's like flying from here to Vegas.
She jumped on southwest for like 80 bucks.
All right.
Yeah.
Good Lord. I apologize.
Next time sir. Or ma'am.
Okay.
Or, or, or transgendered person,
whatever the fuck you are.
I will try and get to Bosnia. All
right. I thought it was going there.
You lie. And Ginger. Fuck, isn't it weird?
Somebody from that part of the
world to be judging somebody. Um,
I'll try to get my ass down there.
All right now here he comes, all the,
all this shit about Europe.
Now it would be getting all this
advice on places to go, things to do.
And the problem is I'm not really
going to have a lot of time. All right,
tip about Poland. Dear Mr Bill, I'm
very excited about your towards so am I.
I'm very excited to go to
Poland. Uh, I'm Polish,
but for now I'm living
and working in Sweden.
So I hope to get the ticket for one of
your stand ups in Stockholm or in Oslow.
One tip about Poland.
Uh,
use it how you want in one of your late
night shows visit you called Poland and
Eastern European country and that
you are excited about visiting.
They're happy to hear that,
but well,
we Polish hate the term eastern
European for a few reasons.
I imagine one of us is gonna be the
Russians first is that if you look at the
map of Europe geographically,
we're not on the east.
Well then explained to me why the
Detroit Redwings for so fucking long.
You know, we're in the
east, weren't they? Are,
they're still on east
coast time and he was so,
it's the same like Nebraska is on the
east coast. I'd say more like Michigan.
And second reason political is that
this term comes from times when we were
under the Soviet Union.
Yes, we fight back, uh,
got our India,
we fought back on our independence.
We are happy and proud about that.
I'm sure that you never
mean to offend us also.
We are not hypersensitive pussies now.
You Polish people seem fucking cool. Uh,
I wish you great time
during the European tour.
Kickass performance and lots of positive
energy. So as always, go fuck yourself.
Mike Guy Named Mike from Poland.
Uh,
anyways. All right. Point
taken point. Fucking take it.
Jesus Christ. Well, let me, let me
look at the fucking map of Europe here.
All right. Uh, you're up
map.
Come on.
Type it correctly.
Wiki fucking TD or why?
Okay.
Why would it go to fucking wicky
fucking country? Pedia I fucking hate.
I love Wikipedia,
but Jesus fucking Christ.
Why does it always go to fucking
Wikipedia? I don't, I don't get it.
Don't fucking get it. All right. Let's
see here. I don't know about this.
Yeah,
I dunno.
You slightly fucking east.
Oh, I see. Cause that much of Russia.
Wait a minute. What do I look
up? Eastern? Yeah, Eastern Europe
map.
See what we got here.
Oh, I got news for you, buddy.
I just looked up eastern Europe maps
and you're fucking right in there.
Eastern Europe is Poland,
Czech Republic,
Slovakia, Hungary, Hungary, Croatia.
They don't have Austria in there. Yeah.
This might be because these are the,
these are the countries that Russia was a
had control of. Yeah. Maybe that's
it is what it is. Let's see.
A more eastern European map.
How about 2019
how about you?
Let me fucking click on
it. Yeah. Jesus Christ.
boom.
I gotta be honest with you, dude.
They're still fucking distill.
Still got you included in this.
Yeah.
Yeah. They got you in it.
Listen, send me the fucking,
whatever fucking map you're looking at is,
I don't know what it is.
Okay.
All right. You know something I give
up. I give up. Why? Why don't bill,
why don't you listen to the guy
that fucking lives over there?
Am I really doing that? Oh, I daig
guy who actually lived in Poland. Uh,
this is me from Los Angeles.
I think you're wrong about
where you live. It might,
was I really just doing that for
the last five minutes. I apologize.
Told um, Rosebowl everybody. Hey,
d
Billy Rose balls. First of all, I'm a
big fan of all your work. Thank you.
I was at your Seattle show and you and
Dean del Ray were hilarious. Thank you.
Anyways,
my school is in the rose bowl this year.
And since you're such a veteran,
I was wondering if you had
any advice for a first timer.
I have the basic tailgating stuff
like a grill, beer, and a cooler.
Should I bring anything special? Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Alex. Uh, Alex,
uh, bring a chair, brings some lawn
chairs, someplace to sit down. Um,
depending if you want to hang afterwards
and let all the traffic leave,
I would bring some firewood that you can
put into your little Hibachi and start
a little fire and stay warm.
Um,
what are things that people forget? Uh,
don't forget plates. Don't forget Napkins.
Bring a trash bag to put all your shit in.
Um,
condiments.
Okay.
Utensils
a table.
You don't want to be sitting there having
everything in your fucking lap. Uh,
what else? Charcoal. Uh, uh, I'd,
I'd bring those little squares that make
it easy to like the, if you get in the,
uh,
the wood burning sort of whatever the
fucking that natural would charge crap if
you're going to do that, unless you,
unless you have the match light stuff. Um,
a lighter
beer bottle opener.
Um,
butter for the bonds,
bonds, it just, everything. I
just go over and over and over.
A Red Solo cups,
booze.
I had a jacket for when it gets cold,
when he gets your tickets,
try to stay on this side with
the, uh, with the press box on it.
That way you're not staring into the
sun for half the fucking game. Um,
oh, and before you leave, even when you
go to take a Piss, when you're tailgating,
find where you are because
you're on a golf course.
It's all going to look the same. The
stadium is round, especially at night.
There's no focal point that you're going
to be able to find and you will walk
around lost. All right. There'll
be these little balloons.
They're finally lighting them up for
years. They did not light them up.
Yeah,
it's literally one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
I don't know how high up it goes, but
just make sure you remember where you are.
Um, pace yourself depending on what time
you're going to go. Bring us to Gar.
Fewer cigar person. Bring a light
or bring a cutter. All of that shit.
You think that you, you're
gonna, you're gonna Forget. Um,
all right, so good luck to
Ya. Alright, daughter MMA,
a Billy red nose tubes,
a belly, the red nose. Pubi
I am a 33 year old lady
D
and I'm also a second
degree black belt in.
Okay,
go. Gee, Guru. Go Djourou karate.
I've done martial arts for the last
eight years that I have also dabbled in
other styles and learned a lot of
things for many different instructors.
That's awesome.
The reason I am writing to you is
because I listened to you on Conan.
Conan needs a friend podcast,
and you've mentioned you wanted your
daughter to learn MMA or something,
but your wife might not be
thrilled about the idea.
I was hoping you could tell her that
as a small woman, I'm only five feet,
that knowing something to protect
myself makes me feel better.
Being outside or in crowds. I think
of it as having insurance. Uh,
you hope you never need it, but
it's nice to have. Yeah, absolutely.
I think all women should know how to
do this shit and they should learn it
without it being broadcast out there
that they're learning it because then the
perverts,
we'll then start taking classes and
try and roll around the mat with you.
Not only they'll have a defense
against whatever you do,
you should spring the shit on them.
Not only will you fucking
be able to defend yourself,
y'all should be able to catch the fucking
Douche that's still stolen it and they
can lock them up in a perfect world.
All right?
There are instructors who are very caring
and our fathers themselves,
they will give your daughter tips
and extra advice on how to face men.
Since generally speaking, men
are stronger. I don't know.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with sending your daughter to dancing
school. Sometimes that can
help with your art. Uh,
my friend at the Dojo also did ballet,
but she said it helped with her foot work.
I have a daughter that's three years old
and when she's a little older I will be
enrolling her at my school,
which my husband and also our son daily.
Being a martial artist wouldn't
make your daughter on feminine. Uh,
when you rather she be a little femme
fatale you're preaching to the choir here.
Exactly.
Does any questions I'd love to answer
and we'll write back merry Christmas and
go fuck yourself. Yeah,
thank you. I'm going to,
I got to read that to my
wife and she'll be like,
I never sad that Jay can fac and dad.
It's like, yet you did, you did on some
level or at least that's the way I heard.
That's the way I heard it.
MMM.
Anyways, I've been doing well with my
anger. Everybody been doing well with it.
Like I immediately now
and when I flip out,
I start to apologize as I'm doing it and
say that I'm being a baby and there has
to be a more mature way to settle this.
And I swear to God,
if you're an angry guy out there,
I cannot tell you what that
means to the woman in your life.
They like,
okay.
They become the person
they were when you met him.
Okay.
You know, a lot of times when
your wife or girlfriend changes,
it's because you are changing and
they're reacting to what you're doing.
You know what I mean?
Not to give women 100% of fucking pass
before all the women listen to this guy
and looking at their fucking
boyfriend now husband.
Yeah.
For one thing women love to
do is fucking rubbing it.
They can't just be right
there. They get out here, see,
look at it and fucking push your face
right down on the paper where it says
there.
Right.
MMM.
So, uh, yeah, that's going to
be my thing. And I'm going to,
I think I might go back to therapy next
year just specifically to talk about my
anger and get this
thing sorted out and uh,
you know,
and I keep threatening.
Then I might start going to
Sunday church again regularly,
even though I don't believe in any of it.
I like it just as a way to reset and
just kind of sit and think as I block out
all the bullshit that's being said to me.
Just sit there and think it'd be like,
what's important? What do
I need to do, you know,
get your shit together,
you know, don't be a dick.
Um, life is flying by. All right.
Friend wants to get matching tattoos.
Oh.
[inaudible] all right.
A Billy Burnett.
Uh,
so I've known this girl for
going on five years now.
We both still remember the night we
met and the developed a close intimate
relationship sense. Yeah. Boy,
we were together officially
earlier this year, then broke up.
And it was during this time she got a
tattoo to symbolize the loss she felt
after our breakup.
We've since started talking
again and we went to, uh,
we went out to a concert together in
San Francisco and fell in love all over
again. Well, since we've returned,
she asked me how I'd feel about
getting a tattoo matching hers.
Okay.
Yeah. No, yeah, don't do that. Uh,
we're not officially back together,
but I think that meaning behind
this tattoo is deeper than that.
I feel like I'm connected to this girl
regardless if I'm with her or not.
So I wouldn't regret it even if
I didn't talk to her ever again.
I'm leading towards yes as
obviously I really liked this girl,
but I need an outsider's perspective.
It'd be my first and probably
only tattoo and it's not,
and it's nothing ridiculous.
Just a word on the forum,
no name or anything like that.
She's beautiful and we get along
like best friends as well as lovers.
What do you think? Uh, yeah, dude, I,
you don't get a matching
tattoo with a woman ever.
And it may be if you're 25 years into
being married and the kids have all moved
out of the house.
Okay.
You don't do that. Don't,
don't fucking do that. Okay.
Because you've already broken up.
It seems like a very volatile
emotional relationship. Um, you know,
you're my soulmate. I love you. Fuck you.
We're breaking it up. I got a tattoo.
A,
it's talking about how sad I was,
wasn't we broke up and now we're getting
back together and now we need to get
matching tattoos. I mean, this is,
it's why wouldn't when, when the,
when the emotions level off a little,
okay,
okay. And you're in the grind
of a relationship and you
guys don't run from that.
They can actually hang,
there's no fucking reason to do that
because if you end up fucking breaking up,
which, who's kidding, who,
that sounds like there's a 50 50 chance
you will now you got this fucking tattoo
on your arm and then you're going to
get with the next person. You know,
the person you ended up where maybe the
person ended up being with and she's
going to be like, what's that? And He, oh,
this is this tattoo that I got from a
past relationship that another woman also
is walking around with and she's,
can you think if you fucking think
that that's going to stay there?
Yeah.
The only reason why I would say to do
it is because there's still that laser
fucking surgery though.
Don't get like regret or missing you
or butterfly, whatever the
fuck my butterfly, whatever
the fuck she has an arm.
All right. She fucked up. She did
that. You didn't. So you know, this is,
you know, this is a good like lock the
door test in the relationship to be like,
yeah, I don't want to do that. I don't
have any tattoos. I'm not a tattoo guy.
I respect the fact that you did that.
I respect what that means and what that
means on your arm is in my heart and I
don't need to draw it on my arm and it,
if that is a deal breaker and you're
going to break up with me then then that,
that's fucking great.
I didn't do it. Okay.
Don't do it. You hear me, sir? Do not.
Okay.
You know, let me ask you this. If you
got the tattoo and she didn't do it,
would you break up with her?
The answer's fucking no.
Then why the fuck should that be a
deal breaker the other way around?
If the answer is yes, then you're fucking
crazy. And I hope she's crazy too.
And uh, you have a positive kid. Two
negatives make a positive. I don't,
I don't want to fuck. I just wouldn't
do it. I wouldn't do it. All right?
I thought many times in my younger time
life of getting a tattoo and I never did
and I'm so glad I did now because I
feel like not having a tattoo is like
rebellious or not even rebellious.
It's unique.
Okay.
Especially now.
You know,
I saw the first fucking person that
wasn't like a pop star walking down the
street with like a fucking face tattoo
and they were coming across the street.
I was like, what in the fuck is
that? Like I didn't know. Like I,
I couldn't tell why the person just look
different until they got up close and
it's like, oh my God. Oh my
God. They drew on their face.
You draw my face.
Um,
do destroys airport ticket machine.
Ah,
oh,
please tell me this is true.
That literally made my entire
body just relax. Hey, hey.
Hey Billy. Ginger nuts. A lot of stuff
about my private sis week. Everybody,
you know, there's a lot of other
things you can make fun of.
You might like this one.
Massive Korean man destroys
all the airport auto ticket
machines because his one
ain't working well. You know something. I
kind of liked this until he had a wreck.
Everybody else's.
Uh,
I spent a fair bit of time at this airport
and the dudes with the machine guns
always seen to be right next to me.
Anyway,
if you get some time out of your
fancy celebrity interview podcasts,
I knew I was going to get shit
for that and want to see, uh,
a normal, a normal slash insane.
Can't lose his shit. Check it out.
Thanks for the company.
It's been great for the last five years
is so best regards to you and yours and
go fuck yourself. All right, I got
to click on this. Yeah, go to page.
Oh my God.
How did I miss out on this?
I haven't been on my Twitter
account for a couple days,
so maybe some people sent me this.
Ah Ha ha ha ha.
Oh, here we go. Come on. This
is all written in Korean.
I love it. This seems like
the real deal. Here we go.
Okay.
Oh,
don't do this to me.
All right.
He's smashing his luggage.
Okay.
On this thing, people are looking
at them just staring at it.
Okay.
He's taken his carry on.
Yeah.
He just tipped it over.
He tipped two of 'em over.
Where is the security?
No,
he just sorta pushed a woman.
Wow.
Oh,
now he's going after another one.
I love this guy. She, Oh my God.
Okay.
Okay. There it goes. Number four.
Yeah.
Dude, this is like the NFL.
Combine a going psycho.
Like this guy just put up and say numbers.
He's first round draft pick.
Yeah.
He does have a sense
of entitlement though.
Yeah.
Somehow he's standing there with
his hand on his hip with his suit.
Where is the security?
Wow.
All right.
I really fucking enjoyed that.
Okay.
Good advertisements. So where can
I buy this suitcase? Very durable.
He's a comment.
This is the English comment you are
looking for because they're all in Korean.
Yeah. Uh, yeah. He probably,
he got a vision of what will happen in
the future. You saw the plane crushed,
so he tried to stop everyone on
boring to board it being positive.
Those of you who are wondering, this is
what happened. A businessman name all die.
Sue is arrested for drunkenness missing
his daughter's fourth birthday and his
friend Chew Hawaiian,
picks him up from the police station.
They go to the phone booth.
Okay.
Calls home.
Okay. This is this bull. This
is just all bullshit. Oh my God.
I hate everybody's trying to
just make a funny comment.
How come nobody's saying like,
oh my God, this is fucking great.
Yo.
If this was in the states,
he would got chopped in the motherfucking
throat after the first kiosk went down.
Korea, you got to work on your anger
management issues. There are better ways.
Is this an American telling people this?
There are better ways this period
is period. Not Period. Okay,
period.
Shut the fuck up.
Okay.
Kind of a fucking asshole. Uses
that to give a lecture. Um,
okay.
Anyways,
uh,
oh.
Just got a message on Facebook. Call
me. I lost all my contacts there. Oh,
how do I know? This is from my friend?
He had never know. Anyways, this is the,
this is the Monday morning podcast.
Everybody go fuck yourselves. Uh,
have a great couple of days.
I'll check in on your,
on Thursday and don't forget
to get your stockings.