Hey,
what's going on and spill?
Burn his time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
November 26th,
2017 what's going on?
How? Wow. Yeah. What's up?
What's going on? How was
your thanksgiving? How was
your Thanksgiving Week? Oh,
it's over. Huh? Jesus Christ.
Isn't that a great weekend? It's,
it's the best. It's the,
if you don't fucking,
if you don't have to go anywhere, first
of all, if you don't have to go anywhere,
you know, if you get, you get
a wife and you've got a kid,
you don't have to go anywhere. People
just come into your place. It's the best,
you know, all your stuff is there
in the end. People help clean up.
I literally, I had the perfect
thanksgiving. It was perfect.
Did I want to thank you?
Oh, I can't yell. My daughter's
asleep. Fuck, I'm taping
this at night. Sunday night.
Um,
the potato sweet potato pie killed.
I think I gave out some misinformation.
I just bought the wrong kind of
sweet potato. I bought a, uh,
it was the white one, which I'm
hurt. I used for other desserts,
but not for the Pi,
but people do actually use sweet
potatoes for sweet potato pie.
You can also actually use yams.
That's what I used. Yams, brown sugar,
cinnamon, some Nutmeg, a
little bit of ginger. Um,
some vanilla,
whatever,
and a whole bunch of sugar stirred the
whole thing together. And I tell you,
I was sweating it. Okay. Fucking
white guy making a sweet potato pie,
you know what I mean? I mean,
I'm living dangerously here.
I thought it was going to get
booed like at the Apollo and uh,
maybe people were just being nice, but
I think, uh, I think everybody liked it.
Um, so I was psyched. And
then my stuffing always kills.
I stuffing always kills.
You know why?
Because it starts off with me melting
as an entire stick of butter in a pan.
That's where,
and I go from there.
I don't care what you make and you can't
lose if you start by melting a stick of
butter and a parent, you know, um,
he's fucking lunatics nowadays.
They will take that note.
Can I pour that entire thing into my
coffee? I don't know what's going on.
All right. I have a lot of stuff
to promote. I apologize for the AC,
but it's as hot as shit in here.
I don't know if he can hear that
running over my loudest voice here.
A bunch of stuff.
The sixth annual Patrice O'Neal
comedy benefit will be Tuesday,
February 20th, 2018 at 7:00
PM. People always go, hey man,
why is it always on Tuesday?
Because I got a bunch of comics
working for free that night.
I can't have them work for free.
And I'm money night.
Money as in churching not isn't not
Monday night and then a Monday night,
a money night. Um, all right,
it's going to be 7:00 PM at the city
center where we've always had it.
One 31 west, 55th street between
sixth and Seventh Avenue Was New York,
New York one double oh one nine. Here's
the lineup. Brendan Burns, p Corey,
Allie Jo to raw Joey roses,
Sam j Robid blobby Kelly there,
Jessica Curson,
um, Sifa sounds and rich Vos, uh,
with more special guests to be announced.
Um,
ticket prices or 75 bucks every seat and
all the money other than what we have
to pay to rent the fucking place.
Um,
goes to a, goes to his mom.
All right. And his, uh,
what would have been his wife,
but he never got around to Marriner.
I don't know how to say
it anyways. Uh, anyways,
there's three ways to buy the tickets
when you go. I'm gonna have all these,
all these links, by the way, are up on
my website, all that stuff. Okay. Um,
and you can,
there's a number you can call if you're
sitting in your cubicle right now. Two,
one, two, five, eight,
one, one, two, one, two,
uh,
at the theater and at the box office,
you can go right to one 31 west 55th
street. All right? It's gonna be,
it's gonna be Tuesday,
February 20th,
2018 at 7:00 PM,
and thank you to everybody who's been
coming for all of these years. Um,
because of you guys coming out,
we've been able to keep Patrice,
his name and his comedy alive.
And everybody that, you know,
that was in his life has that he was
helping to support and everything has
remained living comfortably
and been taken care of. So, um,
it's so one of the things I'm most
proud of as far as all the things that,
um,
you know,
I've done in this business and I've
watched my friends do the fact that we all
get together and make sure that his mom
and his family are right around right is,
uh, is a great thing. So anyways,
onto the podcast,
well,
if I'm going to promote some stuff I
might as well promote a few other things,
is a speaking of comedians and I got
to get her on this benefit one of these
years. A good friend of mine
from way back in the day,
it became a film maker and is now back
is back then when stand up Maya to
Giorgio. Um, absolutely fucking hilarious.
And I was talking to you that night
at the comedy store. I didn't realize.
I told her, uh, you know,
my, I really fucked.
I really fucked up my side
big time by playing drums.
I think I already told you guys,
that's how I was down there and
I was just telling her that,
you know how I messed it up and then
I re screwed it up by playing drum.
She's like, I didn't eat, play
drums and I used to play drums.
I started talking to her mother,
used to be this famous jazz singer and
she played at the cotton club and all
this stuff, the real jazz gigs and
shit. Sit in with all these legends.
Started talking, all this drum stuff.
And she's a great comedian. Anyway,
she's going to be a December six.
She's going to be at levity
live in Oxnard, California,
which is just outside of La.
It's a Wednesday night. Um,
she's just fucking awesome.
So definitely check it out.
I'll have the link up there for that.
And lastly,
Judah Freelander has a new special on
Netflix called America is the greatest
country in the United States.
And me and Nia was sitting in bed watching
it really low on the volume because
you know, our lovely daughter's sleeping
in the other room and just cracking up.
It's fucking hilarious.
It's brilliant.
I haven't seen him in so long because
he's a New York guy and I'm a big La phony
here. And um, I sent him
a text. I told him how he,
that guy is fucking brilliant
man. Uh, definitely check it out.
It's so cool the way he shot it. It looks
like almost lead us in black and white.
And probably there was a
couple of I iPhones. It's
just shot over the course of,
I don't know how many months
of him screwing around
doing bits fucking with the
crowd,
you know,
and he just would just would cut out
and just say, the seller, this date,
the seller, that date all shot at
the seller. It's, uh, it's really,
it's really different.
It's awesome.
Judah Freelander America is the greatest
country in the United States. All right,
that's it. Let's get into the end
of the podcast here. All right,
let's dig in to the God damn podcast.
Um,
in a good way. I did not
do shit this weekend.
I didn't do shit other than this morning.
I woke up and I got all my tax shit.
You know,
I do it at the end of every month.
I just get all my stupid receipts.
I organize them so I don't have
a fucking avalanche, you know,
April 14th to go through and throw it my
accountant and make his life miserable.
I don't do that. End of every month,
like a little old lady, you know,
I try to balance the books.
I just do all of that.
And then all I have to deal
with is whatever bullshit
I did in the last 30 days,
rather than having to deal with 365 days.
It's the smartest fucking thing
I've ever done. Because I remember,
I remember back when I used to live with
Bobby Kelly, right? We would sit in and,
and you know, we would do like a
zillion spots a week. You know,
on the weekend you'd have like six,
seven, eight spots a night, you know,
and I was working uptown and downtown,
so I'd have all these cab receipts and
have all of these receipts from College
Gigs, Club gigs, bus
tickets, train tickets,
all of this shit shoved in like four
different cvs bags by the end of the year.
And, you know, we had to do our
own taxes back then or whatever.
I remember we would just be sitting there
with this shitty fucking coffee table
with our giant plastic bags of receipts.
I can't do it.
Why did we do this?
Why did we fuck it?
Why didn't we just along the way,
at least just to have an envelope that
said taxi receipts that I would try it
every year. You know, in a
good year I'd make it to march,
you know,
but I never made it for the whole year.
Most years I wouldn't even make it into
February. And I've just be like, yeah,
fuck it. Um, but this
year, finally, years later,
25 years into my career,
finally I finally been doing it.
And, uh, I kinda know where
shit is, like major shit,
life insurance and stuff like that.
I kind of know where it is.
Like I know it's in one of two different
places. I don't know which folder,
but um, it's really made my life a
lot easier. Um, or who's kidding, who?
My wife if make her life easier,
if I ever die, it's like,
it's either in that boxer,
in that box and it's sort of organized.
MMM.
So anyways, yeah, I did not do shit
this weekend. Still didn't drink.
I made it through. I did not
drink. So I'm up to 102 days.
By the time you listened to some it triple
digits over there, I'm like fucking,
well chambal it of being sober.
I got him by two fucking days.
Two points.
MMM.
Yeah. It wasn't that, it wasn't that
bad. No one was really drinking.
So the temptation wasn't really there.
MMM.
And once the night was over and my
daughter was awesome and she didn't cry
nothing. She's just like, she's so cool,
man. He's so chill. She's so, you know,
when people, people actually say that
when she gets upset, she looks like me.
That's when she looks like me.
You know what I mean?
And as much as that hurts me to hear that,
I know it's true.
So anyways, um, I ended
up, uh, I, you know,
when I'm home,
I usually am the one that puts her to bed.
I actually really enjoyed doing it
and I haven't down to a whole system.
And the worst part is after they fall
asleep in your arms and he got to set them
down in the Crim and then they cry
for a little bit and just walking away
knowing that fine, no one,
they just crying there. Okay.
MMM.
That's the hard part. But, uh, I
actually enjoy her falling asleep,
you know,
laying on my arm so much that I usually
let it go for like an extra 20 minutes,
cause I figured some day, you know, she's
going to be like, Oh my God, Dad, God,
you're so embarrassing. I'm,
I'm really trying to take
all of this shit in. So, um,
anyways, I put her to bed and uh,
was watching around the little video and
then I went out on my back porch and I
smoked arguably the
best cigar of the year.
It was just perfect. You know, it
was thanksgiving. It was an event.
So there was no guilt of like, look
at me smoking a cigar. What am I,
some bomb at a track. I said, I
smoked it. It was fucking delicious,
delicious.
So couldn't have gone any better.
And just when I thought my weekend
couldn't get all any better,
I decided to watch every college fucking
football game I could get my eyeballs
on. And I did. And it did.
I see some bright ones who,
please tell me,
please tell me you son of a bitch that
you fucking sat down and you watch the
war on I four interstate for that runs
between the two underrated cities of
Tampa in Orlando, Florida.
They don't get any respect.
You know,
you gotta be on the East Coast and south
of Lake Okeechobee to get any respect
and Florida.
And even then,
they still laugh at you if just if
you're living in Fort Lauderdale, right?
You're up north on Daytona beach.
They all know you're doing math right.
You gotta be down in Miami.
I got a buddy of mine forced Shaw.
He's going to be on my shows
out there enough Florida.
I'm doing a show in Hollywood,
Florida and in Orlando going to a magic
game in between knocking off another
team and uh, he's a Miami
guy. So I was trashing him.
I was making fun of
Miami. I was like, dude,
every guy in Miami is either
a drug dealer or a promoter
or both.
I know that isn't true,
but I just like trash in
places that I enjoy going to.
Who doesn't like Miami? Um,
anyways, so interstate four
runs between Tampa and uh,
and uh, Orlando and I watched
that game deck game was fucking,
it was like watching a god, this
was like a video game. I can't,
I can't even remember what
the fucking score was.
It was like 42 35 and I got to tell
you something with some of the fastest,
most athletic to the fastest, most
athletic teams I've seen in a long time.
I don't know that,
I don't know if they're not division one.
I don't know what their deal is. I don't
know where they are. But I know this,
I've seen a lot of like good players come
out of south Florida, central Florida.
Um, so I don't know what happened. Maybe
they fucked up in high school, you know,
punched a teacher.
I don't know what happened,
but these guys look like they could
take on anybody granted at the same,
I don't fucking know.
It looked great. Okay.
Everybody was flying around the field.
So you know,
there was very few white people out
there. You know what I'm saying here? Um,
so, uh, I'm watching this game.
It's 42 35 and C um,
central Florida is trying to be the
first team ever in that conference or
whatever to to ever go winless and
within two years go undefeated.
So they have a chance to do what?
They go up 42 like 35 or some shit and
there's like a minute and a half left,
right? What are you going to do?
You're going to go into the prevent.
You're going to give up the whole,
the first fucking 80 yards and
then you're going to go into,
then you're going to start finally
playing defense, right? You know,
I hate the fucking prevent defense, but
guests, guess what central Florida does?
Evidently they didn't go into the prevent
cause inexplicably.
Somehow this fucking guy got behind their
defense with a minute and a half left
for like a 70 80 yard touchdown,
which by the way,
it was like a 20 yard pass
and then he just ran 50 yards.
So I immediately tweet and all caps.
How the fuck do you let that happen?
As I'm finishing the
tweet and hitting scent,
it's now tied 42 42 south Florida
kicks the fucking ball off.
A stunned stadium of central
Florida fans are watching going,
can we at least get down
to field goal position?
Did we just fucking blow our whole season.
Fucking dude on central Florida catches
the ball debt kickoff and ran the
fucking thing back.
Okay.
So then I had to tweet again.
How the fuck do you let that happen?
So now it was like 49, 42. I'm sure I
got the score wrong with [inaudible].
They both in the forties and then
I'm sitting there going, well
those two places so fucked up.
They did easily.
Central Florida could run this fucking
ball back of south Florida, I should say.
Um, they didn't, and, and the game ended,
but Jesus Christ one an entertaining game.
And then the next day I watched Michigan,
Ohio state,
and then I watched the iron bowl,
um,
and watch Auburn beat Alabama and uh,
watching Michigan
for us,
Ohio state.
I've come to the conclusion that I
fucking hate quarterbacks who run.
I hate a running quarterback. I just
can't, I can't fucking stand it. Yeah,
no, I don't think it should be legal
for a quarterback to run. All right.
Okay.
Or if you run,
then you get treated like a running back.
This whole fucking thing that you can
wait until everybody, everybody covers.
They called the right defense.
Nobody's open and then you can just take
off running and when nobody's fucking
looking, that's all well and
good, but you should get stuck.
But it's all like he gave himself up.
He threw himself on the ground.
Leave him alone. Fuck you. Fuck you.
If you're going to take off running,
you should get stuck.
Either that or keep your fucking fucking
running around to ask behind the God
damn line. It's fucking driving
me crazy. I'm a Michigan Fan,
so I'm watching that shit and Michigan's
fucking defense was lights out and that
fucking cunt kept running eight yards,
nine yards.
Guy couldn't complete a pass. He couldn't
feel pressure, but he could fucking run.
And then when he ran there to be
like, Ooh, he's a quarterback.
If I was coaching for the other team, I'd
be like, listen, he hit the fucking guy.
Take the, take the penalty.
I don't give a shit.
I'm not saying deliberately energy
him, but fucking hit him. I don't care.
Now it drives me up. It drives me
up. The congratulations to a house.
I don't hate Ohio state or whatever.
I'm just more of a Michigan Fan. Um,
and Michigan's just in a
weird year, I don't know what
their deal is. I mean, they,
they don't have their quarterback.
I hate trash and college players
cause there's still kids or whatever.
But he could've had a better game.
He was a little amped up in the beginning
and I don't know what happened on that
last play.
I think a miscommunication.
Maybe the guy broke off the pattern or
whatever cause it will be just fucking
threw it to the guy. But, um,
Jim Harbaugh, oh, in three.
Oh,
in three against Ohio state.
You're telling me his wife
had a good fucking weekend.
So he comes home with this fucking
woody Hayes glasses all steamed up.
MMM.
But Jesus Christ at Defense
Michigan's defense was great. Um,
and how about that kid that came in after,
uh, Ohio state's quarterback went down.
He played great, and he could throw the
ball, he could throw the ball and run. Um,
so maybe they've got a future with him.
I have no idea. And then I, you know, my,
I got a buddy Jay law head
is a big Ohio state guy,
so he's always arguing the case as to
why or how Iowa state should be in the
fucking off every, he did it to me
last shift fucking talking to me.
He tried to explain to me
how our hio state should be.
Yeah.
In, in the, the, the, the,
the 14 play off and it's like
two they lost to Penn state.
Penn State won the big 10 championship.
Penn state does it make it in,
but Ohio state does. He goes,
yeah, I'll tell you why.
Strength of schedule early
fucking does all the fucking math.
And then what happens? They play Clemson
and they get the old right there, Fred,
right. 31 to nothing. You know,
somebody else should have been in there.
So I love Jay. He was doing that
to me again the other day via text.
And I'm just laugh at thinking like,
dude,
he's always talking about how Alabama
stinks and there's nobody fucking in the
sec. It's like the big 10 sucks. The
big 10 still sucks. It's not that good.
Penn state was overrated.
They were overrated.
They lost the White House state
and it was a huge fucking winter.
Then the very next week, what happened?
I always stayed Pete's Penn state,
the next fucker week,
Penn state loses to Michigan State and
Ohio state gets fucking raped rate by
fucking Iowa.
So I dunno,
he's always talking about how
weak the SCC is. It's like, dude,
get the fuck outta here.
Wouldn't look at the big 10
yeah,
Jesus Christ. How many teams you got
laying down every week? Rutgers, Indiana.
Purdue, Northwestern. A fucking Minnesota.
I hate to say Nebraska,
but that they're no good.
That's six fucking t's right there in
Michigan state is always half ass. Oh Man,
I'm going to get some
fucking mail this week
in Michigan. Isn't that good? There's
still trying to put it together.
So who the fuck are you playing out
there? I don't get it. You know?
Okay,
look at fucking Auburn.
Auburn beat Georgia when Georgia was
number one and now they beat Alabama in
Alabama was number one.
So Alabama is number one.
They take a loss in the last game
of the season. So now at they out,
the whole fucking thing is just,
it's just a,
a symptom of the game.
You can't have the march madness because
everybody would be getting concussions
and ruining million dollar
fucking careers. So this
is the best system we got.
So I guess it creates arguing,
but I got to tell you, um,
yeah, what a fucking, I've just, the
college football was fucking amazing.
Then I watched a little bit and I
never watched PAC 12. I watched Lou,
that Washington, Washington
state, Jesus Christ,
a bunch of players on those teams too.
Um,
and for some reason my wife just let me
do it. You know, it's funny, we actually,
we went out shopping after the Michigan
fucking Ohio state game and I was so
fucking pissed,
so fucking pissed.
Cause I just felt like Michigan, they had
a better defense, they should have one.
And they just kept doing that little
cunty fucking eight yards scamper for a
first down to keep the fucking
drive alive was driving me crazy.
Um, and then, uh,
I dunno. And then he just went
out and I just like, you know,
I don't know why I get that
into games, but you know, my,
my laugh could sense it and I just
said, yeah, listen, I just fucking,
you know, I just watched the game.
I did not like the outcome. Right.
It's because Jesus Christ. All right,
so then we're walking around, okay,
we're with all these people like you know,
Christmas shopping and shit and you know,
there was this group of fucking
Asian people, I dunno. I Dunno.
They will for whatever reason,
we're walking down the sidewalk like 17
people across and we were behind them
and they were walking
like half a mile an hour.
I don't know if they just got
done eating Thanksgiving dinner.
I don't know what it was,
but I was having what this comic,
I used to know John Bush used to call
it walk rage instead of road rage.
He's to do this great bit about
having walked rage in New York City.
And I was just sitting there like,
how the fuck do you not?
I mean,
I get it there. There's a whole family,
they were with their grandparents,
you know, an agent. People
respect their elders.
They're not like Americans where we
would have thrown those old people in the
home and we would have picked up the
pace when we walked down the street.
So I was trying to respect their culture,
but at the end of the day, I'm selfish.
So I was just like, ah, what
the fuck. We finally get by him
and my daughter didn't want
to be in the fucking stroller,
so I got her out and I'm carrying in my
ribs a fucking talking to me and one of
my shoulders is fucked up, man. I'm
a mess, right? I'm like, you know,
I'm like a fucking journeyman
quarterback, right? No,
I'm like Steve Drogan at
the end of his career,
I should have been walking around
with like that fucking neck brace.
So I'm already grumpy.
And then this lady's kid is having a
fucking temper tantrum and was stopped at
the, at the red light waiting
to walk across the street,
and this kid is hitting this
fucking note that is making my ears,
which are junk from playing drums,
vibrate in this painful way that's
making my teeth hurt. So Nia goes,
hey, we can cross up here and
right as I do that though,
fucking woman with the screaming kid
heard it too and started following me and
has a say aviation.
She was a beam up my fucking left eardrum,
which means just right alongside of it.
And I just,
I was walking away and I couldn't see.
She was right,
but I couldn't understand why it wasn't
getting quieter and that she came,
I turned around, I saw that she was
following this up there, and I just, I,
I snapped,
I snapped.
I was under my breath.
Caught Jesus fucking Christ.
Can you just fucking get that fucking
kid a fuck away from me? I was, go near.
Stop. Just let him go past Jesus.
Fucking cool. You know, it was,
it was completely irrational.
I was 100% wrong, but, uh,
it was just all those things building up.
And like I said,
I already walk around at a six, so it's
very easy for me to get back up to a 10.
So, uh, Nia, stop talking to me. And uh,
then I was like, ah, here we go. You know?
And then I was a baby about it. I'm like,
Oh really? Dooley, I should have a
football game. I'm driving over here.
We just bought this. I did this.
I took the fucking garbage Joe.
Okay.
Just cause I drop a bunch of f bombs in
public about some other woman's crying
kid, you know, I did the dishes.
That's not a push. That's not a
wash, you know? I thought like,
I thought that all balanced
it out. So, you know,
I put up a good fight on the ride home
and then I find just a mess. Like, yeah,
right. You're right. I'm just arguing
because I know you're writing.
I'm embarrassed. I shouldn't
have done that. Yeah.
MMM.
What do you, what are
you going to do? I mean,
they wrote a song about
me a long time ago. Huh?
I'm not a perfect person.
Um, yeah. I don't know why I did that.
You know, something I would go
to fucking anger management,
but I just don't feel like
telling my stories all over again.
I've already gone to therapy.
I just don't, you know,
you're gonna Retell these fucking things,
you know,
going to reboot it like fucking
full house on a Netflix.
Okay.
Oh, she's got to have it.
They just keep rebooting shit,
doing the same shit over again among,
but I'm going to do that.
Tell these fucking stories all over.
I'm sick of my stories.
That was part of my argument
too. I was just like, you
know, Nia, this is, this is,
you know, something. This is who
I am. This is what I do. Okay. I,
uh, I'm really good at being a
comedian. I make a great living.
We have a great life,
but every once in awhile I'm going to
drop a bunch of f bombs because the baby's
crying. Okay. That's why.
And you have some, I usually,
babies crying usually makes me laugh
because I'm usually on a plane when they
start crying and they were expressing
exactly what I'm feeling and it's just
like, it's like a great comedy.
It's just like, dude, I hear Ya.
That's exactly what the fuck I'm feeling.
MMM.
I don't know. It just all built a house,
state beat Michigan. Then there was the,
uh, hands across America, Asian
family that I couldn't get around
and on those like 20,000 other fucking
things going on too. It was just like,
it was a shit show. And I fucking hate
Christmas shopping, but by the way, dude,
I've, I've crushed it this year. All my
nieces and nephews all have presence.
They're all wrapped and I'm mailing them
out to respective families this week.
Okay.
Hey Sanna,
go fuck yourself a beach it by four weeks.
Granted you have to deliver it to the
whole world, but you know, whatever,
whatever.
San is a number one seat. I'm like a
16 seed. I got into the dance cell.
No, my third, yeah. 16th seat in the
bracket. That's right. Right. Alright.
Anyways. Um, I don't know what the fuck
I'm talking about. Let's do a please,
please buy tickets to the Patrice
O'Neal comedy benefit. Uh,
so we can do this again.
We'll have some surprise guests.
Hopefully I'm reaching out to some big
names. Nudge, nudge, wink, wink. Alright,
me. Andy's everybody. All right.
Um, all right. Oh Shit. Here.
I got to guess I got a singer
Song. Butoh due to me. Andy's me.
Andy's losing my shit over a crying
baby. But Dude, dude, dude, me,
Andy's beyond these. Uh, why
didn't you join the navy?
Because I'm scared of the fucking ocean.
But I would have fought a shark not
to listen to that fucking baby. Sorry.
I don't know. I'm all over
the map. All right. Every,
every year millions of people
receive. That was it? Yeah.
I just,
I fucking snapped.
I didn't always know when Nia is not
going to talk to me anymore because not
only does she not talk to him anymore,
she gets this look on her face cause I
started looking at the side of her face
and I'm just like, oh, that's
that look, I know that look. Uh,
I know what she's doing when she's
rewinding 20 years of her life going,
how the fuck did I ended up
with this guy? Um, all right.
Mian he's every year millions of people
receive the least light gift of all time
underwear.
Okay.
But we still give it up to our family and
our loved ones who just don't want it.
But many will do by the way. What
does that fucking underwear that they,
they, that they sell. Oh Shit.
Look who's here. Oh Shit.
This year.
Oh, come on, on the podcast. I was talking
about how when I got mad at the baby.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus. They'll look,
just came right back.
Okay.
Huh? You're still shaking your head
over there. Yeah, she didn't hear me.
It doesn't matter. I
heard. Oh Shit. Sorry. Uh,
I heard you and I even like it.
Can you sing them? Me undies. Jingle
about what an asshole I am, dude.
Mia.
Andy's candies.
He's a fucking do Mya. Annie. Yes. Yeah.
Knees.
What have you got?
Ooh, what are you doing? Are you doing
this? Do dopey dude. It's me our days.
Mondays, no more sweaty balls. We really
mean it. Yeah, you got that part out.
Whatever you were right. Okay. Every year,
millions of people. What's, what the
give you see? Does it gross you out?
That guy's underwear commercial with,
they're like, no pinch, no stink,
no something or other and it's always
some fat redneck dude. It's like, I know.
I don't want to know that your tastes
smells like deer urine cause you just got
back from the forest and whenever those
fucking people do, I mean it's for,
it's for a practical purpose.
It's not supposed to be sexy.
It's not supposed to be
inviting or whatever.
It seems to be like for fat white guys.
It's definitely for white guys.
Fat White Guys. I mean fee
drawing. The guy's fat.
He's not even a husky. Yeah. He's a little
thick. He's fat. Yeah. I guess he's fat.
Do you want that crawling on top of you?
Uh,
I don't mind a husky
fellow. Really? All right.
We must not like how I'm looking because
I'm crushing it lately. I'm wafer thin.
I told you not to get too skinny. You
should still have a little, you know,
not something to hold onto because
that's a weird, yeah, that is weird.
But like don't get cell like you get,
you just get,
so you really do get men are
exec like you get so like upset.
Oh,
I don't need,
this is the fucking weight I was when
I came into this business and people
weren't like, oh my God,
your man erections that you,
what it is is you get used to
what I look like after eating,
drinking a thousand fucking
glasses of booze and pizza.
That's all beer and pizza.
Then if I actually get to the weight
that I'm supposed to be, you're like,
oh my God, you look sick.
My heart is sites right now.
It never said you look sick. You
said, I look like I have aids.
Don't you bill? That's not even
funny. I would never say that.
Don't tell people I said that on the park.
You said it and you made a sign and you
held it up in the kitchen. Oh, I did not.
See he's exaggerating. Don't know. What
did you say it in a way I, I'm sorry.
You said you want to, do you
want some Rolaids? Yeah. Not,
not those are those an assets you didn't?
I see.
You said you had aids.
All right. Oh my God.
[inaudible] no more blood disease.
All right, but maybe it's not the,
that underwear is the problem.
It's the kind of underwear.
Let me tell you about me undies.
It's the only underwear that's
makes for an amazing gift. Soft,
flexible waistband. Alright
me undies. I love you guys.
But who's kidding who this is a stocking
stuffer. Don't lead with this. Okay, this,
this, this gift is not batting cleanup
to Susan. A Nice little soft landing.
I got you. The fucking thing
you wanted and here you go.
His is very soft though,
Ania.
All I'm going to get you for Christmas
is me undies. How you feel about that?
I would love some meanthey. No,
that's all you're getting. No,
I want more than that. Why? Because I
don't want to just underwear. Thank you.
And when I give you the underwear, where
should I put it? That'll be your age.
I did a lot of that over the net
and it's a stocking stuffer. Sorry,
I'm too close to them.
I care. It's three, not
a copy. It's offer dollar shave club.
Okay. Why don't you get a microphone.
All right.
I just so you won't be off mic so people
can hear you and I can also get through
the,
by the way, people can hear me just
fine, like people tweet me that,
that they can hear me while you're sitting
there below Google. Good. Who are you?
You're used to screaming
into a microphone,
which is hilarious to me because the
microphone is meant to amplify your voice.
It's meant to carry it, but
you like like, yeah. Yeah,
I'm criticizing.
Yeah.
Yeah. I'm threatening you.
Yeah. Threatening. You're
good. Sit down here then.
I was trying to find the, no, I'll look it
up. All right. I'm just giving you shit.
Oh, you got to get another microphone.
The microphone is in the other room.
I'm not doing that. All
right. I'm not doing that yet.
Did you know me undies is three times
softer than cotton. It's very soft.
Very soft, isn't it? Is that
Horse Mussel soft? Mandy's. Huh?
That's my favorite touch. Like the, yeah.
I don't know what you call it.
What do you call it when you have a
favorite thing that you like to touch?
If you said this on a first date, they
wouldn't have been a second day. Oh,
that's my, that's my favorite
touch. What do you call it?
The thing you like to touch?
Little horse muzzle.
It was like my favorite things other
than our baby's beautiful face.
Oh good. Me. Andy's made underwear.
The perfect gift that everyone
is going to love you for.
It's a God damn holiday miracle this year.
They'd have their in the copy this year.
Give the gift of me undies this holiday
season to get your exclusive 20% off the
softer side.
Wearing socks you'll ever wear.
Free Shipping and 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bird that's me undies.com/burp.
Um, all right, darling.
I told Ya Joe Barton,
he told me about that homeless
guy ran into a Milwaukee. No,
he came up to me with a homeless guy.
This is his joke to make you laugh.
To give him money. He came up to
me. Oh yeah, yeah. He goes, hey,
did you hear Bob Barker died?
And Joe Goes, what? He goes,
yeah, he got hit by a new
car.
So stupid. Joe laughed
as AI. It is a buck,
a dollar shave club.
Everybody Dollar Shave club ships.
Amazing razors for a few bucks.
A what? You might not eat dog.
Bob Barker is not ted,
right?
I don't know. I hope not. And I
really hope he wasn't hit by a car.
Well,
he definitely wasn't hit by a car.
TMZ would've been over there and Tony
would read the fucking vin number.
Dollar Shave club ships.
Amazing raises for a few bucks.
What you might not know is that dollar
shave club also has products for pretty
much everything else you need.
And the bathroom man,
bodywash shampoo, Hair Gel,
pube, clippers, lip balm,
everything. They don't have a puke
clippers now you don't have to step foot.
You could shave your pubes
with their razor us. I mean,
no one's telling you not to.
No one's telling you to either.
Certainly not here on the podcast.
Okay?
I know that head moves for to
go around around your chin.
I don't know if you want
to fuck with your junk.
Okay.
Started the year off,
right?
Shave your shaft and your balls.
You heard it here.
Don't do that.
We do not condone that.
Joke's made on the podcast
or not to be taken seriously.
Do not reflect the views of the yes,
the literate reader here.
All right?
Now you don't have to step foot in a
store to get high quality shave and
grooming products.
Dollar Shave Club delivers them right
to your door just like their razors.
Everything is super
high quality and annual.
When we'll have you looking and feeling
amazing from premium ingredients to
sophisticated sense,
dollar shave club is changing the game.
If you're sick of the
nonsense at the store,
now's the time to try out dollar
shave club for a limited time.
Dollar Shave Club is basically
giving away their shit. Shower,
shave starter set to new members for
only $5 to start a set features the
exclusive executive razor and the
three trial size versions of their most
popular products that help you
stay so fresh and so clean.
And your first box you would receive
this shave bodywash and one wipe Charlies
but wipes.
Um,
there's no way to wipe your ass
in one wipe that just isn't okay.
There is a have to wipe your whole
ass or just wiping the whole yeah,
just one wipe and you,
you're good with that.
You're confident to pull up your underwear
and your drawers and just walk around.
Not Thinking you going to be a little
bit to go over it. A couple of, yeah,
you should.
One wipe Charlies.
How bad fucking four wipe Eddie's
a little swirl there. Um, you will
have their one shit jokes here. You
will also receive their executive razor,
which includes their premium weighty
handles in a full class set of cartridges.
After the first box replacement cartridges
are sent for only a few bucks a month,
this offer is exclusively
available@dollarshaveclub.com
slash bird that's dollar
shave club.com/bar and if you
want it to get a great gift,
give him dollar Shave Club.
Uh,
they got super simple gift memberships
at at e gift. Any gift cards,
Fuck Dollar Shave club's high quality
products for have you covered from face
cheeks to butt cheeks. There's no better
time to try the club and mercifully,
wait, can I just say
something? Let me get my water.
Just about like the whole shaving thing.
Especially for dollar Shave Club.
Are these real
razors?
Are they like Gillette style?
I mean,
why wouldn't they be real,
real razors and why did you just name
their competition in the middle of it?
First of all, this Coca Cola
does, it tastes like Pepsi
now isn't, uh, you know,
uh, no, it's a toy.
It doesn't even do the job. It's just,
they're just doing this for fun. For Fun.
What do you call it?
The blades that you put them in the thing
and then you open the, you open the,
not a safety razor. That's what I mean.
It's not, I'll count. Oh, it's like,
it's like the one I shaved my head with.
Gotcha. Okay. I just wanted to say,
because for the safety razor,
they had these people who have
been advertising for a long time.
Please don't ruin this for me. I've lost
so much advertising on this. Can we just,
all right. All right, nevermind.
Don't poke the golden goose here.
Diamonds stamps.com these
kids have ride or die.
They don't give a fuck what I say.
[inaudible] I love dollar Shave Club.
I love stamps.com.
I loved, I loved them.
All. You love old zip.
Alright.
stamps.com with the holiday almost.
Here it is. It just was
Thursday, right? Thanksgiving.
That's a holiday at the mall.
It's time to go.
San has at the mall. Uh, who has
time to go to the post office?
It'll be busy with people sending holiday
cards and gifts. So do what we do.
Use stamps.com instead. I'm so
stupid, I never thought to do this.
I only do it with my posters.
Why don't I send out all those gifts?
Using stamps.com brings all the services
of the US Postal Service right to your
fingertips. Buy and print official
US postage for any letter,
any package, and eclass a mail
using your own computer and printer.
Then the mailman picks it up.
stamps.com makes it easy.
They'll send you a digital scale.
Automatically calculates exact postage
stamps.com we'll even help you decide
that the best class of mail,
every t o help you decide the
best class of mail every time.
Print postage any day, anytime.
Stance Dotcom is always open.
I use stamps.com whenever
I send out my posters.
I'm a moron if I can figure it out.
So can you,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com servers
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus postage
and a digital scale without longterm
commitments.
Go to stamps.com.
Click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburrthatstamps.com
enter
bur
bur are all right with that,
let's read some of the, uh,
some of the letters from our
listeners here. If I'm listening,
his baggy shirt or eight.
Oo,
I'm reading all of these. I read all of
them. Still there like another 20 minutes.
Hey, what's your rush? Okay.
Relax. Sit down. Take it easy,
okay? Okay. Maybe. All right.
Okay, baby. All right. Okay. All right.
Progressive Rock. Oh, by the way,
fuck you Australia. Whoa. Yes.
Fuck that whole country for not telling
me about the wonderful Australian group.
See what I did there. Oh, I got
everybody down there. What to have.
I watch this fucking
fucking shrimp on the Barbie. How do
they talk down there? I know it is,
by the way. It's also a country.
Okay. And it's an island.
They don't know what they want to be.
Um,
how the fuck do you have all these
weeks I've been asking you for a great
fucking new bands. My drum teacher
just told me about this band. Carnival.
A sound awake. I listened to that album.
Jesus fucking Christ. What a band.
There are May. I cannot
recommend that's, that's the one.
I don't know any of their other albums.
That's the one I got sound awake.
They're fucking drummer. I got to get the
guy's name right now. What is his name?
I Bet I've been so
listening to that album.
I didn't even look up the drummer's
name. It's fucking amazing. Um,
where was it? Right? I don't
know. What are you doing?
I'm looking at all the
windows you have open on your,
why are women so fucking nosy?
That is so creepy.
I'm just curious. What was that looking
up cunt with a k maybe. All right.
Carnival. A drummer. Carnival.
That's how it's spelled. Did
they pronounce a carnival
or kind of Steve Judge.
Jesus Christ. That guy's a
beast. Incredible. Incredible.
Top to bottom. Everybody in that band,
singer guitar play a bass player.
The whole fucking thing. That drummer.
Unbelievable. Please download that.
Listen to it.
Tell me how much you love it.
Australia.
What you got to,
you got any more bands like that or
what do you hold now for every week I'm
fucking sitting here like a little,
a little kid, you know, on Christmas.
But no presence. Just asking them. Maybe
they don't tell me anything. I go to,
I like toy go all the way out to Perth
and what thanks do I get? Oh Australia,
that's not cool.
Fucking album came out in 2010.
Why they treat me like that?
I don't know. Anyways, um,
so nice when we went out there anyways,
shout out to little creatures. Beer.
Can we read the ones that I feel like
I'm going to be able to jump in on first
and then I can leave and you can do what?
I don't care.
Can we
the last two progressive rock.
Oh, I know you don't give a fuck about
that. I'll read that one. All right.
Emily Linden tweets. You don't want
to do this one? No, I dunno. Alright,
what does, who is Emily London? I didn't
know who he was. Tell she was either.
She somebody on the Twitter
sphere. Okay. She, she's uh,
she's got, um, social media.
She tweeted some a shit about,
I don't know, some shit. I don't
know. Okay. Hey, the fair trail.
Um,
I imagine you've been sent this article
many times over the last week I had,
here's an excerpt from an article about
what the writer for Teen Vogue tweeted.
A,
here's an unpopular opinion.
I'm not actually all that concerned
about innocent men losing their jobs over
false sexual assault slash
harassment allegations.
The benefit of all of us getting
to finally tell the truth.
Plus the impact on victims far capital's
far outweighs the loss of any one man's
reputation.
He said adding,
if some innocent men's reputation have
to take a hit in the process of undoing
the patriarchy. That is the price
I am absolutely willing to pay.
It's hilarious. You're not paying a
price in that. That innocent guy is, um,
the most cognitive cause
I didn't say the word.
So stupid critique of Linden came
from CNN anchored Jake tapper.
The lead host tweeted, well, this
is CNN. There's bad as Fox News.
I'm guessing you didn't get a good grade
for your seventh grade book report on
to kill a Mockingbird,
uh,
referencing the classic novel that
features the trial of a black man falsely
accused of rape in the 1930s, Alabama. Um,
you said if some innocent men's reputation
have to take a hit in the process,
fun doing the patriarchy, that is a
price, same. Absolutely willing to pay.
That's immoral. Tapper wrote, and it's not
a price you would be paying by the way.
It would be an innocent, innocent
men doing that. Um, all right.
He said, my wife is black,
is back to the guy running.
My wife is black and she has a cousin
who served six months in jail for being
falsely accused of rape. He lost
his academic scholarship, academic,
not sports scholarship,
and has been having trouble getting
his life back on track since having his
conviction overturned from being
physically and emotionally abused in jail.
She said, uh, that is she ever
wait. She said that if she ever saw
this woman in public, she and I quote,
slapped the Shit Outta that irresponsible
cont bill I've never heard of or used
the c word or even threatening violence
against anyone. It's like that light.
Now you just go in a completely different
direction. That line from Batman,
the dark night,
you either die a hero or live long enough
to see yourself become the villain.
All right. You're all over the place.
I don't know what's going on here. Um,
what do I think that, I think that's
the tweets have somebody young. Uh, and,
and also it's kind of seems,
it's a little WWE wrestling,
grandstanding, knowing there's no
way you write that, not knowing,
you know, it's like watching
down, you know, the,
the Tories guy there and the MMA guy,
the crazy shit.
He says he knows what he's doing.
Yeah. And then everyone's like, oh,
this guy's too cocky. I want
to watch it moves. And then,
then he wins and he gets your money.
I think that that's a,
I think that's all this is,
uh,
white feminism.
So that's pretty much womanism.
Yeah.
I mean that's pretty much,
this is why people don't like being
labeled a feminist because of stuff like
that. Not Elaborate. Nah. That's
all I'm going to say about it.
I feel like nobody white and
knows what you're talking about.
But everybody black right now does,
oh my God, was that shade?
Am I woke? Um, yeah.
I mean that's just one of those
that, I dunno. I don't know.
What do you do you know what? That's
how she feels. That's how she feels.
What am I supposed to,
am I supposed to actually respond to that?
Like that's like some sort
of rational human being.
What do you mean what this person
foaming at the mouth. I Dunno.
They remind me of myself
when you think of this complete.
Yeah.
And yet can I make this any more
easier for you? I love how you,
you will only wanted to fucking respond
to the ones that were easy and then when
to give you a chance to respond to you.
Like you like bill Bellacheck lion off.
She's a, yeah, it's white phone is,
I know so. Cause you know, but I, I,
but I can elaborate.
I can get into these next to elaborate.
I don't want to, I don't
want to him why, I dunno.
Maybe I am being a worse, but I just,
uh, yeah, it's, that's, I dunno,
there's really no other way for me
explain it then to say that that's,
it's just you,
it's a level of,
okay,
not nice not,
or they're not naive.
They're not
like maybe just in a bubble or something.
Just like,
so sheltered,
sheltered.
So it's like all they can focus on is
like the one thing, you know what I mean?
And they just can't quite grasp.
Yeah.
Well that's a joke I do on my act when,
when like when I listen to feminists,
like it's hard for me to listen to white
women in the United States of America
complaining, like going, do you know,
you know what it's like
to be me a slightly less
awesome than what my life is.
Like.
If you look at the big picture,
uh, I'm sure that seems to be
a giant gap between me and you,
but if you look at
everybody else's situation,
we were at what kind of
sitting on the same stone here.
So why don't you buy a run around
the lady? All right. I'm sorry.
Am I a rebound chump? Is this good
idea? Is this in your wheel house? Yeah,
I think so. Keep going.
You'd be a great president.
This is what president is due
now. They like, they basically,
I don't like the way that guy asked
questions. Let's bring this person in.
You don't have time for everything. So
you gotta you gotta weed through? No,
I do have to have time for all of
these. You don't have time. Yeah.
I'm not talking about you were talking
about me. Can we read this one? This one?
Okay. All right. Am I a rebound
chump? Probably. Dear Billy forehead.
You're saying all this funny shit
off the Mike. I'm telling you,
but they say and they can hear you.
Okay. I said probably repeat it again.
All right. The time. Yeah,
the time he's gone. All right.
Huge Fan of your comedy and
podcasts. Did you hear that? Nia?
Huge Fan of my comedy.
Huge, huge, huge, greatest,
greatest comedian ever get to do stand
up on a golf course with my own name
attached to it. Donald's Trump
would think of your podcasts.
Okay.
I mean, I don't care what
he thinks about anything,
but I wonder what he would think
about your podcast as far as what?
I don't know. Like do you think
he would be into it or not?
Even though you trash them,
you trash everybody.
I think he's busy running the country.
I don't think he's listening to
fucking nuts by the way that he tweets.
He's clearly not that fucking busy.
He's not that busy.
Who has time to tweet the
petty shit that he does?
He's got what's great about Twitter
it takes to doing all of this.
The actual stuff. He is just
sitting there like, you know the uh,
what do you call it? The spa like, I
don't know. I don't know what the fuck.
He's just, he's working. He's
got me all, he's working Obama.
Bill Clinton Work J. Yeah, that
cigar. He worked at rogue up.
I just get all flustered. I can't
even speak straight anyway. Come on.
Am I rebound chump? Is Trump really
that bad, dear Billy forehead?
So I just like getting me going. I just
like get it ahead. It's really, I mean,
I don't know.
You gotta give the guy and shit
cause it was hot as fuck in here. You're
usually the one who runs hot. I know,
I know. I know. No, I
know. Am I a rebound chump?
Yeah. Shut the fucking
thing off. Jesus Christ.
This is why it takes forever.
You the second you bring a
woman into your fucking thing.
Like if you're going to leave the house,
everything has to be perfect.
Oh my feet are together. Rub them together
like your shoe. You're always are.
Are we ready? Okay. Yes. Huge Fan
of your comedy in the podcast.
Hearing you shoot the shit every
week obviously makes me laugh,
but also gives me insight
and other things. Anyways,
it's hard to find. All right.
I get too many clock minutes.
Thank you. I met this girl,
Buddha [inaudible] who's probably the
beds are good check. While, why blah blah,
blah. I've ever been with. And her
personality so far looks just as good.
We are both in college
and neighboring states,
but we hang out a couple
of times a week on average.
Things have been going great
for the past two months.
We have traveled around her state and she
has shown me places I have never seen.
I did not expect anything to bloom like
it has and was originally content with
just being friends who fuck. However,
after getting to know her better,
she definitely seems like someone I
could stick around with for a while and
maybe even date. Um, well
what are you guys now?
Sightseeing? He just said they're hanging
out. Oh, just hanging out. Okay. Sorry.
Well, if I have to read and also listen
to what I'm saying, like I can't do that.
The only thing is it's called
reading comprehension. Bebe. Yeah,
I'm not good at it. Um, the only
thing she has, the only thing,
the only thing she has an ex who I suspect
she's still hoping we'll come back.
All right.
Incident one on our second date quote,
she rented a movie on an as Amazon on
her ex's account and got a text from him
asking,
okay,
what that was about fucking
sector about Amazon movie.
Wow.
Why
is she, what was she? What
is she doing? All right.
That's some bullshit right there.
You know good and God damn well you
can't order on your ex as account like
they're going to, they're
still paying for that. Ooh.
Sees a little minx the this one,
she seemed delighted that he was forced
to communicate with her eyes and she
wired him money and said,
sorry, incident number two.
So he's obviously broken up
with her fucking dramatic.
Oh Yeah, you ready? Okay.
Incident number two.
She originally stated that
they broke up back in February,
but one night she let it slip that
they had actually broken up in August.
Just a couple months ago. I
acted like I didn't notice. Good.
That's probably good.
After banging one night,
she starts joking about having a
baby and what features it would have.
I have brown hair as
to she and she ran the,
says the baby could be blond,
the color of her exes hair.
She then went on to say your ex's name
was one of her favorite names for a boy.
Oh, Jesus Christ. Dude,
this is always good. My God,
this is like getting ridiculous to the
point. I'm starting to not believe it.
Thankfully she waited until I finished
all my dick and balls would have deflated
immediately during all this baby
slash x talk incident number four,
Jesus Christ, buddy exhibit 1995. Um,
she still uses her ex's,
Amazon prime account to watch movies,
but on two occasions she began snooping
through his order history right in front
of me,
either unaware of how off putting that is,
are simply not giving a shit disrespectful
to myself and the x in my opinion.
Uh,
another confusing twist is that she gets
pissed off and sad if I referred to her
as my friend. We're not in an
official relationship, so this,
which is just that she is
at least kind of interested.
But with all this stuff going on about Rx,
I think she might just like the attention
I provide and I think she may be
stringing me along.
She is also randomly accused me of
using her for attention and having other
hose. Uh, neither
of which are true. Yeah. You don't sound
like it. Yeah. That has a lot of hoes.
Sorry for this long email. It's hard
to put all this bull shit into words,
which you are great at. If the, yeah,
he's in the emotional side of this.
Maybe me just reading what you
just wrote out loud will be enough.
If the lovely Nia is nearby, I would
love to hear her take as well. Thanks.
Uh, and go for a jog once in a while.
Yeah. All right. What do you got it?
Yeah.
This girl is fucking crazy and she's not
over her acts and she is using you to
get jealous and if you don't mind banging
her because she's hot and all that and
letting it go, then fine. But if you're
starting to catch feelings, I would bail.
Wow. You said that nice and quick.
I agree with all of that. I concur.
That's exactly it.
If you could somehow and
not get emotionally tied to
her and just keep banging
her
disrespectful as fuck.
She is incredibly disrespectful.
She does not care about you at all.
The things that she is saying and
doing in front of you is so ridiculous.
Like how are you going to lie
in bed with someone and be like,
you know when I have a baby, like
I ended up this, you know Caleb,
because this is also like some
white girl shit like halo.
I just feel like it'd be the perfect
name for a boy and he's the sitting there
like, are you serious? Like your ex
boyfriend? Oh yeah. You know what?
This could be a great mood and he
should be on the roof. He should
just, I dunno. I think he should
just say some just fake listen like
I have,
but this is one of these people that it's
do you don't even say anything to him
because it's not going to, they're not
going to sit there and be like, Oh wow,
I guess you're right. I really
shouldn't have done that. Just person.
It's not going to give a fuck.
So whatever man,
you got to bang a hot chick and
she's not over the other guy.
So who gives a fuck?
Thank God you didn't marry or they'll
do and thank God that other guy broke up
with her cause she seems I don't,
granted it's all you
talk has the nerve to be
mad at him when he called,
when he introduces her as a friend,
she has the fucking nerve to get mad after
all that craziness that she's putting
him through. Ah, get outta here.
Classic hot chick.
Crazy hot chick behavior though.
This is classic crazy that
I taught that I've taught.
I think I told the two weeks ago that
hot chick I'd met at the gym and she kept
giving me a number and she wanted to go
out and I kept trying to get her up but
she wouldn't go out with me. Then finally
she picks a date and yeah come over,
we can hang on Saturday and
she goes, Oh, I'm moving kids.
She wanted me to help her move
and I just burst out laughing.
I'm not fucking doing that.
And she had some other chump
who came over there too.
It going to be the two
of us standing there.
Like maybe if I pick up something
heavy can fuck whales is like,
she's all yours buddy.
Wow. Yeah. I mean I can't knock the
hustle, but that's incredibly rude.
Yeah, that's the thing. And that's
why that right there, that statement,
I can't knock the hustle, but that's
incredibly rude. That's why. Oh,
you're just being funny. Honestly,
that's, that's why I, I get all that,
that that male feminism horseshit where
they just sitting there drinking the
fucking Koolaid. Like women
just, you know, there aren't
as many,
just as many fucking absolute sociopath
psychos that have vaginas out there is,
it's not drinking the Koolaid.
They're just saying what they think women
want to hear and then they turned out
to be fucking assholes.
So Jesus Damn,
you just really get cut to the chase.
So cut to the chase here.
I'm trying to do an hour here and you
just fucking bang, Bang, boom. Done.
All right. Girlfriend wants
plastic surgery. How do you
feel about that title? Nia,
is this an easy enough class for you?
I'm excited to hear this. Hello, Bill.
Big Fan of your work. Could use
some lady advice here. All right.
Is this a lady? No. No.
Awesome lady advice. Sorry.
My girlfriend has been
dropping hints from month,
months now about getting plastic surgery
knows and boob job bump bump a Boehm bu
a while while she looks perfect in
my eyes. She said she hates her,
her junos in her tiny tits.
She has,
she has big pea size cup.
She has a pea size cup.
Sorry, that's me. Whatever
the fuck it's called,
brow or whatever the fuck it's called,
which like he, he, he, he net which w.
H. I. C. H. O. This is which on
a Bronc, which is all I need.
I tried to ignore it
for as long as I could.
Now she says she wants it for
Christmas to fake press one nose job,
so on. That was a good joke and you
should be sorry. Maybe sleeping,
sorry.
And a bag of fucking tampons
on the third day of Christmas.
My true love gave to me
three fucking removed.
No moles to boob jobs.
One bleach asshole
and a burger. Botox in
a pear tree. Come on,
let's do the plastic surgery
on the fourth day of Christmas.
My true love gave to me for corrected
hammertoes three remove no moles to fake
tits and a bleached asshole and an in
a pear tree. I can't fucking do it.
Go on
five inches off my pussy lips.
They hung down too far.
One bleached asshole too,
and some botox in a pear tree.
Nia,
can you get me hair plugs for Christmas?
We're going to go all the way to
12th on the 12th Day of Christmas.
My true love gave to me
was what would you get?
12 things of 12 stretchmarks removed?
Yeah,
you go 11 to bleached tooth is bleached.
Seven eyebrow hairs plucked. I don't know
what to say. Nick, can you get me here?
Plugs for Christmas.
But here's the thing,
I just want them right down the
center of my head. I want to get,
I want to grow a Mohawk.
Okay.
Anyways, while she looks perfect,
she says, okay, she blah blah, blah.
But now she's saying she
wants it for Christmas
or she's antisemetic no. You know what?
A lot of juice to celebrate Christmas.
What do you mean? [inaudible]? Oh yeah,
maybe she goes again and I got an
Undergrad, I went to him, you know, just,
you know these, they don't like
that she celebrates Christmas,
which I actually have two Jewish friends
to celebrate a Walmart titch to hang
out and sat in my overalls, you
know, so I know it's so stupid.
Act like only only southern
white people are racist. Wow.
All right. Um, now she's
saying she wants for Christmas.
I told her she's perfect the way she is.
I love you just the way you are bad.
But she has low self esteem,
which he can. Which dude is w?
H I c h not which wtch
wt is w. H. I. T. Yeah. No, it's w h.
I. C. H. A. W. I. T. C private pilots. Oh,
alright.
Which he is probably why she uses,
why she's with my fat,
ugly asked to begin with Jesus Christ.
Both of you guys. I know you're both
like just, you know, you have each other.
Just rub your eye Levi's.
Wow.
That close to the holidays
and my a bad influence on you.
You're never mean like that.
That's fucking hilarious.
People know that I'm nice.
They just, you know, I have,
I have my people like me who
like me, but I have, you know,
I have my moments where I can be a little
rude for no reason. Hey, well this,
he's describing it this way.
I couldn't resist though.
Cause sometimes two negatives
make a positive. They have
a great looking kid. Um,
all right.
We got into it the other night about it
and now she's saying she's not happy in
her own skin. Oh God. She wants to
be a dude and if I truly loved her,
then I should expect it.
I should accept it and get it
for her as a Christmas present.
Said some, I was being a dick about
dude, a manipulative fuck this chick.
This chick wants to get her.
No, she's trying to trade
up. She's sick of your fat,
ugly ass.
She wants you to buy some fucking save
some of your cake money and spend it on a
fucking tits or Anna knows.
Right and Oh fuck that shit.
Fuck that Shit said. I haven't felt
this way about a girl in a long time.
I love her the way she is and I don't want
to see her fuck up or looks or a body. I
don't know what to do here, Billy. Boy,
any advice would be appreciated from
you and the lovely Nia. Yeah. Fuck this.
Fuck this.
I think you get out.
Um, you're saying he should
break up with her. Get Out.
They used to break up with her. I should
help her with her self esteem. Fuck that.
What you're just going to give up on
somebody who loved because they have a low
self esteem and they're
like freaking out about it
and no, you know something. I was, I,
that was my advice until she
said you should buy me that right
for Christmas, you know, fucking
expensive. That is. Yeah.
That's very expensive. No,
no dude, no knows. Is
she watching reality TV?
She's going to try to get it on real
housewives of fucking de Moines, Iowa,
wherever the fuck you guys know you should
really like if she's really trying to
do this, it's her body and it's
her choice. She should pay for.
If she really,
really wants to do it,
she should save up her
pennies or whatever it is.
Save up like $100 a week
or whatever the fuck it is.
Cut Out all this other stuff, bullshit
that she's doing, going out with friends,
going out with you,
whatever the fuck and she should
save up for it and just be like,
I don't feel comfortable and get like
paying for you to alter your body.
That's not something that
I, you know, believe in.
That's nothing maybe I have the money for.
It's like this is your body,
this is your choice. And I support
you either way, the uh, no, no, no,
and I support you either way, but I
don't feel comfortable paying for it.
It was a sound of a dump truck backing
up in the alley that you should just drop
her in. Yeah, no, I love you. But
this is not, I'm not doing this.
I would get all feel comfortable.
I gotta be honest with you.
Cause those are boundaries right there.
And that's not,
that's not something you feel comfortable.
You are perfectly well within
your right to say no to that.
And if she has a problem with it,
then yeah,
I guess she can bounce and she's going be
pass those slow self esteem, body
issues onto her, onto your fucking kids.
It's going to be a nightmare.
She needs to go to therapy.
Oh I don't know what the fuck she needs
to do. But if I was you fuck that.
Fuck that.
Fuck that you can you sit me
and you need to pay for it.
Fuck you. That's ridiculous.
I would come over there.
I would dress up like Santa
Claus when I broke up.
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. Get
the fuck out of my life.
I'm spending all my money on me and dude,
you need,
if you think you're fat and ugly,
you could do something about the fat
and he can get a fucking personality.
So why don't you get all the money
she wants you to spend on tits? Wow.
Why don't you fucking get a drain? Or I
forget a fucking training for yourself,
dude. Fucking move on from this train
wreck. Give me a AH, Jesus Christ.
They almost ruined my
fucking thanksgiving. Oh No,
I'm just kidding. Anyways,
don't listen to me. I'm not trying to
take you to fucking break up with it,
but that, that, that's a major like, like,
what the fuck did you just
say to me moment? You know,
don't text during the Goddamn podcast.
Someone to let them know where we are.
What are you having somebody over?
But boop, boop, boop, boop, boop,
boop. All right. It's my, it's my ex.
I'm using his Netflix account, right the
front of you. So fucking deal with it
with you would be,
you know what I think is a great name?
Lamont prog rock.
I'm just trying to pick a stereotypical
black name from way back in the day.
There was nobody named Lamont, by the
way, except that guy on a Sanford and son.
A boo boo. All right.
Progressive Rock. Hey. Oh Billy.
Burford uh, glad to hear you're
looking to do more progressive rock.
Like every genre of music,
99% of it is unimaginably derivative
trash and 1% is really unique and well
done. Yeah, I like your perspective.
Your percentage might be a little harsh.
I'd like to think 10% at least as good.
Even the good stuff can be off putting
at first and just take some time to
digest. Uh, like good scotch.
It might be harsh to most people at first,
but if you put the time and you'll find
a lot of interesting shit going on. Uh,
early generous genesis is some of
my favorite checkout. The tracks,
the musical box watch
ishe did she wake up?
Okay.
A watcher of the skies and
dancing with the moon lit night.
The compositions are complex and beautiful
and Phil Calls Collins was really a
perfect drama. Yeah, he's one of
my favorite drummers of all time.
The band also had some amazing
tracks like close to the edge,
a heart of the sunrise
and gates of delirium.
Bill Bruford was one of their first was
on one of their first few albums and was
a beast. All right. You're
already mentioned King Crimson.
They had some truly great song but always
had a few improvised stinkers on each
album.
Check out 21st century schizo oid man
LARCs tongues in aspect part two and
starless Bruford his drumming
on two of those tracks. Finally,
he got to get into magma
who was one of the,
who has one of the best drummers
to have walked the earth.
I never heard of this guy,
Christian Fandor.
It's really his band.
He composed all of the music and
their sound is totally unique.
They sing in an alien language so you
don't get distracted by stupid lyrics,
but what about their alien language?
That sounds like something
that sounds like a sketch.
Will Ferrell would be an
ad almost 70 years old.
Vander plays incredibly.
They are so good live that I've flown to
La and London just to see them play in
the past couple of years.
I'll have to check this out.
Look up live videos of them playing
the last seven minutes and zombies,
your drum teacher will vouch for them.
Ease easy.
I'm also psyched to hear you
mentioned ms sugar. Uh Oh yeah,
they're unbelievable.
Uh, they were another
one that takes a lot of
time to get a feel for,
but once you figure out that almost all
of their songs are in a strange kind of
four, four, they become one of the
grooviest bands you've ever heard.
And there's no coming back.
Enjoy your foray into the weirdness of
progressive music. You speckled asshole.
That's a good one. Speckle the
asshole that said no one. So Nia,
how was your thanksgiving? It was
delicious. And I don't mean the meal.
I mean, how was the weekend?
Oh, it's great. Thank you.
There you go guys.
That's what it come tome
to raining positivity.
What he just said, that's
like a mom too. I was like,
great. Thank you. And you said,
yeah, that's what I come home. Zoo as
if I was to some big negative Nelly. No,
you just sounded like I was asking for
your autograph as you rush through an
airport. Great. Thank you.
Do you want me to say, I just want you
to throw a roll of paper towels at me.
That's what you should've done. Stop it.
Get away from me. Uh, get away from me.
He doesn't get it hosted. Stop it.
Get off of me. I will clean myself.
I'm always picking at me.
You're a mother now.
Go downstairs and go fucking pick it.
Your daughter. Isn't she beautiful?
She is knocked out. You can hear her like
really? Cause she's got a little stuck.
We know. I know. We had the best day
though. No snuck. Omar. Did you guys do,
uh, we watched the end of
the Patriots game. What's,
you know, I watched the whole
Patriots game and uh, you
know, everybody's, you know,
that's one of the reasons why I don't
get overly excited about a nine.
And to record when you play in the Miami
Dolphins, which was already, uh, just a,
a franchise that has been transitioning,
trying to get to another level for
fucking decades, it feels, feels like,
and you know,
Jay Cutler isn't playing and it's just
one of those games. We got like three,
four sacs, which are going to pad our
numbers. So then we go into the playoffs.
[inaudible] they got a decent pass,
rush and bubble pop.
This like teams like that. We'll pad
your fucking stats. I got to tell you,
that backup quarterback was
actually pretty good. Um, but,
uh, I, I just, and I love and Tamika Sue,
I just, I don't feel he's a dirty player.
I just think that that guy
plays in the wrong era. He is,
he is a fucking Dick.
Butkus violent world of Sam
huff type of football player.
He's just playing in the millennial
age. I love that guy. Um,
anyways,
so we watched that.
Then I started to watch some of the Ram
Saints Game, which was a great game.
And then, you know, she
had a runny nose and stuff,
so I was constantly
having to deal with that.
And I don't know that I read some books.
You like that baby face?
Yeah, she loves that book. I read that
book too. Like five. Really? Yeah.
She loves it. She likes it cause you
act it out. That's like, you know. Yeah.
But she gets the faces too that they're
making, you know, like, like happy face,
you know. And then the last one I'll be
like, I go, I, you know, I go laughing,
I'm like kick, kick, kick,
kick. And she'll look at me
going like, he, she laughs too.
It's fucking awesome.
That's our little like
see has like she still has those,
the big belly laughs like when
you really get her, you know,
like I got her yesterday,
you know,
but then she does a Little Hee Hee Hee
Hee Hee Alpha, which is like funny. No,
but I got the belly blast yesterday
when you were still mad at me.
Did you hear how hard it was
making her laugh? Yes I did. I say,
where are we going to talk about that?
About your,
about what you're like completely,
you know,
being mad at the wrong person because you
were upset about a game and like that.
It wasn't that what it was
was I was carrying Lola,
my ribs were killing me and
then her in the stroller.
I told you because she didn't want
to be in the stroller. I know,
but if she like has a moment where
she's like, Eh, she'll be fine.
You keep it moving and she's fine.
She's not one of those gets,
she's not at that stage yet where she
just screaming for 10 minutes straight.
That's not who she is and plus she has
to learn that you can't carry her all the
time and I wouldn't know.
But she also wrote all the way over there
on the car and then we walked up the
street, we come back down the street.
She was like, I'm over it. You know,
in the this strapped in like astronauts.
I think eventually I was like,
get this fucking thing off
me. I understand. It's like,
yeah, I wouldn't like to,
I mean I'd like to be wheeled around but
after I'm at the time we got stuck in
the ride at six flags. Yeah. That's
what they feel like. You think so? Yeah.
Like fuck out of here. Yeah, I'll
probably, I would think so anyways,
like having a full on parent conversation
right now on the podcast and nobody
goes back. All right. Sorry.
Anyways, that's the podcast.
A Happy Thanksgiving post Thanksgiving
weekend to you what but what did you say
about being mad at that little boy
when we were going down the street?
What did I say?
I don't know.
When I came in you were saying
you were just talking about it.
Did you talk about Utah? I was.
Then I was saying, I said there,
do I do this and you'll do that and
you're just going to be a good dad.
I realized I was being a baby because I
was embarrassed with my behavior there.
Is that enough? Yeah,
and she and she sat down.
She sat down next to me afterwards. I was
watching the late game and she's like,
is this game going to make you upset?
Oh my God. The amount of time sunny.
I swear to God that if you were a guy,
I would just start swinging.
That was one of those moments
I want to start swinging.
I would have done the most,
well,
most guys do acted like I was going
to swing and not you to duties.
Bring it. I'm not the one.
You know what? I am the one,
you can talk all this shit and you
want to, I'm an old man. Let's go, Bro.
You want to do this bro? And when
they're like talking top of the bar,
let's go bro. Yeah. You know what
fucking frat boy white guys also do.
They'll bite your ear off
fucking lunatics. Especially
if their dad's a judge.
Um, you had to the pens
on like what fucking yeah,
yeah.
I stayed out of that world.
I did not like that world at all.
That world was fucked right when,
when I came,
the shit that they used to do
to people during fucking hazing,
the fucking stories.
I'm telling you the stories like fucking
guys got from getting hazed to it.
It was, it was fucking like Frat guy,
white frat guys. I mean, a
lot of guys can drink a lot,
but like they really make
it like a competitive thing.
I'm not talking about that. I'm not
talking about that. And it'd be a,
and we stuck a fucking care it up.
His ass kid was screaming.
I just, what I remember that was one of
my first jokes in my standup back. Yeah,
people go, how come you didn't
join a Frat? I was like,
I dunno cause I kinda got this thing
about letting other guys show fruit up my
ass. And he used to get a laugh back
in the 90s because everybody know,
oh that was like funny.
Like oh hazing.
Like people actually die from that.
So now you don't die from that.
You did souls crushed.
How about talking about them making
you drink all the water and all,
you know when he eat all these
pancakes and then they die.
That's millennial shit.
I'm talking about what the fuck they used
to decent fucking beat the Shit Outta
you and fucking a ass. Rapey with
fucking nuts. The stories. I used to hear
the shit I used to fucking hear that
people used to do to each other and I,
I was just like, I used to always
think of that and then what?
Then you get to hang out
with them afterwards.
I'm not saying that always
fucking happened but through
some of the [inaudible]
this is a one ivy league school with it.
This is some pew pancake
you have to fucking eat.
And somebody finally said something about
it and all these older people that he
was a Dartmouth or something and they
were all mad like dude I can't believe
it's gotten all it's called.
No it's called the vomit.
Disgusting. Why, why,
why is that necessary
to be in a,
in a group to do that sort of thing?
It because they're fucking
losers cause cause cause your,
cause you're exploiting somebody at
a very weak moment in their life.
They've left their parents, they, they
need new friends, they want to fail.
And I always was just, yeah
I draw. Yes. Hell yeah.
You should hear the fucking stories.
Like some of my relatives were in frats,
some of the shit they did to them
took them outside the dead of winter,
sprayed him with like a fire hose because
somebody threw a bucket of paint on
one of the older brothers or whatever.
Spreading with bucket paint. Yeah.
Got like fucking pneumonia almost died.
They could just beat the shit out of you.
It was bad.
Then every once in a while you hear the
fruit that I want to make it seem like
everybody did that. But I remember being
a gold's gym and this guy was sitting,
I think it was just talking about Hasan,
people at football camp and he was
going like, yeah. Then we shoved the,
carry it up. It says kid was
fucking screaming out there.
They're hazing experience, but
like anonymously, cause you know,
I don't want to do that. I'm not going
to do a fucking me to guy thing here.
All right.
I don't want to blame the victims,
but I heard what happened and I
was just like, yeah, fuck frats.
Look at my own friends. Yeah, you gonna
you gonna you gonna rush a Frat. Yeah,
I'll think about a buddy.
Are you, would you just,
you do not have the personality to
be in a fraternity at all. Yeah.
That is the opposite. That
you would, you would eat,
you wouldn't even get past the
first day. Yeah. I, I couldn't,
I couldn't get through the fucking army.
I can get to the army.
You couldn't hear you. Yeah,
you're dead. You're dead.
What are you going to do? Beat the shit
out of me then. I don't have to go to war.
I'll do that.
Oh,
did I get a dishonorable discharge?
I'm still fucking here. Oh, I'll do
that. Private bearskin whole Sassy.
No, I never would have made no, here's
the deal. At my age when I was young kid,
I would have done whatever the
fuck they said. If I was 18, 19,
fuck they said. Yeah. Yeah.
So that's why they do it. But yeah.
Anybody middle-aged. All right. Yeah.
I'd be like Michael J. Fox and like, yeah.
What are, what are we doing here, sarge?
All right, that's it. Um, alright.
Go fuck yourselves. I need to worry.
I'm in this podcast. Uh, I'll talk
to you guys on Thursday, right?
If you want to throw on your fucking
hate your football hazing in, in, in, um,
okay.
Yeah,
I'm above all of that shit.
I remember like faculty members going
talking about Shit that they saw
fucking older kids doing the other kids.
Yeah,
women's do I want to hear
like the sorority and I
don't want to hear it because
it's at this fucking time, because what
you're going to do with Zick creating,
this is how they, everybody's
looking at like Hollywood right now.
Like it's this giant non-consent
consensual like fucking orgy.
And it isn't.
Most people aren't here busting their
ass to fucking great people in all that,
but then now they're going to
say that everybody's, you know,
how are you have you
don't fucking suck a deck.
You're not going to get a fucking
commercial. It's like dad. No.
There's so many amazing, wonderful
people that work in the industry.
So that's true. That's true.
And if they all have to go down,
I don't give a fuck because I'm a
white chicken. My twenties all right,
go fuck yourselves up.
Check in on you on Thursday.