All right.
Hey,
what's going on is bill burr and it's
time for a special episode of the Monday
morning podcast. It's not on
Monday. It's not on Thursday.
It's coming out, I guess
what? Tuesday, Wednesday.
We're going to put this out as soon as
we can. I have a special guest here.
You know, I don't do a lot of
guests, so if I bring somebody in,
they gotta be a heavy hitter. That's
right. They got to be a mover, a shaker,
a shot caller. We have the one and only
John Apatow here. Pleasure to be here.
How are you buddy?
I like to be,
or usually you're all by yourself
just talking to the wall. Yes I am.
And usually you're in the
midst of producing was
fascinates me. I tried to, uh,
talk to you about this because a, I like
to think I'm kind of a busy man too.
How you manage to have movies,
TV shows,
standup special masterclass,
a documentary on Garry Shandling,
how they'll fuck management.
Keep all like how big is the bolt and the,
the war room?
It's all management technique.
That's what you want to know.
I'll tell you a good management technique.
The staff of crashing is the room
right now writing the fourth season.
Third season comes out in January,
but they're writing the fourth
season and I'm here with you.
Yes, that's managed well. So
how do you check in with that?
How do I check it every day?
Did they send you a draft and you just
kind of keep it in bounds of where it
needs to be or at season four?
Is it sort of up and running?
Well, usually what it is is Pete
and I, uh, and also the Judah,
Mila and Oren who work on the show.
We'll kick around a little bit what
we think the season might be, right?
We bring in writers for a month and
we just kick it around very openly,
like anything is on the table and I'll
pop in and out of those meetings and,
and then there's notes that I'll read
the notes and then sit in for half a day
and then take a day off
and then pop back in.
And usually that gives me
some perspective. Because
you've been in those rooms.
There's a lot of Chinese food, there's
a lot of danishes. He get tired.
Lunch is huge.
There's a lot of people talking about
things that have nothing to do with the
show for very long periods of time.
Uh,
and then at some point I'll sit with
Pete and he will go through everything
right and go, okay,
which ideas do we like?
You know what my favorite thing is?
Is the mental break.
You taking the writer's room, it's
like you're pitching, you're pitching,
you're pitching,
then you're fried.
And like I always look around the room
and I'll just see someone hasn't pitched
him in it and that just sort of staring
down at the ground for about 15,
20 minutes. And then they just come
back and be like, yeah, all right.
What if frank did that? If I can get,
but you literally, you have to do it.
And um,
what I learned on f is for family though,
is I didn't realize how fried you get yes.
In the writer's room.
And like my drinking went
off the rails a little bit.
It was was one little scotch and then it
just became like three. So last season.
At what time is
day though?
Are you having your Scotch in the room?
Oh, not in the room.
That was when I got home.
When I got home I would literally
just, you know, put on the fireplace,
turn it on now cause you
don't light a fire anymore,
you just turn it on and then I
would just sit there like uh, yeah.
And it was getting to that shit.
It was just like I need
this at the end of the day.
So in season three like I did this thing,
I'll go,
not only may not drink in this season,
I'm actually gonna try to do the
impossible, which is drop weight and just,
which I did, how I packed a
lunch. Like I was a second grader.
So every day that they would be going
out now I had like this keenwah being
thing that I would always have. And then
yeah, just fruit and nuts, you know,
it would be my, my snacks or
whatever. Cause this whole reward,
you want to reward yourself. You
know, you get to work whatever, nine,
10 o'clock and all you think,
oh morning is that they get 1230.
The food's gonna lay hand. Oh
yeah, the food's going to land.
Then we could stop talking about this
showing if this food and if everybody
voted a place that you fucking hate. It's
just like that is the longest day ever.
But if you're going to like,
you know,
it's like a Friday and they picked an
awesome like lunch place like d that can
literally,
you pitch better.
But I liked that you are not in charge
of that because the only area I will
throw my weight around right is if they
say, hey, we're going to eat here today.
I'm very comfortable going,
we are not going there today.
Daddy needs this right now. There's
definitely a, there's a, uh,
there's also, there's a generation
gap and that also goes with nutrition.
You know, so there's people like
my show takes place in the 70s.
So that's those people that grew up in
the 70s and the other people who were
born in the 80s.
So there they're more likely to go to
something a little more healthy than the
old sort of John Wayne people in the
room. I'm like, I'm not eating that shit.
And some days there's a little bit
of a mutiny, but it's not about, uh,
the writers from here. I actually, they
sent me, which was really cool. Thank you.
You guys send me a link to the first
episode of season three of crashing with
the Great Pete Holmes. And,
uh, just once again, it's like,
like watching that show, it's like,
I've, I've lived this, I've, I've,
I don't want to give away what
the episode is about, but I mean,
and generally speaking,
it's like Pete has now gotten to the
point where he actually has his own place,
which is awesome. And he's mentoring
a young man. Yes. Yabuki from, uh,
a daily, it was on the daily show. Oh,
okay. Yeah. Who's great and it's he,
he finally feels cocky enough to give
someone else advice. Yeah. Oh yeah.
You have to sit and talk.
Like he's in the mix.
He's kind of feeling himself
a little bit and as always,
this business will humble you. So he ends
up getting humbled in. It's like, uh,
just the way the, the, uh,
how you, when he gets humbled,
I don't want to say it is
the way it's written that uh,
he then lashes out at this person that
he kind of smoothed stuff over with.
And that's just like the worst,
especially with the woman.
Then you get that whole, you are enjoying
this, aren't you? You're enjoying that.
I mean, I literally had that fight
with my wife like two days ago.
What was she enjoying then? I lost my
temper. Yeah. And then she, you know,
and then she gets, you know, like,
you know how the deal is with women.
Nothing is off bounds,
but like you with you,
you have to stay within the lines are,
I'll, she'll never hear the end of it.
So you know, she, you know, you know, she
was driving the car all over the place,
all over my life.
Let
me know who I was. But you know, she
was right about a lot of it. And, uh,
that's a worst part is that they
are right about a lot of it. No,
but they're all so wrong. So I did
this, this whole period now where women,
like they went from nobody listening to
them to now everything that they say is
spun with gold is, it's, it's, it's,
it's getting ridiculous. I was like,
we have to be okay, let's, let's,
you know, women are like, guys,
a lot of them are just full
of Shit, you know, as our men.
So I mean that's the art of life is
trying to figure out who actually has the
information that you need, which is why
when I talked to you, how to, you know,
manage a shell, you have the goods with
everything you've got going on here. Um,
well sometimes you know,
the thing about it is that you do need
someone who has the perspective to judge
ideas and how things are going.
So there's a process of generating
maybe a thousand ideas for a show,
but if you're burnt out from
being part of that generation,
it's hard for you to pick what works.
Yeah.
And so like at girls I,
I was very involved in the writing,
but I wouldn't go to the set
because it was so well directed.
There was no reason for me to be there.
The footage always was great.
And Lena and January graded monitoring
the directors and directing themselves.
At what point did you have
confidence to be like, all right,
this thing is cruising?
Well,
I don't think I ever felt like
it was it w it was cruising,
but I had confidence in if the script
was good, they would shoot it great.
And then I can put all my energy into
just reading the scripts to give them a,
a person who could tell them if
the script's worked, you know,
so they were tired from shooting and
writing and they're exhausted and I,
I'm able to have a little more energy
to just read and go on to page four.
It's weird. Why did they say
that? It's not tracking and it's,
that's hard to do when you're in the
thick of it and you're exhausted.
And so there is a value to,
you know,
picking where you're helpful and where
you're like, you don't need me here.
I don't have to sit and look at over the
director's shoulder. You're nailing it.
Let me save that energy for the
writing part. I hate to admit this,
but actually enjoy being in
the writer's room. Oh yeah.
I was like kicking and scream and thinking
about God, I'm a comedian. I'm free.
Why the fuck am I going to
go back into the math class?
So whatever I should say it.
It's on days where it's working,
when it's working and it's cruising and
we're getting good notes, you know, uh,
we always get good notes, but I
mean, positive notes from Netflix,
like we enjoy this, but then on the
days where like, this doesn't really,
there's too much of that.
And then we go, all right,
and then we try to fix it and
then it's just not working.
Those are the days where I feel like I'm
back in high school and I'm just like,
it's like, it's the clock broken. Like
what, what, what are we doing here?
So you're the teacher.
That's the thing, you know,
when you work on the show
and you're not the teacher,
like at the Larry Sanders show, if we
did a table read and it wasn't working,
then suddenly there is
someone upset with you, right?
And you are ashamed child that at
the script and look up and you're,
then you're like, how can I fix it? And,
and there's almost a daddy or mommy
character that you're disappointing if the
show isn't working or
if the isn't working.
There's a lot of ways for it to be
super unhealthy, but it is more fun.
You're right when you're that person and
you can treat people well and you have
your own strong point of view,
it's not as painful.
Well, I would say in my room it, Mike
prices, he's the captain of the ship.
So I'm the guy that's sorta chimes
in and tries to like, I dunno, uh,
keep it like certain things
tethered to reality if it,
if it starts getting a little
too like absurd. But you know,
you brought up Gary Shandling who like,
you know,
anybody who was even
remotely in the comedy just,
and I mean that guy is like on the Mount
Rushmore there. And uh, I just remember,
you know, I watched, you know, you know,
this is the theme, the gallery show.
I watched this first one,
I watched everything.
I used to watch this tonight show sets.
I just always just thought the guy,
he just always, it was funny when
even like when I was in junior high,
I was like in seventh grade I knew that
his stuff was just funnier that it was,
this is like a different level.
Like this guy is better than all of these
other guys. And I was wondering what,
like what was that like, you know, cause
I, I really, I sent an email about that.
Like I thought the Garry Shandling
documentary that you did with that,
that's my favorite thing you've done.
And I have thank you,
40 year old virgin and all this stuff.
But um,
what was that like because you were
friends with somebody like that? Um,
you know, myself, I've lost a couple of
friends and I know that certain things,
it just gets like really emotional.
What was the key,
but I never delved into their life.
To the level that,
that you did with, with Gary, who was
like a friend and a mentor to you.
Like what was that process like? Like
how long did it take you to, to, to,
you know, cause that was on par with
like, did you see that eagles documentary?
I love that. It was like three hours
long and it fell. He was 20 minutes.
I got through like a cross
country flight watching that.
I felt like the Gary Shandling duck
was like that. What was that like?
It was like the Eagles Doc. If,
if Gary, uh, wasn't on coke. Yeah.
Well you know, it's funny cause now that
it's over and I've been, uh, you know,
I finished at six or eight months ago,
something like that. Looking back,
it's almost like a fever dream that
I even did it right because he died.
I was really depressed and it threw me
more than I thought because he was a
constant presence of support and I didn't
realize what an important beam he was
in everything. And, and uh, and I thought,
I think there's just a lesson
that he wants to teach everybody.
And I'll tell you a story that it kind
of launched the documentary is that I
went to Gary's cremation.
And so Gary's cremation was very,
I mean, people don't go to cremations.
You're not supposed to go to cremation.
When you saw him, like
sliding the body in, well,
kind of the CSUS Jud basically,
basically, uh, how did you get
tickets to that? I mean, I only,
I only tell this story
because I think it's, it,
it's helpful to people in their
own lives is that, uh, you know,
a friend put together
a very small service.
So if you can imagine there's only
like eight people there and you know,
oven basically and,
and like for a Buddhist monks,
right?
So it takes the edge off a little bit.
Like here, they're not freaking out yet.
They would, they were fine with
it. That's their whole religion.
So we go to this place and it's in the
valley and it's not that far from these
offices and it's, you know, a crematorium.
Is it part of a strip mall is like
ramen noodles, getting a tax done,
watching your friend get burned.
Even worse,
deeper in the valley where it's just
next to a place that like, you know,
makes glass bowls or something
in an industrial area.
So we go there, it's clear no one's
ever had a service in this space.
This isn't what people do, right?
So there's no like room to do it.
We're literally in like the lobby of a
place that looks like a sham business of
some someplace. Right? And like
what they're selling in the lobby,
there's literally just like
one desk and empty space.
And did you make sure it was Gary
underneath fucking we should a crash test
dummy. That'll be 50 grand. Like
what they were selling there.
They had these little,
these little pamphlets where you could
take some of the ashes of your beloved
and have them put into like a little
glass figurine you could put on your table
or like something you would wear itself,
gone,
gone. So we go, we go to
this, this place, and, uh,
we go into this little room and again,
it's like a,
couldn't be ratty are
really, and they have, uh,
a service, uh, which is very
sweet and it's beautiful.
[inaudible] and moving and all of
the ideas of, of Buddhism and the,
and, uh, and then they
take us in this room.
Now the room with the crematorium,
it's like the kitchen to a restaurant.
It's just like a big room with a
cement floor and like four or five.
So they did a little service. They hit
some little fucking gongs or something.
Like what happened?
Yeah,
they did Buddhist prayers and they
talked about Carrie's life and,
uh, and, and what life is about, you
know, you, you live, you die, you,
you learn the lessons that you can,
you try to be as loving and kindness.
You can hopefully you, uh, you know,
you grew and it was very sweet tea.
That actually sounds cool. Now,
did they believe in a heaven and hell?
Buddhists people, here's what my issue,
Buddhism is.
As you get deeper and deeper into it,
it heads to reincarnation.
I,
I believe and I always get lost
when things get too magical.
I like something that's clear, like
life is about being kind. And that's it.
Like that's,
that's as far as I usually can get.
I use this script writer
and you needed to land
magical in any way. As soon as someone's
reborn and goes to heaven or, hell, I'm,
I've lost, I have trouble
now. I'm not 100% closed,
but I'm pretty close. Uh, but I do,
I can get interested in ideas that are
about how can we let go of our egos and
be kind. That's all I need. Okay. So
we have the service and it's, and it's,
they bring into the other room moving
and then we go in the other room
and it's literally a table
with a cardboard coffin.
And then they say some more prayers.
And then at some point
they open up an oven,
which looks like almost like
a dishwasher in a restaurant.
And they roll it into flames already
going or do they turn it on after they
closed the door?
There's a pilot light and uh,
and then what did they stick?
It's literally not that far
from a pizza oven. Okay.
And you know, they put,
uh, the cardboard coffin,
then they close,
close it almost like if a dishwasher in
a restaurant and then they ask who wants
to push the button? Oh
Jesus. And you know,
they're saying that they have a bunch
of fake buttons, like a firing squad.
Like somebody gets to like young
guy really blows his brains out.
He had no one wants to know who,
who pushed the button.
You don't want to carry that. And
then a friend of Gary's, you know,
push the button and then
suddenly you're here at fire up,
you know,
it's getting hotter than your normal
pizza oven and the room gets hot.
And then it's like you smell
something burning. Like it's like,
you know,
if there was like a fire
at your neighbor's house
and suddenly you like your
chest hurts a little bit, then
you realize it's Gary, they, it,
there's no vent,
I guess.
I guess it maybe it was a place
that needed more ventilation. No,
I mean there is a vent.
It's not like overpowering,
like the room is all filled with smoke,
but you know,
do you realize like someday if you go
on a fast to get rid of toxins in your
body, part of that is Garry Shandling.
Exactly. And that would sadden me.
But, but that's what was crazy about
it. So now I love Gary so much.
I will never go on a fast and I breathed
it. Wow. And so, so I'm, you know,
watching this, crying my
eyes out, just balling.
It's as intense as anything
I've ever experienced.
This is pretty heavy and I'm feeling it
in my chest and I'm aware like that's
Gary, we're breathing in Gary. And
at first it, you know, pardon me,
it made me laugh like, yeah, cause this
is super creepy dude. You know, it's,
it's creepy. It's kind of weirdly, uh,
like the Gary always would make the
joke like I'm inside you, you know,
like there's like a sexual
joke to be made there.
And then I just thought God
carry would find this so funny.
All of us sitting here crying,
watching them cremate his,
he would think that this was fantastic
like me here bawling my eyes out.
Gary would look and just go like,
that's right. That's what it is.
That's what it is. And, and
I thought in that moment,
this is a lesson like having to
look at that will change your life.
Having to be at the crematorium
about, you know, what's important,
what do we care about?
How do we treat people?
What do you want to do with your life?
And I thought, Gary wanted me here.
He wanted me to go through this
hell in this freaking, you know,
always this part of his like,
no, he didn't ask for it,
but I decided in like a spiritual
level. I thought, this is it.
Gary wants me to learn every freaking
lesson to the point of his incineration.
He wants me to look at in the eye and
take from it whatever I can take to be a
better person.
And I think in that moment was the
seed of how do I tell other people this
lesson?
Because I think in Gary's life he was
trying to figure out how to talk about
this stuff.
And you know,
it's very hard in comedy to do it
without seeming really corny or weird.
You know,
as soon as people start talking about
their spirituality in a sincere way,
we're all like, shut the
fuck up. And it feels,
you gotta be interviewed by Oprah and
she has to bring it out of you and act
like, well, she asked me
exactly the only way to,
that's the only cool way to do it. I
mean, I had so many friends that tried to,
and they always seemed odd.
And I think Gary,
when he did comedians
in cars getting coffee,
it was the first time he found
a way to be really funny,
but talk about some things
that he believed in.
And I think that was his goal
near the end of his life.
He was trying to figure out
how to reinvent how he did
stand up and get some of
these ideas in and he hadn't quite
cracked it. He was really into silence.
He loved not getting a laugh.
He loved putting people
through weird silences.
And he would say to the crowd
that that's where it all is.
It's all in that silence. Right.
And he didn't have a joke.
He didn't even know what to do with it.
He just knew in the room went dead
contemplating is what they're doing.
They're contemplating
with what was just said.
And so what I was working
at his memorial service,
I cut together four or five little mini
docs about Gary and when I was making
them I thought,
oh yeah,
there's a whole movie about Carrie
about what he believed in and,
and that's how it started.
Well, it's incredible.
And it just came out on Blu ray people
out there and still have the blue ray
players. You know, I still have
a, I have a DVD VCR player,
but my TV's too advanced and I
can't hook it up to that self.
Anybody knows that there's some sort of
adapter or some darn thing I can do to
try and make that work.
I would appreciate it.
But it's a lot of shit cause you know,
I, I, you know, finally became a parent.
So I had to get my affairs in
order. You know, it's a guy,
you got to make sure everybody's
going to be okay. You got the will,
got to the point like I gave,
I hooked my wife up so much like she
has motive. Like if I die suddenly,
um, I've had the conversation with
my wife and the insurance agent.
Have you done this conversation yet?
Will you sit with an insurance
agent about life insurance? Well,
Judd lives to this age. You get
this. If he, if he lives at this age,
you get that and it's gambling.
You're gambling on me.
Die In paying against yourself. Like, ah,
died before you thought I was going to.
Now you've got to give them all
this money. But my wife wouldn't
by the extra insurance. Cause
she said, I feel really weird,
uh, you know, having any, you
know, handicapping your death.
And she was deeply upset
at the conversation.
That was like six or seven years ago
and just the other day she's like,
maybe we should get that insurance.
Yeah, that's what happened.
That's after a while you and I want you
to have kids and stuff. But like I, uh,
you know,
I went with the cremation thing.
I think it's so stupid to stick yourself
in the box and then there's like,
you're that important that there's got
to be like a headset I guess is for the
living people have someplace to go.
But I think now just with
the world population,
I mean the graveyards at some point,
I mean they,
I don't know if they're going to dig
deeper if you're going to be underneath
somebody else, but uh, I've
had a lot of people go,
well what did you still feel stuff?
And it's just like,
well then let's get it over with.
Which friend of yours thinks
she's still feel stuff.
A lot of people are afraid of death.
It's just the stuff that, you know,
something I don't even know. Cause
I, I, my short term memory is bad,
but a lot of people say that about the,
about like, you know, if you get cremated,
what if you still feel
stuff? It's like, well,
I'd rather just get it
over with in a minute.
I guess I die again somehow
in that minute. But, uh,
rather than laying there waiting for the
worms to slowly work their fucking way
in, burn it and toss it out
of an airplane, I want to go,
I want to, I wish I don't just
probably isn't legal in this country,
but I want to do it like the Viking
way. Like, make a little ship. Sure.
Send me out there. It gives people shoot
some flaming arrows, you know, giving him,
make it a little contest. It's
like a burn it on the Ganges. Yeah,
it's like a clay pigeon type
of thing. But, um, anyways,
uh, what else we got? We got a benefit
coming up too that you're doing a,
at the Grammercy for the Ronald McDonald
House is one of the great charities out.
They can go to Judd apatow.com/tour.
That's January 15th. Uh,
Graham is a Gramercy theater.
Yeah. In the, in New York and it's a
Pete and John Malaney, Pete Holmes,
Regina Spektor and some cast members from,
uh,
from crashing like Buki and
Jamie Lee and me. And uh,
yeah, it's where the Ronald Mcdonald's
house, which is an monster lineup. John.
Yeah.
I'm
Laney, man. That guy's just, he's just
a in New York, England, genius guy.
Um, so, uh, all right. What
else? What else do we, can we,
uh, can we discuss it? We've,
we've, we promoted, we've
promoted your masterclass.
I have a master and the presence of
them. How do you get, I do like get the,
somebody approached you with like,
uh, with something like that.
Like you want to just like,
I could teach a master class
on how not to read out loud,
how to fuck things up, uh, how
to make your wife mad at you for three
days in a row. Sure. I have that mastered.
What was your, what was
your masterclass? Well, I,
I did it because my friend Jay
Roach who directed Austin Powers,
he directed my masterclass.
So it's basically several days of talking
to Jay Roach who's asking me questions.
There's no crowd or anything like that.
And not like a Ted talk or anything. No,
it's just an, they just
edit it, edit it up. And uh,
and I think it came out really well.
You know,
the thing you probably know because you've
worked with a lot of people and staff
is so much of it is just inspiring people
to work hard. People are so damn lazy,
like people just don't
put in the effort at all.
I told him, I told someone that
the other day, I was like, look,
you got to have a certain level of talent.
But what separates people is just like,
I mean the people who have like that work
ethic and it's almost got to be like,
and people in this business,
I kind of workaholics, um,
and like I've learned
that with F is for family.
So many people ain't want to go through
it again. I was like, Oh yeah, yeah.
I'm like, these people are fucking insane.
Like they don't want to go home. Um,
but the people that I saw like
just really, really, really work.
I don't want to name any names
because then if I don't name names,
people saying what he's saying,
I'm fucking lazy. But I just,
I saw a lot of people that
weren't the guy. Yeah.
But work their way, like into
being the guy. But like, you know,
with you,
it's got to feel good when somebody
comes to you and asked you to teach your
master class.
I mean,
you certainly have the body of work
and all this stuff that you've done it
because I, that's I think the last
three times I've, I've talked to you,
that is what I've asked you.
How do you and my delegation of that Shit,
because I still want to be a
comedian and still, you know,
and the only way to go still being good
is you have to be out there doing it.
But if, if, how do I, you know,
but I also love doing the show and then
also got to be a dad. Like how do, how,
how the fuck do you balance all of it?
So it's some of that in, in there, right?
Yeah, absolutely. And I think
that like a lot of it is uh,
that you're just pushing,
pushing balls forward.
So you may be on the road doing standup
and you have a great idea for a movie
and it's just making sure in
some consistent way you're
pushing it forward and
making progress.
Now you might finish it in three months,
you might finish it in three years,
but if you have four or five
things going at the same time,
that's really what it is, is, you know,
I might get up in the morning and go
from the moment I get up to lunch,
I'm going to work with Pete and in
the afternoon and I'm doing a movie p
Davidson, I'm an old, I'm
going to rewrite p Davidson.
And then did you get to get burned out?
Do you get frustrated?
The Illusia Temby seem like a chill guy.
It's just like a, is this how you are?
Or like you behind the scenes,
you one of those guys throwing
laptops like it doesn't work.
We're going to stay here all night where
I only get crazy on two issues. What,
like two or three issues. One is
if the food order is wrong, I just,
I, I can't handle it. Like if they
don't bring the salsa with the Burrito,
like I so reward myself with the food
that could go viral, that could go bad.
You're, you're, uh, you're,
you're flipping out and
that's okay. That's, that's,
that's understandable.
My biggest of shame where I go,
you really lost it are mainly around food.
But the areas where I get
crazy one is I used to,
people would tell me I couldn't have my
casting and that would always drive me
crazy if I said,
you know who the star of the show you be?
It should be Jason Segel.
And then Fox would go, no,
that's where my head would explode.
And where would you explode on the phone
to them? In your car to your windshield?
Every, every scenario. I mean, I, I'd
be, I'd be screaming, I'd be in tears.
I would be threatening. I'd have agents
calling and I never won. As a result,
it took me years to realize,
oh,
all my emotional reactions
have never won me the fight.
And then when I stopped behaving that way,
I started winning more of those debates.
But I would get so upset because to me
the worst thing in the world is if you
have an edit of a movie and someone
forces you to change it and you've ruined
your own movie due to someone.
Is that happened? Well I,
that's the one here.
I just can't allow to happen now.
I have had things change in the past
that I look back at more. So, you know,
a couple of decades ago where I
did give in and now even right now,
if I thought about that movie, I'd be
like, Oh why did we cut that scene?
They told us to cut that
scene and there was a scene in
you failed three cause you were young and
it just trying to get your foot in the
door. Everybody always says that thing,
you know, you just gotta let him get him,
get you the first time,
and then the next time you'll be
able to write your own ticket.
Now do you subscribe to that?
Well, I think it's true. Only
in the sense that you can't win.
You just don't have the power.
Right.
So we made this movie heavyweights and
Paul Feig was in it and still are played
the bad guy who was a summer
camp for fat kids and it was,
it was a Disney movie.
And then when we finished it and see real
directed it and wrote it with me, uh,
it was just a little darker than
any Disney movie you've ever seen.
And it ended with was that was funny.
It was funny.
And not in the way that a lot
of those movies are. Yeah.
I'd still here at the end of the movie,
he's lost his mind.
He's the owner of this fat camp and he's
like this like demented Tony Robbins
guy and he's got a bow and Arrow and
he's like threatening to kill all the
children. Right. And
Disney said, you know,
you really can't have
him like point pointing,
bow and arrows from Chile and children
were like three feet away. Right.
And so we had to Riyadh at the sequence.
That's the kind of stuff,
I'll wake up at two in the morning and go,
why did we cut out the god damn bow and
Arrow sequence still eats at you it.
Oh yeah. And I might have five of
those. And so that's where I can
what point in your career where you're
like, all right, all right Chad.
Screaming at people flipping out during
these moments isn't working. Yeah.
Like how did you, cause I am
like, my big Achilles' heel is,
is uh, it's not, but it's funny. It's
not at work. I don't flip out. Yeah.
In comedy clubs, I don't,
I've never flipped out at, uh,
F as a family. I've raised,
my voice of [inaudible] is crying.
Wait, how do we fuck about,
but I never like got to the
point of light, you know,
never had a big, you know,
storm out fucking throwing shit.
Never had one of those.
But like it's more like at, at, at
home. Yeah. I, I, uh, I, you know,
I just,
I flip out about just stupid shit.
Like I fucking suck at these iPhones
and laptops I get so I'm so frustrated
because I don't like them.
Technology doesn't fascinate me.
It's not something I'm interested in.
It's really, it's ruined the world. So,
you know, anyways, it has it now.
The other ways it hasn't met
with medic medically is it's nice
when your kids are older and they
don't look up at you for hours. You'll,
you'll go,
they ruin the world.
Yes. I, yeah, that aspect of
it. But I definitely like, uh,
I just don't like how yesterday I knew
how to use this device and then now I
don't, now I have to go through this
fucking bullshit. It's just every time,
you know,
you move three feet ahead,
they knock you back with the new
updated system and then you can't,
you can't opt out of not updating.
It cause you to be able to keep your
phone for years and there's just like, no,
we're going to fill up this fucking phone
until you have to bring it in and then
we're going to take everything off it and
sell it to some kid in the Philippines
and you just feel like you're
just part of this thing.
And like that's the type of shit,
like I'm trying to, uh, you know,
and I'm failing miserably at it.
But explaining the flip out, is it a
loans, the throwing it against the wall.
Are you yelling at another person?
Like what does it turn into?
I just literally like,
my wife will be just totally chilling,
watching TV and then I of
where I'll just be like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me.
You fucking piece of shit.
I flip out like that and like what? I
don't know, cause I grew up with that.
I didn't understand what it was doing
to her as far as just really just having
her be on edge. And uh, yeah. So I mean,
how does she tell you not to do it?
What's her approach to
telling you to chill out?
Oh man, she's just straightforward.
She's straightforward. She said,
she said some shit, I'm not going to,
you know, this is too intimate detail,
but she said some shit to me like two
days ago that I will never forget.
And I was like,
wow,
well good.
When you have a kid it changes everything
because she knows you're about to do
it in front of a child that
understands it. So when they're little,
they're babies and you
can go in the other room,
but at some point you just spend so
much time with your kid that they will
absorb it and then you go to,
I like the way I move in the world
cause I think my kid's going to copy it.
Yeah.
So fortunately I am really on my best
behavior for the most part around my kid.
She's seen me flip out a few times,
but I quickly tried to turn it in and do
a joke. But, uh, it's something, yeah,
I got to go to therapy dude. Cause I, I,
I don't wanna cause she's getting to the
point now where she's repeating stuff
and I just don't, I don't want to, this is
the deal. She's not going to be like me.
I already know she's not going to be
like me, uh, as far in a, in a good way.
So I mean that's, that's kind of
what, what does that say about me?
Like my job as a dad is to
make my kid not like me. Well,
the one thing I think your half of me,
but I don't want you to be me at all.
I want you to be like your mom.
Well they don't really have the damage of
us, you know. So that's
something I've noticed is, you
know, my kids are hilarious,
but they're neurotic kids too,
but they didn't go through some of the
intense things and I went through that
really builds how my mind works.
But I'm sure they have their own,
their own menu.
No,
I bet there's a whole new level of
shit with just like social media didn't
exist. So like what I liked about my
childhood was one school was over,
the ass kicking was over, whatever thing,
humiliation. I could go home. It was fine.
It didn't continue. The Mike Douglas
show was on, you'd watch it, you'd heal.
Yes. Yes. There wasn't this think
tank of kids trying to, you know,
getting all online and pile on you
and the shit that they deal with. So,
and they know when they're being excluded.
So the biggest issue is
because of Instagram,
you're aware of what you've been invited
to. So when people are hanging out,
you're like, oh, they didn't want
me at this thing when I was a kid,
I was excluded by everybody.
I had one or two really good friends.
But basically if I thought about it,
if I think about it now,
I was excluded from every possible
social thing that was happening when it
passed at the club. But I, but
I didn't know it, you know,
I just would go home every day and just
watching the Dinah shore show and be
fine and wait for my friends
to get back from football.
But now the kids know like, oh, those
three girls went to the mall. Oh,
those two are hanging out at this
concert. And they feel bad. No.
And then they take a picture,
which is not an accurate depiction
of what it's like. It's like,
it's like this selling the movie of
their life or anything. So that's the,
uh, that's the thing I get nervous
with and that's been a source of, uh,
you know, back and forth.
Me and my wife is like,
I don't like her watching TV and all of
this shit and I don't like her eating
junk food. And uh, you know,
and she has more of like,
like she wants a little bit of TV.
She occasionally has Mcdonald's and six,
like say I ain't, but you know, I mean,
this is the fights you have because yeah,
you,
when you're married you're instantly
deciding how much do I care about each
thing and what,
how far do I want to push my wife?
Like in knocked up one of the
scenes that I like, but it's a,
it's an intense scene is Leslie sitting
there and she's looking at a website
that tells her where sexual predators
live in the neighborhood and Paul comes in
and he just keeps making jokes about
it and she's really freaked out. Like,
do you know there's a guy like three,
three streets over and
Paul keeps making jokes.
Well let's not go to his house on
Halloween. And then finally she's like,
that's what I would though I,
then she finally says like,
sometimes I just want to rip your fucking
head off because you're so fucking
stupid. And that really is what
marriage is about. Is there,
there are issues that you care about.
Like how much McDonald's should the kitty.
Now, when I was a kid, I swear to God,
I hadn't Mcdonald's, I'm not kidding
you six times a week. And I loved it.
I ate it. My mom had no issue
taking me there every single
time. We used to go out as a
family, like it was fine dining.
He got there, we had a big family, so it
was five cheeseburgers, five small fries,
five chocolate shakes, two big
MACs, two large fries to coax.
That was the order for years. And it was
awesome every time. Yeah. Yeah. It was,
it was an ISP and jealous.
And when I got older,
because I kept getting a cheeseburger
and I was big enough to get a quarter
pounder with cheese, but I was afraid
to ask as you get shit. And I just,
we looking at theirs and they would
only like halfway through it with that
little mouse trying to eat it. And I
said, wolf mind down. But uh, yeah,
I remember when I used to,
when I was really young and I
lived in the north shore of Boston,
I remember there was a Mcdonald's and
there was this train track that was right
by,
and you would throw some of your French
fries to the seagulls and you get to see
a train go by and he'd be sitting outside.
And it was like some of my fondest
memories as a kid and um, you know,
yeah, there was no, yeah. You know
that they will roughly the same age.
So it was just all a, you
know, peanut butter and fluff
and all these, these, these,
these, and um, and there's
some of this out about it.
When did you even realize what
Mcdonald's was bad and what,
like how old were you when you were
like, I guess I shouldn't eat that? Well,
you knew fast food was bad,
but he didn't know to the
point like I make Mcdonald's,
remember a few years ago they had a bolt,
a bulletin board,
a billboard just came out and
it's like now with a 100% beef,
which is obviously, well, what
the fuck was it before the page?
Did you watch that movie founder with
Michael Keaton? Oh, you got to watch that.
Michael Keaton's amazing in that movie.
And it's such a,
it's such a well done movie about
like all of that type of stuff. So,
um, but then, you know, your wife says,
I want to give her the good and
some Mcdonald's and you're like,
and they get lengthy.
Awful.
Now I have the police and I have the
reverse with my wife. Used to be poison.
I think now it's more like,
it's a little more healthy right now.
It might be just nothing blank,
no positive anything.
But my,
my wife early in our relationship when
I would get Mcdonald's would look at me
like, what is wrong with you? Are
you an adult? Like you eat this food?
She was so disgusted.
She shamed me to such an extent that
I don't even sneak out and get it.
Like she, she programmed
me to be disgusted by the
thing that made me so happy.
Yeah. My thing was when I
was going to be healthy,
I went to Wendy's cause Wendy's seemed
like it was actually burger meat. Yeah.
Probably wasn't either. No, it probably
wasn't. Well, dude, I gotta tell you, man,
it was, it's such a thrill to have, uh,
someone like you come
on on the show in like,
and I really appreciate the advice both
on this and an off that you've given me
as far as like, how do you know, you
know, keep it all kind of going without,
without screwing it up.
And I'm definitely gonna check out
that masterclass that you were in.
Everybody check out January
15th that the Grammercy, um,
I want you want to say hotel Grammer
seat theater. I mean, John Malaney, uh,
Pete Holmes, Judd Apatow for the
Ronald McDonald House is going to be,
go to [inaudible] dot com
slash tour once again,
season three a crashing with
the Great Pete Holmes. Um,
January in January,
January.
Garry Shandling documentary
is on Blu Ray and uh,
it's masterclass.com where
you can, uh, just I guess,
imagine search Judd Apatow,
Pete Holmes, new special airs,
I think on the 15th, which is like, he's
got a great new standup. What's it called?
It's called a dirty, clean, dirty, clean
and where it, where can they see that?
That'd be on the HBO on Hbo.
I love it. I love this. Why?
Why wouldn't it be nice though? He's
in business with them. All right, Jeff,
thank you so much for coming in and
everybody thank you for listening.
And a checkout. Judd Apatow, January
15th. Gramsci theater. All right buddy.
Thank you.
Thanks buddy.