Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday,
January 16th,
2017 what's going on?
How are you everybody and happy
Luther King Day to everybody you know,
happy Martin Luther King Day, you
know, for, for those you who are,
that means some to you. For those
you just know it's another day off.
It's just like when Georgio
Blah abies birthday in February.
Do we get those days off?
Um, the two whities there,
the two ease in February, I
believe it's in February. Right?
During black history month,
you still got to shoe Horn
George Washington day and
Lincoln's birthday in there.
Correct.
Then you got another yt and hey,
it got another whitey and uh,
and my was Saint Patrick.
Ah,
you pasty faced fucking son
of a bitch. Yeah. Right.
Then in April you got uh Oh,
here comes Peter cottontail
hopping down the body trail. Right.
With his own little white bunny.
Yes. Right. Then what do you got?
You got in May who said, is
that April go to? I don't know.
I've run out somewhere around there.
Those are weird. The dog days of the year.
It's like fucking, you know, uh, flag day.
Then I always get memorial day and
Labor Day Memorial Day is, is May,
right.
Okay.
Memorial Day, Memorial Day is in
May. We recognize all the veterans,
you know,
that fought for your freedom so you
could sit around and eat fucking dip and
shit,
right?
Changing all your fucking VCR tapes over
to fucking DV days and then to a little
fucking stick, whatever the fuck
it is you do that day. Right.
Um,
and you got July 4th,
so everybody can go around and fucking,
you know,
trade stories about their uncle that blue
his fucking fingers off cause he never
got married. He was trying to impress
his nephews and nieces. Right,
right.
See you see that right there son?
You see it out right there.
That's why I told you y'all can cheer
me. Ain't no fucking good. Taiwan.
Right? I want to hear it. No Mall.
Wait, going over uncle Jimmy's. Okay.
It's over there with loose fucking
women and he's playing with them fire
crackers.
Right? So that's July 4th. Then
August, August is kind of like a month.
It's up for grabs.
Yeah.
No Jewish holidays. No. Hey,
remember Jesus did this for you.
What do you say they're Muslims? What do
you got? You got something that month.
How bout you? Buddhist Buddhist. Don't
give a shit right there. Like, hey man,
like every day for everybody
and it's just like,
as long as we're sitting
around and feeling the breeze,
that's what I'm trying to be, you
know, I'm trying to be that person.
Today was going to be my 10th
day in a row to a meditate,
but I didn't,
I woke up late and I had to take
my lady over to the doctors and um,
and I just, I just got up late, you know,
I had this fucking weird ass dream
to have this weird dream where I was,
went out my back portrait.
I was watching these helicopters
flying in formation and dive bomb in my
neighborhood. And I was like, what
the fuck are they doing that for?
And then one of them lost control and I
had this weird view from my house that
I've never had before. And it was
just basically the cockpit, you know,
and the engine that part in the
skids, no main rotor, no tail,
no tail rotor and nothing else.
And for some reason it wasn't tipping
over and falling to the ground,
like a fucking trashcan
or most likely inverting.
It just fucking, it just went
straight and it's sorta landed.
And I ran down there.
I was in my underwear because you were
always in your underwear and the and your
dreams, right? You never have your
pants on. It's so fucking weird.
This is only with mine.
There's always that level of humiliation.
No matter what's going on, I
can't find my pants. Right. Um,
anyway, so the fucking thing lands. So
I run up and then I'm thinking like,
wait a minute, do I want to see
the carnage that is in there?
And then all these people showed up with
like cell phone cameras and stuff and I
was standing there in my underwear and
I ran home. That was that. They go,
there's your dream to interpret
for the week. All right,
cause I'm not going to therapy anymore
because they spend enough fucking money.
You know, with somebody daydreaming
with the goddamn notebook. Right?
And none of them ever looked like that
brought on the Sopranos, let's be honest.
Right? Um, yeah. So I started,
I woke up late. All right?
So I need to fucking relax.
Quiet my mind.
Make it more of a still pond.
Whenever a rock falls into the pond,
what happens? The Weiders ripple. Yes,
the water's ripple. And if too
many rocks fall in, what happens?
There starts to be a storm.
And this is what I want you
to pay attention to today
during today's meditation.
Is your brain as a still pond?
Can you hear it?
This screaming,
watery death of 1200 passengers
going under the water of your mind.
Sorry, I lost it. I don't know what the
fuck I was talking about anyways. Um,
I also am apologies. This
weak apology. Number one,
I owe an apology to the
fucking Atlanta Falcons.
I owe an apology to the Houston Texans.
I owe an apology to Meryl Streep.
Evidently going into Twitter
according to one person. All right,
let's start with the Seattle
Seahawks, right? You know,
I thought those were going
to be the dirty, filthy,
stinking disease carry and birds
that we're going to win that game.
I said last week and I,
I kind of quote,
you know who got off easy this weekend,
the New England patriots and the Seattle
Seahawks because the cowboys and the
packers are gonna beat the fuck out
of each other and the Steelers and the
fucking chiefs are gonna beat the
shit out of each other, right?
And then all we got to do is
play the winner as so, man,
okay
that these two teams,
we're just going to walk to the AFC and
NFC championship game and see if that is
a given. Well, let's start
with the Atlanta Falcons.
I picked the wrong dirty
birds. Uh, very impressive win.
And um, I know Seattle fans going to
be like, we had some major injuries,
which they did coming into the game
and then they lost another guy.
I understand that. Okay,
I totally understand that.
Seattle fans, you're 100% right.
Christ.
I can hear you cry in front of here.
Your stadium is so la.
Oh my God. And those Seattle.
See they're so fucking law.
I'm so sick of ESPN fucking
like just ignoring that
entire fact. They just don't,
they know what it is.
You notice they can't,
they have the ability to separate
themselves from the truth.
That's what I really respect from ESPN
as they could just separate themselves
with truth and just go
for the fucking money.
They don't give a shit about what's
right or none of them give a fuck.
They just say and shit to say shit.
So idiots like me get upset and yell
at their fucking TV and keep watching.
And then what do they do?
They get some more habit Dash
Erie, right? The date, date,
you know, they, they get,
they get a bigger fucking whatever
the fuck it is thereafter over there.
And new tie tech.
I don't know.
I don't know what motivates people that
want to sit around in suits talking
about sports. Why do they wear suits? By
the way, can anybody explain that to me?
Why are they all sitting
there like they're on meet
the press where they taught.
I just, I don't fucking understand
it. You know, and it's contagious.
Okay.
Talking,
standing in a fucking suit.
Talking about a sports
is so fucking contagious.
Ben Roethlisberger.
Yeah.
Ben Big Ben.
I ain't wearing no fucking motorcycle.
Showed up dressed,
dare I say dress to the fucking night.
He looked like a million bucks
from the fucking neck doubt.
Okay.
His suit was fucking sharp.
He had a pocket square that tie
the shirt the whole fucking day.
He was killing it. Okay. Oh,
Jay would've got off this a second time
if he wore that fucking Sudi yet on
Sunday. However, from the neck up,
he just looked at him going like,
this guy crushes a 12 pack while eating.
All right. A French fries. I know he does.
Okay. Why you don't, you know what? He
looked like? He looked like a guy. A key,
like a convicted drunk driver
trying to get his license back.
Now you promise me you're not going to do
this again? Yes, your honor. Absolutely.
I, I've seen the error of my ways.
You know, it's still all puffy.
I'm fucking with you. I Love Ben Ben
Roethlisberger, but seeing him in a suit,
you know?
Okay.
He was, he was all grown up. I'm
proud of him. Um, so my apologies.
The Atlanta Falcons and I'm not going
to know anybody's fucking names. Okay.
I don't know anybody's names. I know
Julio Jones and I know, uh, um, Sherman,
you know Julio Jones made look,
he made him look, I wouldn't,
I would never say regular
because Sherman is the shit.
He made him look a little bit and I've
never seen him do that because that guy
still shuts down his part of
the fucking field. All right.
And he made him look a kind of
a, you know, a guys pretty good.
He's got some pretty good foot work there.
Then also I thought he a
one cab chancellor came up,
well he usually just fucking
lays the fucking and lumber.
Julio Jones dropped his shoulder,
absorbed the shit and dare I say,
I'm not going to say
he put cam on his back,
but it was not an issue that cam hit
him and that really surprised me.
And um, I don't know. I don't
know where the fucking names.
I've say Atlanta is fucking running
back, whatever the fuck his name is. Uh,
the one who doesn't pretend to eat cereal,
whenever he fucking gets a few yards,
that's the cowboys won. He
gets up. You know, you know JC,
you ever seen a guy campaign and harder
to get a Lipton soup add? You know,
it's that guy who used to be on the giants
and then did the show at that little
cutie pie in the morning.
And then for some reason left that show
to be one of 19 with the guy who used to
run fucking, uh, Clinton's campaign.
Is it George Stephanopoulos on
a morning show right now? Like,
that guy's got to be on like,
what the fuck?
Yeah.
What happened? What I, 25 fucking years
ago I was dealing with the Russians.
I'm fucking sitting here
on pancake Wednesday acting
like I'm excited about this
shits in on his fucking couch. You're
not, the worst parts of those shows are,
is the way they decorate the coffee table.
You know,
I can't imagine trudging in there every
fucking day to do that show. Like,
what fucking monkey suit are they
putting you in today? You know,
girls have to have their Sassy. I'm
a morning person. Outfits, you know,
the guys have to have that. Uh, you
know, I'd show up and uh, you know,
I turned the whole
fucking paycheck over to,
you would pull some Angela's ashes
shitty and go to the pub instead.
They got to have that fucking
look. You know what I mean? Um,
why did stray hand lead that
show was that little cutie pie.
What the fuck is her name? I saw once
in real life, she's fucking smoking,
smoking hot. Right. And it was just the
two of them. They had a great time, right?
She come out on his shoulder like
a parakeet. He do the monologue,
she'd giggle alarm in there,
the whole fucking thing. It
was just the two of them,
just the two of them
making heats up to vote.
And if for some reason
he leaves that show,
Michael Strahan, arguably one of the
most successful people, you know,
people look at Mark Cuban and they
go, Amy, here's a guy, you know,
he didn't have any fucking money.
Start to some internet company.
He makes it silly dollars that
he buys an NBA team. Greg,
he starts go bald, he gets to fucking hair
plugs, he goes to Vegas, sees at a rave.
You don't know where this guy's going.
He's got his own fucking jet.
Everybody thinks this is the guy,
this is the next fucking Bill Gates guy.
He's on shark tank.
Okay.
He's having people coming in who can
barely afford the gas and their lawn mower
and he's listening to their ideas and
then owning them and then taking them and
not giving it. You know. You know
what guys like that too, right?
I don't know why I'm picking on this
guy. He's just funny to me. Right. Um,
and you know,
I'll go of this.
Everybody thinks he's the next Bill Gates.
And meanwhile you got Michael Stray here.
Okay.
Who came up from the hard
streets or somewhere? I don't
know where it came from,
but I know he's African American, so I
know his streets weren't soft. Right.
What was the last time you saw an
African American make it and they,
and they said they did not
come from hard streets,
that he came from soft streets.
You never see that.
You do not stay or no soft streets
on that side of the fucking fence.
So we came from the heart streets. I'm
aware of where we going to put that guy.
He doesn't seem like a New York guy.
He seems like a Pennsylvania Dude.
I don't know where the fuck kid, the
hard streets of Harrisburg, Pennsylvania.
Allentown. I don't know where the fuck he
came from. Whatever. He fucking makes it.
Okay. He becomes a
fucking superstar, right?
He deals with Tiki Barber and whatever
the fuck he was trying to do, you know,
throwing the ball all over
the carpet retires early.
They get him out of the way.
It goes into the super
ball. No, whoa. Back Up.
Fucking gets the sack
record. Right. You know,
and his last one of course was the most
impressive, which bread fives run on.
That was the precursor to the but fumble.
It's the exact same body motion,
except he didn't run into a
giant offensive lineman's ass.
He just came in and just sort
of laid down. All right then,
if I remember correctly,
where the fuck did they go?
They went somewhere on the road in one,
then they went into green bay in one
and they wanted to Dallas in one.
I might have those two flip flopped
and then they went to the Superbowl,
played the eighth New England patriots
and they fucking kick the shit out of him
on the offensive line. One on the
last fucking play the game. Okay.
And uh, when's the fucking
super bowl? Then you think
that's it? Oh No. And he goes,
oh, he's a broadcast to toe.
He's fucking killing it a bit.
You know a lot of guys done that. How
long did it Terry Bradshaw dead fuck gain.
Oj Simpson dead it. Everybody fucking
did it. Right? That's just what you do.
If you can actually fucking talk about
the game and you can put on a God damn
suit, then he does the unprecedent. Okay.
A visionary move than not even
Mark Cuban could come up with.
He decides that, you know what, I am the,
I am the next logical choice to
take over for fucking Regis Philbin.
Right? I'm, I did a whole bit about it.
I don't just watch the nigger one
time about all of his accomplishments.
I would put, I would put straight hand
right there. Okay. And then he fucking,
what does he do? What does he do? He gets,
everything's going great for whatever
fucking reason he decides to join the
Partridge family on some
other fucking morning show.
It's going to be the same shit.
Yeah.
Standing around watching
somebody cook something, right?
Talking about how some fucking person
just had the a hundred and fifth birthday.
Why would you want to be over there
with all of those fucking ass heads?
You know,
all of those different personalities.
You know someone's going to be a cunt,
right?
You could have just
stayed at your other show.
Have you ever heard somebody wastes
more time talking about something that
nobody gives a fuck about in your
life? 109. What the hell that was?
That was 10 minutes on Michael Strahan.
Alright. Um, probably like six,
but it felt like 50.
So my apology to the dirty
birds down in Atlanta.
I Apologize for disrespecting your team.
I didn't realize how good you guys were.
I wrote you guys off again
at the beginning of the game
when I heard you had the
day, you know, you scored the most
points, but we're the worst in the league,
in the red zone. I'm like,
well, the game's over.
The game's fucking over it.
So you run up a bunch of points
during the regular season against it.
90% of the teams that are not
going to make the playoffs.
So that's out the window.
And then meanwhile,
you couldn't stop 100% of these
costs in the red zone right there.
That's a formula for disaster. And
what did they do? They went out,
they beat Seattle so bad.
There wasn't one point during that game,
I think may on the first drive
I saw Pete Carroll one time went
woo.
And that was it. That was it. Oh Man,
I love Pete Carroll. Man. He's
a fucking great coach. You know,
he was fucking pissed when they
lost. Oh, he was fucking pissed.
Can you imagine his family dog?
He seems like he'd have a little one too
of just standing the equivalent in the
corner.
Pete walking around with
these ridiculously white
brand new socks walking across
this carpeted floor. That's what
he seems like to make it right.
Has on his fucking docker PJ's
that dog just gets a little too close.
You know,
I don't understand why we didn't shut
up dad defense and fucking thing goes
flying into the fireplace. Um, anyways,
he's probably a cat person who knows.
And my apology to the Texas and Houston,
Texas who without Jj fucking
and a rookie quarterback hun with
the New England Patriots for, uh,
for three and a half
fucking quarters. Um, yeah,
I was not impressed with us. I don't
think, uh, any Patriot fan was, uh,
we'll see. We'll see. I hope that's not,
I think I'm just hoping our offensive
line had a bad game member just had a bad
fucking game.
If you're going to have a bad game,
you might as well do it against the
team that's missing their best offensive
player and as a brand new
guy, quarterback. So maybe
we got away with one.
I have no fucking idea.
All I know is we're playing Pittsburgh
next week and I have no fucking
confidence in that despite
the fact Pittsburgh, you know,
I don't know what they did.
Like they kicked six field goals,
which is essentially,
you know,
I don't know
if he just went on field goals.
You might as well have out there on,
on like those figure skates, you know,
dressed up like Yogi bear or some shit.
I was like some ice capades
shits, but they did it. You don't,
they beat Kansas City.
I didn't see one second of the game.
I watched the beginning of the Dallas
Green Bay game and then my wife wanted to
go to the movies. So I took her to
the movies and I'm like, all right,
I'm recording this game. Let's record it.
The fucking Steelers Kansas City game.
I saw hidden fucking figure and
then I came back. Right now.
I'm like, all right, you know, my wife's
taken a bath. Everything's fucking cool.
I go to pop on the Green Bay Dallas
game and I didn't fucking recorded.
Let me say it again.
I didn't fucking recorded it was sounds
like an insane half and I'd fucking hats
off to that fucking dude Crosby.
I'm telling you right now. That
was some Adam, Vinod Terry Shit.
I never even seen Vinod hit that
many 50 yarders in one fucking game.
Forget about hitting one, get an iced
and then he's got to kick it again.
The guy kicked like 200 yards.
It feel goals in like four attempts
or some shit like that. Um,
that's the kind of guy that's the kind
of guy right there. He gave me a book,
a little children. That's the kind of
guy when your championship right there,
because all you got to fucking uh,
Aaron Rodgers, all he's got now,
all you've got to do is just get your
clothes and old twinkle toes comes running
out with balls the size
of the fucking stadium.
It gives them the old right
there, Fred, right there.
Do you realize how much fucking ass he
got after that game? Even in Dallas,
you know those Dallas women with their
fucking botox and the same amount of
makeup as an 80 year old who can't
admit that she's old. You know,
they all came running out, right.
Took the hats off, take the boots off.
You know they all drop to the knees and
their designer fucking Jordache jeans.
Yeah,
you ever been to Dallas?
This is this dare so far behind in the
styles you would even think that there's
the internet anymore.
They all dress like Dallas is still on TV.
The TV show,
you know bomp bomp bomp bomp bomp.
I'm not saying they brought,
they don't really do that,
but the through line of that is still,
there is a lot of Larry Hagman in
that city with a dash of dead JFK.
That is Dallas and there's a lot of
shiny fucking four door pickup trucks.
You know, I don't know who they
are driven by, but you know,
I think you've got to get on the outskirts
to get to them are ranchers that got
them longhorns walking and
stomping around in the back.
And my apologies to Meryl Streep.
Evidently somebody had a hissy fit on the
fucking Twitter telling me that I am a
typical,
what did he say?
Post modern Synack or I just
criticized and I offered no solutions,
which is hilarious to me. It's
like, okay, so um, in your world,
Meryl Streep and myself,
uh,
should be coming up with problems,
problem solving things you want to say.
I just took Twitter, that guy
back I was, I had just saw,
I was a comedian making fun of Shit.
I didn't know it was a postmodern cynic.
Yeah.
Some people that the level of credit
that they give people don't even watch.
The news is just fucking beyond me.
I had to go to summer school every year
of high school except sophomore year
because my teacher hooked me up with a
d minus and my senior year I just didn't
give a fuck and didn't go, you know, what
are you gonna do? I'm done. It's over.
I'm a loser. All right. I am on my, I'm
on my way out. Whole base to wash dishes.
Thank you very much. All right. So, um,
I know way too much football. How bout
some hockey? Just one quick mention.
Alright.
Did anybody see Adam equates fight
when they fucking against Nashville?
Jesus Christ. Geez, that's crazy.
I don't know the name
of the guy who fought,
but that guy's got fucking
balls bigger than my giant head.
Anybody's got the balls to drop the
gloves. I'm not shitting on the guy.
I just add a McQuaig that fucking guy
can fight. Um, he was like, well guys,
what Gash? What Goshen? And the guy
ducked down and he fucking did it.
I thought it was an uppercut.
Then when I'm watching a slow motion,
I think it might've been a hook. I
Dunno. It just reminded me any very,
very junior way of when Clark Gillies
fucking broke that guy's face.
He was pounding this guy so bad,
the guy just ducked down
and write as he ducked down,
Gillies just went uppercut and his fist
was big enough to cover the guy's whole
face. And it was like, it's like,
it was like he punched a glass
coffee table and this guy just went,
he like straight down like when
they pull a building, you know.
Um, and the first time I noticed
that that guy could fight was, uh,
he beat the fuck out
of a raw Ralphie Torres
when he was playing with
the Phoenix coyotes.
I'll have links to those
fights, but that's, that's our,
I guess he is our enforced now.
And what's great is he's a
fucking unbelievable defensemen
too. So, uh, that's it.
Celtics. What are we doing?
We're doing, we always do.
We beat the pretenders and we can't beat
the contenders. That's our deal. Ed.
A enough sports. All right, let me, uh,
should I read a little bit
of advertising for you?
But everything and I can say you have
to apologize to Meryl Streep. You know,
cause I guess I preach also on my podcast,
which is the same as hijacking
and award show, right?
Did Meryl Streep one say, Hey, I'm
a fucking moron. What do I know?
I don't think she did. All
right. Oh, Billy street. Okay,
here we go. Let's read a little, oh
Jesus. Here we go. Matt. Up, up, up.
Biondi is beyond Ds.
Where in fucking Trump will do
[inaudible]
she wanted to take a dump, but they'll
fuck it. Worries you. Ball will be soft.
They don't care that she got
a lot of shit in the back.
It has a trap door that you open up
like old long underwear. Well Jay,
Jay's all right. The Valentine's
Day gift. Oh, this Valentine's Day.
Give a gift that they can
unwrap again and again.
Matching underwear from me undies.
No, Jesus. Who the fuck wants,
alright, Valentine's is
near and it's time. It's a,
it's a goat and it's go time.
Sorry for thoughtful gift hunting.
Any words that have a dash in it and
like they're together. Like it's a team.
I'm like a rookie quarterback.
I can't, I, you know,
I just look at my number one receiver.
I can't check down to the next
guy and I just stumbled over it.
It's go time anywhere. Any, I guess you
put a dash there cause they'd be like,
it's go time. It's go time for
thoughtful gift hunting me undies.
Has you covered with limited edition
also a dash matching pairs of undies for
you and yours has Valentine's Day.
Got You stumped.
Now it doesn't, I don't, I don't,
I don't give into the crazy emotion of
it much like everybody trying to get me
freaked out that I'm having a
kid any minute now. All right.
Forget the cliches and give
a gift that looks great.
Feels great and will make everyone happy.
Me undies.
Fancy dinners and
chocolate last the night.
Flowers last a week. Oh, shots fired.
It's Sherry's berries and 1-800-FLOWERS.
Me undies getting old Gangsta rap here
and the fucking beginning of the year
this year give the gift of looking great
and feeling great every day with the
world's most comfortable fucking
underwear. Heads up Valentine's days.
February 14th case you haven't noticed
every fucking year of your life.
Why are they saying that?
Like it's fucking groundhog
day, you know like Easter,
how that moves around. You know, February,
December 25th is Jesus's birthday.
Happy Birthday to Jesus,
right? Valentine's days,
February 14th but don't panic. Get your
heart on. Get your heart on. I get it.
And show some love with me undies.
Matching undies.
What are you getting panties his and her
panties. This is getting freaky here.
Me and these other perfect gift for you
and your Valentine. This hell holiday.
They're unbelievably soft and come and
limited edition prints me undies knows
that your special,
someone deserves a special fabric,
which is why their underwear is made
exclusively out of modal, modal,
a fabric with a touch three
times softer than cotton me.
And he says, this is so fucking
creepy. Three times softer than cotton.
Come on,
everybody get in the van me and he says
a special limited edition Valentines,
Valentines undies, which means you and
your Valentine can match. And yeah,
it's as cute as it sounds. It
sounds creepy. It sounds creepy.
I'm like, it's either going
to be really like masculine,
look in a really feminine looking or
are you just saying it's the same print?
You know,
so you know he's going to buy these funds,
fucking underwear of the kinds of people
that have four kids and I'll name them
by the first consonant. These
are my kids, Larry Laurie,
lean up and they Louie.
Why do people do that?
And if for some reason you and
me undies aren't a perfect match,
they give your money back and
let you keep the first pair.
There's no refund on a
bed. Fancy dinner. Dude,
you're in your fucking house,
Larry. You got four kids,
Larry,
Lina, I didn't, was I calling
you? Stop yelling at me. Dad,
call to action.
Uh,
they offer free shipping and for a limited
time listeners to this, this station,
this station, this is the copy
to give to the radio guys.
He kicking kicking me a little
nod listeners to this podcast.
Get 20% off their first order,
but you have to go to me and he's
dot com slash burr with the meal.
These better day guarantee you have
nothing to lose, so don't wait any longer.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bear
right now for 20% off your first order.
It doesn't mean that he's dug cubs
led for if you're matching underwear,
I'm going to go out on a limb
and say the gayest of gay couple.
I don't even know that you
guys would even do that.
Would you even be that festive?
Are Gay people festive or is that just
a stereotype that Hollywood is spoon
feeding to America and that's what
needs to stop dollar shave club?
Everybody Dollar Shave Club always gives
you a close to shave and you can't beat
the convenience of the price.
You don't have to choose between.
Suddenly for a cheap bag is shitty
disposable or ratios are paying out the
fucking nose for a razor with the laser
pointer and 17 blades, it's awful.
Then dollar shave club broke onto
the scene with the smarter choice.
Before Dollar Shave Club,
there was no middle ground.
It was either shave a with
your fucking girlfriends,
thinks she did her legs with,
cut up your fucking face.
So he spend a zillion dollars. Um, there
you get those free ones at the gym,
which felt like shaving with a piece
of glass there or pay a fortune for the
latest. Okay, I'm just skipping around.
The copy of Dollar Shave Club
is the best of both worlds.
You get the premium shape quality
after disposable shape price, right?
It's like buying a
Cadillac for five bucks.
If you haven't tried dollar shave
club yet, you're missing out.
It's an amazing shave and
affordable price. If you
haven't figured that out yet,
what the 20 paragraphs are fucking copy.
There's no smarter choice
on the market right now.
They're giving away a one month trial
of any of their razors for only a dollar
with free shipping and after that,
it's just a few bucks a month
and see that like a drug dealer.
If they gave you a little taste
of the crack, then you're hooked.
Then you're stealing VCRs. There's no
long term commitments, no hidden fees,
and you can cancel whenever you want.
Get your dog,
your $1 trial@dollarshaveclub.com
slash burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/ [inaudible].
All right, there's two more reads and,
uh, I'm seeing double, so I'm going to
take a fucking break here. All right.
Um, okay. What do I want to
talk about here? Oh, you know,
I was watching the, uh, speaking
of Cadillacs. Oh, Elvis Presley.
Um, I was watching the
Meekum autumn, autumn.
I don't wait.
I'm trying to open his fucking blind.
Jesus Christ. Come on for fuck sakes. How
hard is this have to be? There you go.
Shed a little light on the,
I was watching when those Mika,
okay. Automobile auctions.
And uh, I got to tell you,
I'm fucking over the muscle cars.
I love muscle cars like any
other red blood American in a,
and a red blood and blood in American.
I like those fucking cars,
but every fucking what's the same thing?
We got some mopar power coming up.
Of course she dope. Oh,
really? Does it have a Hammy?
Is that as Shelby? It's the
same. And what it basically is,
is that it's the same
fucking like 20 muscle cars.
What are you going to have?
You know what you're going to have,
you're going to have a Shelby Mustang.
You're going to have the tribe
powered fucking corvette, right?
You're going to have the fuck
and you're gonna have a GTO. Ah,
you got to have a fucking a,
all that Mopar fucking Hemi shit that I
never got into. I was never a Chrysler,
dodge guy. Plymouth guy on
there like the Barracuda, right?
They're going to have
a fucking a challenger.
Are they going to have a charger
or they're gonna have a super B.
They're going to have the fucking,
whatever that Zee 28 was that
they only made fucking 10 of them.
They're going to have one of those.
It's the same fucking cars over
and over again. And meanwhile,
here's my question, why the fuck
are all the trucks? You know,
where the fuck are all the trucks?
Kasia only a truck will come across
trucks. The coolest shit and words,
all those great old man gangster cars.
You know,
like the fucking,
my favorite one of all time,
the 1967 Cadillac.
Eldorado yeah,
that fucking car.
It just go fuck yourself.
I love that fucking car. That's the
kind of car, you know what I mean?
That you drive when you read the post
divorce or you were smart enough never to
get married.
Okay.
And you're successful and you're just
fucking driving around and you got,
you got you got,
you got a stable a bitches and you know,
they don't give a fuck about you. You
don't give a fuck about them. Yeah.
They pay girlfriends. That's the
fucking car you have. You know,
and this is a thing.
And rather than secretly being lonely
and empty inside your actually fulfilled
because you own that car,
you are the closest thing to the
most interesting man in the world.
You know that stay thirsty. My friends,
you ever seen a woman in his life?
You see women,
Wim men in his fucking life.
You know what I mean?
You'd never see him at a fucking dance
recital with his fucking rug rats.
Um, anyways, I fucking love that car.
I the most gangster fucking car.
And then I also like to 65, uh,
uh, Jesus Christ with the clamshell
fucking open the headlights,
that Buick Riviera. Okay. And, um,
at some point it might be my next car.
I drive the Jag into the ground.
By the way, I sold my Prius today,
add that fucker for nine years, man. Um,
it was great. I never did that before.
Never sold it to just a person.
I always traded them in.
And this time I actually
sold it to a person. Got The
title, did the whole thing,
felt like Richard Rawlings, you know,
what does he say when he fits him?
Get shoved somebody. Right. So it
was a Prius and I didn't build it.
Other than that, I was just
like him. Speaking of which,
the debut of gas monkey garage is tonight.
And rumor has it that the bearded wander
Aaron is leaving the fucking show,
which is, uh, you know,
that's like Eddie van Halen leave at
Van Halen or David Lee Roth leaving.
I mean it's, it's, it's, I am,
you know, there's a lot of,
I'm interested to see what,
what they do
okay
with this one.
I how you're going to a
yeah.
How are you going to make up for that guy?
Jesus Christ. Uh, but I'll be tuning in.
I'll be tuning in because that's,
that's, I've all the shows out there.
That's the best one out there.
And there's so many shows that rip that
fucking show off and try to capture that
formula. That's the best one out there.
And I love the shit that they built.
Speaking of trucks last season,
they were saying, you know what,
we're all truck guys who are all
truck guys and I'm yelling at the TV.
Well then fucking makes it more trucks.
Okay.
I remember that they
made that one for Casey.
They can count on one hand they made
the one for KC. They made that uh,
they made the Chevy,
especially if you get those ones that
had the two tone Tate to tone taint Jesus
Christ to tone two tone paint.
I don't know if I can finish this idea
to tone tank. You know what that is?
That's your tank is the normal,
your normal flesh color and somebody
tries to kick you in the balls from behind
and they miss and you get a black
and blue mark on party a taint.
Then what you have is a two tone,
tane. All right, two toned paint.
Um, they, and they did last
year. What did they do?
They did a like a 1948 or 49 Chevrolet.
Uh, and they just went all out
with the fucking thing. And uh,
okay.
It was, it was absolutely fucking,
it was, it was, it was just amazing.
It's amazing what they do in that show.
And I wish I had those skills. Um,
who knows?
Someday maybe someday I'll fucking
have the time to find a fucking 67,
uh,
Cadillac Eldorado dragged that fucker
out of somebody's backyard and have
somebody like that build the thing for me.
I'm one of those guys too.
I would drive it. I saw one on, uh, I
hate people. Get those fucking cars.
I don't drive them. I got one for you
if you want to look this up right now.
All right.
Look up 1965 Cadillac El Dorado.
$45,000.
Yeah.
This fucking guy,
he's got the best look at one I
think I've ever seen has like the,
somebody did a whole body off restoration
on it as like fucking 33 miles. Uh,
he got it when it had like seven miles
on it and then now he's selling it with
33 and it's just like,
why would you,
I would drive that fucking
thing to 200,000 miles.
Unbelievable fucking car.
Um,
but the only part, I will warn
you when you watched that video,
when he starts caressing
the leather inside the car,
it gets a little creepy. I had to
fast forward through it. He was like,
look at that. That's fine.
Italian leather. Oh yeah.
He didn't get that bad,
but it got pretty bad.
But this fucking guy has got
a bunch of them. Uh, s uh,
supersport motors.com.
Um,
at least he did as of I guess two
years ago, two and a half years ago.
Whenever you put this fucking video.
Uh, but if I was going to buy one,
I would buy one off of this guy.
Holy fucking shit. I said, all right.
He's got some beautiful cars,
beautiful Cadillacs. Um, anyways,
let's plow ahead here. I
think maybe it's time to, um,
okay,
maybe it's time to do a little like, oh,
Trump gets sworn in this week, you know,
he gets fucking sworn in and, uh, I
would feel so much better about that guy.
You know, it's, it's not the racist people
that he's putting in there, you know,
is unsettling. Is that is,
I mean, everybody's fucking
racist, you know? Well,
that's not true. There's different
degrees of it, but everybody has it.
Even people who are victims of it,
they have it.
You look at another group of people,
everybody's done that.
You look at a group of people, you think
something like, oh, it's like this.
And then you go over there.
Oh, it's actually like that.
Wow. Why did I think that?
And it all was in your fucking head.
You know, I got to do a bit about this.
I was driving down the street the
other day by went to Duke, right.
Driving down the street and I
see this group of young kids,
they school just let out. Right?
This is not a good sign right here.
I'm driving by a school right when the
school got out and I'm caressing my
leather. No, I, I'm driving
down the street and these
kids are all outside like a,
it's right around the corner from where
I'm playing drums. Here's my alibi.
I swear to God was playing
drums around the corner and um,
it's one of those stores that
sells like, uh, you know,
all the fucking snacks and shit that you
eat afterwards and you get all fucking
wired.
So I'm driving by there and usually I
get fucking annoyed because the kids are
fucking walking across the street. Then
I look at both ways and all that shit.
And then I, it takes me forever to
make a fucking left or right hand turn.
Or this day they were all up on the
sidewalk and I saw this movement.
I kind of glanced over
and
none of the kids who were
white and I saw this action.
I thought I was watching somebody
getting the shit kicked out of them,
potentially getting beaten into a gang.
That's what my brain told me.
I was watching when I looked closer,
there was like seven kids standing around,
one kid looking at a fucking smart phone
and then some other kids just sort of
fucking,
you know,
doing whatever running around in
the background and I was sticking.
Why the fuck did I just think that?
You know,
so before you fucking call all these
assholes, all these racist assholes,
you know, you gotta get that shit
out of your head. I was thinking,
why the fuck did I think that part of
that is from the shit that I see on TV,
right? I think your brain just goes,
it, it, once it gets stuffed down,
like how to make cereal, it just gets
it down. Like, okay, just grab this,
fucking put this in here, and then you've
got fucking cereal. You know, it, it,
it connects to one, I want
vision to this, this, this,
and it's like a mode of like survival,
which works.
But in that instant that didn't work,
did it?
I went from that to a couple of
fucking ice cube videos, whatever,
gangsta rap videos or my head shit
that I saw in the news. Right?
I can't say there was fear.
There was no fear.
I was just driving down the street and
I looked and that's what I thought,
you know, but I kind of do
that all the time. You know,
I'd read a Kid's book to my
unborn daughter last night, right?
It's supposed to make them smarter.
Right?
And I was reading this kid's book and
halfway through the book I realized I
didn't, I'd had no fucking idea what it
was about. So maybe I'm just a moron.
I have no idea. But seeing how,
what a flood fucking person, I am a,
I can't judge, uh, I can only judge people
so fucking harshly, right? Honestly,
I mean, I can trash it. Fucking Meryl
Streep. I can go off on a Donald Trump,
but at the end of the day,
I'm a fucking lunatic, right?
I read a kid's book and I couldn't
figure out what it's about.
It's about this fucking caterpillar. All
right. And they were like on day one,
it ate an apple on day two with
a two pairs on day three, eight,
eight fucking three plumps right?
So right there I'm like, all right,
this is like reverse Christmas story.
Rather than go in like seven swans,
a swimming six skis or lane,
it fucking starts with the fucking tree,
the partridge in a pear tree.
Now it's moving up.
And it seems to me like it's about
eating healthy and food and counting.
And then it gets up to like
12 or something. And then,
and the thing just completely abandoned
its fruit diet. And he'd said it had a,
uh, a fucking couple slices of pizza
and ice cream and all this shit,
and then a big stomachache.
So then I was like, all right,
this is about childhood obesity. And, um,
I actually lied that it never dawned on
me that it was about counting in Nios.
I finished the book,
the thing turned into a butterfly
and I said, I said the end.
And I looked at me and I said, I have no
idea what that fucking book was about.
She laughed. She goes,
it's about counting. I go,
it's not about not eating
junk food because it ate all
that fruit and everything
was fine. And then it,
all that other shit.
And then it got sick and she
was like crying laughing at me.
I don't know what that
has to do with Trump,
but I really wish that idiot
would get off of fucking Twitter.
That he's a fucking mess. He said about
Chinese time to take the gloves off.
He,
he,
he's doing that George Bush thing where
you talk about other countries like
you're trying to psych somebody out
before a bar fight and nothing gets people
more excited.
That gets morons excited
though some tough time. Right.
If fucking idiots,
he's like trashiness at all. Cause it
doing sketches about them. It's just like,
I don't, I don't, I don't, he cannot
be running his Twitter account.
There's no way he's this
fucking sensitive. Um,
or he has the time to do this.
Shouldn't he be addressing,
at my worst fear is that he's going to
become president and just deregulate
everything so he can build a golf course
or wherever the fuck he wants to. Like,
that's really, that's his idea
of making it great again. I,
I hope I'm fucking wrong.
I have no idea. Um,
having said all that,
still as much as he's a nightmare.
Unbelievably unbelievable joy watching
Hillary loose. Oh, I love seeing, yeah,
your bags. Okay. Becky
bags. They're fucking,
yeah. Am I going to say it?
All right, let's, let's,
let's continue on. All right,
let's, uh, them off the
fucking rails here. All right.
42 minutes. And can we or can we
read these last two advertising?
They'll do your questions for the
week. Um, all right. Helix. Helix. Hey,
by the way, why don't you guys
send those in? Send in your,
I looked at this thought it was this way
and then it was another way, but nobody,
you heard me say it so everybody thinks
I'm a great guy. And that goes for non,
he's too, cause I know you're looking
at us or some other group of people,
Koreans or some shit or whatever yet I
know you're thinking something. All right.
Hallux Helix. Alright, you're unique.
And I actually, you know, as much as I'm,
I'm not really joking
around about this shit,
but I think that people have to be able
to say that they have those fucking
thoughts. I mean this fucking, uh,
progressive left thing where you have
to act like you're just walking around
going, I don't see color. I don't
care if you're black, white,
green or purple.
And it's all of those,
all of that fucking sing
songs or horse shit. Um,
even those people,
like you get them in the wrong
situation and the fear comes up,
they're gonna think something fucked
up. They're gonna. Um, all right.
So if you have any of those
stories I want to hear,
I want to hear and then I'll try to,
I'll,
I'll try to guess why you think that way.
Okay.
So I'm guessing with mine it's uh,
the news and all the gangster rap
videos than I used to watch and I'm,
I'm old. So that was back when you
could actually have a gun in the video.
And then also I think I've watched too
many of those life on the inside prison
things,
you know what I mean?
All of those things where you
just look at it and go and like,
I would last 15 seconds in there.
I've watched all those ones about gangs.
I watched the ones about motorcycle gangs.
I,
it's probably my, uh, my intake of,
of, of television and youtube videos.
I watched videos of people sucker
punching people. Um, bully fails.
I watch a lot of
violence. Yeah, that's it.
Maybe that's what it is. All right.
Hallux. He licks your unique.
Okay.
You know, walk like anyone else? Talk
loud to anyone else. Shit, whack.
Anyone else asleep? Like anyone else? So
why is your mattress one size fits all?
Because it truly customized mattress
will cost you five to 10,000 bucks until
now.
Go to helix,
sleep.com answer a few simple questions
and they'll run a three d biomechanical
model of your body and
how will they do that?
Through the proprietary algorithms
they've developed with the help of the
world's leading ear ego nomics
in biomechanics experts,
the results they, they build a
fucking robot to take your place,
but in the meantime,
you sleep on the most comfortable
mattress you've ever slept on.
Helux customers report a 30% improvement
overall sleep quality and for couples,
they customize each side of the mattress.
Your mattress arrives at the door
at your door in about a week,
and shipping is 100% free.
That's why everyone from Gq magazine to
Forbes are all talking about helix sleep.
You have 100 nights to try it out.
If you don't like it,
they'll pick it up for free
and give you 100% refund.
No questions asked.
Dude,
I would dress like a fucking beekeeper
when I pick that thing up. Go to helix,
sleep.com/burn and get $50 off your order.
That's helic sleep.com/ [inaudible]
Huh?
You like sound like sleep.com/ [inaudible]
all right. Lastly, but not leastly,
stamps.com you know one great resolution
you can make for the new year.
Maximize every minute and every
dollar for your small business.
I know no easy way to do that.
Hey Lee,
stamps.com stamps.com is the
better way to get postage.
Just use what you're already at your
computer or your printer and your fucking
fingers to get official US
postage for any package or letter.
Then the mail man picks
it up the mail man.
Everything you would do at the post
office you can do right from your desk and
at a fraction of the cost of one
of those expensive postage meters.
I use stamps.com so whenever
I send out my posters,
you know whenever I'm whoring
myself out at the end of the show,
you know what I want to fucking shake
hands that have been sneezed into right
now. Sign up for stamps.com and use my
promo code birth for this special offer,
a four week trial plus $110 bonus offer
that includes a post include cleaning
postage in digital stale scale. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburrthatstamps.com
enter
burr. Ah, right. That is it. All right,
let's read some of the questions here
for the week and then I can get the full
Gatti. Alright. Team relocating.
Dear Billy Brady balls,
my NFL team I rooted for over 20 years
is moving to La Parentheses chargers.
What teams should I route for?
Patriots are out of the question.
Thanks and fuck the Spano his family.
Uh, first of all, my condolences.
I remember,
um,
Jesus almost 25 years ago when
Robert Kraft first bought the team.
Okay.
And, uh, he was threatened at
some point, maybe was in the,
in the year 2000 somewhere around then.
He was fucking threatening to, uh,
move the team to Hartford if he didn't
get his own stadium and shit. And, um,
that really is one of the biggest,
you know,
fuck overs by all of these
sports leagues that they,
they get the cities that we have to
pay for their fucking stadium. Right?
MMM.
That's a time when you need a union.
If you could just have a
somehow of a union of all
sports fans, it'd be like, no,
you fucking pay for it. He fucking
pay for a new stadium. You can't,
you know what I mean?
I go to the ice cream store.
I have to buy a new fucking store when
they want a new store, they pay for it.
But the money they made off ice cream,
like how much money do you have to make?
Do you know when I was
in fucking Indianapolis,
those poor bastards that live out there,
I don't know if this is still the case,
but when I went out there,
when they were putting, uh,
that Lucas oil field deal together,
when they were already paying for that,
they still had not paid off the
RCA dome or the Hoosier Dome,
whatever the fuck they called it.
They were still paying for that other
one in this fucking can't make them buy
another one.
MMM.
Having said that, I, I guess I can't
get mad at the spinal is family.
If everybody else is getting a
new stadium and he wasn't able to,
to blackmail San Diego, you know
what good for you. San Diego.
Fuck him.
You want a new stadium once you pack
your bags up and get the fuck outta here.
But you guys also kind of
fucked up the way Cleveland did.
You can't buy one team a stadium and
then tell the other guys to go fuck
themselves. That's like in Cleveland
when they, the Jake got built and then,
uh,
whenever his fucking name was
the fuck was that guy's name.
Everyone in Cleveland
screaming it right now. Um,
who sounded exactly like a George.
See Scott,
exact same voice.
MMM.
Yeah. He wanted to stay home
and you're like, yeah, fuck you.
You can stay in that
absolute fucking shit hole.
And then he left say it's not personal,
just business.
Um, why can I keep thinking good?
Dell? I'm a patriots fan. That's all.
I think when I think of a fucking Asshole,
I just think Roger Goodell.
MMM.
Yeah. That's sucks man. So who should
you vote for? You know what I'd do?
I would say fuck the NFL.
If the Patriots ever left,
I would just say fuck the NFL.
I would be done with it and I
would just pick a college team, um,
called football is to shit.
MMM.
You know, even though the
athletes, college sports are great,
but the athletes get fucked over that.
They don't get paid.
The fact that they sell at $100,000
stadium and then fucking idiots. Oh.
And it's always nonathletic
people who say this school,
they get a free education.
I'll do, they like,
they have time to fucking go to
class. You major in, in football,
there's too much money at stake and all
these and all the nerds that don't like
the jocks at the college level. It's like
if it wasn't for that football program,
you would be going to science
class in a fucking tent. Um,
100,000 people are not going to show up
to watch you look through a microscope.
Don't ever forget that.
All right,
so why don't you fucking put on your
lab coat and go figure out how to make a
better football cleat?
Oh Jesus.
Bill was no reason to
go that hard was there.
Can't we have respect for all of
the arts? Um, Meryl Streep doesn't,
she doesn't respect mom mixed
martial arts. Hey Merrill,
why don't you tell us what the arts are?
He's uses crisis cause there's
not a symphony behind it.
You never listened to it. Watch NFL
film. That's art. The music they put
behind him. [inaudible] Waianae
wearing that, wearing it, wearing it.
Why that? Why that, why that
brighter? All right. Movie foods,
videos. Uh, hey there.
Billy egg whites saw this
guy's videos on youtube.
He makes food from
different famous movies. Oh,
that's pretty cool. In this one, he makes
the big Kahuna Burger from pulp fiction,
which is pretty basic, but in others
he does some cool ship shit from chef,
one of my favorite movies
of the last few years.
And Acha the cartoon.
I highly recommend
checking a few of them out.
He makes a couple of sandwiches that
would give your grill top some great use
too. That's awesome. Thank
you. Look at debt. No question.
Just great information. I guess I never
tell you guys you can also do that.
That's fucking cool as hell.
I will definitely check that out.
I have been cooking up a fucking storm.
Um,
you know,
cause we can't really go anywhere every
once in a while and take me out to the
movies,
which this weekend,
this past week I saw moonlight and I
saw a hidden figures and I really liked
both for differently. Hidden figures,
big Hollywood movie, you know,
totally did the job. It was great.
Uh, and then I saw moonlight,
which was also great. And my favorite
part of that fucking movie, No,
I'm not ruin it.
No spoiler alert other
unless you're into cars was,
which was annoying was this,
this one part where this showing the
main character and then not showing his
fucking car, but you can tell it's
a nice car. I wanted to see the car.
And then they finally
showed him that was a,
I believe it was in [inaudible]
83 to 87 Oldsmobile cutlass.
And those were those great two doors that
they had in the fucking 80. So it was,
you know, the, the Oldsmobile cutlass,
the fucking Chevy Monte Carlo
in the Blue Buick, regal.
Those fucking cars are the shit.
And I know a lot of those southern guys
redoing when they put the big tires on
them, I don't like the big tires on
them, but that's another one. Um,
that's sort of the pot. Poor man's
fucking Eldorado. But I love those.
And some of the funniest,
like
guys I knew when I was growing
up had those fucking cars.
Just anybody who had a car
like that was a fucking was,
it was a good shit as they say
in Massachusetts, you know,
and slash a little bit shady,
probably dealing a little bit of weed,
maybe had a fight last night.
Those are all those guys.
They go into a bar and within 10 minutes
they're eyeballing somebody and then
they got to take the chain off
cause they're gonna get dual fight.
Remember that in the 80s, don't take your
fucking chain off with dog and tonight
I think the change coming back, I
think it's making a comeback. Um,
anyways, really enjoyed
both of those movies. Uh,
moonlight. I really fucking it.
That was, it had classic just
independent movie where it was like a,
it didn't fucking lead you around
to the by the nose. Like in,
here's the next one and here's the
next point is the next plot point.
Um, really good movie. All right. Uh,
okay.
Putin,
Russian hacking.
Okay.
All right. This guy's writing about
Russian hacking and he start look,
is that we started?
Yes.
This guy started his fucking,
he just started his fucking a
is his email to me with, look,
he's already wagging his finger
at me. Jesus Christ. Dude, relax.
He says,
look,
international politics between two
countries with enough nous to destroy the
earth 10 times over is no laughing matter.
Oh,
am I not supposed to joke about it?
How come you aren't all
over this orange clown.
Okay.
All right. I going to stand with
the ski. Want jokes about it? Sure.
Clinton was no prize.
Okay.
Uh,
but you're willing to give Putin
and an out now gangster a pass.
Oh, I don't remember him running
for president of the United States.
What are you talking about?
What kind of world is going to
be there for your new child? Oh,
shut the fuck up.
I fucking hate when people will get a
new world is going to be there for your
kid. This same world that was there when
I was a kid. Progressively getting worse.
Like what? What is your fucking solution?
There's no solution to this shit.
He got 7 billion people.
I'll run in and fucking to what?
1 million different directions.
It's a shit show. All right.
The second we weren't one
tribe, it was over. It's over.
Second Day was two tribes. It was
fucking over whenever we started out.
Right. Let's just say that I, I don't,
I don't subscribe that there
was a fucking an Adam and eve,
I think there was a pond and there was
a bunch of us that came out of something
quarter did Neil degrasse Tyson.
It was the fucking trees.
Other people say it was the fucking ocean,
whatever the fuck it was.
There was a bunch of it.
You can't have a man and a woman bagging
and then their kids fucking without
having major problems. All right,
well maybe that's why cavemen,
it looked like they
did.
I have no idea.
But whenever we all weren't
Sorta cohabitating together,
but you know what happened is
then when it was, we came along,
there was no language. It
was just, hello Aled shit.
Of course it was going to be
fucking arguments. Everybody
grunting and groaning,
Ya know, I have no idea. Like
we were fucked. This thing
was fucked from day one.
Okay.
And I've gone down the rabbit hole of
trying to fucking give a shit and trying
to,
you know,
I don't get people to
listen to my opinion,
which probably has 0.1% of
1% of the information that
I need to actually make an
even remotely informed opinion.
You know what I mean?
Look at all those guys on TV who
do it for a fucking living from,
from Bill Maher. Bill O'reilly.
Okay. Even those guys,
as much as they pay attention are severely
handicapped by the fact that they can
not look at talks top secret documents.
Okay.
To kind of connect the dots. All y'all
you can do is watch the fucking news,
read newspapers and try to figure out
which one seems to be sort of making sense
with what the fuck you're thinking.
That's the best she could do. So. So I,
I don't know what you want from me,
but I'll continue reading this. Um,
this isn't like telling jokes to a few
middle millennials in a strip mall.
It's not funny that Trump and his swamp
full of white racist Richmond, uh,
robbing us blind.
Okay.
Uh, I, I agree with that.
But you realize that Hillary Clinton in
2008 after the banks went under a when
and gave them a speech and said,
don't worry, I got you guys.
Those aren't those the same rich,
racist white people.
Yeah.
You know, isn't that the same upper 1%
you know, that you're talking about here?
Uh, just saying they are. You
know, by the way that the upper 1%,
no matter who wins, they win.
You understand that, right?
The job pays 500 grand a year. It
takes 100 billion to get. Okay.
And then they all these cots
favors that got them in office,
they push it through, they deregulate
stuff, they looks the other way,
they granted government contracts,
all of that shit.
And then once they're done being
president, you'll watch with Obama,
he's going to make a fuck load of money
going around. Air Quote, giving speeches,
200, 300 grand at nights. The exact same
fucking people that put them in office.
That's just them washing their
bribe money. People with blue ties,
red ties, red panties, blue panties.
They all fucking do it except for
Jimmy Carter. As far as I can tell,
he stopped being president and started
going around building houses for poor
people. Everybody else sits around waiting
for their fucking library to be built.
Ah, my soapbox gimme a
golden globe. All right.
Just saying they are both bad is
really dropping the ball. No, it isn't.
You have your head in the fucking sand.
That's what it is.
You just have your head
in the fucking sand. Um,
I'm from New Jersey and know several small
contractors who were shorted by Trump
and couldn't afford to sue.
Right.
And I worked in Atlantic city and he had
a couple of casinos go under and they
got paid dimes on the dollar. I know
how that works. He's a real asshole.
That doesn't give a shit about the little
guy. He's got the track record. Lk. Okay.
And you're saying Hillary Clinton
gives a shit about the little guy.
Okay.
Hillary Clinton who only swings by the
little guy whenever she needs votes.
It spends the rest of the time on
fucking Martha's vineyard in her zillion
dollar fucking house that she can somehow
afford when her husband is only made
fucking at the most 500 grand a year.
Okay?
She got paid as a center. What
does that make? 175 grand a year.
Okay?
They're making less money than some of
the fucking top comedians in the fucking
world. Yet there were $200
billion. How do you do that?
How do you do that legally, sir, tell me.
Tell me how you do that.
Cause you fucking crooked.
Alright, so there you go. And here's
the thing about Russia spying on us.
Fucking relax.
We're doing it to them too.
Okay?
Jesus Christ.
They've shot our planes out of the sky.
A spine on we spy on each other.
Apps a fucking Luli, okay?
You know, that's, that's what we do.
Every fucking thing that they're doing.
We're doing there fucking with the
elections. We fuck with elections.
They have fucking with people in power,
putting people in power that
shouldn't be in power. We do that.
They invade countries. We invade
countries. They think they're right.
We think we're right.
At the end of the day,
there's you and me sitting in fucking
Russia, regular fucking people.
All right?
That's it.
It's just the people up top that gets
you all fucking stirred up. You know?
I'm telling you, they get y'all
fucking steak on. I get ya.
I don't listen to any of it.
I don't.
I just sit and I drink scotch and I
drank myself into a stupor and I stare at
the wall. You know, ed,
I try to figure out why.
I looked at three nonwhite kids looking
at an iPhone and stuff that someone was
getting beaten into a gang.
When I solve that first,
then I'm going to move on to trying to
solve the world prompts when I fall,
when I solve the problems in the fucking
globe, that is my giant fucking head.
I'll move on to that. And you, sir,
if you're really looking for
somebody to solve the world problems,
you should probably look beyond a comedian
doing a podcast where he says cunt
every other word, and also says
how uninformed he is. Okay.
So you know, there you go.
Agree to disagree. But you know,
if you want Meryl Streep and fucking all
fucking Billy freckled hands to solve
the world's problems,
I think you were a trouble.
Anybody can give the lip service.
It'd be like,
I think that's absolutely deplorable.
Up a vote.
I didn't vote for the fucking guy. Stop
wagging your finger at me. All right.
All right. Plants in the
house. Hey, the ability ficus.
Uh, I want you to know how I want to know
how you feel about having plants in the
house. Growing up, we always had
plants and CACTI in our house.
I think they bring a lot of life in
color to a room and it's fun to water and
take care of them.
I know some people who would never have
any plants saying that they bring dirt
and bugs in the house. I tell them that
it's because they don't take care of,
maintain them.
You could say the same thing about a dog
saying they shouldn't bring fleas into
the house, but obviously that student
neglecting and taking care of the dog.
So do you have any plants in your home?
Do you have any, any your home now? Oh,
do you like having plants in your home?
Do you have any home plants
in your home now? Um,
ps is a total NFL bandwagon fan.
I'm calling Green Bay to win it all.
Uh, all right. Um, no I don't
like plants in the house.
Um,
I had a plant in my house one time a
long time ago when I was a complete loner
and I, my apartment looked like I was
in the witness protection program.
I was seeing this woman and she got me
a plant and immediately I was just like,
Whoa, way, this relationship
is moving too fast.
And what she was trying to
do was to get me to open up.
And I remember she got
me this plant and uh,
then I had to fucking water it and uh,
I kind of liked it,
but then I'd go on the road and I would
come back and it would be near death,
just like, you know,
hang it down, you know,
staring at his fucking toes and then I
would nurse it back to fucking health and
I would have ended up having anxiety.
And then one day it finally died and
I felt this just ridiculous failure.
Um, and it was a metaphor
for the whole factor.
You're on the road so much.
He can't sustain relationships.
You can't even keep a plant alive.
How are you going to keep a
relationship or a kid lab? It was,
it was a horrible fucking
experience. So, um,
I don't mind having him in my house if
they are like growing like Baisil are
fucking rosemary or some shit.
Some, some I can eat, you know,
I'm selfish when it comes to plants.
Like we've got a bunch of
plants around the house.
I don't give a fuck about
them. I'm like, yeah,
why don't we dig these up and put in
some fucking avocado trees, some oranges,
you know, something that we can eat slash
throat. Zombie someday. What do you say?
Plus having trees that grow fruit in
your yard is a great way to figure out
who's your friend and
who isn't your friend.
Especially during the apocalypse when
people come over your fence and try to
steal your food,
they'll go to the food like moths to a
light and then you can be on your roof
and you can pick them
off with your fucking a,
with whatever fucking weapon you
have. Right? I'd go with a bone arrow.
It's nice and quiet.
Right to the neck.
It was the one that was the water. I mean
the blood gushing out of their fucking,
where the fuck, whatever you call it.
The fucking artery there. Alright.
Plants in the house. I already
read that one. Here's the last one.
A Billy bitch tits that Jesus,
I'm a lady and I listened
to your podcast religiously.
I'm 29 years old and I've had roommates
since I moved out of my parent's house
when I was 18. I have a history
of anxiety and depression.
I found that in addition
to taking medicine,
living with people really
keeps me in check. Uh,
in two weeks I'm going to be moving into
my own apartment and living by myself
with my dog. Oh, that's fucking
awesome. That's the best.
I loved living alone by the dog too. That
would have been tremendous. Of course,
it would have died like the fucking
plan. Uh, right now I live at two guys.
The three of us are super close,
but we've lived together for three years
and it's time for us to move out of the
frat house and into our own places.
I'm nervous about living by myself because
I'm scared that I'm going to isolate
myself and fall back into a cycle of
depression. Again. I live in Indy,
so the weather is shit right now, which
doesn't help. In the spring and summer,
I play intermural sports,
football and volleyball.
I'm very much a guy's girl and I
don't have very many girlfriends.
I don't ever have a ladies' night.
I'd rather sit at a bar with a beer and
watch football or college basketball.
I hate dating. I am straight
though to gay people hate dating.
I don't know.
I would love to get your advice for a
lady like me moving in her own apartment
for the very first time.
What would you suggest I do to stay
social and not sit at home alone watching
the Indiana Hoosiers and downing cores
light a ps telling me I said hi and best
of luck to you and neon on
the new your new baby. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Um,
the boy you're asking a fucking loner.
I love when I finally didn't have
to have roommates and I lived alone.
I fucking loved it.
Okay.
I loved it. I talked to myself. I talked
to the TV. I had a great fucking time. Um,
and I guess I was,
I had a level of depression there
that I wasn't really aware of. Um,
well don't you get enough sort of
interaction when the springtime you play
intermural sports? Football. Volleyball.
Okay. So it's the wintertime. Um,
I don't know.
You want to go sledding?
I'm trying to think
what the fuck he can do.
Is there a adult league snowball
fight thing you can get involved in?
There's gotta be something that
you could do if you're into sports.
Why don't you just join a fantasy
league with some of your friends?
MMM.
But I,
I think what you are is,
I think you're a sweetheart
and your relationship person,
you just afraid to do it. So, uh,
that's why you like having roommates.
You don't like being alone.
I'm totally guessing here,
by the way. I don't fucking
know him, but I, I think, uh,
I think it's time to give date and
a try. You know, I would do that.
Maybe you're afraid of doing that.
I would.
I think this seems like you need to face
a fear and look at this living alone as
an opportunity thing and that this is
the next logical step to finding the
person you want to be with in
life, if that's what you're
looking for. So I would,
um, embrace living alone and I'll
fucking awesome that is. And,
uh, decorate your apartment.
Don't do what I did, you know,
have some color in there and off
that type of shit. Something upbeat
and uh,
I would become social.
I would have people over to your place.
You can even, I don't know if you cook,
this is zillion things you could do.
You just have to make the effort. Um,
I don't know why you don't
have many girlfriends,
but it sounds like you
do have some girlfriends,
so you only need a couple of friends.
I would open up to your friends
rather than some psycho on a podcast.
Not saying this was a bad move, but it's
a nice step. I would open up to them,
just say, listen, I'm prone to depression.
So I'm worried that when I live alone
that I'm going to become depressed.
You know, if you'd like to
swing by and watch a game with
me, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah,
I would do that.
I would be open and honest and maybe go
talk to somebody about your depression.
Um, so you don't go down
that fucking rabbit hole,
but it's great that you know that
you're depressed and that you need to do
something about it so that you're way
ahead of the game as opposed to where I
was, where I did know I was
depressed and I fucking, uh,
yeah.
I don't know. It made a lot of stupid
fucking moves for a long time. All right.
That's the podcast for this week. Uh,
thank you so much for listening and, uh,
I'll post that video of
that Cadillac. Eldorado it's
fucking beautiful. All right.
Go fuck yourselves and I'll
talk to you on Thursday.