Yeah. And taste the 25th of September.
All right. Hey, what's going on?
Is Bill Burn? It's time for the
Monday morning podcasts for Monday.
Did I say podcasts? Podcasts for
Monday, September 25th, 2017.
What's going on? How are Yah, what's up?
I am back from Toronto, Canada,
and every once in a while,
every once in a long while I have a, I
have a guest and I always get good guests.
And this is, no, today is no exception.
We have the great Philippe aspires are
on here who has a welcome, first of all,
welcome.
[inaudible] was so full.
They go fully based bars if fun
of what's selling podcast. And uh,
let's get all the hype out of the way.
At first we got a,
you have a new HBO special?
Yes.
A new HBO special on so 30th 10
September 30th at 10 on Hbo. That's
where the HBO specials are. Culled.
Translate this. So, uh, let's
get into it. Tell me about that.
What's it like to shoot a
hour long special for HBO?
Um, it was, it was good. Um,
I showed him myself. Um, I,
I, um, I got the money together.
I stayed up the money and
my wife and I are, we, um,
we chose that Jose Improv
and we got cloud shires and,
um, it was all DIY, you know,
so you did it yourself and HBO liked
it so much. They bought it. Oh,
so when you were doing it, you weren't
thinking like, Oh shit, I'm doing an HBS,
Mashallah, no. To Go, they open,
go to Netflix or even Amazon.
No, but that's, I think that's
a, uh, that's a great way to do,
I had a fuck is nobody giving you a shot?
I don't know.
You know why you're not white
like me. Um, I gotta be honest,
before where I did this,
you know,
I was looking up like videos and all
that type of stuff to make sure I got
something to talk about. So
it doesn't become this, like,
my biggest fear with these interviews
is it's just gonna become this horrific
staring contest because I'm
such a huge fan of what you do.
And I had never seen the, uh, the Irish
when Ari Shaffir was hosting the show.
Uh, this isn't happening. When
you told that whole story about,
uh,
being in the gang and fight and the
guy biting his air off and shit,
it's just like, like I was listening
to that, that story. It was like,
this is like at least three different
Tarantino movies and then you ended it and
just such a nice place. I don't want
to force you to tell the story again,
but if you could just recap mine.
Um, I like to start by where did you grow?
I grew up in Boyle Heights, California,
Los Angeles, but east la,
but he called Boyle Heights.
East la is like further east,
east.
I love that. Engineers, you know,
is by almost close to Monterey Park,
but Boyle heights in the neighborhood.
Right, right. How far away is that?
To put it in white perspective. How far
away is that from the staples center? Ooh.
If I were to walk it'll
take me like an hour.
And so if you were to drive
probably 50 minutes with him.
He's minutes. Okay, cool.
A 30 minute bus ride.
Okay. 30 minute bus ride.
So you grew up, uh, what,
what, what decade? You were a
child of what? You're the 80s
and we're been 80. So that was
the real deal. Yeah. I grew up in,
my neighborhood was in
the housing projects,
Pico Gardens and the one like
three separate out in projects.
Those Aliso village peak or at least so
and then Pico Gardens from first street
to like sixth street. Okay.
And there was like say man,
it was like a shit load of gangs.
Like maybe 11.
How did you, now, when you're not
in a gang and you're a young kid,
how do you negotiate?
Like I got to get from my house.
I gotta go pick up my, my fuck, I got to
go do my laundry. I got to go to school.
How do you negotiate? Uh, is
it, uh, now our gangs 24, seven.
Oh Yeah, man, the 2,400
neighborhood, there were 24, seven I,
how we start that came out around five,
like anybody with like just
live in a regular lifestyle,
goes to bed and then they just kind
of give up this, the area. Yeah.
Then those gangs,
they come on at five.
They're let the gangs that there are
still living in a gentrified neighborhood.
Okay. They don't come on a data, they
might call the cops on them. Oh yeah.
Remember most guys, you know from
Echo Park, they come on at night, man.
Robbing people. Really? Yeah. They
come on at night. Those guys were,
were those jetro vacation?
Those gangs are still around but they
come on at night and the gang bangers,
different areas, you know. But there's
still gang banging. They don't have yet.
How old were you the
first time you got mugged?
I got mugged the first time when I
was like 18 years old. My friend,
I'm coco. That's pretty good math. Yeah,
I got all the 18 downtown crossing when
I was like in eighth grade that I was
like,
I was selling crack on my first day like
that where they one hour I got robbed.
Somebody put a knife behind my back
under the knife in my like in front of me
and they took all my crack away.
Tacony crack away.
So then what do you have to do?
Oh,
I have to go back to the guy who gave it
to me or a friend of mine who I grew up
with and you know he passed away already
because they used to call them cocoa
and we grew up together. Him and I
were, I'm from second grade to adults.
I needed money at the time I got somebody
pregnant and I didn't know how to make
money. So I asked him for a
job in the criminal business,
can I, you know, hey man, I had
no money. How does that go down?
You'd probably avoid it. It's like
I don't want to sell drugs, but I,
I kind of have to now I got a kid comment,
so help me.
So he gave me like $100 of crack,
you know,
a hundred to bring me back a hundred
they didn't give you more to sell.
So as soon as I got out, they didn't
know who I was in that neighborhood.
They just came around me
and he took all my stuff.
They didn't hurt me or anything.
I was begging for my just can I
keep my id and the Game Id Alec did.
How scared I was scared. I thought they
were going to kill me right there. I was,
I felt like oh young. I was really scared
but I'll calm, you know, I wouldn't like,
uh, all right, just take your man, just
take your, leave me alone, you know,
just walked out of I take it,
I didn't fight him or nothing cause I
knew they would have killed me or stab me
or worse.
So went back to my friend Coco and I
told him what happened and I thought,
you know, he was going to be okay
man. You know it's all right.
You know it's your fault. It
happens. It happens. No Man man,
that night escalate it like it took it,
he gave you the crack
and I go on midnight,
I go rather than one 30 at two 30 in
the morning and back at his house. What?
Who robbed you? Cause so what
happened? He gave me a gun,
he gave me a pistol, he got himself
a pistol and he, and he put a,
a blue handkerchief on his head and he
put a black beanie on and we both were
looking for those guys.
And you must have been praying to God
like I didn't want to murder somebody the
first, Oh hell yeah. Mel Praying,
please don't find it guys. Wow. Cause I,
there I was like,
I would've probably with done anything,
he would have told me all the vulnerable.
I was weak, you know I have no,
I didn't know what to do.
So we went together and we saw one guy
that saw what happened but he didn't do
anything and, and then like he kinda
like hit him real hard. And who did it?
Man where the ad then I say manual
is in here, man. It wasn't him.
So it wasn't him. Wait, how did
Danny, so you go, oh there's,
I remember that guy standing
there watching me get broad.
Now this poor pastor to gets dragged into,
which he gets dragged into anything.
He got like, he got a gun
slap, you know by my friend.
He's my friend name and no question,
he just hit him in the face hard man.
And like he started to believe, I
mean the year and I just say, wow man.
He was looking at me like, come on man,
please tell them what they mean to you.
Wait until after the pistol slap. I meant
meant to tell you this. It wasn't him.
So we got nothing happened to him and
we went back and later on those guys who
actually did it, walked back
and gave it back or everything.
Get back to crack to that
guy and everything was cool
because of what he has to
have. Sorry, we didn't know that
they were afraid of that guy. Yeah.
So we didn't know Batman. We're with
you. We should street nickname. Yeah.
So then after that then they
knew that you were with him.
So then people stop fucking with you.
People Start Messing with me. Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
This is what kills me about you is you
have like a thousand of those stories and
you're the most relaxed,
laid back guy ever.
Like where did it all go?
Because due to I look at me,
I sound like I lived your life and
you sound like you lived my life.
Like you sound like you grew up in a
nice little cul de sac area and played
street hockey and I'm all fucking
wound up. How did you do that? Well,
I have a mom.
I have parents,
I have my mom and dad and most of my
crazy friends in the projects, you know,
the crazier ones, they didn't
have a mom and dad. Right.
They had nobody telling him you better
come home early or there was nobody
telling those kids to come home and
the lights go on in the streets.
So they had no really nobody telling
them what to do, how to live. Right.
No discipline.
I have my mom and dad mom and worked
and my mom stood up on my work that a
elementary school and then be home from
selling crack when the streetlights came
on. Right? Yeah, yeah, you had that.
And I've always that family foundation,
but I've always out. But I don't
get that. I just now you're talking,
you got a home life,
but you're telling you you're doing
all this other shit will know the kid.
You know when I was like 13, 12, 14
years old, I wasn't crazy. Oh, I see.
Crazy. After high school, that's the
one pregnant. I didn't know what to do,
but it was always like
a little hustler man.
My mom will saw a bond and I
will collect the money for her.
He knows who I learned how
to collect money for people,
at least from my mom was always
telling, um, herbal life, a bond.
She was always studying something.
Can we live by the warehouses in
downtown la where the factories are Rad,
where other trucks will come in and pick
up stuff on the trains and take them to
like stores.
So when Mama knew where like we used to
go to this one factory and we used to,
um, put a bunch of that synthetic
cotton, the plastic one,
they will throw it away. And my mom and
I will put it in bags, like hefty bags.
And then we go to another place where
they will throw these raggedy old sheets.
And then my mind was so those raggedy old
sheets with the cotton and then we'll,
we'll, we'll, we'll door to Dell
door to door in the housing projects,
selling pillows.
So you guys were real green family man.
You were there, you were there. Recycling.
That's wonderful thing.
We've sold,
we've borrowed the trash and we
sold it like we've so pillows.
I used to when I was like 14,
I used to walk to Delta
to do with pallets.
Would you build a little house and then
sell that? No, that's too much work.
I want to, we want fast
money. Oh, okay. Cash.
Although there's a bunch of
batteries where I live, you know,
I felt like I felt like Henry
Hill from Goodfellas, right.
Because they were always stealing stuff
from the airport and we always taking
stuff from these factories.
I wasn't stealing from these batteries.
My friends where I was taking
stuff in the trash like, um,
though there was a watermelon factory and
they will throw away run water matters
and I will get the watermelons
and clinicians, watermelon,
they make waterman grew them.
Know that they were getting from
the farmer I guess. And they right.
They would hold them there.
They have pallets full of watermelon from,
cause there's like a grocery area of
downtown la where every grocer oh gets all
this other stuff. Flowers, stereos,
you know, you name it bananas.
I know where everything is that suits
you. Cheap suits. I know everything's at.
So we'll get the wanting to hang out
with and just go to the dumpsters and
whenever they threw out you
would then go sell. Yeah,
I will cut that water money to have
and then go sell it to the Mexicans.
They laborers,
everybody working in the factories.
Much a bunch of immigrants.
Right.
And always thought though the
half a watermelon for a dollar,
$2 five I'll just cut
the running piece off.
You know what I mean? Oh it once
in a while. Nobody is looking.
I will stay in my little home girl.
This girl,
the little less well should a lesbian now,
but we didn't know she was a lesbian now.
She was like a tomboy.
I was sending her in there
with my brother and then went.
There was like when they were,
everybody was looking,
they would throw good
watermen in the trashcan too,
so we had to make sure of
good and bad water, mountains.
How long did you stay in that whole world
is selling crack and all of that and
and all those fights and bite and
the guy's ear off and all that shit.
Before you became a comedian,
like how long,
how long was that period of your life?
That was my period of from 18
years old to like 21 and a half,
21 and a half because at 21 is when
I was like messing up already man.
I was like,
I'm smoking a lot of PCP.
That was like my drug of choice
for the time being and man,
I used to get all crazy, see PCP and like
I think it's an elephant tranquilizer.
That's what the people tell me.
I saw he's here that grown a PCP,
angel dust and all that and angel angel
does is like coming crystallized PCP.
You could put it in a cigarette
but PCP in my neighborhood,
we were at the PCP capitol,
the of Los Angeles,
like in my neighborhood they sold
gallons of it. People had to,
they would have,
I'm sparkers water full of
PCP so everybody had PCP.
Wait a minute. And you how did, how
did you ingest it? You smoked it.
No you did like a,
I'm giving away secrets here.
I'll tell you why I'm asking.
Cause everybody tries to act like,
oh you understand all no man,
I don't know any of that stuff.
You will get a Newport cigarette.
Oh for real menthol cigarette,
a new port and then you put you or you
and you dip it instead like a little jar.
Like I'm just the tip and
that's a $5 tip as a $5 dip.
He did put again at 10 you dip
a whole one is 20 you know, you,
you soak it is $30 and it's by
Deb. You know. Now I get it.
That's like when I drank booze,
there's like the 10 year old
shit that you're only up to 25.
Then you get into the cognacs and
that can be like, I dunno, like a fun,
I don't know. Wines and shit could
be like a century or older some.
So there's one night I was smoking PC
just cause I'm stupid as hell when it
comes to it. So what is it?
What's that highlight is mad.
It's like you're the incredible hoke.
Oh, if somebody attacks you, oh,
this is a shit when like five cops up
and they got to see that I've marked,
did you see that Charles Bronson movie?
There's worse three. One white boy,
like a surf fourth. He's been,
he's fighting other police
officers. He's on PCP. Oh,
okay. I got to rewatch that. Yeah,
about PCB. You take, you have, um,
like incredible host strength, but you
just have like, you don't feel pain,
but while people are hitting you, man,
you could just keep attacking forever.
You know what I mean?
Right.
And then the next morning you wake up
and you feel like you played 12 years in
the NFL. Yeah, man. Alright,
so the first time you smoked
PCP and that shit hits you,
it's like literally like you're turning
into like a superhero. Yeah, man.
Well, the one time, when did you do,
did you try to bend something? Nah,
that's what I was taught. Cops. No,
no, that's what I would've done it.
I want to try to pull something off
the fucking wall a bit ago. The Rona,
well when I, when they work in a row,
I'll be coming to be known as Batman.
You know, he's crazy. We'll chop.
We're here. Why did they call you?
Why did they call you Batman? Cause um,
I love Batman and I used to wear my, my,
those um, superhero on
the rules and 18. Yeah,
man.
Well the Batman shirts still fit,
so I wore it and I don't know where
to go to a Batman shirt anywhere else.
It was the underoos factory
right down the street.
It took it out of the dumps to the
bad projects. Yeah. That's amazing.
All right, so you don't
want all that. I'm watching,
I'm driving the theater with my friends
smoking PCP watching terminator two
asking what I was saying.
I'd fight that guy. Yeah man.
And I'm thinking about the guy that
bullied me for the last two weeks.
So I go wait,
if you smoke that she say say a guy views
I fuck I shouldn't do this cause I'm
like doing a commercial here for the
drug sane is somebody bullying you.
You can't beat that guy.
Right.
If you were to smoke some PCP it
definitely would give you the belief.
But can it overcome how slow you are
and your inability to slip a punch in or
you just walked through his shit? Yeah
man, you're throwing punches. Cause um,
when I, when I got into a
fight with his guys, I will,
they told me I was doing things
though I remember doing that.
They told me that took my belt off
in a whipping them all over the,
we keep alluding to the story. You got to
tell the story, right? So you're Batman,
you got on your under roofs,
you smoked PCP at the driving.
He saw the terminator two
when I left the Terminator two movie,
I come back into a project and I see
this guy that he looked like an old dude,
man. He's like 30 years old. He just came
out of prison. He don't know who I am.
He's like calling me bad names and um,
pushing me and pushing me and I, I want
to fight him pushing me. They finally,
I socked him in the face
but I kind of missed that.
He hit me right in the eye and he hit
me hard and my, I got black right away.
He punched me in the pace. I started
bleeding. Then he started choking me.
So when he started choking me,
that's when I like, I went crazy.
I went crazy man. I lifted
him up, dropped him, period.
I bet his dear our first of our period,
the era of malware at the whole Kogan
retire brother, let me ask you this,
when you build a zero, if we were
underneath, are you on top of him?
I was like underneath him,
he was choking me and you just,
all of a sudden that PCP, I paid it off,
man. I never thought mass gain his solos.
Easy to bite off and spin. Crochet. No,
not even man.
I spit it out and I started punching
him and then my friends told me that um,
wait, what did he do? Or May
took the hits like a soldier.
So when you bend his ear off,
this guy [inaudible] he's,
he's screaming like a little
girl. Okay. Do you think pain?
So actually he's kind of screaming like
a guy who got his ear bit off point.
I think you're still a man if you,
if you go up a few octaves when
you're missing a fucking year.
But I don't know why. I believe
the Arab, I mean I had no,
I get the handle of choice,
you know, he was choking me.
Sounded like that was the move.
No one helping me. He wasn't,
didn't seem like he was going to be
stopping. All right. See you beat,
then you took your belt off and you were,
my friends told me that I took him my
belt off and I thought it were whipping
him. Like he will like chasing them
with a bout whipping them like,
like he was like, oh, runaway
property or something.
And how many people are witnessing
this? I think it's wild. 15 people,
but they're all like cheering
me on, cheering here, Mar.
Nobody's helping Denomie hits that
would get like nowadays if they were to,
that would be, that wouldn't be
like, it would be epic PCP guy,
epic belt guy. They'd be something
like that or been a rap song. Autotune
man, we're, yeah, so wait a
minute. So when you, so you
don't remember doing that.
So there was like, oh fuck,
this guy's going to kill me.
Then you start to bite his
ear off. You're like, wow,
here's come off really easily.
Then you sort of blackout and then like
when you just sorta came to with like
blood all over, you going
like, uh, the nicest seat,
a hot dog or something together.
Next day I wake up,
the next day I'm walking around,
it's like a seven in the morning,
eight in the morning. I don't know, man.
I'm looking at, my body is full of blood,
my pants, my face. You know my, I have a
black guy, my shirt, it's full of blood.
I have no idea what happened.
You probably thought it was your
blood. I didn't know that. Whoa man.
I was like checking steel. I got shot
or stabbed by somebody they didn't know.
Then my friends told me what happened
and the guy was in the house,
he went to the hospital for
like a broken ribs missing,
missing an ear, you know, where he's
just putting neosporin on that has it.
And they went to,
he was laying in bed and they asked him
if you want to press charges, you know,
cause everybody know there was witnesses.
Everybody knew who did it. And um,
he said, no, we're going to handle
the right way. And I was like, oh,
I didn't even know. No, there's a little
later on, like a week later you go,
yeah man, I think there's like
a green light on you right now.
And the mean like green light. What
do you mean green light? Yeah man.
Shoot to kill and they see you.
What the fuck. So that's the first
time you ever heard that. So now what?
Now what do you do besides not go outside?
Do they know where you live?
They know where I live, but I don't
know. He's still in the hospital though,
but everything's calm, you
know. But he's doing a hospital.
But I can feel tension from people who
are who I thought were my friend one time
who had, who I grew up with, you know,
you know they were turning on me like,
cause I would never in their gang,
I was in another gang.
When you watch the wire, do you like
fall asleep as it like boring to you?
Because you don't need to.
You lift it. So I'm like,
it sounds like an
award winning series to me. I'm more like
blood in blood out. So wait a minute.
So now, now there's a
green light on you. Yeah.
And think at some point you got to go
outside to get food because you're hungry.
Yeah. So I'm going to take, when you
have a green light on you in, in East La,
what's a good time to go out to?
If you've got to go hit,
hit the Mayfair market or whatever.
What's it called? Man Do. And you know,
when you have a green light
and in from anybody, you know,
whether it comes from prison or ever
come from just the neighborhood,
it's just relieve man, move
somewhere safe. Like Modesto.
What's a more serious greenlight?
If it came from prison or from the
neighborhood? And if it come from prison,
you're a dead man man. I mean there's
nowhere to go. They're nowhere to go, man.
And um, I read about these things,
you know, on kind of it on books.
There's no way coming back from that.
But then it was like only like a green
light from his neighborhood. You know,
let's go to the mall, like the Grove, pick
a really white mall. And you know what?
All those thoughts came to my
mind at that time. Like, man,
I wish I would like the
fresh prince of Bel Air.
I wish that a rich white guy didn't
take a rich white guy or a wish. Fuck,
you're Mexican guy. Oh No, wait.
They weren't wearing that show.
That was different strokes, those
different struggles. But to drumming,
they switched it up. They're
like, it's different strokes.
Except the marathon allowed into right
now. Yeah. That's what they over there.
They always do that shit. So my
mom called out farther. Greg Boyle.
He's like this priest that I
grew up with in the neighborhood.
He's from the homeboy industries
hearing our name. That's a thing.
Yeah, he helps. He helps them. Gang
members. That's a cool name. All right.
Father Greg Boyle, he'd like a
priest from my neighborhood and um,
he's always helped the neighborhood.
Like he will go on his way to help people.
He was like, if he like if
he's driving and then you like,
he will pick up kids that were drunk
off the streets and take him home.
He did that a couple of times for me.
In a good way. In a good way. Yeah.
Like if you're a gay member in the wrong
neighborhood and then you know you're
pretty much,
someone's going to kill you in that
neighborhood for the great boy would tell
you, get in a van. I think
you're back home as a, as,
as a gang member, how do you end up in
the wrong neighborhood other than a woman,
a man on PCP, the Goddamn PCP. There's no,
there's no heroin in your neighborhood.
So nothing there.
Go buy heroin or somewhere else, you know,
there's no crack in the neighborhood.
You know, there's, it's a dry spell
somewhere and you've got to get high,
so you got to go to another neighborhood
and buy it. Oh God. Oh, you have a,
and so how did they know you
were in a different gang?
You don't go over there wearing your
whole, your colors. Right. Most of the,
the hardcore gang members, they
were the colors, man. They,
they're not going to stop
wearing their colors. Yeah. Boy,
they're now on the cover there 24 seven.
But I was one,
I wasn't even one of those guys.
I was nothing like that.
It was just a guy who will just
hanging around with these kids.
And the one thing I get jumped
into a gang and I'm getting
into so much trouble,
but I don't no idea to get beaten into a
gang just in case I ever fucked my life
up and I go to prison,
you know when I go to prison,
my only hope is I got to
join the area and Nazi guys,
I can listen to their bullshit and
pretend I believe it just to save myself.
How long is that beat though?
Um, well in, in, in the
streets it will be like,
I guess whatever number the gang is.
So with 18th street you going to get
beat up for 18 seconds. That's it. Yeah.
Or, but I mean, how many guys are
all of them? Oh Jesus. Okay. Fuck.
Can I strike thing? That's
it from the record there.
Because when I got jumped in,
I was just hanging out man. Like I was
just hanging out and then somebody said,
I'm a man, you want to get jumped in. And
I wasn't going to say no. If I say no,
I'm a punk, I'm gonna get jumped in.
I'm going to get Joe for being a punk.
So I said, fuck it, let's do it.
And then I punched the guy
next to me for no reason. Well,
because I want to prove that I'm, I'm,
I'm tough. So the guy next to him,
I just knocked him out with one punch man.
And then I hit like,
he wasn't even looking. I said, let's
do this. And then like I hit him. Right.
You know,
you gotta be really big dog to look
God homie. They said Warren Sapp moment.
Keep your head on a swivel. Look good.
I bet he get the other
guy shit later. Like, Hey,
next time you're going to jump somebody.
Yeah.
Can you not say what I'm sitting
right next to you knew he was a lefty.
What the fuck you get beat up and I
got a job by everybody that one in and
they're, did you get more than one
ended? You get one. I've got two in one,
him and another guy.
But then after that I felt like
Nike cortex all over my face.
So you just laying on the ground and
you just go at one Mississippi two.
We're just waiting for this reign of,
of footlocker to stop coming down on you.
Yeah, man. I was like, I tried to never
going to stop, man. So what do you do?
I would just, Oh, they're funny. They
still all right. Hit enough, hit enough.
Then everybody's hugging me. The same
people that were beating my brains up.
We're hugging me and kissing me.
You'll, I love you. You're my boy.
You're my family now.
And they're like, wow.
So then you come home. Okay.
And then you just sit in there,
all right with Huc and sneaker mocks all
over you and you're going like, okay,
now I guess I'm in a
gang. Jesus Christ. Okay.
So then what happens?
Um,
I thought what happened was I started
hanging around with white people.
Talk about white privilege going to, what
the fuck is that? This is what it is.
Totally.
Yes.
It can sit there selling lemonade at the
end of your driveway and accidentally,
did I just join a gang? There
was, there's a green light on you.
You were selling lemonade at
the end of the wrong driveway
neighborhood. Okay. Was dumb.
But you know like there was two white
boys in my neighborhood that were gangs
was one the red headed
kid from children of the,
exactly. He was. He was.
He said, well the one guy,
he was a blood actually guy. He was
from east La. Slow man. Econom okay.
Those are, those are actually two
white boys had offensive by the way,
but continued.
There was two white boys in the hood man.
And they were both gangbangers and one
thing about bought white boy Cholos like
when you see a white boy join a gang and
when you see a white guy that someone
like you and you're hanging around
with them, nothing but Mexicans,
white white guys are the
most craziest gangsters.
When they were in a Mexican gang and
they do stuff that a Mexican man would
never think of. Like I remember this
one white guy, slow man. He was a blood.
He said, man, let's go do
a home invasion. And I,
and everybody was asking him
where he goes, my mom house.
Oh, he wanted a home game.
All right, that's not right.
And he wanted them,
he wanted the Ibrance,
the other homeys to rob his house
because he wanted his mom and dad to get
robbed. Why? Cause I don't know
man. They're probably saying stop hanging
out with all those Mexicans, his idea.
And I was like, Damn. So they
probably behave that way. Cause they,
they felt no matter what, they had
to constantly proof, constantly men,
because technically they could
just get a haircut or whatever,
put away the flannel and just slip, slip
away, man. Slip away down at the Grove,
slip away,
become a social worker and that'll be it.
So how long were you when this gang for,
and did you ever get beaten out?
No, I was in his gang, um, when
I'm father Greg Boyle and a,
but they go to the year off. I went
to Rehab. My Father Greg Boyle,
took me to rehab and I'm, I, I
disappeared for, I'm still gone.
I never went back. Oh, he never went back
or when you get beaten out of a gang,
how uh, how long has that beat
though? As long as they want to. Um,
I knew what we had. I had a guy in
the podcast named Fabian who was in a,
in a gang and he talks about
he got beat up, beat out.
He got jumped out and he said that when
he got jumped, they just last longer.
But I'm,
his uncle is doing the gang simple
expression is doing the gang.
So his uncle over saw him getting jumped
out so he didn't get hurt that bad.
Uh,
I don't have a no go.
I probably would have got killed if I
got jumped out with him when I was 20
white version of that
is our dad's the judge,
so we don't go to jail or
whatever the fuck we just did.
Your version is that you got an uncle
that overseas being jumped out? Yeah,
I got tagged to it. I'm, I'm learning
all kinds of stuff. Like I wonder,
I don't know my case, somebody
just walking by somebody recorder.
So he's feels weird to have
to like re hype something.
So your special on HBO that you shot
yourself learning all of your do it
yourself stuff from fucking
going around in those warehouses,
making pillows out of nothing. You
ended up shooting and said, uh, the, uh,
the Improv in San Jose, which is one of
my favorite color and then a great club.
Cause you feel like you're doing a
theater even though even it's a club,
it's tremendous.
And a,
you shot it there.
It's going to be on Hbo September 30th
at 10 o'clock called translate this.
Now are you, I know you're a
great joke writer, but you,
uh, I saw an Irish affairs,
you told that and he told the amazing
story that you, you touched on today. Um,
is your standup style on this more joke
telling, more storytelling or both?
You know what my common special
is? It's more about, um,
it's more about how I got to this country
with my parents and I'm being as a
single father and being a cheater.
But yeah, I cheat a lot.
I get caught, cheat,
cheating all the time.
I'm bad. I can't help it.
I love women.
I tell her about getting caught
cheating because I will cut cheating.
You Know Bert? Both girls
showed up to my house. Oh God.
You know what I mean? Aliyah in a
man. It was crazy and he asked me,
are going to save for yourself?
How long have you made?
How long was that beat down? Was that
long in 18 seconds. It was crazy.
They showed up in the same car. Oh they,
they talked to each other. Yeah, man.
On how they film it and Shit.
And then you go in there and then you're
going to do like an apology and all
that shit though. First
48 yeah. Wow. Okay,
so you got to do it. I can't wait
to see this photo, Michelle. I see.
I really honestly do.
All right,
stand up comedian. I cannot
wait to see this. Thank you.
One of the most interesting dudes.
How are you so fucking happy?
Go lucky. I don't get it. I don't know
much. I love life. You know, I'm never,
I'm never going to go back
to that type of life though,
that I had in my twenties.
And I'm just love living life man.
And I'm not going to say
that I'm perfect because I'm,
I did fall off two hours
where after I went to Rehab,
I was sober for 11 years. I didn't touch
no drugs. I didn't trust no alcohol,
no beer or nothing. But, um,
along the way you know that the more that
the standup comedy, the more you know,
I did it. I'm not going nowhere.
I went back to smoking crack.
She went right back to crack. She
never really wear a booze guy, huh? No,
it's probably an on
booze. And he said, dude,
it's like Ralphie may retweeted
my tweet the other night and I'm,
I don't understand what he meant at
first because I was in Houston and he
retweeted, um, what cha
full of spoons, bro.
And then I, what the hell is Rafi? We're
talking about them spools. Then I say,
Oh shit,
I got so coked out in Houston,
Texas. I, I, they known for that day.
I couldn't do no more coke
and my nose was bleeding,
so I wanted to rocket up and smoking
crack instead. You know, cause I want to,
Oh see you just like, I'm
just going to snort a couple
of lines. Yeah, but did you,
did you anticipate like,
we were like, fuck this,
when I go to Houston I'm going to party
or was was it just a spontaneous thing
and all of a sudden you just said,
fuck it. Oh Man, I was over there.
I'll working the last stop in Houston.
Shut out to Pete [inaudible] book in me,
Pete,
and often the laptop. Um, I've
got, I've got, I started party man.
I uh, I started partying and I
couldn't find no powder, no coke.
So I'm, I hope you don't mind me Italian
dude. But I call it with Joel Diaz. I say,
Hey, your deal, you know anybody over
here, you caught me at six in the morning.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You'll probably metrics in the morning.
You fucking cock saga.
Ah,
I wrote that grant. Joey. I know somebody.
okay.
So I knew he knew somebody.
I know he, he, uh,
we go talk to this comedian.
So I spoke to this comedian and then I'm
this little Mexican food showed up all
week taking care of me.
I give them free tickets every day.
I think you and um,
I,
I don't know what happened man,
but I, I did too much coke.
I felt like I can't do no more code
through my nose, so I'm going to go bad.
I want to smoke crack now. You know
what I mean? I don't want to stay.
I want burgers now. Dude. A
reoccurring story with you is,
I don't know what happened last time.
He didn't know what happened.
You were whipping somebody with the belt.
Now you don't know what happened is like
a fucking hole in your nose. Jesus do.
Well, how long ago was this? This was
them 2006. All right, so you, okay,
so you broke your record.
You've gone, you've gone, it's
11. Yeah. Yeah. I called up,
um,
room service.
The one is more cracked and I call
it a committee of a color room.
Service Room Service.
I'm going to need,
I'm a big spoon and a baking
soda brought over right now.
And they did not bring that to
the room. Oh, they brought it man,
they did two guys that brought
here the governor front dead.
He knew me cause I'm,
I made friends with him,
I already know from previous times and
he brought it and it was like a big spoon
and he brought the arm and hammer
baking soda. And the guy with him,
he just went with him to laugh
at me, I guess. He goes, Hey,
I guess he couldn't believe it.
You know this guy just order baking
soda and spoon. No Way. Let's go see.
So the bolt open a door. I they,
they give it to me. They both laugh.
But yeah, man, I wanted
to smoke crack. Okay, so,
and then, and then how long were you
off the wagon for? From when? Okay,
so you're sober for 11 years.
You go to Houston,
you order a spoon and some baking
soda and now you snort coke,
now you're smoking. I got you partied that
weekend. Did you just come back and go,
what the fuck was that?
And were you able to or did you
have to go to rehab and no man,
I continue party man from that moment
on and the grow with, with man,
she ended up being a hermaphrodite but
that was another story for another time,
you know? But yeah, sure.
The hermaphrodite she had,
you were born with a peanut,
then a vagina. Right?
So like how long was she your
girlfriend before you figured that out?
Well, we were part of that three
months. You must be a gentleman. Yes.
That's what it was. I was a
gentleman. I didn't want to touch her.
Nothing because she broke freak,
cold man. I can be that guy.
So I just kissed her a couple of times,
but then by the third night, you know,
we're, we're, oh for three nice to rate
her an I. But when I finally found out,
I was like, whoa man. Yeah, that's
a big skin tag you got there.
So it was that. So was that enough
to get your sober again? No, man.
I think he's sober again to a
2009 that stop sign. All right,
so now we're still going. I didn't
get sober till 2009. Oh fuck.
And you were already doing it.
So during those periods he was
still doing stand up and you won't
y'all doing standup?
I won't even know.
I even got to go to Montreal
comedy festival in 2005 and um,
I was bad. I did the young
comedian show and I did well.
I guess I did well,
I got a little,
a little print on the Hollywood reporter.
I got an agent.
Uta,
actually
they didn't have any idea you were high.
No ma'am. I was on, I was smoking crack
in Montreal too. I hooked it up. I mean,
I found crack and Montreal.
It's funny,
I saw a Mexican guy in Montreal and I
knew he spoke Spanish and I told him,
man, could you tell him? I just could
tell him, man, he had the boots, you know,
he had that look like I need a job. You
know, I don't even know what that means.
It's hilarious. He got the boots,
you know, he had that look like I,
I just got here cross country.
So he spoke Spanish,
he spoke Spanish, no
English, but he does know,
he knows how to speak French now.
But with a Mexican, you know,
Mexican accent.
He was doing all the romantic languages.
Dawn bubble ball to Doug and he comes back
a romance languages.
Yeah, man. Crag. Well,
all right dude,
you are,
I could talk to you for like fucking
10 hours and you just don't run out.
It's amazing man. I don't have, thank God
you're still here. Oh, I'm sober. I know.
But all this stuff you've done,
you know,
like realistically you probably could
have died in 80% of the stories. You just,
man, I'm glad I'm alive. Yeah,
I am too mad cause I think you're a
fucking amazing comedian and person.
I'm psyched that you're on all
the all things comedy, podcasts,
network with the what's up fool podcast.
Um,
I wish you nothing but the
best with your, uh, your,
your standup special HPL Saturday,
September 30th,
set your DVR is whatever the kids do now,
you cord cutters,
whatever you do to fucking
see this thing and uh,
more success to you in a
stay out of Houston are will.
All right,
thanks Philippe.
They bill burr Billy Burke all all right.
That was
Phillippi aspire as a man like fucking
guy. Amazing. Please. Checkout is special.
I just said all that shit.
I got to do my reads here and then
I'm gonna talk a little NFL football.
Maybe answer a couple of questions.
Fill out the rest of this hour here. A.
All right, our first, ah, oh Jesus,
look who's back. It's all zip.
Um, talk about the challenge of finding,
I'm not doing that with zip recruiter.
You can post your job to 100%,
100 plus job sites with just one click.
Then their powerful technology efficiently
matches the right people to your job
better than anyone else. That is
why that is why, that's why zip
recruiter is different.
Unlike any other sites.
Ziprecruiter doesn't depend on candidates.
Finding you would find them. In fact,
80% of employers who post jobs on zip
get a quality candidate through the site
within one day. No more juggling emails.
You don't have time for that shit or
calls to your office. Simply screen rate,
manage candidates all in one place at
Ziprecruiter's. Easy to use dashboard.
Find out today why zip
has been used by businesses of all sizes
to find the most quality job candidates
with immediate results.
And right now my listeners can
post jobs on Ziprecruiter for free.
That's right free.
Just go to ziprecruiter.com/burr.
That's zip recruiter.com/ [inaudible]
one more time for free. Go to zip
[inaudible] dot com slash burp um,
alright.
Mvmt also known as movement.
The company that started what was started
by two broke college kids that wanted
to wear stylish watches
but couldn't afford them.
They had no money at somehow
they started a watch company. Uh,
so they started their own watch company.
Um, how is this like how you started?
Well, I didn't have any money and
I then I started a comedy club.
I built my grand off. Fuck it. What I got,
I got to come up with
like a metaphor here.
Movement watches start at just
$95 at a department store.
You're looking at four to 500
bucks and that's why people steal.
No more shoplifting or boosting
whatever your people call it.
Movement figured out.
Yeah,
that by selling online,
they were able to cut out the
middleman and retail markup,
providing the best possible experience.
Over 1 million watches
sold in over 160 countries.
Get 15% off today with free shipping
and free returns by going to movement
watches.com that's m v m t.com/burr.
This watch has a really clean design.
Seriously,
I've been getting compliments
and not just on my eyes.
They're talking about the watch. Now
is the time to step up. You Watch game.
Go to mvmt.com/burr join
the movement and lastly,
but certainly not leastly,
stamps.com the cornerstone
of this podcast.
Oh advertisement.
Avoid the hassle man of the post office
and mail everything from postcards to
envelope to packages,
domestic or international.
Create your stamps account in just minutes
online with no equipment to lease and
no longterm commitments.
Click print mail and you're done.
Unlike the post office
stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for letters or
packages at your convenience.
24 seven a keyword slash. Descriptors.
I guess I'm supposed to say this.
It's convenient. It's easy, it's
reliable, it's flexible. All right,
just like you side piece there.
Sorry. I use stamps.com because,
uh, I always, whenever I sell
posters at the end of my show,
when I want them to go out there
and shake sweaty hands, you know,
and I need to send out my posters.
I use stamps.com and I'm a moron if I can
figure it out. So can you in right now,
you too can enjoy the stamps.com service
with a special offer that includes a
four week trial plus postage and a digital
scale without longterm commitments.
Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbirdthatstamps.com
and to
bear
one
more
time. Hey stamps.com never
go to the post office again.
All right, that's it. Okay.
Stomach is growling here.
I'm still on my fucking
diet. Oh, Billy died.
Some fucking asshole sent
me a tweet going like,
you are obsessed with your fucking weight.
You look fine. Get help. It's like, dude,
that's why I look fine. You fucking moron.
You don't give a shit. You potato skins,
eating fat. Fuck these guys
with your thick fucking torsos.
You know what I mean?
Making that noise when you
reached back to get the seatbelt,
trying to pull it around
you running out of material.
I don't want to be that guy.
You know what I mean?
That guy who gets killed by his airbag
because his fat face is too close to the,
the miniature explosion. Um, anyways,
all things comedy festival by the
way, podcast festival, October 26th,
27th, 28th, 29th in Phoenix.
Ticket links@bird.com.
By the way,
I am going to do my first ever live Monday
morning podcast there at the standup
live, um, comedy club.
I'm going to do it live.
I'll do it live and I'm going to do
it just how I do it my fucking house.
All right. I thought about getting
a guest and I was like, fuck that.
That's not the Cham of what it is
that I do, so I'm just going to do it.
I Dunno what I'll lay down on the stage.
I don't know what the
fuck I'm going to do,
but I'm going to do it the exact way I do.
So if you ever wanted to see this
shit life, this absolute train wreck,
if you wanted to see what it looked
like in real time, come on down to uh,
the stand up live comedy club in Phoenix,
Arizona. October 28th. I will be there.
I don't know when tickets go on sale.
They aren't, I guess they're on sales now.
Their own ticket links for it. Bill
bird.com. There you go. All right. Um,
anyways, let's talk some NFL football.
Went back, got bad. Boonoo Beatty.
Did you guys enjoy it? Did your team. When
my team won the New England patriots,
who everybody said was going to go
undefeated and then we lost to the Kansas
city chiefs and then everybody said,
oh, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I think Tom Brady is old now.
I think he's washed up.
I think the Kansas City chiefs are going
to win their first Superbowl since 1970
that's what everybody said,
because the Kansas City chiefs beat
the New England patriots in September.
Now all of a sudden they can see
January. How fucking crazy is that? Um,
how many fucking times?
How many times are you going to watch
the giants go into when Owen three and
just start writing them off. You
saw all the points they scored. Huh?
You think they're not going
to come back and beat Philly?
They're not going to come back and
be Dallas later on this fucking year.
When they all get on the same page.
They were protecting Eli much better
according to the 30 seconds of highlights
that I saw. I'm sticking by my
prediction. New England patriots,
New York giants, Superbowl
rematch. All right.
Until the Kansas City chiefs who I
actually like until Andy Reid, who,
I'm not saying he's fat until those
fuckers do something in January.
All right. I think all you
need to sit down a little bit.
If fucking relax with all your shit talk
and how many fucking guys have you seen
throw for 500 yards in the regular
season and get bounced out and the first
round of the playoffs,
how many times did you see a fucking
guy zigzagging all over the field?
You can't tackle them
and come playoff time.
He sitting on a fucking exercise
bike wearing a tinted windshield.
Crossed his eyes.
Huh?
The incredible lack of fucking respect
that you gave our little quarterback that
could Tom Brady. How
dare you? How dare you?
Right off the New England patriots
after one fucking week. Huh?
It's all wishful thinking.
What common again,
and we're going to take your hearts out
and we're going to pull them out of your
chest.
We're going to show him to you and then
we're going to under inflate them honor
away to another fucking, actually,
we never got caught doing that.
They just suggested that we did it
and they got laughed out of court. Um,
and then do what I really need to address.
Um,
these stupid controversy of the fucking
people taking a knee during the national
anthem. You know, watching all these white
people getting fucking upset by that.
Like it really does.
It really affect your fucking life and
all these fucking idiots trying to make
the point of what they're doing.
It's not about your point.
The people who started this thing,
it's about my point.
It's about the way that I see it. You
know, I had a buddy of mine go, yeah,
these fucking guys are making $1 million.
You know, he'd take his bad here.
Why don't you go fucking move to Syria?
It's like, why do they have to move?
Why can't they just live here the way
you do? I don't understand that dumb,
but Donald Trump is a fucking genius.
Daddy has everybody talking about
this issue because he is trying to get
everybody to stop focusing on the pool
party he had with fucking Vladimir.
What's his face over there in Russia? He
doesn't want you watching that. He goes,
oh, look at this over here. Right?
He goes down to Alabama and he gets
all them fuck and paypal all riled up,
and he keeps talking about this
fatty over and fucking North Korea.
That's what he's still one. It reminds
me of when, oh, fucking slick Willie,
you know,
bombed that country because he stuck his
cigar and that woman's Nether region,
this is the type of sick people that
become president. This is what they do.
All right?
They get caught doing some fucked up shit.
And then I will say this about Trump
least they didn't go bomb. Some people,
unlike what's his face
with his bitch hands,
who now gets treated like a fucking hero.
I don't understand that guy at all.
You know what I mean? Ah Ha. Oh,
that's great. Oh, I got caught.
Get my Dick sucked on the overall office.
So I bombed a country.
I'm out of killed the baby, but
I sleep lock one every night. Um,
I know I'm a conspiracy theorist.
I fucking hate them all.
You just see that thing. Uh,
what's his face and fucking, uh,
Korea considered that we declared
war on them, right? So, uh,
uh, Maggie Magen Hall, whatever
fucking name is, uh, Maggie Gyllenhaal,
what is it?
What is the fucking,
the poor woman who has to go out and
fucking give the press conferences now
because that dude with no neck,
you know,
who kind of looks like the
political version of Roger
Goodell went out there and
fucked it all up. The hell's her name?
She's got a classic political name.
I don't know what the hell it is.
She said the fact that North Korea
thinks that we're at war with them is
absolutely preposterous or something
like that. And then like a week before,
what's his face?
Trump basically tweeted like that,
that fatty over there
wasn't long for this earth.
And it's like you kinda just
said he's not gonna last,
he's not going to be around long.
That's what he said. Yeah. I mean,
I would take that as a threat. We'll
have a dash for his habit. Daesh,
um,
you know what they really need to do?
They both need to just go to a whorehouse
together and fucking grow up, you know,
Bang, a couple of whores they
need to do a threesome, right?
One of them is getting blown the others
hitting it doggy style and just their
eyes meet and they just start laughing
being like, this is a great life. Right?
You've got a personal chef to yeah, it's
fucking amazing. You live in a castle,
live in a White House. I mean, it's fun.
It's cool. They should just talk about,
you know, trade stories, the way
comedians trade stories about bombing.
They could just talk about fucking bomb
and other countries and I dunno what
fishing, whatever, whatever people
at that level talk about. All right,
let's get to the questions for this week.
So I don't have any fucking problem. Uh,
with these,
these guys taking a knee,
I try to listen to what it's about rather
than getting wrapped up in what, uh,
what, what it means to me. Um, uh,
pharmacists writing in
dear Billy bag chaser.
I don't know what that means. Um,
by the way, people 39 days sober,
39 fucking days. And this is, this is
how well I'm doing with my sobriety. I,
when I flew to Canada, I went by
this duty free and there's this, uh,
Macallan rare cask. They got this new
one black oak or some shit like that.
And I was like, I'm
going to buy that. Okay,
I'm not going to take it to fucking
Canada then suck it down like a fucking
jackass. I'm just going to have this thing
waiting for me. You know what I mean?
For whenever I fall off the wagon.
So this is like what I was thinking
the whole ride in and like, you know,
I'm getting off the plane,
I'm trying to beat the crowd to get over
to the taxi line cause I don't fucking
Uber, I never remember to set up a car.
So I always go to the fucking taxi line.
And what's great at lax is,
is never anybody there because
nobody fucking takes a taxi.
Everybody's got a friend to pick him up.
Um, I don't know what the fuck they do.
There's always plenty of cabs,
so I don't even try to be
first in line at the cap stand.
I go out of my way over to this duty free
place and I grabbed this fucking thing,
you know,
and I like
bring it up to the counter and the lady
goes, Oh my God. She goes, fucking, uh,
what a wonderful choice and
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
You have great tastes like I am. I
go, I'm on the wagon when I come off,
this is the bottle I'm opening
up. She goes, are you going
to Canada? I said, Nope,
I'm going home. And she goes, yeah,
Oh, I'm sorry I can't sell you this.
And I'm like, why not? She goes,
you have to be going to Kansas, some of
the about the duty free. And I'm like,
it's, it's legal though. Do they sell
this anywhere else in the airport?
If you just going back right
to your home? They're
like, no, no, we don't.
So I dunno.
So I had a fucking hissy fit.
I had a fucking hissy fit
hi to hissy fits. One of the way
they're going through Canadian customs.
When they made me take the delined green
plastic cover off of my fucking laptop,
like I somehow had a bomb in there
or some sort of bomb residue and I'm
literally taking it off going, I'm
going to crack this thing. And they go,
well just try to take it off easily.
Okay.
It's just like when you look, I love
it. Like fucking howdy duty. What? What?
I'm in this matrix.
I like what's going on?
Tell me what you want me to do the fuck.
So they make me take that fucking
thing off. Ended up cracking the cover.
Some are in a bad mood.
So rather than, you know,
growing up and realizing that
these fucking people at that,
what is it that to Tca TCP, whatever, fuck
it took a tea, what is it called? Tsa.
Tsa.
The fucking Tsa.
Rather than just realizing these
people are trying to protect me,
which I don't think that trying to do.
I think they're trying to make it
as inconvenient as fucking possible.
So I'll agree to have my fucking retina
scan so they can share that fucking
information and gradually
build a fucking robot.
Sorry, put this fucking
headphones back. Um,
yeah,
so all I wanted was a bottle of booze.
That's all I wanted and they wouldn't sell
it to me. They wouldn't sell it to me.
So I went online and off. I'll figure
out a fucking place to get it. All right,
let's, let's do the
little right in here. Um,
pharmacist writing in a
dear Billy bag chaser.
Your rant on pharmacists last week
was hilarious. We have to be able,
able to laugh at ourselves.
Right.
I just wanted to weigh in on
a couple of things. First off,
the medication you were prescribed,
the antiinflammatory drug you received
was in the nonsteroidal antiinflammatory
drug class. How to fuck. Do you
know you didn't even look at it?
Maybe you've just be, Ya know, I can tell
just by the way he's talking about it,
I understand.
Basically these drugs
decrease the formation of
prostaglandins and thromboxane
named those chemicals are involved
in the inflammation process,
which itself causes pain.
So these drugs cannot just decrease
inflammation without also decreasing pain.
That's being labeled a
painkiller. Oh, okay.
Yeah.
End Saids are not in the opioid family.
Okay.
Are Not happy habit forming. I don't
know what this guy's talking about,
but it sounds like he's blowing my
argument out of the water. However,
they can be very dangerous in susceptible.
Okay.
Populations. Why can't you
say with addicts, society,
the bull populations, you guys are
such fucking creeps in that world.
And Sade's n s a I. D. S.
Yeah.
And ceds increased the
risk of cardiac events,
kidney damage and stomach ulcers.
I'm sorry, recovered addicts. Uh,
usually in the elderly or those
with preexisting conditions.
I'm not sure what the
other drug you receive was.
If it was a narcotic opioid painkiller
and the doctrine pharmacist did not
discuss it with you, they would be now
negligible on their parts since when?
Since when? I want to
know now that the, uh,
the fucking heroin epidemic is completely
out of control in the state of Ohio is
suing pharmaceutical companies.
I guarantee I graduated four years
ago and the dangers of narcotics was
extremely stressed.
Now all the medical bodies are
communicating the dangers of narcotics to
practitioners and overseeing that
prescribing is done appropriately.
And maybe this is just the fucking,
okay.
It's just how we are. You
know, like when we first,
they first had that DDT and they sprayed
it all over the place and this is like
great. We just end it all these plagues
and then we did all this damage to the
environment.
We created this fucking window that is
starting to close I feel where it was
this golden age of not having to walk
around with a fucking boil on your face
and dying of the black plague.
And um,
okay.
We just got a little
out of control with it,
which would have been great is if as
we eradicated all of these different
diseases,
if we somehow didn't grow the population,
I feel like that's the sweet spot.
I feel like that's what the
fuck [inaudible] Illuminati
should be discussing is
like what is the optimal number of people,
including ourselves of course,
who should be allowed to survive while
we keep all the modern day technologies.
So we can still live this awesome
flat screen life with no plagues.
Okay.
But like we also can still sustain
like living on this fucking planet.
What is thing?
What is,
what does that number and they're not
taking college cause they're a fucking
close to entity. All right, let
me read a few more of these.
How much time are we up to at this point?
We're at 18 minutes.
18 minutes plus 37 is 55.
Okay. All right, so here we go.
Gold money.com day or Billy copper nuts.
Uh,
I heard you talk about gold money.com
on your pot Monday morning podcast,
wherever emailed you about it.
Didn't explain it very well.
I feel like all these are just
like free commercials. Um,
I haven't put any money into it yet,
but now I'm going to speak
about it as an authority. Uh,
but I am considering it
as it seems pretty legit.
If you listened to Rogan's
podcast with Peter Schiff,
he explains it pretty well
and makes a good pitch. Yeah.
But that guide stands to profit off it
granted shift admits that he invested
money in the company. Yeah.
So he's out. He's out.
I want an independent fucking data.
I can even find that anymore.
Evidently they sell you the
gold at a low market price,
half of 1%,
I think.
What do you mean ha?
Half of 1% of what?
That's just sort of a number
floating out there, right. Uh,
stored for you in a vault of your
choosing with your name on it.
And if you want it, they will actually
mail your goal to you for free.
Minimum of them have like
five grams or something.
You also get a mastercard debit card
that you can use to spend your gold slash
money.
Evidently you can use,
you can even get a debit card
that is made of real gold,
which sounds fucking baller. The
Federal Reserve and powers that may be,
may never let it work, but it seems
like a great idea. At least. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Yeah, there's
a bunch of great ideas. Yeah,
I'm all set on that. Hey,
you give me your cash and uh,
we'll put it in gold in
a vault that you choose.
That's not where you can say it. Um,
all right. Dating and Saudi Arabia.
Now mate, maybe. I Dunno, I, it
sounds like a, even if their,
their mind is in the right place,
it's going to go belly up and then
they're all gonna write themselves bonus
checks off your gold.
That's what I would guess what happened.
Or the Federal Reserve will come in and
say this is all illegal and take all the
gold and then act like it's in Fort Knox
when it's really fucking, uh, I dunno.
I Dunno what the fuck it is.
Somewhere in the Hamptons. All right.
Dating and Saudi Arabia. Hey there,
Billy pie. Billy the pie maker.
Hope you're having a great day.
Anyways,
I wanted your advice on this problematic
shit that I'm stuck in. I met this
lady
through a common friend of ours.
Oh God. We talk, this is nuts.
It's going to get messy when you break
up with her and you're going to lose her
Anna Front. Uh, we talked,
she's really cool person and we've
got a lot of things in common.
Then we met again twice as a friend
and now I want to ask her out.
But here's the thing,
she is a Gypson and I'm Indian
and we live in Saudi Arabia.
Rabia and dating is illegal here.
Well then what the fuck did
you go out with their four?
Now your heart's going to get cause you
to get your fucking, what did they do?
Have their beat your feet in the square.
You're going to fucking slap your
dick around in public or something.
Whatever the punishment is over there.
I made the authority could
deport you immediately or worse,
send you to jail for years.
Now,
I really liked this girl
more than your freedom.
All right? Now I really liked this girl
and like, you're not even love this girl.
And I've already thought of of names
for our kids before she even said yes to
me.
But I'm really stuck on
thinking through my brain.
Okay,
this is second language here.
I'm gonna try to help this out
here from really stuck here,
which she should I think through my
brain and through my Dick. Uh, should, I
will do none of that is your heart.
So you should just leave.
Should I ask her out and open for a
whole nother level of problems or so they
just shut the fuck up. Any advice
from, he was highly appreciated.
Love the podcast and love you
as a brother. Go Fuck Yourself.
There's not a woman or a man out there
worth going to fucking prison in Saudi
Arabia.
I know a bad the prisons are of here.
I don't know what they like over there.
You guys got a lot of oil money.
Although I did run into this guy from
Saudi Arabian who is laughing his ass off
and he goes, dude, we don't, we don't all
have oil money. Now's a sec. All right,
fair enough. There's oil men over here. I
don't have any of that money. Yeah, do it.
I would walk away from the shit. It's
fucking illegal. You could go to jail.
You get deported. You know what I
mean? And even if you love somebody,
they're going to annoy the
shit out of yourself. I mean,
is that worth going to jail for? You know,
I mean, is it illegal to just banger,
but then if you love her, I
dunno. I Dunno. I, I would,
I would get out of that.
Uh, I get out of it. All right.
All right. Great movie scene,
unknown actor. All right. Oh
yeah. I was talking about,
uh, this is the, uh,
this is a new topic here where I was
talking about actors that you saw just to
like five lines in a fucking movie and
they absolutely destroyed it and you and
your friends still quote them.
You don't even know their fucking names.
I brought it that guy last week,
the guy from pulp, a reservoir dogs,
the guy in,
you know when Tim Roth's character is a,
what is he? He's in the fucking bathroom
and that cop's telling that story.
I said, buddy, I am going
to shoot you in the face.
You don't put your fucking hands. And that
dashboard, love that guy. So he, he goes,
one of my favorite scenes with an unknown
actor was kill bill to bill's brother
Bud. I wish I need to see these
movies to do this justice. I mean,
I saw this but I don't remember it.
Um, she, she wore the same outfit,
that fucking yellow outfit,
both movies than she bill's brother Bud
is working as a bouncer at a rundown
strip club. He shows up late for work,
gets called into his boss's office.
His boss,
Larry Gomez is played by actor Larry
Bishop and he looks like half a wolf man
after doing a line of blow with
the haggard looking stripper.
I vaguely remember this. He levels
his gaze at buzz and bud and says,
uh,
I don't know what car wash you worked
before you came here that let you stroll
in 20 minutes late.
But it wasn't owned by view of what,
it wasn't owned by me and
I own a fucking car wash.
I just butchered that line.
People I can't really,
I realized that I needed glasses
and I have slight dyslexia. Um,
like I was trying to write squawk
today and I knew all the letters.
I just could not remember cause I was
trying to remember what squawking 7,700
versus 7,500.
I always get those two mixed up.
If that's an emergency landing
or a fucking hijacking,
I was cause one stay alive and
the other is fucking go to heaven.
Um, all right. Sorry. That's how
you remember it. 75 stay alive.
77 go to heaven. All
right. 75 is hijacking.
77 is emergency and 76 Nita fixed
meets you fucking radios out.
This doesn't mean anything to you guys.
Um,
I don't know what car wash you worked
before you came here that let you stroll
in 20 minutes late, but it wasn't owned
by me and I own a fucking car wash day.
You Go. That was a good fucking read.
That makes me want to go see that movie.
He said he then proceeded to give this
worldclass assassin a humiliating dress
down,
telling him he's as useless as an asshole
on his elbow and crossing off all his
scheduled work days on the calendar.
He finishes by telling him
never to wear his cowboy,
had to work and has cleaned
a clog toilet on his way out.
All Bud can do is stand there and take it.
I hope you've seen this great movie.
If not, it's worth the watch.
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself.
I'm going to go watch it again.
All right.
I think I'm a think this bit is going
to make people go see these cool movies
again and it's also going to make
everybody laugh at how bad I can't fucking
read out loud. All right bill. My favorite
line in a comedy ever might be from,
from
blazing saddles delivered by slim pickins.
He rides into the scene where
his workers are singing,
uh, camp. Is it Camptown races? I was,
I was camp Camptown races and says what
in the wide wide world of sport is going
on here.
I hired two people to try to get,
I had you people to try to
get a little track late,
not to jump around like a bunch of Kansas
City faggots. I remember that line.
Whatever the hell that means.
And I'm quoting a movie by the way,
before everybody gets all fucking
uptight about the, uh, you know,
Richard Pryor road on that.
And he was actually supposed to be the
leading it and then they went with the,
the other actor and I don't know
any of the actress names. Okay.
Three number three,
Bill,
you asked for movie lines said by a non
movie star actress that your listeners
friends talked about from my group of
friends. It's aligned from Ghostbusters.
When Peter Venkman,
uh,
Bill Murray shows up to Dana's w weaver
apartment right after the dog monster
runs loose from Louis.
Tell you I've never seen that movie.
I've never seen Ghostbusters.
Just not a Scifi guy.
Vanke is that considered vanquish shows
up to this scene and asks a cop what
happened. And the cop
nonchalantly replies, uh,
some more on brought a cougar
to a party and it went buzzer.
Yeah.
My friends and I have been
quoting that cop for years.
Check it out at two 30 of the following.
Oh, I can, I can look at these. Fuck,
I can click on the links.
This is even better.
Why have me read it when I can
click on the links. All right.
We'll compare my read.
I get around.
It was 120 to three k is
the mold off the board
when you were a slave, you
sang live, Bert. Come on.
How bad our good old nigger work song.
Jesus Christ. What the fuck?
Kind of lucky is sending me here.
I thought that was going to
go to your fucking oh boy.
Oh boy. Am I going to have to
have an apology video here?
What the fuck just happened? Oh it,
let's do I do this other one. This one.
How are you doing?
Why didn't you have some of the free,
it's at room temperature if you
think it's too warm in here.
All right.
Fuck. All these things he thinks are
going to be too long and evidently they,
they have the n word in them. Yeah. Boy,
do I need to take a knee after this one?
All right.
Number four.
I have two unknown and unheralded
actors with memorable movie lines.
Both are the Great Mel Brooks movies.
Uh,
the first one is the Roman soldier in
the history of the world, part one,
the emphasis is approaching, but
the, there's a horse and a carriage.
And the way the Roman soldier looks
directly at the camera and says,
move that miserable piece of shit. Uh,
the over the top way delivers the line,
comes out of nowhere. I say
it all the time and the, uh,
and the best impression I could,
do you know what I gotta do?
I have to get the actual clips for this
to work because what I'm now doing is
ruining. I'm ruining great movies. All
right. Girlfriend believes in ghosts.
Uh, all right. Girlfriend believes
in ghosts dear grandmaster be,
I met this lady a few weeks ago.
Things went really good.
She's very cool.
I found her good looking and we
have a lot of stuff to talk about.
I didn't have a great a lot of, I didn't
have a lot of relationships in the past.
I'm 32 and I picked up my
game about four years ago.
Everything was great until we went to a
restaurant one day and she told me she
believes in ghosts,
not just that she said she actually sees
them and even God patients who come to
her for treatment about it. I tried
to be open minded about it. Oh my God,
I can just hear the silverware
hitting the plates at this point,
trying to compare it to
people who believe in God,
but her believing in this keeps bugging
me. I'm not saying she's crazy or wrong.
Who am I to know? But she doesn't
sit right the way I see the world.
Well then fucking dropper.
This is the thing.
Now this is whole fucking
straight across the board.
You have to look at everything like
all the leaves are brown and the sky is
gray. Like if you're dating and somebody
does something and it makes you buddy,
you just body literally go like, what
the fuck? And then you're literally,
you're going to fight that feeling and go,
well,
maybe I need to stop being so
ghost of phobic. It's like, no,
it's fucking ghost. It's
weird. You know you,
you're going to fucking live with
Whoopi Goldberg's character from ghosts.
That's what you're gonna do.
People trying to sit on her and shit
trying to sit on your [inaudible].
That's what you're going to sign up
for me if that's what you're into.
By all means do it, but if you're
on a date and that there's like,
that's a major fucking thing because
it's not like she just believes in and
every once in a while she's going to hear
a thump in the house and start telling
you it's a ghost. When you're like, honey,
it's fucking air in the pipes. All right,
we just have to fucking turn
on the faucet. You know?
Remember if the plumber did work today
and they shut it off for a second,
that that's what that is. You
know, that's not that she actually,
she's going to become like a ghost
hunter and all of that stuff and uh,
gradually she's going to get,
start dressing more and more like she
can predict the future and you don't want
to fuck that.
You know what I mean?
When they start wearing those long
flowing things, you know, just,
you just so many layers of clothes to
try to pick up to just get it going.
You know, you start wearing like curtains
and shit. You don't need that anyways.
All right. I'm sorry. That whole
fucking movie thing, just, I dunno.
Can you guys just send me the Goddamn
clip or I guess you sent me the clip.
What I should've done was cue it up.
I tried to do too many things.
I tried to promote shit.
I tried to do all that and then do the
whole thing and the whole fucking thing
just fell apart. All right. Let me
just finish with this last thing. Uh,
a buddy of mine is opening a fucking,
uh,
a new comedy club on the upper west
side in Manhattan. Okay. Friday,
October six and October 7th.
It's like a little 100 seat fucking club.
I'm going to be coming to the town in
November and I'm going to pop in and do a
spot. I love little clubs like that.
Uh, let's see here. Uh, Russman.
Money's going to be there. Greer Barnes,
Mark Norman, John Fisch, rod small,
Brian Scott McFadden. Uh, and many more.
It's going to be a great show. Uh,
if you're on the upper east side,
upper west side,
sorry,
it's on a two oh one west 75th streets
right next to the beacon theater,
which is also cool.
You know what I mean?
You go in there and you fucking do your
spots and you come out and you go, wow.
Someday I'll be across the street.
It's tremendous. Give it a shot.
If you're in town, uh, Friday, October
six and October 7th, I got the hiccups.
That's the podcast. Please check out.
Philippe espouses a standup special.
Um,
what's it called?
Translate this September 30th on Hbo.
10:00 PM it feels more like indigestion.
I have any meeting today. All right.
Go fuck yourselves.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.