Hey,
what's going on is bill burn?
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday. What is it?
August 28th, 2017 what's
going on out? Why?
What's up? Sorry. It was obnoxious.
I understand. I understand,
but I got to make the lady shut
it off first, right? Oh my God.
Who is this guy yelling?
Why would you want to listen to that and
when you could just see when you could
just sit and watch reality
television with myself.
Let's do a bunch of broads fucking
yelling at each other. It's unreal.
It's unreal. My wife Watches that shit
all the time. All the fucking time.
You come home and it's just like,
it's like they live with us.
You know what I mean? Me and my wife,
we get a, we get along great, you know,
but you wouldn't know it. Walking up
the fucking front walk to the house.
You hear like five women's
screaming at each other. You know?
It's just like, Whoa, how are we hosting
the Jerry Springer show? What's going on?
And you open the door and she's
watching the real housewives of a,
who gives a fuck the real
housewives of Trenton,
the real housewives of Dayton,
Ohio. Wherever the hell they are,
wherever they are, whatever city
they're in, the real housewives,
they got fake tits.
They got big ass fucking,
they got ass injection lips.
They got the fucking botox
jumble it. No matter where they are.
Real housewives, grand rapids. He's like,
there's not going to be some
Hollywood shit guy. And there it is.
Why is everybody walking around acting
like there is some aging actress?
You know what I mean? And they somehow
they have to look good for what the,
what the fuck are you looking?
If you ever 50 year old mom,
okay,
just be your mom. Relax. It's over.
You landed a guy, he knocked job.
All the laws are in your favor.
For God's sakes.
Go have a fucking piece of
pie and go smoke a camel.
I don't understand what the fuck these
fucking spaghetti strapped women,
you know the the stupidest still wearing
the tank tops. You know what I mean?
Okay.
Jesus Christ with the fucking tired
skin show. And what are you doing?
Trying to compete with your data.
What are you doing?
Okay,
good. Lola, take take a page out of my
book. Just fucking just given to it.
Here's starts falling out.
Fucking shaving.
Your legs are too white.
Put some pants on.
Okay.
You fucking guts getting to big
start wearing sport coats on stage.
These are the, this, this,
that's the classy way.
That's the classy way to just gracefully,
you know,
go from being young NT.
You're middle aged and to just be an old,
this what you do. Then you get an old man
hat, right? You start pottering around,
you make funny little jokes.
Everybody. Lao, we look at them,
look at that guy still making jokes.
That's what you do.
Yeah.
You don't get chemical shot and
your fucking face, you know,
and enhance your fucking tits. Like
what? What are you trying to do?
You're trying to give some
60 year old a hard on.
I don't understand what these
women are doing and it was funny,
I didn't even want to talk
about this shit. I just,
I don't know why that just came
out. It just did. All right.
I had a wonderful show last night,
a wonderful show.
I was at the Cape Cod melody,
Melody Tent, if I can say it,
which is a such a special place for me
to do stand up because the one and only
time I ever saw it,
the Great George Carlin live was that
the cape cod melody tent and I am
embarrassed to say I saw him in 1988
and me and this other guy went to go see
them to laugh at him because my buddy
had me convinced that he had stopped
writing and that he was
still doing 20 year old bits.
So we were going to go see him as a joke.
If you complicit, how fucking stupid.
I was one of the most prolific
comedians of all fucking time.
So we show up to laugh at this guy
and within two seconds we were,
we were just on the fucking floor
laughing and the guy hit his brand new 90
fucking minutes and we
were driving home like he,
he wasn't doing more stuff. He wasn't
doing fucking like, that's how dumb I was.
Um,
I did a lot of dumb shit back then.
I went to some comedy shows and I was
literally the person in the crowd I wasn't
hackle in or anything,
you know what I mean?
Although one time I did Haeckel Don
Rickles just cause I wanted to have an
interaction with them and I knew that
I wasn't going to meet him. You know,
I saw him at a casino about four years ago
and um,
I waited till his encore and it came out
in the encore and he was just doing his
jokes, doing his jokes and I was way in
the back. He's playing this giant room.
I was waiting in the back and I just
went, hey, it didn't say anything.
He kept doing his jokes,
kept doing it as jokes.
I waited like another three minutes and
I went dark and he just looked out to
where I was sitting. He goes, yeah, I know
my name made that fucking Rickles face.
And I was with Bart, nick and
he fucking elbow. He goes,
he heard you, he heard you.
And that was it.
You know,
I broke a major rule of engagement there
with fucking as a standup comedian.
I shouldn't have done it, but I couldn't
help myself. I couldn't help myself.
You know what? Let's be honest.
Why don't we just be honest? Okay.
Now that that's stupid,
fucking fight is over.
Can we all just be honest with
ourselves here? I'm a selfish person
in rather than accepting the fact that I
wasn't going to get an interaction with
them, I had to do that because
I'm a selfish cunt. Okay. And, uh,
you know, now can we all be honest
about what went on Saturday night?
I gotta be honest with you.
I have not even seen highlights of it.
I didn't fucking watch it. I
actually came home and, uh,
I was staying with some relatives here
in Boston who also didn't get the fight,
cause they're saying people feel
like, yeah, it's just, you know,
he's Floyd's gonna carry him for a couple
of rounds that he's going to finish
them and then they both, you know,
they're not going to really each other up.
They're both going to leave
with a buttload of money.
Isn't that what's going on here?
Yeah.
Isn't there some Guy Alvarez who's
actually a fucking modern day champion or
some shit like that coming up anyway,
we'll spend the money on that.
We'll spend the money on that fucking
thing. Whatever that boxing match.
I don't know shit about boxing,
but I do know lousy auto versus
Mohammed Ali when I fucking see it.
So I mean a better version of it,
I should say. But anyways, um,
okay.
We actually watched a wicked tuna.
I have such mixed emotions when I
watched those fishing shows, you know,
I got this love of animals,
but I also love tuna. You know,
I am of an environmentalist
who loves crab, you know,
King Crab. Who the fuck doesn't love
that? I mean, that's just fucking,
it's tremendous.
So when they,
they're sitting and talking about how
it's all fished out and they can't find
any and that type of stuff, you know,
it's not that we should stop crabbing.
They should just be less fucking people
that they have to find it for, you know,
so,
um,
you know,
I dunno, I always have all these
fucking ideas of how to, you know,
okay,
trim down the population. And of course
I'm never part of the problem. Right.
As us as most mass murdering maniacs,
you're never part of
the problem like Hitler.
I'm sure when he looked in the window,
the window looked in the mirror,
right and was brushing his fucking teeth.
Right.
I'm sure that he saw a blonde
haired blue eyed person
instead of seeing what he truly was,
which was the runt of the litter.
You know what I mean?
But the guy had heart,
any fucking overcame what
the fuck he looked like to
achieve his dream. You know,
granted he was out of his fucking mind,
but I mean,
that alone should have just see, should
have been, if he wasn't so crazy,
it would have been, well, look at me.
I'm fucking ugly as Shit
and look what I've achieved.
You know
what, if somebody who looks like
me actually had a good heart,
imagine what they would achieve. Isn't
that what we'll have fucking Luna ticket.
Well, how was y'all fucking
loaded ticket? Is that okay?
Okay.
They're like,
you know,
my dream came true and I played the
Cape Cod melody tent telling jokes.
His dream came true and fucking, you
know, tens of millions of people died.
That was literally his dream.
You know,
like imagine if he never did his shit
right and he just lived a regular life and
then all of a sudden God for why
came say God forbid it's him.
I just naturally say, God forbid when I
talk about terminal disease, Adolf Hitler,
right? Doesn't fucking, you know, somebody
bought his paintings or some shit, right?
So he just doesn't go down that
fucking road. Now he's just, you know,
some regular guy and a,
and then he has like,
he gets some terminal illness and for
some reason make a wishes back then and
they'd go, what is your drink?
What is your wish? And then he's,
and then he g rarely you're going to
make my wish true. This is what we do.
Eight off. We make sure you
die with a smile on your face.
What is your dream? And he
would have led the, you know,
telling the guy to come a little
bit closer. What do you want to do?
I want to exterminate all of the Jews.
That's what he would've sent.
I want a fucking quagmire that
make a wish would've been,
they would've had to have, they
would have to, hey, hang on a second.
They'd have to step out in the hall
going, I, what do we do here? I mean, uh,
you know, we, we, we,
we just kind of made a broad statement
that we make dreams come true. We,
we didn't clarify it. Like, what do you
want me to stand out here long enough?
Maybe he'll fucking die of the disease. I
mean, our are, reputation's on the line,
right? And then all of a sudden
make a wish gets dragged into it,
gets dragged into the madness of this man
and then no longer looked upon as this
wonderful organization that they are,
right.
Which takes in millions and
millions of dollars, right?
And God knows what the fuck they do.
Who knows?
You never know what those charities,
right?
Are they helping people out?
Are they helping themselves to a
classic Camaro with some t types?
When we return, we'll be
taken some college. Sorry,
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking
about today. Um, so anyways, yeah,
everybody thought I was going to cave.
I have not caved on two fronts.
I have not drank in 11 days and I
feel this is it dude. I go 11 days.
I could go a year,
I could go a fucking year.
I feel fucking fantastic.
And I just used the word fantastic.
I never is fantastic. You know, I'm
doing cardio like I've always been doing,
but I'm not negating it at night with
the fucking three or four home pours over
there with the giant ice cube.
Um,
and it's actually, the sober life is
fucking great. It just sucks at night.
It's the only thing at night.
It's sucks at night, you know,
because it's like, what the fuck
do I do? Um, I'm like, yeah,
like I'm a habit guy,
so this is the time of night.
I fucking do this and then I'm not doing
it. I'm like, well, now what do I do?
What do I do? So you know what I did? I
started playing guitar again. Anything,
you know, I suck. What do you want?
I mean, it just, I go in there,
I fucking play a little bit,
and during that time then it gets late
and then I literally feel my body just
going to come on and do
it. Go Paul, go there.
It's right over there and look at
the bottom to look at the bottle.
It's right there just by
yourself. One. And I just,
all I have to do is just go
downstairs to my bedroom.
And then the fact that I'm an old
man takes over. Like, God, dude,
I am not fucking going all the way back
up there. He's in. I'm like, he's it.
Even as I'm laying there,
you know,
I go downstairs and my angel of a wife
is laying in bed watching five women.
She doesn't know, screaming at each
other and say horrible things. You know,
they're really big on attacking like a,
if a woman's never had a child,
they're really big on attacking
that file, man. That fucking mean.
Just God damn fucking main people,
you know,
it's dumb. These guys are the way we
solve shit with violence. I just think,
you know,
just punching somebody in the
face is way more civil than say,
well that's why you're bearing and
you can't have a child. It's like,
really? Do me a favor next time. Just
punched me in the nose when that just be,
can we just,
can we just leave it at that?
So there's something to salvage
afterwards. Jesus Christ, um,
20 but now that I've gone 11
days, now it's, it's, it's
just starts to fade. Like,
I don't even know. I walked by
my, my fucking, I told you 19,
27 Yankees lineup worth of fucking
booze and I'm telling you like,
I don't even see it anymore.
Yeah.
Like, you know, I don't, I don't, I don't,
I get murderer's row murderer's row,
the shit that I drink.
Um, you know, and then they're all, I have
the batting order. You know what I mean?
Top of the order,
right through cleanup is the
top of the shelf top shelf shit.
You know that Shit pappies
I say,
okay, here we go. Let's go with
booze. So what would you align up? B?
Who's hitting lead off?
Who's getting on base? Right?
Who's your fucking Rickey Henderson?
That's gonna fucking possibly hit a solo
shot and the next guys don't even have
to knock them in. You know what
I'm going to say? I'm going to go.
Okay.
My Rickey Henderson is
Johnnie Walker blue.
Okay.
Oh, this is going to be hard. I
got too many cleanup hitters. Dan.
I would say baton second is grant patrol.
All right.
I'm not a big Tequila guy,
so I'm not getting into that fucking a
Gavi shit. Where the fuck they put in it?
Yeah, Dan. I would say,
uh, this is a hard one.
I would say maybe some pappy
van winkles is going third.
Then bat and up in my world,
I would say is a McCallum rare cask.
Right now we're getting to
the middle of the order.
This is a,
you know,
it's not a special occasion. I just
want to get fucked up. All right.
These are the guys hitting to 70 to
80 then you get in the middle already.
You got Johnny Walker Black is baton fifth
I'd say no. Fifth is patroned
silver. Johnnie Walker black.
Yeah,
his bat and six baton.
Seventh, eighth and ninth.
Now you're talking companies coming over.
You like these people, but they don't,
they don't like appreciate good boots.
So you just got to hit him
with some basic shit, right?
That's when you have to go maker's mark.
Jack Daniels
batting ninth
batting ninth. If someone wants to mix
it, I'll give you, this is the fuck this.
This is the national league. When
the pitcher bads. Johnnie Walker.
Red Label.
There you go. That's my guy. You know
what? Send me in your booze lineups
probably should have had a you.
I could do the bear one
lead off Scott to be Budweiser. You know
that? Thanks. Getting on fucking base,
right?
Batten's second.
I would have a Miller
high life baton third.
No, no. Let me see. I'm going to be a
fucked, I got the lead off cores light.
No, but we put doing best beer all the way
down. Not On, oh, what am I doing here?
What am I doing here?
All right.
Okay.
I am. I am. I am white trash
when it comes to beer. Okay.
The fanciest, I mean Alco, I would say
our Eggo Budweiser,
then Miller
highlife.
Then I'd say a third baton third and beer.
Yeah,
that's a tough one. You start wanting
to people clear the basis a little bit.
I'll go a little snobby
and I will say Blue Moon.
I don't mind the orange slice. I
don't mind it like I, if I want,
if I'm just fucking thirsty, I'll have
one of those bat and cleanup is Guinness.
All right.
Then I'd have a black and Tan and fifth.
Six. Now you just get it. Now
you want to get fucked up, right?
But you don't want to get your
fucking going to become a fat fuck.
So I would say cores, light, light, beer.
Famila now eight.
Nine.
Okay.
Eight and nine. This is
four when some, you know,
some older people are coming over with
their kids and you just get a fun,
I dunno, for whatever fucking
reason, you got to have an IPA.
And when I was others, like a
Sierra Nevada or some shit, I would,
something like that. I
don't drink, but I mean,
okay,
I'd leave that alone. This isn't,
this is stupid. It's congress.
I'm literally fucking sober and I'm
making booze. Batting lineups. All right.
If you're a beer drinker or if
you're a hard liquor, you know,
I want to hear your lineups.
Okay, let's get ready, man.
Up The fucking pennant races
are heating up. All right.
I want to, I want to see
what you line up. Sorry.
You come walking up to the bar with you,
a little pulling your mate,
you fucking lineup card out
of your back pocket. Um,
okay.
By the way, that Blue Moon eyes is signed
to like a one year contract. You know,
you don't,
you just pick up a fucking big bat at the
end of the fucking season and like, he,
you know, he's not, he's not a
true red sock. Um, all right.
So anyways, by the way,
somebody tweeted at me,
that's stupid company out there and
fucking Wisconsin microchipping they're
fucking employees and these fucking
idiots are doing it. And you know,
and I'm like,
why would they do that?
And then all you have to do is look
at their faces and you look at them,
they, I have this childlike
innocence. They are believers.
That's all it is.
They grew up in a great state of Wisconsin
where you're sheltered. All right.
You're in the Midwest,
you're in the hat or the country that
fed fucking weasel and North Korea,
his missiles, even if it makes it that
far, he's not shooting it at Wisconsin.
Right.
The Green Bay packers did
they like owned by the fans?
It's fucking everybody's making cheese.
It's Mayberry. You ever been to Wisconsin?
It's fucking tremendous.
The air is fresh.
The water is fucking clean.
At least it looks that way.
When I drive by at 80 miles an hour and
a way to some God forsaken fucking place,
I'm going to perform it
right.
It's tremendous. Fuck
these people, they believe,
well,
I,
they all ordered the fight.
Okay.
They think he's gonna make it great again.
They Jace, they believe. You know why?
Because they're fucking
good people out there.
So they walk into the workday, hey
guys, this is the new thing, and they,
and they sit there, look at
GI. Don't know. This seems
a little bit creepy, right?
But how did they get them and how do you,
how do you get the general masses?
How do you get them all right?
There's two ways to get the general
masses fear and free tee shirts.
Yeah.
One or the other.
You scared the shit out of them.
They're fucking onboard.
You tell him the boogie
man under their bed,
whatever the fuck you tell them they
need to do, they got to fucking do it.
If you don't want to fucking waste your
time coming up some fucking boogeyman
story, just make a free fucking tee shirt.
And that's what they did in Wisconsin.
They had these fucking tee
shirts that said, I got chipped.
That was it. That was, that was
the tipping point. Wait a minute.
If I put that foreign object in
me that I have no idea what it is,
no idea what it's capabilities are.
No idea what it really does other
than what you tell me you evil cunt,
you'll give me that free tee shirt and
you know, they got to be extra soft once.
Oh my God, dude, my, I tell
you right now, my favorite,
my favorite go to t shirt is my,
I got chipped.
It's so soft,
you know?
Then as much as I'm making fun of them,
I see the writing on the wall
because there's way more people.
There's way more believers out there, you
know, believing in the invisible lines,
believing in the teams believe
in and all that fucking bullshit,
right?
Believing that they're evil,
but these people are saints or vice
versa, right? These people are either,
they do it,
they do it all over the world.
Okay?
God loves us, Baz. These people are
infidels. These people are fucking days.
These people are fucking that.
It's the thing is the common thread
with human beings is that this fucking
lunatics at the top.
Okay,
okay. And then you have nice people at
the bottom, you know, Wisconsin people,
people give the shirt off
your fucking back, you know,
provided you not to 10 let's,
let's not,
let's not overly romanticize these
white people. At the end of the day,
they are wiping, okay? And I'm
not shitting on my own people,
but just in a position, it's a
society and we were, you know,
nobody's watching us so we get
to go full fucking, you know,
full fucking frontal nudity with
their fucking brains. There's nobody,
there's nobody in our way, right? That's
why we go is where we go fucking crazy.
You need some sort of hand on,
maybe that's what the microchip is for.
I have no idea. I just know at the
end of the fucking trail, who is it?
Think of some of the people that run shit.
Look at Bill Clinton.
The man could not keep his dick in
his pants. He shoving cigars up,
women's vaginas half his fucking age.
That fucking guy that,
that's one of the guys run shit or someone
of his fucking ill keep you gonna let
that guy put a fucking microchip. What
do I get? A free shirt? Yes. Shit,
don't skippy. I write,
I'm in. And that's it.
And this is the thing they don't need.
They don't need thinking people to buy in.
All they need is the free tee shirt
people and the free t shirt people.
You get enough of them,
it becomes a tipping point and
then they can start changing.
You know what I mean? It's like the
toll booths, right? Everybody easy pass.
I'm not getting that. You're not gonna
fucking track where I'm going. All right.
And that was just one easy pass lane.
10 fucking lanes where you
throw your change in her
fucking went to a guy, right?
And then it became eight,
seven, six, five, four, three,
two, one. Go Fuck Yourself.
Well, you don't have to, you can
use the fucking surface roads.
You don't have to use the highways,
but your taxes did pay for them.
Then you like, fuck. That's what
happens. And they'll get all of us.
Do you know what?
Okay.
You know what I love about life though?
They can never stop you from
drinking yourself to death.
Okay?
And that's one to grow on. All right.
With that, let's, uh, I'm sorry.
They've got really fucking dark.
Um,
all right. What are we doing
here? Uh, live reads. Okay.
I'm reading off my phone here because I
have no internet where I'm at right now.
I'm gonna have to go drive down to
a fucking coffee shop. You know,
there's nothing in a coffee shop that I
want other than their internet. You know,
I don't drink coffee.
You're your little pastries.
Are they like eating a fucking bathroom
tile? They're always fucking up.
They just suck.
Everything in Starbucks fucking sucks.
I don't, I don't have the coffee.
I know the coffees that heroin.
All right,
but you have to go into a bodega
that's really selling fucking drugs.
You know what I mean? You know, like
oldest cereal is, that's what that's like.
What fucking
like a Starbucks is?
It's like a drug deal in Bodega.
Okay.
Do you know what I mean? And
like the only thing that, that,
that is good in there that is,
that is not passed,
it's fucking date of freshness is
the fucking drugs at this selling.
And what Starbucks. It's the coffee.
Everything else in this sucks.
That's why you've got to
love Dunkin donuts, you know?
Okay.
The copy of a dental needs out of this
fucking world, but they also make,
they make these quite done. It's
all right. Draftkings everybody
okay?
A fantasy for all shit.
Draftkings is back.
I love these guys because they finally
admitted what the fuck they were doing.
All right. All right. She fucking
degenerate. Gamblers. Hey, you go,
you're in a loveless marriage.
Let's add to the pain draft kings fantasy
football season is almost here and
there's no better way to get closer
to the game you love than to put your
fucking paycheck on it.
With draft kings one week fantasy
football draft kings is hosting a $100,000
contest that is totally free to enter.
All you have to do is put your
paycheck down and if, yeah,
and if you don't draft the perfect lineup,
you can what?
And if you drafted the perfect lineup,
you can win $1 billion.
Okay?
All right. I was making fun of this.
Now I think I'm in with draft kings.
There are many ways to play.
Choose between public contest with big
cash prizes or private contests where you
can compete against a
group of your friends.
Draftkings also has a beginner and casual
contests where you play against people
of a similar skill level.
That's like when the drug
dealer gives you a free taste.
The best part is you get to draft a new
team each week without any commitment.
So to get draftkings.com now and use a,
so get draftkings.com now and use promo
code bur bur to play and draft king free
week one contest with the
$100,000 in total prizes.
And if these guys are brilliant,
and if you don't,
if you draft the perfect lineup,
you can win $1 billion.
I don't know what the perfect lineup is.
Use My promo code bird to
play for free and week one.
That's Promo Code [inaudible]
at draftkings.com eligibility
restrictions apply.
See draft kings.com for details.
I love that they're back in the ring.
I want us,
I want to see that movie get made.
Okay.
How they came about,
how quickly they grew,
and now quickly at the state and federal
level, they're like, wait a minute,
this is a national dry eye gambling ring
and we're not getting any fucking money
out of this.
How many beaks did you have to
fucking wet to get back into the game?
Yeah.
Geez. I bet they went to one of
those. Bilderberg makes all right.
He like started a, he looks
at me with Alex. I don't know
what the fuck this is. A,
you're your unique. Oh, you're
a special person, aren't you?
You don't walk like everyone else.
Talk like everyone else. Sure.
Chat or anything that anyone
else has sleep like anyone else.
So why the fuck is your mattress?
One size fits all?
I don't know. Cause there's a
basic shape to everybody. Um,
because a truly customized mattress
will cost you five to 10,000 bucks. Oh,
there's the answer right
there. Until now, go to helix,
sleep.com and answer a few simple
questions and they'll run a three d
biomechanical model of your body through
their proprietary algorithms they
developed with the help of the world's
leading irrigant comics that biomechanics
experts, Jesus Christ. What
a sentence. The result,
the most comfortable mattress
you've ever slept on.
Helix customers report a 30% improvement
in overall sleep quality and for
couples, they customize each
side of the mattress. I, yes,
the beginning of the
end of the relationship,
you're a mattress arrives at your door in
about a week and shipping is 100% free.
I like buying to be like this.
Yeah, I like it to be like that.
I'd rather fuck this guy. I don't give
a shit. I'm already paying in her.
He likes sleep.
That's why everyone from Gq magazine to
Forbes are all talking about headaches.
Sleep. You have 100 nights to try
it out and if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free,
gross and give you a 100% refund.
No questions asked to be funny. If they
asked you what was the problem? Well,
I mean sleeping was okay,
but when I went to Bang my wife,
I kept getting this pain in my left knee.
Yeah, you know, I played sports, but I,
you know, I never had
pain in that one. Look,
my fucking knee hurts when I banged my
wife. I don't have to tell you. All right,
I'll sign there. All right, go to hell.
[inaudible] sleep.com/burr
and get $50 off your order.
That's helix sleep.com/burr. Hey, hell,
it's sleek.com/burr h.
E. L. I. X. O. Jesus. Look who's back
movement watches. Everyone hang in there.
I got two more here. Movement watches.
You guys know movement, right?
They reinvented the watch business
by selling directly to you.
With over 1 million watches
sold to date. Well, goddammit,
these bastards did it again except
this time with sunglasses, right?
You thought they were done with watches.
Now they're going to keep going.
They just shove one right across
the bow of every designer.
Fucking sunglass boat out there.
They were tired of having to pay.
They were tired of having to pay for
cheaply made throwaway shades are
overpriced designer glasses. So they said,
fuck it. They actually wrote, screw it.
They said fuck it. You know, that's
what they said in the meeting.
We'll make our own starting at just 70
bucks movement sunglasses start at just
$70 with the option to
upgrade to polarized
with over. What the fuck
does that mean? Polarized.
You stop agreeing with people
the second length you fucking,
he's a polarizing character. Um,
those overpriced designer brands will,
will run you upwards of 200 bucks.
Movement figured out by selling online.
They were able to cut out the middleman
and retail markup providing the best
possible prices. They figured this
out with watches. They like, hey,
why not do it with John? Glad
did, I hope they keep going.
We've done it again. We've cut out
the middle man with fucking Dildos,
uh, where they are. High quality premium.
Okay.
I don't know how to say it's a c e t.
A T a state.
Okay.
Acetate.
He Tate's frames.
No cheap plastic here.
You're got to see these.
They have a lot of styles to
choose from. Classy, trendy,
round aviator mirrored polarized.
Okay.
You know, if I had the Internet, I've
looked that up. Polarized sunglasses.
What the fuck does that mean? You
wear him down in Antarctica, uh,
for him and for her. Uh, you're
sure to find the perfect pair of,
get 15% off today with free shipping
and free returns by going to
movement.com/burr,
you know,
Movement for how they've
revolutionized the watch industry.
Now's the time to check
out this sunglasses.
Go to M v M t.com/burr join the movement.
All right, last one. Oh God,
why is this copy so long?
Just get to the fucking point.
Wink,
W I N C for some reason pronounced wink.
Uh,
when you have a great glass of wine,
it enhances the moment whether
you're reflecting on, I, you know,
if I had to make a wine lineup,
okay,
this is what it would be.
Who's leading off you got to
get lead off with a cat eye
man. You fucking, uh, bottom of the order.
I don't know who the fuck all I know is
a Barolos battened cleanup for me and I
don't give a fuck about anything
else about why. You know what I mean?
I take on the whole wine world, but
just the two of those nice fucking cab.
But I want to get shit face Barolo if I
don't know if I did something that day.
All right? Uh, when you have a great
glass of wine, it enhances the moment.
Whether you're reflecting on the
day or with someone you love.
Wink understands this.
It's why they started their company.
I mean how many times we have to tell
you this is why they fucking did it.
To give you access to exceptional wines
from around the world so you can have
more of these moments. See I need to
use it. What if I wasn't on the wagon?
I do say shit cause I,
cause if you can't put together a nine
fucking bottle list of booze bear or why,
yeah,
I guess liquor I should say then,
then you know,
okay,
you're really doing your liver a
disservice. Just try winc.com t r y,
W,
I n c.com take a brief palate profile
quiz and somehow that'll end up on
somebody's microchip in their
fucking hand in Wisconsin and Winkle.
Recommend distinct and interesting wines
actually customized to your pallet to
be shipped directly to your door every
month. None of your time is what?
You'd be funny if he committed a murder
years later and you left the fucking
wine glass and they went back
to this information. Well,
it says here that that wine
glass was part of your profile.
Is that not true?
Yeah,
it's part of your palate.
Then you get all nervous.
She just confessed to it on the stand.
Right? Like they could sit 1950s cop show.
They were tired of having to pay
for cheaply. Made throwaway wait,
that's the shades were like,
what did I do here?
Or none of your time is wasted fitting
in a run to the store or your way home
from work or your way to
an event or a gathering.
No more time spent guessing what you
might like because wink basis the wines
they send you on your taste preferences,
wink.
We'll even introduce you to new rare
custom wines that are not available
anywhere else and tell you the story
behind each one. No membership fees.
Skip any month.
Cancel anytime and Winc
has a 100% satisfaction
guaranteed so you never pay for
a bottle you don't like and right now
Winc is offering listeners $20 off your
first order. When you go to go to
try winc.com/bird that's try Winc,
spelled t, r, y,
W I n c.com/bar they get
$20 off your first order.
Now try winc.com/barb there you go.
Oh, thank God it's fucking over.
Thank God it's fucking over.
Not Jesus Christ.
You don't. One thing I do like about
tech technology, I like docusign.
I really enjoy that shit makes it nice and
fucking easy. Oh, by the way, I have to,
I have to hide this gig
because they don't do a lot of,
they don't do a lot of standup
at this venue. Now at this point,
if you listen to the podcast for a while,
now you realize that you know as much
as old freckles goes on stage telling
jokes, he's actually a
frustrated musician. You know,
I wish I was good at guitar,
was show as good at trumps.
I have a tremendous amount
of respect for musicians.
Speaking of which Queens of the Stone Age,
one of my favorite bands of all time
put out their brand new album this week.
I'm going to be listening to it and
I'll give you my own review of it on
Thursday. Just kidding. I
fucking hate when people do that.
That comes supposed to listen to
you. Who the fuck are you? You know,
fucking listen to you. I'll listen
to it myself and make up my own mind.
How about that? How about that? All there
youtube person, youtube person. Anyways,
I'm going to be a November 2nd.
I'm going to be in clear lake,
Iowa at the surf ballroom.
Now the surf ballroom is the,
that's the last place buddy Holly,
the big Bopper, Ritchie Valens.
All of those guys played.
Waylon Jennings was there that night and
he went on the bus and everything. Um,
just being a music fan, I dunno if
it's slightly morbid to play there,
but I'm going to play
there and I'm flying in.
I'm landing at the fucking airport. They
took off from every everyday a killer.
Angie fucking nervous.
They crashed because there was
no de sync technology back then.
They had too much weight on their wings,
which changed the shape of the air foil.
They were overweight.
They could fucking produce enough lift.
They crashed and they die.
That's not going to happen in 2017 so I'm
going to be there. Won't happen to me.
It won't happen to you. If you want
to check out this legendary venue, uh,
November 2nd clear lake,
Iowa surf ballroom.
I'm going to be there with Dean del Rey
who was actually born the same day that
they all died. Not the same year, but
the same day. So it's going to be,
there's going to be tremendously
freaky fucking night. Um,
I got a brand new hour and last night I,
I it could not have gone better and
I left out half of my fucking jokes.
I was having so much fun, uh,
down at the Cape Cod Melody Tent.
So please get you tickets to
November 2nd clear lake, Iowa,
the surf ballroom and I will be tweeting
out and Facebooking out a link because
I am an old man. I'm not on Photoshop,
I'm not on Instagram. It's not Photoshop.
What's the other one is Instagram. And
then there's the other one. Snapchat.
I need to get on those, right? Is
that what I need to do a, by the way,
I'm thinking of putting
together a college tour,
a tour of colleges in the
beginning of next year, um,
to help promote F is for family
and bringing a bunch of swag to,
uh, you know, free merchandise
free f is for family merchandise.
This is what I want to do by get
enough interest from certain schools,
especially the University of Kansas,
when the Jay Hawks have
a home basketball game.
So I can go to that legendary arena.
That would be tremendous.
Do you understand what I'm saying here?
I was actually thinking of doing that
once a year, right in every like,
you know, college fucking,
um, division. You know,
like one year I'll do a big 10 fucking f
is for family tour. I'll do an SCC one,
I'll do a pack 12, whatever the fuck
they're called now. Um, the whack,
right. Do something
like that. I don't know.
I'm always thinking of fucking
idea like that shit, but uh,
just to help promote it and um,
may cause that's my fucking job.
I got to sell the goddamn shoving. They'll
get mad at me. All right. All right,
37 minutes in. Here we go. Here
we go. All right, let's uh,
let's read some of your questions here
for this week. I'm up up, up, up, up, up,
up a bone. The nineties.
Dear Billy temple pilot,
I'm feeling a bit nostalgic for the 90s.
I was 12 and 1990.
I'm 10 years older than you.
You have bested and had no
stress or responsibilities.
I get how that influences this,
but it was a good time.
I'm happy with technology
now in our society. Is more
conscious of social issues,
but everything is so loud now.
Do you ever get into style
check for the 90s if so,
what part of the nineties can you have
your podcast guy use the friends theme
song for the Thursday podcast?
That's a question mark there or anything.
Awesome from the 90s uh, thanks
for reading this. If you do,
life is pretty boring these days
and if I could you use something?
Yeah,
to brighten my day as a pet store manager.
All right sir.
Here's what's happening to you is you're
slipping into your life and you don't
like what's going on. So rather than
fixing the, now you're going back in time,
that's not, I mean that's,
that's a temporary fix. Okay.
If you don't want to manage a pet store,
asked yourself what you really want to
do and start slowly walking towards that,
taking a half a step,
a quarter step every day in one point
you're going to look up and God damn it,
there it is.
Just like Indiana Jones and then you
grab it and all of a sudden a giant ball
starts rolling FDA and you got to fucking
run out of there and that's you after
you make it, then trying
to stay there. All right.
But that's way more exciting than
managing this pet store that, you know,
you're saying brighten your
day as a pet store manager.
You one of these guys who
actually doesn't like animals.
You probably don't like the people.
Right? Coming in there, whatever.
I don't know what it is but it's,
but I will answer your question.
My favorite part of the 90s
was the month before nevermind came
out and I was listening to the skid row
slave to the grind and I thought hair
metal and all night when the hair metal,
but metal was never going to end because
that was what you love was the end of
my youth because I was 22 in 1990 so
that was the end of the end of it for me.
So like think about 2000 for you.
You're getting out of college,
all this new music is coming out. You're
starting to not be able to, you know,
the next few years,
you can't keep up with it.
What the fuck are they listening to?
And then that's what happens.
And then you start driving around it.
But I'm not going to lie to you do the
shit that I say. I still listened to 'em
okay.
You know, I try to listen to newer shit
like you know, it's a new band to me,
like Cold War kids and I'm
like guy, I saw them, you know,
recently they were on TV, I'll download
some of this stuff. And I'm like,
oh I remember that song.
Okay
that fucking ball. Bam
My pant, that Song Ben
fucking soon. The guys singing way,
the really high voice, amazing voice.
And um,
I was looking at dance like that fucking
album came out 2006 or something.
So I'm way behind the curve but
uh, I try to stay up on, all right,
you want to hear something embarrassing?
I'm going to fucking tell you all
my latest, my latest downloads.
I downloaded dream weaver by Gary Wright,
that album tremendously,
tremendously fucking uh,
underrated album.
All right.
Cause everybody thinks of a,
they think of that song,
we'll, we'll, we'll dream weaver.
Right? And everybody laughs at
that song, you know, they use it.
And these ironic history hipster
fucking ways. I gotta tell you, man,
that fucking album is the shit.
And um, this stuff is some
poppy shit on that. But, um,
all these years of me talking about
loving to play drums and all this stuff,
why did nobody tell me about Andy Newmark?
Jesus Christ.
That guy's one of the best fucking
drummers I've ever heard he plays on this
album. And uh, you know,
you don't have to get it for fucking
dream weaver or any of that shit.
Like a love is alive.
The longest time I thought that
sounded like Clapton to me.
Singing or maybe like one of
those, uh, Steve Winwood bands.
MMM.
Just listen to how tasty
the fucking drums are.
And I'll actually post a video this week
of him fucking playing with like Rod
Stewart and these guys just fucking
Waylon. All right. So he downloaded that.
Then I downloaded Cold War kids,
Robertson cowards.
I'm downloading the new
queens of the stone age today.
And then here's, oh Jesus,
by his in defense of me,
I lost a lot of my music when I dropped
my last phone into the toilet. Um,
it was actually in my back pocket
and I stood up from taking,
taking a dump, right? No, no I didn't.
I didn't, I was fucking hammered.
I remember this guy was saying there
was something about standing up when you
take a Piss, some fucking health reasons.
So I sat down like a lady, right?
And I had my phone in my back pocket
when I stood up at fucking fell into the
toilet. Fucking brutal. Like I
was going to go get that. Nah,
it ain't happen. And so I don't
use the cloud and everything.
Just I lost everything. So I downloaded
ACDC. If you want blood, you got it.
Live ACDC for those about to rock a c
d c high voltage than I had to get my
vintage Aerosmith and there I
downloaded get your wings, rocks,
toys in the attic.
Then I downloaded the new fucking mute
math while I'm on weight and I'm still
waiting for the rest of that album.
Come out to play dead.
I downloaded Glen Campbell rhinestone
cowboy cause I've been singing that with
the advertising LACOE Rad stone ball bag.
Uh,
Peter Frampton, Frampton
comes alive. All js,
all j a this is all yours.
Marvin gay sexual healing download.
What a fucking tremendous song that is.
The new royal blood album.
MMM
Anthony Hamilton.
Then I downloaded like three prints
albums not to have them sign of the times
and then a dirty mind.
The first sound garden album,
the prince album for you.
Then Dave Brubeck live at Carnegie Hall,
then a bunch of miles Davis. That's what
I've done in the last couple of months.
Stamen with miles working with miles
round about midnight, relaxing with miles,
cooking with miles.
And there you go.
That's what the fuck I've
been downloading. What
else do I get here, Wayne?
Shorter.
Okay.
The idiot king. Attention
deficits. I think that's it.
Oh, that's what's his face? Tim Alexander
on drums on that. The brown album.
Bad Motor finger. Temple of the dog. Oh,
that was right when
I'm Chris Cornell died.
I had to get all that fucking music
back on my phone. John Coltrane,
Sonny Rollins, Tesla skid, they go,
Marilyn Manson, prime primers, primers,
animals should not act like people.
Pork, Soda and sailing the seas. Cheese.
You're not Derosa just sent
me a new fucking, they're new.
Their latest fucking track. It's
the shit. I absolutely loved it.
Primus has a new one coming out with
the fuck is it called? Let me see here.
Where is it? Where is it? Where is it?
In my phone. In my phone and my phone.
All right. What do I have
him underneath? You know,
everybody says Joe has no shoulders.
That's not true.
He lacks the meat that is between
your neck and your shoulders.
Basically his trip. He's, he's, he
was born without it. Um, all right.
Prime is the seven. Check
that out this week. All right.
Enough with his old man telling
you the music that he likes.
Let's get back to your young people
questions here, shall we? So, um, yeah,
when grunge came in, I got
up. I didn't like the first,
like when Pearl jam first came
out and Nirvana first came out,
I didn't like those bands because they
knocked all my bands off the top 10.
You know, I was like, this isn't a
good band. What about Brittany Fox?
What about winger? A man. What about
warrant? Um, and yeah, I listened.
I didn't necessarily buy all those albums,
but I didn't think any of that
was bad music. I was young,
I didn't fucking know any
better, you know, lease.
Those guys could fucking play under these
cons today with a fucking laptop and a
God damn Christmas tree in their head.
Um,
so it took me a long time to admit that
nirvana pearl jam were great bands,
but like Soundgarden and fucking Allison
chains had like fucking that anger in
there. Um, and just the
sound of the lead singers,
man, I just, I really liked
their front men and uh,
okay.
Now of course, you know, I love Pearl
Jam. I love Nirvana and all that shit,
but I was a bit of a baby when their
music came out. I was, I was too young.
This is the first time I was seeing my
music go away so I wasn't mature enough
to be like, you know what, you know,
I have to accept that, uh, you know,
my time has come and gone and that this
is what the fucking music is now and I
should listen to him. It took me a good
20 years to be able to do that. All right.
Hey there, Billy Clinton. Uh, did
you, did you hear that she had,
the court ruled that the head of the
Democratic National Convention Debit
Wasserman,
that's her name.
Dib B I t Sholtz rig the
primaries against Bernie Sanders.
The court what court.
So this woman under the influence of
Hillary Clinton's camp tampered in the u s
election process,
but none of the Democrats are celebrity.
Do rights are going to be outraged
because there's sanctimonious ass hats.
And for the record, I was a registered
Democrat and stop fucking saying that.
If it's a fact, it's a
fact. I don't need to know.
I used to be or this or I
actually voted for Obama.
I don't give a fuck what you did.
If what you're saying is factual,
I don't need to know what the fuck he did.
I was a registered Democrat
until about 2010 by Blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. With the exception of
Bush and Gerald Ford. Uh, anyways,
the hypocrisy is just so insane
to me to not be mad at this,
especially as a democrat. I think you
have to have clinical issues. Yeah. Well,
I heard like Bernie Sanders was drawn
a bunch of people and they just didn't
even cover it. All right. Now where
does this coming from? This is the, uh,
the observer.com.
Okay.
June,
2016,
a class action suit was filed against
the Democratic National Committee and the
former Democratic national, uh, was Debbie
Debbie Wasserman Schultz for violating,
uh,
the DNC charter by rigging the Democratic
presidential primaries for Hillary
Clinton against Bernie Sanders.
How hilarious would be this big?
It's actually doubly sad if this is true.
Even former Senate minority leader
Harry Reid admitted in July,
2016 I knew everybody knew
that this was not a fair deal.
He added that Debbie Wasserman Schultz
should have resigned much sooner than she
did.
The lawsuit was filed to
push the Democratic National
Convention to admit their
wrongdoing and provide Bernie Sanders
supporters who supported him financially
millions of dollars in
campaign contributions with
restitution for being cheated
on August 25th, 2017 federal judge
Williams shy is this all true,
dismissed the lawsuit after several
months of litigation during which the
Democratic national conventions attorneys
argued that the DNC would be with,
well within their rights to rig primaries
and select their own candidates.
That was their argument.
So they weren't denying it.
And evaluating plaintiff's claims that
this, you know what I'm going to do?
I'm going to send this to Jimmy door
and I want him to cause he, you know,
I'm too stupid to be able
to debunk this or say that.
It's actually fucking trope.
I want to know.
I want to know what love is.
Yeah,
I mean, this wouldn't surprise
me. You know what I mean?
I would actually love if this got some
fucking attention just to truly shut up
all these fucking dopes in Hollywood. You
don't, you know, back in the day. Yeah.
I mean, I guess I, I mean I think
that, I mean it was getting, no,
I'm not trying to be the spokesperson
for fucking Wesson oil or whatever the
fuck people are trying to do out there,
but like,
I try to like evenly trash everybody
and I'm totally into conspiracy theory.
Like none of this is shocking to me.
You know?
I just, I just think we're just inherently
flawed and I base that on myself
as I fucking, you know, I as
like just fuck up all the time,
which is what, just inherently
flawed people. All right, Jimmy door.
There we go.
This is how dumb I am.
I'm going to send this to him and
I'm just going to text. Is this true?
Okay.
You know, and he loves me
enough to actually reply this.
I know part of him is going to
feel sad that I'm as dumb as I am.
Yeah.
And then I have his phone
number. Um, yeah. I mean,
okay.
None of that surprises me.
I mean it was,
he kind of felt that Bernie was
getting boxed out and I guess maybe the
Democratic National
Committee does have the,
I guess does have the right to do it
the same way the NFL had the right to
suspend Tom Brady, whether he
did anything or not. I mean,
when they took it to court,
they go, yeah, this is bullshit.
You don't have enough fucking
evidence. And they're like, well,
we're a cooperation. Right.
It doesn't cooperate and have
a right, this is planned.
It's employee. Yes, you dealt
well Tom Brady's our employee,
therefore he suspended.
Um,
that's Kinda like what they did
to Bernie Sanders and yes, I did.
Just compare him to Tom Brady.
I think they have a lot in common.
I'm living in a retirement
community at 33 years of age.
What's up freckled ball bag.
Um,
a friend recently turned me onto your
podcast. It's hilarious. Well thank you.
Thank you for preventing me from killing
myself with my one hour commute to work.
Well, that's great. I like
to, I like to do what I can,
although I am into population. Maybe I
should take a control population control.
Maybe we should take a couple
of weeks off. Uh, my wife,
28 and I 33 finally had enough
money to buy our first home to what?
You guys are crushing it. So he purchased
a nice little townhouse in Connecticut.
We didn't know at the time,
but we were moving into a community that
is potentially the evil offspring of a
retirement village and the house of wax.
Oh yeah.
Well that's what happens when you
buy your first house. You so excited.
You don't drive around. You don't know
the questions to ask. Now, you know,
are the people oldest shit around here?
Just out of curiosity,
is this a drug filled the neighborhood?
Okay.
Is there any chemical
fucking shit in the water?
What are the schools like? You know,
all those questions you have to ask.
All right, we are nice,
courteous people. And so we think
or so we think he's a, so don't take
the anger in this email out of context.
Um, well he had a little
perspective that we used to.
If you said we're a nice courtesy people,
courteous people,
but the fact that you actually have
the intelligence to say or so we think
understanding that there is
another perspective in life
other than your own. Uh,
we've helped some of our old ass
neighbors carry shit, you know,
because they can't,
with the osteoporosis and everything,
we wave and chat with them when walking
our dog and we even hold the charity
beer pong tournament in New York City
every year to raise money for ms uh,
unrelated to our community, but
shows we care. Question Mark,
I guess question Mark
Anyhoo enough about us. Uh,
this past weekend we had my brother
and sister in law in town and invited
another couple over on Saturday,
Saturday.
I'm sorry if I blew your eardrums out.
I tried to pull it away enough. Uh,
I don't think I took it
away in time. Sorry. Uh,
we went to hang out at school
at our, at our pool, sorry.
We took a float snacks,
a couple of beers and a speaker.
There were five to seven other people
at the pool, all in their hundreds.
It did not look like the pool
scene from caddy shack. Uh,
we hung out,
chatted symptom beer and listened on
low to Jack Johnson or some other mellow
soft shit.
Monday morning at 10:00 AM the entire
community got this email residents,
it was reported to the board and the
management that over this past weekend
there was some owners and guests
who behaved inappropriately,
loud and shouting conversations,
foul language and may have partaken in
alcoholic beverages prior to or while
visiting the pool.
None of these things are acceptable and
are also violation of the pool rules of
the old fucks court.
Obviously you added that if [inaudible]
if set individuals we're seeing behaving
in such a manner going forward,
the police may be called
and said individuals will
not be permitted to use the
facilities and may also be subject to
a hearing in front of the board whereby
fines may be imposed.
The pool facility is for the peaceful
enjoyment of all residents and we hope to
keep it that way.
Thank you.
Signed the old ass board of directors,
Jesus Christ,
to what the f you didn't realize your
fucking bought a house in a retirement
community says first off,
let me say I've had,
I had nothing against the elderly.
I love my grandparents. It's,
you don't have to stop
establishing credibility.
You bought a fucking house is a bunny
in it and it's like the movie cocoon.
But if you jump in the pool, you're
still fucking old. I get it. Um,
anyways,
I called the once a week.
I enjoy quiet night in the couch with
some scotch or an old fashion and shit.
I still use hotmail.
Yes, we're a part of Hoa.
And then rules above above about
alcohol drinks at the pool.
You can only have two guests
per household. Oh Shit.
We violated the covenant.
But this email from the board is still
absurd, right? No, it's not absurd.
You just didn't do your homework.
You didn't do your homework.
That's what happened.
You didn't do your homework and they just
fucking rip the spread here with that
pen in the back pocket waiting on
my mother's fucking quilt here. Um,
I'm on the fuck am I here? I got to
go back to this year. By the way,
everybody thinks every sound on my podcast
is a fart now cause I hold this thing
to my chest and he's fucking
sound that's made though.
You're fucking ripped ass last
week. Uh, I mean, maybe I did.
I don't think, I mean I don't feel that
I am. Maybe I am. I don't know. Um,
but it's, I'm mean, I mean my house,
you know, I have to Fart. I let it go.
You can't fucking smell
it. Deal with it. Um,
no dude is all on you.
This is just, and he said,
but loud conversations.
What?
Drinking alcoholic beverages prior to
visiting the pool area. You kidding me?
The police may be called
get an f in life to do.
This is their life. This is the end
of their life. And they want quiet.
Okay. Half of them probably
fought and fucking wars.
The last thing I need is you with
your new fangled fucking Elvis' music.
That is Jack Johnson to them.
Yeah,
look at this is the deal.
You guys fucked up.
Okay.
You guys fucked up. All right. And this
is part of buying your first house. Okay.
I bought my first house back in 2011
mmm.
And you know what I was like,
wow is a great old house.
It has a lot of character and you know,
you know what my fucking old people at
the pool was galvanized pipes in the
walls. Cloth wiring, a gas leak flashing.
When I turned on the lights to possibly
ignite the gas underneath my fucking
house, a wood rot, termites,
non permitted fucking building shy,
just you fucking name it.
Put a new roof on it. The Guy fucked
up. He didn't reattach the thing.
The water came through. They blamed me. I
just said fuck it. I paid for it myself.
This is part of it, dude. I'm really
sorry that you're going through this.
I'm sure there's somebody else old
that will buy your fucking house.
MMM.
Other than that, I would just,
you are in a communal area.
I would be quiet when you
go down to the pool, I mean,
I try to look at the bright side.
At least nobody's going to be listening
to loud fucking Benny Goodman music all
the way into the night because old people,
you know,
they fall asleep like nine times a day.
So,
and even if he don't like your neighbor,
they're going to die soon.
There's a lot of positive ways
to look at it and you can also,
you can always sell. So I would make
the best of it. You can always Uber.
I would Uber,
I would go out and go get fucking
hammered and be loud and the young part of
town and then come back.
Just make sure you get some
sort of electric car to
crucially up real quietly to
your fucking front door.
I'm sorry you're going through that.
But what you learned is you have to
fucking check out your neighborhood before
you, uh, you know, you
got to read everything,
you know, so that's the deal. All
right. I hope it works out for you.
All right.
Oh guess who just texts me back?
This is why Jimmy doors to shit cause
I just read shit and Jimmy gets to the
bottom. But this is what Jimmy just sent
me back. Basically. Yes, the judge left,
opened the door for the lawyers to,
to refile in a way that
would be more successful.
The important thing in this case is that
the lawsuit forced the DNC lawyer to
admit in court that they don't have to
run a fair primary and that they can pick
and choose whoever, whoever they
want and can ignore the voters.
Uh, they can ignore the
voters, will if they to do so.
The wiki leaks emails revealed that
the DNC was colluding with the Clinton
campaign and gave her an unfair advantage,
which is why Wasserman Schultz resigned
before the DNC convention last summer.
The judge dismissed the case.
It appears to me based on the fact that
plaintiff did not have stand standing to
sue and the federal court did not
have jurisdiction in this case.
I am interviewing the lawyer
who filed this case today,
so hopefully lots will be cleared up
in that interview. So there you go.
Search Jimmy Dore. Um,
I'll send out a link to,
that's a comedian that's,
that's an informed guide.
Here are that thing was written.
You hear on eloquent. That was,
I actually sounded smart while
rating that. Um, check that out.
Oh Man. Oh my God. Oh my God.
All those women who cried over fucking
Hillary Clinton and she's just as fucking
filthy as this guy. Can you believe this?
Trump. Can you fucking believe this?
Trump.
That's all you hear out in fucking
Hollywood land where I live and it's just
like I want to,
I hope it's true so I can be like,
well what do you think about that?
And watch them completely dismiss it
the same way to go back to Tom Brady.
Well I'll be all right. So He lets a
cons. Hair, what they are out of a ball.
What about when you guys did this and
that the other people root for the law?
That was no fucking big
deal cause our team did it.
I fucking love it. I love it. Oh
Jesus Christ. Do I love it? Okay.
Boss, racist, racist,
racist. Question Mark.
Hey Billy. Booze bag. Ah, Bill. You
know, fun. 11 days motherfucker.
Ah, shut up. I know you're not
drinking. Oh, he got me. Look at that.
I'm any more, it's all I could come
up with. All right. Bill recently,
our company at an event where we give
a tour to possible clients who will
partner with us in the
future during this event,
our boss who was outgoing and funny,
was ironing white sheets and thought
it'd be funny to poke fun at the KKK by
placing a white sheet over his head
and saying, black lives matter.
Uh,
he immediately recognized the situation
and took it off his head and address the
whole company in the next day.
He apologized and made our counselors
available to the company for whatever was
affected and offended Jesus fucking
Christ. You got to go through all of that.
Okay.
I just love these people
that are just so fucking,
I don't know where the fuck they live
that they feel like I can do this and
they're not going to have a problem,
but then everybody's like so fucking hurt.
They need to be counseled.
Why don't you just trying to get
out of your job for a couple hours?
Just walk up to the guy and say,
you're a fucking asshole.
And then if you want the guy fired,
just say that someone's got to
sit there and hold your hand. I'm,
the only problem was that he left out the
black lives mattered part in the first
meeting and simply said,
oh, wait a minute. So when
I would, he's saying, okay,
wait a second.
Yeah.
The only problem was that he left out
the black life lives matter part in the
first meeting and simply said,
he placed the sheet over his head,
which is where the outrage came from.
Yeah.
You know, dude, that's one of the
most important part information,
most important information
in this fucking story.
And you left out some words here.
Okay.
The only problem was that he left out the
black lives mattered part in the first
meeting and simply said,
he plays
the sheet over his head,
which is where we're wdre
worthy outrage came from to,
what am I supposed to do with this?
And the counselor meeting with everyone.
I couldn't help but notice only,
okay,
white middle aged women were
trashing the guy. They were crying,
et cetera.
Okay.
Not One minority in that
room said they were affected.
It pissed me off because it was almost
insulting to minorities watching this.
What if,
yeah,
there was actually a minority who was
actually racially discriminate against and
went to court and wasn't listened to too.
I don't know what you're
talking about right now.
I'm 90% sure these women
were just looking for money.
It's not like our boss tried
to hide or make excuses,
so the white women got offended.
What else?
This is like a fucking beat sheet
for a script that isn't written yet.
What white middle aged
women were trashing the guy,
they were crying,
et cetera.
That fucking sentence ended.
Then he began a new paragraph with that
and then start to talking about the
minority women there. I don't, I don't
know what you're talking about here, sir.
Okay, so, okay, so you're
asking me what, okay,
what am I opinions you think these women
are just looking for an opportunity to
sue sue,
s e w
so for money or do you think they actually
believe these ladies were offended?
Thanks bill. I don't know what you're
talking about here sir. I have no idea.
I have no idea.
I mean I'm I making fun of white women
for acting like they were offended and
crying
cause you think I have no idea.
I don't know what Sir proofread. Okay. I'm
not a good speller either, but you know,
I do know where the spell check is and
I hit the button and it erases all my
impurities. Alright. My fiance
is an into fucking other men.
Okay. He says, I feel are, she said,
I don't know what the fuck this is,
what gender this is.
He said,
I feel like this is a slightly different
yet amusing take on relationship issues
and we'd love to hear your tackle. You
tackle this in a podcast. Basically.
I really like watching my girl.
Fuck other men.
It's not a cuckold thing because I'll
fucker right after and it's always the
best sex we ever had.
Right after
you don't have her shower first sir.
Right after. Okay, thank you know,
I don't judge. Whatever you want to
do, if that's what you guys are in.
My issue is that our sex is already great
and I'm well above average in size and
stamina.
So it's hard for her to find another
guy she's actually interested in,
oh Jesus Christ.
Okay.
Jesus Christ,
you started all the way to the left.
Now we're all the way to the
right. Oh Wow. Yeah. This
guy, this fucking guy here.
You know, I don't mind. I don't
mind her fucking other guys.
I can handle it cause at the
end of the day, my GIC show big.
Nobody can follow me. Um, okay,
now I'm judging the guy.
I don't know why I'm doing this
is just all over the fucking map.
I don't push the issue because
I'm confident in my abilities.
Evidently so confident.
You've got to fucking write an email
about it and don't want her to have a bad
time simply for my pleasure. But I wanted
to know your opinion on the subject.
We have threesomes with other women.
God bless you and I
can't even get into them,
so I can't judge her.
I love her and are amazing.
Sex has been a driving factor
after almost four years. Yet.
There's something about fucking her after
she's been with another man that is so
hot to me,
I can't act accurately explain it and
she just doesn't seem into it because as
she puts it,
I do it better.
This is one of the greatest email. I hope
he, if even if you just made this up,
I would really appreciate your opinion
on this weird kind of relationship where
the issue for me is that I can't get off
because the girl as incredible as she
is,
is too perfect.
Okay.
What,
where the issue for me is that
I can't get off because the girl
as incredible as she is,
is too perfect.
Okay.
So the way her to make her not perfect as
to have you watch her fuck another guy.
Okay.
She got a giant Dick and you enjoy it
and you kind of like want to show like
that is the only way I can look at it.
This is like,
you're like the head like
the best comedian in the
fucking country. All right?
But there's still some level of insecurity
you have that you have to go on on
these,
these shows where the comics aren't at
your level and you have to go on last and
you have to fucking kill harder and kill
longer than anybody else to prove that
you are the best comedian in the
fucking country, if not the world,
if not the fucking universe.
Right?
Yeah.
Is that what it is?
Okay.
Is it the fact that you know, that you
fucking nail it or better than these,
these other fucking guys,
they come out with their average decks
and their little fucking dicks and she's
bored shitless.
Okay.
Do you make the other people watch?
You know what I mean? Like, yeah,
helping out their golf swing.
Okay.
It, Oh, you keep lifting your head.
You've got to fucking keep your head down
as you follow through. Do, I don't know.
I don't have the problems. You have surf.
All right. I am very followup. Will,
um, I have no idea. Um,
I, I do what I, I have
no idea that is like,
I would send that into a can
you please go on Doctor Phil?
Cause I just want to watch him and see
what goes on in his eyes when he listens
to this story where he just goes like,
so
you need to have another man have sex
with your woman where the penile device
that is smaller than yours
in order for you to get off.
Glad Swerte you're saying,
okay. And you know, Doctor Phil's got
some giant x Cop Dick, right? You know,
he's got some fucking huge Hogan.
That's what you do.
That's the end of the episode is you go
in the back and you watch doctor Phil.
Fuck your wife
with the sweat pouring off his fucking
head and you're just sitting there
relaxed and confident. Right? You be
funny. Probably by winning get naked.
He just dropped his pants down.
He'd still have his fucking wing tips on.
MMM. You know what he do to try to beat
you? A, B and inner ear and the fucking,
you know, this dirty talk will be
how much fucking money he's worth.
He want to go to opens
tonight, honey. One good.
Do you want to go to old tonight?
I can make it happen
then. That's what I'm sorry. I know this
is a fucked up podcasts, but I didn't,
I didn't, I wasn't the one that
took it into that area. All right.
Other people did a, that was really
weird. That was a really weird visual.
The whole thing was weird. And
who knew? Who the fuck knew?
Who the fuck knew that this podcast
would start as innocently as it did?
Talking about Hitler getting his make a
wish and what ends so fucked up with a,
whenever the fuck it is. I was just
describing. All right, that's the podcast.
Everybody, um, please, uh,
download the new queens
of the stone age album.
Please buy some tickets to my
show at the surf ball room.
And uh, it was it clear Lake Iowa. It's
going to be a fucking amazing night.
And what else? What else? What else? What
else? I'll post those videos for you.
That's it. And congratulations,
everybody that rented the fight and, uh,
and enjoyed it. I don't want to ruin your
fucking time and, uh, I think that's it.
I'll check it on you
on Thursday. Go. Fuck.
So.