Hey, what's going on? Is Bill Burn?
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday, October 15,
2018 what's going on?
How I yeah,
you hear the echo, echo, echo. I
am in New York City, everybody.
I am, uh, here for the
next two, three days.
I'm doing a bunch of press to promote
my show at Madison Square Garden. No,
November 7th of this same year of
our Lord and the Chinese chicken,
whatever, the fucking Chinese, whatever.
Is it, is it the year of the Monkey?
It was the year I was born. I was
born the year of the monkey. You know,
I find that very offensive. I am not a
monkey. Yeah. Yeah. I'm a dancing monkey.
I was born in the Chinese New
Year of the dancing monkey,
uh,
Shanghai Shit joke. I'm trying to do a
little ration right there. I did my work.
Um, anyways, what's, I've,
could I be having a better sports weekend?
Okay.
I mean, I've got to tell you, if I'll feel
poor, I gotta be pretty fucking happy.
We'll put [inaudible] on the
boob too. Um, you would think,
okay.
You would think that I would be excited
last night that my new England patriots.
Okay.
That I would be excited that they knocked
off the undefeated Kansas city chiefs.
Okay. Now obviously I am happy
that we won the fucking game,
but if somebody is going to sit there
and tell me that that's what a football
game is going to look like in the future.
I don't even know what that
was like watching two people
playing Madden football
in what?
It reminded me of the Superbowl last
year where there was just no defense
and you know who likes shit like that?
People who aren't fans
of the fucking game.
Okay.
I, I just, you know Tyree
kill everybody. How many,
how many fucking times cause he get to,
was he going to catch your fucking ball?
It was like that when Tom Brady goes down,
leads us down like he always
fucking does for the go ahead score.
All right.
Tyreek hill number 10 and you're
fucking playbook and your program
have a fucking accountant who doesn't
watch sports would be like, hey,
you know, I don't want to come off like a
know it all. I barely watched this game,
but I'm going to say you might
want to cover that number 10 guy.
Okay.
Oh,
it comes up to like
fucking the guy goes up untouched,
running across the middle of a fucking
NFL defense on fucking touched.
Tra La la catches the fucking ball.
Okay.
I Dunno, I was in a
sports bar. Was it 60, 70,
80 fucking yards untouched.
Who would've thought,
okay,
that Patrick show time,
my hope was going to go to fucking the
guy he'd been going to who had been
killing you the whole fucking Gig.
I understand that the guy beats you.
I understand that. I guess how
bad, see, I understand that,
but to basically not even cover the guy
devil.
I mean,
I would expect to see some play like that
and central park watching a couple of
Wall Street's psychopaths played fucking
touch football there was pathetic.
It was fucking pathetic. All right. Having
said that. Um, I love Patrick, my homes.
I'm sold on the guy now.
All right.
I don't crown somebody king in September
of their first fucking year as a
starter, but yes. Yes. Fucking amazing.
Just an amazing beast of a fucking player.
Having said that,
I don't know what in the, I don't
know what the fuck is going on. Dude,
that fucking guy in the Kansas city chiefs
where they're trying to suggest that
he had Tom Brady for a and he's like,
Oh,
don't hurt the quarterback,
and then he fucking,
he runs in for a touchdown.
It's just like I,
you know, I understand. I
guess because of the, the, the,
the concussions in the longterm effects.
I guess I have to adjust how I watched
the game and when it comes to quarterback,
who's kitten heel? All right.
Those are the hot chicks. Okay.
They're not paying a cover. They're
not buying a drink. You know,
they're going to be sitting there looking
at their fucking Instagram bored out
of their fucking minds
because they get every day.
That's what a quarterback is going to be.
All right.
Depending on what they're doing for the
league because those are the ones that,
you know, bring in the
money. But that, you know,
I don't know.
It's fun to watch all of that offense.
But like watching that,
watching a guy,
okay.
Sack a quarterback and then unsat camp
because he doesn't want to get in trouble.
And then seeing that same
guy who runs worse than me,
score a touchdown I guess was
fun because I was a patriots fan.
But as a fan of football, I mean, I don't
know, I guess, oh no, I don't want them.
Okay.
I remember a long time ago I watched an
NFL films and this is before, you know.
Okay.
They started overly protecting
quarterbacks and you know,
leading with your shoulder, which I think
is a good, who's good? No. All right.
Not the project overly protecting the
quarterbacks. I don't like that at all.
MMM.
But I remember seeing this
old school football game,
he and he played in the 1950s or forties
and they asked him what you thought
about today's NFL.
And this was like in the 90s,
and he just was talking through his teeth.
He's like a wood look,
she'll football game the day you bugging
you gave you, they give him his fucking,
his head almost exploded steam coming out
of his ears. And I was just going like,
what the fuck is wrong with this guy?
And now that I am old enough
to seeing the game change
as much as it has, I feel like
I'm turning into that guy a pill.
What'd you think about your teen
beat? And the chief says nay. Good.
Are you going to come a Guy Rick Hale?
Like I'm fucking
okay
dude. I was in this sports bar and the
whole game it was just people screaming.
Oh my God. Oh my God. Oh my God.
It was like they were watching an eight
year old tried to land a jumbo jet was
the energy in the fucking room. But
you know, which I guess is great. Oh,
by the way,
epic fucking sports bar guy.
Okay.
I really learned how much
people hate the fucking patriots
with, uh, the fucking
they hatred. This guy had to, he literally
got, he got thrown out of the bar,
like he was fucking Earl weaver.
It was like, I swear to God,
I was like watching a
baseball manager get objected.
He got thrown out of a sports bar,
not for fighting because how much
he was yelling at the fucking TV,
like completely lost.
Yeah,
his composure.
I saw so much of me in this guy,
but it's like I do it in private.
I do it when I'm driving a car or when
I'm at home with my wife, which is why,
you know, she fucking, you
know, it doesn't like me.
Mmm
No,
she likes me,
but I mean I'm tough to live with this
fucking guy was like when the Cino
patriots what went up big,
right, 24 to whatever,
you know, when the chief started
coming back, this guy, like,
he just fucking lost it.
He like the whole night was fucking
hilarious cause I went in there with a
friend of mine and we were uh,
we will meet and another buddy of mine
and uh,
I was texting him going, hey man, we're
almost here. All right, well, you know,
we're pulling up. And he's
like, cool, cool. Right. So I
go in there, I don't see him.
So I'm like, Oh shit, that's
weird. I can't believe I
fucking beat this guy here.
So we grabbed a table when we yeah, but
you know, we got one other guide comments.
We grabbed the four top
and was sitting there
and uh,
the Patriots scored a touchdown and I
just hear this fucking guy just be like,
yeah, that's what I'm
talking about. America,
like just being an idiot. And I'm
like, who the fuck is that jackass?
I look down, it's my buddy that I'm
supposed to be fucking hanging out with.
So me and my friend, we laughed and
get a shit. We go over there certainly.
So we sit down. So that's the first clue
that there was going to be this lunacy.
So at that point we'd gone up like 24 to
like fucking three or six or something
like that. It was like, wow, man. Then
mopping the floor with these guys,
this is crazy. Right? And all of a sudden
the chief start coming back.
It's like 24, 13, 24 twenties.
And this fucking guy down the
end of the bar man. And uh,
he looked like he was older than me,
you know, but at this point, at my age,
I probably was fucking five to seven
years old in this guy. Right. But, um,
but I'm going to Hollywood, so I take
care of myself. I drink plenty of water.
I use lotions.
This fucking guy was agent like
that fucking quint in, uh, in jaws.
Right? So he's down, you know,
when the chief scored this the first time
she's called, he's like, yeah, all right.
You know,
and then when they scored the second time,
he just started yelling like, that's
right. That's right. It's 2018.
This is the new,
this is the new NFL.
It's fucking over for you
and it's over for you.
And he was yelling about the Patriots.
He was so sick of them winning
dude, I'm telling you. And then the
Patriots of course come back and match it.
And you know,
we've got a couple of paths in a Ferris
calls and this fucking guy who's losing
his shit and just getting
madder and madder and it's,
it started off where he would yell about
the play and then yell about it for
three minutes.
And then hs was five minutes set myth
and then he was just yelling at the
fucking TV and he had just
completely lost all composure.
Um, and the Patriots went up by seven
again and they look like they were pulling
away. He missed the whole
end of the fucking game.
I just wish she was like it was getting,
yeah.
You know, the old me would have
engaged with this guy, you know,
cause I was having a couple of pops,
but I was kind of like a, you know,
older and wiser.
You know,
when the chiefs went up by three points
and he was learning, he was screaming,
this is a new rule, blah, blah, blah.
I did one point, one point yelled down,
I went regular season because
he was starting to annoy me.
And then he just completely,
like I said,
he was just yelling
like,
I mean they see the only thing
was missing was this guy.
Like just if they had a home plate on
the bar room floor and he could have just
pushed the dirt all over it.
I mean he,
he completely fucking lost it.
Okay.
And we just got back fucking rapper
reason that fucking Pittsburgh game.
I have some good mother fucker fucking
Porsche, but everybody in here knows it.
He said that everybody in here knows it
and I was just,
I was like,
yeah.
I was just like, is that what I
look like? I asked fucking this guy,
but he took it to a next and like
the next level, you know what I mean?
What you thought, like, you know,
it was like I was fucking
Michael Jordan of losing my shit.
Okay.
You know? And then along
comes Coby Brian like, oh wow.
I thought it was not a good
comparison cause he wasn't better.
Yeah.
I don't know. Dan Marino.
Right. And then everybody,
that's not a good comparison because
Dan Marino would've thrown for 6,000.
I didn't know what happened. Yo,
you're fucking hall of Famer.
You put up all these fucking number, like
no one's ever going to catch this guy.
And then all of a sudden you see yourself
get taught. You're like, wow, man,
records really are meant to be broken.
Even the ones no one wants to break.
So I guess they had been warning the guy.
Okay.
Because it got to the point
where it was kind of like, uh,
he basically turned everybody into the
bar into like his kid and he was the dad
driving the car and everybody was just
sort of be looking around like who dad's
really getting worked up today.
Huh.
And he was with this woman and she was
just smiling, looking at down at the bar.
I mean, she couldn't have been
with them. She would have,
she would have been mortified,
I dunno. Or She's just the biggest
st ever. And she just, what I like,
I like a passionate fellow. So
anyways, the bouncer comes in
and literally just have some on
the shoulders like you have to go.
And he put his jacket on.
He didn't resist on any level,
but he never stopped yelling.
Okay.
And screamed the whole way out of the bar.
It was like,
it was literally like performance art
and,
and everybody in the bar just had like
such, like a funny attitude towards it.
Like, um, there was no, uh,
none of that fucking shit that goes on
today where that triggered me and this is
a safe space. It was none of
that. People were just laughing.
Okay.
Just watching like one of the most epic
fucking frustrated sports fans I've ever
seen. I mean, I actually started, I did,
I just tried to start the slow clap
when he was being escorted out.
You know, I just felt like the guy, he
deserved a round of applause. I haven't,
I don't, I've never seen
anybody like, you know,
back in the day they came up
with something in the 70s.
Okay.
Because people were,
uh,
yeah,
we're,
we're throwing shit at their TVs and
they were breaking them while they were
watching television.
So somebody invented like this thing,
it looked like a brick,
but it was soft and you could throw it,
but you know,
eventually that went away because the
satisfaction is this sound of glass
shattering.
Okay.
You know,
of breaking the thing.
Okay.
That's making you up that either,
you know,
it's not working for you speaking
as a person with a temper. Right.
Okay.
You want to,
you
want, you want the inanimate
object to pay. MMM.
Which is why I remember a
long time ago when this actor,
I'm not going to say his fucking name,
whatever,
but
he was trying to call this quaff and
the fucking phone wasn't working and he
called down to the hotel,
the front desk and they couldn't help him.
Yeah.
Make it work.
So he ripped it out of the wall and
he went downstairs and he threw it.
He threw the phone at the fucking guy.
You know,
the guy got a little cut on his head and
shit. But I gotta be honest with you,
like as much as he
shouldn't have done that,
I can't imagine the release that that
must've been how satisfied he literally
took the thing that wasn't working any
through it at the person that couldn't
help him make it work. I mean
that is just like, you know,
two for two. Right. But that's like a,
that's like pitching a
perfect game in anger.
MMM.
So anyways, hats off to that fucking
guy. Hats off to Patrick, my homes,
he's a fucking amazing cheese. Have a
great fucking team. But like, you know,
mmm.
I don't know how anybody thinks either
one of those teams is going to win the
fucking super bowl.
You can't do,
they both lit up 40 invoice
it 40 and 43 points.
Okay.
And everybody's, I remember seeing
that back in the fucking day.
Like that was how the adult, the dolphins,
never one when they had Dan Marino,
cause they had no fucking defense. It
was just like, all right dad, you know,
we're going to give up 35 38 points.
Do you got 40 and yet again today,
he had to go out and score fucking 40
points so we can win by two or three. Um,
and those teams never won super bowls.
And to this fucking day
he gets shit for it. Like they blamed
the one guy who wasn't a problem.
Okay.
They blamed the fucking guy that
got him to as far as they can
fucking goal before they would
run into a fucking great defense,
which would,
you know,
knock down whatever Dan was going
to do by seven to 10 points.
But his shit defense would still give
up the fucking 35 38 points and then
they'd lose. And then in real Dan
Marino can win the big one. You know,
fucking Joe Montana couldn't win the
big one with those fucking differences.
MMM.
I mean, how many times you got to watch
sports defense wins championships. Okay.
I don't know what the fuck everybody's
so excited about last night's God damn
game.
Watching two teams giving up 40.0 I
can't wait to come play off toe player
player. Right. Um, anyways, so,
okay.
Meanwhile on a TV screen right next to it.
It was the red sox and the Astros.
Now I was out doing, so I missed like
the first half of the game I kicked by
the time I came in, it was five to four.
Um,
I don't know how price looked or whatever.
I got to go read some shit on it.
But um,
I think he left at five four.
So I believe if if,
uh,
Kimbro hadn't let that run
in to make it seven to five,
I used to know how this works.
I think he would have got the victory.
So if that is the case,
then he kinda got screwed out of a,
out of a win last night.
Um,
but I got to tell you the Astros
fucking lettuce up off the mat because
obviously going up to Oh is huge.
But the thing was they beat sale.
Yeah.
And that's what the Yankees had to do.
They had to beat sale because then you
get the price and price has not one in
October. So you basically get yourself
to fucking wins. And for the Yankees,
they got the first two, one a three that
they needed. And even with the Astros,
if he went in the first two fucking gags,
the other team has to win
for the next five and you
just have to go to a three c.
It's all about the mouth. So, um,
you know,
I did not have high hopes for how we were
going to look a against the Astros and
how game one went down was, well, how I
thought the series was going to go down.
But after watching last night
I was like, alright, you know,
this is the fucking Sylvester
Stallone. Yeah, it's so bad.
It's so bad.
Um,
but they are an incredible fucking team.
so we shall see,
hey,
who's that bearded guy with
the Bob Stanley body that
we have in a middle relief.
That guy's been doing all right.
When I saw him,
I had flashbacks to 1986 with Bob
Stanley running out of the bullpen.
I mean, that fucking guy, I swear
to God, like he had like a cop body.
Like it's a stereotypical like,
like bad cop.
I don't meet crooked cop.
I mean like, you know,
yeah.
Just, you know, you just keep, every year
you just order a bigger uniform, you know,
one of those fucking guys and
then just coming, running out,
you know,
this skinny fucking legs and
his flabby fucking, I mean,
how are you like a professional athlete
and then you can't take your shirt off
at the pool. You know, it's
just fucking unbelievable to me.
That's basically the body that gay had.
So all muffin top Johnson,
whoever the fuck we have on coming
out in a middle relief, that guy is,
he's just been asis, these big fucking
asis and uh, Kimbrell just, you know,
you die a thousand fucking deaths
with that guy. He's just like,
he's going to let in at least one
run is what I've just come to expect.
And um,
okay.
The shit that I say when he out of
this mother Fucker, this fucking Cook,
I'm son of a bar. You follow?
Yeah, of course. Of course.
You're walked up, right.
Um,
I have the second he gets in the game,
I stand up and I just start pacing.
Um,
yeah.
And I know that like I'm also
okay
a lunatic,
but I hats off.
Okay.
To that fucking guy.
Like that guy last night,
he's one of those grown men that when
his team finally wins it, like he's,
he's going to fucking cry.
Yeah.
Like he's like,
this is the new NFL did like how much
it meant to him for his team to win and
how sick he was.
Okay.
Of the Patriots just fucking getting all
the calls and all the shit that you say
about all the, all the fucking great
teams. I've fucking been there.
And it was just to watch it. It was,
I really learned a lot about myself.
MMM,
okay.
It's very rare that you see
two exciting games like that.
And then somebody's behavior
is at the same level. I mean,
all three of them were,
uh, were asis, but, uh,
okay.
Jesus Christ is Emma
homes kid. Good. My God.
Okay.
I wish that Monday night guy didn't
fucking hype them up so much and make me a
fucking contrarion like tap
into that shit. He's like,
can you just let me watch and be great?
And then I can say he's great rather than
you spoon feeding what I'm supposed to
beat them.
I hope you realize what you just saw.
All right buddy.
Dial it down.
Okay.
It reminds me of like when
that woman with the Yankees.
Okay.
The Roger Clemens called Roger.
Roger Clemens.
Oh my goodness gracious.
What is,
um, both of them should be,
they'd be doing wrestling.
Um, by the way, um,
I want to thank everyone that came out
in Saginaw, Michigan. First of all,
I landed at the airport and I
swung by the old address, uh,
where my great grandparents lived. They
had a house in my great grandfather, uh,
evidently dug the basement by hand.
Okay.
Stubborn German guy. Right.
And I don't buy, by the way,
I don't know how the fuck do you do that
without your house falling down into
the hall.
Okay.
I would imagine you'd have to start in
the middle of the room, work your way out,
and then pick one side. You know,
and as you started to do it,
you have to put something
underneath the fucking foundation
because I wouldn't feel safe going within
two feet of whatever dirt the fucking
foundation was sitting on.
I don't know how the fuck he do that.
Okay.
But my buddy was laugh because we,
so we showed up to where the house
okay.
Was supposed to be the address and
there was no house there anymore.
That was in fact a lot of in that area,
you know, the houses, obviously my great,
great grandparents lived there a
hundred fucking years ago. So, um,
okay.
The house is no longer there.
It's now like it was knocked down.
They put up something new.
It was just like an empty lot.
And my buddy was joke
being like, well, you know,
your grandfather dug a basement here.
Maybe that's why the house
isn't here anymore. But, um,
I gotta tell you,
man,
that theater that I played in the
sound in that theater was incredible.
It's just, um, it was such a live
theater. It was, it was incredible.
I was like, well, how can you get,
this is another one.
He can take the fucking special in here.
And the crowd was
awesome. And um, you know,
I was teasing him about fucking,
you know,
being farmers and all of that
dumb shit that I do. And uh,
you know,
we were going to try it.
We would drive and right down to Ann
Arbor for the University of Michigan,
Wisconsin Badger game the next day and
we meet somebody in a bar and all of that
shit, by the way. Yes. Sober October
is just out the window for me.
It's not happening. All
right, I'm having a bad year.
Um, next year, next year I'll
win the title. So anyways, uh,
I was saying in my head, all right, I
usually do like upwards of 90 minutes.
I'll probably do like an hour and 15
jump in the car and we'll get the fuck
outta here. Blah, blah, blah, Blah and
all that shit. And I had such a good time.
I ended up doing like an
hour, 30 an hour, 35. Um,
ended up going out doing like the
meet and greet thing. And, uh,
but it's still all worked out because
we found this bar that was open till two
in the morning. And me and my
buddies, you know, for Z, Bart,
nick and our two other buddies,
uh,
that we go to the games with every year,
we would have in such a good fucking time.
Just laughing.
It's like the most laughs
I've had on a weekend.
Just laughing our fucking asses off,
just breaking each other's balls and we
were just having such a good time and we
were so excited about the game the
next day, you know, like all this,
like the people that work there,
they just start liking you. Um,
then they were coming over and you know,
next thing you know the bar
is closed and like, all right,
what does it just go downstairs?
Cause there was a downstairs
area so we don't get in trouble.
And then we stayed down there until
like fucking four in the morning.
So thank God it was a seven 30 game.
So the next day we fucking wake up and um,
we go out to go with some meat
before we head over to the tailgate.
When I mentioned meeting a bunch
of other friends, you know,
some of my relatives and all that shit
to tailgate before we go into the fucking
big house. Right. This is my weekend.
Ridiculous.
Right?
So we go out to this place
to get something to eat, man.
I'll tell you like, why did I
tell you everything was just okay.
It was all almost like
that almost tasted good.
You know how long it took
for the food to get out.
They didn't clear off any
of the fucking plates.
It was so fucking funny like this.
It was just one of the worst run
places I've been to in a long time.
And like I remember at one point
we, um, I just saw this random,
you know, personal work, then
go by and I just say, excuse me,
can we get our, uh, can we
get our check? She's like, ah,
you're going to have to ask your server.
And I don't know who that is.
Okay.
And I'm looking at it like,
well go fucking find out.
And then
do you know, of course she doesn't. They
finally see our server and to do that.
And then she said comes out and she goes,
excuse me,
the people over there trying to say
that you're somebody, are you somebody?
Are you,
are you bill Maher is what she said,
which was so fucking perfect cause the
food, all the food was almost good.
And then
she almost recognized me and almost got
my name right. So we were fucking crying,
laughing,
okay.
About how they just kept almost. And
then she goes, what is your name?
And I go,
Michael,
okay.
And she goes, Michael, who?
And it goes stray hand.
Okay.
And then afterwards I go, none.
And I am, I go, actually Bill Burr,
Bill Maher does. And she
goes, all right. She goes,
so who was the guy you said you were?
I said, Michael Strain. And he goes,
I used to play for the New York giants.
Now he does one of those morning
talk shows. And she goes, Oh, what?
So like you think that,
you know,
because I work in a sports bar that you
just got to say like a sports process
name that's kind of
stereotypical isn't it?
And I looked at her like Isaiah got
Mike getting like me to do right now.
Like what the fuck kind of energy is that?
You know,
that that part was like
fucking annoying to me.
Like,
like how fucking fully yourself are you,
you know?
Do you think that's all I am as a person?
It's like I don't even fucking know yet.
The only reason why he
said straight hands,
cause I didn't think there'd be
a follow up question to Michael.
And that was the first name I thought of.
Um,
anyway,
so I did stand up last night at Gotham
comedy club and I was having a great time
until I started making fun of women and
then everybody just fucking pulls back.
It's one of my issues with fucking
doing standup in New York City now is
everybody's so air quote woke.
It's like,
it's like doing stand up at
a fucking woman's college.
I feel like I'm performing in front of
old people on a cruise ship and you look
at them and they're like half my age and
they're borderline fanning themselves
and you're just looking at him like,
guys, I'm 50. You should be shocking me.
I'm telling you this fucking generation,
it's not millennials,
it's the generation. You
know, what does it see?
Whatever the fuck they call these fucking
people that like the level of midlife
crisis that these people are
going to have. It's just,
it's just going to be off the fucking,
it's going to be off the fucking rails.
So anyways,
um,
after crying laughing the night
before we were in this place,
the colon at the, almost
something, or rather crying,
laughing, it just how poorly run
the fucking thing was. Right.
Um, them, we're out in the parking
lot. We're trying to decide, all right,
are we going to Uber over there?
You know,
cause Uber is just taking
forever to call or whatever.
And so we finally decided
we're going to Uber.
Okay.
And we just started singing this
Bruce Bruce Springsteen song,
just trashing each other.
Okay.
Uh,
you know that it,
oh,
we just kept doing that.
It would make it fun of Barton it cause
he was driving, Joe can't see shit.
He's like farsighted so he could see
the fucking big house from Saginaw,
but he couldn't see the car
fucking two feet in front of them.
And we're driving in, it's raining out
and first he's in the back seat like
okay,
well a quiver in his voice
the entire fucking time.
And I've resigned myself to the
fact that we're going to die.
And Paul was mad at me that I didn't get
as upset as he was. It's just like, dude,
we're doing 80 miles an hour with the
guy who can't see in the rain. So,
okay,
what am I Jack Ryan? Am I going to
fucking reach over and grab the wheel?
It's like we're, we're, we're either
going to live or die, you know,
we're not walking away
with severe injuries.
This is going to be a fireball death.
Okay.
So we just was singing,
okay,
I can't move.
So those Joe bought nick,
he can't see shit changing
blades in the rain.
I can't even do it anymore.
Right.
Fucking shredded my voice doing it,
just trashing each other
and it just went all around pulverize
z and the whole fucking thing.
And then they say one about me and
we're just drinking in this parking lot
laughing
like the whole weekend was,
it just was one nonstop fucking laugh.
Then we get to the tailgate and my
buddies are on this golf course and I have
the Uber dropped us off on the
other side of the golf course.
We had to walk like 10 fairways and you
know the ball breaking started by the
second hole. And I'm like, I think
it's over the next till. Yeah,
but all it's telling me the next
silly, where the fuck are we? You know,
I don't know. I believe it was a Magellan
reference. I can't even remember him.
We just fucking laughing. Right.
And we finally ended up finding, um,
finding the tailgate with
throwing the football around,
but playing that bean bag toss game or
whatever, that one of the guys there,
he made his own, he built it from hand and
then he had in the hole, he had it lit.
He had like lights around
the hole on the inside.
It was just like to a whole other level
and it got really fucking competitive
and Farzeen this dude al that we go with,
they would like to, to best, I'm like,
you guys are the Dream Team.
You've got to take down the dentist.
Cause this kid who was a
dentist was the go fucking
built the thing himself. Um, corn hall I
believe is what the fucking games called.
And it got to the point, everyone
was just so fucking into it, right?
And uh, I sucked at it. Like I
just kept going for the whole,
I never got one to just,
I didn't that you gotta have like that
Robert Parish foul shot, rts shit.
So anyways,
um,
was standing there with plain and all
of a sudden this fucking guy, you know,
people kept walking between his throwing
and we know we will take an a time
letting people pass. And
one guy, I swear to God,
it looked like the dude
from fucking radio head,
he just comes walking up and he's
fucking hammered real slowly.
And then they tried to grab one of the
bags out of my buddies' hands and he,
you know, he's sort of a Midwest
guy. So the, the, you know this guys,
they got like a long fuse Midwest people,
but you know when they snap,
forget about it cause they're like had
to pick up tractors when they were kids
so they fucking squeeze you to death.
So he kind of chills out and they
got the east coast short fuse.
So I just didn't like it cause he wasn't
saying anything and he was just staring
that kid down. So I just looked at him
as a 50 year old man at a tailgate.
I looked at him and I said,
the fuck is your problem. Like,
like I'm going to roll around on the
grass with this guy with my fucked up
shoulder and my 50 year old Barney,
right? Not even, not even thinking, oh,
I've been PNID accident, have your
bill. You're half a century old.
Keep your fucking mouth shut and
drink your role in rock. But I didn't.
So what the fuck is your problem?
So he's walking away and he's staring
at me and I'm fucking staring at him and
I'm like going, ah, I'm about where
you get into a fight. Why? Uh,
I got a kid, like, what
am I doing? But like,
I'm not going to fucking look away from
this fucking guy because as much as some
thinking that I fucking hate this kid,
right?
So he's staring at me, staring at
me, and then all of a sudden you can,
he won't stop staring as he's kind
of walking away and he's just,
as he's getting into a distance of like,
all right,
I think he's just going to
bluff his way out of this.
He fucking walks into an empty
chair of somebody else's tailgate.
And when I tell you it took like
nine seconds for this guy to slowly,
it was like somebody
chopped down a redwood,
how long it took for him to fall and all
the tailgates cause they were kind of
watching it. The whole
thing transpire. Uh,
the like three tailgates as this
guy falls, everyone were like, oh,
hit the ground
and everybody's dying laughing.
And then he stands up and
he's still staring at me.
Like you ever see a drunk guy fall down,
but he doesn't spill any part of his
beverage. That's what he was doing.
But with like a stare down,
he had a cigarette is what he had and he
fucking hits the ground and he's still
staring him that Radiohead with one
fucking I more open than the other one.
And then he puts his cigarette in
his mouth and as he's getting up,
he's still staring at me and he grabs
the chair and for half a second I'm like,
this fucking Luna is going
to throw this chair at me.
And he just stood the fucking thing up
and then looked at everybody and did a
giant wave.
Like it was the end of the performance.
And I want to say he got an
applause break and he walked away.
So now we're all once again crying,
laughing.
Yeah.
Fucking crying, laughing. Just
having the best time ever.
Then we ended up,
we ended up going into the game.
Okay.
You know,
I'm a couple of heaters in here,
so this is when it becomes
like the slideshow, right?
We're at the tail gate shall change. Now
we're getting checked by security. Um,
so we're fucking going into the big house
and I'm telling my buddies, I'm like,
dude, it's not going to look like
anything. As you're walking up to it,
like two thirds of it,
they dug it into the ground.
It's when you go in there and you see
the fucking magnitude of this fucking
place, it's going to be unreal. So we
walked in there and one of my buddies,
I don't know how he did it, but you know,
you know, there's no booze in there.
He snuck in entire fifth of crown royal.
I mean like,
okay,
like the one Keith Richards
would take a swig out of,
um,
sit down and he just pulls it up
and the people behind us laughed.
It was so fucking ridiculous that
he got it in. They would just laugh.
They're like cheeses.
They started laughing and we just
shared it with everyone around us.
So then we were sort of like surround,
it was like when you play
chess and you build a castle.
We did that with drunk people around
us and it was fucking cold out. And um,
then we just kept everybody warm
and just proceed then and then,
oh, then then the fucking pregame things
started. I'm trying to find the video.
They have James Earl Jones
do it and they're like,
we all though Michigan moval reach,
we've won more games,
the college football team,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then at one point he goes, we bow to
no one. And we would just laugh and like,
I do it. I'm ready to run
through a fucking wall. Um,
and then the wolverines came running out.
We was sitting right on the 50 yard line,
like 12 rows up.
We weren't too low that, you know, you
lose like depth of perception. You know,
we would sit and perfectly and they all
just come fucking running out on one
whole side of 100,000 people's
is screaming God and on
the other side would go.
It was fucking just got chills and um,
and then the game started and fucking
Michigan had their way with them.
Thank God. Uh, cause I did not
want to see them loose, you know,
and would have ruined the experience.
I always root for the fucking whole team,
you know, unless Lsu is play.
Um, and then the game was great.
I mean it sucked if you were badger
fans cause it kind of just had their way
with them but it was such a fucking like
okay
an amazing experience and the
amount of laughs that we had,
I really think like we were
all sitting there talking go.
I think that was the best one. I,
I'm a, I'm calling it right now.
We're going to have a hangover one next
year where like last year where we went,
we went to Lsu, Florida
gators, and it was just so,
uh,
fucking hot out that it was,
it was almost impossible to
enjoy yourself. It was, it was,
it was fucking ridiculous.
So I think next year we're going
to try to go to Clemson. Yeah.
MMM.
I think we're going to try to go to
Clemson or something like that and, uh,
we're going to try to knock out all
those ones that are in like hurricane,
you know, part of the world just so, uh,
you know,
with global warming and all of that shit,
we want to try to knock those up
before those stadiums are under water.
It's so sad, but when he can't do
anything but laugh about it, right.
Um, oh, I got a Texas person back,
uh,
be there.
I'll be there around 1215.
There we go. There we go. Um,
all right, plowing it. Let's,
let me do a couple of reads here.
Okay,
let me do it, Joe. Bob, Nick.
Okay, here we go. Uh, oh my bookie,
everybody. Oh Jesus Christ. By the way,
how bad where my picks,
one of my locks of the weeks with was the
giants take the giants with the points
at home. Holy Shit. Sorry. Although
I might be good at picking games.
We just listened to me
and you do the opposite.
I want to say a couple of them came in.
I think I went two and three.
I think it was more like one and two.
Um,
okay.
I picked three games, so either two,
one one or I went one, one and two.
I can't remember which. All right.
Sure. Watching football is fun,
but it's more entertaining
when he got some action on
the game guys. Yeah, me too.
I'll get about this for weeks and some
of you are still on this side lights,
whether you're an expert or a rookie,
you should be betting at my bookie.
If you're the kind of guy that likes to
bed a little and when a lot like playing
the numbers on roulette,
you can create a big payday parlay.
He picked three teams to,
when you hit all three,
you could turn on $100 into $600 there's
so much to bet on. Playoff baseball,
hockey primetime, fights
and more. But my book,
he is the one bed I know you'll
be happy with all year. All right?
People recommend these guys
and really trust them. My book,
he has been in business for years.
They got great online reviews and
their mobile site is easy to use.
If you're on the sidelines.
Now is the time to get in the game.
My bookie will still match your
first deposit, dollar for dollar,
but you got to join now because
there'll be pulling that offer.
Log on to my bookie right
now and double your money.
Use Promo Code Burr and you'll get your
first deposit matched 100% that's Promo
Code [inaudible] you play, you win,
you get paid, right? You play, you win,
you get paid. Okay. Um,
zero to hell is this.
I don't even remember.
I didn't know this one for any
smokers out there trying to quit.
If you know someone who is,
there's a revolutionary revolutionary
new way to quit called zero zero's.
Quick Kit is a new quitting solution
proven to increase your chances of kicking
the habit by up to four times
compared to going cold Turkey. Um,
talk about your experience
or the experience of someone
you know who is trying
to quit smoking. Well, I never
really, I mean I smoked cigars,
but I never did the cigarette. The
cigarette thing is the hard thing. Um,
and evidently it's harder to
quit than kicking heroin. So,
and um,
that's all I know.
The zero quick kit is a three tiered
approach that includes prescription
medication, nicotine, gum, and
continued support through a mobile app.
Here's how it works.
Go to quit with xero.com to
start your online doctor visit.
After your five minute visit,
a physician will then determine if
you're eligible to use the quick kit.
If you're eligible,
the doctor will prescribe your medication
in the quick kit will be shipped
directly to your door.
Zero costs less than what the average
smoker spends on cigarettes and less than
other quittings options go to quit.
Would xero.com/pir and for a limited time,
my listeners can get their first month
of the quit kit to stop smoking for just
$37.
That's quit with zero.com/burr quit
with xero.com/bar that's like another
fucking thing where you just realize
that it really is all about money.
You know, because you know, we're,
we're allegedly fighting a war on
terror and you have a fucking American
corporations that like literally put
glass in dip to give you microscopic cuts
so you get more of a buzz and get more
fucking into it. And just, I mean,
they literally killed people
that fucking mass mass murderers,
mass fucking murders. You tell me what
isis would do different with tobacco.
They probably try to kill you a
little quicker. Those dumb fucks,
they'd probably put some fucking
explosives in it and they only kill a few
people and then get caught. Um, yeah.
But you know what I'm telling you,
all you need to do to go from being a
terrorist to an upstanding us citizen is
just donate to a politician's
campaign and then you'll, you're,
you're in the clear, that's all you got
to do. All right. Dollar Shave Club,
dollar Shave Club has everything you
need to look, feel and smell your best.
And you never have to go to a store.
That's because they deliver everything
you need right to your door and they keep
you fully stocked and what you use. So
you don't run out. Here's how it works.
Dollar Shave Club,
there's everything you need to get ready.
No matter what you're getting ready for.
They have you covered head to toe, uh,
for your, your what? Oh, your hair.
Your skin, your face, you name it,
they have it.
And they have this new program where
they automatically keep you stocked up on
the product she used. You determine
what you want and when you want it.
And it shows up right at your door,
uh,
from once a month to once every six
months plus with their handsome discount.
The more you buy, the more
you save. And Right now,
dollar shave club has a bunch of status
sets you can try for just $5 like their
oral care kit.
After that,
the restock box ships regular sized
products at regular price gets you start a
set for just $5 right now
at dollar shave club, dude,
dollar shave club.com/bird that's
dollar shave club.com/burn and lastly,
but certainly the lease.
Aye
stamps.com stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for any letters or
any packages at your convenience.
24 seven print postage for any class, a
male right from your own computer. Uh,
the exact amount of postage every time.
Never underpay or overpay again.
stamps.com saves you time and money,
uh,
which you can use to grow
your business stamps saw,
brings all the amazing services of
the u s postal service right to your
fingertips. Tips, buy and print official
US postage for any letter, any package,
any class of mail using your own computer
and printer stamps.com makes it easy.
They'll send you a digital scale,
automatically calculates exact postage
stamps.com we'll even help you decide the
best class of mail based on your needs.
No need to lease an expensive postage
meter and there are no long term
commitment.
So right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com servers
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus postage
and a digital sale scale. Sorry,
go to stamps.com.
Click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburburthatstamps.com
enter
bar. All right, let's get into some of
the questions here for the week. Oh,
we have some upcoming dates.
Baltimore, Maryland, October 18th.
This Thursday I'll be at
the modal model lyric.
Uh, early show is sold out late show
tick, uh, tickets still available.
Atlantic City,
New Jersey Borgata resort.
October 19th two shows a Phoenix,
Arizona.
October 26 Comerica Theater,
um,
evening show says sold
out. Stand up live. Mm. Oh,
I'm doing a, Oh, I'm doing
a live podcast. Once again.
The only time I've ever done it before,
it was the same place.
Stand up live Monday morning,
podcast taping.
There's still a few tickets still
available. Um, New York City,
Madison Square Garden. I'll be
there. November 7th and Chicago.
November 8th to 10th.
I'll a tickets still available
for the late show on the eighth.
MMM.
Oh my God. The late shows. That means I'm
doing two shows. Jesus Christ, Chicago.
All you guys always supported me, man.
I really appreciate that. All right,
let's get into some of the questions
here for the week. All right.
Sociopath island.
You'll Billy one punch.
Checkout psychopaths.
It's an animated show about the same
idea you had last week throwing all this
psychos on an island.
MMM.
Hey. You know what, man, I got a
phone. I actually just watched the, uh,
I watched the clip of that. I think
I'm going to get into that show. Um,
as far as I can tell,
cause there's no talking or anything,
there's no dialogue in it.
It looks like there's a group of people
who aren't sociopaths and for some
reason they have to go to associate
psycho island in fucking maybe rescue
somebody.
Yeah.
MMM.
I Dunno. But it's definitely
interesting and it's always, uh,
I came up with a great idea that not
only did somebody else already have,
they've already developed it. Um,
that happens to me all the time.
And the worst case of it was a time
when I wanted to do a parody of a drum
instructional video and someone's like,
somebody already did that. I was like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me,
Fred. Armisen. All right, dude.
You called it DNA. Uh, Yo belt.
Listening to the throwback last week.
And you mentioned how even if you don't
bank online, your shit is online anyway.
So that was 2010.
Now you're coming down on ancestry DNA
test and I think history is going to
repeat itself.
This article basically says that even
if you don't send your DNA into the
Internet, they will be able to deduce
all of your DNA Info anyways. Yeah,
they need like 6 million people.
They're halfway there. All felons,
you know,
have to give up their fucking DNA.
And then all these fucking
mouth breathe in fucking morons
who just trust people are sending in
their fucking saliva to the fucking
Internet.
It's so stupid.
The article says once the registry reached
3 million off, I, okay, I was wrong.
There'll be able to identify the people
who haven't sent in their DNA currently
there at the 1 million mark.
Dude, you called it. Yeah.
And it's like what are they
going to do with it? Like the,
the fact that you're going to sit there
and you're going to depend on all of
these fucking people to do the right
thing. I mean, look, look what's going on.
Like everybody knows what the fuck
is going on in the world right now,
but she can't really talk about
it because they got the game.
So sewed up that you're viewed as like
a sociopath or fucking UNAMERICAN.
If you even remotely criticize what the
fucking people who are making tons of
money off of other people's misery, R
and d, they're just going to have you,
it's going to be game set.
Fucking match.
MMM.
And I'm not even gonna read that article
because it's going to be so fucking
depressing because people are just,
they're just gonna keep doing it.
MMM.
Yeah.
It's just going to be like,
okay.
I think it,
it all ties into,
uh,
how people that are in control,
if they're doing wrong things,
it makes you paranoid and you can not
have enough information on people.
And then also there's no
fucking way that these people,
when they go to those
Bilderberg fucking meetings,
there is no fucking way that
they are not having hardcore,
you know,
I need to go to the hotel bar after
this and fucking drink this meeting off
talks about the population
problem and climate change.
There's no fucking way that, that, that
they're not talking about that shit.
How the fuck they're going to handle it
and how they're going to survive and who
else they're going to determine it's going
to survive and that God has put us in
power. We have to make these tough
decisions. Um, which I mean, I like,
I have a solution on how
to, you could fucking solve
those problems, but you know,
I don't know.
So I think they're trying to get as much
information so they don't, you know,
I think once they get
everybody microchipped uh,
then that's when they're going to start
fucking thin in the herd and they need
to do it quick.
And this right here,
this train of thought is why I don't
watch the fucking news because that's
everything that's going on in
everything that they're showing.
That's what I can't even watch the weather
channel anymore. I'm just like, dude,
this is like, this is, this is a fucking
done deal here. This is over. Um, anyways,
buying a car. Hey, let's get back to
some fucking bread and circus here.
Buying a car. Dear Billy Ball boy, uh,
a bill first. I just first, uh,
just wanted to say thank you for
your show you put on in Springfield.
It was fantastic and definitely
would love to see come back sometime.
I had a great time to thank you.
I always listened to the podcast
on my bus ride to school. Anyways,
I am a sophomore in high school
and I just received my permit. Ah,
good for you man. That's a big day. I
have a job and I'm saving up for a car.
I was wondering what your first car ever
was and what kind of car would be good
for a first timer like me and what
should I look for when buying a car that
would be beneficial.
Thanks to go fuck yourself.
I had a 1983 Ford ranger,
four cylinder,
five speed overdrive,
a black vinyl seats,
fire engine red. Um, the long bed,
there was enough two wheel
drive, nothing cool about it. Um,
but it only at 19,000 miles on when I
bought it. So it was definitely reliable.
I paid five grand for it. Um, I went
out and got alone and with the job.
So you know, I got alone, I established
credit and that type of shit.
Still remember my, my, it
was Danvers savings bank,
one cone and street Danvers mass,
something, something, something. And I'm,
my payment was $138 and 63 cents.
I still fucking remember that.
So if I was you, um, you're
obviously going to buy a used car.
Okay.
I mean, I always loved the Honda's and
the Toyota's back in the day because those
engines would just last forever.
I don't know what they're doing now,
but I remember I, I got some
acting work and it made some money,
but I've always been a
frugal son of a bitch.
So rather than buying a new
car in like the late nineties,
I bought a 1988 Honda
accord LX five speed,
four to a five speed.
And I fucking loved that car.
It had a hundred thousand
miles on it when I drove it.
And that fucking thing could
cruise at a hundred miles an hour.
Still no fucking problem.
It was such a well built car.
So if I was going to go
used, you know, you gotta be,
you gotta be careful with
whatever the flashy cars are.
Like when I was a kid,
everybody would try to go out and
buy the Burt Reynolds fucking trans.
And with the screaming
chicken of the flaming Eagle,
whatever the fuck they
called it on the hood.
And you just had to know
that those cars were,
they would driven like a sports car,
fucking burnouts and neutral drops and
all this shit that people use to do,
try and do the gym Rockford back in an
up and whip in the fucking front end
around. So, um, I dunno.
And I also liked having a four door car
cause I used to like hanging out with my
friends. Everybody could
pile in and uh, you know,
all depends on what you're looking for.
But I would definitely,
I would get something that, uh, is, is uh,
that has the reputation
of lasting rather than,
I dunno. I mean you do want
something kind of cool try.
If you can blend both those worlds,
something kind of cool looking,
but also it's going to last. I
would get something like that. Um,
and you know, if you have to take
out a little bit of a loan, you know,
you already got a job that's fucking
cool. You established credit, um,
you pay the fucker rough. And, uh, then
you know, then you're into that world,
right? Learn about money and
all of that shit. All right.
Halloween costumes. Um, oh,
I gotta wrap this up quick here
because I got to get running here.
All dear Billy Billy's
dear Dr. Billy Stein,
I have a two year old daughter.
Oh, congratulations as well.
And I'm starting to remember all this
fun stuff we do this autumn season,
jumping piles,
Aleve,
watch Halloween movies and tried to scare
the shit out of ourselves by running
through the woods at night.
I don't think I've ever heard you recall
any favorite Halloween costumes for
Halloween memories.
The you and Nia have any place plans
to dress up your daughter. Also,
if you had a professional
costume and makeup team,
what would you go for as Halloween
at this point in your life?
Um, ps, nothing goes better
with the cigar than apple cider.
Nothing really. Rarely. Well,
it just so happens I know somebody who
makes apple cider who also happens to be
one of my favorite drummers of all time.
Tim Alexander from Primus.
He has his own a site or what
the fuck is it called again?
He just fucking ask me if I wanted
some too, when I told them I can't,
I'm fucking in sober October,
which I was.
And now I'm not.
Let's see.
Tim Owl eggs and they're cider.
The shit is, I mean if you're into, if
you're into fucking site or man. Okay.
Herb site or.com.
MMM.
What do we got here? Here we go.
Yeah, it's called heard cider.
It's hard.
Our herb site or is a craft cider
produced by world renowned drummer,
Tim Herb Alexander and his wife Sharma
created their first batch of cider in
their garage in the fall of 2016. Yeah,
dude, he gave me some of that stuff.
It's fucking delicious. And then I brought
me, give me like a whole case of it.
So I brought it down to the comedy
store and gave it out to see a bunch of
comics and everyone's just like kind of
fucking went nuts for it. So anyways, um,
let's get back to the Halloween stuff.
Um, mum, mum, mum, mum.
Uh, okay. What are you asking me? Do I
have any plans to dress up? Yeah, I mean,
I usually dress up like John
Bonham or a fucking, you know,
maybe I was going to go with
Vinnie Paul this year, you know,
just as he passed away this
year or something like that.
And as far as our daughter, my wife
was talking, she was going to dress,
dress her up like Bruno Mars because
our daughter has like curly hair.
She's so fucking cute.
It's ridiculous. But uh,
at the last second she went to the
costume place and she got us all like
matching like skeleton costumes,
which I thought was a little hacky going
out as, as, uh, when she told me the idea,
but then I saw him, they're really
fucking cool and it's going to look cute.
You know, we're having a, um, Nia does
the kid Halloween party every year,
so we have a bunch of kids come over.
So I guess I couldn't dress
up like something too scary.
And I guess if I dressed up
like John Bonam or Vinnie Paul,
they wouldn't know who it was.
And it probably just looked
like a scary fucking guy. Um,
okay.
So anyways, um, did I
answer your question?
I don't even fucking know.
I'm just thinking about smoking a scar.
Drink at some fucking apple
cider. Them are underrated. Uh,
going to things by yourself.
A No girls, no friends,
no family, no problem. Hey
there, Billy freckled glutes.
My whole life I had this dilemma regarding
going to events or social gatherings
alone.
I've even had friends say that I,
if you eat alone at a restaurant or
Mcdonald's or something that's social
suicide. Well, no one ever told me that
I love going to ship on myself. Uh,
this can be really debilitating,
especially if your work schedule sucks.
You live in a town or a
million other reasons.
But I figured I've been thinking well,
but I finally figured it out.
Who cares half the time that you could,
that you do have a group to go
to something with people, flake,
want to change plans, times, cetera. If
there's an event you really want to go to,
you have to think about
yourself and just go,
even if you are by yourself.
And I write this as,
I'm a little nervous wanting to go to
see a comedy show tonight that I have to
drive a bit to that's out of
the way and go there alone.
Well, I'll be honest with you,
I just don't sit up front.
If you go to a comedy show
alone, but other than that,
there's no problem with it.
And then, you know, usually
meet people. You know,
I used to go to shit by myself all the
time, baseball games, football games,
all of that shit. I wouldn't talk to
anybody because I was a fucking lunatic.
Anyways, I say this because I say this
constantly having to deal with the issue,
uh,
including your tours.
Some very good friends dropped out
of going to your show show. Well,
I don't blame them.
I just feel like for me it
puts you in this spot of, oh,
now I just can't go.
And your instinct is that you
getting that experience is impossible
and your instinct is that you are
getting that experience is impossible.
We'll fuck that.
You might as well go because if you think
of it and that way you will miss out
on a thousand bill birth, special
sporting events, holidays.
And before you know it,
you're,
you're at the end of your road and
have all these piled up regrets.
Forget about the stigma of Solo attending
things. Live your life and have fun.
Did you guys hear my
stomach growl in there?
Try not to eat like a fucking asshole
here. Um, and that's all you have to say.
That's all I have to say about that.
Can't wait for you to see what
the guidance you ranty bastard.
Go Fuck Yourself. Thanks for the
laugh. Inspiration. And one more time.
Go Fuck Yourself. Yeah, you've
got, if you want to go, go. Yeah.
Just because someone else can't go.
I mean, what are they, what are they,
the the fucking dictator of
what you go to. Absolutely.
Go to use by yourself and then
chat up a couple of ladies.
Who were you here with?
Ah, I came by myself.
It's actually like a fucking strong move.
All my friends slaked and I was like,
fuck it. I'm going to go. I'm show
me somebody nice and look at it.
I ran into you and then your red,
right?
Go on a fire. My baby got a hold.
It's hard going to have an afternoon.
I came to this shit all by myself
and now I'm talking to you.
Would you like to see my deck?
Hey, I was just fucking around.
Please don't lead to me age. Sorry. Um,
anyways, would you like to see my
Dick? I asked fucking permission.
Why you flip out?
Please don't put that on Twitter. Uh,
sorry. I'm losing my fucking mind.
You don't want to realize too, I'm in my
fucking this fucking apartment here and,
and people. Yeah. People are gonna
be hearing me down the hall singing
about me to stuff and I don't want to
trigger anybody. All
right. Dash had. All right,
go red sox. Go Patriots.
Patrick bulbs is the real deal.
I miss defense in the NFL.
Um, that's all I have to say.
Go fuck yourselves and I'll
check in on you on Thursday.