Hey, what's going on is bill burn. It's
time for the Monday morning podcast,
but Monday, March 13th,
2017 what's going on?
How are you? You know what?
I asked you that every week.
How are but this, you know,
this Monday I would really
like to know how are you?
What's going on Mandy? What's
going on with you? You're,
you're scaring me.
You know,
that's the type of shit you can do when
you were abroad. But if you're a gay,
you can't do that. You can't be
like, Mike, what's going on with me?
What's going on? What's going on with
you? You're scaring me. You, it was,
you're taking by both his hands.
MMM.
All right. I've got an hour here to
do and I gotta be honest with you.
I don't have shit to say because my
life has become very compartmentalized.
Being a dad here. Daddy. Oh,
she's asleep downstairs,
man. She's fucking awesome.
Anybody who says that being a parent is
hard. It's a fucking pussy. You know,
I'm not saying that it's not tedious.
I'm not say saying it's not like walking
around with a little fucking Kettlebell
all day long, you know, especially if
you fucked up on your rotator cuffs.
I got to keep her in close in the right
hand side, you know, keep her in tight.
Tiki barber don't fumble.
MMM.
But uh, we just sit around, we
listen to a lot of music with the,
I was listening to fucking, um, there was,
I listened to yesterday just like
they called Mulch shot oldies.
It's basically like Doo wop from the 1950s
and I kind of settled on that channel
and after awhile I wanted
to turn the channel,
but I couldn't because she was sleeping
and the remote was like across the table
once they must say fall asleep,
dude. It's just like, you know,
I don't care what position you're in,
you're not moving because
if fucking sleeping, right.
So I just sat there and listened
to on a loop to all this
Dadda that,
but, but, but, but, but, but they book
slowly going out of my fucking mind.
Do ops great for about
four songs in a row.
And then it just becomes the same song
over and over and fuck it over again.
Um, I was listening to that
shit for like a fucking,
like an hour and like half of those
songs have been in Scorsese movies.
You know, it's always like some guy's
name and then the name of a card,
you know,
so and so in the Fleetwood's something
something and the Belmonts Dion and a
bell much. You gotta Love
Them. Miss still fucking great.
Okay.
You know,
the wanderer,
that fucking song is so applicable
to anybody who didn't get married.
You're in your forties.
Yeah. Well, on the Jab,
a guy who will never settled down.
It makes you feel great about the
choice you made until if you know,
you realize he sang it in his
twenties, then you're like, oh fuck.
What was another one?
You talk too much.
Talk too much. You were re
meet a dead. You talk too much.
At least as you've been
worried. My pet, it's just like,
I can't be the fucking line.
But they played it twice. Um,
speaking of talking too much, just what
the fuck I do on this podcast. Um, oh,
I know what I can, I know what,
we actually had a date night.
This is how much of a fucking
dad I'm becoming, you know,
still playing drums, you know,
schedule a helicopter, uh,
thing. So, you know, I'm still trying to
keep the hobbies going, but they're there.
They're starting to wobble
on the sticks here. So, um,
we were watching a
commercial the other day. No,
you're watching will ah,
um,
the other day and um,
they always get to the fucking,
the last prize and wheel fortunate
is so fucked in a touristy cheap.
Okay.
First of all,
you're basically spending this giant
roulette wheel and even on the real weapon
roulette wheel, they got
it, you know, green zero in
Dutton, the double green zero.
And just that alone,
that alone will completely fuck you over.
Now obviously you guys hopefully listen
to his podcast long enough to know that
I am not a mathematician,
so I cannot explain why,
but just having those two will
fuck you over. But what's it faces?
The, uh, we were fortunate. I
got like fucking, I swear to God,
it's like two or three
bankrupts lose a turn.
Just every two seconds.
You just hear that fucking reverse flute
thing or they go bankrupt and then it
comes to their big price. Well,
they try to act like they're gonna.
They gonna throw down some goddamn cash.
The last one, it's so fucking difficult,
but we're going to get some letters
for you then get some letters for you.
Me Get some letters for me.
You know the fucking answer.
And they act like it's weird when only
like one letter, they only get one letter.
Right. Then he'd be like, okay, give me,
give me three fucking letters
in a vile p f owl if a,
and then it's always like great
guesses, but you're not gonna like this.
We only got one letter. It's just
like, you know, do the best you can.
They always fuck them over.
But this lady, this lady,
she actually did okay and she won
the prize. She didn't do okay.
She fucking crushed it.
Yeah.
I came in to say keep your
hands to yourself or something
like that was solving
like, no, this is a phrase.
Yeah.
Like who would ever come up
with that on a fucking game?
She'll keep your hands to yourself
with something on that level.
It's like semi aggressive slash you know,
date rapey and it's on a fucking
game show and she somehow got it.
Okay.
There is a point at the end of this,
right.
And she ends up winning this fucking to
see some sort of Mazda is some shit's
not a Miata. I don't know what
the fuck it was. Sue. Suki,
I have no idea.
It was a two seat sports
car. And um, okay.
Immediately my first thought was
I looked at me, I was just like,
he can't get a kid in there. And then
she laughed. She's like, ah, look, yeah,
becoming a dad. And I'm like,
no, no, I'm still young and cool.
But she was right. You know, not
becoming a dad. I am a god Damn Damn,
but I'm not going to
be one as douchey dead.
It talks about how parents who stalks
about how fucking difficult their lives.
It's fucking awesome.
But having a kid when you're in
your 20s and you're broke sucks,
you know,
but when you travel in the country and
their pay and your money to talk about
your dicks and do fucking dicks talking
about your Dick and do shit jokes,
it's not dead bed. I'm only on the
road like six days of fucking month,
you know,
let's say flying at night early to go
watch the fucking Bruins and Celtics Assam
Shit for our schedules line up.
Um,
uh, that, that I'm here and she's cool
as shit. Man. She doesn't really cry.
She only cries, you know, needs a
diaper change, wants to be held,
you know, it's hungry. Other than that,
she totally Chels she's
met a bunch of people.
She doesn't freak out with strangers. One
of the best compliments I got was like,
oh your kid's really, uh, cause
a really relaxed, healthy baby.
You know what I mean? Which I'm fucking
site cause that's what I want it.
I obviously healthy, but I want to
fucking chill baby. I don't want,
like, I basically don't
want my kid to be like me.
That's why I got to keep up with this
meditating because I didn't do it for a
minute. And the, Oh, the
old gray mare, she a,
I started fucking going
back to what the fuck I was,
you know, like I fucking, uh,
I was trying to, you know,
sneak out of the bedroom because I
was going to go work out because I'm a
fucking fat cupcake Eaton dose.
And um,
Nina just opens your eyes and just goes,
could you change a really quick,
I just stopped and I
looked her and I said,
you really need to work on your
good mornings. She's like, sorry,
could morning.
And even though I was right,
my tone was just, it was way
too, you know, I was like, Dad,
uh, I always say Liam Neeson
Niamh Niamh Leeson lease them.
I don't know, whatever. I took
it too far, which kills me.
That's why I love meditating
because I don't take it too far.
And if I make a point, I'm still right,
but when I don't meditate, you know,
I'd basically, I walk
around at a six, you know,
like saying 10 is completely
losing your shit. I walk around,
I'm just walking down the street with a
fucking balloon on my wrist at a six to
a seven. So it's very easy for me to
go write the 10 unless I meditate.
Then that backs me down to about four
or three, which still is pretty high,
but it's kind of cut my
number almost in half.
The what kills me is when
I'm not meditating and I'm
up around a six or seven,
you know, it gets to that
point, even if I'm right,
my reaction gives them this,
this wiggle room,
you know, some Bill Clinton wiggle room
to get the fuck out of it. You know,
some Trump executive order thing
to go around some shit. Um,
so, uh, you know, so I gotta I gotta see,
I gotta stay on that type of shit, dude.
Speaking of fucking Niamh Niamh Gleason,
why can't it, you know, it's one of
those fuckers goes by so fucking quick.
You never really even hear it. No, Bill.
We all hear it. You don't know. May Look,
okay. Get this guy's fucking name
right. He's great actor here. It Niamh.
Yeah.
Oh No,
it's Liam Neeson is first names not Liam
is it is Niamh Lisa, whatever.
I'll never get that right. I'm never
going to get that fucking right. Anyways,
a fucking head of hair on that
son of a bitch. Um, anyways,
I saw a fucking great movie this
week. So Saturday nights, Saturday,
Saturday we go out and uh,
we actually have a date night,
so we'll be like, all right,
well go get maybe like dinner and a movie.
Well,
it basically turned about appetizer
and a drink and I'm sitting there like,
you know, I'm on the wagon, I can't do it.
He was like, oh, just fucking have one.
So I was like, all right, I'll have
one still on the wagon, you know,
I'm not like a fucking alcoholic or I
just got to shut the whole thing off,
you know what I mean? So I had one, I
had a cognac. Oh, fucking corn. Yeah.
Can I just say, you know, I just ordered
the best one that they had, you know,
so it tasted amazing,
but it was also like drinking
gasoline so that can only sip it.
And we got like an appetizer and
then we just sat there, you know?
Okay.
Shooting the shit. It felt weird because
we hadn't been out together in a while.
And then we just started talking about
our daughter and looking at pictures of
her.
It's like two addicts going out,
you know what I mean?
At some point you're going to start
talking about blow and how much fun it is.
Um, so then, you know, after
that we walked up the street,
we went to the movie theater and uh,
we saw get out,
um, the Jordan Peele fee, uh,
film dude. It was fucking him.
That was amazing. It got to go
see it. I know there's, you know,
there's always that movie and he's
like, dude, you gotta go fucking see it.
And it doesn't live up to the eye.
It lived up to the hype man.
It was fucking great. And what
I loved, what I loved about it.
And what I love about all
fucking movies like is,
so it was a bunch of shit
in there that you had,
he left you to figure out yourself.
And I saw the movie like two, three days
ago, Saturday, and that was a Monday,
two days ago, you know, and
I keep evil, I'm driving,
I'm still thinking about the
movie. I was like, Oh fuck,
that was this and this meant dad and
this was over here and this person's ad
like, you know, it was the perfect length,
the whole thing and the acting
and it was unbelievable. Um,
dude, that fucking guys swear to God, man.
That's like one of the most
talented people to come
around in a long, long time,
you know, to be that
good at like, you know,
the characters they did on a
sketch show and the writing.
And then on top of that you can direct,
I mean,
these kind of fucking limitless
as far as talent goes,
but if you haven't seen it
yet before somebody ruins it,
you got to go check it out. All right,
there's my, I never do a movie plugs,
so there you go. There's one for you. Um,
so we ended up going to that thing and uh,
I know what the fuck we did after that
thing. We just came straight home. Oh,
I know. Walked up to my car and for
some reason the fucking lights were on.
Okay.
Because cars are so God damn confusing.
Like wherever the fuck my lights
used to be. Boosie the automatic,
he just turned the car on and
they fucking come on at night.
Like somehow the lights sense night.
Fucking creepy is that,
and I did the manual one
and now that it's on the manual and I
can't figure out where the fuck to put it.
So now I always have to do it and
now I'm like, you know, but you know,
kills me with today's technology
is I left those things on,
went and had a drink and an appetizer
and then saw like a fucking whatever,
whatever that movies, 90 minutes. I
won 45 minute movie and I came back.
My car is still started up back
in the day. You are fucked.
Okay.
Everybody had jumper cables,
doe, can you give me a jump?
Do you mind if I ate to bar the,
can you give me a jump?
And it was always like the shittiest
fucking car ever. And you're like, ah man,
Naw man, a kid, a kid. Now you can
just say, no, I can't. The big,
why not? It's like, well
what? Today's technology,
it's pointless for me to
ever look under my hood.
I just take it down to the dealer
and they deal with everything.
I don't even know where the battery is
and I can guarantee fucking to you when I,
when I fucking lift up the hood I got,
I'd probably have to remove something
to get to one of the terminals.
So I don't know why you're not a member
of AAA, but I don't want it to tell you.
And I leave and I get my car and I
drive away from a fellow American.
You understand me? Do what's
going on with the fucking Celtics.
We've lost six of the last 11 games.
They're five and six and now the wizards,
the Wiz ease on down,
ease on down the row home.
I never really realized that until a
buddy of mine has been giving me Shit,
you know,
cause they're wizards amp and playing
well against the Celtics and just point
great to share.
They slid into a second place and I
just keep trashing about the name.
I like the bullets is too violent,
you know,
which I understand because the city was
so violent back in the day, you know,
but to go from being the bullets,
which I used to think, you know,
number one with a bullet,
that's how I always looked at it
off faster than a speeding bullet.
Superman Shit. I didn't
think like, you know,
the team was embracing gang violence out
on the street. It was like pro crack.
It's such stupid shit. I fucking hate
when they, so then what do they do?
What are the soccer moms
fucking political correct.
Police who for some fucking stupid
reason think that they're the eggs,
progressive people and think
that they can just, Oh,
we'll change words if we change words.
It changes to reception. No, it doesn't.
No, it doesn't. If your parents
would dopes racist country,
that's what the fuck your
kids going to be. That's it.
Unless your kid is lucky enough to win
a rack with somebody within the group
that your parents used to fucking trash,
they maybe he got some day like you don't
just change a word and it's this fairy
dust that sprinkles over somebody's
heart and you'd change the thought.
It's so fucking dumb.
All it did was just become a way to
lose your job because you said the wrong
fucking word. And then what?
The person who uses the word,
then they realize it after they lose a
job. Oh, now I'm not racist or homophobic.
It's so fucking dumb.
So they've gone right down to
these stupid fucking team names.
I love how they changed the bullets,
but not the Redskins.
You know? I think it'd be got,
you get like the fucking a victim.
If they ever changed the Redskins, it'd
be like, yeah, I get that. I get that.
Like the Indians, you know, it's like, all
right. You know, we weren't from fucking,
we weren't, you know, Columbus didn't
understand that there was a real world.
This shit's even real. Who the fuck
knows? There was no tape recorders.
This guy didn't have a fucking diary,
but other story was told was
that he was like, Nah, man,
the world is fucking round.
Okay,
this guy had the balls.
Okay.
Sky had the fucking balls to,
to start going towards where they thought
you'd go off the edge of the earth in
a fucking boat.
Okay.
You know, I don't know why the water,
it makes it more scary, but you know,
if anybody just sat around and thought
about Saturday until the world is fucking
flat.
Okay.
Um, how is it the water just
running off the edges here.
Okay.
Did they not have counters and sinks?
I guess they didn't,
did they have plumbing at that
point? It, you know, the Romans did
fucking Eden's banging each other in
the goddamn bathrooms there, whatever.
They eight til he had puke rooms
just eat until you fucking puke.
So I would actually think, well, at
the very least, even if it is flat,
the fact that there's
still water in the ocean,
there's gotta be land on the
other side holding it in. Right?
Okay.
But not all, Christopher Columbus, not
all crazy. It was like, no, fuck that.
I'm going to get to the West indies,
whatever the fuck I was,
I'm going to get to India.
I'm going the other way.
You fucking sky the balls to sail
out that way. Sales out that way.
And then he thinks, well fuck
these people must be Indian.
You know, that's just sort of like, oh,
are you Arab? I thought
you were Italian. I mean,
it's at that level of offensive, like, I
mean, would you really get that offended?
Like, no, I'm fucking Arab. How dare you?
Well, what do you got against Italians?
You can't,
sorry.
Anyways,
um,
speaking of which,
I don't understand all these people going
into ancestry.com why you would go to
a fucking website and let them take
a swab of your saliva. I get eight.
How fucking dumb or people,
okay.
Oh my God, I didn't realize,
you know, I'm also Swahili.
Whenever the fuck, why don't always
pick swell, Uli. I was taking Romania.
I didn't understand that.
We show so Hungarian. Great.
Now I know why I like Goulash
one eighth of the time.
Okay.
At this point is so fucking far removed
and I don't understand why people are
sitting there acting like there's any
sort of culture there. Is it all right?
It's just like what I saw
in the Greater Phoenix area.
There's a new patch of land, you
know, you fucking clear it out.
You put a bunch of houses
down and then you slam down
a fucking strip ball. Sorry, I
got to do this podcast before,
but daughter wakes up here. Um, yeah,
they slept on a fucking strip mall and
they just continue to progress that.
That's basically, you know, then
there's a cheesecake factory.
They get a frozen yogurt place and
that's what has become, okay. There's no,
there's no culture left. Is
there? I mean that is the culture.
I just sounds like one of the douchey
talk show right now, there is no culture.
Okay.
And this is what needs to stop. We have
to stop these strip malls. All right.
Do you have a solution? Uh, no I don't.
I just don't like cvs
anchored strip malls.
Yeah.
There was a bunch of people out the
other day, you know, you don't want,
you just have like shit to do.
I go Saturday, right. And, uh,
it's rained a bunch when we were out
here with some fucking idiot politicians
said the drought's over. It's like,
no, it isn't. It's never over.
It's just in a good place right now.
When is it going to rain again?
You don't know snow.
You going to let people go back
to taking long fucking showers.
I never do that out here.
Okay.
I shut, I turn it on and shut off
the water like fucking five times.
When I take a shower, I turn it on,
you know, get yourself wet, you know?
And then you shut it off,
set yourself up,
then you turn it back on, rinse yourself
off. He shut it off. And that's it.
So it says, standing there under
the cascading water, you know,
like he's some sort of,
God.
MMM.
Then I like to think a lot of people try
to do that. At least my wife does it.
She fucking turns a thing on his
fucking walking around, you know,
she's one of those chill people.
She hasn't,
she hasn't think about shit like that.
You know?
I guess what I'm trying to say is I'm
a better person in my wife and I don't
know how to bring that up.
If you guys know a good way to word it.
Like how can I basically say,
you know what it is honey.
I guess at the end of the day I'm just,
okay,
I'm just a better person than you are.
I just already pictured her
rolling her eyes anyways. Um,
the fuck was my point. All right. Yeah.
So Indians. Okay. That's like fucking,
yeah,
that's almost kind of funny.
Like now you're fucking dope.
You like 6,000 miles away
from what you think you are.
I guess it was probably funny at first
they started chopping people's arms off
cause they couldn't fucking get some
gold for the holes in his teeth.
And who the fuck am I to
say what's offensive way?
But you would think that red skin that
would be at the top of the fucking list
over bullets. You know,
it's the worst one.
The fact that the Tampa Bay
devil rays and now just the race,
you know, that's when you know you got
to move. That's when you just sit like,
wait a minute,
are there enough Jesus freaks in this
area that the local team has to appease
their, you know, hocus pocus bullshit.
I mean devil rays that isn't,
that isn't then that an actual name
of like some sort of sting ray.
I have no idea. Maybe
it is. Maybe it isn't.
All I know is that that
guy's first name is Liam.
It sounds too close. Like Lima,
like Lyme disease. Um, alright.
Devil Ray.
Hey, we go. Yeah.
Let me see here.
All I'm seeing is pictures of fucking
sting rays, giant ones with the fucking,
you know,
like they're flying through the water.
If somebody can explain to me how that
makes you move forward when they make you
go up to the surface.
Yeah.
Do these things a fucking gigantic.
They're bad ass
because I think it's getting there.
It's jumping out of the water
unless somebody's photo shopped it.
I got to go video now and they
just change it to the race.
Okay.
We're just to ray.
Incredible flying race.
So I guess devil ray was the nickname.
Protect Your Business Data from,
Oh Jesus Christ. I don't need a
commercial. I do the commercials. Not you
on the west coast.
On the west coast is always some fucking
English accent and the shock pluses to
BBC.
Sorry.
Oh, Jesus said, what are they showing
that I somehow I got a fucking Pelican.
Okay.
20 abnormally large animals
that actually exist.
This is how you fucking go down
aisle. You go down just like a, a,
what do they call it?
The go down the fucking rabbit hole.
Yeah.
Let's see. Come on man. Oh, that
was us. Stove was a school of a,
I'm an asshole. Right?
Is it fucking God. Good.
Okay.
Jesus. Those things are ugly as Shit, Huh?
All right. So there in a helicopter. I
imagine they're flying over this, uh,
this whole school of him. It's like a
fucking devil ray or gee, that's why.
I bet the other ones are like more like
a, what do they, what do you call it?
[inaudible] just monogamous.
These things are out of your fucking
the shit out of each other and the local
Jesus freaks down in Clearwater,
Florida. They couldn't have it.
They fly out of the fucking water.
They're not two graceful with the,
with the landing there.
All right,
I'll repost that fucking video in case
you want to watch that while you listen
to me ramble about it.
MMM.
Yeah. They changed it to the,
to raise the Tampa Bay rays,
the Tampa Bay devil rays.
Two syllables. Two syllables.
Okay. They went from four,
four time to three. Four.
They turned their fucking team into a wasp
bump. Bump, bump. Bump, bump.
Oh, I dunno. I didn't know what the fuck
I'm talking about. Can I, can I read?
Can I read you guys? You guys want
you to listen to me? Read out loud.
Hey everybody,
it's time to feel better about your
f the brain you are blessed with.
Okay.
Just sit right here.
Somebody explained to me why
it's not at the font I need.
I like a nice fucking 18
font. That's good for me. All right.
Oh, dollar shave club, everybody.
Oh Jesus Christ. There's no reason
to use a cheap disposable razor.
You stupid cunt.
Oh,
pay a ridiculously high
price for gimmicky,
for gimmicky thing that's got
a laser pointer with 17 blades.
You don't need to do it.
Make the smarter choice and join.
Do I always shave club
before dollar shave club?
It was either save money and get a
painful shave from a disposable like ones
they give away for free at the gym,
which felt like shaving with a piece of
glass or pay a fortune for the latest
gimmick. He shaped breakthrough. You
don't need like a laser chin detector
or has 17 blades.
As I told you before,
the sweet spot was two blades,
two plates was perfect.
Nothing shaved like the two
blade three blade stinks.
That's when it get the gets too big.
You can't get underneath,
you knows dollar shave club.
It's the best of both worlds.
Worlds a premium shave at a
disposable price. Get a close,
smooth shave every time.
God dammit.
If you can't beat the convenience
of the price of the club,
I don't know what the fuck it tell you.
You haven't tried dollar shave club yet.
You're missing out. It's an amazing
shave at an affordable price.
If you haven't figured that out yet, like
they haven't said at 27 fucking times,
are they saying at one time
for every blade you don't need,
there's no smarter choice on the market.
And right now they're giving away a one
month trial of any of their raises for
$1 with free shipping. And after
that, it's just a few bucks a month.
There's no long term commitments,
no hidden fees.
You know your girlfriend won't fuck
around on you and you can cancel whenever
you want.
Get your $1 trial@dollarshaveclub.com
slash [inaudible] that's dollar shave
club.com/bar uh,
is our friends.
Oh, here we go. It's sold zip.
Are you hiring?
Do you know where to post your job to
find the best candidates you don't to you,
but you don't want to admit it to anybody.
So when no one's around,
you put your head down to your desk and
you quietly crowdy yourself wishing that
you were a child again and your parents
were taking me out for an ice cream
because you can't deal with the
pressures of the world. Well, I got to,
I got a solution for you.
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
You stupid. Fuck. You want
to find the perfect hire?
What do you need to post your job on all
the top job sites and now you can with
Zip
[inaudible] dot com you can post your job
to 200 plus job sites including social
media networks like the
Facebook and the Twitter.
All with a single click
left that said single dick.
It's a fucking pervert with giant keys.
You know,
sticking his helmet on the keyboard.
Find candidates in any city or
industry nationwide. Just roll well.
Just post once and watch your qualified
candidates roll into ZipRecruiter's.
Easy to use interface.
No juggling emails or calls to your
office quickly screen candidates,
rate them,
judge,
put them in a box and hire
the right person fast.
Find out today why zip
has been used by fortune 100 companies
and thousands of small and medium size
businesses and right now my listeners,
my listeners and anybody else they sold
this to can post jobs on Ziprecruiter
for free by going to ziprecruiter.com/burn
that's ziprecruiter.com/bar one more
time. Try It for free. Go to zip
[inaudible] dot com slash burp all right.
How many more of these fucking things? I
got two more. Let go and hang in there.
Hang in there with me.
It's helix. Everybody.
Helux you're unique. You're special. No,
you're not.
You're drowning in mediocrity.
When are you going to find your voice?
When are you going to spread your wings?
Like a devil ray?
Come out of the water and deal with your
fucking eyeballs and hang out at the
side of your fucking head.
Come out of the water and show people
who you are and then belly flopped back
into it. All right. Your
unique. Okay. Yeah. There's
something about you, I guess.
You know, I guess if I talked to
your mother she could find something.
Yeah.
You don't walk like everyone
else talk like everyone else,
show Chet or sleep like anyone else.
Okay?
So why the fuck is your mattress one
size fits all they've ever thought about
this course you haven't.
Who the fuck has time to think about this?
Because it truly customized mattress
will cost you five to 10,000 bucks.
Jesus Christ as it come with
a couple of who is until now
go to hell, exceed [inaudible] sleep.com
and answer a few simple questions.
Do a saliva swab and they'll run a three
d biomechanical model modelle of your
body through the proprietary algorithms
they developed with the help of the
world's leading era,
arrogant nomics and biomechanics experts.
They're going to make a fucking robot.
That's what they're going to do it.
They're not going to do this.
I bet helix is going to fucking sell that.
That for fucking proprietary
algorithm of your goddamn nuts, sec.
And next thing you know,
there's going to be a fucking lifelike
robots walking around with an exact
replica of your junk,
but I'm going to tell you right now,
you're going to sleep like you never
slept before. All right. You know why?
Because Helen's customers,
he looks report at 30% improvement
in overall sleep quality.
Okay?
How they figured that out.
I have no idea.
How can you fucking take
notes while you're sleeping?
I guess when they wake up,
they feel you want,
if you want to improve your fucking
sleep by 30% lay off the booze.
You're fucking drunk. Save money on
the mattress. If you lay off the bump,
maybe this is the,
this is the fucking mattress for drunks.
So as much as you're hung over,
you offset it with this great mattress.
I'm going to get one of these things. And
for couples, Oh, now they getting freaky.
They customize each side of the
mattress. Ah, they went the other way.
They customize each side of the mattress.
You know,
that's for someone in a loveless marriage.
If you notice that your side
of the bed isn't, as you know,
if you're annoyed that your wife likes
soft of magic, that's fucking over.
And I liked the hard mattress.
That's it.
Just go start sleeping on the couch
and when she goes to bed, you know,
start trolling for Internet,
Pussy, social media.
And that's what you should do.
But anyways,
your mattress arrives at your door and
about a week and in shipping is 100% free.
That's why everyone from
Gq magazine to Forbes,
they're all talking about he likes sleep.
Alex,
you have a hundred nights to try it
out, grouse. And if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free to
day and give you 100% refund.
No questions asked.
I always picture Mr. White and Jesse
Pinkman showing up in a hazmat suit.
You know,
we're here for your mattress
and you won't even touch it at that point
yet. It's in the back. Good luck to you.
Go to helix,
sleep.com/burn and get $50 off your order.
That's [inaudible] dot com
slash bar one more time. Hey,
he looks sleek.com/burr.
Lastly, but not leastly.
MVMT watches the company started
by two broke college kids.
I never understood that line. Hey, we're
flat broke. You want to start a company?
Absolutely. Um, they wanted
to wear stylish watches,
but they couldn't afford them.
So they started their own watch company.
Did they just solve the homeless problem?
You know,
I'm fucking living outside.
I can't afford a house.
So I went out and I bought
one no more homeless guy.
How is this like how you started built
a following, launched into a podcast,
youtube, radio, etc.
Oh, I guess awesome. Oh,
you know what this reminds me of
when I started out like a comedian.
I didn't have any jokes,
so I,
I sat down and wrote something
that I went up on stage at a,
you know, I did. Okay. Does
that remind you of watches?
All right. Ooh, bit watches started
at just $95 at a department store.
I'm sorry, 95 movement watches
start at just $95. Dot Dot. Dot.
At a department store.
You're looking at four to 500 bucks.
Movement watches. Well move. It
figured out that by selling online,
they were able to cut out the middleman
and retail market. We figured it out.
Everybody knows that
Jesus Christ,
these guys are changes providing the
best quality price. Classic design,
quality construction,
and minimalism.
Over 1 million watches
sold in over 160 countries.
Okay,
that's almost 50,000
watches in each country.
Get 15% off today with free watches
and free returns by going to movement
watches.com/bar this watch
has a really clean design.
Seriously, I've been getting
compliments ever since I put mine on.
Now is the time to step up your
watch game. Go to movement,
watches.com/bar join the movement.
Now,
why the fuck would they say that
I'm walking around wearing them?
I would wear that if I was
like 20 years younger. Okay.
Yeah.
Let me tell you something.
If you're in your late fucking forties
and you can't afford a fucking,
you can't afford a decent, decent watch.
Cause I don't, I don't go for the flash.
You know what I mean? I
don't, I don't understand that
dead fuck. I mean, I get it.
I guess I get that Rolex thing,
that hacky thing.
I got a Rolex. As you can see,
I've made my dreams come true.
I'm a man in the world.
Okay.
You know, there's a lot of
guys out there, you know,
my dad always said a man should own
a nice watch. What else did he say?
And I get the fuck out of here.
I'm taking a shit. You know?
What else did he say that was so
fucking deep baby? You know what?
Maybe at a nice calm,
relaxed,
relaxing person in your life.
Maybe you did.
I'm always jealous of that.
When I see like calm families,
they've gotta be bored shitless though.
There's going to be, you know what?
I would actually be willing to guess
that the child that is more likely
to just go fucking nuts. You know what I
mean? Take out the family car, you know,
throw a hatchet over somebody's
head is going to come from a calm
family after awhile.
It's stupid. No it isn't.
Okay.
I'm just saying it's possible.
Just the fucking monotony of it.
I give it go to Disneyland and you
fucking worn out and then he just started
hearing.
It's a small world and it just keeps
going over and over again and you slowly
fill yourself, like
losing your sanity there,
right there is why I don't
believe in heaven or hell.
You know what I mean?
I just don't believe in it.
It doesn't make any fucking sense.
You know,
like if heaven was, if it was just
having the whole fucking time,
heaven would eventually become health
because it would just be so fucking nice
and everybody would just be walking around
isn't as great. Oh my God, it's gay.
Can you believe how great this is?
This is just fucking great.
It's quite like every fucking day, and
at some point you're gonna be like, ah,
it's fucking gray.
You know?
Like,
what do you do
for the rest of your fucking life?
You just sitting there and it's
always the same. It's just awesome.
It never rains. There's no
disappointments. There's no challenges.
There's no funny stories to tell anymore.
Hey,
you remember, remember, remember
that time when it was awesome? Yeah,
it's always awesome,
right?
Then if you're in hell, oh, I'm fine. No,
I'm fine. I've got, I'm, I'm fire. Uh,
fire after a while, you
know? Um, yeah, I'm on fire.
I can't yell anymore.
This just become normal.
I don't even remember what my fucking
life was like before it got here.
I Dunno. I guess how well you can
actually see how that would suck.
I said I just don't get heaven. I don't
want to fucking be like, you know,
at some point there's some apps to happen.
Um,
so as I'm riding around in my
fucking all angel white bicycle,
at some point you got to get a flat,
right?
Yeah.
Did immediately somebody would
be there to help, help you out.
They just be saying a bunch of Nice Shit
too. I would slowly just start crying.
I would just whisper at some point. You
like cheeses. I told chief as I can make.
I know. It's just weird. I understand.
I'm not, I'm not trying to be,
that guy's not appreciative,
but could you just say no,
cause you just call me
a cunt or something?
Could you fucking just slap
me with you the Sandal?
You know, can you just imagine the
look on his face as he just sits there?
You know,
not saying anything as you talk yourself
into a corner and she's sort of looking
at, you know, when people look at you and
they go from one eye to the other, right?
Or your left eye, your right eye,
left eye, and he likes his mother.
Motherfuckers trying to
get in my head right now.
The son of God is trying
to get in my fucking head.
Then you got to explain
it to the bosses son.
Why you don't like heaven? Not that you
don't like it, but it's just like, can,
can you make it rain
every once in a while?
Can it be that dog that's just fucking
barking right as I'm going to sleep? Come.
Can we just have that?
Does every fucking dog
have to behave itself?
Okay,
why can't I say that word? Jesus. Why
can't I say that word? My disrupted it.
What are you going to do now?
Send me down to hell. It's over.
I already passed the test.
All right.
Can somebody be annoyed?
What's fucking something up here?
Look at everybody looking at,
well,
okay,
these fucking God smiles on their faces.
It's creepy cheeses.
I don't know.
Would you want to fucking be like,
it's like you joined a cult,
all of these fucking, you know
what I mean? If I was running shit,
I would make religion illegal.
It would just be fucking,
I would just take it all away
from everybody, you know?
I will answer what I would do. I would
have, I would have a fucking crew, robots,
you know,
to infiltrate every fucking religion.
And then at,
when I made it illegal,
they would join the radicalized
people in every group. Right.
And then they would just
wipe them all out. You don't,
and then you'd have to listen to the
whining and the crying and people that
remembered fucking religion and all,
he just,
he just take the whole fucking thing
away. And the new religion is, hey,
I don't know what the fuck happens
after you die,
you know?
But you know,
let's be nice to each other
and then that's it. Okay.
No walking on water. No, never
running out of fish part and CS.
I don't know about anybody else's
religion. I don't know what the fuck,
but I know there's always some
fucking crazy thing that you know,
didn't happen and everybody
acts like it happened.
It didn't happen.
Who is painted on a fucking cave
wall and somebody elaborated on it.
Okay.
I Dunno, I get rid of
all personally. I'm just,
I'm just talking for myself personally.
I would get rid of it. Um, but yeah,
by the way, guess what I'm doing on
March 29th out here in Los Angeles.
All right. If you are, um,
if you're in Los Angeles and you're a
guns and roses fan and you like reading
their books about the band,
I've read every fucking one of them.
Um,
I read slashes,
I read Steven ad was, I read, uh,
the kid from canter's. Do you know,
knew the band, took all the pictures.
I have that fucking book.
And uh, recently, I dunno,
I dunno when she put it out,
but Deanna Adler, Steven
Adler, his mom wrote a book,
sweet child of mine. And, um,
especially if you, if you,
you should read this, you should
read Steven's first. You know,
you get his version of the hell he went
through as an addict and then you get
his mother's version,
which is unbelievable.
And you know what would be a fucking
amazing is if you could go down
and meet her at a book signing at Barnes
and noble at the Grove on March 29th I
believe it starts at 7:00 PM and you go
down there and you could fucking meet
the mother. The best fucking one of the
best dramas, the 80s my personal opinion,
and you know, it'd be even more
fucking amazing, is it followed them,
came on my podcast and I got
to interview him. Oh Shit.
Is there a special Monday morning
podcast coming up this week?
Wouldn't that be incredible? Why?
What would it be like if Steven Adler,
you guys all know how
much I fucking love him.
He's mother Adler and then
that brother Jamie had,
they're all came on my fucking podcast.
What would that be like? We'll be out.
Like if they all came on at the same
time and there was this big happy family
that just sat there
interrupting each other.
And you felt like you were at
their fucking dinner table.
How fucking cool would that be if
I did a podcast like that? Well,
it's going to happen. It already
happened. I already recorded it and um,
I'll wait till you guys
listen to it. But, um,
I had so much fun with them and their
mother is an absolute salt of the earth
sweetheart and she has
a book signing and um,
she's all excited slash nervous that
no one's going to show up, you know,
as you know, same way when
I put out a special, what if
nobody watches it? So I'm,
I'm going to be hyping this,
um, right up until March 29th.
Um, it would be such a great thing if
there was a bunch of people down there.
I'm going to be down there standing
in line with the rest of you is, uh,
probably get down there. I don't
know, probably like around eight ish.
They get starts at like seven,
but I'll be down there around
h just because I get it.
I get some fucking thing.
I'm taping right before, but, um,
yeah, I did a special podcast.
I get to meet Steven Adler and I'm
still fucking freaking out. And, uh,
and I'll,
I'll wait till you guys listen to the
interview and then I'll tell you all the
fucking cool stories. All right, here
we go. Let's, let's plow ahead here. Oh,
my Bruins beat the fucking fly as,
oh,
at that little fucking prayer of
his shot at the end. Not a prayer,
just put it on net.
Somehow it found its way to the back of
the net Bruins pickup by huge two points,
Bruins a playing great. Um,
and as are the Canadians,
which, um, I don't like the Canadians,
but I'm happy for Khloe, Julian, you know,
and uh, I'm actually, you know what?
I think the Bruins might have been right
to make a move at this point. I think,
uh, it's just one of those things
with coaching after awhile,
even if the person is great, even
if they won your cup, it's just,
it's just part of coaching. At some point.
They just show you the door. But, um,
we're playing great. We look a lot better
than we did. So I think maybe both.
It's worked out in the fucking Canadians
are playing better with Cloe. Julian,
all my friends in this
business who are have fans,
they keep texting me saying
that they love and the guy,
so I guess it worked out for everybody.
So there you go.
And Clode went from original fucking six,
two original six.
Um, there you go. All right. So
anyways, let's plow ahead here.
Um, let's read some of the,
uh, some of the fucking,
whenever you call them for this
week. The uh, the questions. Alright,
DDP Yoga. Hey Bill, first of all,
thank you very much for your
consistently amazing podcasts. Well,
thank you for listening.
Thank you for doing what you do,
sir. Or ma'am. I absolutely
love it. To be honest with you.
I feel like it's getting,
it's,
I feel like getting it
for free is too much.
I'd gladly pay five to 10 bucks a month
for all the content you're releasing.
You don't need to do that. I'm fucking,
I'm doing great with the advertising.
You know,
that's why I fuck around during the
advertising because that's how I fucking
make money.
But I know you guys are going to fast
forward to it unless I keep peppering it
with Fox and cons. That's it. It's
a very simple formula. Anyhow,
he said,
I want to get in touch and address
your self proclaimed dad bod.
Yeah.
Have you ever heard of
or looked into DDP Yoga?
Okay.
Uh,
if not,
maybe the name Diamond Dave
Dallas page rings a bell,
former WC, WWE wrestling wrestler
and all around. Great Guy.
After leaving the wrestling business,
he devoted himself to getting
his body back in peak condition,
even through wrassling,
even though wrassling is his quote fake,
it definitely takes a toll. Yeah. They
beat the shit out of their bodies. Um,
long story short,
he went from being a guy who wouldn't be
caught dead in a yoga studio to trying
it after all else failed to develop
his own system and helping thousands of
people completely revitalize their lives.
And I can tell you from
personal experience, it's
fucking great. No bullshit,
no fluff, no one's structures, structures,
calmly whispering about Schapera
alignment is that he say Chakra Schapera.
It's about consistently performing the
physical and mental exercises that will
have you operating at your best.
This is a commercial healing,
nagging aches and pains, increasing
your endurance gating, mental clarity,
et cetera. Like I said, no fluff.
Here's the video that got me to take a
chance on it. It's not too late for you,
Billy. I hope you'll check it out.
Thanks again for the God damn podcast.
All the best to you and your family. Uh,
that actually read like a commercial.
But you know what,
I don't give a shit.
It's a physical fitness thing and so
many people have taken yoga and done in a
different way. You know,
cause there is that thing.
If you really like a wound up psycho to
go into a yoga class and the tone with
which that they speak is a little jarring,
you know,
okay.
To be in your cargo. Oh you're
fucking caught the lightest weight.
You could have made it
okay
to then being like,
how is everyone feeling today?
I know the traffic was kind of bad.
I hope.
I hope you're not bringing
that energy in here.
Is it slowly walking around lighting
these smelly fucking things,
you know, and as you're talking
to the person next to you, just go
and immediately you just want to like,
I dunno,
just slowly roll up your mat
and just walk out. Like I can't,
like I get it, I get, I need to
chill out, but I can't feel like,
yeah,
you know,
you know where it just becomes like this
asexual thing wherever you were just
kind of like, hey man, was just kinda,
you know, everybody's just like,
we're all like one, you
know, we're like plants. Um,
that's a little fucking jarring.
I'll give it a shot.
I've actually been meaning to do it
because I keep having setbacks with my
fucking shoulder. Um, which
is really frustrating. But,
um, most of it is diet. So, uh,
whenever I get in shape, the first thing
I do is I cut out the booze and, um,
all I really need to, I need to
go like 46 days without any booze.
Even just having that one cognac
didn't really do anything.
Like I had the one and then
immediately my buddy's like, hey,
why don't we have 50 more? But I had
to go to the movie and then I was fine.
Um, and then the second I'm in there
and the bus starts to wear off.
I think I'll thank God I didn't have
15 more. Not to mention I got to drive.
Right. Um, I'm going to give it a
shot. I just think if I did yoga,
I did have to do in the morning
before the little one wakes up. Um,
she's so fucking awesome, dude. I'm
telling you right. You'll never regret it.
I guess you know when you'll get it.
If you have a kid with somebody
that you're not love with,
I guess that that would suck. But at the
end of the day, the kid is still awesome.
It's a hell of a door price, I'll tell you
that, right? Oh, I'll tell you. All right.
Trans wrestling. Hey there,
I'm already gonna Watch this.
If this is what I think it
is a there Billy boo. Ah,
did you hear the story about the Trans
girl going through home hormone treatment
who was still wrestling
girls in high school?
His slash her defense is that it's a
low dose of testosterone and it does not
allow for any competitive advantage.
Wait a minute. Isn't that what Hg
ages? That's human growth hormone.
Well, I guess I don't think human
growth hormone. I don't know why.
I don't know what kind of hormones
they take. Um, having said that,
I'm not sure I'd let my daughter
Rasul a girl who had any edge at all.
Even if it's a tiny bit of extra strength.
It could be the difference
in breaking a bone. Thoughts.
Would you let your daughter wrestle
in that situation? Uh, yeah. Yeah.
I would then take a break. A
fucking bone, you know what I mean?
How many times do people break a bone
and wrestling? Does that really happen?
They just fucking on each other
the whole time. It's like a,
you know, like that official level
shit. Not that, not the fun shit,
the stone cold shit that the actual
official college shit, it's like a,
it's like competitive spooning.
You know what I mean?
It's like one person is trying
to spoon with the other person.
The other person is like, I want to
be this, the Spooner, not the spoonie.
That's basically what's going on.
They don't like, you know. No,
I wouldn't be concerned about that.
Yeah.
I'm one of those debts.
Okay,
well the kids crying going away.
You know, she's already half a guy.
I'd be driving her. As far as I know.
She's still a girl, so suck it up.
You want to pay them?
Well then you gotta wrestle half of too.
That's a thing. I don't want
to hear another word out again.
I'd be like dead.
Okay.
Why don't you embrace the opportunity
to be like, well, here we go.
If this is actually a fucking advantage,
all this is going to do is make me better.
You know what I mean?
And then he could go up there and give
you a record 27 and oak against hundred
percent chicks
and wanted to get someone
who's happened to, right.
You got to with Bryce, it mean, what
does that person supposed to do?
There's not enough fucking people that
are going through what the fuck she's
going through to fit any of the side,
you know, I think it's, I think it's a
cool thing. Fuck it. Who gives a shit?
Look, there's already going to
be that fucking monster anyways,
so some woman's going to walk in there
and just going to be blessed with
frontier strength.
You know what I mean?
Chopping wood strength is going
to be that person anyways. Uh,
I mean I guess if she was actually,
if she was trying to get a scholarship
in a loss could potentially affect it.
Um, maybe. Yeah,
but I gotta be honest
with you. I think, um,
I dunno, I would visit father.
I'd be like cycle MLC. I you do.
This is actually an advantage.
This is a great fucking opportunity to,
you become a, for you to become a better
wrestler. There's no money on the line.
Who gives a fuck?
Let's go.
Let me tell you something,
brother.
Come this Saturday when my daughter
wrestles a good stat. Half a dude.
What are you going to do when these
pythons run wild on your eyes?
I get up for it. I wouldn't
give a shit. Fuck it. Um, yeah.
Many guys in Europe.
So the is from Yemen,
Yemen, Yemen, Yemen, and he,
how the fuck do you say that
guy in Europe. All right.
Hey Bill, I'm a Yemeni guy.
Who is better? I hope I'm saying
that right. No disrespect here.
Who's been living in Europe
for the past six fucking years?
Okay.
Although everything is going all right.
I want to ask your advice because
I can relate to your personality.
Hang on a second sir. Or ma'am, I want
to fucking figure out where the fuck.
I'm assuming you're from Yemen.
What is yeah.
Many.
What is a yummy whom to whom is a,
is a Yemenite. Oh yeah.
Why did that all disappear?
What is a Yemeni
come on.
Alright. Relating to Yemen or it's
people. Holy Shit. I was right.
Okay.
That's a nice flag. They got a nice
flag. I like just to three bars.
Okay.
I'm a big three bar
flag guy. France, Italy,
Ireland, Yemen. I'm all right.
What do you guys think of the new
Russian flag? I kinda liked the old one.
The old one was the shit all red
with that sickle. I thought the,
I thought that that one was fucking dope.
The new ones. All right. What is it? Red,
white and blue. Holy Shit. They got
the same colors as us. Is that one?
Is it something like that?
I Dunno that was watching this whole thing
about flatter me or putting poison in
these guys and shit.
Allegedly. I have no idea.
So watching it on 60 minutes so it's gotta
be true, right? Tick, tick, tick, tick,
tick.
You.
How many guys in your or I've been over
there for the last six fucking years.
I want to ask you a question
cause I can relate to personally.
My family has been living in a war
zone in Yemen for the past two years.
Our old house,
our old house there was bombed
and my father was inside,
but the lucky bastard came
out without a scratch.
I miss them and wish I could help them,
but that's kind of not possible now.
All right before the, I already feel like
this is going to be way over my head.
Before that I lost some good old friends
that I knew for more than 10 years
because of some stupid incidents was
beaten by a gang of more than 15 men in
Malaysia on a trip there for no reason.
And my two year ex girlfriend at the
time cheated on me with their current
boyfriend isn't fucking amazing.
This guy's from the other side of the
planet and then seek sex, same shit,
gang violence and you fucking girl got
sick of you and fucking bang somebody
else.
Yeah,
cheated on me with her current
boyfriend while I was on that trip,
I guess to Malaysia, it didn't have the
decency to break up with me before that.
She was my first, uh, you know, what
are you going to do? People are young,
they don't know how to break up.
So they wait til you go to Malaysia
and they fucked somebody, man.
That this is a time honored tradition
of how to break up with somebody.
All right, so if you're with your
first love, what have we learned?
Do not go by yourself to Malaysia.
I don't know how many times I
brought that up on this podcast.
You cannot go to fucking Malaysia. All
right. I just graduated from college.
I have a beautiful girlfriend, which I
love and feel blessed with what I have.
I know that I an asshole at
certain moments in my life,
but I changed a long time ago and
I'm still trying to be more honest,
clear and focus. Well,
welcome to the club, sir.
I'm currently looking for a job in Germany
and we'll try to apply after that for
a German passport,
which will make my life much easier and
allow me to start a company and sustain
myself without being dependent on others.
Exactly.
You want to work for yourself.
I know that you have lived certain moments
in your life where you are faced by
challenged, faced with challenges
that might have taught a lesson,
but at the same time left a
mark on your self confidence.
How did you empower yourself and what
advice would you give a young man like me
confronting life's challenges that said,
fuck face.
Congratulations on your baby and fuck you.
Now there's a guy,
okay,
who speaks at least three languages
and still is able to break balls.
Isn't that amazing? He's
probably speaks Yemeni, Yemenite,
Yemen, Asian, whatever the fuck he
speaks. Right? He's knows that one.
He's in Germany. So he's got his speak
that language on to via you in this space.
Right.
And he can also speak English.
MMM.
How did I empower myself?
Uh,
I used to just say shit out
loud to myself. You know,
when I would feel the dark cloud
of doubt coming in, I would just,
you know, and it took me a while,
but I would, I would, um, but I mean,
I wasn't facing what you are,
you're facing being an immigrant.
So I mean, you're facing way more
than I did in the, but the fact that,
uh, I know you're trying to become a
better person. You know what, you know,
to reach out for help and
all that. I, I think I,
my gut says you're going to be fine.
Well,
you have to do in general
is when the doubt comes in.
You got to beat the shit out of it. You
know you have to, the biggest thing is,
is that you're conscious
that this of the self doubt.
So once you're conscious of it, you
can then address it. It's when you,
when you're really young and
you're not conscious of it
and that thought comes in and then you
start dwelling on it and then it just
washes over your whole
body and you can literally,
you know,
have a fucking panic attack.
Would you have to do,
I did anyways is um,
okay.
You know, you try to cancel it
out with a positive thought.
I know this sounds like hokey shit,
but I used to just say shit out loud.
I read some book one where,
and it started off with like,
I would just be walking down the street,
you know,
walking by other people and I would just
really be just be like, yeah, fuck, fuck.
He looking at me like I was nuts,
but I was like,
fuck that negative thought man.
Wouldn't yell it. But I would,
I would kind of just say fuck that. Fuck
that. No, it isn't. No one has it, right?
No,
it won't or whatever the hell it was.
And then it just became like
when I moved to New York
and I'm trying to get into the clubs,
I knew I was going to get in.
But you know,
if the day to day just seemed like a
like impossible and you know, the club
owners and everything and you know,
some of them were cool and others enjoyed
the fact that you were desperate and
just really enjoyed that
position of power over you.
And I would walk out of the club dejected,
you know, I was afraid, you know,
am I going to run out of money?
I don't have a job right now.
I'm doing these driving back to
Massachusetts to fucking feature in Dick
Doherty's rooms that was not
barely covering, you know,
living in New York every time you stepped
outside your blue, 20 bucks, 30 bucks,
you know,
and um,
okay.
I just first started, I what I
said was, I'm tougher than you.
New York is still what I would say, as
Hokey as that sounds. That's what they,
you know,
the city would kick me in the balls and
then I would just mumble that to myself
sometimes,
like six times in a row
until I got that thought on my head.
And I would just say,
and then I would just pick,
I'm going to get in the clubs,
I'm going to get in and I'm going to
make a living. I'm going to be fine,
I'm going to be fine. Everything's gonna
be fine. Fuck that. Fuck that. Fuck that.
I mean something like that.
That's what I had to do. And um,
okay.
And then it just,
you know,
and that continues to rot your
fucking life and uh, you know,
then you get to my age, you know,
and I'm doing great and everything,
but there's also,
there's always your mortality around
the fucking corner and how I've kind of
mentally dealt with death,
the inevitable death is that like,
um,
that I just think it's going to be a
great experience. You know what I mean?
That, uh, I don't think anything bad
happens to you when you die, either.
You just go into the ground
and then that's it. And, uh,
then that's it.
You know,
you got to be a person on this planet
as opposed to like a fucking mosquito.
You got the best fucking experience.
Hopefully you did.
Um, and then that's it. It's fucking over.
Or did you become something else?
And I just don't think that is bad.
Okay.
You know,
I just don't think that it doesn't make
any sense that it would then just be bad.
Um, I don't know. I hope that helps
you. I got a little off the rails there.
So what I would say is
you just baby your way,
you know?
And like for me,
making it as a comedian was
like a 20 year fucking 15,
20 year process. I was obviously, I was
not the overnight, I didn't have the hook,
I didn't have any of that fucking
shit. And I just basically, every day,
you know, was fucking hacking at the
tree until it came down. And, um,
you know, you just don't quit. You
just, that's it. You just don't quit.
You don't give it a negative thought and
every day you just fucking take a few
steps towards it and then one day you
just wake up and your way you want it to
be and you're like, how the fuck did
that happen? He didn't. He was funny.
You don't feel any
different, you know, so, um,
but she'll be all right. I think
you're going to be all right. You know,
you speak three different
fucking languages. You can
break balls and English.
I mean you sound,
you sound like you've got a great sense
of humor and you're trying to get,
you're going to be fine. Just say that
to yourself. I'm going to be fine.
This is going to work
out and then that's it.
Then you can try to fucking help somebody
else out along the way. All right,
last one here. Documentary
recommendations. Hey.
Oh Billy. Oh Billy. Beat down. I was
wondering if you had heard of the,
this new documentary that just
came out called ice guardians.
It's about the history
of enforcers and hockey,
and I would love to hear your
take on it if you haven't seen it.
I watch all of these fucking
things. Um, I haven't seen it,
but I watched the trailer
and it looked great. Um,
I don't know about the name.
Ice Guardians.
That sounds somewhere between
a superhero movie and,
um, a musical, a musical on ice
coming to Madison Square Garden.
It's ice guardians,
Fossey hands skating around
the ice. Um, he said,
thanks for all the laughs and for always
making me feel better about the way I
read things out loud.
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself.
Here's the link to the
trailer. Okay, I'll,
I'll send out this link here
to the trailer. By the way. Um,
I'm going to be at the south
by southwest on Tuesday.
I'm flying in Tuesday.
I'm doing a podcast with Al Madrigal
for all things comedy network,
and then I'm a flying
right back out that night.
That's it. Boom. Doing a Putt,
landing, doing a podcast,
jump it back on the plane and flying back.
That's my dedication
to the goddamn network,
and also my dedication to fucking coming
back to see my daughter. That's it.
And after that, I got
three days, a Monday,
a Tuesday or Wednesday at
the Improv in San Jose Cruz.
Um, and I think that that's
my, that'll be my fucking, uh,
that'll be my month. That's it. All
right. Thanks. Listen to podcasts.
Go fuck yourselves. I'll check
in on you on Thursday. And,
uh, I think that's it. That is
it. All right. Go Fuck Yourself.