Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Berg.
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday, April nine, 2018.
How the fuck are you doing?
Huh?
Oh, that's good. That's good.
I just got back from Cincinnati
or as they call it, the Natty,
the night before I was in Pittsburgh,
or as they call it, the Berg
about a year ago. This time I was
in Cleveland, or as they call it,
the land.
I've always wanted to do a gig
in Akron or as they call it,
the Ron.
What is with that part
of the fucking country.
Okay.
What is Saint Louis?
They call it the Louis.
The Louie a welcome to the Louis.
Hey,
welcome to the walkie.
Yeah,
welcome to the in a older, not to
state Minnesota mean any, any odor.
Welcome to the Apolis.
Welcome to the Paul.
Now it only works with the Berg,
the Natty,
the land and I'll Belper the
Dosha and when we return,
we're going to be discussing the upturn
in the stock market. Um, you know,
it's funny,
I didn't give him shit about that at all.
Okay.
I didn't even think about that the
whole time I was there. I was still,
I was too fucking tired. I flew
in Thursday night so I could, uh,
get up early the next
day and go do a Wda d
okay.
With Randy and bill. And I went in
there, he and bag sitting there.
Okay.
Like the fucking headliner he is and
there's Joe Barton [inaudible] we had a
great time and I evidently I said
bullshit twice. And I said fuck.
Once I knew when I said
fuck cause everyone, oh Eh,
uh,
I'm such a foul mouth.
Freckled jerk off. I didn't even
realize it did it. I felt bad.
MMM.
Whatever.
I had a good time.
So I want to thank Randy and bill
for having me and all these years,
that's why sell tickets in Pittsburgh.
Pittsburgh was a very difficult ticket
to sell for a long fucking time.
You know, I used to work that
goddamn cavernous Improv.
It's not a comedy club, it's not
a theater. It's just a giant,
like they should have a
fucking DJ in there when it
was big rooms with no chairs.
Right. And the guys just starts spinning
and everybody's on fucking drugs,
whatever it is, say to actually, you
know, I've seen some of those djs lately,
I've seen some of those youtube videos
and you, they have little Casio keyboards,
you know,
to add to their beats.
MMM.
Do you think it's hard to play drums with
just your little fingers then actually
play drums?
You know what I'm getting sick of.
I'm getting sick of the one man band guy.
You know when they got that
little fucking thing where they,
they do,
they do a drum beat first and they add
the base and then they yell some shit and
then they fucking do something else and
meet how many people are going to do
that fucking act.
All right.
It's like I get it. You
have no friends. You know,
it's like the baseball kid for a musician.
The whole point of making music is
to go door with other fucking people.
Look if you're doing it at a high
fucking level, I don't, I don't mind,
but this does a lot of people on
youtube who just come, pull, pull, pull,
get,
get in and they had the thing and then
they're just standing there and they can
still hear his voice going. Pork, pork,
pork and also I'm going to turn this
into a song so I'm not going to make the
rest of the fucking noises.
All right.
You probably just used to like the
part of the podcast or
maybe that laughed there.
Put that over the top right and then
add your own stuff and then you have a
fucking ego. They make, make a
podcast team or whatever the fuck.
I was just dough it.
Um,
every time everybody flips the fuck out,
like holy shit,
I can't believe they just did that.
It's like musicians have been
doing that for years, haven't they?
I remember Steven Tyler way back in the
day when they had their making a pump.
He was on every fucking instrument in
there. I guess because we never saw it.
I don't know what I'm talking
about. Oh, this is one. I never,
I try not to do podcasts on days that
I flew on an airplane because they feel
like free me.
They're never funny.
They're always fucking scatter brained.
MMM.
Oh Man. We got me and partner
drove from fucking, uh,
an from Pittsburgh over to Cincinnati
I thought was like a three hour drive.
I always forget like that fucking the
conehead part of West Virginia is in
between that part of
Pennsylvania and Ohio.
And uh, I'll tell you, man,
I feel fucking life of me.
I do not understand the poverty of
that state. Pennsylvania is doing fine.
Ohio's doing fine.
And you'd just drive to that
little fucking triangle on the 70.
I was joking on stage. You're on your
drive by on the highway and you look off,
you see people like wave and asking
for help. You know what I mean?
Like fucking Willem Defoe and platooned.
Um, it's such a gorgeous state.
I don't get it.
Um,
I dunno. I think one day that, that place,
that place is going to turn around
the way downtown Cincinnati did.
I remember 10 years ago I did that funny
bone that's just across the fucking
river, the Ohio River in, um, Cincinnati.
I was in Kentucky
and I stayed there like, you want to stay
out in the Kentucky area is like, Nah,
I want to stay in downtown Cincinnati.
Won't be downtown where, where,
where shit is happening.
And I was at 10 years ago and it
was one of these fucking towns bed.
Everybody comes into work at eight and it
five, everybody leaves and it's, you're,
you're alone. There's nobody
there. There's homeless
people, there's people who,
who need medical, uh, mental
assistance, you know, crazy people
and all the stores is fucking closed up.
You gotta get your last meal by
three o'clock or you're fucked.
And um, I had been there, I
feel it feels like forever.
And um, I, uh, by immediately
the downtown area, if it's
fucking amazing, it's fucking him.
It's actually a whole article. The
second I got there, I was like,
this is not the Cincinnati that
I remember from that fucking Gig.
And that I carried with
me the next two times,
even though it was slowly getting better.
I had such a bad
experience the first time.
MMM.
They actually people right.
And fucking articles on it.
Where the hell is it, bill?
There you go. Cincinnati Streetcar.
They've got a fucking street car.
Okay.
By the time the first passengers boarded
Cincinnati straight current September,
it's advocates had already been on a
wild 15 year ride that included surviving
two ballot initiatives to
derail the project. Whatever.
I'm not reading all this boring shit.
They got all this fucking cool
stuff to do down there and now,
and evidently I was talking
to this guy in the plane.
They revitalized a bunch of bad areas,
but they didn't kick the people out.
Now this was according to a white
male in first class. So who knows?
Who knows what happens cause that's
what I'd like to see done, you know,
have that done.
And for poor white people too.
I never understand where it's
just like, oh, we're, we're,
we're making this area better. It's like,
what about the people that were there?
Yeah.
They would have made it better
if they had any fucking money.
Okay.
I don't understand why
like areas like that.
Okay.
This point, you know, we're doing all
these startups and all of this shit.
We ought to do it for our around fucking
country men should we then every place
is nice. Every way you go is a nice
little fucking cupcake area or whatever.
I don't know.
Do you think it then everything would
be the same because you already had that
fucking problem.
You know?
It has to be a way to go into different
neighborhoods of people and fucking help
out broke ass people.
Yet they still,
they don't lose their vibe,
you know, the music, the food,
the people, the whole fucking
thing. Because once like,
I dunno what's once,
what's the fucking people they want?
What's, why people come in and it just,
it just becomes white.
You know? It's be I,
I really don't even know
what I'm about right now.
I just don't understand West Virginia.
It's fucking gorgeous.
I don't know why people don't want to,
it's been a minor.
The only fucking job is that why,
you know,
they see the people that
mining isn't that fucking
honey booboo from their fucking
dirt floor cab and she grew up in,
so one of the saddest things I ever was,
I tried to watch the show one fucking
time and they were going down the grocery
store and they were having an auction on
food that was at the grocery store that
they no longer could legally sell.
They weren't even buying shit that
at least you used to be healthy like
perishable shit,
like fruits and vegetables,
which God knows what the fuck they
sprayed it with. Right. They will,
they will fucking bidden on like
a double stuffed Oreo cookies.
It's like they've already expired
and they're not good for you.
And she's sitting there looking like
Haystack Calhoun. I mean, what, what,
what the fuck do you went out? Here's
a question. What do you do with that?
You know what I mean?
That's just like, I mean, it's just a shit
show in and already fucking procreated.
So now you've got half of
that and somebody else,
maybe there'll be half as stupid.
Okay.
Maybe some smart person got drunk and
fucked her. That's the best thing you can,
you can hope for and knocked
down her stupid by 50%. Right.
Because certain people you see, they're
broken. You just like, all right,
well maybe if they had some opportunity,
then there's other people.
It's just like, Nah, you know, even
if she was born rich, I just don't.
Then once the parents died, I think, uh,
I don't see that fortune and
let's look up honey fucking booboo.
Oh, honey booboo was the mom. No,
that was the kid and he booboo mother.
Okay,
come on. Internet Mama. June, Mama.
June of here comes honey boo boo.
Famous for raising Padgett prisoners upper
uh, where the fuck is she
from? Amazing weight loss.
Jesus Christ. You know, when people are
really fat and they lose all that weight,
then they get it figured out what
they're going to do with the skin.
Then they then they need to do a startup
to get rid of the skin, right? I mean,
Jesus Christ, you need an extra startup
just for the shit underneath her chin.
She has had an unfortunate
thing where it like, you know,
it's like your chin is flushed with your
chest and she's way too young to have
that level of a double chin.
And that's what happens.
People when you go down
to the gross to her,
because she's so fucking
broke and you have to,
you have to bid on already
expired double stuf Oreo cookies.
Her neck is full of the cream. That's
what it is. I know. It's disgusting,
isn't it?
Okay,
but you know what? In this day and
age, I imagine she's a hero. All right,
so let's see. Let's see her loss. She
lost a bunch of weight. Good for her.
Good for her.
Now she's going to live longer.
You know what they should
have with the facelift? They
should also fucking,
they should have fixed her.
I know this is harsh people,
but there's too many fucking people.
There's too much traffic.
Okay.
You can't have dumb people like make it
more fucking people that are going to be
out there on the road,
you know,
and the DNA is full of fucking expired
Oreo cookie double stuff. He just Gig,
he can't fucking do it.
Okay.
And this is the thing that liberals
cannot handle and conservatives go too far
with.
Okay.
There has to be a feel good solution.
What would you do? I would just say,
listen, if you're, if you're dumb
and you don't have kids,
the government will give you Oreo cookies
that have not expired. How about that?
We'll start with is that as, as as a,
as an, uh, taxpayers will pay for that.
That'll come off the top
right.
I don't know how to solve this. I
mean, what the fuck I'm talking about?
I can't tell you this. Guess what
the fuck I'm doing on April 13th.
I'm going to be in shock.
Okay.
North Carolina at the rough
and rowdy and vet a event.
Um, I cannot fucking wait
for this. I think I got the
suit then I'm going to wear,
um, I'm very excited and,
uh, I'm going to be there.
It's going to be 1599. If you order
now 1999, the day of the event,
I'm going to be commenting
the entire night. God willing,
I'm going to be there with Al Pres
Day Portnoy and the big Cat d uh,
Dan Katz. And guess who's fighting
on the card? The one man thrill ride.
All right. He's not
wrestling, he's fighting.
He's not wrassling he's fighting and
he's going to show why he's an absolute
savage and I can't fucking wait.
I'm very excited for this event.
I hope I add to what and uh,
bring some more humor to it and check
it out. 16 bucks the fuck. Do you care?
What do you do with these 16 bucks?
Go down their bed on some cookies.
Um,
okay.
So anyways, I had a great flight back from
Cincinnati. Congratulations, by the way.
I'm very excited for Cincinnati.
I have to watch. And Pittsburgh,
they hold downtown areas start
to get going again. Alright.
Cleveland's made a huge comeback.
Cincinnati has made a comeback.
It's fucking tremendous.
I hope this keeps happening because
I've been on the road since the 90s and
those places were really sad.
And I remember in 2004, um,
when nick costs is opened hilarides I
remember looking across the street and
talking to one of the comics here,
seeing if I had money,
I'd buy the fucking [inaudible]
building right across the street.
And it was just like this beautiful
building that was just empty,
just fucking empty.
And hilarides were the only lights on,
on that block.
And I would finish my show and the cop
would walk me to my hotel around the
corner to make sure I didn't get
jumped or anything. Right. So,
uh,
and here we are now,
like that whole street now is lit up
like the fuck and Bullwinkle shelf and a
band. If I was where I am now, back then,
I would have invested in all of those.
And I want to do invest in Detroit
now that's fucking coming back to.
But I still might do that.
You know,
I think that's a great thing to do by
a fucking in an up and coming city that
needs some money in there.
You buy something there and
you don't kick the people out.
And He'd give them a nice safe
place. You know, they pay in ramp,
the fuck did these fucking assholes.
They redo these things and
then they kick everybody out.
Then they try and flip it,
you know,
this fucking heartless cunts that'll go
into some beautiful building and just
gut the place and come back
with like home depot bullshit.
Um, and then kick everybody out
and try to get fucking, you know,
20 and 30 somethings in there.
I Dunno,
I'm against it personally, but then
again, I never tried to do it. Who knows?
Who knows?
Maybe someday I'll become a slum lord.
I don't know what the fuck
I'm going to do. All right.
Anyways, plowing ahead here.
Uh, so my flight back, I overslept,
but fortunately the airport was right
down the street and a cruise through
security and all that shit got
there in plenty of time. And, um,
I get on the plane and a Delta Airlines,
I would slide different airlines.
I'm not fucking loyalty any of them,
cause I never used the fucking miles.
All right?
I have no interest in getting on the
phone, trying to figure out, you know,
when I can use them. You know,
I don't give a fuck. Keep,
keep the fucking miles.
What am I George Clooney and that
fucking movie up, up in a way,
um, uh, up in a way. Hey,
with my salt and pepper,
perfect. Five can, hey,
you know, I love most about that
movie. I'm going to ruin it.
Here is when he finally finds love and
he comes and he finds out that woman's
married and she looks at him like,
get the fuck Outta here.
And he has to get the fuck out here.
That was one of the realest things
I've seen in a movie, you know? Well,
that's how it usually works out.
You know, something happens.
Um, so anyways, the, uh,
why would I say that?
Why would I, why would I put that
sort of negativity out there?
Only because I'm a cunt? That's right.
Uh, so I get on the plane and uh,
I made sure I told my half to take
the f one race from Bar Bardeen and,
uh, get on the plane. Lone and behold,
I have ESPN two and I'm like, Holy Shit,
the fucking racist coming
on at 10 past 11. Right?
So I sit there and I'm watching
fucking ESPN, which is hilarious now,
you know what I mean?
Every sports talk show now it seems
like a woman has to be like running it.
And then the guys are sitting there like,
she's the teacher now,
just like the overcorrection,
you know what I mean?
So now like a guy can't run a show, I
don't, I don't fucking get it right.
So I'm watching this shit and
they show this woman from the, uh,
women's hockey team throwing
out the first pitch.
Instead of throwing out the first pitch,
she uses a hockey stick and she takes
a fucking risk data and sends it to the
catcher and the guy comes out
of his crouch and he catches it.
It was a fucking ball by the way.
So there's a woman and a man commentating
on this fucking shit. She goes,
see that? You see it,
you know, most, you know,
a lot of the dudes can't even get it over,
you know? That's why I'm telling you,
women are just better. They're just
better at things. And the guy's like,
little buddy though, the elbow, you're
going to say anything. She goes,
that's right. You got a
wife and a daughter. It was
just like, what in the what?
What the fuck was that?
Just imagine
that conversation and you flipped the sex,
the guys saying that to her.
Hey,
you see that most of broads can't get it
over the plate guys are just better at
Shit. Right. I'm not even gonna
say anything. That's right.
You got a husband and almost slap
the shit out of you. You dumb bitch.
All right, dumb bitch. I put a
little bit too much mustard on it,
but that's basically
what the fuck they said.
And then she came back
again and she said it again.
MMM.
Which is hilarious. And I,
uh, you see that a lot now.
Yeah.
And, um, at first it bothered me. Then
I'm just like, this is actually just,
it's not coming from a place of strength
that's coming from this really insecure
place. Like, right. See, we can
do stuff. Nobody said you kid.
I guess they did back in the day, but
nobody now is saying that. I just,
I can't know. Every guy has set
up his tail between his legs.
I wish I was commentating,
whether it'd be like,
that's astoundingly
ignorant and reverse sexist.
What are you talking about?
Yeah,
I could fucking do what she just did.
If he gave me three tries,
it's a fucking wrist shot with a baseball.
You got a teed up on a mound.
I don't even play hockey.
I think you give me five attempts.
I think I could fucking do that.
But you know what's funny is
if I went in and I failed,
that woman would feel justified because
a standup comedian couldn't get a
baseball nut 90 feet or 45 feet,
whatever the fuck it
is with a hockey stick,
that would be considered a
victory, I guess. I don't know.
So then I'm still watching.
Right? And then they had
this really weird commercial,
you got to see this one.
I actually wrote it down in my
phone so I wouldn't forget, uh,
where am I getting the notes?
Women are just better.
They're just better.
I was fucking around with that this
weekend where they just sit there going,
you know the, the, the future is female.
Like all guys are just going
to step aside. You'd have
to, we built everything up.
We're just going to give
you the airplanes. Go Fuck
Yourself. Earn them. Um,
I'm with you ladies,
but she knows something. So here's how
you divide and conquer the cool ones.
Know what I'm saying?
All right.
There's a commercial out right now that
you have to see for new genic that has
the big hurt in it.
And I swear to God he standing there
cause he lost all this weight and this
woman standing there with this guy who
I assume that kind of together, right?
She goes, he says something. Oh Wow.
Is that the big heart? She says, wow.
He looks okay.
Think that's the big hurt.
She said she should call a call.
Like the big handsome or
some she compliments on the
way he looks and then the
guy rather than being like the fuck you
looking at another man for and commented
it and in front of me, fucking disrespect
me like that and this grocery store,
you know, is this something I need to
know? Instead of saying that he just goes,
yeah, he kind of agreed with her. Right.
Then they get over there and I that this
is really weird conversation with it,
talking about this stuff that helps you
lose weight and every and suddenly makes
you a fuck better. I swear to God the way
the dialogue when I don't, I, you know,
I couldn't write it down fast enough.
I thought in the end the dude was
going to ask big hurt to fuck his wife.
Listen, I dunno. It might,
maybe it's me. Maybe it's me.
Maybe all of this is playful and I just
have to disease to fucking mind and
that's how I'm seeing this shit, so
don't take it seriously. All right.
Speaking of disease mine. Um, April,
I am going to be no vice
Billy, no vice, no drinking,
no smoking cigars,
no online porn,
meditating, yoga, working out,
eating right, drinking water,
all of that fucking little house on
the prairie shit. Okay. And I am,
when you hear this, I'll be
nine days in. All right. Oh,
Billy, no, vice hashtag Billy. Nice, Nice.
Billy boredom. What else? Oh, William.
Without a fucking,
I'm almost halfway through the month.
Um, no, I think I'm gonna try
to go to my birthday, right?
I'm going to go to my birthday,
you know, get myself, you know,
in the shape I want to be. And so turn
50, you know, a 50 wasn't bugging me.
Now all of a sudden, now that it's
like two months away, as of today, no,
as of Tuesday, it's two months away.
It's starting to fucking hit me,
even though I know I'm not
going to feel any different. Um,
it's just that you can kind
of lie to yourself through
your 40 set, you know? Nah,
Nah. You know, I look good for my age
above. When you turn 50, you fucking old.
You fucking, you're, you're, you're
even old to people that are old.
Okay?
Like somebody 70 would love to be 50, but
they're not looking at you like, like,
you know, they're not
pick the, they'll take 50.
You know what I mean? But if, if you know,
okay,
nobody's picking that age. If they rubbed
a genie lamp and a genie comes out,
what age do you want to be? Nobody
saying 50. Even if you fucking 120,
um, was getting who don't be seen 40 or
30. I don't want to get the fuck anyways.
Um, so, uh, it's been going,
God spend going good.
I like not drinking.
I guess I do,
but I dunno if you go to Pittsburgh,
Pittsburgh's just the town. You just
like, fuck man, I'm getting drunk.
How do it or not? This is
just, it's too amazing.
We went to the Primanti brothers,
however the fuck you say it,
you know, we went to the place, the,
the Italian market, uh,
part next favorite one.
We get the Gabba wool.
Why the guy that got all of
that and they just, you know,
was eating that all fucking
weekend stuffed olives.
I ate like a fucking lunatic, but,
um, I didn't need it at night,
so it wasn't that bad.
But I definitely did not eat healthy
over the last couple of fucking days.
But anyways,
but I didn't booze,
I didn't smoke and in both towns had
cigar bars and I had to walk by them.
And on the plane ride home I was watching
top 10 tight ends of all time and they
got to Mike Ditka and he was talking
all this shit. And then he just took,
you know, fucking, you know, a
couple of Poles off this fat cigar.
I was just like, ah, fuck, fuck,
but I'm going to get a, we're
going to make it. I Dunno.
I Dunno.
You know what it is.
It's like everyday I wake up and I don't
miss not doing heroin because I never
did it. And that's the thing, like they
say, once you open the Pandora's box,
all Fox speaking in that
shit, you know, that, um,
you know, that's ACDC songs, Sin
City. And when they do the breakdown,
when whatever the fuck, I can't remember,
I can't remember the baseline of that.
But boom,
boom,
kick drums on too, which is weird. Um,
and then bond Scott
goes lattice and snakes.
That is guilt snakes take right now.
He's always like it. What is he saying?
That lat ladders, ladders
and snakes. Liars.
Sounds like he's saying ladders
like something you'd climb up.
I never knew what the fuck it meant.
Did I tell you guys to see how the,
I can't remember it. Mike. Devin
told me he goes, no, it's, it's a,
he said that's in Australia.
That's like chutes and ladders.
But the original was called ladders
and snakes. And then I looked it up.
It's actually from India, if I'm
right. And it has to do with, um,
vices and virtues and it's
called snakes and ladders.
So she played sorta the same board game of
chutes and ladders. Right. So, you know,
if you get on a snake that's a vice
and you slide down the land on a snake,
I should say you slide down. But
to go on a ladder, that's a virtue.
And virtue is bring you up.
So, uh, basically, you know,
after years of sliding down and device,
I'm now going to try to go up a couple
of floors on the ladder, I guess.
I don't fucking know.
I don't know what I'm doing.
All I know is every once in
a while I got to shut down,
but every time I have to shut it down,
like the window is shorter.
Basical hard for 10 months and
then shut it down for a month.
Now it's like I go hard for two,
three months and then I shut it
down for like four or five. Um,
I dunno. I don't know. Could he hit it?
Just all the comedy just left at
this fucking podcast. It's just,
it's just not fun. It's not fucking, I
don't give a fuck. People have, yeah.
I fucking love being sober.
I love being sober. You,
I'm sitting next to this fucking guy
that one of these guys that says, yes,
that's the worst when you're sober. Okay,
I get you something to drink. I'm like,
yeah, I'll have a water. And he
goes, I'll have a bloody Mary.
Like fuck, I love of bloody Mary. He
finishes his bloody Mary, which she goes,
would you like another one? He's
like, yeah, how about you sir? Nah,
I'm fine with my water. I was
just clock in this guy, right?
I flew out.
Another guy had a jack and coke
that he got the fucking meal.
You don't think got another jack
and coke and the lady said, Hey,
you want some ice cream?
Right? And he's like, uh, yeah,
but can I wait? She goes, yeah, the letter
you had the ice cream, you said? Yes.
The entire fucking flight is,
I sat down, just have a water.
Um, anyways, plowing ahead. By the way,
that's what you can look forward to.
He worked your ass off.
You sit at the front of the plane,
they bring your ice cream.
Like it's a figure of fucking two
year old. But here's the thing that,
here's the thing.
All right?
You die sooner because you're up there
eating and drinking like a fucking
asshole. All right? At least if you're in
the back, you know what I mean? You back,
they're starving, but you're
going to live longer. All right.
And the worst thing is to write up
front and be sober and watching somebody
acting like they're in
the fucking Roman empire.
And you're sitting there
drinking fucking waters
or s INA said salad. Um,
anyway, so let me do this.
Let me do the fucking, uh,
the reads for the week here.
What do we got here?
Have any advertising left on this
file? The black tops, everybody,
the black talks like the
Ohio state or the land,
the Natty, the Berg, the black
Tux for more than a year.
Now I've talked about the black tux.com.
The black Tux never gets old because
they always have new and exciting styles
for your next big event.
Ooh, look at that lapel. Hey,
I your cumber bun,
whether you're going for a stylist,
stylist selected outfit
or building a custom look,
the black talks has tons of new
suits and Tuxedos to choose from.
I thought it was for fat people,
tons of new suits and Tuxedos to
choose from for your big spring event.
The Black Tux, they black Tux is
always changing up their looks,
making it fun to try out
different suits and Tuxedos.
Even if you have your own suit,
switching to be black Tux
is always a great idea.
And what their new fit algorithm,
one of the most overly used fucking words
in the English language are algorithm
in other,
you know how they all have
a fucking algorithm because
you gave your information
at cvs, she got your fucking retina scan
at the airport and they all share the
information.
So now they have an algorithm on what
the day of fucking three d model of your
if goddamn skeleton. Now here's what
the mouth breathing more and says, yeah,
you know, I don't give a fuck
as long as it Tuxedo fits. Um,
Jesus questions I think in Atlanta on
my fucking house, the black trucks,
um, and within I would
been their fit algorithm.
You don't have to
awkwardly measure yourself.
How is it awkward to measure yourself?
See how they was trying to make it
seem more easy. Just measure yourself.
You'd dump content simple or ask a friend
for help. That's when it gets awkward.
The, I guess, you know, it's kind of hard
to, it's not awkward. It's difficult.
I see what you're saying.
Then your roommates a guy and all of a
sudden he's going to measure it in scene.
Yeah. Know the back of his hands
touching the underneath the ball bag.
You know what? I take that back. Thank
God you have an algorithm, you know?
All right.
The Black Tux does it for you.
Plus the black Tux is free home.
Try on,
let's just see the fit and feel the
quality of your suit months before your
event. I always think that's
dangerous. Months before your event,
you try it on and then what?
You fucking go out boozing and
it doesn't fit your person.
You come upon there after ordering
your suit. After ordering your suit,
will I never, I always blogged
commas after ordering your suit. No.
After ordering your suit will arrive 14
days before your event and remember how
simple returns are where it turned heads.
Then send it back three days after
your event. Shipping is free.
Both ways. Standout at your
event for the right reason.
With the Black Tux where it
just ship it back. Good Lord.
It can imagine the Hazmat suit they're
wearing when they take that thing back
during prom season.
To get $20 off your purchase,
visit the Black tux.com/bird that's
the black tux.com/bar for $20 off your
purchase.
Just
the black tux.com premium rental suits
and Tuxedos delivered simply safe.
Here's why I'm a big fan of simply
safe home security. Evidently,
simply safe is prepared for
anything that gets thrown at it.
Uh,
if a storm takes out your power,
simply safe is ready and
intruder cuts your phone line.
Simply safe is ready.
Say they destroy your keypad or a siren.
Simply safe.
We'll get you the help you need.
They come running up your front
door with a fucking chainsaw on.
Simply safe is ready.
Sure. Maybe it's overkill.
Maybe you don't need to be ready
for every worst case scenario,
but that's what makes simply safe
home security systems. So great.
It is always ready. Simply save. Could
cost an arm and a leg, but you know what?
It does it instead. The
only chick you, you'll,
they only charge you
what's, what's fair. Sorry.
24 seven professional security
monitoring is just 1499 a month.
It's only a dollar less than the
fucking barstool event. Rough and rowdy.
Look at that. Cross promoting. There
are no contracts, no hidden fees.
I recommend simply safe to everyone
I know you got to check it out.
Go to simply say bird.com
that's simply safe.
bird.com to protect your
home and family today.
Simply safe bird.com and lastly,
but not leastly are old friends.
They'd been with us since the beginning.
This might be out my first advertise if
I could remember and they've never had a
fucking problem.
All right,
salt of the earth stamps.com create your
stamps.com account in minutes online
with no equipment to lease
and no long term commitments.
Click print mail and you'd
done key words and descriptors.
Convenient, easy, reliable, efficient.
stamps.com brings all,
am I supposed to work those in stamps?
DOTCOM brings all the amazing services
of the US Postal Service right to your
fingertips by or your toes.
If you don't have any arms,
you have a salespeople
with born with no arms,
how flexible they are
shooting bows and arrows.
They can use this shit to um,
buy in,
print US official what? Buy and print
official US postage for any letter,
any package,
any class with mail using your own
computer and printer stamps.com makes it
easy.
They'll send you a digital scale automat
that automatically calculates the exact
postage stamps.com we'll even help you
decide the best class of mail based on
your needs.
No need to lease an expensive postage
meter and there are no long term
commitments.
I use stamps.com whenever
I'm sending out my posters,
I'm a moron if I can figure
out how to do it. God dammit.
So can you all right when I use it,
I really find it so easily,
conveniently,
reliably efficient and right now,
um, absolutely no negative references
to the post office. Okay, got it.
I will not say one bad
thing about the post office.
And right now you too can enjoy the
stamps.com services with a special,
that includes a four week trial
plus postage and a digital scale.
Go to stamps.com.
Click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinbirdthatstamps.com
enter
ber. Ah, right. That right there.
That was textbook fucking advertising
reading. Oh, did I? So anyway,
so I watched the fucking f one race.
Congratulations to Max for stabbing.
Congratulations to the Ferrari team.
Uh,
I don't know what the
fuck's going on in the pits.
I hope that guy from Ferrari as our
right. You know, he broke his leg.
Um,
what's his face?
Okay,
what the fuck's his name?
Kimmy something or other?
Kimmy Rigatoni,
the other guy in the fucking Ferrari team.
I thought I had thought I
fucking knew his name. Anyways,
he comes in for a pit stop and they'd
been having all these problems like the
house team,
both their cars last,
the previous race in Australia.
Um,
sorry,
I'm typing this in here.
They fucking went to go change the tires
and they didn't get them on properly
and they left and the cars were unsafe
and they both got knocked out. Oh,
Kimi Raikkonen he came in for a pit stop.
They didn't put the
right rear one on right,
or they didn't get it on in time
or they thought it was done.
I don't know what the guy with the
Jack lets the fucking car down.
I don't know who fucked up.
There's like 40 people that run up to
the car and they're all dressed exactly
the same.
And when he went to drive out the guy's
fucking dead giant back rear tire went
right over this guy's fucking
foot and leg and uh, you know,
and he's sorta peeling out too.
So Jesus Christ so that not
their car out of the race.
Lewis Hamilton had a great race, started
at ninth, got all the way up to third,
got to the podium.
What's his face Max for stabbing,
accidentally crashed into him or whatever.
And Lewis Hamilton once again,
fucking wine and about it
said Max is a dickhead.
It was a dickhead move. He wasn't
showing them any respect out there.
It's like Louis,
he's doing what you did when you came up.
What's he supposed to do? But they
all, my God, that's Lewis Hamilton.
I'm not going to try to beat
him through this fucking turn.
I didn't have a problem what he
did and neither did the judges.
So what's the problem? He had this
whole fucking thing where he's saying,
you know, he was disrespectful. It was
a dickhead move and all of that. A,
I don't know that guy. That
guy is, I totally respect him.
He's a fucking amazing driver. But I swear
to God, if he doesn't win, he fucking,
he's always bitching about something.
He reminds me a Peyton manning early
in his career we had protection issue,
you know? Oh, he's
fucking finger pointing.
Well, you know, by radio
wasn't working is you?
Little is very difficult to Jody for
Europe. We know supposed to drive or
not have you done enough of these?
There's somebody in front of you,
go get them a bill. It's a little
more sophisticated than that.
He was out in the mediums and the other
guy was on the super soft anyways,
it was a great race. I'm just fucking
with the Lewis Hamilton fence.
Fucking relax.
I'm just fucking around.
I know he's your Beyonce and I'm gonna
have to deal with the fucking, the uh,
the Louis Hive coming at me.
Um,
I don't know. I make fun of Lewis
Hamilton cause he is the best. The guys,
the best Mercedes last
year was the fucking best.
The last couple of years they'd bend the
God damn best and I'm new to this sport,
so what am I gonna do? Am I going to jump
on the bandwagon? I can't. I'm actually,
I'm ruined. I root for
Haas. The American team,
we, we kink Kevin Magnuson came
in fifth place. That's 10 points.
Mother fuckers fortunate.
Our other driver,
Romaine like the lettuce garaging,
however you say his name, he came in 13th.
It was a great fucking race
and I hate to say this,
ESPN to their coverage of that
race was fucking phenomenal.
It was phenomenal. And I got, I
got to kind of knock a little fuck.
I got to not fuck sports a little bit
cause they just used to just follow the
leader, whoever it was leading.
They were just up there.
And then while the racing was going on
in the back and forth, fifth, sixth,
seventh, eighth, like the level
that ESPN two was covering the race,
um, and showing that all that
passing and like, you know, when,
when anybody gets a good, it was a good
driver gets to get some sort of penalty,
a gearbox penalty or whatever.
Um, and they move back.
You don't get to watch him come
to the field in these past years,
the way ESPN, you know, was
following Lewis Hamilton coming up.
It was fucking great. I
love the race. Now granted,
I don't know shit about racing and I
watched it on the back of somebody's
fucking chair on a,
on a flight.
I could barely tell how many laps will
left saw I imagined I missed a lot of the
drama.
But I went back and I looked at that.
It's just like Max step and you can see
he's, he's going to be one of those guys.
He's probably going to win a championship.
He's really young.
He's a great driver and he's got balls.
You know,
it takes a lot of balls to go into
a term with Lewis Hamilton. Be like,
fuck this guy. I think I have position
could fam. Unfortunately, you know,
it's fucked up his car. I Dunno.
I think Lewis has a little scared,
you know, he reminds me
of, it was like, when I,
you see that that interview in Milton
Berle is trying to get Richard prior to
fucking, you know, stand down
because Richard Pryor has the
nerve to fucking laugh at him.
And then Milton Berle does that. He
goes, I'll give you some advice. He goes,
picky spots maybe.
And then Richard goes,
all right sweetheart,
if fuck you would you invent comedy?
He didn't go fuck yourself. I'm funny too.
That's how I feel. Max Verstappen deck.
He's a fucking race car driver. It's
supposed to fucking get out of the way.
That's not reason not raising anymore.
I was just driving around.
I fucking do that for red bull team.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
Fucking now Daniel Ricardo,
Aka Riky Rican and [inaudible] fucking
nice car just died for stamps and after
he tried to pass Lewis Hamilton, what?
He's tire went out as differential,
get all fucked up but a whatever that's
opening the doors for the American
racing team. Haas, we were
doing great in Australia too.
We couldn't put tires on.
It was fucking hilarious watching our
pit crew coming out there was so god damn
nervous
they came out with like laces out energy.
But it was a great race in our next week.
Everybody,
the Moto GP race I think is
next week. You get, yeah, it is.
Is it?
No wait, is it in two weeks? Was
the impending I've been one today.
If there was one today, I fucking recorded
it. Hang on a second. Hang on a second.
I was trying to go to that one and uh,
after I do,
Nashville is trying to go down to Austin
and go to the race. I just, I got a kid,
man, I can't fucking do that. If
I was in Austin I would do it,
but I'm not going to fly out of my way.
And not hang out with my kid.
What am I a fucking degenerates. Ah, yes.
I'm not that big a degenerate though.
All right. Moto GP, come on. Load load,
load is that bad? My Internet is
said I have to cheer it on. Come on.
You could do it. I took like lamaze
classes with my fucking Internet. Come on.
Do it. Push. Push. You look so
beautiful. It's still loading.
This is fucking, I, I pay
like as I got to get somebody,
I'm going to get it like a tech nerd
over here, you know. But before they do,
they've got to wear a helmet with a
Chin strap so that John doesn't hit the
floor when they see them, which I'm
fucking paying a month for cable.
Okay.
You don't said they'd help me out with
that. I've got to take him up on it.
A Red Ban told me to help me out with
that shit cause he told me a story.
He said he went home to his parents' house
and saw how much they were paying and
then called up there, their
provider, and uh, you know,
tore him a new asshole with his algorithm.
Um,
it's still fucking loading.
All right. I give up.
Okay.
I give up whatever.
That's a,
what's the most recent fucking question
has for this week, by the way? You know,
I gave up arguing with my wife for lent
and I'm continuing it and I'm going to
tell you right now, I am getting
some wins. I'm getting some wins,
you know, because what it, look,
I'm still losing a lot. All right?
But, you know, uh, I look, I'm looking
at like a seven and nine season.
I think that's what I'm projected at.
But you know, I was like fucking own 16,
like the browns last year
because I'm finding like a,
what's good about not losing your
temper is, uh, when you're right.
And if he can somehow keep your wife
on topic, you're actually going to win.
You know? I don't know. Who knows? I was,
I already know. She's already
fucking adjusting her game
to my new fucking style.
Why won't this fucking thing load?
What is the fucking problem?
How much money do I have to fucking pay?
Okay,
wait a second.
Let me just bring my energy back down.
Bring it back down again. It's
not that big a deal. All right,
here we go. Come on. Load load.
There it is.
Oh,
there was one today. There was
one in Argentina. I gotta Watch.
I gotta Watch it before somebody
tells me the fucking results.
I'll talk about this one
on Thursday. Um, naive.
Then I also have to watch
the, uh, the UFC. Um,
even though I already know the results
there, I got to watch this shit.
The big fights rose, Nama, Eunice first,
Jordana, Jordana in
dry trick. I say right,
Yolanda,
now you right trick you and I know how
to say that because I listened to this
fucking Russian guy.
Okay.
Yeah.
I listened to this guy for like an hour.
It was rose Nama Eunice verse.
You're Angela. Did you
guys get dead? It was
once again,
the fight was rose.
Nama Yunus versus your own Inner Ian.
Say,
tick your honor. Right. Tick. Yolanda,
at some point in her life,
she has to meet fucking axl rose
so he can sing her name. Right.
Sorry. Um, Boogie woman
is coming for your,
um, I don't know what she was
trying to say. Like the Boogie man,
she probably read up on the Boogie
man. I mean, it's a second language.
It's pretty good that she
could come up with that.
But that was oddly terrifying when she
was saying that Boogie woman is coming
for you. I was like, I don't, this brought
me back to when I was single. I was like,
man, I remember I dated Boogie
woman a couple of times. You know,
one of those women you break up with,
you don't need to go back for your stuff.
You're just like, fuck this. You can
have it, man. I'm fucking Outta here.
A goddamn which, alright. De
Moines, Iowa billary swank. Hey,
billary swank, uh, just checking
in on you and giving you some ammo.
When you go back to your,
uh, advertisers, uh,
of all the podcasts that I
listen to on a regular basis,
your ad reads are the only ones that I
will not skip through. Uh, yeah, exactly.
That's why I fuck around through them.
So you got to keep it entertaining
because there's nothing stopping you from
fast forward through it. You don't
understand. Understands that stamps.com,
you know,
didn't nature's box,
they didn't get it in those other
fucking constant blue apron.
A right of all the pog here.
Also,
how many corn fed asks is
do I need get into seats
to get you to make a stop in De
Moines, Iowa? I've been up there.
I was up there in the last year.
I did a Gig at Iowa state.
I don't know if that's the morning.
I'll get all that and give a fuck.
I'll go out there.
A hippie music blind spot.
Always something I learned with drumming.
Uh,
that thrash,
the thrash drum beat is
the same beat and like,
like shout music.
Basically.
It's just the bands
there playing with the,
how they phrase the music on top is
different. Punk thrash and shout music.
There's a lot of fucking similarities
and that's one to grow on. Hippie music.
Blind spot.
A dear Billy curve bald.
I love your podcast and I'm coming
to see in Denver. Thank you.
I love to hear you talk about music
and drummers in particular. All right.
I got somebody new that I'm
following on Instagram. Instagram. I,
she just came up in my feed and
she blew me away. Uh, what is it?
Oh fuck the pocket queen.
And I thought it was funny cause I don't
know if she's a guns and roses fan or
if it's just a coincidence,
but a, you know,
rocket queen guns and roses fan
and then the pocket queens and uh,
she's just an amazing,
amazing drummer who's having the
time of her life when she plays.
I think it's the
underscore a pocket drama.
But uh,
I started following her and um,
that'd be, I don't know, she's just a
fucking amazing drummer. So anyways,
plowing ahead here. Uh, where is it here?
I love to hear you talk about
music and traumas in particular.
Have you ever taken a listen to John
Fishermen, the drummer and fish? I know,
bunch of hairy hippies.
I get it. You know,
it's not that it's that their
songs or 17 minutes long,
it's just such a fucking commitment.
Um,
I will say because of fish,
I learned about the little feet
album waiting for Columbus,
so I would do one at their live album.
I do want to thank them for that. Um,
then he was, people always put
them in the hippie music category,
but they aren't the fucking
mamas and the Papas.
I don't mind the mamas and the Papas.
My mother loved them.
So when I listened to them, reminds
me of driving around, you know,
in the car when I was a kid with my mom,
uh,
they've put on more sold out shows and
consecutively my computer just died
the fuck.
All right.
They put up more shows consecutively
at Msg than anyone ever. Wow.
Even when the Billy Joel,
Huh. And at any rate,
love episode family and go fuck
yourself. All right, well give me,
give me a fucking album that I can,
you know,
that's a good jump off that I
could get into this shit. Um,
I saw them live in the early
nineties at the Boston Garden.
They headlined the spin doctors
were there off their first album.
Little Miss can't be wrong. All of
that shit. It was like a fucking, uh,
uh, grunge thing. I don't know what
the fuck it was. It was like overnight.
All of a sudden it had just changed.
It was 1992 when I saw him.
Let me see if I can look that up,
see if I could find that.
The whole lineup and I think I
want to say WBCN was a part of it.
Let's see here.
A fish.
Okay.
Spin doctors.
Boston Garden.
1992.
Yeah.
Okay.
No Way. Yeah. October 30th. I mean,
the reason why I went
there was because, uh, the,
the sketch comedy group, Alan, the
monkeys had won the BCN comedy, right.
Al Del Benny, Dane Cook, Bobby Kelly
were in it and they perform there too.
And I got to watch them perform at
Boston Garden. And let me see if, uh,
they got the lineup. This was a
semi Halloween theme. Devil's night.
One set show at the WBC New
Music Concert Rocca Boston event.
It was fish first show at the
Boston Garden. Oh, no way.
I saw that show.
This is how old I am.
They actually have to
describe the Boston Garden.
A historic basketball and ice hockey
arena built in the 20s with a capacity of
about 15,000 addition to
fish and the spin doctors,
the level levelers materially issue.
Michael Penn and a comedy troupe
that include Dane Cook. Alan,
the monkeys performed between,
but there was called Allen the monkeys.
The comedy to committees
were okay. We won't, we won't
get into the rest of it. Uh,
um, anyways, plowing ahead. Uh, yeah,
I saw them I guess October 30th.
That's right. That's right.
I just started doing comedy right around
them was right when I met Patrice.
So there you go.
So I've actually seen them.
So there's a lot of like psycho phish
fans that would be like, oh my God,
you still up for the first
time at the bus to garden?
I saw one of their legendary shows
and had no idea who they were.
I just remember they had these
little workout trampolines,
personal trampolines that they were
jumping up and down on the whole time and
the crowd was jumping with them and
I thought they were cool. But, uh,
I never really got into all
right. Race documentary. Hi Bill.
I was listening to your podcast where
you talked about your new interests in
Moto GP. Uh, yeah, it's
fucking, I'm obsessed with, uh,
you should check out this documentary
about the annual isle of Man tt race.
I was trying to go to that the last two
years and I can't get anybody to go with
me. It's not moto GP, but it
has similar bikes I think.
Yeah, it's uh, yeah, it's,
it's a road race around the island
and more people have died than years.
They've had it. So, I mean,
it's incredibly dangerous.
I'd like to go see it,
see people driving that fast,
but I don't know,
watch somebody die either or die myself.
Um,
was shit flying into the crowd.
It's road racing instead of track.
So there's no tire walls to crash into,
et cetera.
It's insanely dangerous. Usually
couple writers are killed each year.
And this document who falls one of the
writers for one of the years. I've only,
I only have a passing interest in racing,
but this illustrates the danger
of the sport really well.
In case the link doesn't work, the doc
is called tt three d closer to the edge.
Love the podcasts. You cracked me up.
Uh, I might even buy some of your shit.
You're pedaling. I'm really not pet.
I don't sell anything on my website.
All right? So I didn't need the
little snide fucking comment. Oh,
l maybe just talking about the shit that
I'm advertising and that case fucking
about it.
All right.
The evil woman.
Ooh,
evil woman.
Uh,
Dear Billy Hale Bob,
I don't get that. Oh, my
fucking daughter's up here.
I gotta I gotta finish this thing.
All right.
I was watching the documentary called
wild wild country with my girlfriend.
It's about a group of followers of a
guru from India who set up shot shop in a
remote town in Oregon.
Everybody's watching this right now.
I won't get into the higher question of
what is a cult and what does a religion,
oh, I'll tell you the exact thing. A,
a cult is a new religion.
A religion is a former
cult that took over.
That's the only difference.
A while watching my girlfriend
while watching my girlfriend
didn't seem as angry
with a particular person is I was the
first in command under the guru was a
woman named Sheila. I don't want
to spoil the doc free listener,
but she did some evil shit in the name
of her cause I, yeah, yeah, she did.
She was a fucking lunatic.
I'm like most guys who are in power,
she acted accordingly.
See,
and that's the thing right there where
they sit there and they act like if women
ran the world, there would
be no war. It's, it's not,
it doesn't have to do with sex.
Most people when given
power do not handle it well.
Uh, they either hurt other
people, they hurt themselves,
they sabotage it because they can't
deal with the fucking pressure.
Or they just become a con like me. Uh,
she's a very compelling person to hear.
And speak, and I understand how some
of her might find a charismatic,
I liked her to a point.
I liked that she was just like standing
up to everybody, but then, uh, you know,
she went too far. She kind
of went like, uh, you know,
I'll fucking kill everybody instead
of just the people she was upset with.
She didn't try to hurt them. She
tried to fuck over everybody. Uh,
but when it gets to the part for the,
this six part series,
you started hearing about the town's
water supplies being poisoned under her
authority. Uh, he goes on, this
is disgusting, isn't it? No,
that's fucking terrorism. But this
is, you know, what, 25 years before,
27 years before, uh, 20 years,
maybe before nine 11. So, um,
okay.
She was just considered
a, you know, bitchy.
I think my girlfriend started giving me
a hard time for calling this Sheila cunt
saying, I worship guys like Tony
Soprano and Walter White. Uh, yeah.
He goes, yeah, I do. I worship
fictional characters that they were,
but I never defended waste management,
racketeering and lying to my family
about being a meth chemist. Uh,
it ended with her telling me that I'm
biased towards the achievements of men.
I can't deal with this lack of rationale.
I'm considering breaking it
off with their thoughts. Um,
keep your calm and just say,
listen,
the difference between me liking,
you know,
anti heroes in a movie versus you
liking antihero that actually existed in
really poisoned the town.
You just say, listen,
if Tony Soprano Walter, right, we're
real people. I wouldn't be a fan of them,
but you know, you know, you like
to surprise you. You're, you're,
you like the characters. You like the
acting, the writing, the way it's shot,
you know, breaking bad and all that.
That's, that's, that's all that is a,
if you considered breaking it off with
her over this and I would say, you know,
I think you should, I mean, if this
is enough to make you break it off,
you might as well,
you know,
just, you know, I wouldn't drink your
tap water for a couple of months.
Apparently. I'm controlling
is the name of this. Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
I'm going to say just by that title,
I'm going to say that you are
apparently I'm controlling.
Like people will always like get called
out on this shit. They'll go with,
you know, it's like that
bearded content, the flyers.
Every time he fucking takes out somebody's
knee and every time he, it's like,
so Blake, what the fuck he just did.
It's like totally away from the pocket,
complete penalty. And he always puts
his hand. I was like, what the fuck?
What the fuck did I tow
a dear Billy bung hole?
I recently started dating this lady
d
and everything was going well,
so I decided to invite her to a
mariners game for opening weekend.
You know, had I known you were gonna
say the name of the baseball team,
I would've switched it just to,
in case I don't know so much.
Somebody figures this out. Anyways,
I knew she was a baseball fan.
It would be excited to go. I invited
her and she said that sounded really,
so I was really excited as well.
I told her I would take care of the
tickets because I knew finding tickets for
opening weekend would be hard,
so she agreed and said she would pay
for food and drinks. Oh, look at this.
Everything's going great so far. It's
like a classic horror movie, you know,
they get to the fucking crystal lake.
Everybody's having a good time and it's
all enjoyable to the first time they go
check.
A couple of days later she started
having car troubles and was worried she
couldn't make it to the game because she
wanted to fix her car by Monday and the
game was on Sunday.
I live in the city and don't have a car,
but offered to rent a car to pick her up
or we could ride the bus together since
we would be drinking and the bus drops
people off right outside the stadium.
She didn't answer my texts for a couple
of days and told me less than told me
less than 24 hours that she
wasn't going to make it.
I sent her a text back saying that I was
upset about it and that if we had just
had a regular day date
scheduled, I wouldn't mind.
But the tickets weren't cheap.
Front row,
lower level outfield.
And I don't get to go to many ball
games at, it's important to me.
She didn't reply until the next day and
said she wants to stop seeing me because
the tech same controlling.
But I was honestly just trying to tell
her how I felt about being ditched.
I'm usually a pushover and this was the
first time I sent texts like this before.
So do you think that I was
being controlling that would
appreciate some advice.
Thank you. And Go fuck yourself.
Ps, bring back the sonics. Oh,
you're going to get a hockey team instead.
Sonics on ice.
Okay.
Calm is Seattle soliloquy piece.
Um,
yeah.
No, but I understand both. She has to
get to go to work on fucking Monday.
She wants to make sure cars are right.
I get that. This, but to say that she,
you're controlling and she
wants to stop seeing you.
Um,
I would say she dated a psycho before and
is a little gun shy or she wasn't that
NC anyways, to quote
Greg Barrett, you know,
um, I hope he just went to the
game with a buddy or yours.
It got fucking hammered.
Okay.
Um, yeah, I dunno, I would just
write back, just say, you know, well,
I guess we had a miscommunication.
Okay.
But I have to admit, if you
know, one little spat like that,
it makes you think about
breaking up with me.
I kind of feel like you're
not that into me anyway.
So before one of us really gets hurt,
why don't we just,
let's just end his friends and really
try to end his friends. That is,
that is such a skill I wish I had.
And to add the way you end
is friends with somebody.
Okay.
This is for men and women is you just,
you have to be 100% honest with them,
you know?
Uh,
and if you haven't been
honest with somebody and
you're in a relationship right
now,
if you're really honest with them now,
there's still probably going to hate you.
But you still have to do it because what
she's doing now is you're setting up
healthy relationships in the future.
All right?
So then he could just got it all
out there. They knew from day one,
from day one, when you meet a woman, you
do what's, what's going on between us.
Not that I've just, you know, I'm not
looking to be in a relationship right now.
I'm just having fun. That's it. So
why you just want to have sex with me?
Yes.
But yet I know what you're gorgeous.
I'm attracted to.
There are, I'll practice safe
sex. Do you want to get fucked?
I'm the man for the job. You don't have
to be that honest. All right. Anyways,
black girlfriends, family. Hey Billy Bird.
Pubes guys are killing me today.
I'm a 24 or five year old guy and I've
been with my girlfriend about eight
months,
uh,
25 year old guy, but with my
girlfriend for about 18 months. Sorry.
Things are great between us and
she's awesome. We're both single.
Parents have a four of four year olds
are both in school and both work decent
jobs. All right. I have to ask you
this before we go any further. Uh,
at night, do you dress up like a
black woman? I'm just, you know,
this is too many coincidences.
Does this like some fucking psycho
shit where it's your Norman annual,
your mother? No. All right, I'll continue.
She's a great mother, a
very sweet, encouraging,
beautiful woman who keeps herself in great
shape and is working on her doctorate
in nursing. The total package. The
only problem is her family, bub, bub,
bub bomb back.
She's a black woman and I'm the
first white guy she's been with.
My daughter is mixed and I'm used to
dating interracially and my parents and
brothers lover, but with her family,
her brothers and dad just don't like me.
They barely speak to me even though we
have a lot of the same interest in sports,
music, et cetera. This sounds like a like
a fucking ice cube movie. Her mother,
grandmother and sister loved
me and we get along great,
but I plan on marrying her and would like
a good relationship with the brothers
and a dad.
They have no reason to dislike me as I
treat my girlfriend very well and have
never acted like an asshole
around that boy. Yeah.
You're getting judged probably
by other white people. Uh,
and the shift that they've done.
The only thing we can think of is they
don't like me because I'm white because
she said her, she said her ex
and them were cool and even
hoop together often. Oh, wait
away. Okay. So her ex all day,
like the other boyfriend better.
Her brothers said to me a few weeks ago
when I tried to talk him and invite him
to play ball, he said, we
got nothing to speak on.
You're never going to be my be family.
It came out of nowhere before
they were just cold to me.
I've come across people
being prejudice to me,
well hooping and in my area I grew up,
but it's just weird because they actually
know me and know how much I care about
their sister.
Any advice from you or the lovely Nia
on how to approach the situation or if
you've ever run into this problem?
I'm saving up to buyer to buy a ring
and we'd like to rectify this before
committing the rest of my life to her.
Thanks for all the laughs over the
years and go fuck yourself. Ah,
that's a fucking major issue.
That's a major issue.
And,
and relationships are hard enough.
Forget about when one whole side
of the family doesn't like you.
MMM.
I would just use humor. That's how I'd
get through it. I go over a hustler like,
hey everybody, it's the white
guy. Nobody likes, yeah,
you guys want me to stand outside
while you talk to you, your,
that your daughter or sister?
Um, I dunno. Or an act extra white.
I go over there dressed like an a with
a Donald Trump extra long red tie.
I just started having fun with it,
you know.
Hey, do you guys see that, that
fucking great speech by Trump?
Yeah.
I don't know. See, I'm a dick. I
would, I'd probably start doing that,
but I gotta be honest. Uh,
that's going to wear on. Thanks.
I think I would pump the brakes on
the ring until you work that out.
And, uh, I think you guys should maybe the
need help beyond some Dick joke fucking
comedian.
Um,
okay.
Yeah.
Cause that sounds like that's
going in a direction where,
uh, you're going to have to, she's
going to have to make a choice,
either be with you or have a relationship
with the family. I don't know,
but that's,
that's above my pay grade.
So my advice to you is I would
talk to her about it and,
um,
okay.
You know, I would tell
us it, listen, you know,
I'm ready to commit to you for
the rest of my life, but like,
I don't know if I could,
I don't,
I don't want to commit to that because
this is his thing. You don't marry her,
you marry her family in a for
family, fucking hate you, dude.
You're going to be miserable.
All right.
And having Ben with somebody
for as long as I have, you know,
there's ups and downs and shit,
even without that,
fortunately near his family is fucking
awesome. So I lucked out there.
And even then, we still had difficult
times, mostly because I'm a fucking idiot.
But, um, yeah. So I would try
to work that up. All right.
Yeah. What the fuck you in a rush
for? You know, you already have a kid.
Okay. And, uh,
I dunno. I would just feel listened
to. I'm not going over your head.
They don't fucking don't want me
around there again. Fuck them.
You know, I don't give a shit. I'm tired
of going over there being like, Hey,
what do you want to fucking hang out? And
they go, yeah, get the fuck out of here.
So it's just like, all
right, I get it. I get it.
But there's no reason it'd be stubborn,
you know all about it.
Um,
it's weird because your heart's involved,
but anybody with a brain would be like,
well dude, that's going to be a
fucking miserable marriage. Yeah.
Okay.
You know,
God,
Jesus Christ,
and then what they're going to show
up at the fucking man at the wedding.
Just fucking mean mugging
here the whole time. Okay.
Oh, Davis, if you marry a fucking
a Lope, that's the way to do it.
You know, I, I would go, I would go that
route. I don't know, Dude. Cz little bit.
What does she now you got to do all of
this shit now. You got to do all of the,
it's already gonna be hard enough.
You know, dirty. Be Hard
enough. If you get married,
it's already going to be hard enough and
I you going to add that? Fuck that shit.
I Dunno, but you'll love her, so I
don't know what to tell you. Get,
have to get help. All right. Talking
in circles. All right, that's it.
I'm going to watch that. You Watch to
see it. That moto GP, I'll fucking even,
I'll be old news. I don't give
a fuck. I'll make it funny.
I'll talk about on Thursday,
have a great couple of days.
You con and I'll check
in on you in a few days.