Hey,
what's going on?
It's Bill Byrd is time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
September 3rd,
2018 what's going on?
How are Ya?
Oh happy Labor Day
to you.
Happy Fac in Labor Day to you.
Whoa.
Ooh,
happy fuck and Labor Day
you.
Oh
Cuba goal dwelling
happy be fucking Labor Day to you.
How many fucking podcasts are out there
wishing you a happy Labor Day with an
original song?
Huh?
Am I going to get sued for saying
that in the podcasting world,
in the podcasting stratosphere. Where
are you guys doing today? On Labor Day?
Okay.
What the fuck is Labor Day Anyway?
So does this have something to do with
the troops? How hard they're working,
right? And you're not doing shit cause
you're not wearing a uniform, right? Huh?
You fucking civilian piece of shit.
Don't you love how, that's the vibe. Now,
how about a round of applause for
our troops? I have around a plus.
The rest of us paying the fucking taxes.
You can't do this God damn field trip
over there and it's never going to fucking
end until what we bankrupt the whole
fucking thing and five cons have all the
money. Ah. How about a round
plus for us? You're rich. Cons.
June is growing and leaving
us with the fucking tab.
Okay.
Can I get on the plane first? Every
once in a while. You're fucking asshole.
All right. Labor Day. Labor Day,
fucking me.
Nay Labor Day is a public holiday or
a day of festivities held in honor of
working people in the United States
and Canada. This ain't about your wife,
is it? Oh, shots fired.
I'm on the first Monday in September
and in many countries on May 1st.
Why do we always have to
be different over here?
You know the whole fucking
world's on the metric system. Oh,
fucking world is celebrating
Labor Day on May 1st not America.
Now we're on standard September 1st.
Yeah.
The rest of the world respecting
the summer or at least the spring.
Okay.
Oh yeah. He shares your fucking day
off at the end of the goddamn summer.
How you like,
you got to pack up the water skis.
Hey Buddy.
You know,
and that's about the Nath fucking
negative thing you said about the United
States of America. I got one for
you. I, you got a fucking day off.
Why don't you pack your shit
up and get the fuck out.
See how you like it if some mother fucking
yeah,
fucking Moscatos the size of
your fucking freckled ball head.
You fucking orange mother fucker.
I got a good fucking mind to get out of
my truck and go in and show you what's
what
pappy labored.
Hey dear America.
Oh you fucking wine and crime.
Fucking snowflakes out there
bitching about global warming.
You want to see warming? I bought
my fucking nuts, mother fucker.
I'm a God damn coal miner.
You understand me?
I'm a coal miner in 2018 why the fuck
would I want to go out and learn about
solar power when I can continue
doing a fucking job that's out slate.
I don't give a fuck if I'm
digging in a national park.
Stepping on a fucking Bald
Eagle fucking head. All right.
If that's going to put spam on my
fucking table, I'm going to do it.
And at some orange to play where a mother
fucker where the Goddamn red tie down
his fucking name is going to
do it for me and a God damn.
And I'm going to vote for
dear America.
Um,
does he know what he was wondering?
What my neighbors think?
You know how many people live in that
house in, are any of them in a good, yeah.
Mood.
Oh Jesus.
So it's Labor Day.
Now let me ask you a question since
it's a fucking day off, right?
Does your wife's give you the day off?
Huh?
Or does she wants you to run around and
do a bunch of God damn jobs that need to
be done while she stays in the
house doing God knows what,
right?
I was
silver. We could get those boxes.
Is that what you were hoping?
Well God gave you a couple of arms
and a back started lifting this week.
Okay.
He's fucking ladies. I swear to God it
can you, can you ever just sit down?
Yeah.
What is a couch for in their world other
than to throw too many fucking pillows
on it. See, can't even fucking sit down.
And the second year it's like they know
this second, you fucking god damn acids,
the couch and your head's on the pillow
and you grabbed the remote to watch a
little.
Yeah,
Carly football. What happened? Hi.
Sorry. I am in a mood. I'm
actually happy married guy.
I don't know why I'm doing this.
I'm just trying to make you guys laugh.
All right. Cause I've been in
those relationship. All right.
My wife's cool as shit though. You know,
the other night I was hanging out, right?
Smoking a Sega. Oh No, I
wasn't. He supposed to hang out.
I ended up just fucking partner called
me up and we ended up hanging out and
she's like, you know, she sent me
the usual texts and I was like,
I'm down to the comedy store, I'm smoking
a cigar with some buddies of mine.
We did a spot. Sorry. And she goes, she
goes, no, hang out with your friends,
have a good time. And I texted
her back. Best wife ever. Right.
You can't complain if your wife does that
once a fucking year you, you got a gym,
you know, and my wife consistently does it
unless, you know, at two three, you know,
the next night when I went out again,
that took a little four day vacation is
what I did here as I stayed on my diet.
By the way, I had a couple of
little missteps here or there,
but generally speaking, I'm, I'm drinking
a little fucking smoothie here, you know,
I don't know what I'm doing.
I've got to add some cardio,
but you don't stuff that I
got this fucking Shit beat
out of me by some God damn
bugs. I don't even know where they
always go after my left foot, you know,
I'm like the fucking Daniel Day Lewis,
a bug bites my left foot.
They just go after it
right now it is on fire.
You know,
I literally have to put like some that
oxy 10 on it and then I got to put a sock
on it like so I won't
scratch it. Like, you know,
when you put a fucking the Goddamn I,
someone said chandelier
a fucking lampshade.
Okay.
Over dogs fucking, you know, so he can't
turn around by itself. The problem is,
that's why should always just stick a
fucking one of those lampshades on my, uh,
on my ankle.
But the problem is I'm a God damn human
being made in the image of our Lord and
Savior,
Jesus Christ.
So I have the ability to figure out how
to take off said lamp shade and started
scratching the fuck out of my ankle.
It was so bad the other
night actually woke me up.
Okay.
Like nothing could touch it.
It was on fucking fire and a dude.
These are next level. These are next
level. Global warming. Fucking mosquitoes.
All right. If you got a pair of jeans on
or Dungarees as they used to be called,
they'll bite right through them.
They don't give a shit. You know,
I wish it could be some assassin
fucking mosquitoes. Right?
And rather than just buying regular old
fucking people and giving them malaria
in that shit,
like it could just
fucking just go find one of
those Bilderberg meetings.
It just find who the fuck is in
front of all this? God Damn Madness.
Okay.
Sorry guys. I don't know. This is
why I don't watch the fucking news.
Um,
yeah.
Just go on a hundred million fucking
miles hour into the brick wall and all
these fucking rich people think that
somehow they're going to have a parachute.
And I guess what the rest of us are
all going to die. Is that what it is?
I'll bill. Come on. It's a
holiday. All right. All right.
Let's talk football here.
Let's talk football.
BOMP bomp bomp bomp bomp um,
how about those Red Sox? Woo.
Lots of the white sox last night,
eight to nothing for the first time.
We're actually kind of playing like 500
ball and I think it's a great thing.
I don't want to go to the
fucking playoffs. Not knowing
what losing feels like.
Like, wait, what's this other
wheels coming off? I wanted
to more be like, oh yeah,
this, we got out of this. All right.
Sales still on the disabled
list as far as I know.
And I don't know if price has,
uh, has pitched since, uh,
he got hit by that comeback
line or off his wrist.
X Rays were negative,
were doing further fucking studies.
So a, we shall see. We'll see what's
going to happen. Uh, last I saw,
um,
the Astros,
the team to beat the defending world
series champions getting zero respect out
there in Houston.
You know,
you would think that the baseball team
was as fat as the average person in
Houston. And I don't even fucking
wrinkle your Goddamn snout up at me.
If you fucking live in Houston,
you guys went back to back.
You had a goddamn dynasty
of being fucking, uh,
nominated or winning the fattest
city in the United States of America.
All right. And this is the fattest
fucking country evidently. Okay.
You are a,
you are a fat person's fatty Houston.
Okay.
Down there. Fucking barbecue
and everything, aren't you? Huh?
Do you know how it's just actually was
actually just in Houston there there is
not a juice joint and that entire city
lettuce is illegal. This,
this is, this is a US city.
Okay.
Now you wondering why they had
that Biblical flood down there.
Maybe God was like this.
This is a level of slough
that I have never seen. See,
that's why there's never a
flood out here in Hollywood,
okay?
Because we are so righteous.
We
are so living,
okay,
day to day and his image in his word.
I want you all right now.
I want you to close your eyes.
I want you to close your eyes right
now and just to know that Jesus,
he wants you to live in Hollywood.
He wants you to go there.
He wants you to do some coke.
He wants to get a girlfriend trying to
fuck her friend and try to keep both in
the fuck you at the same time.
He wants that. I'm sorry,
that was my Joel Olsteen. That's why
he didn't open the Goddamn doors.
When I'm that flood fucking Cayman
say I don't have enough fucking,
what am I fucking,
Jesus is going to keep pulling out
fucking barbecue fish for these people. I,
I don't,
I simply do not have enough
wafers to sustain this.
It's going to be a ride. They can,
they can rip up my blue carpet.
Okay.
Um, he was content to let those
fatties just float right by the arena.
Oh, well, you know what I would've done?
I would've put some fucking moorings.
Is that what you call those things?
You get dock a boat too.
I would have thrown some rope out there
and just had those fatties fucking,
you know,
now they're like a bunch of dinghies
until the water came down. I mean,
what was Joel Olsteen supposed to do?
Okay.
Joel Osteen's in shape. He lives
in Houston. You know why that is?
It's a miracle. I tell you, I saw a,
the image of a skinny Joel Olsteen and
my pop tart deal the day when I was in
downtown Houston.
You ever take two pop tarts or heat him
up and you stick a glazed doughnut in
the middle of it cos you don't,
you don't live in Houston.
He weigh in about this laugh.
Um,
I had a drink smoothies
more before I do a podcast.
I have incredible energy and a new
level of disrespect for a lot of things.
Dude,
my fucking foot,
my fucking foot is driving me nuts.
And then I got,
I got a bug bite on the back of my arm
and then I got another one on my lower
back, like just to the right of
where a tramp stamp would be.
Did I ever tell you guys I was dumb enough
to get one of those in the nineties?
I did. I got a Boston Bruins stamp. Tramp.
Okay.
Do you know and it said real men wear
black and I had that right above my ass
and I had to,
I had to work so hard.
Yeah.
Sorry.
In stand up to finally be able to
afford enough money to begin my laser
treatments to remove it.
I know a lot of you probably always
wondered why I never wore a half shirt on
stage. Well, that is why.
Okay.
I mean, I guess my big fault
is that I'm a hockey fan. Okay.
There I said it. Um, did you guys
watch any college football yesterday?
How about college football?
Just taking over this weekend.
The way the NFL does
towards the end of the year,
the NFL is give a fuck that you
got Christmas shopping to do.
They don't care that you got,
you're Jewish and you got to buy.
Fuck was it eight gifts?
Nine gifts for each fucking person,
right?
Is that candle fucking ghosts
candle number one. What do you got?
Well, how do you do what? Jewish people,
Dhea, Dhea, Dhea. Build the buildup.
The gifts. That's why
you got to do it, right?
You've got to start with the
weakest thing you got right.
What do you guy got a pair of socks,
you know,
and you just gradually
build the whole outfit up.
MMM.
Too Sharp and for Kwanzaa,
right?
The NFL does not give a fuck come
the end of the year. They like,
we own all the weekends.
We're taking all the fucking money.
All right.
We're showing games on Saturday that we
thought were going to matter, but don't.
We're kicking off the NFL season
this Thursday. This Thursday.
The NFL season is back,
ladies and gentlemen,
and it fell.
Football is back.
Okay.
And for the next 17 fucking weeks
with the bye week,
I ever fucking lonely. The, the, the,
the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
the fucking season is
now the regular season.
Okay.
I like to think that this country
can set aside all of the issues
that are weighing us down and we can lose
ourselves in the bread and circus that
is professional football. And
when does it start, Bill? Or
put it up, put it on. It
starts Thursday night.
Thursday night with yellow
defending super bowl champions.
The Philadelphia Eagles.
Did you ever think you'd ever
hear that in your fucking life?
People of Philadelphia,
you know, you didn't,
don't even act like you did.
Right? Where the fuck am I?
You guys are playing the dirty birds
down there and fucking
Atlanta. It's, it's,
it's the battle of the
birds this Thursday night.
This is the only Thursday game worth
watching for the entire fucking season.
Why you may not have asked,
because this is the only one where the
fucking teams didn't play four days
earlier and they're all banged up.
Yes.
The Eagles who will be
wearing green on green. Yes.
The Falcons will be wearing, I dunno,
black and red on black and red.
It's a home game for the goes. They're
probably going to bring the, if the, the,
the,
the championship flag up there.
And can you imagine how many people in
the city of Philadelphia are not going to
be able to time their alcohol intake to
when the flag is going to be raised and
they'll be in that little jail in
the Eagle's stadium looking out,
you know,
while the police laugh at them,
the local cops as they play iron
maiden's rhyming the ancient mariner.
Right.
Somehow it combined Ryman, the ancient
Mariner with the of Monte Cristo I'm on,
he's looking out the fucking his
jail cell and he could see the ocean.
You could see how free,
you know,
see the boats going by and
he was just sitting in there.
MMM.
And then later he got a Gig
on sesame street. Anyways,
it starts with the eagles and the falcons.
Now I've got, if you're a Philadelphia
Eagles fan, you gotta be asking yourself,
will this be a hangover game?
Yeah.
Are The eagles still celebrating?
Who Am I patriots playing?
Tom Brady coming up,
one of his great games is
a pro against the eagles.
A lot of people forget that though.
I thought thought the fucking ball he
threw for over 500 yards in a Superbowl
and lost.
Okay.
Now let's the Patriots go to
the Superbowl again this year.
You tell me when the fuck that's
ever going to happen again.
Everybody talking about Joe Dimaggio,
Oh, oh 56 game hitting streak,
whatever. Anybody can fucking do. That
56 game hitting streak is, is uh, is
pretty, God dammit. Impressive. You know,
to the point, they literally were
writing songs Jolton Joe Dimaggio,
whatever they were doing, right?
President was paying attention.
Did anybody write a fucking
song with Tom Brady?
Threw for 500 fucking yards and a god
damn Superbowl people have thrown for half
that much, smoked a cigar
and paraded around with the,
he threw enough yards to win to fucking
trophies in one game and the man lost.
Yeah.
So everybody's sitting around going,
how it can Tom keep doing it?
I used fucking old and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. Okay.
And I'm sitting over here with no
more hair left on top of my head.
The pullout going,
the problem is not Tommy.
Okay.
I would say it's our defense.
That's what I, I would say that
that was the fucking problem.
Okay.
That was such a fucking weird game.
Um,
I would love to go back
and watch it at some point
and just try to figure out how there was
only fucking two points or three points.
The whole fucking game. The
weirdest Goddamn game I've
ever seen in my life. Um,
it's like both offenses
showed up to play and the,
and the fucking defense was just
like this, this is the Superbowl.
I just can't get comfortable.
Um, what else we could,
we got the bangles or the bangles
as a is Paul Versey calls him the bangles,
calls him the girl group there,
and he calls the girl group the
bangles. Okay. But Paul Versey,
he marches to the beat of his own drummer
is playing the cults. Andrew Luck.
And I'm gonna tell you
something right now.
I'm gonna you something right
now by Andrew Luck. All right?
If you're fucking sitting there right,
and life keeps kicking you in the Dick
and you landed face down in the dust,
you know, and you just don't want to
get up anymore. Watch Andrew Luck.
Take a fucking hit. He
doesn't give a fuck. Gets up.
He congratulates the Gay Greg Job,
man.
I'll probably be filling that in
my early fifties. Granulation.
See on the next play.
I love that guy.
This is me actually saying something
positive about the Indianapolis Colts as
much as I hate gym or say,
okay.
All right.
Andrew luck the way he conducts himself
out there with such fucking class,
it actually actually transcends the fact
did he takes a paycheck from that corrupt
piece of shit that Flimflam the boss
Hog, the fucking NFL. Um,
anyways, the bills are playing the
ravens. This is what I gotta be asking my,
if I'm a buffalo bills fan and I got my
face in a plate full of fucking wings
over at anchor bar or fucking Duffy's,
whatever the fuck you supposed to go.
I got to be asking myself,
is this the year where the
bills for the finally return
to their AFC championship winning glory.
Okay.
Do the bills finally
get back to their peak?
Going to a super bowl?
Yeah.
Sorry. You know, I'm going to get
people in the AFC east. A lot of shit.
The Buccaneers and the saints,
uh, drew breeze, by the way.
Not In a lot of people realize this guy,
he's second all time.
I think he's strong for more yards and
Tom Brady and nobody pays attention to
him. Who's, who's kidding, who,
he's not dreamy. Like Tom Brady.
He's not as tall as Tom Brady.
You know,
supermodels are not knocking on his door.
He is a regular Joe.
He's a family man,
you know, and he's down there and, and,
and a fucking city that the devil is
even scared to go to and he is gone. He,
he's been able to maintain
of the stuff,
the fucking values that he was,
he was brought up and I would say that
is actually more impressive to me than
actually the amount of yards he's thrown
in his career were taking collars.
Okay.
Patriots are playing the Texans.
Right.
And that fucking saint
quarterbacks coming back,
I already forgot everybody's names.
Was that kid from Louisville.
Okay.
So Clemson and all the fuck he's from.
Yeah.
But um,
I know he's amazing and JJ watts is back,
so they should be an early test for these
[inaudible] page with the 49 is versus
the vikings. I don't even know what's
going on over there. Okay. Is Catherine.
It's still kneeling on the
ground. Kaepernick doesn't
have a Gig. The Vikings,
the vikings who are at
their peak right now
doing what they do,
coming fucking it up,
waiting to the next season and they
are on the rock. Can they finally,
can they finally turn the fucking
corner? What else? What else is going on?
The giants are looking good.
They got that maniac running
back from fucking Penn state.
They're playing the Jaguars,
the Brown.
They got that fucking dude from
Oklahoma, right? Or that the other,
the guy on TV said was undrafted and
he went on his fucking show with an
undrafted bill shirt.
They got this kid.
Okay.
Little bit of swagger.
The Cleveland browns playing the Steelers
right out of the gate. Jesus Christ.
Those two cities, they didn't even get
a chance to put their fucking face up.
I cannot fucking wait.
I am taping all of these games.
And your Los Angeles Rams versus the
Oakland soon to be Las Vegas Raiders.
I mean, how great a fucking game is that
going to be? That's the game right there.
That's the game of the week right there.
Rams first Raiders as far as I'm
concerned. That's the one I want to see.
Okay.
Oh, the 49 is have, what's his
face? Seattle's a Richard Sherman.
They got him coming back from the,
the, the fucking dreaded Achilles
tendon injury. See what he can do for
the 40. Niners you know what I mean? Um,
all right.
There you go.
So good luck to all you guys
unless you're playing the patriots.
Um,
okay,
now let's talk college football. How
Great was the college football? You know,
they were smart enough to not have all
those cupcake games of beginning of the
year. I mean, when I was growing
up, like September was a joke.
You get your football cad from your
bookie and what would they be saying?
It will be just like Nebraska would be
favored by 59 against like Kent State and
you'd take Kent State and then
like they would be up like,
like fucking 35 to nothing at the half.
And you like tea, they would cover.
Um, anyways, I watched my Lsu,
my adopted Lsu Tigers against the Miami
hurricanes, and a good friend of mine,
he's a huge Miami hurricane fan to the
point that I actually root for the Miami
hurricanes because I'm friends with him.
Not that I was ever a hurricane fan,
I wasn't.
So he was playing my adopted Lsu Tigers.
His team was playing my team. So I
texted him before the game. I said,
the Miami tropical depression,
you don't like when they think
it's going to be a hurricane.
And then they downgraded
to a tropical storm.
Will the downgrade of tropical storm
is tropical depression, I believe,
according to the weather that I
looked up. So he's like, fuck you man.
So we bought him a better round of drinks.
Some cigar came even fucking remember.
And I got to tell you right
now, I thought, you know,
Lsu the entire time I've been a fan of
these guys since like 2008 when I moved
out here, 2007, 2008.
So 2007 when I came out to
La and I actually had time
to watch college football.
MMM.
And I'd like less Meyers and how he
would go for it on fourth down and trick
plays and all that shit.
You know, and I just,
I wasn't going to just jump
on the Alabama bandwagon.
Isn't it amazing that they're
still at the peak 10 years later?
MMM.
There's still the team to beat. So I
was like, I'm gonna go with these guys.
So I've been watching them for 10 years
and for 10 years we have not had a
fucking quarterback.
They were doing that awful thing like
that old school college football thing
where it was just like, this is a running
down, putting the black quarterback.
This is oh, passing down,
put in the white quarterback.
They were doing that shit
in the two thousands.
Right.
Um,
and then I think there are there all time
rushing leader was their quarterback,
you know,
which is not a good stat.
They've had these bees at defense. They
actually had Odell Beckham at one point.
My buddy was saying like,
what a fucking waste.
They had nobody that throw
it to throw it to them. Um,
so I'm watching the game yesterday.
This kid, Joe Borrow, I guess,
transferred some from some other college.
Um,
I was losing my mind watching this guy.
I like, this guy's a fucking quarterback,
you know, people getting in
his face, giving him shit.
He's giving him shit back.
Okay.
He's fucking, he's reading
the blitz, you know, he's,
he was doing all this type of
shit and I was all excited.
And then I was just like,
this guy has got to have like 250 yards.
He only had a hundred,
144.
That's how much the QB position has
suffered while I've been watching these
guys,
uh,
that I was excited that there was a
guy in the middle of the third quarter.
I had 144 yards passing.
Um, and their new coach,
I hope I say his name,
White, uh, ed or German.
Okay.
Or Gerard, I don't even know how to
say his name, but all I know is he's,
he's got that by you fucking accent and
he, he sounds like fucking Hulk Hogan.
He sounds like he's
doing a wrestling promo.
I was waiting for me at lemme tell
you yourself to a broader, um,
I'll try to get you a clip of him and he
flips out and screams and yells at the
players and uh, that reminds me of what a
football coach was when I was a kid. Uh,
Lsu for the most part
just handled 25th ranked.
Lsu just handled eighth ranked Miami,
tropical depression,
Miami hurricanes. And uh,
but in typical Lsu fashion,
they still scare me towards the end
when all of a sudden l a Miami started
coming back and then it was just like,
it was 33 to 17 was six minutes
left and Miami stopped him again.
I'm like, they are two drives
in to two point conversions.
Touchdown two point convergence
away from tying this fucking game.
Only Lsu could make me this nervous
after being up like 33 to 10 or some shit
like that. Um, but they held
on they want and all of that.
So I am excited.
Uh,
I know it's the first week of the season
before all you negative concepts out
there are going to be fucking,
you know,
you know what [inaudible] was all,
all over overrated
much. You know, like
that's some sort of like,
people just hate people being excited.
Okay.
Oh,
well what are you happy about?
Something and how cop can I
fucking shit all over this?
MMM.
Anyway,
so let's,
let's do some ad reach
here on Labor Day to you.
Oh, just in time for fucking football
season, I now remember people,
you got to gamble responsibly.
What I love about these guys is these
guys to not hide behind the fact that they
are a gambling site. Like some of
those other ones way back in the day,
like this is a, this is a game
of skill. All right. My bookie
bookie, they're proud. You know, like,
like a fucking fat actress going up,
accepting an award being like,
I know I look good, right? Same
thing. They're being brave right now.
Um, my bookie, you know,
ever since I, this podcast,
people have been asking me for advice.
I don't know why.
Ask me what team do bet on. The truth
is, I don't know who's going to win,
but if you think you know you got a chair,
you got to check out my bookie.
I could have done it in a way, but at
the truth is, I dunno who's gonna win,
but if you think you know, you got
to check out my bookie. Remember,
okay,
who you're betting on is just as
important as who you're betting with.
That's why I always tell people to bet
with my bookie. I didn't know I did that.
Trust me guys, they your
best bet this season, they've
been in business for years,
have been getting great reviews online
and their mobile site is easy to use.
I'll tell you, if you're going
to put your paycheck on a t,
this is the website that though it,
I would only recommend a service to my
listeners that that's been good to me.
That's why I'm urging you to make your
way to my bookie. You when they peg,
that's how it works.
Why are they making this sound off like
the fuck are doing some cub scout shit?
Listen,
you fucking degenerate gamblers.
Here's a fucking website that's not a
shame that they're going to try and take
your fucking money.
You think you can beat him.
Go to the fucking website they have in
game living, live better live bedding,
Jesus bill the most rewarding
player perks in the business.
And for you fantasy guys out there,
man,
all you guys on Unicorns
bet non fucking football.
You can even bet the over under on how
many fantasy points or player will score
each game.
Join now and my bookie will match your
deposit dollar for dollar use Promo Code
Bur bur to activate the offer.
Visit my bookie online today.
That's my bookie. M, Y, B, O, o, k, I. E.
And don't forget to use the Promo Code
[inaudible] when creating your account to
claim up to $1,000 in free
play, you play, you win,
you get paid. Also, you play,
you lose, you don't get laid,
especially if it's your girlfriends money.
So please fucking bet responsibly.
I will be calling in
tomorrow till my bookie,
I believe it's seven o'clock
or eight o'clock at night, um,
uh, Pacific time. All right.
I'll be calling in with my pics even
though I don't know what the fuck's going
on. I'll make you laugh is what I'll
do. All right, so if you want to gamble,
there's a place to go, but to
do it responsibly. Okay? Don't,
don't be getting fucking crazy. All
right, frame bridge heavy buddy. Okay.
You've been listening to this show.
You heard me talk about frame
bridge or at least read about it.
They made it super easy and affordable
to frame your favorite things from art
prints and posters to the travel
photos sitting on your phone.
Here's how it works.
You know what?
I just framed three of them from France
and London and we got him sitting right
on my TV and it looks great.
It's a little collage.
If you will just go to [inaudible] Dot
Com and upload your photo or they'll send
you a package to safely mail it in your,
in your physical pieces.
The fuck does that mean preview
your item online in any frame style?
Choose your favorite or get
free recommendations from
their talented designers
though bought a blue frame.
The expert team at frame Bridgeville
custom frame your item and delivery your
finished piece directly to your door ready
to hang instead of the hundreds you'd
pay at the framing store, their prices
start at just $39 in all shipping is free.
Plus my listeners will get 15% off their
first order@framebridge.com when they
use my code. Burr B u. R.
R give your personal experience
using frame bridge. Yeah.
Ah,
I went to London and I went to Paris.
Okay.
France and I showed my tramp
stamp underpants and a,
I took a couple of pictures,
you know,
with my wife and our beautiful
daughter in front of the loo,
front of the Eiffel Tower.
Right. My favorite place to, uh,
the, my favorite cafe de Mayo. Um,
I'll rule Sanjay Sharma. No, it's
not over there. Where the fuck is it?
I forgot what street it's on.
And then I took one of me smoking a cigar
with my dad when we were in London and
I just had all of those framed.
And that's great because you know,
you take all these great pictures,
they stay on your phone and then you know,
they ended up in some hard drive
and then you break up with somebody.
You forget the fucking hard drive.
Make sure you're framed your good ones,
you know, they're good to look at
too. You're like, oh, that's right.
There are people in the world that
liked me. Um, get started today.
Frame your photos or send the
perfect gift for weddings, birthdays,
and special event. Go to [inaudible] dot
com and use the Promo Code [inaudible].
You'll save an additional
15% off your first order.
Just go to frame bridge.com
Promo Code Burr F R A M E B R,
I d g e.com,
Promo Code.
[inaudible] I wonder if people who like
rob banks take selfies with each other,
you know, just as a joke and then the boy,
you can't send it to frame bridge. Well,
they wouldn't know what
the fuck was going on.
They think they were at a Halloween party.
No matter what you do in the bathroom,
stop jerking off to get ready.
Dollar Shave Club has everything you
need to look, feel and smell your best.
They have amazing shower stuff,
hairstyling products,
toothbrushes and toothpaste and of
course raises and shaved supplies.
You might shave your whole body
to get ready for a bike race.
You might have to shape your whole body.
Dollar Shave Club's executive razor and
shave can help you might do your hair to
get ready for your soccer match.
Well, I don't play soccer and I,
and I'm fucking shape my head here.
Um,
bogies by dollar shave club can
help you get your style right.
Bogies Huh? The thing is, no
matter what you do to get ready,
dollar shave club has everything you need.
And right now you can get ready
with an amazing deal on one,
on anyone of their starters.
Sets like the daily
essential started that.
But you can't go wrong with any of them.
Head over to dollar shave
club.com/burr to pick up your own DSC.
Start a set for just five bucks
after your starter set product.
Ship at a regular price and make
sure, yeah, check out their new video.
Two that's dollar shave club.com/bar high
dollar shave club.com/burr all right,
two more reads. Oh, draft kings,
everybody. Oh they're not ashamed anymore.
Draft Kings football
returns Thursday night.
Put it to put it up and huge cash
prizes are up for grabs at draft kings,
the leader in one week.
Fantasy sports for the season opener.
Draft kings is hosting a fantasy
football contest that just,
that's just $10 to enter and
has a a $1 million top prize.
Well, you guys on your Unicorns with your
fantasy teams, but for a limited time,
if you sign up with the code,
Burp B U are draft kings will give you
a free entry with your first deposit.
Single game show down is
the newest way to play.
Just draft six players
from Thursdays game.
Stay under the salary cap and see
how your team stacks up against the
competition,
puts your football knowledge to work
and you could win 1 million bucks while
watching the season opened. You
know, I make funny fantasy guys,
but like that's actually really fucking
cool and I'm afraid to fucking do it
because I will become addicted and I'll
be like you guys and stop rooting for
teams and I'll start rooting for players.
It's the gay within the gay man.
Uh, you don't even have to
come in first to be a winner.
There are two and a half
million dollars in total prices,
which means thousands of winners.
Download the APP or go to draft kings.com
now and use the code burr to sign up
and make your first deposit.
Where'd you do draft kings will give
you a free shot at 1 million bucks.
Uh,
this star state,
that's Promo Code Promo Code Bar only
at draftkings kings minimum $5 deposit
eligibility restrictions apply.
See draftkings.com for details.
And lastly, but not
leastly. Sorry, I fucked up.
The rest of that read my head
was actually, I've already
made the Burger patties.
Okay. Now next thing I'm going to do
them a cup to the tomatoes, the lettuce,
have all the pickles, have everything
ready to fucking go. And this year,
for the first time ever,
I am going to do a practice burger just
to make sure my temperature is right,
to know how long. So for all the people
who want it, medium rare, medium, well,
well done, all of that fucking shit.
I made my patty small this year.
I made him Finn.
All right.
Better than Mcdonald's or old school
Mcdonald's. Not Quite Wendy's all right.
Right in the fucking wheel house because
I used to work, I used to work in a,
uh,
this place called the sable cafe in,
um, in Cary, North Carolina. I,
I worked there, I swear
to God, 31 years ago.
I worked there for nine months.
And unfortunately the restaurant
was gradually going out of business.
I was a busboy and then I became
the busboy and dishwasher.
And then at one point, I swear to
God, I was the grill chef. The busboy.
And a dishwasher.
As I took on these extra jobs,
they would give me like a 50 cent
raise and I was so bad with math,
it never dawned on me like, hey, minimal
wage is three 50 an hour and, and,
and the dishwasher was getting paid
three 50 an hour and I was getting paid
three 50 an hour.
So you're paying two people,
$7 an hour to do these two jobs
and now I'm doing both jobs.
That other person doesn't have a
job and I'm only making $4 an hour.
Yeah.
Then I became the grill shift and I think
I was making four 75 an hour of five
bucks an hour to do three fucking
jobs. And I would be out there and, uh,
I would be,
I was glassed in on a mesquite grill with
the chef hat and underneath my apron I
had the bow tie fucking, um, busboy
outfit. It was literally like, you know,
when Peter Brady had two dates
in one night, right. And, um,
okay.
I fucking wood duck down when I saw a
table almost done eating and I would run
out there, bus table, run back,
throw all the dishes in the dishwasher
and then run fucking back out without
washing my hands.
Okay,
this is just food. But
you still, you know,
I'm just handling your food and then
I would continue fucking cooking.
MMM.
And then that's when I learned that little
trick. You know, where you, you know,
I learned it this way. You
put shift, you put your, uh,
you just touch your thumb to your index
finger and then touch the fleshy part of
your,
uh,
of your hand that connects to your thumb
and you press on that. That's rare.
Then you just move it to your middle
finger. That's like medium rare.
Then the ring fingers. Well, and
then the fucking pinkies well done.
Now that fucking works
provided you're in an all,
but it all depends on how thick the patty
is and how high your fucking heaters.
So you got to balance all of that out so
you can use that because that actually
fucking works unless you heats up too
high and your meats too thick and then you
think it's well done and all you
did was Chad the outside and inside.
It's a fucking Friday the 13th so I'm
going to do that and have myself a tasty
fucking burger before
anybody even arrives.
I'm going to have my timer. I'm going to
adjust my fucking heat and I'm going to,
I'm going to be ready for fucking
Freddy. You know what I mean? That's,
that's my deal here. Okay? That's how I'm
doing it and I'm going simple this year.
Burgers and dogs. Fuck
you, but you don't like it.
Get the fuck out this country.
I'm not smoking anything.
I'm not fucking,
I'm not doing any of this bullshit.
Burgers and dogs.
We got potato chips.
We have this standard fucking
condiments, lettuce, tomato,
pickles, ketchup, onions,
mustard. All right,
now fucking Asian and fused fucking
this already Italian influenced that.
Oh, Billy ballgame. I'm go on the
fucking, I'm going old school.
We got cheese. What kind of cheese you
want. You want the white or the yellow?
We don't have any margin.
We have butter.
Yeah,
on toast in the buns
unless you tell me otherwise.
All right.
That's it.
Can you feel my anxiety? All
right. stamps.com everybody.
The US Postal Service is an
important tool for any business.
stamps.com is the easiest way to access
all the amazing services of the post
office.
I don't know why,
but I feel like over in annunciating
this whole read stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for letters or
packages at your convenience.
24 seven print postage for any male
class right from your own computer.
Buy and print official US postage
for any letter, any package,
any class of mail using your
own computer and printer,
they'll send you a digital scale automatic
that automatically calculates exact
postage.
stamps.com we'll even help you decide
the best class of mail based on your
needs.
No need to lease an expensive,
expensive postage meter and there
are no long term commitments.
I use stamps.com because include
your personal recommendation.
Whenever I send out my fucking posters.
Dude,
I use stamps.com I'm a
moron if I could do it.
So can you absolutely know negative
references to the post office.
Oh my God. I wish I could cook a
Burger for people at the post office.
And right now you too can enjoy stamps.cab
service with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus
postage and a digital scale.
Go to stamps.com click on the microphone
at the top of the homepage and type in
Burr that stamps dad cam enter burr.
All right,
that was my nod to people in the Midwest.
Bob,
go to stamps.com in
order their butcher box.
I'm speaking of butcher box,
butcher box pork and a t c a festival.
That's right.
The all things comedy festival is,
um,
is a, is coming back to Phoenix. It's
coming back to Phoenix in October.
Hey, and by the way, and I will
be there doing a live podcast.
This is a pre fucking promo.
Okay.
I don't have any dates yet. I'm just
letting you know, keep your October open.
It's October 20 something
I believe. Um, anyways,
Shit's probably already on sale.
I don't even know.
Speaking of other things
that I need to promote,
I did a movie last year
called the front row.
Okay.
All right. And, uh,
the trailer starring Hugh Jackman,
the trailers who's already getting Oscar,
Oscar buzz,
he's getting Oscar buzz all freckles. All
right. And I actually made the trailer,
um,
you realize how much I'm moving up in
the world that I'm actually in the movie
trailer. Now. I'm not saying that
if you drop a piece of popcorn,
you look down and kick it under the seat
in front of you that you won't miss me
in the trailer.
I'm just saying that I am in it for a
hot second with one of the best actors of
today who is getting Oscar
Buzz repeat Oscar buzz.
Um, this weekend I'm going to be in, um,
some casino north of,
uh,
the hell is it Sacramento.
And then the next day on going to the
Toronto Film Festival for the Premiere of
the Front runner starring Hugh Jackman,
who's getting Oscar buzz.
Okay. And then, um, and, and, and,
and the movie was directed by the
Great Jason Reitman, by the way,
if you want to fucking win an Oscar.
Okay.
It's starting to become
work with old freckles here.
All right.
We had to Oscar winners last year,
two or three from,
fromF is for family.
Fucking Sam Rockwell one
it Allison Janney won it.
I think Laura dern guy like a golden
globe. I don't watch award shows. Okay.
I don't have time. I'm busy focusing on
things that don't matter like sports.
Um,
and now we'll look what happens.
I have about seven lines in this movie
and all of a sudden, not coincidentally,
Hugh Jackman is now nominated or no,
he's getting Oscar buzz I should
say. Okay. And why is that?
Because he's unbelievably talented
because he puts the work in because he's a
pro maybe, maybe, but I think
more so
is that he had half a scene with
me. I think that's what it is. See,
once I go in the scene and they see what
I look like and where my acting is heck
at right. I almost said Hack
and act at the same time,
then whatever you're doing as the other
actor is just going to be so fucking
elevated, then all of a sudden you're, you
know, you're going to be in the running.
Okay. And that's what I bring
to Hollywood. All right,
put your box everybody and the all
things comedy festival. Oh, by the way,
congratulations to a Jason Reitman Ntu
Jackman for getting all this great and
everybody else sits in the fucking movie,
you know,
forgetting all this awesome reviews,
which is a very hard thing to do this
day in age with all the cuts out there in
the Internet.
It's really difficult to try and
get some sort of positive feedback.
Um, and I'm, I'm just happy just to be a
small part of it. You know what I mean?
I'm like, Bill Walton, when he joined
the Celtics, okay, my feet are fucked up.
I'm just happy,
you know,
every once in a while throw it to
me and I'll get a couple of points.
The crowd would go nuts because I
am on the scoring sheet that that's,
that's where I'm at. Put your box pork
at the all things comedy festival.
Hey Bill, huge fan. Just
riding into, thank you for
the butcher block. Block plug.
I'll listen to this. This dude tried the
pork chop that I've been raving about.
The heritage bread. Fucking pork. Okay.
You talk about the pork chops.
You talked about the pork
chops and how great they were,
so I had to get my hands on them.
My wife, who is an amazing cook,
seasoned these chops so well.
I have to share it with you.
She put extra virgin olive oil
on them and salt and pepper.
Then let them rest for like 45 minutes.
Look at that.
I mean that's about as standard
of rub as you could possibly get.
That's all you have to do.
About a half a teaspoon per chop.
Then she just cooked them in
the oven for like 25 minutes.
You said the over cook them in the
over for like 20 to 25 minutes.
I'm assuming that meant of it bill.
It was the best God damn pork chop
I ever had. I fucking told jump.
He goes, when you get a cheat
day, uh, try that recipe. Uh,
thanks again. Can't wait to
see you in Phoenix in October.
So I guess the tickets
are already on sale. Um,
yeah guys,
I'm telling you man,
who fucking knew that there was a
pure bred fucking pig out there,
which blood can be traced back
to the original white people,
the Oji whities over there in
Europe. Um, I'm telling you,
I did my differently.
I took out a black skillet and uh,
I got that heat going right? And
I just, I, I forget what I, I,
I don't even know what I
put on the fucking thing.
I probably didn't know in me German,
Irish guy that I am, I see both sides.
And then I finished it in the oven and
then I brought it out and I did a like a
rosemary, a butter Beth. Oh,
I mean, I didn't even need a fucking
side. Who's every bite I took?
I was just punching the
fucking table. It was, it's,
it's that fucking good. All right.
If you're a kind of war there,
you got to get the fucking
heritage bread point.
They're not even paying me for this.
This is how fucking good is all right.
Urban mayor,
although that's a real slick way to get
some fucking advertising in for free.
Be Somebody that fucking writes
in with their own experience. Uh,
urban Meyer or mayor, how it's
spelled. Is that John Mayer,
but it's urban Meyer.
Is it John Meyer? Hey,
Billy Beluga whale.
What are your thoughts about
urban Meyer and the Osu scandal?
Do you think he should have been fired?
Oh, you know, I stopped following it.
Fired over that. What the fuck
was this? Is this jerseys again?
Urban mayor fired reason layer.
We go bump,
bump, bump, Palm Bodo.
Why is urban Meyer, uh,
he's suspended. It doesn't
say, oh, he's not fired.
He suspended.
I'm going to say Jason Lie ahead.
What had been fucking tweeting all in
capitals at, at the whole fucking world.
Maybe he was. Why is urban
wires suspended? Here's the
short and the long answer.
I'll state suspended urban Meyer,
uh,
for the first three games
of Ohio state's 2018 season.
Who the fuck are they
playing? Fuck, had you, is it,
this is the non suspension suspension
is misses the Buckeye season opener
against Oregon state a likely
blowout win four weeks,
two and three against Rutgers.
Another likely blowout win and Tcu
a tougher game and a trip to Texas.
Tcu is kind of fell off
while we won't happen at Tcu.
Come up from a mayor.
Can coach during the week before
sitting out the game itself or offensive
coordinator? Ryan Day is acting head
coach while Meijer is out. Yeah.
And he has a headset on the whole game.
Gee,
who the fuck he think he's talking to?
Uh,
the short reason for the
head coaches suspension, uh,
school commission investigation decided
he mishandled domestic abuse allegations
against his former receiver's coach Zach
Smith. Oh, this is a little more serious,
but they didn't think,
is it bill?
Is it a little more serious than fucking
players selling their own jerseys?
But they didn't think mayors conduct
was egregious enough to merit firing.
One of the most successful coaches
in college history. Subtext. A,
it was only one broad. All right. We got
a national championship with this guy.
A below is the longer reason or
recap for the details. Smiths.
Now ex wife Courtney Smith has repeatedly
accused them of domestic violence
going back to 2009 so how does
this fall on on urban Meyer Meyer,
he supposed to be a fucking cop too.
In 2009 Zach Smith,
then a staffer under Meyer at Florida,
went to a party at Meyer's house.
Smith came home with a woman,
coworker who had been drinking and
planned to have her stay on Smith's couch
according to investigation. All right.
It sounds like a standard party.
They said Courtney Smith strenuously
objected and drove the woman to her home
that began a disagreement,
coordinate called nine one one and alleged
that Zack picked her up and threw her
against the wall.
Police arrested Zach for Acra aggravated
battery and later dropped the charge.
Meyer says Zack and Courtney met with
them at his Florida office and told him
Zach's arrest was based on false
information. Courtney gave to the police.
Yeah.
In other words,
she told the fucking truth and then when
they fucking sobered up or calm down,
they were like, this could cost us
a lot of money. Don't do it again.
And we'll say that I lied.
Courtney denies that she attended that
meeting and Zach also recalled a to Osu
investigators that she wasn't there.
Okay.
So he sounds like he's lying,
uh, to the investigative team.
Courtney Smith denied
recanting her allegations.
She has never walked back any
allegations in public interviews either.
All right.
No charges were ultimately filed
against Zach for the 2009 incident.
Uh, yeah, cause they were working for
a big university when Meyer, well,
how does this go on urban Meyer?
Mayor Meyer hired him at Ohio state in
2011 a university background check didn't
turn up and arrest.
Meyer didn't tell anyone else at Ohio
state about it because he told Invesco
charges weren't filed and he didn't
think Zach had actually committed any
domestic violence between October
and November, 2050. And what,
what's the show that he even saw the shit,
uh,
in October and November,
2015 police twice went to court.
He's home to investigate abuse
allegations against Zach to this one.
These deals with, it's like, well you
just fucking break up already. Um,
that year Courtney texted with
Mayor's wife Shelly about Zach.
Shelly expressed sympathy and fear
for Courtney and her own message.
And Courtney has said,
Shelley told her she'd informed the
head coach about Courtney's allegations.
Yeah, but she could have been
lying. You know, both mayor
Meyer maintain to Osu investigators that
Shelly never did inform urban about the
text messages. But myra has
acknowledged both in a public statement,
early August and two investigators that
he did know of an allegation in 2015
I don't understand. So what, so he
knows about it. So call the fucking cops
like I don't understand
like why this is on
the football fucking program.
They are,
they are not the cops. They are
not judges. They are not juries.
This whole fucking thing now where like
the judge and the jury and all of that
shit is now on social media and all
of this shit. It's fucking, I don't,
I don't get this.
It's like if he fucking did something
called the cops, the cops go there,
they fucking arrest him and
he fucking goes to jail.
I don't understand how the cops go there.
I re candidate. No you didn't. All right.
We dropped the fucking charges,
but then the cops dropped the charges,
but then the school is supposed to
go. No, but you still fucking guilty.
I don't know.
I mean, unless he was there
and saw him doing that shit,
what the fuck is he supposed to do?
This is why you have cops.
This is why the cops don't
coach a football team. Um,
I dunno. I have no idea. I don't,
I don't get that. I get that.
If the university fired that guy,
you know,
I don't get why urban
mayor Meyer,
why that guy gets dragged into this shit.
I mean,
if he was beating the shit out of her
ed at a fucking football practice,
then I guess urban was there going,
hey, settle down. Settle down.
Nothing to see here. And I guess he
implicated himself by that. I mean,
I don't,
you know,
yeah.
I mean, these, these are,
these are fucking adults here.
That guy knows he's not supposed to be
beaten up his fucking wife. He's an adult.
So he should pay the fucking price.
I don't get why this guy has to do now.
You know what I mean? When some gold
digging horror fucking, uh, you know,
take some guy's house. Uh, does she
go to jail? Does she lose her job?
Does her friend that knew she was a
gold digging hoard is she then lose her
fucking position in the fucking
world? I don't get just, it's just,
it's just like,
it's a fucking one side street here.
If a guy does something to a
woman that he shouldn't be doing,
not only is he going to get punished now
everybody around them is going to get
fucking punished. But if a woman does
something to a guy, eh, it's all right.
Everything's fucking fine. It's
fucking bullshit. That's what I say.
I think it's fucking bullshit.
If they are doing this on both
sides of the fucking fence,
if you could somehow prove that this
guy actually fucking knew this shit.
Granted, I'm just going off of
one website here. All right.
From what I read on the Internet,
which doesn't mean shit. Now,
what do you guys asked me these fucking
questions. All right, dancing. Hey Bill.
I'm a 16 year old kid from Minnesota,
Minnesota and I'm starting my
junior year in high school week.
I'm not a loser and I'm not the coolest
kid either. I'm right. Yeah, there you go.
You're in the mill.
That's where I was.
I feel like I'm being held
back by my inability to dance.
What do you go to fame high school.
It's not that I don't have rhythm.
I play three instruments.
My Band leader told me to dance
like I was playing an instruments.
The problem is I never know what to do
with my hands and it can't exactly be
playing air sacks at dances this year.
I really don't care that much.
It's just that I know I can dance,
but I haven't figured out moves yet all.
Then start dancing there buddy.
Okay,
go on the fucking Internet.
I'll go on the Internet right now.
Find you a fucking video and then practice
by yourself and do it in the mirror
like the chicks do, right?
All right. You Tube, you tube,
you can dance to. All right. Search.
Okay.
Basic dance moves to not look stupid.
I just felt stupid with an e at the end.
What the stupid.
How to dance with confidence.
Not Look like a Dork.
And I gotta tell you this
Guy Club dance moves for men.
How to not look stiff and
awkward. Bam. There you go.
Here we go.
A three minute video after this fucking
stupid God damn guide tells me about
great nuts standing on
a fucking mountain does.
I'm always just started running naked.
How to dance for men.
It's an Asian kid with the cool hat. You
know he's going to be good. There you go.
Bam. The name of this video
is club dance moves for men.
How to not look stiff and awkward
for beginner. All right dude,
I found that in two fucking sec. Second.
So right. There you go. There you go.
You're in.
So just fucking do that for a while
till it's second God damn nature.
Put a little stank on your face and uh,
you know,
pump up fucking couple of
drinks in yourself. Now. I
know you're under age. Uh,
you'll be fine. You'll be fine.
Just do it. Learn how to, how,
how did you learn how to get
good at saxophone? Did you
sit there going, you know,
I know I can play saxophone, but you
never did it. Just go out and do it.
You'll be fine. All right,
Solo. Fucking dear bill.
This old house. I'm a home owner
like yourself and like yourself.
I looked into solar power.
Hey Dude, not for nothing.
I want to be a contact or do you
have you paid off your house?
Cause he'd be haven't paid off your
house. You're not a homeowner. All right.
What you own is the debt on the house.
Okay. I hate when people go, oh, you,
you ran home. I am. No,
you dumb. You don't know.
You don't own it until I give it to you.
That did fucking God damn piece of
paper. Sorry. And like yourself.
I looked into solar power bill.
When I tell you I spent over 200 hours
reading up on solar and talking to
different installers on
telling you the truth.
I had zero luck finding
anything that made sense. Yeah.
I think there's a lot of taxes and shit.
There's a lot of oil and coal kind
of jockeying against that shit. Um,
the more research I did,
the more discouraged I got.
I went in thinking there was no way I
wouldn't come out with some type of solar
panel subsidizing the energy I use.
Yeah.
Now they do this thing
where the electric company,
they used to buy back your power.
Now they just claim the shit that you
don't even use. Um, I hate to be cynical,
but I feel like solar is useless
till the technology gets better.
I don't know if you've ever
followed through, but I was
hoping to get an update.
Um, I don't think it's
useless. I understand. Um,
anything that is going to help us
slow down fucking global warming.
Okay.
Is going to be an asset if you can't
afford to do it. I understand. Um,
I have not done it yet.
Um,
I keep telling my wife I want
to do and she's just like,
this is going to be loud.
And then it's just like, you
know, I would love to do it.
I have some Spanish style,
not are on all the whole roof.
My roof is flat and then there's
little lip of Spanish tiles,
but like a Tesla is allegedly
coming out with those,
those Spanish tiles that
are also solar powered. Um,
I mean that fucking guy is like actually
addressing what's going on and I wish
there was a way that he could fucking
hire coal miners to fucking work in the
solar industry so they didn't have to
take away 30% of our beautiful public
parks to continue using this fucking
form of energy that is fucking with the
planet. That for some reason you're
not allowed to bring it up. If you do,
you're crying snowflake.
MMM,
I dunno.
It's
okay.
I have no idea. And I have not write up
as nearly as much as you have a, I have,
I have not even overheard as much
as you've probably read on it. Um,
I'll read up on it. I should do
it. I would love to do it. Um,
you know, but I just, every time
I fucking go to do something,
I'd fucking something in my house.
I only tell you guys what I'm
fucking dealing with right now.
I don't even want to fuck on failure.
What on the fucking deal with them. Uh,
have you ever heard a
roof? Rats, roof rats?
Uh,
evidently we somehow,
some way we have a crawl space between
our roof and you know, you can't stand up,
but it was enough that these
fucking mice get up there and I,
we have an exterminator come up there.
You know,
God knows what they did in the walls.
Thank God they didn't chew through
any fucking wires. And, uh, you know,
so then I got to go up there and,
you know, get rid of the dead mice.
Okay.
That's my life. Okay.
Sobriety. Hey Billy Bama set.
Yeah,
I'm a 27 year old male and I just wanted
to truly say thank you for helping me
onto the wagon of sobriety.
Forget the past few months,
every since he started listening to your
podcasts and have heard you bitch and
moan the whole time about
being sober from drinking.
This made me think to myself, hey, if
this can, this can can do it. So can I.
It's been a few weeks now and I've been
clean from drugs and alcohol and I've
never felt better. Yeah, it was
fucking amazing. Not living a clean,
I mean at night it sucks.
That's when you get squirrely.
But if you just fucking push through
it and you wake up in the morning stone
sober, it's, it's like you feel
like you've compared to, you know,
being hung over and shit. And I never
even fucked with drugs other than alcohol,
which is a drug in all fairness.
Um,
you feel like an eight year
old when you wake up. He says,
I don't have friends because
they're dead beat drug addict,
losers every day at my job I list,
I literally listened to eight hours
of the podcasts a day. Um, see,
see you're learning how to take your
addictive personality and it had been
pointing it at shit that's more positive.
Hopefully this positive
is more pod positive.
So in a sense you're my only
friends so thanks for that as well.
Thanks for helping me through these
trying times and I really look forward to
maybe seeing your set at one of your
Chicago shows in November. Hey, you know,
I was hanging out Friday night with a
buddy of mine who's been sober for nine
months and he just wanted to do it
for a month, but just after a month,
all this shit that
you've been putting off,
all of a sudden he started
getting shit done. He said,
I'm going to go two months and
now he's just staying sober.
He was saying just start a superstition
that I don't want to go back to that.
And,
um,
that's a great thing.
So I'm going to try to go September
without drinking today. I have,
I have,
my big cheat thing is I have a glass
bottle of grape phanta that I am going to
have, um, with my burger and then I'm
right back on the wagon, but a pretty,
but I'm going to be eaten,
you know,
eating healthy the rest day.
I hate that when people say I'm eating,
I've been eating clean,
you know,
I like, I, I just, I don't like that.
Okay.
Yeah. You know, just clean
eating, but eating clean.
It's like you don't even know
what the fuck you're reading.
I go to these farmer's markets and you
have no idea where this shit came from.
Okay.
There's nobody down there play.
I've heard like the FDA basically
polices like 3% of the food.
You have no idea where
the fuck it came from.
Okay.
You have no fucking idea.
You have no idea what it's been
sprayed with and all of that shit.
But it says organic and it gets in your
fucking hair. UHMM Leeton fucking clean.
You have no fucking idea
unless you grew it yourself.
Um, dilemma. Um,
all right,
dear Billy Brown belt.
Okay.
Would you rather be forced to eat protein
bars every meal for the rest of your
life or eat one meal every four days?
MMM.
Can I survive?
Can I survive eating one
meal every four days?
Okay.
I don't know if he could
survive doing that,
man.
That's a good one.
No,
I'd rather you one meal every four days.
I think it would be more healthy than
those protein bars cause you don't know
what the fuck's in those things either.
You mean you flip that thing over like a
Django anyway. Thanks. Fucking overrated.
GNC.
Okay.
All those powdered fucking
chemicals like that Maca powder.
Every time I put that in there and go,
what the fuck is this shit?
You know,
plant based protein powder
and all that. It's Cisco. We'll go
eat a fucking plant. Um, anyways,
number two. All right.
Now that dilemma. Um,
I wouldn't want to be Billy Clif
bar for the rest of my fucking life
cause once every four
days I could actually, uh,
yeah,
I could actually have
something that I liked.
Beto chicken and dumplings, some shit
like that. Something really fancy. Let me,
there'll be like having a death
row fucking meal every four days.
Yeah, that would be
tremendous. Um, as long as you,
I could do that in a healthy
way. Yeah, I would do that.
You get used to that quick. Um,
number two, you're going to die,
but you can save your life if
you succeed at one of two things,
which do you have more
confidence in doing successfully?
Having one year to study and get a
perfect score on the sats. Fuck that.
Or come in first place
in a game of monopoly.
I have one year to come in,
first place in a game of monopoly.
How many games can I play?
Um,
is it a monopoly tournament?
My plane with a bunch of old ladies that
have been playing it since the fucking
depression and they're going
to kick my ass. All right.
Having one year to study and get a perfect
score on the sats. You know what, Dude,
I would love to try to do that.
Okay.
And it would take me way more than a year
with the math.
Um, all I know is that
I took a college, uh,
sat prep course and I still got,
I got a three something combined.
I'm not even fucking lying to you
guys. Like I, that sounds like a joke,
but I mean an Uber, you can
do the two porches to signing
the paper. Yeah, I know.
I know.
I forget what I got. I got, did I get
a four, 10 or a three 90? It was bad.
And I remember getting
laughs at my sat score.
Yeah.
That's how, you know,
that's how I always say no,
he's fucking made fun of myself and I,
and I got laughs so I actually,
okay.
I remember I didn't give a shit.
I never gave a shit.
I always kind of always kind of had
this feeling that I was going to do all
right in life.
You know,
I had an overall positive outlook
despite everything that I was doing.
You don't have two years of a language.
Yeah.
He all his fucking stupid shit.
You know what I mean?
That's not a, life is not
about those things. All right?
I'm not saying don't try,
don't fucking try to do well on
the thing and all of that shit.
I'm not fucking saying that.
Well, what are you saying, bill?
I'm just saying there's, there's a
million ways to skin a cat. Okay.
How the fuck did that come about?
Huh? I will look that one up.
It's more than one to skin a cat.
Right?
There's more than one
way to skin a cat origin
and early appearance is in
way down east to Jesus Christ.
Okay.
What, what, what? Okay.
Etymology of the phrase, this
more one. More than one. Which,
you know, so many times when you look
these up, it's just not satisfying.
Okay.
MMM.
So there's actually only two ways to
skin a cat while it's alive or while it's
dead. Well, I mean,
you could also start at the head.
You could start at the back.
Didn't want to say the ass.
There are two ways. One,
one of them is you skin a cat
cause you are a bad person.
The other is you don't skin a cat.
You are a nice
yeah.
Or the cat never existed.
The third one,
weight is both you skin a cat and
at the same time you don't skin it.
Okay.
This is just people writing.
I find your use of boiled down
in this context disturbing.
You knew this would, this would bring
out all the fucking animal lovers, right?
Let's see if there's any comments from the
fucking Peta people, Peta people, Peta,
Peta people.
There's more than one way to skin a cat
is not referring to the removal of flesh
from our feline friends,
but rather a phrase that originated
from the Mississippi River region that
pertains to the preparation of a catfish.
Okay.
Oh,
okay.
Oh
well maybe that's what it is. I have
no idea. I don't fucking know. Anyways,
that's the podcast.
Happy Labor Day to y'all.
Happy Labor Day to you.
Woo.
Woo are fucking check
in on you this Thursday.
Hey,
go fuck yourselves and enjoy your day.
Ah,
fuck it.