Hey, what's going on? Spill bird.
It's time for the Monday
morning podcasts from Monday,
April 23rd,
2018 what's going on?
How are you?
How's it going?
I'm actually recording
this on fucking Wednesday.
April 25th case.
You listening to this and the future
and you wanted to know what was going on
with me as far as my health goes. Now
notice I said, as far as my health goes,
instead of health wise,
I learned in vocab improvement
back in high school.
There's no such thing as the
wiseguys healthwise weather wise.
You know, that's why I can never
listen to come fly with me. Why the,
why is it such a lovely day?
A frank, I know you connected,
but that's improper grammar.
All right?
I'm not attacking you or your heritage
of the fact that you from New Jersey,
right? You overly sensitive so-and-so,
um, of just saying that, that's, you know,
I don't know who wrote that song.
Okay.
So why don't you Scooby Doo
da that, that, that blew over.
Do a fucking dictionary and you,
you find me wise Francis.
Um, am I really trashing a dead fucking
Frank Sinatra? Sorry, I'm, I'm a, I'm,
I'm almost lied and tried to tell
you I'm going call medication,
but I don't take cold medication.
Cold medication is for
fucking millennials.
All right. And even if you're older and
you take it, you're a millennial at heart,
he can't deal with the fact that you
got yourself sick. You need to lay down,
get eight hours and let your body
fucking go through it. All right?
The reason why your nose is running this
cause it's trying to get the virus, it
just led an APP. He's fucking
assholes. I swear to God, man.
The amount of people that gave me advice,
you know,
there's no cure for the common cold, but
everybody thinks they have one. You know,
I'd sink. I'd go ted twice.
And Zinc shot a whiskey.
Dube I manager told me, he goes,
vitamin D, everybody thinks it's,
see vitamin D unbelievable.
Well,
the greatest managers in the world, and
he also knows the cure for a cold. I mean,
who knew that? Just
fucking we could Dave. Um,
let's get that out on the way.
Jesus Christ.
This is just the cold that won't quit.
This is the cold that's letting me
know that mother nature is regrouping.
You know,
right now we're squeezing her all right.
Like the way Andre,
the giant was squeezed in fucking Hulk
Hogan in that documentary and they lifted
mother nature's arm and they're dropping
it down and they lifted up to dropping
it down. And I'm like, oh my God,
the bad guys are going to win.
And I went point or I'm just going to
stay there and she's going to start
shaking a fucking blonde hair.
That was always my favorite part.
When oak would start coming back and
he'd give him that one big head and then
he'd walk around the ring looking up and
they look it up at the rafters to his
head. Uh, that was the best. I watched
that documentary like three times.
And when, uh, when, um, I watched that,
that part of the fight with NEA,
we were both laughing our asses
off in a great way, like day,
just some of the greatest fucking
performers of all time and professional
wrestlers.
You know,
when I was growing up right through
the rock and all those guys,
like their ability,
stone cold, all of them,
their ability to work a crowd is just,
it's second to none.
You know,
I got a buddy might still
going like, dude, the Yampa
isn't it like a fake fight,
you know is but isn't it like
a fake fight? It's just like I,
how fucking dumb are you?
It's like,
yes,
it's entertainment.
They take fucking set at like
30 years ago at some guy cried.
All right.
And the greatest thing they ever did was
say that it was all arranged and all of
that shit for the most part.
So then they could actually talk about
how fucking heart they got when they
actually would do in these fake fights.
I had to tell Burnsy that like fuzzy,
if you knew,
okay,
we had a fake fight and I said I was
going to pick you up and throw you across
the room and you're going to
land on your back, you know,
that would still hurt even though,
you know,
we arranged that I was going to happen.
Right. Physics is still in play there. No,
sorry,
I'm a little hot here with this fucking
Mike's and I was having a problem with
my recorder here. Oh God.
Um, so believe it or not,
I'm actually on the
other side of this thing.
I completely lost my voice by uh,
by Sunday and uh,
so I started gargling with a little bit
of a apple cider vinegar and some salt
in there and that kind of
cleared me up a little bit. Um,
I'll do that shit but I'm not going down
to the fucking drug store even though I
did and I bought all this shit and I
just looked at the ingredients. I'm like,
I'm not putting this in my fucking body.
So basically what?
I kicked the shit out of my fucking liver
so this medicine can fool my fucking
or knows that I don't have a cold.
I apologize to file stuff Ian.
But I got to do this cause I'm going to
be fucking backed up on podcasts cause I
got the Thursday one tomorrow.
I'm liking that.
I love Lucy sketch where they
got the chocolates coming down,
except it's podcasting. I mean, Christ,
I don't have time for this shit.
Guess what the fuck I watched
yesterday on the plane coming back,
actually went up to Boston and I
visited with my family back east and I'm
on a two by the way,
the fucking anger that is
still in Massachusetts.
It's not really what the younger kids,
which kind of makes me happy
and a little bit sad. You know,
some point you do have
to let go of the anger,
but hope I help all the
characters are still around.
But I was driving through my,
uh,
my old neighborhood and I this cop direct
and traffic and a little fucking three
way stop and he tells this guy
to stop and evidently he didn't.
And the cop starts flipping
out and I'm like, fucking two,
three cars down the line. So I,
I can't hear what the guy saying,
but he is fucking flailing his
arms like Earl weaver, right?
He manages the Orioles above
fucking 40 years ago. Sorry. Um,
yeah.
And I'm laughing my balls off. How
fucking angry is it? The Sky. Right.
And then when he gets the guy to stop
and then the other key waves us to start
going,
like that's not enough for him.
He walks up to the guy's car
and starts screaming at him.
So I'm thinking maybe this is some young
punk with his radio turned up and he's
not listening to the cop.
I show up,
it's like some old dude with like white
hair and this fucking eight foot cop is
screaming at a
Ah,
I dunno how you'd do it. I would
not, I would not have handled that.
Well if he came up to my window,
there's no way I would've been like relax
and then I would have been, you know,
in cuffs.
Cause she can't tell a guy who's flipping
out and screaming at you to fucking
relax.
I need to learn my rights for those
moments because I am a control freak and I
forget that.
I don't know how to fight in those moments
and I just immediately go to go fuck
yourself.
And then,
and then the ramification cups
that I am not prepared for.
MMM.
I actually got angry for that guy.
Okay.
And started, drove past the cops saying
all this shit to the cop in my car,
to myself as if I was that guy
talking to that cop of fucking nuts.
Is that or is that normal? Is that
something you do? I just feel like for me,
Jesus Christ,
um,
I haven't been this sick
since I'd been a dad.
She was fucking brutal to get this sick
when you're a dad because then you can't
hug a kid.
Uh,
which is the worst. I mean, that's what
you have a kid for seeking hog up, right.
In lie about what you did when you were
a kid. Right? That's what you did. Wow.
I used to make my bed every day.
I did all my homework.
I was never a problem for my parents.
Okay.
Um, anyways, I, uh, I
had a fucking amazing we,
so I got to work the Ryman once again.
It's the third time I've been
there. I did Vince violence, uh,
Nashville Comedy Festival in 2014 then
I did it again in 2016 I take my last
special there, walk your way
out, and then I got to do it. Uh,
one show Friday lunch,
so Saturday and they brought me a drum
kit and shit to play on and I was so sick
I couldn't play. It felt bad. And um,
I had a splitting fucking headache,
but the shows were really fun.
And I actually a, I always hit that
Jack's barbecue next door and then,
uh, I went to the Woolworth,
they've got a Woolworths sales,
like you owe the fucking lunch counter
like where they had like back in the day
during segregation where they just like
only white people can sit here and get a
grilled cheese sandwich.
God made everybody in his image.
Buddy made us closer to his image and
he loves his chest a little bit better
because of that.
We get to see it at this shine
and counter that RSD you on.
Why, why, and why fucking play
evil guy to go around bag.
Uh, so I sat down, I got a
fucking cheeseburger. They're,
you know, taking pictures.
Just, I went into Woolworth's,
like a white person going,
oh my God, I remember these things. You
know, he used to be able to buy from,
can assure it.
And then get a cheeseburger.
So I walked in not realizing
the historical, um,
magnitude or what I was walking
into. I was just walking, okay,
you guys tell self sharps hair,
nobody.
We doubt we don't.
And I walked right up
to the fucking count.
I was taking pictures and shit and
everybody thought I was like some fucking
historian and I was,
I was as excited that had the same
emotional historical context to me is if I
walked into a Jordan Marsh,
did they have Jordan Marsh as anymore?
Do you remember all those?
All those defunct superstores
it's funny,
they were evil when they came up cause
they put out the mom and pop businesses
and then eventually when you watch
them get eaten, you love you.
You ended up feeling bad for them.
Places like mammoth Martin,
you remember mammoth mart and a big woolly
mammoth child world got destroyed by
fucking toys r us leach mayor.
They lost out to the fucking best buys
radio shack to still a few of them left
over. You know what I mean? They're like,
fucking old Nazis is still,
a couple of them are running around
scurrying around South America.
You know what I mean? Trying to get a
fucking tangent fit in with the regulars.
Right.
Well some of the other ones
that they used to have,
I can't even remember
anyone so long goes filings,
Jordan Marsh than Macy's just came along.
It just fucked him all up.
Just fucked him all up.
Okay.
Bloomingdale's beat the
fuck out of everybody.
And then you had all those like storage
she just heard about. But you know,
like Saks fifth avenue
when I was a little kid, I,
they might've been one in Boston,
but I think if you wanted to go to Saks
fifth avenue had to go to fifth avenue.
Yeah.
In New York City.
And nobody really fucking knew all of the,
all of that, all of that
designer shit that, um,
all the kids were nowadays like,
and I was like mobile, Alabama.
They had like a fucking, uh, Louis Vitton
store. They never used to have that shit.
You know what I mean?
They only had three series of the BMW,
the three, the five and the
seven till they also had the sex.
If you could afford one of those,
go fuck yourself.
Okay.
They didn't make it fucking SUV. I
didn't think. I don't think they did.
They didn't have a one series, a
to series of four series, you know,
just fucking doing anything they can.
That's like wouldn't miss Mercedes
Benz drop their co? Not that quality,
but they dropped it all the way
down where you could buy the uh,
was it the one 90? He the baby
Benz, they used to call it.
All of sudden you drive around in
Mercedes Benz that cost the same amount of
money as a Monte Carlo.
Right. And you were,
there's a Monte Carlo fucking t
top pot dealing Douche, you know,
who would it looked right
in his Oldsmobile cutlass.
But instead you'd ride around this one
90. He like, you're fucking sophisticated.
Everybody saw right through
your Keno second he got out
of the fucking car. Right
though your personal belongings fall
on the fucking ground, you know,
some scale to weigh your product.
Okay.
I know what I'm talking about,
but when I was a kid,
all the cool older guys to guys who
were like 25 which to me was a man.
You had a mustache,
you had your own place.
Okay.
It check was living with you and you
can fuck her whenever you wanted.
You know my id is a 14 year old
dude. He lives with her. They can,
he can fuck her whenever
he wants to not realize it.
Not realizing like the fucking
that he was probably looking at me,
envious of me.
Go look at that fucking orange headed,
hairless faced fucking loser over there.
He's got it all ahead of does
it have any credit card bills?
It doesn't have some broad living with it.
A bitch moaning and complaining about
where he leaves his fucking neon green
fucking sunglasses. Anyways.
But when I was looking at him,
they were the coolest people ever. And
then there was, there was the Buick Regal,
the Monte Carlo and
the Oldsmobile cutlass,
and they would get these two door coops.
And if you got the fucking t top,
you know, I loved, I loved the guy
that went down to the fucking art,
whatever the whatever auto parts store.
Okay,
got the auto zone's eight all up.
If you go down there.
And I remember people would get their,
uh, they put curb finders on them,
they'd cut tee tops at them.
They get the glass tinted,
the fucking headlights
and all these cheesy shit.
They'd get a custom license plate
on the front, said like Mikey,
you know,
and then you are the fucking mad
if you actually get a CD player.
And Emma, that was a big thing like you
gotta like it was an external thing.
I remember this, I knew it. He had
a fucking Volkswagen shall Rocco,
which looks cute. I swear to God
that was the name of the car. Um,
and he had this fucking
CD player and it was like,
it was like an external hard drives.
Like you had to plug this cord in that
Ben plugged into the CD that was mounted
on the armrests between
the two bucket seats.
And if you even hiccuped in the car,
the CD skipped,
but it was still fucking is Sayed.
And then of course she had to have your
radar detector for the fucking state he
stowed. And all of that is God. You
know it back then. If you got a cold,
you put a little Vick's vapor rub on
your fucking chest. And that was it.
Now what did they cut? Uh, Jesus
Christ. At least they could fucking,
they can hold off the HIV virus.
Now you'd think that they could fucking,
you know,
do something about the call.
But you always pay a price is always a
price to pay. You know, he's always pay,
you know, the battered fucking wife
of your organs is your fucking liver.
And liver always takes it.
You know what I mean?
You fuck up in other areas and
then you take your medicine, right?
You're scatterbrain alluded tank can't
get to sleep. See, take some Tylenol.
PM and who pays for it?
Huh? You're fucking liver.
Um,
how many times are you going to have
your liver have to walk around with his
eyes looking down at your fucking
colon, you know, as the other fucking
organs are going, what happened?
I walked into the ribs.
Is he making light of domestic violence?
Yes,
I am. Um, I think that's the
problem with this country.
There needs to be more domestic violence.
We actually live in an era that someone
wouldn't even look at that even remotely
is fucking absurd.
And in an era where in fucking,
I can't say the word anymore,
okay.
People unlike the, uh, the Internet,
we'll just take that clip and
they try to get you in trouble.
You know what I mean? Everybody's rat
and everybody out. Like, you know,
I really looked at that fucking
Conor McGregor thing, who's that guy?
Videotape and at four.
Yeah.
And then he fucking puts it up on the
fucking Internet and just get sis guy and
all this fucking trouble. I'm not saying
Conor McGregor was right, but like,
who's this fucking ass? I was there.
I would have videotaped that shit.
I would just be like, wow, glad
I wasn't on that bus. Right.
You know,
I mean,
that guy's a reason.
Everybody on that bus was making fucking
a zillion dollars anyways is any,
I can't every once in a while throw a
fucking two wheeler and a God damn by me
chief. He had the fucking champ, you know?
Okay.
You'll get a little bit of leeway.
All it takes is one fucking Douche with
his flip phone and all of a sudden he's
down there talking to the,
I don't want to talking about,
guess what today is everybody.
Oh,
it's gained seven for the Boston Bruins.
Um,
everybody's freaking out and
all this shit. I'm like, God,
we have three games to one.
Who gives a fuck?
How are we going to do is win tonight?
Well,
you going to do is win tonight and no
one fucking remembers so many series than
a three to one go to game seven.
It happens all the fucking time.
MMM.
I will say though,
as a Bruins fan,
if I see or didn't have to listen to one
more commentator tell me that it was a
stretch pass.
Okay.
MMM.
You know, and Jesus Christ said,
Anderson is played so great for Toronto.
I don't know why he does all that,
flop it around.
You literally skate by that guy when
knocks him off his fucking feet.
Just shameless, shameless. But, uh,
I liked the fucking maple leafs,
you know what I mean?
Despite the timidly cocky fans on
Twitter who said absolutely nothing,
and now all of a sudden, you know, they're
like mere cats. You know what I mean?
What a fucking Cobra comes around and
they all sit there lunging at you and shit
talking all this shit as a backup.
If they're not really going to fight and
they try to appear bigger than they are.
Um, I got no beef. What's around you
guys went tonight. Congratulations.
I can get past it. I don't
give a fuck. Right. Um,
I know that we're a team of the future
and so you guys this still probably be
the beginning of a great rivalry.
That's what we need.
God knows because the Canadians
are in the fucking shit. Um,
I have his fucking guy that like,
I can't remember how fuck I met him.
So like a Gig a long time
ago and he drove his Sam,
somebody got my phone number this fucking
con to every year during the playoffs.
The brewers do so good.
One of those fucking
Douche is so I've finally,
I just finally blocked his number.
Like, I don't, I don't get,
I'll get this kid's like, I get it. You
fucking drove me to a couple of gigs.
I get to listen to your fucking horseshit
shit. Every time we're doing bad.
There's so many fucking country
sports fans like that. Um,
and after almost 20 years
of voting a cell phone,
I finally learned how to block people.
I love it.
It's fucking love it.
It's just like
if somebody I used to work
with to this business fucking,
I dunno what the fuck his deal was,
he fucking started calling
me and emailing me, you know,
block over.
You know what I mean?
It's like you get to assassinate somebody
without having to kill him and deal
with the guilt,
you know?
Okay.
I wonder if in the future when we're all
just being watched by robots and every
blessed thing you do is videotaped.
Uh,
so you can't do anything wrong.
I wonder if they'll have to switch
the commandments just so they can get
somebody in trouble because
nobody can do anything anymore.
So rather than thou shall not kill
the fifth commandment, we'll be,
thou shall not block
somebody on your cell phone.
You shall not assassinate them digitally.
I'm sorry,
did I just,
did I just float out a perfect
premise for the next blade runner?
Uh, no I didn't. I did not. However,
there was that movie that came out where
people had to take a test and if you
know, when the world was
overpopulated, those fucking cards,
where the hell did you get that idea?
God bless him. But you know what I mean?
How about a tip of the cap?
Uh,
anyways, sorry. People
have just at a fucking,
I just had a headache for so fucking long.
I did buy some bare aspart
I did that. Uh, Celtics.
Everybody.
How about those Boston Celtics.
How about the high or the Boston Celtics?
And how about those fucking Milwaukee
Bucks? This is the best day Ben,
since back with like Sidney Moncrief,
you know,
then they got that white dude from fucking
the Seattle Sonics with that fuck was
his name Jack Sigma.
Um,
but I have to be honest with you dude,
the basketball is so fucking awful.
Then I'm watching,
did I even playing hoop?
It looks like a fucking pickup game
and an unbelievably high level.
How many fucking times can you throw
up at three with nobody underneath?
Okay,
let me, I don't understand that
new little semicircle there.
I got to read up on it in the paint.
Is it illegal if you don't have the ball
as an offensive player to get under the
fucking rim was the last time you saw a
center post up and put his hand in the
air and do a couple up and under.
She got a little Kevin Mchale action.
Little Sky Hook.
It's all fucking God.
You just run down the court a little
pass and then the guy just takes a three
point.
I had 10 go in or somebody does so
and one shit to try to get around.
A guy dropped a, it's
fucking, it's horrible.
I think a lot of the
entire second quarter,
I don't think I saw one pick and roll.
You know,
there's a reason that they did that for
fucking close to 80 years. It works.
I dunno why everybody's trying to
do this globe trotters shit data.
Uh, having said that, I love
where we're going in the future.
I just don't like the future of the game.
I guess people got too big.
Is that what it was?
Um,
I miss the bang and down low in the paint,
you know,
and then fucking old school yard play
with the guy's leaning against you leave
it and you stepped out behind him. Like
he pulled his chair out, he falls down.
Then they'd stand up and
get in each other's grills.
The little fucking ref came up to the
dicks. Who's trying to push them apart?
I miss all of that dumb ass shit,
man. I miss the way you smell.
Um, I actually got to be honest
with you. I shut the game off.
Okay.
Cause I was so fucking mad. Cause I
hate NBA hoop. I just hate basketball.
I just hate how no lead is safe.
It's like you're up by 40,
you go with the kitchen and then you make
a sandwich and it's like the audit team
follow the three pointer. This
could tie it up. It's just like,
can there ever be,
can you ever just have an easy win?
Um,
I just felt myself getting ready to throw
something at the fucking TV and I got
a kid now so I can't,
so I just shut it off and I was just,
and I just watched the score throughout
the fourth quarter. Then they wanted,
I was like good, uh, uh, more
of a hockey guy obviously. Um,
that, having said that, I,
you know, of course I have to,
I've got to edit some shift for
emphasis of family tonight. Um,
but I'll get to watch most of the game.
It's only a game seven,
you know, um, I'm very excited for this.
Got To love the game seven.
Even if your team was up three to one
who gives a fuck gotta love a game.
Seven and a, and here's the
deal is if we lose the Toronto,
that's my team for the rest of the
playoffs because they haven't won since 67
and uh,
I think it's high time that they get and
it'd be cool to see Winnipeg get their
first one. So those are my
two teams. Those are my onesy.
Twosy alright. Uh, so there you go.
Did she have fucking Bruins
is NBA and Nhl Hay fever.
Fucking talk for the God
damn week. Oh, you know what?
I forgot to fucking mentioned.
I started to mention it,
but maybe I'll mention it after I,
I do a little law.
I got one read for this week. All right,
bye. [inaudible] me on Ds me undies.
Get in the fucking paint
to do dooby ids me undies,
throw it down to is tanked.
Sped around and fucking dunk it.
Stop throwing up threes if you please.
It's fucking boring.
I feel like I'm at the fucking
YFCA except people can't dunk.
You've heard me talk about me undies
and you know that I'm a big believer in
their product. They just sent me another
bag of underwear. These guys got to stop.
It's just like I don't have a
bladder problem. Okay, I get it.
You guys make a lot of underwear.
I have some and I like it.
You don't need to send me
some every fucking month.
Treat me like you fucking
underwear horror on the side. Uh,
there perfect balance of comfortable fit.
Every month they have new and exciting
prince and they arrive at your door in a
fun bag. Me Undies, uh,
uses lenses.
Micro Modal,
modal in their underwear.
It's sustainably sourced.
Naturally soft fiber that starts with
beechwood trees and ends with the most.
Imagine amazing fabric
you've ever experienced.
I don't know why that is in the
fucking copy, at least in my copy.
My listeners are not smart.
I'm not smart.
When you start saying that your
underwear is made out of trees,
we start thinking about kittens. Split
us in our under carriage. You know,
Joe, do you hear about fucking Fitzy
can't have kids is fucking underwear.
It was being out of beechwood trees.
He fucking took them off too fast.
He stabbed both his balls.
He's got older,
he's gotten to much is left well
because it ran down his leg. Kid.
You elicited a fucking story.
The results have been downright dreamy
beyond these adventurous prints and
designs are all limited
editions. Yeah, it just, I,
I wouldn't even take them out
of the rap. You know, who knows?
Someday somebody might want to collect
them like action figures and new patterns
are released every few weeks on a rolling
basis. 100% satisfaction guarantee.
Okay,
a guarantee me on these guarantees,
you will love their undies or your money
back if he didn't know what a guarantee
was. Me undies has a great offer for my
listeners, so whenever the fuck else,
they gave us two for any
first time purchasers, when
you purchase any me undies,
you get 20% off at a fed free shipping
beyond these is so sure you'll love their
own to where they offer 100%
satisfaction guaranteed.
You already fucking said this.
If you don't love the first pair,
you get a full refund. That's a
no brainer. Get 20% off a pair.
The most comfortable undies he will ever
put on to get you 20% off your first
pair of free shipping. One
upset, satisfactory care tick.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bar that's me, undies.com/bar.
All right,
so I've tasted twice.
Let me see.
Liverpool football share. Joel,
what do they play next?
I was on the plane and I actually watched
level Liverpool versus fucking Roma.
Eh? It was a shock. It was a
blowout. It was an awesome game.
Liverpool went up five to fucking nothing.
Saturday 4:30 AM
I don't I? I just, I just don't
fucking get how this shit works.
They play in Roma.
Isn't that like Rome?
Yeah,
that's the Champions
League. Semifinal leg.
Two of two.
Okay.
Aggregate two to five.
Yeah, they won five to two.
Okay,
so they're going to play again on May
2nd is that because they scored five
goals? Enrollments coma score too.
What's the coincidence of that?
I just don't understand it because
they were up five to nothing.
And then all of a sudden Roma Roma scored
a goal and then they scored another
one on a penalty kick and
then they would say it.
Then the dancers are going nuts.
Okay.
Like what are they?
And it's like fucking two minutes left.
Why they flipping out like
they going to lose this case.
I think there were some sort of tournament
that happens at the same time that
the premiere ship is being played.
It's weird,
but that's the Champions League
and I think Liverpool, Chelsea,
that's the Premiere Premiere League,
right? They do it at the same,
somebody from the love of God,
somebody over there in Great Britain,
somewhere around the fucker world
explained to me what's going on.
Cause I actually really enjoyed,
um,
the fucking game to this guy. Holy Shit.
This Egyptian dude who kind of look,
he looks like an Egyptian Judd Apatow.
Most Salah,
this fucking guy put on a goddamn clinic.
First of all,
he used to play for Roma. So he scores
a goal and he does his big dramatic.
I'm not going to celebrate,
you know,
which was more annoying than if he just
celebrated cassette. He scored again.
The first one
was like a fight.
It was like a lot of it's like hockey
but fucking top shelf quarter on the far
side,
I believe with his left foot.
And then a few minutes later whenever
he comes back down again and he just,
and that wasn't,
that was the first one was a fucking
blast and the next one's nice,
soft touch right up and
over the fucking guy.
The goalkeeper I believe for a second
goal. Once again, he starts praying,
getting on his knees and fucking kissing
the ground and doing all this shit.
Like he's not going to have a
threesome after the fucking game,
you know what I mean? Like he's going to
go fucking rescue a cat out of a tree.
So I like to take your junk out and shake
it and the other teams face, you know,
you want to, and then he
set up, he had two assists,
whatever they call the helpers,
uh, to fucking crumpets.
I don't know what the fuck they call you.
Guy had like four points.
If he was playing hockey, two
goals to assist. It was incredible.
Then there was this other poor pass
and I think he finally scored a goal.
He had a breakaway, fucked that
up that he was in one in hockey,
what would be called the slot.
And he just fucking miss kicked it,
blasted it over the fuck.
And that,
I think he spent more time on his
fucking Mohawk than he did on his fucking
learning how to shoot the ball
into the Goddamn net. But, uh,
there was seven goals.
It was like the kind of fucking soccer
game that a yank could enjoy it. But, uh,
I was stuck on a plane and we had a
ridiculous headwind and I was like,
I'm going to sit here and watch this
fucking thing. And I totally got into it.
By the way, Liverpool's
fucking, uh, coach.
His dentist should be fucking disbarred.
He should have his licensed
fucking revoked. You know,
I'm sure it was the coach's idea.
But if you've got to fucking go tan and
you don't get your fake teeth whitened
to that level,
Jesus Christ,
he looked like the plant in little shop
of horrors except he had glasses on.
Uh,
so anyways, I was really
into it, so I guess I get it.
Why is it so much time between games
though? Oh No. The next one is April 28th.
That's it. I'm going to watch. Fuck
it. I'm going to support Liverpool.
I liked the Beatles. Who gives a fuck,
right? Like I got time for this shit.
There's no way to watch it and not all
of a sudden want to have a fucking beer
though. I will tell you that. You
know, and I've been fucking Billy.
No Fun Billy. No vice other
than four hits a weed one night,
which I immediately regret it cause all
it does is make me sleepy and not trying
to become one with the world.
I don't get munchies.
I just fall asleep like a
cat on a fucking window sill.
I don't give a fuck where I am.
I'm going to sleep. Yep. Um,
anyways, let's get on with the questions
here. I still have to watch that moto GP.
I know that mark mark has one.
It uh,
when there was a big anticipation
that him and a Valentino Rossi,
we're going to be fucking donkey kicking
each other about fucking 200 kilometers.
Uh, but he just fucking blew by
everybody by the second turn. Um,
I don't know. I got to watch it though.
I fucking love that sport though. Okay.
Emails for the week. I might have to,
to a little short, uh, podcast here.
Everybody looked fucking voices bugging
the shit out of me. All right, Belgium.
Hey Bill,
would you consider to come back to
Belgium in 2019 please keep us posted.
Uh, absolutely I would. I was only
there for like 24 hours and I loved it.
I was an ant Twerp I believe.
Excuse me.
Yeah. Gross. Disgusting. Sorry.
It has to be done.
Yeah,
got a blow it out.
I should have do a kid show sketch
about having a cold. You know,
you just have some up,
but that's always fucking sick.
And then the kids can't fucking sell
touched the thing cause it's sick.
And then you make the firm up at
act all sad cause it's lonely.
And then when the kids come over
because they feel bad for it,
he chastised the hell out of them for
giving into the weak emotion of love.
And you see a yes, set them up for
the real world. Uh, fish start a pack.
You know what? I downloaded one of those
cds here. Harmonies are amazing. Uh,
the music,
it doesn't quite grab me.
They're incredible fucking musician,
but they just stayed. There's a,
I dunno, there's something I want
to keep listening. All right,
you're talking about fucking bad.
That's sold out Madison Square Garden
like 18 nights in a row or something.
So it's, it's gotta be me on
some level. You know what I mean?
Okay.
I look at fish, the way I look at Beyonce,
like it's, it's gotta be me. Right?
I have to be the person that's when
somebody fills up the fucking Rosewell.
You know what I mean?
The second they say they're going
to be there and you're like, yeah,
I don't get it there. Then it's
some point. It's you issue, right?
I Dunno.
Is Billy Bright breathes breaths.
I always say when I appreciate,
while I appreciated the last fish suggests
fish suggested of starting with rift.
It's a very specific album.
Pretty Ballsy,
but that guy who started you with rift,
it's as if he wants to make
it hard on you. Oh, okay.
I like this guy. I liked the other
guy too. They thought I was smart.
I liked this guy because he
knows I'm stupid. All right.
Yeah. Make it easy. Read.
Give me the answers.
You should download hoist.
Is that how you say that?
As the last guy suggested
alive one that'll give you
something fun to work with.
Again, I love riffs, but I also
want you to have a fair shot. Also,
story of ghosts is funky and
Billy Billy breaths is fun too.
Who Was it? Billy breathes. I'm so dumb,
and not to sound cliche,
but have you seen dead and company yet?
It's a really fun show and
definitely worth checking out, man.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah,
those hippy shows to, it's
just such a vibe of, of uh,
insincerity,
Adam that I can't handle from the crowd
where everybody's just trying to like,
I dunno,
you don't think when you see a mom and
she's talking to a kid in public and
talking really loudly, some cute
conversation and looking at you smiling,
it's like, will you shut the fuck up?
You bring the volume down. I get it.
Kids are cute. It's not my kid. You know,
I don't care if the kid
just countered the five.
No, no. Busy.
You have to sit there and you need to
put teacher in here First Ota and then
they look at you and smile
is they do the play by play of the kid
putting a fucking marshmallow in its
mouth.
I feel like when you go to one of those
hippie things that people are doing that,
but they're kind of doing it, you know,
to show like how everybody's, you know,
this is like how society should be man.
Oh, in the fucking, the body
odor. I don't mean like,
I mean the Cologne that they wear,
whatever the fuck it is, just the, uh,
the, the, the fucking Douche Gumbo.
That's what I can't handle when I'm there.
It's always fucking hot, you
know? And everybody's wearing
a sun dress. It's just,
I dunno, I'm too much of a curmudgeon.
Why? I think we bombed Syria.
Oh, good for you. Help me
out here. Or bill ball bag.
Uh,
I believe we blew their chemical weapon
plants up because they gassed little
kids.
Okay.
Jess,
a guess of what I read.
I think you overly simplified and
I think some kids also died. Um,
but if we're going to
start doing that body,
if we're going to start bombing people
because they gas people are bond people
and killed little kids, uh, for everybody
who does that as a piece of shit.
I don't know how well we come
out in the wash, their pal,
a chest to cast for what I've read.
But you're not allowed to say that.
Cause if you do, that means
you're an isis. You not
allowed to criticize anything.
It'd be like, what the
fuck are we doing? Uh,
but I do understand your fear of debt.
Love the cast and your work
as unimportant as it may seem.
We couldn't live without laughing piece.
Okay man,
you get your sun dress
on there. Um, yeah, okay.
I understand that Syria, okay. What they
did was horrifically wrong, but you know,
should we have a lot more of our ducks
in a row before we start policing the
fucking world is all I'm saying.
You know what I mean?
If we're going to fucking bomb those guys,
cause they guessed a little kids,
that sounds good.
But you know,
at what point were they going to fucking
shoot some missiles at the people who
poisoned our food supply,
that food supply then that we're now
trying to sell around the world and people
like, you're not bringing that shit
in our country. Do you know this?
Say that about our food like France
and India. Francis like, all right,
but you're going to have to say what's in
it? And we're like, no, we're not. We are.
There's no way we're going to say what's
in our food. I'll fucked up as that.
And I got to try to navigate those
waters with my kid. You know,
and there's no explanation to
it. There's no, well, listen man,
if you want to somehow make
300 people not starve to death,
you got to cut some corners
that I understand it, but
there's, there's nothing,
they're not saying anything. They're
like, shut the fuck up and a and eat it.
Um,
you know,
I dunno the key in this world to make it,
you got to make so much money.
You can donate the politicians' campaigns
and then they just fucking leave you
alone.
And you can do whatever you want.
Like poisoned the food supply of a
country, which if I'm not mistaking,
is a terrorist act.
When you then become an evil
doer, uh, dude, I'm fat.
This is all shit.
And you're not allowed to see if
you can say it about anybody else.
But if you actually fucking
Kev constructive criticism
about your own team,
you're immediately a conspiracy theorists
or you're a socialist. You know,
I don't understand.
I don't know when the fuck that happened,
but it's brilliant PR. Um, so evidently
I'm a communist right now. Oh, Bill. Yeah,
he's got a red beard.
I mean it's all right there.
Probably jugs off to Stalin's
fucking head shot every morning.
How dairy want healthy food for everyone
in this country. Uh, Hay Bell, no fun.
Hey Billy. No Fun. Love the podcast. I'm
a fat guy. Totally agreeing with you.
Fat people blame everyone around them,
but I'm one that knows that I shouldn't
be shoving cheeseburgers down my gullet.
Yeah,
dude,
that's the power fucking
choice right there.
If you start blaming everybody else
and all this other shit outside,
he has to change as you keep
fucking Chauhan this shit the,
granted I don't have a psychology degree
or even know anything about nutrition
as I trash what's in our
food supply. Uh, you know,
you know Kenny Rogers, who was the gambler
from the hypocrite. Uh, anyone. Anyway,
my question is,
do you think it's worse to know that you
are ruining your life and eating like a
fat fuck or pretending like it's
a thyroid problem or some excuse.
Anyways, please come to the bay
area. I am, I'm doing a whole week.
It shows in May up in San Francisco or
reno cause I miss you on the last one.
Uh,
all right.
Do you think it's worse to know that
you're ruining your life and eating like a
fat fuck or pretending like
it's a thyroid problem?
I think if you pretend like it's a
thyroid problem is a good way to go.
If your apps, if you had no
power in this situation, like,
um, a lot of the shit that I alluded
to, you know, like our food supply,
like I'm powerless against that.
So it's something I will joke about
and then I quickly don't think about it
because I don't know what
to do. What, you know,
you go down to a farmer's market and
those kinds of infiltrated down there too,
when you start asking the fucking hippie
down their eggs, so this is blah, blah,
blah,
where did this come from?
And they start getting all fucking
shifty themselves and they then all of a
sudden you feel like you're an invasion
of the body snatchers, you know? So, um,
but I think the fact that
you're addressing that,
you're the ones shoving the
cheeseburgers down your gullet. Um,
okay.
I have found that, uh, you
know, the longest time I
didn't think food was a drug.
I totally believe it now.
And Dean del Ray put me on this,
I guess it's a gluten free diet and I'm
all this and I barely have to work out.
Okay.
You know, and uh, Kina Wa
is like this fucking like,
I eat the food that I eat on this diet
afterwards. I don't feel like, ah,
I gotta take a nap. I feel like energized
even though I feel like shit right now.
But,
um,
yeah,
I dunno. But I was taking a multivitamin,
somebody shit all over that go.
It doesn't have enough of this and of that
you need to take this. It's just like,
okay. All right. All right. So, uh,
I think it's,
it's
okay.
Well, look, if you're not going to
do anything about being a fat fuck,
it's going to be more painful.
If you're just going to continue to be
a fat fucking not do anything about it,
then I would lie. That's your thyroid
problem. You know what I mean?
Yeah.
MMM.
That's like if you put out
something artistic and uh,
it doesn't do well and then you blame
the left or the right
or some shit like that.
Like I've seen with some
movies and other shit.
You can do that if you want stuck not
to help you. Next fucking project.
If the project have you a
navy training in Australia.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
It's the last fucking place I would
be in the God damn navy is Australia.
Oh my God.
Okay.
What do you have to do to become
a fucking navy seal in Australia?
You have to stab a great white shark to
death after they cut the very make you
bleed before you get in the
fucking water. Alright. Hey Bill.
Just watched.
Okay.
Add voice clip.
I think that voice clip of you on Youtube
about how you watched the two weeks in
health thing. I was in the
Australian navy and it was similar,
but you got shit for not keeping your own.
I don't know what that means.
Preface,
this was before the media
cared about all genders.
We had big Bertha,
okay.
Which on the second day of recruit school,
we were kept up until 2:00 AM and
we're only allowed a breakfast bar.
The night before they woke us up by
smashing trash cans in each of our dorms
right there. I'd be out, I'd
be out. I'd be like, dude,
fuck this. And I'd walk out.
They'd be like, good, you're too
weak. And I'd be like, you're right,
and I'm going to a Holiday Inn.
I want to thank all of you for protecting
me in my eight hours sleep. All right.
That we had to run downstairs and
carry the rope called Big Bertha,
which was the equivalent. Oh my
God. Of the old ships anchor lines,
and we ran for about six kilometers,
3.7 miles. What the fuck?
Until we were allowed
to have food after that.
Anyone that couldn't continue,
we were partnered up with and had to
carry them and big Bertha shaming the
people that couldn't continue.
Uh, I couldn't do that.
Okay.
I couldn't do that to where
they up on the rope weeping.
Do they literally get broken
that bed? Every event? Well,
when we eventually got back to base,
we were allowed breakfast and then had
to go on with the eight hour drills and
fulfill our duty watches.
Yeah.
Wow. Dude. That is some psychological
breakdown right there. Holy Shit.
The most fucked up
thing about all of this.
Okay.
Hey, wait to, did you make
it through all of this?
Okay.
Oh my God.
Juvie or ATR difficult.
It is to be me.
Has your girlfriend ever said that to
you when you're thinking about that big
Bertha March? Was this, okay?
This was in m o two o three and
the Australian Defense Force,
our military,
God forbid we seem aggressive.
You say Defense Force had instituted
a policy where females could only be
treated or ordered for
so many hours a day,
so handing a dash gas helicopter shoe.
So handling. Okay. Helicopter.
Sheila was only be performed by men
because it caused impotence and women but
also men,
but females could hold
positions on the yeah,
but they can also make a baby. They
know anybody. We'll fuck himself.
Your Dick and your balls are expendable
at that point. That's simple math,
but females could hold positions
on the Hilo refuel team.
Okay,
well that doesn't make sense, but when
it came to actually handling fuel,
they get volunteer males to do it after
dealing with shit like being blamed
because my ship couldn't get any new
workers from land because the ship was a
fucking grinder and being in charge of
people when I haven't even been promoted,
I decided to just start drinking so much.
I got kicked off and it
was my best decision ever.
This is like a great movie.
Spent my last year of my contract
at a base in a rich part of Sydney,
Australia surfing in the morning and
bagging a few of the new female sailors
that all over 21 he puts in parentheses
that had never been to sea by proudest
moment was when I was awarded these
humanitarian aid metal because I build
hospitals in some Matera
after the o five tsunami.
I spent days helping and building and the
people have so much or was some of the
most thankful, kindest people ever met.
What a fucking great story that is.
Oh my God. Can you imagine if you
quit like how tired you'd have to be,
how excrutiatingly tired you have
to be to climb up on that rope.
It'd be carried back 3.7 miles.
I just have to go
mentally with every step.
This humiliation is one
step closer to being over.
What do you say when you get off?
Good. I make sorry about that. Yeah.
Have a fucking,
oh my God.
I can't imagine what people said
to you all the way back. Overrated.
Underrated or overrated.
New York and Los Angeles.
I've lived in both cities for
over four years each. I love them,
but I've also lived on a creek in
Virginia and a farm in Vermont.
Lsu need to be in one of those cities.
Just don't go there.
I that I agree with that whole
heart and he should visit him.
A underrated Wayne's world.
I never heard you talk about this movie.
He should definitely rewatch this. Next
time you take a hit man. All right,
I'll check it out. I will
definitely check it out. Um,
I ended it. Overrated. Underrated.
Okay. I, well, you know what? Overrated.
These new fucking elevators
where I got to fucking hit like 20 goddamn
buttons to let the elevator know that
I'm going to floor four so it can fucking
compartmentalize all the people there
when I'm the only fucking person there,
you know,
and I gotta take my key out and
fucking run it over the scanner.
I liked the old school ones. We
just got in. You push the button
first fucking 10 years I was on the
road. That was, that was the way it was.
And I never had that guy from no country
for old men blow out the lock on my
door, you know, it was completely fine.
I've been one time I stayed in a bed and
breakfast in fucking Colorado with this
dude from Germany.
It was so fucking creepy cause he was
walking the halls at night and I was just
sitting there in the hall.
Light would be on and I was looking at
the light and I didn't have a lock of did
I think maybe on a skeleton cheat,
but I was just sitting there.
Oh I just moved with my luggage.
I had this ugly ass green like made out
of cloth bag cloth and plastic that this
guy puked on one side.
Oh my God. Remember that
change.
Describe it through a lot of shit people.
All right, let's tell the
chairman would first some fucking,
I will tell the puke one. No,
you've got to close with the puke.
I've already told that story
and it's so fucking gross.
I've been puked on twice in my life.
Once on my head,
you know,
everybody in my family had gotten sick
and we had this bathroom was a half a
bathroom with no door.
You were around the corner,
no privacy whatsoever. We lived in a
duplex, squirrels got into the walls.
I had to scare them out and then
my dad would kill him, you know,
was the 70s, eighties, you know,
Shit like that happen. So, uh,
there was no place to, you couldn't, I
couldn't make a Facebook video and Shay,
my landlord, you know, or my dad couldn't
do that, you know, so you just stopped.
She had to kill the fuckers. I remember
I had a broken, I was fucking shaking it,
try to get this thing to come out.
And my dad was on the other side.
You have this giant fucking butcher
knife or metal bar or something,
I can't remember.
And that was a metal bar.
That's what it was like a big
piece of lettuce or something. Any,
flush that thing out and that fucking
thing came running up the broom,
the broom handle,
I remember his eyes were wide is shit.
It's tail was straight up in the end.
This little brown Cutie Pie
fucking ran up my arm in,
launched off of my shoulder.
I went la and then it ran
into the half a bathroom
and there was one way
in and only one way out,
my dad was in the way and
he fucking brought that led
dig down right on the back
of its fucking neck and just
slowly killed the three.
And I watched him do it.
MMM.
So anyways,
what time?
We were all fucking sick and I was in
there finishing puking in the bathroom
with no door.
My brother came running in,
just ran and rather than puking in the
fucking sink that was readily available.
You know,
we were young so it was just like you
puke in the toilet and my head obstructing
the toilet and it was like how low
pressure goes to high pressure.
It takes the most direct route,
which is right through the airfoil.
And that's how you get lift when you fly.
He used those same principles,
would puke it into the toilet.
And my head was the airfoil and
every fucking puked on my head.
And I just freaked out and I was punching
him as hard as I could in the stomach
as he was continuing to Puke.
But parents came in,
they were laughing their ass off at bay
and the kitchen sink was there and she
just fucking dunk my head in there,
fucking Washington. It was so gross.
So gross.
So then the second time I got puked on,
I was trying to save money and I was
taking a bus from Manhattan to Laguardia
Airport.
We were almost in my turmoil.
Yeah.
I take the subway up to Harlem and
then took the bus over the bridge
and this dude just got up,
look at all gray.
Yeah.
And he fucking projectile vomited and
he hit the sweet old lady in front of me
on her chest.
It was like the Kennedy assassination,
where to spray just went back except it
didn't go to the left and went to the
right where I was sitting.
And it got on my foot,
my sock and my lower pants
in all over my luggage.
And then he just stumbled off the bus
and I was like, you mother fucker. And
I wanted to beat the shit out of him,
but I was broke and I needed the
money and I had to go to my gig.
I just glared at them as all I could do.
And then I had to go in there,
got off the bus and now people look at
me like I'm an animal because I smelled
like fucking puke.
And I
went into the bathroom
like beyond Tourette's.
Took the sock off shoe off fucking,
but I didn't only had one
pair of footwear, so I threw
out the size disgusting.
Had to wash off my fucking
pant leg the best I could.
My sneaker was so could fucking wet.
I had one sock on, one sock off,
walking in a squishy wet
fucking sneaker and my fucking
okay.
Green cloth bag.
I wiped off all of the Pew,
but it was like stayed and they had like
the little fucking paper towel balls
audit.
It was so fucking gross.
And I then had to get on like a
fucking flight to like Minnesota,
just sitting there
smelling of stomach acid
and I got off the plane.
Yeah.
I immediately went to a mall and I
bought some sweatpants and the cheapest
fucking sneakers and socks and
I just fucking the shit out.
And I bought a bag. But I didn't have
time to do that before, which is about,
oh my God, it was a fucking terrible trip
on a fucking terrible trip. That was,
uh,
but you know,
it's not as bad as what fucking happened
on southwest could have been worse.
You know, the poor fucking
woman, Jesus Christ.
So that's the second time I've heard
of somebody gets sucked out like that.
He read that fucking story that,
uh,
it fucking mechanic puts a new
windshield on it, on the plane, and the,
uh,
the used the wrong fucking screws.
They weren't long enough and they
fucking fly in like, you know,
they're cruising altitude,
so they gotta be going full 500 miles an
hour in the fucking windshield flew off
and the captain got sucked out.
But his legs got stuck on the yoke and
he was outside the fucking plane and they
were trying to hold onto them and that
the door to the cockpit got blown in and
the guy couldn't slow down
because it was on the controls.
They sub out of the stewardess has helped
out, you know when the peer pressure,
okay.
I guess leveled off where they
can move and not get sucked out.
And they were trying to
pull them in and they could,
one of the students could see the guy
outside the window looking at him and his,
he wasn't blinking and she goes, I
think he's dead. We should let them go.
Fortunately they didn't.
They ended up landing.
It turned out the guy was in shock.
Okay.
Um,
fucking nuts.
Just sitting there like catatonic.
He got frostbite in one of his eyes.
It was just,
and this is what kills me is a fucking
maniac was flying again in a couple of
weeks, but I think he still
flies. I can't imagine.
You know what the thing is,
is what they really should have in the
back of the plane is you should also have
those shoulder on a, since you
should have that, you know,
when it goes across your lap
and then over your shoulder.
So then if you sit next to the
fucking window, God forbid,
if the fucking thing blows out,
you still fine.
But that would be prohibitively expensive.
Yeah.
So I guess what I'm saying is get
the ILC. All right, everybody,
um,
go Bruins and,
uh, go Celtics. I had a,
I dunno,
I'm going to go fucking take a hot shower
and try to clear my goddamn scientists
is, uh, I want to do another
podcast tomorrow and I'll
be all caught up. All right.
Go Fuck Yourself. She can't sit. I'll
check it on your tomorrow. Go. Oh, Geez.