Hey,
what's going on?
Is Bill burn his time for the Monday
morning podcast for Monday, November 26,
2018 what's going on?
How,
how's it going everybody?
How are you do uh,
how the fucking fucker
you, um, while I'm back,
everybody vacation is officially over.
I have shit to do every frigging
day of this week. You know why?
Why Bill? Cause you actually have to
go to work. You'll lazy cunt. Hey,
every once in a while I want to share
my feelings and I appreciate it.
You were with thin for Kate.
Um,
F is for family is coming out,
uh, on Netflix this
Wednesday, November 29th.
Please watch, please watch again.
Please watch with all your friends are,
don't do whatever the fuck you want to do.
I think it's going to be,
I think you're going to enjoy it. You
know, the, you're listening to this.
I think you'd enjoy it.
Um,
you know what I would enjoy if somebody
could tell me how I can buy a quality
quality. You know what? Maybe it's
just these fucking headphones.
Maybe it's just as Jack, whatever.
Let's continue promoting.
Knowing that people can hear me,
but I can't hear myself.
And when you can't hear yourself,
how are you going to be
able to open up to others?
That's the question that we want
to talk about here today. Um,
it's going to be on November 29th.
It's fucking going to be on
Netflix. All right, that's the deal.
Let's see what we got here.
Let's try to put this in here and
let's see if this fixes the problem.
How about this new headphones?
You know, most people,
if they were a professional, they
woulda hit pause by now. That's not me,
is it not? That's not how bill does it.
Bill just keeps going. And why would you,
what do you know? It's still doesn't
fucking work. Does anybody know
the fuck makes a god Damn fucking
headphone Jack that's of quality?
You know,
you go down to guitar center
and get fucking by the
Goddamn fucking make sure it
works and then everything
else fucking sucks.
It doesn't make any sense.
You go to a Lexus dealership,
everything's at the fucking Lexus level.
Unfucking believable.
It is fucking bullshit.
I've been bitching about this for
fucking two Goddamn fucking months.
You know all the dumb shit that I do with
my life. Oh, the fucking bars I go into.
You take one night, you take a fucking
night off and go buy a fucking headphone.
Jack did this effort as a family
is going to be a lot of that.
If that's what you're into.
Hey,
does anybody know where the fuck I can
fucking go and buy some shit that wasn't
made in fucking shiner is they're passive
aggressive fucking way to say fuck you
to my country. Is anything made in his
fucking Goddamn fucking country anymore?
The fact that this fucking thing,
I just bought this and then you can
sell this and who the fuck am I going to
call?
Awesome fucking guy in India
who's pretending like he's
here and then he can do
this fucking bullshit. I'm sorry
sir. I'm you feel that way. I
understand. Get the fuck Outta here.
By the way, I know your name is a Todd.
Ah, it feels good to blow out
the lines every once in a while.
Everybody over over something
that you totally have power over.
Um, anyways, this is what I
do now. I just yell at things.
I don't yell at people anymore. I
just, I do. You know, you know what I,
you know what I like when you
yell at an inanimate objects,
you feel like it's listening, you
know, cause it never interrupts.
That would tell you you're
wrong. All right. Anyways,
afis or family is going to be
up November 29th on Netflix.
Please watch it. Also, uh,
the seventh annual Patrice O'Neal comedy
benefit tickets going fast. Loving it.
Tuesday, February 19th at 7:00 PM
at the city center in New York City.
A lineup. Jim Gaffigan, big
Jay Oakerson. Gary Gulman,
Chris read Michelle Wolf. Scifest sounds
rich. Vos is hosting and yours too.
Oh, freckles. Oh, fucking freckles
with is fucked up headphones.
I'm not the headphones. It's the God
damn check. Just a fucking Jack. Bomp.
BOMP bomp bone. I'm sorry. Anyways,
so this week I got to do this, this inner,
the Skype interview with this
coffee company. All right.
And uh, I fucking hate,
I hate Skype.
Okay.
I fucking hate it. You know what, Eh,
Skypes in and all those fucking things
on your computer that once you download
it,
every time you turn your computer on,
it fucking sticks his fucking Goddamn
face out there. It's like, Hey,
did I click on you?
Okay.
Did I click on you?
They sit down and shut up.
I've got this other thing. Right? I got
you. I got this external hard drive thing.
I used it one time.
Every time I shut down my computer
and turn it back on again.
It's like that fucking,
you know,
you know that person at the party
when you just sit in there like,
who invited this guy that?
That's what all of those apps are like.
You know,
we need to make sure every time they
turn on your computer that this comes on
and we remind them that
it's on your computer.
Okay,
I'll,
it makes me want to do is eventually
grab that icon or whatever the fuck you
call it and drag it over to the trashcan.
And my favorite thing ever
is when you hit delete trash,
that little poof poof of dust, you
know? Would you like? I'm going to be,
wouldn't it be great if he could do
that to the guy at the party? You know,
just fucking big paper,
machete Arrow.
You put it on him and you poke them in
his belly. He giggles and then he just,
he just disappears and he can get
back to the core conversation.
You what happened?
Or maybe you were just sitting there
enjoying yourself in the corner and he
decided that he was going to
be, you know, I'm a social guy.
I'm just going to come up and say hello.
Rather than seeing that somebody clearly
is over in the corner not wanting to
talk to anybody. I'm going to go over
there and go fucking talk to him.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
I Dunno.
I mean maybe that's just a fucking
white thing. The way we fucking walk up
to wild animals and shit. Maybe we, it's,
it starts at the party by going over to
the person in the corner who clearly has
some sort of fucking issues. Clearly not
a PR person you want to steer clear of.
You got to walk up,
you walk up,
you say a low and because of
the rules of society over there,
this guy doesn't rip your fucking
head off and then you just, Oh,
I think maybe I'll apply
the same annoying behavior.
I use it a party into the wild.
Maybe I'll do that. Hey polar bear.
I'm going to come out and
be an open fucking spirit.
Yeah.
He might have, you know, I followed
that uh, discover sharks on Instagram.
The amount of fucking morons
that are so into sharks.
They're trying to prove how not dangerous
they are and they're fucking jumping
in the water with them.
It's like he didn't,
you didn't watch the crocodile hunter.
That's what the fuck he did.
Do you think you know
nature better than that guy
do? The way that guy got killed, that
was like a great episode of the wire.
You just didn't see it coming.
You know what I mean?
All those years fucking
with those ridiculously
ridiculously poisoned snakes and
they get snakes and fucking Australia.
That could be take out a
small country with one bite,
the entire fucking population.
And this guy is going over there with
his fucking booty shorts on with aerobics
socks.
Fucking with these things.
Do you think in one of these days this
guy is going to get bit and his shapely
Tan calves, right?
Didn't happen. All right.
Maybe it's going to be, I don't know. The,
what else did he fuck with
some sort of fucking wild boar?
That's what you thought was going to
get them. Certainly a fucking crocodile,
you know,
you thought that would get them and
one ended up fucking getting them a
goddamned sting. Ray never saw that calm
and that was just like the wire. Well,
what's his face?
Okay.
Oh my God, I forgot the iconic fucking
Dick Guy used to rob the drug dealers.
I'm not going to ruin and much
spoiler alert, a spoiler alert.
It's been out for fucking 15
years or whatever. I'm not
going to ruin the ending.
But the way that guy,
you know what happens to him,
you just don't fucking see it coming.
MMM.
I don't even know what I'm talking
about anymore. But anyways, I'm doing a,
one of my favorite people,
one of my favorite podcasts of all time.
This Wednesday I'm going to be
on the Joe Rogan experience.
I'm also doing dice Clay's podcasts,
uh,
later on that day and I'm finally
calling in to spit and check what's on
Barstool. All right.
I'm running the gamut,
the gamut of podcasts that day.
I'm doing Kevin and been on Friday
and that's local out here.
If you live in La local radio,
I'm sure they have an app that you can
download and listen to it wherever the
fuck you want to. And then what else?
I got a couple of foreigners tomorrow,
but again,
and now you have to download fucking
Skype so I can do this phone or today at
noon so then I could then
immediately fucking delete it again.
Don't forget about me. I'm on
your computer. We know Skype.
Everybody knows you here.
Everybody knows you're fucking here.
Okay.
Well the one,
one positive thing I will say about
Skype as I love the phone ring that Bompy
boom. I don't know what it is about it.
I like it. I like it. Other than that,
everything about it is,
it's fucking annoying,
you know what I mean? Um, anyways,
how was your Thanksgiving [inaudible]
I already talked about thanksgiving.
I forgot I did it on Friday.
I talked Friday. What, what
are you gonna talk about?
Let's talk about the debacle. If you
are a wolverines fan that was Michigan,
Ohio state,
Jesus fucking Christ.
I was just, that was just a,
sorry fucking, they should
have beat them this year.
They really should have,
you know something.
As much as the buckeyes are walking
around with their chest puffs out is like
you let up 40 fucking points.
I don't know what you're so excited
about. Fucking unbelievable, man.
I swear to God,
if those kinds didn't get that
fucking ridiculous spot two years ago,
it would have been a rivalry
again. Nowaday, they just,
they just got the psychological advantage
that fucking gave two years ago when
everybody, I'll let you tie.
Officiating Squad was from fucking Ohio.
I think he got the first down,
whatever the fuck it was. Anyways,
I just wanted a game,
is what I wanted,
and I wanted Harbaugh to win one,
so then he could have the fucking
urban Maya Harbach 10 years war,
but now you know, I dunno. Urban Meyers
got some sort of assist in his head.
Ain't no fucking idea. I don't know that.
So it's just like, yeah, dude, you got to,
you got a wife and kids. What
are you doing here? You know,
every time they run the ball for a lost,
the guy literally has to
fucking bend over to his ankles.
He gets headaches when he flips
out and it's just like, it's like,
it's literally a ticking time buds.
It's Mos,
I'm going to say it's unsettling to watch.
You know what I mean? Jesus Christ. But
then it's like, what is he going to do?
Just sit at home with his
sister being pleasant. I mean,
the man has to live his fucking life,
right?
MMM.
Anyways, what else? What did we talked
about? We talked about headphone jacks.
He's talked about sis in people's heads.
Um,
okay.
Patriots jets.
That was the one football game.
I watched that one and I watched the,
uh, watch the end of the Steelers game.
That was tough to watch. Big
Ben. Uh, lose that one. Man.
I saw two fucking amazing
quarterbacks have tough games.
Aaron Rogers had that guy open and then
a big band, you know, I don't know.
I'm talking like I would have
fucking made the past, but um, um,
so out of it right now,
like I was actually rooting
for the Steelers cause the,
just,
I fucking hate the Broncos just because
they kicked our ass from Craig Morton,
right through John Elway.
And I'm still not over it
every fucking time in any to
every fucking time we play him,
it's always an away game. Okay. Who's
always back in their horse shoe.
Back in the day it'd be
freezing fucking cold out.
It would start snowing and then we would
just get the shit kicked out and we all
in every time we played them,
it was just be like, you know,
we had hope and it had some
sort of playoff implications
and then that would be
it. That's the old, you know,
that's the old Boston sports fan as
opposed to now where everybody's mean.
Anybody born from the ninth,
1990 on is just absolutely spoiled.
Um, as far as being the Paiche
us, uh, a Boston sports fan,
which I'm totally fine with. Um,
I watched a little bit of Celtics,
caught a little bit of the Bruins verse
the Canadians and um, I don't know.
I just had it. I had a great weekend, man.
I really had a great weekend. I tell you,
I think I told you that guys,
this did I tell you I took my, uh,
I told you that last, last week. I
took my kid to guitar center, man,
it was fucking awesome.
God knows we didn't buy any fucking
headphone Jacks and those fucking idiots.
They're not idiots.
Okay.
But you don't need to know why.
Why are you selling shit that
doesn't fucking work. Hey Bill,
why didn't you keep the
receipt and bring it back?
Because I don't want to fucking
make another trip over there.
Okay.
All right. I never take the
receipt. I'm not coming back.
It doesn't fucking work.
I'll just yell about it
rather than just getting in my
car and solving the problem.
Yeah.
MMM. You know, every time I think
I turned the corner as a person,
I just realized, oh Jesus,
it's just like this.
There's another fucking storage shed
of emotional shit I have to fucking go
through.
You know,
if, imagine if they could do
that with your personality.
They had this storage wars with you.
Right.
And they just make you stand in there
as a middle aged person and they got a
bunch of fucking women out there looking
for a partner and they're just bid
nodded, you know? And then they just,
they opened the door and
your fucking standing there
with your fucking dad jeans and you
little cunt belly trying to suck it in and
they're just looking in your eyes and
you're trying not to look away like some
wild animals, shit, you know? Then
they start bidding on you. What,
what do you think they'd been on
you? Let's just say, you know,
we'll make it easy.
A hundred bucks is like,
this guy looks like the
winner top shelf Johnny blue.
I want to be with this guy in
zero is this guy's a fucking zero.
This guy's a loser. Everything he
touches turns to shit. You know?
What do you think you'd be on that?
I think the only thing that
saves me is a earn a good living.
If you take that out of the equation.
All right.
I think I have,
I'm in the 30s,
depending on how fucking
crazy your dad was.
I would say I might even drop
down into the 20s. You know,
I'm looking at an emotional lottery pick
the next season. Uh, oh, by the way,
um, you know, I was talking to
[inaudible] and he would say, I was,
fuck this guy's name's sake. Saquon
Barkley was just having like a career day,
almost a hundred yards in the first half
or some fucking shit against the eagles.
And then they ran them four times in the
second half and he just couldn't wrap
his head around the fact. It's like,
dude, the giants are tanking. Okay.
They're not going to make the fucking fit
tanking. You know, the Patriots did it.
We'd be in trouble, but they, they're
going to tank people tank. All right.
Indianapolis. They tank to get Andrew
Luck. Peyton manning came back,
gay doctor said, I'm good. Oh No,
Peyton, we're worried about you.
Uh, we'll fucking worried about you
than paint goes on to fucking, you know,
when a Superbowl over
there and fucking Denver,
I love that you have an
artist said whatever.
Anybody treats this superstar
with absolute disrespect.
That guy ends up in Colorado
and wins championships.
If he noticed that the fucking Canadians.
All right,
this scarf wearing fucking snooty guide.
Damn fans booed Patrick Wall.
I'm going to say this again.
They booed Patrick wa a man,
not only a hall of Famer,
not only winter of two Stanley cups at
that point that Ddi change the position.
You're talking about this a handful of
fucking people in the history of the NHL.
They can say that I changed the position
of Patrick was one of them and what did
he do? He went to the Colorado
avalanche at one, not one,
but two fucking Stanley cups
and all of those fucking
pocket square blue blog,
a rouge con sport coat where in concept
there has still sitting there with the
course, sign up their
ass, wait for another cup.
25 fucking years later,
Indianapolis Colts tank a fucking season
so they can get Andrew luck with his
pate manning go.
Does he try to pile on in San Francisco
and Jim Harbaugh was there and they were
one fucking piece away. No, he
does not. Pate Manning says,
I'm going to be a fucking man about this.
I'm going to the Goddamn Broncos.
Not saying they were bad, but that would
have been a layup and San Francisco.
It's tough to say.
It would have been a lamp with Jim
Harbaugh after that fucking loss the other
day. But I'll, and I'll put up the
unimaginative fucking play, calling run,
play action. Fake third and
long. Let's throw it. Um,
wait, if fucked his way to
fuck his pate man and go,
he goes to Denver and it goes to not one,
but two Superbowls gets his ass kicked in
the first one by other playing Seattle.
You know,
they were all fucking roided up and nobody
gave a shit cause they're in Seattle.
That's not cheating. You know,
that's a competitive edge. Right.
But he comes back and wins it like the
next year of the year. A year later,
I forget which, right.
Another Superbowl trophy.
Okay. So I'm thinking that the
giants are going to tank this year.
Okay.
Then they're going to go out, they're
going to draft the fucking quarterback.
They're going to tell Eli when or
if not one, but two super bowls.
Yeah.
Against Bill Bellacheck,
the greatest fucking coach of all time.
They're going to tell him to hit the
fucking bricks of where do you think that
man's going?
Okay.
Not The Broncos.
He's going to shock everybody's going to
play point guard for the Denver Nuggets
and they win an NBA championship.
Right?
Yeah.
Um, sorry. Um,
what you're listening to right now is
a man who has a lot of Shitty as to do
this week and he doesn't want to get out
of bed. Oh, was I enjoy in my time off.
Okay.
Oh, did I enjoy it? You know,
but I realized I was enjoying it too much
because I was continuing to, you know,
have some drinks, have some cigars, and
what I really realized it was, Bill,
when you have time off,
what you need to be doing is drinking
water and getting eight hours sleep,
then you'll actually feel rested.
Okay.
Then the vacation won't seem
like it went by too quickly.
I realized this last night,
the last day of my vacation.
All right,
but what I'm going to do is I'm going
to apply the wisdom that I've learned.
I can't even say wisdom because
I have learned this lesson.
I've learned this lesson
more fucking times.
Okay.
Then Ohio state has kicked the
fucking shit out of the wolverines.
Okay.
In the last decade and a half.
Um,
okay.
Anyways, what's going to
happen? Ohio State Urban Meyer.
Everybody's saying he's going
to leave this year. I mean that,
that's not good for football.
You got to me that did,
it was just building
up you now Harpo Harpo,
I has to hardwire has,
whenever those smokers had got
my voice cracks the next day,
Harbo has to fuck it. He's got a, he's
got to get these, got a big debt guy.
He can't take his ball and go home off
for health reasons. He Kit, you know,
how about give him shit.
Oh, is that it buddy? Huh?
One little fucking cyst and
you're going to go home.
The urban could just walk away going
62, 63, whatever they fucking scored.
Um, anyways, uh,
Jesus Christ. Now what do I do? I
do some reads. Let's do some reads.
That's why I'm reading.
Ah,
read notes on the moon home
a wall. Then. All right,
five reads everybody, not one, not two,
like the Stanley Cups at Patrick Wall one.
Actually the Canadians are
playing good this year. You know,
you know not good enough for their fan
base because they expect things I love.
I love when a fan base expects things out
of their professional sports franchise,
but nothing out of their own
personal lives. That right there,
that is a true sports fan.
All right,
fine butchers box everybody.
Oh Jesus do I love these guys.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and the one
the only never to be replaced.
The the, the, the fucking pork
that changed the position.
The Patrick Wa
okay.
Of pork heritage. Bread. Pork.
Now a lot of you are like me.
Probably Saint Boob.
Well what exactly is heritage breed pork.
And I know I've explained this well.
Guess what? It's so fucking
good. I'm gonna explain it again.
Heritage budge pork is,
is,
is murdered pigs that are pure bred picks
that you can trace their family tree
all the way back to Europe.
They weren't over here.
Fucking these low rent pigs here
in the United States of America.
You know that sit around watching reality
TV while eat, eating cotton candy,
Thies ds. These are
European pigs. They read,
they smoked cigarettes,
holding the cigarette from underneath.
These pigs can ride scooters.
Everybody not do this,
so it's incredible. It's the best takes
and pork chop I've ever fucking had.
My mouth literally waters when
I read this shit. Incredible.
Incredible quality of butcher box meat
starts with the commitment to raising
animals humanely and free of
antibiotics and hormones before they are
slaughtered.
Yeah,
they listen to fucking feel good music
and then one day you just walk up.
Hey Peggy, look at that over there.
Then he gave me all right there.
Fred over cook with a piece of,
with the peace of mind knowing you
are eating healthy, high quality meat.
Each box comes with at least
eight to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individual size meals.
Unless you're a tub of shit and you're
fucking gluttonous and you go through it
in three days.
Yeah,
it's your choice.
You know you want to have the meat sweats.
So you want to have abs.
It's all up to you.
You can choose from five
different box types. All beef,
beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed box.
Custom box lets you choose your own cuts.
Like my new favorite cook did Johnny,
Johnny,
I live on the hill every morning.
I walked down to buy what
I'm going to cook that day.
My name is Johnny and this is what's left
of the Italian American section at San
Francisco. I fucking love that guy.
Next time I go to San Francisco,
I want that guy to come to a show.
MMM.
All right, customer. All right.
For $20 off your first box and a package
of free bacon in every box for life,
for the life of your subscription,
uh,
go to butcher box.com/burr and enter
bar at chicken, uh, at checkout.
By the way, fuck Turkey Bacon.
All right, that's a little aside.
You know what?
I need to learn how to cook cause I tried
to cook it like the pig shit, you know,
or did he just bathes in its own grease?
I like to burn it up. By the way,
you know, my wife's, I take, I take it
off at about 15 minutes. You know mine.
I leave it in there for another
eight minutes. Um, all right,
that's $20 off your first box in a
package of free bacon in every box for the
life of your subscription by going
to butcher box.com/burr and entering
[inaudible] at checkout. All
right, and don't cheat. Uh,
mentioned that there's no longer any
excuse for wearing ill fitting suits.
Everybody, you know something I just
would just love to mention something.
There is no longer any excuse for
wearing an ill fitting suit. Okay.
It's 2018.
I think it's time you fucking gras.
Okay.
Especially when they're available at
such great prices. Highest quality,
lowest price.
Here's how it works.
Visit a stylist at our
showroom and have them.
Take your measurements personally or
measure@homeyourselfandshoponlineatindochino.com
choose
your
fabric
inside
and
out. Choose your design
customization. Submit your
measurements with your choices.
Relax while you're a suit
gets professionally tailored
and mailed to you in a
couple of weeks. November is black
Friday. Uh, I think that already happened.
Meaning 2018 is lowest prices,
up to 70% off everything.
The theme is all about stepping out
from backstage, making entrance,
take center stage, your biggest
moment, grand finale, et cetera.
This week my listeners can have,
can avail of black price black Friday
prices by using code [inaudible] at
checkout.
That 70% off the regular price for a made
to measure suit plus shipping is free.
That's indochino.com
Promo code up to 70% off.
Incredible deal for a made to
measure suit. One should go custom.
You don't go rack. Hey, by the way,
I don't think anybody got trampled or
murdered or killed during black Friday.
I think they finally have it down
due to Doto Mandy's me undies.
Nobody fucking died due due due to me.
Id me undies are those as fat fucks tried
getting pressed up against the glass.
Your bellies round with your flat ass.
She got a pancake.
It's not worth it to get the
DVD VCR at fucking Walmart.
Yeah,
you're gonna get bludgeoned with
a fish tank. All right, Mandy,
this is the year that you can finally
tackle your holiday shopping early.
And guess what?
You can get everything you need for
you and your loved ones at [inaudible].
Imagine fucking where's Doo Doo Doo Doo.
Brds brds nobody fucking cares that your
wife and you got a shark on your tape
and you tasting tarp. Sorry. Talk about
why me undies are the best underwear.
Feel free to improvise.
You know I love about me undies.
I don't have to go to the store to
get them. How about that? All right.
I don't give a fuck about your prints.
They're comfortable.
They fit my bulls and undercarriage there.
Uh,
my undies uses the coveted
micro mode out modal fabric,
which is three times softer than cotton.
If you've never felt this fabric,
get ready to experience pure bliss
in underwear form. All right.
As you sashay down the street,
feeling your balls swishing to and
fro this holiday, season me on these,
we'll be releasing a
new print every Tuesday.
That means you have no excuse
to celebrate the holidays, uh,
right down to your very core.
But why stop at me undies this year?
Me undies is launching their
holiday prince in lounge
pants and one sees as well.
Both are made from the same micro
modal modal fabric as their undies.
Seriously, how can you not get you and
your loved ones a matching holiday theme?
One Z this year. I don't
know. Maybe you got laid off.
Me undies has a great all bill [inaudible]
has a great offer for my listeners.
Friday, first time purchasers, you
put your shirts, your structures,
you can purchase any me undies you get
for 50% off and free shipping to get your
15% off your first pair and free
shipping and 100% satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] that's
[inaudible] dot com slash
burr one more. Everybody stamps. Dot.
Con Talk Bout how the holidays are always
the busiest time of year. You know,
people tell you, you think you're busy
for the first 11 months of the year,
and then the holidays come
around and you're like, wow,
this is the busiest time of year.
Sorry,
I'm contractually obligated to do that.
Why do you, what do you have on your list?
Your holiday list?
I want the Beastie boys
hardcover book that they put out,
or is it just Beastie boys?
I never been able to figure
that out because they were
always called the Beastie
boys and then one time they go, we're
not, the Beastie boys were Beastie boys.
And then you go back and listen to their
first fucking song. It's like, ah, pocket.
Just jealous were the Beastie
boys, right? It's like,
you fucking set it. What are you
guys, a bunch of hypocrites like me.
I want the,
I want Beastie boys or I can
say the one of my Russian,
I can't use the word though.
I want the Doug and then quote,
Beastie boys hardcover book.
That's what I want.
I want that a little fucking peace
and quiet where I can go read it. Um,
all right.
Can take a book.
I think I actually liked
their instrumental albums as
much as the ones that they
wrap on once a day. Hip Hop on.
I'm too white to know anything about
this shit, but I liked that band up.
Okay. Where am I? How many
errands do you have to run?
I don't think it's any
of your fucking business.
How is stamps.com helping you to
save times this holiday season? Well,
I can mail out all my Christmas gifts
right from the come from my own home.
Where in [inaudible] Bob,
a dop, dop out. Where? Eh,
sorry. That was a remix. Um, how is stamps
dot. I already answered that. As you know,
the holidays are the busiest time of year
am I am I stuck in like a fucking loop
here, especially at the post office.
That's why we use stamps.com.
It saves us so much time during the hectic
holiday season with all the time and
money you'll save.
stamps.com is the best gift you can give
yourself this holiday season and right
now you too can enjoy the stamps.com
service with a special offer that includes
a four week trial plus
postage and a digital scale
without longterm commitments.
Go to stamps.com click on
the microphone at the top,
the homepage and type in [inaudible],
B u r r that stamps.com and to burry.
Wait, there's another read. All
right, I'm waiting for that one. Okay.
You guys have listened to me. Read out
loud, but then I'm going to forget it.
If I don't do it, I'm going to forget
it. Ah, Jesus. What do I do here?
What do you guys, I'm going
to let you guys vote. Okay.
Calling one 800 red pubes and let me
know. All right, now I'm going to read it.
Okay, here we go. Um, my bookie,
everybody a and we want to place a bet,
but you didn't think you were vague.
You a big one team over
there this thanksgiving,
it's finally possible to get 100%
refund on your bed if you lose it.
But on your family, how
could they fucking, uh,
with the Turkey Day free play,
you can bet on this.
You can bet the spread on either
the law bears of the lions.
Why am I reading this? It's already
happened. If it wins you in,
if it loses my book, he will get
built. And these guys are trustworthy,
fast and helpful.
So you know they're good for it.
Nude to sports betting.
Uh, Jesus Christ. Okay,
I can read this shit here cause this
is just, you can read this anyway.
A new to sports betting and
have a lot of questions.
That's okay too because my book,
he's patient customer service can
teach you how to gamble on sports.
Sign up this week and my book,
He will give you a 50% deposit
bonus to jumpstart your bankroll.
It's a great way to bank
even more money when you win.
Log onto my bookie right now and use the
Promo Code [inaudible] B U R R to get
50% off. Uh, if they don't
get 50% deposit bone,
it says Promo Code Bar.
You need a,
you don't need a promo code for your
Turkey Day. Free play. That's over.
That's over. All right. All right,
we're done. Okay. There we go.
We ain't got to take a day. They
could give. We do. All right. Um,
there was something I
wanted to talk about. Yeah.
Black Friday and we've got to look
that up. Let's see. Did anybody,
why is it called black? For
me? It's an accounting term.
You're in the black, right?
If you're in the red.
Well incident,
not sensitive to native,
you know, Jesus. Alright. Um, black.
Okay.
Fry.
They
injuries
2018, you know some piece
of shit. Lawyers also
googling this black Friday death count.
Oh wait.
Two injured and stabbing at
New York Mall on Black Friday.
My fault man,
shopping on black Friday at Walmart
has a parent heart attack and dies.
Coroner says, man, injured
in shooting in New Jersey.
Jesus Christ.
People.
Is it really worth it to,
to,
to go out and get it the fucking deep
fryer you or whenever the hell it is
you're looking for.
Okay.
I'm telling you, you shop on Saturday.
You walk in like a gentleman. All right.
200 and stabbing in New York Mall.
All right. Now you do wonder,
did the person bring the knife there
just in case they didn't quite get to the
fucking nerf football fast enough.
Okay.
Um,
I don't like making fun of people with
not a lot of money who have to go and do
shit like this,
but that there's no reason to stab
somebody over a fucking microwave. Is that
okay?
Um, I mean, you can shoot
somebody over refrigerator,
but we're talking to microwave
here. I mean this, he can,
he can get one of those like 30
bucks. All right. Syracuse, New York.
Two men have been stabbed at a
confrontation at a central New York Mall,
a mid black Friday shopping.
This couldn't have been about this.
I feel like the violence only
happens at Walmart. Am I crazy?
Allegedly? All right. Syracuse
police tell local media outlets.
It happened around 4:15 PM at destiny USA
police and the mall manager management
say the dispute began at May,
at a Macy's store.
It's not immediately clear what
sparked the confrontation. Well,
if you're in Macy's,
I imagine it's the men department and
they were looking at a couple of button
downs there.
A officers found one man wounded in
the abdomen and another man wounded
elsewhere on his body.
That means you get stabbed in the groin.
Both are in their twenties and were
taken to a hospital managers just laying
under a clothes,
clothes rack.
Just looking up at the shirt that was
so fucking important eight seconds ago.
Please say the injuries don't
appear. Life threatening, uh,
photos by syracuse.com
and w s why our TV show,
a portion of Macy's and another store's
entrance were taped off for a time.
Uh,
destiny USA managers say the statement,
the bloodshed was an isolated incident
that that's absolutely unacceptable.
There you go, buddy. Make, make, make,
make a strong stand and strengthens
our resolve to remain vigilant.
What does that mean?
That's the statement.
Let's say those were the, all this
is, this is the, of all that. Listen,
those were the only two people
that got stabbed at Destiny USA,
uh,
which it's absolutely not acceptable
to stab someone at this mall.
Okay.
And,
uh,
we're now going to try
to really look at people,
okay?
Do make sure there's no stabbing
motions towards another customer.
Okay.
Are we really going to get to the point
in this country where going to have to
have a metal detector at a fucking
clothing store? All right, man.
Shopping on black Friday at
Walmart has a heart attack.
He must've got to the Billy Best first
and he couldn't fucking imagine his luck.
Oh, Bill. Really? I'm sorry. What am
I, this is a fucking comedy podcasts.
They have to make fun of things.
We ain't got a alright,
wham, wham, wham, wham. Bonk, Bonk, bonk.
All right.
A man died Friday after having an apparent
heart attack while shopping at the
Walmart. Wayne, sorry. This
is the Walmart right now.
It'll take this job and shove
who I worked in here no more.
That's my belly back.
She put that damn mother fucker all right.
At the Walmart on the u s to 80.
Okay.
In Phenix city authority. Say where
the fuck is Fenix looks like Phoenix,
but it's not. It's Phenix city. All
right. Little geography lesson. Everybody.
All right, here we go. F, p.
H.
F. P. H. E. N. I. X. Okay. Phoenix City,
Alabama. Oh, Jim, give me a break.
This is probably against
fucking a Bam. A fucking, uh,
War Eagle Fan. It's a city and Lee and
Russell counties in the state of Alabama.
Oh, it's almost a Georgia.
It's almost in Georgia.
That's the funniest thing about
Georgia is they look down on Alabama.
Fucking hilarious.
Yeah.
Wait Lot Graham. Shit. We
Polish our boots. All right.
A man died Friday after having an apparent
heart attack while shopping at the
Walmart on us to 80.
And Phenix city authority said the death
during Black Friday shopping was a sad
note to the holiday season. Oh,
here's, here's a, a little side note.
As a toddler drowned in his big
Gulf that he dropped, they dropped
and whatever, it's black Friday.
This is a black humor. Um,
witnesses on Facebook
expressing their condolences.
Russell County Coroner said
Teddy Venable 71. Ah, I feel bad.
It's just somebody's grandfather had
a heart, a history of heart problems.
He was pronounced. All right.
So that doesn't have anything
to do with, uh, Walmart.
Yeah, the history of let's lets the
guy had a history of heart problems.
He made it to 71.
God bless him.
Okay.
I hope for is peace of mind was a
fucking Bama fan rather than Auburn,
you know, just so we had more joy in
his life. He probably was. I bet he was.
That's what kept him going. All
right, man. Injured in shooting.
Okay.
See where we go from here.
Jesus Christ.
All this shows a glock when
you get here. All right, man.
Injured and shooting at New Jersey
Mall. Elizabeth, New Jersey.
The waning hours of black Friday were
disrupted and New Jersey Mall on Friday as
a man was wounded by gunfire
shortly after 8:00 PM.
That is way too early in
the evening to get shot.
Okay.
What did the guy who got shot
say, I'm actually, I'm actually,
I'm going to side with the shooter
on this one. You know what I mean?
You should somebody around midnight
then see now here you're fucking drunk,
asshole. But you shoot somebody at
8:00 AM and 8:00 PM they deserved it.
All right?
The man was shot in the wrist,
in a hallway between the marshals and
Tommy Hilfiger stores at the Mills,
at Jersey Gardens in Elizabeth.
All right.
The shooter was,
has not been caught in.
The victim is not cooperating
with the authorities are right.
This is gang related. This has nothing
to do. Okay. There you go. See,
you know what's in. Those are really
only just one stabbing at Macy's.
Now the guy had a history
of heart problems. You know,
we went there that the fucking,
I dunno.
What did the hedge clippers were
still there? He couldn't believe it.
He fucking had a heart attack. Yeah.
That guy. Yeah. That shit, you know,
get shot in the wrist. Yeah, I'm not what
happened? Yeah, I know. I don't know.
You sit in that booth, a bullet in your
fucking arrested. You not cooperate.
That is gang related. I'm going to go
out on a limb there. All right, Bill,
can we get back to the podcast? Wait, I'm
going to make you guys hate that song.
Sorry.
Okay.
All right. Let's get to a little, so
let's get to some of the questions here.
All right. Gaslighting.
Hey, Billy. Truck, nuts. Um,
I didn't know what that means. I heard
you and Nia talking about gaslighting.
I thought you might find it interesting
that the origin of that word comes from
in 1944 movie called gaslight.
Yeah. Somebody sent this to me.
This is really interesting.
It's about a husband that's systematically
manipulates little things in her
environment to get her
to think she's crazy.
One example is when he dimmed
the gas lights in the house,
she mentioned to her husband about the
dim lights and he would pretend that they
were fine. The wiki
page explains it. Well,
longtime way listener and love the show.
I'm going to have to watch that.
All right. Go to the page. Here
we go. Let's read. All right.
Gaslighting. I thought gaslighting was
you. You, you're like blowing somebody up,
you know, saying that they
were better than they were.
It turns out it was the exact opposite.
It's a form of psychological manipulation
that seeks to sow the seeds of doubt
in a targeted individual or in
a member of a targeted group,
making them question their own memory,
perception and sanity.
Using persistent denial, misdirection,
counter diction, and lying.
I feel like persistent denial,
misdirection and counter contradiction.
That's more like, that's more
finessed. The lying is just, yeah,
that's just gorilla pimp,
right?
You just fucking punching him in the face
and attempts to Dee Dee stabilize the
victim in de legitimize
the victim's belief, uh,
instances may range from the denial
by an abuser that the previous abusive
incidents ever occurred. Oh, this
is what your parents always saw.
That never happened.
Um,
up to staging of bizarre events by the
abuser with the intention of disorienting
the victim.
Okay.
All right.
Guess what I'm going to watch tonight.
I'm going to watch that movie cast lady,
uh, guys, a gaslight or gas lighting.
Um, well, we called gaslight.
I got to watch that. Anything
in black and white. I fucking,
I really enjoy cleaning
one of my specials. Sorry.
Advice for the fellow cubicle warriors.
Hey Billy Wonka.
Now how did nobody ever come
up with that one? Billy Walker.
I recently changed my life by
setting all my devices to night mode,
permanently phone, laptop, iPad.
I had the standard headache and I pains
from all these screens in my face all
day long. We got to buy those glasses
that they gave me the blue tint on him.
Okay.
Yeah. What do, what do wherever you,
it's to the point now when
someone shows me their iPhone,
I kind of pull back cause I can feel
those blue lights wrapping my brain.
I think it's something you and
your listeners should know.
Oh, you said everything
tonight. Oh, night mode. Oh,
so it's not as bright in
your face. Well, you know,
it'd be great if you show me how to do
that. I could probably look that up.
I liked the direction you're going.
Answer any sort of paranoia is
right in my fucking wheel off. Uh,
my first comedy show. What's the etiquette
of sit there and shut the fuck up.
Laugh if it's funny.
If you want to heckle Haeckel but don't
be a obeyed anyways. Hi Bill. Big Fan.
So glad that you're coming to Germany out.
Jesus.
This is somebody from another country.
There's no comedy in
Germany on say laughing.
Um, I have just bought a ticket
to your first show of the tour,
the one in Cologne.
Okay.
Uh, on June 4th of January. By the
way, I learned the last time Cologne,
Germany was one of the number one bombed
cities in World War II and there's
still a few buildings
that survived a big fan.
So glad that you were coming to Germany.
I have just bought a ticket for
your first show in that tour. Uh,
the one in Cologne. I ended the best
time when I was there last time. Uh,
so I'm anticipating it's going to be
another way to show this will be the first
comedy show I go to in my whole life.
I moved to Germany two years ago.
Before that I lived in Moldova,
a small,
insignificant country that
bright stars don't go to anyways.
Do you think that on one
of your podcast episodes,
you could take a minute or two to explain
how these comedy shows go for you?
What does the ideal spectator behave like?
Should I bring flowers and give them
to you on stage? Uh, I, this guy,
this guy's going to
heckle the shit out of me.
And how do you get the chance
to meet you after the show?
It would be a real honor
to be able to do so.
Thank you all the best to you and your
family and I wish you a great European
trucks, a tour. Um, that's it.
You go there, you sit down,
you get yourself a drink,
and then you listen to the comedians.
If what they say is funny,
you laugh at what if it isn't
right? Don't laugh. And uh,
if you go too long without laughing,
then you heckle. I mean that,
that's a part of it. I hate to tell
that to, to, to an audience member.
But that's true.
And I think that that's one of the
great things about standup comedy is the
heckling. It's a great thing about
politics too. You know, it's fun,
but it sucks as a politician cause you
can't tell him to go fuck themselves,
you know?
Well,
why don't you raise the taxes in our
county because you're fucking your sister
in that fucking pig trough.
Yup.
Hayseed content that gets an
applause break in my business.
That ends your career as a politician.
Although Donald Trump,
president Trump has shown that
maybe that isn't the case. Um,
I am so excited for this European tour.
I am,
I am clean living Billy until I get
out there. You know what I mean?
And I'm not going to fuck it up either
because I'm taping a special in March,
I believe of next year. So,
um, I had my last bit of fun.
Um, this weekend I am done.
No cigars, no fucking booze,
no bread, no cookies, no
chips, no, no nothing. And uh,
I'm shutting it down during the, during
the toughest time of the year. And uh,
I feel fucking good about an eight hours
sleep and I'm drinking fucking waters.
And this includes right through the
rose bowl because I'm sad to announce
that the,
literally the cornerstone of the tailgate
can't make it this year because he's
got a Gig. Uh, the, the,
the five star Chef Jason Law head,
unfortunately due to circumstances beyond
his control cannot be there this year.
And, um, it, it's, yeah,
it's, it's like, you know,
he's going to be there next
year, hopefully. You know,
who knows if he keeps fucking getting
gigs, I don't know. But this is like,
you know,
I don't know.
I'm hoping it's just this year,
the fact that he's not going
to be there. I mean, you know,
he does his Reggie Jackson impression,
he fucking just crushes it
with the breakfast sandwiches
he just made. It's just,
it's like a massive, you know,
this is like Derek Jeter retired.
Well, I was, I'm just going to
say he's out with an injury,
so we're going to go easier. I think
we're going to go easier this year,
do it a little bit differently, but I'm
not going to be boozing, um, at all.
I'm done with this shit.
I gotta get myself a tip top condition
because I am not a young man anymore.
And that,
that European tour is a
10 cities in 10 nights.
MMM.
And it's just, yeah. So I'm,
and a lot of those places
I haven't been to ever,
so I cannot go there and fuck up. I
have to go there and be, you know,
I gotta be in my best on my best behavior.
Got To help him not on
planes every fucking day.
MMM.
But if I am going to be,
the last thing I need to be doing is
fucking going out there acting like a
fucking idiot. All right. Here we go.
Uh, drinking as a college freshman.
Speaking of boozing, dear
bill, I'm a college freshmen,
freshmen and just recently went to my
first dorm party that wasn't held in my
room to hilarious. You sound like me
back in the day. I'm an introvert.
So luckily for me, I got a roommate
who is social and likes to party.
Otherwise I would probably be spending
all my time in my room and not
interacting with anybody. Well, that's
good. Give get yourself out there.
It doesn't mean he gotta be
an idiot though. All right.
You got to drink responsibly.
Actually.
You're not supposed to be drinking
because you're under age. Look at me.
I'm a dad now.
Uh,
I mostly kept to myself throughout high
school and had a few friends but never
really did much with them outside
of school. Uh, because of that,
I never had any alcohol.
I'm not much of a party guy,
but I wanted to step out of my comfort
zone. So I decided, decided to go.
It sounds like the beginning of the,
a really interesting movie. Oh God.
Okay. So you go in there. All right. Um,
yeah.
Hey, this is the thing for all
you young people out there.
If you've never really
done something before,
the best thing you could do is tell people
that you haven't just fucking own it.
Yeah. I never, I never drank any
more. I'm a little nervous about it.
I just want to go easy. Just give me one
here and there, all lap. But they'll,
they'll like,
it is when you act like you been there
before and that's when you get in trouble.
I'm not much of a party guy, but I
wanted to step out of my comfort zone.
So I decided to go, uh, that
includes even being a virgin.
Yeah.
Do you know where's the fucking
shy? Never, never bagged anybody.
It has an APP right
for me.
Help me out guys.
Yeah.
Then it began to date.
Have you get, brings people
together. Lets get them laid.
Okay.
Just don't go to a hookah. Uh,
I'm not much of a party guy,
but I wanted to step
out of my comfort zone.
So I decided to go for my lack of
experience. It seemed pretty wild.
Okay.
There was lots of alcohol,
mostly hard liquor,
vaping making out and loud rap music
that I didn't know the lyrics to. Dude,
you are hilarious man.
This guy's a writer.
MMM.
Really? Paint the picture here.
Being the sheltered person that I am,
I stayed in the corner and
just observed everyone else.
I was approached by a few people that
offered alcohol, but I kindly refuse.
That's good. You're a strong person
saying that I would drink something else.
I realized that the alcohol would help
me loosen up. So it was pretty tempting,
but not having any experience with it.
I decided not to smart
man using your head,
even though I kept to
myself for the most part,
I had some fun and I'm looking
forward to the next party. I am,
I am a pretty small person, 105 pounds
soaking wet and about five feet,
seven inches tall. So it wouldn't
take much for me to feel the effects.
Um,
I'm mostly afraid of how I would act.
And what I would say through
your very smart person,
a college is all about new experiences.
Right? So what do you think?
Should I drink the next time a party
at a party or gathering comes up?
If so, what advice do you have?
Thanks and go fuck yourself. Um,
I dunno, you're underage so I can't
tell you to go drink. He shouldn't do.
If if I how I w I wish I would
have handled situations like that.
I just tell your roommate
that that's the deal.
I never really drank
or anything like that.
And I would stay in your dorm
room and just drink a beer.
I would do that. And then
tell your roommate to say,
Hey, can you do me a favor?
Just look out for me at this party. I
don't want to do with say anything stupid.
Right. And then on top of that, when
you go to the party, don't fucking,
don't get crazy as long as you got it,
as long as you sitting there
with a beer in your hand,
you can literally have water in the,
in the can for all they know and just
be sipping a, you know, but it's,
it's a very mature thing that you're
already considering not being out of
control. So I wouldn't do that. Okay.
You shouldn't drink if you're underage.
You shouldn't. I did. It was stupid.
I got in a lot of trouble and it ended
with me getting fucking arrested and me
finally fucking smart enough. Really,
the reality is, is you, you know,
nothing good comes from it.
It's not good for you.
It's not good for you health
wise. Um, it's not, it's not good.
It's just not good for
you. Um, you put on,
you're going to put on the wrong kind
of weight if, if you do. However,
when you're of age, occasionally
having a beer is the way you do it.
If you are mature person,
here I am 50 years of fucking age and
I still have to shut it down because I
don't even know how to do it.
Um,
so that know that that is the
world that you're going into.
So I think it's good that
you're very cautious. Um,
having said that, there's other
ways to have fun, but you know,
you want to meet some women or
whatever, so just fucking go, you know,
it's a strong move. These would
go there and you're not drinking.
You know what I mean?
But then it gets weird if you start
talking to a woman and she's been drinking
and then you haven't,
and then she wants to fucking hookup,
then it's this weird
fucking, yeah, it gets,
it gets fucking weird man. Um, I
would, you know what I would do,
I would explore the place to other ways
to be social. Go to the fucking party,
don't fucking drink. You know,
you'll be ahead of the game.
Um, and then I would find out the
other social activities. I mean,
you're not the only person at
school that doesn't drink. You know,
maybe you can meet some
fucking responsible, you know,
woman have a good time that way.
There's a lot of ways to skin the cat.
And I'm really outside my element
because I was the idiot that went to the
fucking party and did shitty in school.
So do
you go up?
You don't have to drink.
You don't have to fucking have a beer.
All right?
Depress girlfriend. Just no, dude,
you're totally in control and there's
nothing wrong with anything about you,
anything that you're doing.
And uh,
in a lot of ways you're stronger than
most other people because they're just
doing what everybody else is doing,
which is the easiest thing, right?
And you'll see it in your lifetime when
every douche bag goes out and get some
sells a fucking robot because
their neighbor has one. All right.
Depress girlfriend. Hello Billy
blue blobs. Billy blue balls.
Um, so recently I've started
a relationship with a girl.
Okay.
And uh,
she told me that she needed to tell me
something very important that I might not
like about her.
Uh,
she told me that she had been diagnosed
as depressed for several years.
Mind you,
I've only known this girl for several
months and I don't know her circumstances.
Is this a deal breaker? Do I break
up with their, should I ignore it?
If I break up with her,
is she going to harm herself?
The situation puts me in a bad
position and I am not sure what to do.
I think she regrets telling me because
she doesn't want me to judge her. Also,
I am a younger male still in high school
and I feel like I am not mature enough
to deal with this situation.
Help us appreciate it.
All right.
Okay. Number one, anytime you have a
problem you should never ignore it.
Cause all it does is just get bigger.
MMM.
Is this a deal breaker?
Do I break up with her?
These are all decisions you have to
make. Um, as far as you breaking,
if you do break up with it, is it
going to harm her? He, it's not your,
your responsibility in life is your
happiness when it comes to relationships.
Okay. And if you're in something
you don't want to be in, in a nice,
respectful way,
you sit down with the person,
you tell them you're not
happy that you liked them.
You just don't like him in a
way where you want to continue.
And then you don't just not talk to them.
You can still be friends with them
and stuff like that. You just,
you don't have to be a fucking
asshole about it. However,
though, if, if, you know,
if at the end,
all of this shit,
what this person is bringing to
the table is not what you're into,
then there's nothing wrong
with breaking up with them. Um,
there's plenty of ways
for her to get help.
It's not your responsibility that
she has been diagnosed as depressed.
Um,
okay.
But you know, I, I would talk to
her about it. They just say like,
you know what? It's what? It's
okay.
How it makes you feel just yet. I don't
want to just say, listen, I'm not judging.
We all got our issues or
whatever. Um, you know,
I would just talk to her and learn more
about it. Learn how is it, how deep is it?
You know, she laid on the floor for weeks
and can't get out of the fucking house.
I mean, you know, I mean, that's, that's,
that's a lot to take on as summer
is out there with butterflies.
Fly Swirling around your head. If you're
not having a fucking problem, you know,
it's, it's all gonna be up to
you. But I would not ignore it.
I would just sit down and talk to her
about it and then digest it and then see
how you're feeling about it and
whatever your gut is telling you to do,
I would do, and if it's stay with
her, I would stay with during,
if it's says to leave, leave, but do
what, you know, you don't have to be me.
And when you break up with somebody,
and one of the worst things ever is they
don't teach people how to break up with
people. Uh, there should just
be a fucking class on that.
And like the,
the masters of it are the ones who can
break up with somebody and they can still
be friends with them is an incredible
thing. But, and, but I, and you know,
and I think the only way to
do that is if from day one,
you're just honest and you're constantly
checking in emotionally about where
you're at. Because if you don't, and
it's going off the rails and you know,
it's off the rails and
the other person doesn't,
that's when somebody feels
like they got dumped.
But if you're talking the whole way along,
the other person kind of knows
what's good, still sucks.
It's still going to be painful,
but it's not that fucking like,
where did that come from?
And then the next thing you know,
she's standing outside your fucking
bedroom window with a pair of sharpen
scissors. All right, so there
you go. That's the podcast.
It's a little bit short
this week, but, uh,
I gotta I gotta figure out how to fucking
download Skype again so I can throw
this other bullshit or whatever.
All right. Uh, that's it. Everybody.
Hope you all had a great thanksgiving.
I hope y'all had great thanksgiving.
I hope you didn't get
trampled on black Friday.
I will check in on you on Thursday. I'm
enjoying Monday night football tonight.
And once again, please watch, uh,
I know you already listened to it,
but if you haven't listened to it,
the Joe Rogan experience,
I'll be there Wednesday, uh,
spitting chiclets Wednesday, uh,
Barstool sports and I'm doing
dice Clay's podcast. Um,
I don't know when that one's
going to be uploaded. Um,
I don't know how he does it. I've
never done this podcast, but, uh,
that's what I'll be doing this week.
Kevin had been on Friday. Okay.
Get your Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit
tickets and lastly, but not leastly.
What was the other thing?
Um, oh, F is for family.
Jesus Christ. Jesus Christ.
November 29th, Netflix.
Please sit down and watch it.
All right.
See Ya.