Hey, what's going on? Is Bill Burn?
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast from Monday. Yeah.
[inaudible] 11th,
2019 what's going on?
How I yeah. Oh, how you doing?
I'm in a great mood despite the fact
that I missed that fucking the first moto
GP race of the, of the year. Uh,
I found out direct TV isn't,
doesn't have it on fucking
television anymore out here,
which was very disappointing
to me. You know, I couldn't
find it. I was scampering.
I woke up in a sweat gold. Wait a minute.
Wait. It says f one stock today. I know.
Thought ducks today. Ha Ha. Going
to miss it. Right? Freaking out.
OCD. Fucking 20 God damn
racist. God forbid you miss one.
So I look up f one that doesn't start
til next week down in Australia.
Okay.
I already have that recorded.
That's easy because that got picked
up by ESPN. So I'm like, all right.
Where the fuck's the Moto GP?
I have direct TV. All right.
I'm not trying to talk down to
all you people. That's right.
I can still afford to pay for cable.
That's how fucking hard I am.
Crushing it
out here in these streets. All
you fucking cord cutters, Huh?
Just backing yourself into a
fucking entertainment corner.
Just sitting there with your apps and
your little Netflix fucking subscription.
That's your world, Huh?
What are you going to do?
Watch every episode of Narcos and then
some stupid documentary to try and
impress your friends,
you what you, you need.
You need those 700 fucking channels
that they have 300 of which are radio
stations.
What are you walking away from?
Millennials? What are you afraid
of? They're all proud of it too,
because when I couldn't
find it on direct TV,
I went onto the Twitter and very nicely,
dare I say eloquently, I just put out
to the Twitter sphere. I said, hey,
does anybody know what channel the
Moto GP is on? On? On direct TV. Okay.
And Oh,
oh good.
The cons come out of the woodwork.
Jesus Christ.
You would've thought I put a fucking
piece of cheese down in a bun.
All the fucking little ratchet
that came running out, right?
Durant's even eat cheese.
Don't they can eat anything.
You know what I mean? Like if you just
put like a severed finger in a mousetrap,
wouldn't have fucking rat eventually come
up and try and eat the fucking thing.
I mean, I don't give a shit.
Right? I like that relative.
That always shows up to the event, never
brings anything and just hovers. Right.
Hovers around the fucking table. Doesn't
use that fucking spoon, you know,
to scoop it out. Easiest. Reach it in with
his fucking myths. That's what rats are,
right? That's a rat. And social
Runkle. Anyways, plowing ahead.
So I put it out there nicely. Okay.
I, I like to feel like, you know,
being a man in my fifties now that I am,
I am refined. I am a man of the world.
All right? I drive a four door
sedan. I still pay for cable.
Okay. So I'm, I'm like this close
to buying a pair of loafers.
Do you want to stand it?
Like that?
Debt is like how established
I am as an adult.
So I put it out there nicely. Does anybody
know what channel the MotoGP races on?
Uh, on direct TV? Oh, these fucking cops
come out of the woodwork at first of all,
you know, channels 60 died. Huh? You
get it. Are you going to try that? Huh?
Right. Then they start
doing this. What? Boris?
Then they start speaking in Twitter speak.
I didn't know that direct
TV was still a thing.
Oh wow man. You're like so cool. The way
you, the way you get your entertainment,
Jesus Christ, you would've thought
I showed up with a fucking, I dunno,
the wrong pair of sneakers on it and I
wouldn't always, like in fifth grade,
the fact that I actually suggested that
I had no idea there was so much shame
and still having direct TV.
I pay like 200 bucks a month for cable.
I swear to God. What do you think?
I went from one fucking, uh,
podcasts a week to two. I got
to pay for my direct TV. I do.
You know, somebody told me one time, he
goes, dude, you pay way too much money.
Just kept me come over
there and I'll yell at him.
I'll cut it in half because all these
fucking people a cord cutting and shit.
You can, you know I have all the sports
packages. Oh yeah, I'm talking shit here.
People.
Okay.
I pay for direct TV.
I am all for sports packages.
All right man.
I miss most of the Games.
Okay.
You want to talk about taking hundreds
of just throwing them into a fire?
A lightness. A Garth.
That's how I'm rolling. Um,
anyway, so it turns out that
direct TV no longer, um,
carries moto GP,
which in my world is the best fucking
racing out there as far as if you want to
see excitement. If you want
passing, okay, okay. You, you, you,
you fucking NASCAR guys down there.
Huh? With your fucking stale.
That also doubles as a smoker during
the tailgate. You want to get drunk.
You stayed on this side if you want
some buffalo, but you get on that side,
right?
You guys want to see fucking excitement.
Do you want to see passing and
that type of shit? You want to see,
if you want to see a Rick watch a fucking
guy high side on a motorcycle going
like fucking 200 miles an hour,
like once every three racist.
It's just something that would make evil
Knievel be like Jesus fucking Christ.
Is that guy still alive? Which point
you said it's called an airbag evil.
You know they watched you a little
jump there at fucking Caesar's.
Who am I tell he evil Knievel
would laugh at that bullshit.
The little light bikes in their
fucking airbags. You know,
he went out there wearing a fucking
pair of leather under roos and gun on a
fucking chopper. You can fucking
buy down at the local store
fucking bike.
Way more than my goddamn head.
Um,
anyway,
um, you want to watch this motor GP?
So I fucking end ended up going online.
Everybody is like, why don't you watch
it on Reddit for free or whatever.
So I did, I go to moto GP, their
website. I sign up for this season.
Hundred and 39 bucks, right? More
money, more money, just fucking,
just flying out the window. Right. So, um,
I signed up for it and
then I'm such an old guy,
I couldn't figure out where to watch it.
And I finally figured it
out after the race was over,
you got to click on this like four lines
on the side and one of them says live
and when you click on that,
that's the fucking race.
So by the time I figured that out, you
know, it's counting down like fucking,
you know, 9,000 hours until the
next God damn race. So I missed it.
Okay.
And like all MotoGP races
said that sounded like it
was exciting as hell and it
came right down to the end and uh,
divisio so beat mock mock test like he
did last year by like the length of his
bike. And um, I dunno,
I'm hoping if anybody you know,
watches it on MotoGP GP site,
if they replay it, I can't even
find a fucking highlight of it. Um,
but anyways, so all you read
next down there, who like
you stock car racing, just,
it's 20 something lapse.
It'll go by in two seconds.
And I know it's a bunch of foreigners
out there on their little Modo scooters.
Hi. Eight. Nobody named
Kale or Harry or Dale.
You know,
there's a mark that's kind of
an, you know, Andre's divisio.
So Jorge Lorenzo,
close the fucking bar.
I'd like to build a wall around that
fucking race tracks. What the fuck?
I'd like to do, jump over
that motherfucker. Um,
so anyways, I might seem a little
like my energy is a little higher,
little more giddy. It's
because, uh, I ain't doing shit.
I got a special in the can man.
And uh,
I'm just,
uh,
I haven't done stand up since I said good
night on the second show and a tonight
I'm actually going down to the,
um, to the comedy store that had,
it's close to the public. It's just
for comics only and it's the, uh,
the memorial for Brody Stevens,
which I think is going to be a,
I think it's going to be great.
It's going to be sad, but I,
I really think it's like, he was
such an uplifting guy and it was so,
so much to learn from him that
I am really looking forward to,
uh,
to going down there and celebrating that
guy's life and the work that he, uh,
that he did down at the comedy store.
One of the legends, one of the legends.
Um, there's a place out
front where they put all the,
all the names of the people that really
built that place and kept it going.
I hope they move his name up there.
That's what I'm going to, uh, suggest.
Um, so anyway, um, yeah,
all I did, I took my daughter
down to the park, you know,
we went on the fucking, all the
rides and all that stuff. Just said,
like the best time hanging out with her.
And um,
I, we've said we'd watched the
Bruins. We watched the Celtics Swat.
I watch the Bruins, I watched three
Bruins games is fucking weekend. Um,
the panthers, Ottawa, which bolt
ended great. And then, uh, Pittsburgh,
I had a feeling they were going to get us.
I mean we literally one like
18 or 19 in a row undefeated,
you know, we were like, we
were like 1501 four I think.
So at some point someone was going
to have to stop us and uh, uh,
the penguins always play as tough and as
much as it sucked that the streak ended.
It was our longest point streaks since
I guess the early forties. But um,
I got to tell you some Sidney
Crosby's pass and the second period,
did anybody see that?
Jesus Christ.
Oh yeah. You, that's one of the
things you watch. It's just like,
what do we need robots for? Like that's
like the kind of thing like a robot,
you know,
skating that fast,
trying to get around the defenseman and
then he has another guy streaking down
on the outside of another diff,
a defenseman and then you've got the
goalie who could poke check the pass away.
He put it the only place where it could
fucking be like a top rate fucking pass
to the quarter of the end zone.
Yeah,
right on the tape bag bag in
the back of the fucking nuts.
It was just one of those.
It's one of those things,
even though the other team did it,
you can't even get mad.
You just like Jesus Christ. That was
fucking, it was a thing of beauty. Um,
so,
uh,
I don't have another fucking gig other
than one quick benefit in New York then
I'm doing on April 2nd garden dreams,
um, at Msg, uh, in the theater
where Eddie Murphy did raw.
I always think about that when I, when
I go down and do a show that, that,
that this is where he did that
special and I saw him on that tour,
what used to be called
great words and Mansfield,
Massachusetts with the
weather girls opening up. I,
for the life of me cannot find any
record of that date. When it happened.
I think I finally found it.
What do you,
what are you fucking millennial
nerds find that all right.
It was like 85 or 1986.
Great Woods had just opened Mansfield,
Massachusetts.
And that summer I saw,
I saw Rodney Dangerfield and
this was post back to school.
He was that movie hit and
he was on this huge tour.
Um,
yeah.
And then,
uh,
I saw him and then that a couple of
weeks later I saw Eddie Murphy and I
remember that, that really, uh,
was something that stuck with
me. I was like 18 years old. And,
um,
I remember when I went to
see danger fields watching
him and just looking around
at the crowd. Um, and it didn't dawn
on me, that was an all white crowd.
Cause I, you know, I'm
white. I was just like,
this is what the world looks like to
me at that point in my life. You know,
living in the s the
safe suburbs of Boston,
Massachusetts was just a bunch of white
people. So it didn't really dawn on me.
That was an all white crowd. And I
remember looking around thinking, wow man,
this guy's making everybody laugh.
He's killing. This is amazing. Right?
And then a couple of weeks later I saw
Eddie Murphy and the crowd was mixed.
And I remember that stuck with me.
I was like, this guy, but this guy,
this guy's making everybody laugh.
Um, I had lawn seats for that.
I had seats for Dangerfield,
so I actually saw him and, uh,
it kills me that I didn't try and
pony up some more money back then,
but I didn't have any money to not
sit in the, in, in a fucking field.
I mean,
I didn't really technically see him.
I was just watching them on the monitors
and, but he was wearing that purple,
a Mariachi suit that he wore.
Um,
so anyways, uh, fuck am I talking about
here? How the hell did I get onto that?
Uh,
I dunno when I watched the
Celtics versus the Lakers and, uh,
at the risk of sounding like an old man,
I fucking hate NBA hoop now.
You know, it's just, it's, he says,
fuck up and down the fucking court.
Everybody launched in a three.
There's nobody underneath, you know,
the other teams on a 10 old Ron
yet just keep launching three's.
There's no feed and the
big man down low anymore.
None of nobody can stand
in the fucking paint. Um,
you know,
I dunno.
I Dunno what the fuck is going on with
the Celtics. I haven't watched too much,
but I watched a bunch of the last couple
of years, and I can tell you this,
we had fucking Jae Crowder and Kelly
Olynyk and everybody was fucking listening
to Brad Stevens.
We were a tougher team to beat.
We didn't have the level of talent,
but we were a tougher team to beat
and this whole fucking new era.
And you hear the announcers
just like, you know, they,
they condone the behavior that people get
so good that they don't have to listen
to the coach anymore.
And I'm not just picking on the Celtics,
like that's like a round the
fucking league. And I dunno,
I don't know. You know, he's going to have
to get his touch. His fuck is touches.
They're going out here to win the
fucking game. Drives me quick.
We have this unbelievable chance right now
with the talent talent that we have.
We should be able to at the very
least scare the Golden State Warriors.
Um, I know we beat him the day in
regular, but that doesn't mean shit.
It's one game regular season.
Like those guys are the fucking champs.
They're in the middle of a fucking dynasty
and they're going to have an entirely
different energy when you meet
them in the finals. All right?
As opposed to fucking one game out of 80
or whatever that you happened to catch
him on a fucking Wednesday
night and you beat them. Um,
we have this great opportunity to win
another one while the Lakers are fucking
rebuilding and I love how
everybody's second panic mode,
like Magic Johnson and those guys are
doing exactly what the fuck they said they
were going to do it. We brought in
Lebron. Okay. This is a two year plan.
Like the, the, the fan base is
there is so fucking impatient now,
like a two year plan is taking too long.
So it's literally you bring in fucking
Lebron the first year and then he's going
to attract all of this free agent help
and then they're all gonna go out there
and pile on because everyone wants to
be part of the Lakers fucking, you know,
great history and they want to fuck
models and famous women yet all that stuff
fucking thing that they
have over the Celtics.
They got the weather and they got the
pussy. We just can't fucking compete.
You know you want to go racist city
to racist city. We're right there. Oh,
we got your eyeball to eyeball.
You want to go championships?
We got two more than they do. Unless
you count that Ba one that they count.
Okay.
But they have the weather and
they have the pussy and that,
that right fucking there.
You know what I mean?
The fuck are you going to do with
that? How do you, how do you beat that?
Okay.
Location, location, location.
How many titles do you
think that the fucking
Lakers would have had if
they stayed in Minneapolis?
Okay.
And they had the exact same ownership.
I'm asking you,
can they still attract the level
of talent that they attracted
being out there in Hollywood.
Now all of a sudden you're
in the frozen Tundra.
Okay.
Of Minneapolis, Minnesota, right.
You got fucking farm fed checks where
in their overalls coming in from Duluth.
Right. You got some hayseeds making
the trek in from fucking the Dakotas.
I mean, I don't, I, I just
don't see it. I just don't,
I just don't think there's enough pussy
and you don't have the fucking weather,
whether in pussy have,
have,
have caused more goddamn athletes to
make stupid fucking moves to jump out of
the NFL and join the fucking
world football league.
Well, money to money whether
and pussy, the TRIFECTA.
Um, so I don't know, I'm just hoping
people listen to Brad Stevens.
Just listen to what the fuck this
guy says. Play like a Goddamn team.
Fuck your own stats and just go out there
and get it done and let's fucking win
another one before the lake is a
common cause the Lakers are common.
They're always coming. Okay.
It's almost like a rule.
They can only suck for like five fucking
years before they're going to read.
And you know that their whole fucking,
their whole fucking history is, is,
is free agents,
free agents.
Three write down to Koby Bryant who
was a fucking, uh, Charlotte Hornet.
But what kills me, you know, look at
that and Antonio Brown like, yeah,
you're going to the bills.
Yeah.
I'm not playing for them when they
get the fuck out of the league.
Like,
I don't understand the bills just made a
move to get one of the top receivers in
the league, but he doesn't
like where the fuck they are.
So he's not going to fucking
go. I mean that, that,
I don't know what happened to parody in
the fucking league. I'd like, listen,
I'm all for it. Like players not
getting fucked over by ownership,
but they're at the point now where
they have too much power. You know,
kind of like where the
unions were when I was a kid,
which caused all these
fucking corporations. It'd
be like, all right, well,
we're just going to move the
corporation out of this fucking country
and go back to sweatshop labor.
You know, and I'm a I, you know,
I don't mind union unions.
I'm not saying don't have a fucking union,
but who's kidding? No kidding. And most
people don't handle power. Well. Right.
And then it became to Grady to conti
too much leaning on the mop and then the
fucking rich guys who were like,
yeah, we're fucking out of here.
I gotta tell you something. All of
what I've just said here. I've, no,
I don't think I've ever really read on it.
I've just,
this is all me just pasting
together conversations I've
heard throughout my life.
Okay.
Well like I've said before,
if you want clear and
accurate information,
you listen to the Joe Rogan podcast.
By the way.
I have to give that guy a shout out.
Right.
As far as like what that
guy has done with his part.
Have you been looking at the fucking
guests at that guy's getting,
he's getting like
Elon Musk and the doctor Phil and a David
Lee Roth and then like some scientists
that everyone heard of who then blows
my mind about like some sort of like a,
I dunno, I know some scientific
shit. I know fucking,
I mean I'm too stupid understand it,
but like that guy is
like, I dunno, I dunno what school,
where this podcasting world goes,
but like at this point,
if you do,
if you're a guest on his show,
you get more heat than if you do like,
like a fucking legendary talk show.
It's honor.
It's unbelievable what
that guy is as has done.
I was just thinking the other day, I
forget what the fuck. Yes. Did I see,
I think once a David Lee Roth,
I think it was just the,
the variety of guests.
They, I mean, again,
Doctor Phil,
that's fucking huge.
I mean that is like a big
mainstream old school guest.
I'm going to go do the talk show circuit.
I'm going to fucking go do
terrestrial radio and all that.
You get that fucking guy. I mean
that, I thought that that was a big,
you know, I don't know. That's a big
moment that's right up there. You know,
when Marin had Obama on,
um,
I think when they look back at like
what are these podcasts come from?
But what were some of the
watershed moments like I would say,
okay,
I dunno,
stamps.com starting to advertise and then
it goes Obama on Mark Marin's and then
it's Joe Rogan's numbers
and his wide variety of gay,
I mean he had like Elon Musk on his show.
The guy took a hit of a joint
and it affected his stock prices.
That's fucking amazing.
Um, anyways, but meanwhile,
here I sit in my fucking sweatpants
talking to myself, stubborn,
stubborn German Irish guy.
He's just going to do it this way.
I don't want to talk to people,
man. I'm not fucking with you. I,
I if you've noticed when I do interviews,
I'm a lot of times of too busy thinking
about what the fuck I want to say or
somebody says something and I drift
off and that it becomes like that Chris
Farley thing where I'm just fucking
grabbing the side of my pants going, man,
when you did this, that was awesome. Um,
all right, so, oh Billy, no booze bag.
Okay.
107 fucking days.
And I went to the gym yesterday
and for the first time,
and I like the three years I did
a dip testing out my shoulders.
Fortunately where I go to the gym,
they have like this, uh, the, the,
the dip machine, you can actually remove
the dip bar and adjusted to your height.
So I have it just way down near the
floor where my arms are actually straight
when I'm holding onto it.
And then I just sort of, uh,
went up on my toes,
you know,
supporting my weight with my arms and
went up on my toes like Michael Jackson,
you know, and uh, you know,
minus that documentary,
whatever the fuck is going on with that.
And I was just slowing myself down.
And every day,
every time I felt a little bit stronger.
And then yesterday I was
like, oh no, I think I can do
one. I did one filter, right?
And then I kind of did three
in a row and I was just like,
why did I just do that?
Because I'm finding what the,
the rotator cuff, it's a,
is it rotator or road? Rotor cuff.
Rotator cuff. Um, rotor cuff.
Jesus Christ. I've had this injury
for three fucking years and I don't,
it's one of the,
you know,
I just had these words that I
don't really know how to say.
So I just say fast and
hope people don't notice rotator cuff.
Yeah.
Oh, at first I used to think, is
it rotator cup? A rotator cuff?
I don't know what the fuck it is. Um, if
you're still listening, God bless you.
That's all I can say.
So anyways,
I was able to do that and then
they have one of those, uh, those,
those pull up machines that you can,
you know,
be on your knees would like
the weight and all that stuff.
So I did like two or three of those and
now it's fucking hilarious cause I'm
kind of filling a weird feeling in my
other shoulder cause I think at this one
got worn out because of the other
one. And um, I think I'm finally,
I'm just going to go in and get
an Mri on both of my shoulders,
figuring out what the fuck's going on.
And then I might do a Rogan,
but Rogan's been telling me to do is go
fucking check out this guy that does the
stem cell thing and they just shoot it
in there and all of a sudden you're like
a fucking x Matt. I think
I might do that. You know,
I think I deserved that idea.
I didn't get the hair plugs right.
I'm not doing botox. I'm
aging naturally, you know,
I don't think is anything wrong with
rebuilding the engine and my fucking
shoulders. Oh Geez. My kids
screaming down. Um, but anyways,
I haven't been drinking,
I haven't really been smoking and uh,
I dunno, I'm actually calling a
fucking therapist today to find,
cause I've been saying on my stage of,
and working on my anger,
but I've been kind of doing it on my own
and I'm finally going to get some help
here. And uh, I've been doing this
joke in my act saying like, you know,
if I just didn't have a temper,
like
as far as like, you know, your
wife's always, you know, trying to,
we'll say in a nice way,
tries.
It's always trying to help
you become a better person.
Like I think if I got rid of my temper,
she would be out of suggestions.
Yeah.
Because other than my temper, I
mean, I'm fucking crushing it.
Do you understand that guys? Do
you understand that? I am a man.
Okay.
They can still afford to pay for DIRECTV.
900 channels,
350 of which are radio stations.
I don't even listen to those,
you know,
I'll fucking,
I'll pay for that direct TV subscription
and then I'll order a UFC fight and a
sports package. I'll give
a fuck. I'll fuck off.
I'll fucking stare right at $300 bill.
Pay It just like that.
I'm sorry I'm doing this.
I just was so shamed for still paying
for fucking cable and I didn't. I didn't,
I didn't know that yet. I'm going to
fucking doing this shit where I got.
Everything's like, I like it all
right there. Oh my fucking TV.
And I watched this on my laptop.
I watched this on my phone.
I got this thing on Mike. Mike fucking
pad bill. They're all the same technology.
You can watch them anywhere.
I don't want to figure,
I don't want to figure it out. You said
just fucking turn it on. And that was it.
Three fucking channels.
Boom.
Dodo. No. No.
Okay.
Ooh,
Ooh.
All right.
You knew all the fucking socks.
Making the way in your world today.
Who can turn though where
a dog with her smile.
Okay.
Who can take her Harry muff and warm
some cock up air bed. Minneapolis.
Well don't fuck it.
Lakers have left down the hallway.
Show laugh.
And Todd is Mary Tyler
Moore's pocket Pussy.
Sorry. Um, all right,
let's read some a three.
Some advertising. All right.
Oh look who's back everybody.
But at, at, at data all zip.
You know, hiring is a challenge,
but there's one place you can go.
We're hiring is simple.
Sometimes you want to go where
higher ed people, his book, boom,
boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
And it's fucking fast. Fasted,
smart. Bobo. Bobo.
You want to keep on fucking Busan
without anybody giving you shit.
You want to hae with more
alcohol. Liquor, sorry.
A place where growing businesses
connected to qualified candidates.
That place is zip.com/burr zipper
sends your job to over 100 of the web's
leading job boards.
They don't stop the APP with their
powerful matching technology exists.
Scans thousands of resumes to find people
with the right experience and invite
them to apply to your job.
As applications come in,
zip
analyzes each one and spotlight
spotlight's the top candidates.
So you never miss a great match.
Ziprecruiter is so effective that
80% of employers who post on day,
Eh,
uh, get a quality. That was my,
uh, my nod to motorcycle racing.
Yay.
Get a quality candidate through the site
within the first day and right now my
listeners can try ZipRecruiter for
free at this exclusive web address.
Zip recruiter.com/bird. That's
ziprecruiter.com/bar. Spell it out. Zip.
Okay.
Chari CR Uit r.com/burp ZipRecruiter
is the smartest way to hire.
All right, look it. I talked, talked
about them earlier and here they are.
stamps.com everybody sliding
in like Kramer on Seinfeld.
No one really has time to go to the
post office. You're busy. Who's got the,
you got to be a busy looking at all and
watching. Yeah, give your apps, you know,
check out fucking TV. RBU watching.
Who's got time for all that traffic.
Parking,
lugging all your mail and packages.
Let's get lugging male.
I mean, Jesus Christ.
How many fucking envelopes do you have?
It's a pain in the ass. We get it.
It's a real hassle,
man.
That's why you need stamps.com one of
the most popular timesaving tools for
small businesses, businesses, distances,
stamps.com eliminates trips to the
post office and saves you money with
discounts that you can get
even at the post office.
stamps.com brings all the amazing
services of the US Postal Service right to
your computer. Whether
you're a small office sending
invoices and online sellers,
shipping out products, or
even a warehouse, sending
thousands of packages a day.
stamps.com can handle it all with ease.
Simply use your computer to print official
US postage. 24 seven for any letter,
any package, any class of mail,
anywhere you want to send it.
Once your mail is ready,
just handed over to your mail carrier
or drop it in a mailbox mail carrier.
You got that? You see that that
was, that was Unisex. Now Mailman,
not mailwoman mail
carrier, person, carrier.
Why does it say male?
Um, it's that simple.
With stamps.com you get 5 cents off
every first class stamp and up to 40% off
priority mail.
Not to mention it's a fraction of the
cost of those expensive postage meters.
stamps.com is a no brainer,
saving you time and money.
It's no wonder over 700,000 small
businesses already use stamps.com not to
mention it's a fraction of the cost.
Oh, and I just went right back. Hey,
I just was checking the time
to see where I was at. Sorry,
I'm not losing my mind here.
Right now.
My listeners get a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus free
postage and a digital scale
without any longterm commitment.
Just go to stamps.com click on the
microphone at the top of the home page and
try and type in burpee. You are, are
that stamps.com enter [inaudible].
B. U. R. R. Okay, there we go. That was,
that was relatively painless,
right?
You know what I realized
halfway through this,
I need to let somebody know that I'm not
gonna be able to get to with the fuck
I'm supposed to be. Anyways,
we plow forward here. Okay.
Creepy Lennon Mannequin.
All right.
A couple of weeks ago,
I was in Liverpool and uh,
I went down to this, this
um, oh it says right here,
Magical Beatles Museum.
Okay. This, I actually,
and I was making fun of that fucking John
Lennon statue. If you miss the episode,
you can of literally the,
one of the first fucking things you
see and it's like the white suit like,
oh fuck,
is that the white suit?
Why would that be out here in the
open where anybody could just take it?
You Walk Up,
you realize it isn't the white suit.
You realize it doesn't look like
fucking John Lennon and all,
it's got this awful beard like taped
to the things face. I mean it just,
it just looks like a rip off.
I mean they might as well.
I had a fucking two headed goat
standing out there or something,
so I made fun of it. So
anyways, it says high belt.
I work at the Magical Beatles
Museum and parentheses.
I like most of the staff agree with you.
The mannequin should be thrown
in the river. Mercy. Mercy. Okay.
The guys from cheap trick found
it weird as well. All right,
so that's a major fucking band with I
believe that bands in the rock and roll
hall of fame and they are looking
at it like, dude, what the fuck? Um,
it's unfortunate.
You and your pal decided not to come
in as the mannequin certainly does not
represent what is inside the museum is
on three floors in is filled with 300 and
counting genuine Beatles
artifacts from 1959 to 1970.
See now this is making
me wish I went in there.
You got to get rid of that
fucking mannequin. Uh,
these include the metals John Lennon
wore on the sergeant pepper cover. Wow.
George Harrison's future Rama Guitar.
I didn't know what that is.
The spotlights from Abbey Road Studios,
Ringo Star's snared rump,
Jesus seeds from Shea Stadium and the
cello from the blue Jay way video,
et Cetera, et Cetera, et
cetera. The owner of the museum,
also the guy responsible
for the creepy mannequin is
okay.
Rogue Aspinall Lee best.
I didn't, couldn't tell if that was an
affliction or a name. It's a name. Okay.
He is the son of Neil Aspinall Beatles
roadie and head of apple records.
He's also brother of Pete best original
Beatles Drummer. And as a great guy,
next time you were in Liverpool comment
and we'll give you and your pals slash
family of free toward all the best.
They'll fuck that dude. I'm going to pay.
I'm gonna pay.
Although I would ask them,
it does peak get upset that he started
a fucking museum to the band that fired
him, fired his brother. He's
gotta be kind of weird. Right.
Um, I don't know. I'm sure. I'm sure Pete
best is over it at this point. Right?
I have. Oh, is there any
other, you know, that's another
thing too, you know, on, on,
on Twitter. I'm an old man. I'm still on
Twitter. Right? I'm still on the Twitter.
Some they had this, this hashtag
going around that said, um, um,
not popular opinions. And people would
say like, you know, I don't know,
pick somebody like a, I don't think
at Dell has a good voice, you know,
stupid shit. Like nobody said that
by the way. Um, I'm just happy.
I know how to say her name. I was calling
her Adelai for a long fucking time. Um,
but somebody wrote that the Beatles
are overrated. That's another one.
That's a big one.
When millennials one of appear edgy,
they go, they're overrated.
Oh, are they? Okay. Okay.
Well maybe if you read up on the
history at some fucking point.
Hachi second a phone call.
Hang on a second. All right,
here's the thing about that.
I understand if the Beatles,
you're young and the Beatles music
doesn't move you because I mean,
it's music from literally 50
fucking years ago at this point.
That's the end of their career to,
and then the other stuff is
coming up on 60 years. Okay.
So in defense of you guys,
I understand that, uh,
if you don't like it or it does it, but
they're not overrated. I mean, they just,
they influenced an entire generation
okay.
Of, of bands to get started. They
made the whole fucking thing possible.
And because of them,
you're listening to the music
that you're listening to today.
They are an undeniable
part of music history. But,
um, I would never, you know, be
this old guy going like, you know,
if you told me that music sucks, I'm not
going to argue that. That's just like,
I mean,
if I fucking grew up now,
I would like some of their songs
even I remember in the 80s,
like liking them and my teacher being
like, going like, dude, you don't get it.
You don't get how fucking huge it
was when a Beatles album came out.
It's like they'll,
they'll,
they'll fucking world stopped
for younger people then,
and you bought it and people do it.
I got to new Beatles album.
Everybody came over and fucking
listen to it. It, I, I mean,
I wasn't even part of that,
so, um, but as far as like, uh,
like first he always suffers.
He hates the Beatles and he's just
like yellow submarine, Bill Yellow.
So it was like, dude, everybody's got
a bad fucking joke in the rack. C'Mon.
Okay.
Um, anyways, you know, first I, you know,
whatever I, it's, I, I get it. I get
it. It's, it's too much time has passed.
I've heard,
I've heard younger comics talk about
some big comics that way and not get like
what the big deal is, but what
happens is, is the further,
okay,
like,
let's look at Beethoven.
Can you fucking imagine when
that Shit first came out?
Like it just keep fucking sitting there.
You got a goddamn boil the size of my
foot on the side of your fucking head.
You'll fighting off typhoid for yellow
feet, whatever the fuck God damn plague.
And also this guy just shows up with
100 of his friends I yet. Uh, but like,
dude, what the fuck? You know?
And now you're just sitting there eating
a subway sandwich in an elevator and in
the background is gone.
But other, the, it just,
it just doesn't have the
same fucking kick impact. Um,
but that doesn't mean the dude's
overrated does it? I don't fucking know.
MMM.
Okay.
Anyways, moving ahead here, or if you look
at you, if you look at what is the salt,
you've watched soul train,
do you watch some of the people
dancing from way fucking back then?
There's a lot of them that I,
compared to today's standards,
I'm not talking about the legendary
dancers, just people on the dance floor.
I just, when I watched, cause Nia loves
that show and I'll be just watching,
I just laugh going like,
you know,
there's a lot of people on this show
that are dancing at a level that awful
white people dance that today,
like the barges keeps getting raised
off of the work. So if you go back,
the hardest thing to do when you go
back in history is to block out what has
happened since then and try to put
it into historical perspective,
which is practically impossible.
Um,
it's like going back and
looking at Johnny Unitas,
how he threw for over 40,000 yards in
his career and like the next closest guy
had half as much as that. But now I
like the way the rules have changed.
Like a fucking Goddamn backup quarterback
will throw for 30,000 in his career.
So it doesn't seem like a
big deal. Um, so I dunno,
I'm just defending the beetle sets all
and now I feel bad that I trashed his
fucking museum and I judged
it by that goddamn mannequin.
I think the whole purpose,
all that was me just realizing
that I'm a bit of a cunt.
He's a bit of a con there.
He is a, he's a bit of a con.
Um, alright. Cheesy cheesing babies,
a dear Billy badge.
Have you seen these pussies throwing
cheese onto their kids' faces?
I saw one of them.
It's just the fucking desperation
for people to get views.
Um, on the Internet to the
appointment. Look, I'm a performer. I,
I have a desperation for it.
I get it on some level,
but when you start like the amount of
videos I just see of like parents with
like their kids,
right?
And they're starting to fall and they
don't do anything and they just film it so
they can laugh and they just like
let their kid get hurt is, you know,
the real ones like you can tell it wasn't
set up is cause right as a kid starts
to fall like that,
you see the fucking phone flies out
of frame and you actually miss the kid
falling down. You, she can tell the parent
lunged and tried to save the person.
But um, yeah, I don't get it anyway.
It's like how much the person said,
uh,
how much do you hate yourself that
you'd throw cheese on a baby's face?
Just imagine what type of
memory is sublimely stored
where a baby sees a camera
and then something hit their face.
I'd arrest all these asshole parents
and throw firehose water in the,
at their faces. Um, yeah. I mean,
I don't know if it does like
psychological damage to the baby.
If you can even fucking remember it.
Like someday it's going to be
in Philly and they're like, hey,
you want to get a cheese
steak? It's like, hey,
Jason fucking starts slamming
the sandwich into its face.
Um,
I don't know that it does that.
There is just the thing
where when you are,
you become a parent just sounded
like defenseless and helpless.
You kid is um,
look not advocating being a helicopter
parent, I'm not saying that,
but there's just something
about filming it like cause it,
it's,
the kid obviously doesn't
enjoy it obviously startles
the kid and the fact that
you're putting your own fucking
adult needs ahead of that. I mean I,
I all of that,
that whole category is giving your kid a
stupid fucking name like coat hanger or
some dumps, Hollywood celebrity
fucking name or, or, or
putting your fucking political agenda
like your kid is going to live your
political agenda.
I'm raising my kid gender neutral and
then all of a sudden your kid asks you,
your son has to wear a fucking dress
just so you can show off how fucking
progressive you are rather than asking
the kid if he just wants a football
instead. You know what I mean? Like
you're going to make that decision.
I think all of that stuff is,
um,
I dunno what the, I'm not a psychologist.
I just, it's not how I would do it,
you know, I think he should,
if your kid starts to fall,
you should try to catch your kid.
I think if this cheese,
you should hand it to your child. If
your kid wants to eat it, they eat it.
If they don't, then you finish it and
gain a few more pounds, like a dead.
Right.
Um,
I dunno. And I, I also,
I also just like if your kid fucks up
and then you put it on the Internet,
it's just like, it, it exists
forever and kids are already made.
You're literally giving
like, um, ammunition.
Like somebody showed me this video,
this woman or a kid was being a class
clown and dancing at school and she gave
him the option. She says, I'm either going
to give you the belt or you can dance.
So the kid is crying cause he's scared
and he's sitting there and doing this
half ass like dancing while he's
crying and everybody thinks it's funny.
It's like this fucking
kid has to go to school.
Not to mention you should
have hit a kid with a belt.
There's like so many fucking
things that are wrong with it.
MMM.
I Dunno. So yeah, I don't, I don't like,
and I think you know, your instincts
that you're that mad that you, you,
I could feel the anger that
you have towards it. Yeah.
Like you shouldn't do that.
I imagine with your level of anger,
like some shit was done to you,
um, as was done to me and I
think he'd go one of two ways.
You either repeated slash tried to take
it to the next level or you just go back
to like, oh, I remember what that felt
like. I, yeah, I'm not doing that.
Why would I do that? Uh, but you know,
there's a lot of morons that, um,
you know, you don't have to be smart
to know how to fuck. That's the thing.
If they just made it like something
like, uh, like if it was as difficult is,
is getting like a degree in something,
I think the world would be a better place.
But anyway, it can be like
goodbye Dick, stand it up.
But I want to just stick it in their diet.
Next scene or you a fucking kid and
you're throwing cheese at it and you're
filming it.
MMM,
I dunno. I it's, I
wouldn't do it. We'll see.
We'll see what the fallout is,
but my kid's not going to be part of
that fucking experiment. All right.
Premiere league soccer.
Soccer is in quotes.
So I'm imagining this is a fucking
somebody who doesn't live in the u s uh,
hey Billy Ball breaker.
I've been listening for a long
time and really enjoy your podcast,
especially during football season as
I find your analysis is put more in
layman's terms for us Brits
being a fellow Patriot Fan.
Nice here also gets me shit as
most people follow the Seahawks.
Well isn't that interesting?
Yeah.
If you don't mind right back and let me
know why did they follow the Seahawks.
Okay.
And is it,
cause it's always cloudy over there and
they had the same kind of weather in
Britain as they do in Seattle.
That's really interesting. Um,
I've enjoyed your recent ramblings.
About the premier league and Liverpool's
battle with Manchester this year.
So I thought I'd share a few facts you
may enjoy and help you understand more.
Uh, Liverpool were actually the more
successful team in history with 18 league
titles. Oh yeah, I heard about this.
This is like before the
Premiere League existed.
It's almost like pre Superbowl error.
They had five Europe Aka,
so 80 league titles,
five European titles and a bunch of other
cups until recently when their biggest
rivals,
Manchester United overtook them and
have 20 titles but only three European
titles.
So that's basically the Celtics and
Lakers of a premier league football.
Um,
given your gripe about the Steelers,
I thought you'd be interested to know
that all 18 of Liverpool's titles were
before the Premiere League error,
but are still very much counted here
as it should be. Yes, it should. Uh,
their Wikipedia page is very interesting
as they have also faced tragedies along
with other clubs and
still cake out on top.
Never heard that expression unless
you, that's a typo. Secondly, uh,
match man city are only recently
a good team as 10 years ago.
They were about,
they were,
I think you missed a word
here as 10 years ago,
they were about over by Arab,
I think they were bought out his what?
He wanted Arab billionaires
and it basically play paid
extraordinary amounts of
money for the best players and are still
not quite good enough to win all the
cops. See this is, this is
what you need to get into it.
It's already a beautiful game and now
I need is the backstory and the drama.
So I think that's really
interesting that man city,
all of a sudden they have all this money.
Um,
which who gives a fuck,
cause you know,
before then everyone was probably going
to man United or Liverpool if they
wanted to win a title. Now, hey,
they come out of nowhere. I like it.
It's good. You know, you guys
all got money. The Boston
Red Sox on the Liverpool,
God knows they got fucking more money
than God. Um, what about man United?
Did they get a bunch of money?
But that legacy,
I feel like they need to do something.
So are all of a sudden it starts to
fade a little bit like the Michigan
Wolverines. Like thank God they got
a, what's his face there? Captain,
come back to save the any
debts even though he hasn't
beaten no house state yet.
Uh, Harbaugh saved that fucking program
because you can only be bad for so long.
We're all of us. If you suck for
kids, uh, recruits entire life,
they don't give a shit that becomes
beetle ever. Stuff like, yeah, whatever,
that's yellow submarine football.
I don't give a fuck about it.
And they're going to end up in like
Oregon came out of nowhere cause all of a
sudden they started having these cool
uniforms and started winning games. Um,
Abbott. Don a total tangent here.
So let's see. Here we go. Thirdly,
going on what you said about the offsides
rule and the defending player slowing
down, they can do this, but if the
attacking player is behind them,
when the ball is played,
they are still on side and can
score. Wait, how does that work?
The attacking player is behind them.
When the ball is played,
what does that mean?
He ran past him with the ball.
He can't go past the last
defender without the ball. Right.
So the attacker must time they're run
with the are other players making the pass
and the defending players must do the
same but also be aware that if they get,
oh I see what you're saying.
So like if he's like parallel
to um,
or is it perpendicular?
If he's parallel to the defenseman
and somebody kicks the ball past the
Defenseman,
he can take off as the ball's
kicked and then he won't,
he'll still be on site. I get that.
All right. That's a little more, uh,
okay. I guess. So it's sort of
like a moving blue line I guess.
I really appreciate you taking the
time to explain this to me though. Um,
so let me read that again. Slowly when
the ball is played, that means kicked,
I guess then they are still
on the outside kids score.
So the a two, wait, wait,
where the fuck with thirdly going on
what you said about the offsides rule and
the defending players slowing down.
They can do this but if the attacking
player is behind them when the ball is
played, meaning kicked, then they
are still on site and can score.
So the attacker must time they're run.
Okay
with their other player.
I liked that there's a finesse to that.
I have to respect making the past.
Oh do you have to respect it?
You fucking arrogant con whatever.
I'm trying to be nicer and the defending
players must do the same but also be
aware that if they get
okay,
if they get wrong they have
to chase back and stop the,
there are also other factors such as the
other player isn't involved in the play.
He is an offside and can stand anywhere.
All right. Apologies for the length.
Nah Man, you actually cleared
it up a little bit more.
It's still don't think I 100% understand
it cause I don't know how far away you
have to be from the play and stay
and you can still be on side. Uh,
hope you found this interesting and
please do a show and either Belfast or
Dublin so I can go. Thanks and go fuck
yourself. I was out in Dublin last June.
I haven't been a Belfast in,
in a little bit, but, um,
I have to tell you how excited the two
tours I've done this year through Europe
if been incredible.
And um,
I got one more that starts in
Iceland at the end of April and um,
uh, it's, I don't know, it's just
incredible the people showing up,
the venues I get to play too. Um, yeah,
I dunno,
I'm still kind of a blown away by that,
so I'm looking forward to it and I
still have not been down to Australia.
I keep saying if something always ends
up coming up, I've got some acting work.
I had to push some dates, but, um,
after I do my next year
up on the next one, I do,
I have to go back to Australia because I
haven't been there in a couple of years.
Um,
all right.
And now I just take the specialist and
I got to build a fucking hour back up
again and I can't go over there when
it's weak. I got to make sure, you know,
cause those are these fucking people
don't screw around it. Right. Um,
so I gotta make sure it's where it needs
to be, but I will figure all of this up.
All right. Um, all right.
By Nuria all beats,
B I n. U. A R a. L. Beats dear bill,
have you heard of binary aisle beets?
They're a great alternative to silent
meditation and have the same benefits.
All you need is a nice pair of
headphones and Youtube on your phone.
Just wanted to let you know because
I'm also an angry cunt sometimes.
Um,
I found these and they really
help with every negative emotion.
They are even a few. There are even a
few that apparently help with migraines.
Check them out. Thanks for the laughs.
Is this a real thing? Is this a thing?
Let me see. Here we go. Let me
right. Let me, let me, let me,
let me look this up here.
B.
I n a r a l for the people
looking at it up to beats.
All right. Um, all right.
This is for meditation. This is
three hours and 15 minutes. Let's go.
We'll little listen to
a little bit of this.
A vegetarian. It's LV. Lily. Eat
French fries all day. Here we go.
Here is some binaural beats.
Sounds like a horror movie.
No.
All right. You know, I can get it to that.
Start off a little scanners started off
alumni going lie to you. I was a little,
uh, e Oh. Speaking is
scary movies. Did you, ah,
did you see Jordan peals the
trailer for his new movie?
That movie looks so scary.
I'm almost angry at him because I've got,
I'm going to go see it. I saw that and he
was like, oh my God. And I was like, dude,
fuck that movie. Fuck that. I'm
going to go see it. But Jesus Christ.
Oh my God, I fucking hate scary
movies, but I love Jordan,
so I'm going to go see that movie. And I
also love, this is the last one he did.
So,
but like this one looks like it's
just full on fucking horror and uh,
I don't need that, but you know,
I'm going to go see it. Alright.
Boyfriend's family is
silent during dinner.
We should go see me in d and then we'll
come on the podcast and talk about it.
She'll be like, oh my God, I love that.
I love being scared and I'll be fucking
pissed that I went through that shit.
You know, I told you when I saw
it, when I saw the Blair witch,
I had a set at the laugh
factory and I went to the move,
like the midnight showing by myself, and
then I walked down to the parking garage
by myself to the car. Just totally
freaked off. Like Josh, Josh.
I know I, I'm not one of those people
that can just sit there and be like,
this is the movie I fucking buy in and
it's scares the shit out of me. Um,
all right. Boyfriend's family
is silent during dinner.
Yeah.
Okay. Let's see. What do we
do with this one? Dear Bill?
I need some advice about a guy
I've been seeing who is great,
but his family are kind of strange.
They are lovely and quite nice,
but they are incredibly awkward
when together as a family.
It's not that they say or do weird things,
it's that we basically sit in
the silence when we're together.
When I first met him, when I
first met them, Jesus Christ,
I feel like I should be playing
that and meditation. Music.
Well I fucking [inaudible]
cause I read this. Um,
there's nobody there stirring coffee
slowly or they are a tea, whatever it was.
Now when I first met them,
I thought that they must have just came
from a funeral because we went out for
lunch and it was eerily silent. I was
trying to be nice and ask a few question,
but I was just getting one word answers.
I asked my boyfriend about this and he
had no idea what I was talking about.
Even started to get a bit defensive. Oh,
all right, well there you go. That's,
that's just how they are.
Um,
we'd been dating about six months and I
dread seeing that because it feels like
I'm being tortured and
an under of speaking.
Okay.
My boyfriend is completely oblivious
to it and love seeing his family,
which is crazy weird because I would say
he is reasonably outgoing and fun when
we go out with a group of friends. Yeah.
That is where it's really fucking weird.
Should I stop seeing him or do you think,
okay,
uh, he missed a word you'd think would
be some good techniques for dealing with
them. Please give me some advice. A,
you're single, you're not married,
so this is all about you.
All right.
You, you just have to,
you have to figure out,
do I love this guy you haven't
even said you loved them.
Am I into this person enough to put
up with this? Like these people,
you have a kid with this guy.
These fucking non talking motherfuckers
are coming over to your house.
All right.
It seems like you're early on.
We like,
should I stop seeing this
guy or should maybe a,
okay.
It all depends on how
much she liked the guy.
MMM.
That's so,
it's so weird that it's not weird that
they're like that and it's not weird that
he's oblivious because,
you know,
your family just seems like your
family you grew up, but the fact
that
he loves seeing them,
that's what's weird to me.
Like if they just like a not close,
cold family that barely talks,
like that's usually would mean that,
you know, I see once every year,
year and a half, I come around during
the holidays and then that's it.
But the fact that he goes there all
the time to sit there and then not say
anything to them.
Okay.
MMM.
I Dunno. It starts making me wonder if
they're like fucking aliens or something.
They're communicating through the center
of their foreheads or some shit. Um,
yeah, that's definitely strange. Uh,
okay.
And the fact that you're so uncomfortable
that now you're thinking maybe there's
some good techniques that you're going
to go in there and Dr Phil and fix the
whole fucking family and one
segment. It's not gonna happen. Um,
so I think you need to,
uh,
you got to make a tough choice there.
All right.
Neither let this Greg guy go and
try to find another great guy.
He sound like he's still young. He's still
drafted in the first couple of rounds,
so there's plenty of good talent left out
there and maybe you could have more of
a normal family,
but that is a or,
yeah,
you just learn to deal with their
creepy horror show fucking vibe.
But,
um,
I don't know what good techniques
you're going to use to fix that.
Especially when you brought it up to him.
He had no idea what you were talking
about and was like defensive about it. So,
so there is that. Um, anyways,
okay.
I'm going to try that. That fucking horror
music chanting shit. Sorry. You your,
ah, I think I would actually
like this better than
I have a meditation app and it's just
this and this guy just keeps talking
throughout being like hello again and
welcome to another beautiful day with an
opportunity to clear your mind.
Okay.
Meditate.
I'd like you to find a comfortable chair
and just sit in it,
feel the chair
up against your body.
Are there places that it's
okay
touching you too much
or does it feel just right?
I'm
fucking that shit and it's just like,
oh my God, dude, just shut the fuck up.
All right. Just tell me to breathe
and that just shut up please.
For the love of God shut up.
So I think I would rather,
rather than listen to that guy,
I'd rather listen to this shit.
Josh.
I don't mean to end this so fucking
in such a creepy goddamn way. Um,
maybe I need to listen to this
shit so I can go see Jordan teals,
new fucking movie and not be overly
freaked out and traumatized by it.
Um, how great is it that
that guy's making movies is,
it's every once in a while somebody
fucking like that comes along.
It's just awesome. It's awesome. If
you love movies, it's fucking awesome.
All right. That is the, uh, that is
the podcast, ladies and gentlemen.
I'll check it on. Yeah, on
Thursday. Go broads, go Celtics.
Um, if anybody knows how, if I can
watch a replay of the moto GP race,
I would love to watch it. Um,
send it to my Twitter account.
Please let me know. I would love
to see it. All right. That's it.
Go fuck yourselves and
I'll see you on Thursday.