Hey,
what's going on is bill burn is time for
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
March 25th,
2018 what's going on? How are you? Oh,
stop it.
Yeah.
Everything's gonna be
fine. Okay. Shake it off.
What'd you think?
Bad stuff was only going to happen.
Other people every once in a while comes
to your neighborhood. Shake it off.
Put a smile on your mother fucker.
Um,
anyways, uh oh. Did I
wake up mad this morning?
What a surprise.
What are unique emotion from the freckled
country you've come to know and love?
Yeah.
Um, by the way, you know,
and now that I went through all of that
bullshit to get on fucking Instagram,
the fact that you have to follow
9,000 fucking people or you,
you get to say you're just staring
at the same photo every fucking day.
And it's just really like a,
it's like a maze.
Okay.
You know, you're on Twitter,
you just fucking on Twitter now.
You still have to follow people, I
guess. Now I got to fucking go on.
I got to fucking follow
all these fucking gay,
get on the edge of my wife's telling me,
get on here.
We just follow all your friends
and some speaking things.
You're interested so I can just
be another mouth breathing dope.
Staring at my fucking phone. I already,
I already stare at it too much.
Um,
you know,
I thought I was going to get on Instagram
and all it's going to see his ass and
titties and I just not seeing it.
Right.
It's probably cause I only follow Dean
del Ray and Joe Rogan. So what I see is,
uh,
what did I see?
I saw Joe Rogan walking around holding
a chicken with another 40 chickens
following him. All right? All
these years I've known Joe Rogan.
I had no idea that he owned chickens.
Okay.
You know, this is causing me to
reevaluate our entire friendship. I mean,
I don't know why he would
keep that from me. Does he?
Does he think he can't trust
me with that information?
That these are the kinds of things
I'm going to ask him the next time.
I think I've had them on here.
Yeah.
I don't fucking know. Anyways. And,
and, and Dean del Ray's in New York,
that's what I know.
That's all I know.
No horse, no inspirational
workout videos. You know,
where some guys trying to
inspire you to work out,
but he's really just wanting
to take his shirt off.
You know what's funny about those fucking
Instagram people is beyond the fact
that they're doing that show,
the inspirational celebrity would,
they're just every day,
you know,
acting like they have life all figured
out and now they're going to patch these
gems on to you. Hey, next
time you're thinking outward,
look inward to find the real so your
truth can be even fucking sent to the
stratosphere and shut the fuck up.
Yeah.
And the other one I love,
I love the celebrity fucking standing
outside his private jet with this serious
look on his face. How about
a smile? You fucking cunt
standing there, yo. This is how we do.
Yeah.
This is my Louis Vuitton luggage.
What a fucking moron.
Gotta asshole buys $5,000 fucking pieces
of luggage so some asshole can throw it
in the bottom of a fucking United
flight. You know? I don't know.
You'd have to fly private for the rest
of your life and watch your luggage just
go easy,
easy,
or you could just get a fucking bag
that's designed to get the shit kicked out
of it. You can keep all your
fucking jewels inside of it.
Okay.
Oh my God.
If I see one more,
can't do the photo shoot with all
their cars and then there's the fucking
private jet in the background. What?
What does, what is that? You know?
Just to fuck fucking just put it under.
I'm rubbing it in your face
that I have more money than you.
Don't fucking do that thing where I'm
trying to inspire you to get to my level.
Okay.
Do you realize everything that
has to be involved? They're like,
you have to fucking call
up the fucking airport.
Some poor bastard has to do that.
You have your cars.
It's not enough that you have your cars.
It's not enough that
you're flying private.
It's not enough that your luggage costs
more than what a lot of people make to
fucking teach kids in public schools.
You have to have all of that. I mean,
how many fucking drivers do you need
to get all your fucking cars out there?
Did you got to figure out what
fucking outfit you're gonna wear?
I don't know. Anyways, plowing ahead,
but that is the kind of shit that I want
to see are actually kind of have this
thing going on with,
with friends of mine.
Well we just send each other
all of those like photos.
Yeah.
You know that poor kid who died
there, the, the humble Brag Guy,
he would've had a fucking
field day on Instagram. Okay.
Jesus Christ. I mean, that's
why I kind of went on there.
I just didn't realize it was going to
be that much work to try and find all of
those fucking photos because people would
just send me them all the time and I
was like, Jesus Christ, I really
missing out not being on Instagram.
And then you get on there.
And I,
I've followed Dean del Ray and Joe Rogan
and my beautiful wife, and that's it.
And Rogan and deed, Delray, or normal
grounded human being. So it's just
tell me who to follow.
Okay.
I do enough fucking promotional
as other ones. I just want to see,
I want to see that.
That's the Shit I want to see.
I want to see people that
are pretending to inspire me,
but they're really just fucking,
you know,
they want to show me how much money they
have or how great is shaped they're in.
Um, I mean, why can't everybody
be down to Earth like me?
I'm sorry, I'm just a self involved.
I'm just not as motivated in the gym.
Plus you, it's fun. Even if I got
shredded, I mean, if I took my shirt off,
all people would say is like, dude,
fucking white. You are. Oh my God.
I'd be, what about my
boulevard, my Apac, abs?
Nobody cares. Um, all right,
so let's get to my week here.
I went and I saw ministry live
for the first time. I saw them,
uh, down at the, uh,
the fuck is it going at the
house of Blues in Anaheim.
And I was meeting some friends
down there and they're like, oh,
we're at the fuck and we're at the Ramada
and my guy, so I fuck, we're at the bar.
So I walk into the Ramada, go to
the fucking bar there. They, uh,
there's nobody there.
It turns out I'm at the Ron Romano who
knew there was more than one role model,
whatever the fuck it was, wherever
the hell that was gone. So anyways,
we ended up going over to the, uh, to
the show. It was just, it was awesome.
Live music was and
always will be the shit.
And I got to see them, uh,
basically played the entire album.
There are new album
America can't KKK aunt,
um,
an Al Jourgensen as always,
just fucking crushing it. Fucking
crushing it, man. You know,
there's front men and then there's
front men still has the passion.
Okay.
Silky. You know, got the fucking crowd
going. You're looking around, you know,
a lot of people like my age by that,
like the fucking fourth song,
there was a mosh pit.
I stayed clear of it.
I definitely stay clear of it,
but they got a bunch of, uh,
I think they're on like a 25 city
tour right now. And they write,
they did a Anaheim and then Oxnard,
I don't know where they're off to now.
When you promote a couple
of their dates here,
considering such a fucking awesome show.
Here we go.
Am I man,
this story toward dates?
He at that data that,
that,
come on, man. Why is my
Internet so fucking slow?
Yeah.
It'd be funny if they actually had it
run at the same speed as your intellect.
Okay.
And you couldn't get mad
anymore. It's like, well,
it's because I'm a fucking
asshole. I'm dumb. All right.
They're going to be in Sacramento
at the ace of spades. Portland,
the Roseland theater. Oh, that's
a beauty. That's on Wednesday.
Thursday they're gonna be in
Vancouver at the vogue theater.
Saturday. They're going to
be an Edmonton. All right.
And then when they go into end to April,
they get a B in uh,
Montana, Nebraska, Chicago, Illinois.
A couple of nights there.
Cincinnati, grand rapids,
Michigan, Indianapolis, Toronto,
Moria when they're playing great
places. BOSTON, April 17th,
um, couple of nights there. Portland,
Maine, Jesus, they'd go on everywhere.
He got to catch him and
the dude runs through
the fuck is it runs through the end of
April as far as what they have here. Um,
all right,
back to the podcast here.
So old freckles forgot that it was formula
one season and unfortunately somebody
on Twitter said, hey, are you excited
for this weekend? I was like, Oh shit.
That's right.
And because it's now not on NBC sports,
the ESPN cons took it over and God
knows they'll fuck it up somehow.
That's what I thought they were
going to do. I've got to admit,
I watched what I got out of the race.
I thought they did a good job,
although I don't understand why we'll
Buxton isn't there now they have like this
comedy team or some shit.
They got two people down there who
then throw it over to another guy.
You think ESPN would try to save money
and not fucking hire
three people for the job.
That one guy was doing outstandingly
since I've been watching, but a,
I don't run the shit. So
anyways, I fucking go on in my,
my cable box and I go to record the
race and I don't know what happened.
All I recorded was the pregame,
which ended up getting me like
the first 10 laps of the race.
So I missed the fucking race. Uh, but
then I went on and I read all about it.
First thing that I noticed was the new,
the uh, Jesus Christ. I'm stuttering here,
the new design of the uh,
the cop pain. I'm like,
what the fuck is that thing that's
like in the driver's line of sight.
And they got this new halo thing
that they got going on. Um,
I guess for a years since like 2010 or 11,
they've been trying to figure out,
you know, cause it's the open
cockpit, people smashing into walls,
tires and bolts go fly in. These
guys are driving, you know,
upwards of 100 fucking 80 miles an hour.
If you get hit with a screw, you know,
could go right through your helmet,
India fucking head. I don't know.
They've been trying to figure out
how to protect them, you know,
and then all everybody in the
crowd's like, well, hey man,
don't put in like make it look like
a fighter jet man. We were like,
it's just always been open cockpit.
So everybody in the crowd,
you know, they want to
see, it's like, listen,
if we're going to sit here along this
fucking fence and at any point a washer
can come flying off the car,
go through my eye socket and into
the back of my brain. I mean,
at least you could do is with your
fucking Alamut drive around in an open
cockpit.
So they decided
to come up with this new design.
Uh, the halo cockpit picked design,
which is supposed to, uh, it looks
like a giant piece of plastic to me.
It's probably made out of carbon fiber.
Um,
but evidently that will stop a tire
for smashing you in the fucking head.
And killing you. Nobody wants that,
right? I don't think so. So anyways,
I saw at the beginning of
the race and as always,
Lewis Hamilton got the pole position,
it help
and uh,
the race starts and he gets
to the first corner first.
So obviously he's going to win the
fucking race. That's how it works.
And even one of the announcers
stupidly said, well, you know,
it history has shown that whoever wins
the first race of the year usually goes
on to win the championship.
That,
I don't know if that was a comment on
how much lack of fucking passing there is
or the fact that basically Mercedes and
Ferrari have such superior engines that
you don't, nobody else can
compete with them. You know?
I mean,
I know other teams,
like the American team
Haas has Ferrari engines,
but that's like their shit one.
Like they get the z 28 engine,
we get the fucking rally sport,
um,
just for white trash people from the 70s.
Um,
so anyways, uh, I guess what happened?
Sebastian Vettel one,
the uh,
on the Australian Grand Prix for Ferrari
who went back to the Ferrari red or I
guess less white in their car.
The car is definitely look different,
look like at different color red.
And I was like,
there's no way that there's like a
specific read the Ferrari has to be,
but it turns out they just had less
white in the car this year. Uh,
they went on to win it because,
um,
the Mercedes team I guess fucked up where,
uh,
Lewis Hamilton went into Pitt.
They thought they had enough space
between the fucking second place in first
place. He was going to get out of
the pit first or something like that.
I don't know what, oh no, he was out
on the track. I just saw the highlight.
I don't fucking know. And they screwed
up, but you know, it's fucked up.
They blamed their software.
So it's just like,
is there any sort of like,
I dunno,
racing going on.
So they've got some computers looking
where the fucking Sebastian Vettel's car
is in the pit and wow. How fast
they have to be going. What tar?
The off the computer figures,
all of that out.
You got an APP and every now lily the APP,
shit the bed.
And uh, that'll got out
first. And you know, Hamilton,
he's always fucking sell cause it was, it
was a nickel. Who's, are you all right?
I love Hamilton, but he
gets so fucking, he, oh,
he just starts bleeding and
whenever he fucking lose, um,
I remember last year something happened
and qualifying and then he just sat in
his car for like fucking
mean when,
when you were a kid and he got
mad at your parents or whatever,
and they got out of the car, went in the
house, you're trying to make a point.
You just sat in the car in the driveway.
They didn't give a shit to like, great.
How's, he'll be quiet without your
fucking complainant acid in here. Um,
so he ended up winning Ferrari
one. Sebastian Vettel came
in first, uh, a sulking.
Lewis Hamilton came in second, Kimi
Reagan, and he didn't drive anybody off.
The track came in third. And, uh,
Ricky Ricardo, Daniel Ricardo came in,
uh,
the hometown favorite came in in
fourth place and what's his face fell.
Terry Bolt. Haas, I guess he crashed,
you're in qualifying and then was
given us five spot penalty for uh,
cause he changed a gearbox.
He started in 15th and then
ended up finishing eighth.
But I think the real big story was how
well the USA team with the sh the sh the
fucking Ferrari engine, that Ferrari
throughout in their back dumpster,
um, was fucking killing it
in the beginning. We will,
I can fourth and sixth place at one point,
a part of the only part of the race that
I saw. And then, uh, I got all excited,
you know,
to look up to see where we finished.
We finished 19th and 20th with two,
not one,
but did not finish,
I guess.
Evidently
we know how to take the tire off,
but we don't know how to put it back on.
Okay.
Twice in the same race.
One of the hottest cars went in.
Okay.
To get their tire change their way.
They put the fuck guitars back on.
Three out of four were on but one wasn't.
They did that the first time and then the
fucking mechanic was screwed it up was
hilarious.
They cut to the cut to the uh,
the pit team and he just
walked out of the camera shop.
I think he went into the bathroom and
close the door and probably throw up that
he cost his team one of the cars,
you know, and then the fucking,
then they turned around and
they did it again. But uh,
they're keeping their chin up
there saying, you know what?
Well Ah, you know, if uh,
you know, just stick. What
would have happened if we
actually put the bolts back?
God,
I'll tell you if Rorem Mercedes better
look out because we're going to be
practicing how to take a tire on
and off when we get that down.
I'm telling you things are going to be
real shook up and the a fourth to six
positions this year. Yeah. Boy,
you know what it is. We're Americans.
We don't give a shit. Okay cause this,
this whole fucking Duh left
turns and right turns the eye.
We have land over here,
fucking assholes in Europe and
everywhere else around the world.
You're all fucking over populated,
driving around,
fucking gone an old cow
paths. Um, that's all I got.
What else can I do? What do you
do when you completely screw up?
You know what you do?
You make fun of the rest of the world.
Okay.
It's exactly what you do.
All right,
let's get into some happier American
news to Bruins. Once again, were down.
They were down two to nothing
to the Goddamn Dallas Stars.
So down in fucking Dallas now they
used to be the Minnesota north stars.
Okay.
And it was an eclectic group of incredibly
normal looking people in the crowd.
Okay. And, and the Minnesota
people. Nice people.
The kind of people you say hello to,
or if you Philly fans,
you throw full beers at.
Right.
Then they moved down to fucking Dallas.
Okay.
The fake teddy capital of the world.
All right.
You know,
you know silicone valley out there where
they do all the fucking computer shit.
You know,
an Apple's big fucking all look at our
round building with the forest in the
middle of it.
Um,
that's where all the computer shit
happens down in Hollywood's where all the
movies get made out in
Arizona is where they,
they don't want to celebrate Martin Luther
King Day New Mexico's where they shop
breaking bad. And then you get
out to Dallas, Texas. Okay.
And you basically you have Dealey
plaza and you have fake titties that is
fucking Dallas.
And then you have a bunch of shiny four
door pickup trucks that has never seen a
day of blue collar work driving
around out there. I don't know why.
I don't know why you think and
they get them Cadillac. Um,
everybody's acting like they
got a ranch. Um, anyways,
we went down,
then we played them and we were down two
to nothing and we score three goals and
the third fucking period it was just,
and of course I missed the game
cause I got the kid now I was at,
I was at a birthday party,
a great birthday party.
We're now to a fucking farm and
all of that. Had an awesome time,
but I didn't get to see the
game and I saw Tim shallows,
fucking filthy shorthand
for nice feed from Brad.
My Sean Pasta had the game winner and
it seems even though you know Theresa
version runs out with a broken foot,
I don't know if shower is back.
Last game I saw he fell the way I used
to fall when I was public at like a
public skating rink.
You know what I mean?
Will you try to stop and then you catch
an edge and all of a sudden you go like
headfirst, do a face plant before
the board's mercifully stopped.
You've usually knocked down like a five
year old trying to learn how to figure
skate. Uh, I'm trying to say we have a lot
of injuries but we're still winning. Ah,
the Celtics on the other hand,
Kyrie Irving is going to
be out three to six weeks.
Sports illustrates website is
telling me I don't need to panic.
Toronto's going to get the number one
seed and we're probably going to play some
shit bomb fucking team and he'll be back
by the end of it. I don't fucking know.
Uh, I think Toronto's looking
pretty strong. It's going
to be obviously Toronto.
Cleveland.
When you think,
when you think and can Lebron put his
fucking team on his back once again. Okay.
And get to the finals again while the
entire basketball world shits on him and
says how much he's an asshole and how
much I've never seen a guy achieve more
and get more shit. I just don't get it.
What more does he have to do our right,
he took his talents to south beach.
All right.
He won two championships on a pile on
team, but then he went back to Cleveland,
put the fucking team on his back
and beat the Golden State Warriors.
Right.
Right there.
It should have been over.
It was over for Steve Young when he
beat the fucking San Diego chargers.
Okay.
Whew. Whew. Whew. Was it chuck Humphreys?
Huge Humphreys.
Chuck Humphreys.
I don't remember
Pete.
That fucking team,
one of the most boring super bowls there
ever was 49 is went out and they had
fucking white pants on and shit.
MMM.
And then the monkey's been off his back
and nobody ever fucking questioned him
again.
Ever questioned him again.
Even after fucking spygate when he said
the Patriot should give up their three
fucking super bowl titles.
You know the fucking guys on TV,
he's in a hall of fame player.
He didn't realize that that was a brand
new rule and the patriots work guilty,
but it was only illegal for one gay.
Nobody gave him shit yet. They
still give Lebron Shit. Why is that?
Why do you think that is?
Is it because Steve Young
is a fucking moron? Um,
I have no idea. Anyways, so I
went to this birthday party,
a two year old's birthday party, some
friends of ours and there was this, uh,
went out to the speaking ranches.
We went out to this farm way
the fuck out towards Oxnard.
Came to Rio.
MMM.
It was awesome. It's part, you know,
part of Los Angeles. I very rarely go to,
I fly over it, but I never
fucking actually went out there.
It was absolutely beautiful out there,
past this fee me valley.
And they had all like
these animals and stuff.
They're big animal farm and I realized
that I am a big fan of Al packers.
You know,
there was this brown one just with these
giant fucking brown eyes just looking
at you. A little weird little wema
admittedly a little weird, you know,
they kind of look like Lama's still
like better looking llamas, you know?
Um, potbelly pig, which I
never realized when people say,
I got, you know, you got a pot belly.
What an insult that is. I mean,
these things were fat fucks.
That belly was,
was like on the ground.
MMM.
They just like, they just, they fucking
pigs. I mean, pigs really, our pigs,
they always talk about how smart
they are and that type of stuff.
I think the level that they eat and the
fact that they roll around in their own
shit, it's just really hard
to see the intelligence.
You know what I mean?
I mean, I think a lot of fat
people get treated the same way.
Do you think if Albert
Einstein was a fat fuck, like
okay.
I Dunno. Rolling around in his own
shit. I mean, I don't think we,
when World War Two, what do you
guys think? You care to comment?
Would you like to write into
the podcast about that one? Um,
I'm just filibustering here.
I got to get this shit done cause I got
all kinds of stuff to do today and I'm
waiting for my advertising and my
questions to come in and got, dammit. Oh,
the reeds is sent. Oh Shit.
Everything's fucking here. Ready to go.
I love it. All right, let's download
these. God Damn. Thanks. Um,
so anyways, we were at where?
Out there and uh, at that,
at the birthday party,
you got so fucked up about me.
Loved to fuck all the birthday parties
stuff. I, first thing I did was alpacas.
I looked at those things and I'm like,
wow,
those things look like a food source
because they said they were from South
America.
So all of that picturing
his boa constrictors and
God knows what kill on those
things, you know, or that
like the Komodo Dragon,
this time he sat this stock in this
giant bull looking thing and did,
did,
did those Komodo dragons,
they have such fucking shit breath in
their mouth is so full of bacteria that if
they all they to do,
it was just nick and owl.
An animal just did 10 times its size.
It just need a bite it and then they just
followed around for three days is that
bacteria just slowly
fucking kills the thing.
I just wished the bull knew that the
second one was bit by that fucking dragon
that it was over because then you just do,
you just turn around and blow.
You're not going to fucking eat me.
Yeah,
right.
Just go over and kill the fucking thing
because the problem with those God damn
reptiles and my issue with reptiles is
they don't have the Dan Chimpanzees,
they don't have the decency to kill
you before they start eat. Yeah,
yeah.
They don't know. Yeah. They don't
like that thing. Once you collapse,
it just walks up. It has no
feeling whatsoever, you know,
which is why chimpanzees and human beings
are the worst chimpanzees and human
beings.
The only people I've ever seen get off
on the suffering of something else.
Like it actually excites them.
I told you that.
I think I saw that thing one time
when they did for the longest time,
they didn't think chimpanzees, monkeys,
eight other monkeys, they disapproved it.
They found out it wasn't true.
And I saw these fucking chimpanzees
catch this fucking smaller monkey.
All right.
And the,
he just stood on the thing's fucking back
and with his fingers was digging flesh
out of its back as the
other monkeys screaming.
And the chip was getting off
on a sec, dude. Like, you know,
how fresh does it have to be?
Just snap.
It's a little fucking neck and get
on with it. Um, and ever since then,
I fucking hate chimpanzees.
I hate him.
I hate him as much as I
love, uh, uh, gorillas.
But having said that, I don't want to see
chimpanzees ever hurt though. You know,
I, I, you know,
although I wanted that bold to fucking
destroy that Komodo dragon has it just
kept falling around,
you know,
like some damn bank or watching a
fucking farmer working himself to death,
waiting to take over the land to sell
to some other, fuck. All right, Bill,
let's not get that dramatic.
Okay. It's the wild. Get Mad
at God. You created it. Um,
it, well, I don't know if
it's a fucking lady or not
how fucked up, but human beings is,
is big pieces of shit that we are,
that uh,
we actually think God looks like us
and actually argue about
what it's races or it's sex.
It's the stupidest shit ever.
MMM.
Okay. Let me, uh, let me for the,
I have like 90 fucking window windows
open and I'm getting rid of all of these,
except from my Brian Kest yoga videos.
I'm back into it. I'm taking my
power yogas watching these things.
You know what's funny is I end case
anybody from his class, here's this,
I own all of his shit on VHS.
I just don't have a fucking VCR anymore.
So I have purchased the things,
but I just can't play him son.
I have to watch him on Youtube.
Um, all right. Where am I?
Where am I going here? I fucking,
is it ever on the right email?
Come on. You son of a bitch.
Why? Why, why, why, why? Why
are you doing this to me?
Loading as slow as humanly possible.
Do I have to hit pause?
All right,
my account. Sign out. Start over again.
There we go.
Come on. Open Up. Do you can do
it. All right. I'm hitting pause.
This is pathetic. I'll wait.
It's coming up. Loading,
loading, loading. People.
Just try busy yourselves as I wait
for this fucking thing to open up. No,
I don't want the APP.
Okay.
Oh my God.
All right. Live reads. Here we are. Look
who's here? Everybody at Sarab friends.
Old Zip.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah. Talk about how important it
is to have the right employees.
I'll tell you right now.
You know,
the only thing worse to have a right
employees is the wrong employees.
Like what are you doing? I Dunno.
I guess I'm the wrong guy. Hey,
get the fuck out of here.
Wouldn't it be great?
Was this service that would help you
to stop picking the wrong employee?
You know what I mean? Do you hire some
person who comes in ready to work,
you know, not showing up
with fuck me, pumps and tits,
hanging out thinking that that's all
they got to do is just look good, right?
All ZipRecruiter knew
there was a smarter way.
So they built a platform
that finds you the right job.
Job Kat candidates for you. Ziprecruiter
learns what you're looking for,
identifies people with
the right experience and
invites them to apply to your
job. Uh, those invitations
have revolutionized how
you find your next hire.
In fact,
80% of employers who post a job on
ZipRecruiter get a qualified candidate
through the site in just one day.
This is also a great way to get a job
right post you fucking resume on there and
zip
doesn't stop there.
They even spotlight the strongest
applications you receive,
so you never miss a great match. That's
a, the right candidates are out there.
Ziprecruiter is how you find them.
Businesses of all sizes. Trust, sip.
Okay.
For hiring needs brought
their hiring needs right now.
My listeners can try ZipRecruiter
for free. That's right. Free.
Just go to ziprecruiter.com/bird
that's ziprecruiter.com/bro Huh?
gretta.com/burns ZipRecruiter
is the smartest way to hire.
I'm running out of ways
to say that fucking word.
Oh look who's here in don't Cido.
Uh,
talk about how every man looks
better in a suit. Listen,
I love checking out the fellows,
but I'll tell you nothing gets
my freckled motor running.
Like seeing a man in a well tailored suit.
The confidence,
the way the jacket blows in the breeze.
Indochino is the largest
custom apparel company.
Guys love the wild selection of high
quality fabrics and the options to
personalize all the details, including
the lapel jacket, line lining,
monogram, and much more. Here's
how it works. Pick your fabric,
choose your customizations,
submit your measurements,
place your order and wait for it to
run to arrive in three weeks or less.
You can shop online@indochino.com or
visit any of their showrooms across North
America.
Yeah,
they have stores. I don't think
I've ever seen one this week.
My listeners can get any premium premium
indochine know a suit for just 359
bucks. That's indochino.com
when entering burr at checkout,
I n d o, c h, I n o.com.
That's over 50% off the regular price
for a premium made to measure suit plus
shipping is free.
That's right.
indochino.com promo code [inaudible]
for any premium suit for just 359 bucks
plus free shipping.
It's an incredible deal for
a perfectly tailored suit.
Okay,
there you go.
Three 59 bucks
and you're out the door.
You're out the fucking door.
Um, all right. Here's
all the God damn reads.
Here's all the God damn reads. Here's what
the fuck I was looking for. God dammit.
Hey, speaking of that, am I in
a Tulsa, Oklahoma this weekend?
Speaking of southern accents?
Margaret, I'll be down.
There are no over there in Tulsa,
Oklahoma. The Braden theater.
Yes, I am March 30th Oh my
God. I love it. What's today?
Today's the 26 let's see here.
That's Thursday.
No, Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday, Friday. So this,
say I'm going to be, um,
at the Brady theater,
Tulsa, Oklahoma. And then on March 31st
I'm going to be down in San Antonio,
Texas,
right?
They're stars at night are big and
bright deep in the heart of Texas.
What do they have their,
what do they call that thing?
That little fucking river
that the river walk.
It's actually really relaxing,
you know,
and then you don't really ever
have to get off and buy anything.
You just fucking sitting there floating
around on a God damn boat. Okay.
That's gonna be one of those weird
flights where like it should only take me
like an hour to go from fucking Tulsa,
Oklahoma or 90 minutes to San Antonio.
But it's going to take the whole fucking
day cause they don't have to like
connect through like Denver or some shit.
Um,
speaking of what she,
I got some shows coming up in Pittsburgh
April 6th and for whatever fucking
reason, the only direct flight I could
get out of La is a southwest flight.
I don't understand Philly and
Pittsburgh back in the day.
The only direct flight from
La to Philly was on u s air.
I don't mind. I don't mind southwest
Linda till they start telling the jokes,
you know, and just fucking, it's so God
damn obnoxious because nobody heckles him.
That's what's missing on a
southwest flight. Boeing,
the jokes,
you have such a captive audience.
Everybody's afraid we're going to crash.
You know,
for some reason you think the steward or
the store it is actually is flying the
plane so you don't want to give him shit.
Right.
Oh God. That's what I
wish I, you know, Patrice,
I could just fucking see him and that
if he ever saw what those fucking people
per character,
okay.
He would have heckled.
Okay.
Hey, he definitely would
have fucking happened. Um,
I just sit there stewing and anger and
not even mad at the fucking steward or
stewardess is, which I
still call them, by the way.
I don't understand how the fuck that ever
became offensive. You know what I mean?
Or they feel like steward had
mmm.
Like, I don't know, come up to it.
Why is, I mean, look this up, why is
Stuart is offensive?
I might be wrong.
Here's why.
Flight attendants don't like
being called stewardesses.
All right. Flight attendants. Oh man,
they got an old fucking school one.
Look how hot they used to be.
I swear to God, they must have
fucking drop the pay dramatically.
I Dunno what they used to be.
Fucking gorgeous. Unbelievable.
All right. Flight, but the food was way
worse. There's always a tradeoff, right?
Um,
flight attendants have a job that holds
a lot of prestige in the eyes of most
travelers.
Y and w what?
There's a giant vague bullshit statement.
I think that used to be when the,
when they were beautiful women,
it seemed glamorous.
The whole thing.
The pilot seemed like a
fucking borderline James Bond.
There's all these sexy women
fucking walking around like wow,
they get to go to all of these places
before everybody flew her all the time.
MMM.
People you actually used to dress up when
they went on planes wearing suits and
women get all dolled up and shit.
You know,
this is before they treated you
like a fucking animal though.
Then they started treating
everybody like animals.
Now people walk in and on that, getting
the borderline pajamas. Anyways,
they get called a lot of different things
while doing their jobs. Waitress, ma'am?
Hey,
you miss air hostess and Trolley Dolly.
Okay. You know what? I have well over a
million fucking a frequent flier miles.
I've never heard anybody say
waitress. No one's ever said, hey,
you air hostess.
Hey Trolley Dolly,
get I get a fucking drag. C'Mon. I'm
sure everybody has a story, but come on.
I think pretty much everybody's been
respectful as certainly after nine 11,
because then all the stewards and
stewardesses, all they have to say is, uh,
why are you being hostile? Do
you not want to fly today? Uh,
anyway, some flight attendants
have a job then Obama. Okay. Uh,
but one moniker that is
pretty much gone out.
The emergency exit door is stewardess.
And here's why I love it.
This person just made up all of this
other shit waitress, ma'am. Hey you
trolley Dolly just made up all of that
shit so they could get to this stewardess
part.
All right.
I think it's safe to say that a strip
tease ad for an airline like this one from
Braniff international airways
below would not fly today. Yeah.
A lot of things from back then wouldn't
fly today. Uh, at least not in America.
Oh, look at that. Um, but this type of ad,
which most would now consider
objectifying towards women.
Okay.
Was the only way to go in
the sex cells day. Okay. Sorry. I was
thinking about clicking on the video.
I was doing the math,
whether I could do that and not get in
trouble because I'm advertising on this,
sorry. Let me go back to
trying to read this. Uh,
was the only way to go in the sex cells
day of the early jet age. Oh yeah.
Because they don't use sex
to sell anything anymore.
A brand Braniff was hugely
popular in its heyday. Uh,
their flight attendants war psychedelic
trends from some are fashions top
designers such as
Emilio Pucci. Oh, he fell off on a murder.
That fucking Guy Pacific southwest
airlines was another airline average.
I'm going to watch this fucking video.
Let's see what's going on here. Uh,
Pacific salesforce airlines was another
airline press start to play with color
course advertising.
And it's a bunch of sexy women winking
at me and all this using sex to sell.
Okay.
In 2018.
Yeah.
What is going on here?
It's just another ad.
This is an ad for Disneyland. Oh,
you know what? Go Fuck Yourself.
Fuck this video.
Is this just clickbait?
Is that what I've done here?
Um,
yeah.
Was it another and can I
tell you something right now?
I guarantee you all these fucking
hotties that were on this airline,
they weren't the ones that bitched.
It was ugly women that couldn't
get the fucking job. I can,
I'm so sick of like this certain jobs,
you should just be good. Lucky. Okay.
And as a fucking, uh, unsightly human
being, I feel like I can say this shit,
right?
Yeah.
Yeah. Like you walk into a restaurant,
you want to see somebody good looking,
okay.
You know, hotel, gym,
all of that Shit,
this fucking thing.
Now that you don't have to be good
looking and you can be like a, you know,
overweight and all of that stuff is,
that's really not helping out fat people.
I can tell you that yes,
they're getting a job,
but there's still eating their way to a
fucking early grave who doesn't want to
live. It's sort of what you're doing
is as much as you're giving them a job,
you're also in this roundabout way in
kind of doing this assisted suicide,
you kind of a part of it,
right? In a food sense.
I don't know what I'm talking about,
but I'm going to continue speaking. Um,
Pacific southwest airlines was another
airline that advertise the attractiveness
of its flight attendance. They introduced
the miniskirt 1965 in our book,
long legs and short nights
form a PSA flight attendant,
Maryland trips said they used to
be a distinction between flight and
stewardesses.
Flight attendants were there for safety
while stewardesses were there to be eye
candy. Flirt and serve
drinks. Yeah, that's your job.
The pilot passes out.
Do you know how to fly to fucking plane?
Well then start waking at
people. This sweetheart, um,
she noted stewardesses were not allowed
to do pa announcements because nobody
could understand, okay, this is getting
a little weird, therefore, let's face it.
They were deep. They were along for the
ride. Now they weren't. They were like,
they were serving drinks.
Maryland,
trich Schwartz contacted me to let me
know that I had misunderstood a quote and
there was not a distinction between
stewardesses in flight attendants.
They merely changed the job titles
once more men joined the industry.
Yeah. These were called stewards when
she referred to stewardesses as they,
because she was one herself.
I misinterpreted that to mean that
there were actually two different jobs.
So this guy really doesn't know what the
fuck he's talking about. Oh, this woman,
okay,
what am I reading here? I don't even
know many modern and dare I say,
older flight attendants now considered
stewardess a derogatory term toward their
profession and even their personal
virtue because they take their job more
seriously.
That being there is simply too
okay
to serve as eye candy. All right. Uh,
I'm done with this fucking article.
All right.
I learned absolutely nothing other than
the astounding lack of fucking research.
I mean,
I thought only I did that on my podcast,
this fucking person and like he literally
his article rather than going back and
correcting it, he's fucking
correct. And himself,
like he writes the article out
and I realized I fucked up.
But he's just continuing on.
Yeah. I mean at the, at the end of
the fucking day, like this is just,
I think what really fucking happened,
it was flying back then was glamorous.
Okay. It was way more glamorous. She got
treated way more. It was considered an,
an an an an an amazing luxury.
Okay.
To be able to fly now everybody, everybody
fucking flies. They Jamey in the back,
you know,
you have to pay for food.
Okay.
I mean, back then it was like
coffee tea or me was, was,
that was basically the,
uh,
okay.
The vibe back debt, you know what
I mean? And they're acting like,
okay,
I dunno. I Dunno what they're active,
they're, they're acting like a, the
that, that there weren't some fucking
women that that was an appealing job to
not everybody has a dream.
Okay.
That's, you know, something that's,
maybe that's what's going on right now
was fucking all of the medias is that
everybody's acting like they're fucking
Joe Montana. You know what I mean?
That they're like an Oscar winner.
It's just most of us would
just put background. That's it.
Where that guy in the fucking
middle seat staring at the cell,
a woman serving them peanuts,
that is way out of their league that
you'd never have the balls to talk to.
Not now. Everybody's a
winner. According to Oprah.
You could do whatever you want.
It's going to be great.
All your dreams are gonna come true.
Nobody's going to try to steal your ideas.
There's plenty of room for everybody.
Top of the mountain.
I, that's just not the
case. I hate to say that.
If just go out and look at a mountain,
just look at the shape of this.
Plenty of room down the
bottom. There is a, you know,
there's less but still a
lot of room in the middle.
But as you keep going higher and
higher, you know, I don't know.
I don't even know what I'm talking about.
I still don't understand why.
So basically,
yeah.
Flight attendants wanted to distill,
still doing the same fucking job.
I Dunno. Maybe now they, they actually
know CPR or some shit like that,
that took a couple of Mas classes.
Yeah.
Um, but you know, what are they,
what are they going to tell him?
You know what I mean? I mean, if, if,
if like some terrorists
go to take over the plane,
do they also have like Chinese stars
that they're allowed to bring onto the
fucking plane?
Okay.
Um, plead people, I don't want
to be called a comedian anymore.
I think that's offensive because people
just feel like I'm going to have a
lampshade on my head.
I would now like to be called a,
uh,
a humor doctor,
doctor humor something, or
I'll come up with it. I don't,
I don't want to, um, I think it's very
sexist. It's be called the comedian.
MMM.
I don't know why. And you know, other
languages have male and female things.
So I think that's the thing.
I'm in my business to comedian,
they want to be called a comedian. We
have a community and coming to the stage,
look, why do you have to
just make a distinction?
I don't know why. I don't know. I
don't know. I don't know. I'm just,
can we get a gender neutral microphone?
It was out there.
That's probably gonna be the next thing.
Maybe that microphones are shaped
too much. Like dicks. They get
above like a hermaphrodite style one.
You can have like a dick coming
out of vagina. Uh, you know,
something maybe like
those old school Elvis.
Once you get to have that and just bad,
like,
I don't know what you speak into.
Looks like a clip. I don't know.
Is this technically even
like still a podcast?
Let me just get to the questions this
week that went nowhere, by the way.
And I know a lot of it was ignorant and,
uh,
I think I stand by it. Um, all
right, let's get to the, uh,
let's get to the questions here.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Yeah.
Become a pilot.
Okay.
You know, do that then become a pilot.
Run an airline. You want respect
to them. Okay. You fucking do that.
These P he's bullies.
People on special teams all of a sudden
want to be treated like quarterbacks. I,
it's just, you're not
a quarterback. Sorry.
Um,
oh shit.
The all things comedy festival is
coming back again this year and uh,
it's going to be a Comerica theater
in Phoenix, Arizona and October 26,
Jesus Christ. Get your tickets
early at ticket master. Uh,
the Presale is Wednesday,
March 28th at 10:00 AM
public on sale is Friday,
March 30th at 10:00 AM local
time. Both for both of those. Uh,
and I will be posting the link on my
Twitter and my Instagram and my Facebook.
Just an internet. Dushoney alright,
Mr. Rogers movie. Oh, I love it.
It's a beautiful day in the neighborhood.
A Beautiful Day in the neighborhood.
Would you be mine? Could you
be mine? I have always wanted,
I can't believe I remember this.
Have our neighbor just like you.
I've always wanted to live in
their neighborhood with you.
So let's make the most
of this beautiful day.
Don't call them stewardesses
and don't say, hey,
columns, flight attendants make it
seem like they have a master's degree.
Would you like some fucking peanuts?
You will respect me and my slacks.
Hello,
Mr Neighbors. Uh, Mr. Rogers
movie. Hey there, bill,
I'm writing to you here from Minneapolis
and very much looking forward to your
upcoming show here. You know,
back when I was a kid, you know,
getting treated like shit
motivated you to get a better job,
not demand that your,
you fucking be treated with respect at
the low level that you had attained in
the job world.
Anyway,
I was wondering if you heard about
the movie being made about Mr. Rogers
starring Tom Hanks is Fred Rogers.
Coincidentally,
a movie trailer was also just released
for a new documentary about Fred Rogers
that just premiered at
Sundance and it looks awesome.
I grew up watching Mr. Rogers as a kid
and it's really refreshing to look back
at some of the clips that show what
a great one of a kind person he was.
Did you grow up watching Mr.
RogersRogers' neighborhood? Yes, I did.
Mister McFeely speedy delivery.
And if so,
what were your thoughts about
them making a movie about him?
Maybe you have a different perspective
now that you have a kid because it seems
like there's so much awful shit that kids
are exposed to on TV and the Internet.
And Mr. Rogers was a rare TV show,
which actually helps kids to become
better human beings. Last but not least,
would you consider auditioning
for this shows? Longtime guests?
Mister McFeely?
I think you'd look hilarious and that
mailman hat and when with the spectacles
and the mustache, thanks for being a
great neighbor and go fuck yourself. Ah,
I absolutely would play mister McFeely.
Um,
I loved, I loved Mr. Rogers when I was
a kid. I like sesame street better.
Um,
and there was something about him that
did make me a little uncomfortable when I
was a kid. I will admit
that. No, you know what?
I didn't like lady Elaine and King Friday.
I liked the trolley when
it went into the uh,
the make believe land or whatever.
But um,
I dunno, Lady Lane and, and King Friday,
they just used to make
me sick to my stomach.
Yeah.
They just weren't as funny and they didn't
have the personality of like Ernie or
Grover Harry the cookie monster.
I mean,
there was just those who liked the guys
guys have puppets over there on sesame
street. I just thought it Mr.
RogersRogers' neighborhood was,
it was just a little stiff. But um, I've,
I imagined that I learned
a bunch of great lessons.
I was too young to understand like,
oh,
this guy's trying to teach me how
to be a better person. You know,
it was just a kid watching the shit go.
Wouldn't that be cool if we had a trolley
in our house and then he could get on
it and it go to a magical neighborhood
and avoid king Friday and Lady Elaine,
she was fucking weird looking
to right I to look this up here,
lady Elaine Lady Lady.
How do you spell a lane? Oh yeah. Yeah.
She was ugly. Is there, what
does my God lay off the Booze
Lady Lane Fairchild.
I never knew.
The last name is a neighborhood
and mischief maker.
And having learned from
the wizard of loophole,
which often uses or boomerang tumor
Marangu summa rang. Oh my God,
I forgot about that.
To do things such as rearranged the
neighborhood or turn it upside down.
She's credited with the discovery
of planet purple, purple,
which she found while flying
in or something or other.
Well, you know, that would never happen.
Now that would be considered sexist. Oh,
why? Why does the woman have
to be the bad person? Well,
she's in a position of power. Isn't
that enough? No. Ah, what are you doing?
Come on. Um, alright. Do I,
I, I think Tom Hanks is going to do
a great job because he always does.
You know,
you look how we just said that like he's
an up and coming actor rather than the
two times back to back.
Best actor.
Um, do I call him an actress
now? Is that progressive?
Should I not identify by his gender? I
don't fucking know. I don't know. I don't,
I don't know what, what
to do right now. Uh,
I think it'd be interesting if they
actually get into his, his whole life,
you know? But if it's just Tom Hanks
doing an episode of Mr. Rogers and then,
I dunno. I Dunno what the, I don't
fucking know. I watch sports.
Why would you ask me about movies? All
right. Linkedin business APP. Dear Billy,
balloon head.
My girlfriend and I had been together,
his girlfriend, one or two words.
There was two, one word. My girlfriend
and I have been together for a year.
For the past two months.
She's been out of work.
So two months. It has been using
this business app to get work online.
It has never bothered me as of revenue.
I think you said recently
as of Raven reverently me,
she has been getting
notifications from the APP.
I don't know what any of that means.
I didn't think anything of it,
but I noticed that she had gotten a
message in the middle of the night. Oh,
as of recently.
This is a voice text.
Reverently reverently me as of recently,
she has been getting notifications from
the APP. I didn't think anything of it.
Um, but I've noticed that
she has gotten messages,
gotten a message in the
middle of the night.
I asked her about it and she always tells
me that it's strictly professional and
that is just business
men seeking to employ.
Do you think that APP is just
a cover up for meeting men?
She would meet on apps like Tinder.
Um, I don't know dude, but it doesn't
sound like you fucking trust your, uh,
your girlfriend, which is definitely
an issue. So what you have done,
you have to figure out as if you don't
trust her because she got saying she
shady or is it some,
some of your own shit that you brought
because of a previous relationship or
possibly something that happened?
She was a child when you
were watching Mr. Rogers
calling women's stewardesses.
Um,
okay.
I Dunno. It's possible women are
really good at fucking around,
which is why they don't get caught
as much as guys do. Guys, you know,
guys are the worst. You know,
we just fucking, we get caught.
Um, anyways he wants, I dunno, I
dunno what to tell you to do there.
Okay,
so now you got to start snooping and
then if you get caught in you're wrong,
then what?
Where does that leave you
just tell her it's making you feel
insecure and you would just, can you just,
you know,
and it's your issue.
Can you just see one of the texts next
time it happens and then just say,
sorry,
I dunno,
I just love these sub black and I was
worried that somebody else was still a
year. Passions. Talk your way out of it
that way. Does that work? I don't know.
This is not professional advice.
He wants to get married. I don't,
I hate built your fountain of Cynical
Humor and knowledge that I've admired for
years. Yo, you are a
fountain of Jesus Christ.
So I wanted to ask some advice. Hey,
this is not professional advice.
My boyfriend proposed two
years ago after I said yes.
He said he wanted to keep it a secret
since he hadn't met my parents yet,
except via Skype calls.
They live across the country by parents
kept canceling their plans to visit last
minute.
So he planned to visit them for this
past Christmas where he would publicly
propose Jesus.
Chris is the longest proposal ever.
I kept this a secret for two years.
We only had two fights,
but each time he broke off the engagement,
only do apologize and make up the
next day. One month prior to the trip,
he says he wants to postpone proposing
due to finances since we will be moving
to another state after I
graduate. I understand. Uh,
why spend five grand on a wedding when
we'll soon need that to get a house while
the next day he admitted.
The other reason is because I had gained
weight after getting on birth control
and anxiety met. Yeah, you fuck this guy?
Okay,
I'm getting a Master's in
physics and have a part time job.
So sorry if I couldn't hit the gym
enough. Uh, well that's no excuse.
She should also fucking eat well. And
I'm not saying that about him and your,
your relationship would do
it for yourself because uh,
you really do not want the health issues
that fucking start earliest in your
late thirties and your forties.
Um,
okay.
You know,
I've lost friends to heart attack set
look like they're in the same shape as me,
but I dunno, you got to get checked
up. Um, just cause you're busy.
This is what you do.
You're fucking cook all your food
on the weekend and that you get,
you got to make that up fucking priority
cause it's going to be stressful enough.
But anyways, ice, I still maintain
it this point. Fuck this guy.
Anyways, that Christmas was so
depressing, but who could I talk to?
The engagement was a secret.
I told him being engaged was a joke.
I don't want to be on this
rollercoaster anymore or ever again.
Now he started because he says
marriage is, it is important to him.
He does want to marry me. Just not
yet hot. No thanks. I'm good. He said,
well we'll just revisit this later.
Your thoughts from one cynical ginger
to another thanks to the left. Yeah.
Fuck this guy. Fuck this guy. This,
this is what,
yeah,
this guy's an asshole.
I want to postpone the engagement because
you gain weight. That's what the fuck.
You going to hitch your wagon
to? Fuck this guy. Fuck that guy.
Um, and you seem really strong
and [inaudible], you know,
you're getting his
master's degree in physics.
You can be out there designing roller
coasters or whatever the fuck you're going
to be doing. You don't
need this guy. By the way,
I watched this thing that I have recorded.
You know my wife's, we thank you.
We need stuff on the Dvr, right?
Whatever the fuck you call it nowadays.
So we had to go back and erase
a bunch of shit that I taped.
I kept all my Superbowl highlights.
I kept 'em the Patriots for
Seattle and Patriots first.
Atlanta had no problem erasing
patriots versus eagles. Um,
and I don't know where those patriots,
verse giants Games went. Geez. Um,
Ethel Merman. All right. You want to talk
about a fucking hilarious human being?
Uh, I got to find this
fucking thing. Ethel Merman.
She was all right.
We were watching this fucking
thing on the JFK inauguration,
which was supposed to be broadcast by NBC.
And,
uh, there was a horrific snow storm.
They were in this weird venue.
It was like Frank Sinatra,
Nat King Cole, Ethel Merman,
uh, uh, Milton Berle.
Who else? Gene Kelly. Harry Belafonte,
Ella Fitzgerald.
I mean,
it was crazy lineup and I'm
Jimmy Duranti and all this shit.
This was like a,
it was a big deal.
This is the first time
like marrying Hollywood and
politics now where that's led
us is probably a bad thing.
But
MMM.
It was just on a, watching all
these performances and everything.
So watch an Ethel Merman
and she's literally wearing
just like this winter coat
during the performance because she went
there for rehearsals and she got stuck
in the snow and couldn't get back to a
hotel and she was a Republican and still
sang to the president rather than
all these fucking Douche is today.
It'd be like, Oh, good look
good is the shit right.
And then she put politics
aside and she did it.
And as she was singing near
just goes like, she said
something like that. There's,
there's a fucking there right there,
there is a tough broad.
And I just started laughing. I
said, what do you mean? She goes,
you could just see it. She's,
she's been through it all,
bunch of asshole guys and she survived.
She's seen it all and blah blah.
So I look her up and of course
[inaudible] was 100% right.
She'd been married like four times
and she was married one time for like
three months to earn as Borgnine and they
got divorced.
All they did was argue and she,
one of the things she
said was extreme cruelty.
So there's a quote,
I wish I could find the fucking thing.
Um, let me, I got to find, cause
I, cause she it so perfectly.
You want to talk about somebody hilarious
that you've loved to hang out with?
Uh,
okay.
Earnest. I just put in
Ethel Merman. Earnest cunt.
Okay.
Ernest Borgnine. Ethel
Merman. There we go.
The classic Ethel Merman Story.
All right,
I'll of course this is going to be some
dude's turning it into an entire fucking
okay.
Tire fucking blog.
Okay.
God damn ass holes.
Okay. Yeah. So she was
in her brief marriage.
Mirman was on some fucking um,
yeah,
she was on some fucking
movie set and she came home,
she was all excited because the director
had complimented her saying her if she
had the voice of like a 25 year old,
you know the face and she was
like, she was like 60, all right,
35 year old face and a 35 year old figure.
And she said, and then Ernest
Borgnine said, oh yeah, it goes,
did he bring up your old
content? And she goes, no,
he didn't mention you once.
Stuff like that. I Dunno,
they fight. This isn't,
this isn't written as well.
And what about your 65 year old cut and
she said, nobody mentioned you at all.
I've seen this thing written like
five different ways. She also did it.
She did a guest star on some set comp
and they had a curse jar and she was in
the middle of whatever sketch they
would do it. And then she just stopped.
She goes,
what the hell is this going?
And then the star of the show
was just like a Bethel, you know,
my rule that'll cost you a dollar.
And She just goes out. Howdy.
What would it cost me to
tell you to go fuck yourself?
So
Ethel Merman.
Ethel Merman is a new, um, a
new, I'm a big fan of hers. Um,
unfortunately she passed
away a long time ago,
so you can't go out and have a drink with
her, but just seemed fucking hilarious.
All right,
let me read the last goddamn question here
so I can move on with my fucking life.
MMM.
Why do I keep doing this? I keep going
away from my fucking, the questions here.
This is like unprecedented the amount
of times I fucked this up and you guys
have to listen to me, uh, on precedent
for this podcast, I should say.
All right, content. Here's
the last one. The last one.
Okay.
He is a jealous boyfriend. I love that the
women are finally right now. All right.
Hello Bill Burr. I really
love your podcast. Thank you.
When I was wondering what your thoughts
on a situation I am going through.
This is my first serious relationship.
My boyfriend and I just moved in
about four months ago. I have, oh,
I have always fucking known that he's
bent over protective and jealous.
However, I did started to progress
more and more. Oh, get out,
get out. I trust him that he's
not cheating on me. Of course,
like many other women,
I can be self conscious and think that
maybe he could stray or do better,
but I've never once accused him of
cheating on me. Not once, however,
he has caused me
what he has caused me of cheating on.
He's accused do,
these are all voice texts he has
caused me of cheating on him.
He's accused me of cheating
on him multiple times.
The worst case of when
it should have been up,
which he made accusations,
uh, was fairly recently.
I just got a full,
a new full time job.
I was only working part
time minimum wage job,
which I'm very excited about
that this full time job. Um,
so that he's not the only one working.
I feel like I can contribute now.
However, he started accusing me of
cheating on him with someone at work,
even though there is no evidence,
he even started accusing me of
cheating on him with his own cousin.
He's the one that helped me get the job
is act, use of Tint to dump this guy.
His accusations are not just him speaking,
but yelling,
hitting walls and scaring me to the point
like he might get violent. Ah, right.
Here's what should do.
Okay.
Okay. Put a deposit down on
another fucking apartment.
Okay. One day when he goes to
work, you take a fucking sick day,
all right? You get a friend, you
clear all your shit out of there,
okay?
Yeah. Fuck this guy.
Fuck this guy. All right?
You don't want to be
anywhere near this guy.
You don't want to be around this guy when
you break up with him, he seems like a,
I don't like any of this.
Uh,
he doesn't even want me to wear shorts
and we live in this area that gets hot.
I am not the type of person to show a
lot of skins. However, when it's hot,
I would like to wear shorts.
He Isi. What's going on here?
This guy's taking over your whole life.
I'm just wondering if this,
if his thoughts
that me wearing shorts is disrespectful
to him to the point he is just the f.
Wait a minute.
I'm just wondering if his thoughts
that me wearing shorts is different.
It's disrespectful to him to the point
he is justified breaking up with me over
this.
Okay.
I am not sure where to draw the line.
Oh,
you should have drawn the line of
while ago are now, let me ask you this.
If any girlfriend you had was telling
you this story, you would be like,
get the fuck out. Right. I really
believe that. I love and care about him.
That's the problem. However, when he does.
Okay,
when love, when does love turn
into more of an obsession? Also,
what is considered an abusive or
unhealthy relationship? I would say this.
I would really like to know your thoughts.
You are straight up and I believe
you'll be able to give some good advice,
especially since you will not have real
bias since you don't know us. Thank you.
Yeah, you should get the fire as far as
your version. What's going on? You should
get the fuck out of here.
Just the fact that he's choosing
you are cheating on him. Um,
and what's your, what's his
cousin, which is fucking weird.
And then yelling and hitting the
walls. I mean, you're already out.
You're already gone. You
should be gone. And now, uh,
the fact that he's telling you what
you can and can't wear. Fuck this guy.
So the problem is as you
moved in with the guy,
so if you break up with the guy,
what are you going to go into another
room and then you've got to worry about
this guy, you know,
doing God knows what. Um,
do you have any male friends? Do you
have a brother? Somebody, you know,
they can help protect you when
you get your shit out of there.
I would get another fucking, I mean, I,
this is the type of situation
I wouldn't fuck you pride.
I would move back in with my parents if
I had to and drive longer to work the
fuck out of that.
Um,
and uh, I'd be it sees he's
breakup ever as far as the reasons.
Uh,
I dunno,
cause you don't trust me because you think
I'm fucking your cousin to the point,
your raw acting like Jeff Goldbloom and
the fly and start punching the goddamn
door jams out. Oh. And by the way,
it's 90 degrees out and I can't wear
shorts because you and your fragile ego
can't fucking handle it.
And I wouldn't say it this way because
this guy sounds like a lunatic. Um,
I dunno what, what could
you say that would just make
this guy go away? Just say,
ah,
you know,
I just decided that I want to get really
fat and wear shorts and I didn't want
to put you through that.
I don't know what to tell you,
but I would get out of this. And when
somebody is violent like this, uh,
I would be concerned about
your own safety. So like I
said, I would take a, uh,
okay.
This is what you do. All right. I
figured you, you sound like a young,
so you probably don't have that much shit.
Okay.
So, uh, I would just,
whatever your friend is that's
going to help you move out.
You put the boxes together over her
house. All right? And then bump,
bump, bump, bump, bump, bump, bump.
You fucking go in there. All right.
You just act like you go into work
and then you don't fucking go to work.
Okay. And, and uh, I would even
tell you boss, just say, listen,
I am living with a guy I have to break
up with and I'm afraid he's going to get
violent. So he's at work today. Uh,
I'm going to act like I'm going to work
and I'm going to clear my shit out of
that. And I think you should be
fine. And then you guys fucking,
and he'd probably be like, you
want some fucking help? You know,
cause he's a good dude and then ball.
So He's maybe,
maybe he's trying to fuck you.
Wait a minute.
Maybe a boyfriend's actually make
it a good point. No, I'm kidding.
Go in there and I would just clear
all your fucking shit out and uh,
I would fucking yeah.
And I would go live somewhere else.
Uh,
then I would have one last conversation
with this guy and I would change my cell
phone number. That's it. Eh,
uh, I dunno. Depending on
where the fuck you live,
maybe you can just, he won't be able to
find your butter. Yeah. This is just,
this is good.
This is the beginning.
This has the beginnings of someone
that's going to stalk you and possibly do
something fucking horrible.
Fuck this guy. All right.
I wish my wife was here to hear this God
damn email. She's always talking about,
you know, how fucking difficult
a person I am. You know,
I'm going to fucking print this email
out and put it on her side of the bed,
on the pillow.
I shouldn't be making jokes like this.
Yeah, I would get the fuck out of it. Uh,
and that's it. And I will, uh,
go find love with somebody that's
excited that she got a new job,
but you're going to be
participating and that a,
and let you wear shorts when it's
hot out. There you go. Everybody,
that's the podcast for this week.
Go fuck yourselves and I'll check it
on, uh, on Thursday.
Could we congratulations to the Ferrari
team for winning. The next one is,
I believe in Bahrain
or something like that,
and then they go to fucking
Singapore. All right, I'll see you.