Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Monday morning
podcast for Monday match 25th,
2019. What's going on? How are you? Um,
okay.
I'm going to fucking great
mood this Monday. 121 days.
No fucking bullshit.
On Wednesday I'll be a third through
the year already. 33 fucking percent.
33.5, whatever the fuck you
need. 33.3, three, three,
three, three, three, repeating,
uh, through the year. Just
like that. I feel great. You
know, it's funny, there was a,
okay,
we had some people over here yesterday.
Um,
I got some family in town so
we had a little cookout and uh,
you know, I needed some space on this
table so we can pre prep some shit.
So I took all my booze and I just,
I brought it out of the kitchen and I
just took it upstairs and put it in the
bedroom. And um, you know,
just so we have another area pregnant.
I was sent the biggest fucking kitchen,
right?
So fucking little prep area to cook.
So I fucking last night I'm
going to bed and my new thing,
I swear to God to go to sleep rather than
they have three fucking scotches like
I used to is I actually read,
I swear to God, I'm reading, I'm sober
and I'm reading how fucking funny.
So I uh,
okay.
I finished this book on Bob Cousy and
Bill Russell that I really enjoyed.
You know,
I'm going to give it to a buddy of
mine cause I don't like keeping books.
They're fucking heavy.
They take up space and I always act
like I'm going to go back and read them
again and I don't. So, um,
now I'm reading the, uh, the Beastie
boy book, a hardcover edition.
And as I was taking the plastic off,
I was thinking like,
is this going to affect the value
of it? It's just like, Bill,
when do you sell anything on
Ebay? Never. Alright, cool.
So I was reading that and all I had
was my little reading light on it,
my bed and I looked over and I
had a bottle of the Yippy Kai.
Yay. Right. The Bourbon,
absolutely delicious. Unopened.
Just sitting there and the way the
light was hitting it and the way it was
passing through the bottle, it literally
looked like it like, like a sunrise.
And I would be lying to you if I didn't
sort of sit up in bed and just look at
it for a hard 20 seconds.
MMM.
And I was just, Oh my God. Yeah. That
was like, that looks fucking delicious.
But I didn't, I, but I will tell you this,
I'm going to get it out
of the bedroom though.
I don't need to be staring at that
late at night, you know. Well,
I need to do is have a tough day and
then have those bottles looking at as me
sitting there like, Hey, bill
will help you take the edge off.
I had one drink every hundred 21
days. It's not a bad thing. You see?
Okay.
It's a little taste to tell that tasted,
um,
anyways, uh, plowing ahead. So, uh, I'm
going to get that shit out of there. Um,
I also buy ordered a one
of those pitch backs,
which I haven't had since I was
a kid. Well, you, you know, it's,
you throw the ball,
it's like basically just like a
net and it records Shay's back.
He can either get grounders fly balls
or can come back straight, you know,
like you actually have a
friend to play catch with.
And I've since my fucked up my shoulder,
which is feeling great now by the way.
MMM.
Since I messed it up, I've been, uh,
I switched to becoming a lefty and a, I
just want to get my, my mechanics down.
I'm almost fucking there where I
can get a little velocity on it.
So that's basic.
What I'm a basically living like a
God damn eight year old and I love it.
I absolutely love it. And uh, you know,
we're up at this week,
we're doing episode number eight of a f
is for family four Oh eight written by
yours truly. Um, I've
um, eight out of 10. So,
uh, this season as far as
like the heavy lifting,
the writing aspect of it is almost over.
Very thankful for that.
And um,
we've always had a killer writer,
writers' room and I think this
year is our strongest room.
It just keeps getting better and better.
I think that it helps that the
show's been on for as long as it has.
So writers come in the room now
just hitting the ground running.
They just understand the characters
and all that. So it's been, uh,
it's definitely been great.
So with that,
I have some new dates I have to announce.
Announce.
Uh,
let's see here.
I am going to be at the cosmopolitan
in Las Vegas on September 6th.
Um,
venue and ticket master Presale
is Thursday match 28th. Uh,
the public on sale is Friday, March
29th. I don't know what that means.
The public can't go to ticket master.
I'll presale Jesus Christ.
There's always somebody board before
group one isn't there? Um, anyways, yeah,
I'm going to be out there.
I'm going to do a Gig and
then the following day I'm
going to go see Elton John
because I know this is like his last tour.
A lot of people wrapping it up out there,
lot of people wrapping it up out
there on their fucking tours.
And, um, so I'm like, fuck, I gotta
go see these people before the date.
They just don't talk anymore. And then
they die. And I, I know you're thinking,
how many times can he get
suckered into that bill?
How many fucking times could somebody
say it's their last fucking tore?
And then they come back around
again? You know, listen,
I forgive it if you get into
some sort of tax trouble.
MMM.
You know what I mean?
Fucking taxes.
Jesus Christ Jesus that I
start a shitstorm on fucking
read it when I was about
the,
uh,
that taxing people,
70% money north of $10 million.
And I am passionately against that.
I don't make north of $10 million,
but I also know how taxes work.
All right?
So they'll create that and then a few
years later they are going to be like,
well, people who make eight
to 10 should play this.
People who make six to
eight should pay this,
and it's just going to trickle all
the fucking way down. Um, yeah,
to 70% tax.
There's no justification for it on any
level that is absolute fucking rape.
MMM.
And people who were saying that,
uh,
that $20 trillion that is in offshore
accounts is a complete separate issue,
isn't I?
Completely disagree.
That's basically like you have a house
and the foundation is cracked and you're
worried that the house is going to fall
into the front yard and you're sitting
there going, we need to raise
money to paint the fucking
thing. And it's like, no,
dude, we need to fix the foundation.
And you like, that's a separate issue.
Technically, I guess it is a
separate issue, but it's like it's,
it's a more important issue.
You're going to paint some that's going
to fall down on it's fucking face.
All right.
If you're going to sit there and ignore
that and you're going to ignore the fact
that corporations are dictating our
foreign policy and have bankrupted this
country, this country is fucking bank
truck right now. And they're not bankrupt.
We're not bankrupt because people who
make $10 million or more are not paying
70% taxes.
We're fucking bankrupt because we're
spending $1 billion over $1 billion a
fucking month fighting some shit
that we could actually solve here.
We could just convert to fucking solar
power if oil companies didn't own the
politicians, you could convert
to that. Give the solar power,
give the fucking sun to the oil companies
so they can still have their eyes wide
shut fucking parties.
And I'm not saying solar powers cleaner,
it doesn't fucking fuck up the ocean
when you throw the big fucking things in
there or whatever.
I'm not saying that,
but I'm just saying it would
solve the Middle East problem
because all of that fucking terrorism
is funded with oil money and nobody uses
more of it than us. So let's just
switch over. I know it's a, it's a,
it's a fucking, not an
easy endeavor, but do it.
Let fucking Ilan mucks puts his little
fucking glow sticks in the Goddamn road.
We'll do that.
Not for a cleaner earth,
just to get us the fuck out of there.
Cause right now they have a saw walking
around like zombies going and I support
the to support [inaudible]
support the troops, right?
Who does it support the fucking home team.
But they take it to the point where you
can't question where you're sending the
troops and for how fucking long and
you can't even bring up like, hey guys,
we're fucking bankrupt.
This isn't working.
Separate issue.
Let's fucking rape the guy
that started dollar shave club.
That's the solution and let me guess,
let me guess.
These are the tax dollars
that's are actually going to
make it to public schools.
These are the tax dollars that are
going to pay for nationwide healthcare.
These are the tax dollars.
They're going to fucking take over our
food supply again. So it's not peak.
You know,
little girls aren't getting their period
of 10 years old because of all the
fucking hormones in it.
Okay.
Like you're going to sit there,
you want to put money on the,
this is the tax dollars. It's
going to be spent, right.
That these fucking assholes
correct piece of shit.
Politicians aren't going to
steal the fuck outta here,
dude.
This people in this country,
you make an 80 to $100 million
that are paying 0% taxes,
0% taxes. Go look up apple. I
got an apple laptop right here,
sitting right in front of me.
Go look up how they successfully avoided
paying 50 billion in American taxes.
Hey, gay guys, separate
issue, separate fucking issue.
All these corporations making money hand
over fucking fist and as such greedy
fucking conch.
They won't pay dollar
number one on $50 billion.
Oh yeah, no, no, no. Fuck that. Fuck that.
Let's go after fucking individual
Americans who had the balls to go after a
fucking look.
Let's just look at standup comedians.
I W I would if somebody
told me the percentage.
I can't imagine the percentage
that actually make it, you know?
And I was that guy in my mid to late
30 sitting on a fucking futon. No wife,
no kids,
okay.
In a fucking studio apartment.
Sit knowing that I'm
in a young man's game.
Okay,
going, what? Where the fuck does this
go do if I don't fucking make it?
Okay,
you know, I'm going to end
up on fucking cruise ships.
They might 50s and 60s
fighting every night to not throw
myself over the fucking railing,
all right? And I had the balls
to stay in it, but because I did,
you're now going to fucking
punish me and demonize, you know,
and I'm not saying I don't make that
money, but I know how this game works.
That is going to start at
10 and then there's going to
fucking work its way down.
And then what you're going to
have as my voice is cracking.
What you're going to have
is a literally a wall.
Yeah.
Between ridiculously unbelievably fucking
rich people who are paying no fucking
money in taxes.
And then you're going to push the
rest of everybody else backed down.
And that was all fighting with one another
with all of these fucking people who
sent me emails,
who are just saying they think never
heard me be so greedy like I'm breathing.
How fucking funny is that? I'm
breathing with what? My money.
Okay?
The money that I earned, I'm fucking
greedy with that. And you who?
It isn't your fucking money,
uh,
telling me to give it to you
and I'm the fucking greedy one.
And meanwhile,
you're going to completely ignore this
other subset of people who are paying
nobody to fucking taxes and tell me
that that's a separate fucking issue.
Okay?
I'm not the guy who was poisoned
the fucking food supply.
I'm not the one who's pouring
shit into our drinking water.
Okay?
I'm not the one who runs a company
that makes 50 billion fucking dollars.
And I got lawyers,
a team of fucking lawyers figuring
out how I can pay $0 million.
Okay?
Okay.
I don't have a fucking sweat shop where
people are trying to jump to that death
and rather than pay a more fucking money,
I put nets outside of the fucking factory.
So they just land in that and when I can
yank him out of the net and stick them
back at their fucking workstation,
okay,
I'm not the guy doing that.
But you're going to sit there and tell
me that that's a separate fucking issue.
Yeah.
Is it a separate issue or is it
just more difficult to police?
So you're going to go
for the fucking lay up.
Yeah.
Unfucking believable.
It's a separate issue.
I'll sit there all day and listen to
your fucking point until you say it's a
separate issue.
Okay?
Pay Taxes and paying your fair share is,
is fucking straight across the board.
This same issue.
And if you're going to go after people
who were already paying more than 50%
taxes on their fucking income,
which is fucking criminal in my world,
that the person who does the
job has to give away more.
Okay?
Then they made they get to keep less
than what they fucking made and they did
the fucking job. And you're going to
sit there and tell me that. That's fair.
The Fuck Outta here.
Okay.
I'll never agree with that,
but I will read your fucking emails.
All of these fucking politicians are all
in these fucking people's back pockets.
Okay?
Don't fucking believe these Goddamn
fucking people who come along and say,
I like Trump. I'm going to, I'm
going to clean up the swell.
I'm going to drain the swamp.
He hasn't taken a fucking,
he hasn't taken a Dixie Cup worth
of water out of that fucking swamp.
Okay.
All right. Cause this is what we
all want to fucking to ignore,
to really change then you would have to
have an all out fucking revolution and
there would have to be bloodshed and
the only people that really have the
ability to do it would be
those lunatics and blackwater.
They would be the only guys
who'd be able to do it.
And all you have to do is cross your
fingers and pray that they're decent
fucking human beings because they
actually have the weaponry to pull it off.
Other than that,
all you're going to do is fucking
go after innocent fucking people,
which is what you guys are. Uh,
some of you are fucking advocating
while you ignore the fucking 9,000 pound
gorilla in the room who's paying $0
million in taxes. All right, I'm done
until I read it more later. Rock.
Did you guys watch any of the,
um,
I think someone who makes 50 grand
a year should be paying 59% taxes.
Okay.
MMM.
All right.
Did you guys watch it?
Did you guys watch the Duke for
Central Florida game? Oh my God.
What a fucking heartbreak of that was.
I didn't know what to do cause I love
Duke, but I also root for an underdog.
And uh,
it was June the end of that game.
It was like the basketball
gods just chose fucking Duke.
You know, that alley. I don't know if
it would look like it was mistimed.
I don't know what.
And then the fucking
Duke misses it and then gets the fucking
rebound and then the shot in the end
and the tip and just didn't, just
didn't want to fucking go in. Um,
you know, I'll tell you right
now, if you're a fucking
NBA fan, you're missing out.
You're missing out in what's left of
college basketball because there's so many
one and done.
It's just a pleasure to watch
that level of talent and they're
actually listening to their coach.
Okay.
Because that's just what's
missing in the fucking NBA.
This fucking shit where
it's just like these guys,
they make so much fucking money that,
that they, they feel like they, they
don't have to listen to their coach.
Yeah.
I just don't know. I'm not
saying all of it, but just,
it just blows my fucking mind.
It's like you're a platoon and that's
the general and he's coming in with the
fight plan and you're like, ah Nah,
Nah, we're just going to Improv this.
Okay,
we're just going to go, we're all going
to go in there and just start open fire,
you know, in the same general
fucking direction. Okay.
Yeah.
I just feel like when you do that,
that's when a team that on paper isn't
as good as you can come in and you're
open yourself up to getting beat.
That's what it is, man. That is, that is,
that is how the NBA game is played. Now.
What is the individual fucking game?
It's the,
and one influence on the game,
which I'm not 100% against that level
of fucking creativity in one on one and
all that type of shit.
But like,
you know when you have like a coach just
sitting there with his fucking thumbs
up his ass,
cause he can only talk to the
lower fucking 70% of the team.
You know what I mean?
It's almost like those
superstars are like apple, right?
Don't pay their taxes.
They don't want it.
They think they think they're
above being coached. Um,
anyways,
everything's going to go back to that.
I've been paying attention
to the premier league.
Liverpool is still two points ahead,
but I looked up the schedule this time
cause I thought that they were in the
lead.
It's just they've played more games.
They have nine games left and
Man City has 11 games left.
And as far as I can tell,
none of them really have that much
challenging games left other than man city
plays, man United. That could be
the fly in the ointment game there.
So I'll try to pay attention.
I'll,
I'll watch that game because I figured
that's going to be a big one. Um,
and then I'm going to be
watching the Bruins versus
Tampa Bay lightening tonight.
That's going to be my a, that's
going to be my little fucking, uh,
my little evening tonight. And uh,
I mentioned, uh, last week I went,
I went to the premiere, that
Motley Crue movie, the dirt. Uh,
definitely check it out just to fucking,
I, I really loved the movie. Uh,
didn't pull any punches and uh,
I actually saw some woman
in the La Times was,
was given one of the band
members shit going like,
how could you put a movie out post me too.
How could you put a movie out like this?
And the dude was like,
well, I mean it happened. You
want us to rewrite history?
It was like the perfect fucking answer.
And if you watch it,
what's so fucked up is it's,
it's all consensual sex.
It's just a bunch of
people over indulging.
So have we gotten literally
to this point that,
that a bunch of guys playing in a band
who have a bunch of groupies who want to
fuck the shit out of him so
they do is like a bad fuck. Is,
is like somehow like that,
that there was something wrong there.
I mean, you could say there was
something wrong as far as like a,
okay,
what everybody was doing their,
do you want to get into some sort of
religious debate about morals leave if you
want to get out of religion and just
talk about the emptiness of living a life
like that,
how it's exciting in the beginning,
but then afterwards is a
profound loneliness to living
a life like that for both
people that Groupie End,
the fucking rock star.
I can have that fucking
conversation with you,
but I don't understand how that fucking,
you know,
I thought me too was you took your dick
out at work and just on a plant, right?
That was in that world,
right?
It wasn't played some songs and chicks
in the crowd is showing that tidies to
you.
Then afterwards you bang them.
I didn't think that that that
fell under that fucking umbrella
does meet to basically also get
to the point of like, you know,
the dead men can't go
out and enjoy themselves.
Okay.
If they're out there and they,
if you play in a band,
it's going to its rated pussy,
you know? That's going to happen.
This is actually people
that got into bands
just for the chicks,
and all of a sudden they're fucking,
they're band somehow fucking made it
and they're standing up there without,
in that passion is pussy.
Okay.
Look at Gene Simmons.
I've never heard that guy
talk passionately about music.
He just talks passionately about women,
any so obsessed with it.
He literally says Dumb Shit.
Like anybody who says they got dual bed
for the music is a fucking liar that got
in it for the pussy. I mean, it,
that's how it that far down
the fucking road that guy is,
if everybody doesn't share my opinion,
okay,
then, then, uh, they're fucking
lying. Um, anyways. Yeah, it was,
it was 30,
40 fucking years ago.
And uh, you know, I dunno.
Motley Crue did what a lot of bands did
and they made a fucking movie about it.
And even then, it's sort of like,
they kind of glossed over a lot of it.
So I don't, I don't understand
what the fucking problem is.
There's always somebody,
now let's get some sort of problems.
Don't she think that that
movie about seagulls,
Josie, does it misses the
mark about the main issue,
the main issue being the issue
that am I'm concerned with.
Okay.
By the way,
my favorite thing right now
on the Internet
is crystally is, uh, that
thing he did that thing,
he's trying to start jokingly
or not called the unfollowing
follow Chris Delea on
Instagram and scroll through.
I'm sure he's made a couple
videos since his last one.
He did this fucking thing I,
and I was talking about,
I think I've just talked about this,
but I just want to promote it
again because I think it's a,
like all those Instagram models,
you know?
Okay.
It goes, hey, he goes,
make no mistake if you're on Instagram
and you're taking pictures of your booty
and you Teddy's, yeah. Okay.
And he literally breaks it down to all
of this shit that I didn't even know
exist that I guess, you know, hot
chicks biting into a giant sandwich,
like looking up in the air, trying to be,
try to be cute or something like that.
And it's like, uh, I don't know.
He's just saying to unfollow them,
which is fucking funny to me
because I'm not in that world at all.
But I was talking to younger
comics about this and I, you know,
they run into these people I guess,
and they were saying like, yeah,
they actually come up to you
and have like an attitude.
Like they're doing something
now they are doing something.
They are going to the gym,
they are keeping themselves in shape
and God bless him in an entrepreneurial
way. I respect the fact that
they're building a brand here.
Um,
but okay,
I don't,
uh,
I don't coach sign on then walking
around acting like an egotistical maniac.
If that's what the fuck that dude,
I don't fucking know.
There's so much shit on there.
That's fucking hilarious.
I saw it. Somebody made,
made a post where they would talk when
it was women's Day and of course they
were like, you know, fuck that. It should
be women's Day every day of the year.
Which is hilarious because it's just like,
and when would it be guys day then?
Does that seem fair to you?
And the person like took like a fucking
picture and it's like a sexy picture.
Like they couldn't just make their,
their statement.
They also had to show off their fucking,
you know,
they're flat stomach and their fucking
ass and stuff. It's just like, it's like,
what, what are you,
what are we doing here?
It's like if that exact picture,
if a guy used it to sell like,
uh,
like it out some Coca Cola,
it'd be like objectifying women,
Shell Jody Dki Blake needs to
change. But then, you know, I dunno,
but then you can't do it if it's you
doing it to yourself selling woman's Day.
I don't know. I don't, I don't
get out of fucking math works,
but you know something I
was never good at math.
Yeah.
All I can tell you this is,
I don't think Lebron James should have
to give away 70% of his money over $10
million. I don't, I don't, I think he's
already fucking paying well over 50,
Tom Brady, all of these fucking
people and I think you know something.
I think you paying your
fair share at that point.
How much more fucking money do you want
to take from these fucking people while
ignoring people who are
paying no money in taxes.
Why? Ignoring companies that are
leading us off into war that has no end,
that bankrupts the country.
That's a separate issue.
Oh, Jesus. All right, let me
read some advertising here. Hey,
my bookie, I look for
you doing all right. Um,
brackets first round upsets the
final four march madness is here,
right there on your television screen.
It's time to bet with the
best at my bookie. Hey,
would you rather sit at your office
desk or call out sick and binge on Ncaa
Tournament Games and junk food? Like
that's okay. Or let's see. Would you,
would you rather s I am the worst.
Would you rather sit at your office
desk or call out sick and binge on NCA
tournament games and junk
food? Like that's even a
choice. I love how these guys,
they're not even trying to hide how
to generate the year gamble on sports.
It don't go to work.
Don't even have an apple
eat some Fritos anyways.
Sometimes it feels good to be bad.
It's the balance of life,
especially when it's
with someone you trust.
And if you're looking for a
place to get in on the action,
you can trust my bookie.
They'd been in business for years
and they're growing like wow. Fat.
The best part is they pay out fast.
So when you call that 12
over five upset this year,
make sure to celebrate. You'll
be pocketing cold, hard cash, uh,
core talking points.
March madness is the most exciting
action packed sporting event of the year.
Even grandmothers fill out brackets
to place your bets with Mike bookie.
Now before you miss out my bag,
my book,
you will match your
deposit with the 50% bonus.
Use Promo Code Burr to activate
the offer. Visit my bookie. Dot.
Agee today you play, you win. You
get paid only at my bookie. Dot.
A g. All right. Oh look who's here.
Oh,
zip.
But Gouda. Hiring used
to be hard. Oh my God,
it's so difficult. You know,
writing where? Hiring on a sign,
sticking it in a window,
hoping that dream person
walked by and they need a job.
It ain't like that anymore.
All right. With Ziprecruiter,
ZipRecruiter's sends you,
boy sends your job to over 100
of the web's leading job boards,
but they don't stop there with their
powerful matching technologies. Zip.
Yeah,
good scans,
thousands of job resumes
to find out people with the
right experience and invite
them to apply to your job.
As applications come in,
zip recruiter analyzes each one and spots
lights the top candidates so you never
miss a great match.
Zip [inaudible] is so effective that
80% of employers who post on Zip,
okay.
Get a quality candidate through the site
within the first day and right now my
listeners can try ZipRecruiter for
free at the exclusive website address,
ziprecruiter.com/burr that's zip
recruiter.com/burr one more time.
Zip
gretta.com/burns zip,
r.
E. C. R. U. I. T. E. R.
The smartest way to hire.
Oh Geez. We've got a lot today.
What do we got here? What do we,
what do we have here? Uh, you know
what, I got one, two, three left,
so I'm going to break them up.
I'll read the third one here.
We'll get over the hump. This
is Wednesday here. Simply safe.
Hi fellows.
Here's something interesting.
Studies show that security
systems deter burglars.
It's a fact, but there's still a
burglary every eight seconds in America.
Um, how well think about
it. Think about it.
Do burglaries give up just because
somehow swi houses have security systems?
Of course not. They just find
a house that isn't protected.
That's why securing your home is
truly necessary. So wait a minute.
So if everybody ends up getting a security
system that these guys are going to
have to up their game like a
virus because of, uh, you know,
if you don't kill the virus,
you just keep using the medicine.
They get immune to it.
Okay,
we have to kill the virus.
so simply safe, what I would be doing
if I was them, I would eventually,
I would come with up
with a security system.
Okay.
No, it only detours the
intruder. It also kills them.
Okay.
All right.
But that's a different read.
Simply save senses will protect every
point of access to your home doors,
windows, garage, you name it.
If a burglary even tries to
break in and ear shattering side
it, maybe it was old cy, five things
where they would shoot like a sound rate.
It's somebody they would just
grab both their residents be like
drop to their knees. Uh, Jesus Christ.
I just picture the burglar
dressed like Captain Kirk. Uh,
best of balls simply saves
24. You wouldn't want him
in, is he a fucking house?
He tried to bang your wife first
of all. Simply see, saves 24,
seven monitoring is just 1499 a month
and they'll never lock you in a longterm
contract.
More than 3 million people already know.
It feels good to feel
less with simply safe.
So go with the only home
security system you can trust.
Simply safe by going to
simply say bird.com B u r r.
Go today and get free shipping
and a 60 day money back guarantee.
That's simply safe.
bird.com for home security.
S I. M p. L. I. S. A. F. E. Okay.
bird.com. All right, let's plow ahead.
Alright. Cubans role
too tight. Hey, Billy,
suction face.
Uh,
if you're Cubans turn your face
purple when you smoke them,
then they are probably counterfeit.
I know people tell me that but you know
something, I have to be honest with you.
I get a lot of Dominicans,
I get a lot of Nicaraguans and
I run into this same problem.
Not the same problem with the Cubans.
So if somebody making fake
Nicaraguans and Dominican's anyways,
the demand for Cuban cigars far,
far outweighs the availability.
Um, and here's another
thing too sir. I fucking,
I've smoked him in different countries
and I've had run into the same problem.
Maybe you're saying the worldwide demand,
which you're probably right so they are
often faked in nearly indistinguishable
from the real deal.
Even for the train I,
it's only when you start smoking
them that it's noticeable.
Rolling a good cigar is a true art
which is not mastered by counterfeiters
looking for a quick buck.
The demand for Dominican's for example
is a lot lower and they are not con and
they are not considered
extremely rare or valuable.
They are rarely counterfeit
greetings from Ghent,
Belgium and as per usual go fuck
yourself. Well he is in Belgium, so, yeah.
Yeah.
I gotta be honest with you,
I'm kind of getting away from
the Cubans because they're,
they're really expensive. And, um,
I remember one time
when I was in Australia,
I must've got the real deal because I
bought these cohibas and when I came back
they, they were, they were incredible.
Okay.
Like they were a cigar that
as you were lighting it,
like the first couple of puffs
you went, oh my God. Oh my God.
That's believing what you do. Your
whole body fucking relaxes. And it's,
it's an amazing, having said
that, I would like to quit those.
That might be the next thing
that I want to do. And I am, um,
I am,
I would like to just replace all my vices
with something a little more healthy
and then eventually come back
to a vice that isn't a bad vice.
Yeah.
What's your vice,
you know,
I guess I think I read
too much in bad lighting.
I have to stop. I know I'm so
bad. I need to go to meetings.
Like I'd love to be that
fucking person, you know? Um,
so eventually I think I'm gonna
like get down to maybe like three,
four cigars a year, the Rose
Bowl, the big college game,
my birthday, and then something
around Christmas. And um,
okay.
Just sort of leave it at that because
I am really getting into living like a
fucking nerd.
MMM.
You know, it's underrated
or overrated, underrated.
I'll tell you underrated reading a great
book at night to make you sleepy rather
than staring at a screen.
And A,
I've kind of realized that one of my vices
is the amount of time that I spend on
my phone
and um,
I want to get used to like not being,
uh,
you know,
like I'll be in the car and I just find
myself going over and picking it up like,
like a fucking child with,
with its little favorite teddy bear and
fucking sitting there looking at the God
damn screen and it's like I'm driving,
scrolling, trying to find a song.
MMM.
So I think what I'm going to just,
okay,
I tried to put it in airplane mode,
but then most of my songs
are on the fucking cloud.
And then I lose all my God damn music.
So now what I'm gonna do is I'm going
to have a playlist, download those,
you know,
10 songs or whatever,
and then put it on airplane mode and
then literally take the thing and fucking
throw it in the back seat.
Um,
I would like to do that and um,
okay.
But I'll tell you man, underrated.
Fucking reading back into it.
And,
uh,
and I told you,
I had this woman telling me that I
wasn't going to be able to learn French,
saw back to the flash cards
and stuff. And, uh, I got a
couple of friends of mine,
I can French. So we only text each
other strictly in French. And I'm not,
I'm really starting to learn this shit.
I can't speak it well,
but I can read it really well now, or
at least to another level. And it's,
uh, I mean, I can, I can fucking be doing
that rather than slowly killing myself.
And killing brain cells and shit. And, um,
okay.
I Dunno man. I think, uh, you know,
like I had that cookout yesterday and
there was a bunch of people over and shit
and I was stoned, fucking sober.
So then, you know, it was,
I'm walking around and then I run
into my kid, hey, how you doing?
I'm not like buzzed.
Yeah,
they, there's a low point in
your fucking life, you know,
having a little buzz going, then you
see your fucking kid. It's just like,
what am I doing?
What if something happens right now and
I need to react and I'm a little buzzed
right now. I just can't fucking do
it anymore. Then the guilt of it,
I can't handle it. So, um, anyways,
I agree with you sir. I like the, uh,
the Casa Magna's, the, uh,
I, I swear to God, I think
they're called calligraphy us,
like that fucking half a porno movie.
Um,
I liked the Aurora emeralds and um,
there's a couple of my father's cigars
that I really like, but, um, I don't know.
I'm going to be basically trying to
phase those fuckers up. All right.
Card Games and board games.
Um,
hey bill catching up on the podcasts. I
heard you had fun playing cards. Yeah,
I loved it. Played with my
mom. It was awesome. Uh, you
should check out the word.
Okay.
Um,
the world of card games and board games.
There's a regular popular
game called five crowns.
That's a rummy style game. That is fun.
Also, board games have come a long way.
I feel like you may have been a
risk guy. I was, I loved that game.
Taking over the world. Uh, though
I don't recall you saying it.
Oh, I love that fucking game. Uh,
there are a great strategy games
out there that are fun to play with.
Friends and cigars.
Uh,
people love settlers of Catan or Catan.
Again,
that is probably sold.
Okay.
Thriller like numbers in
the tabletop game world.
I'm going to check that out. Hey,
you know what? I missed? I lost.
Um,
let me see if I that
meditation fucking music.
I lost it. Uh, you fucking asshole bill.
Okay.
I was really looking forward to that shit.
God Damn.
I'll be able to find it.
I guess it's just that music that goes
on for like fucking three hours or I can
just go back and listen to my old pod.
You know?
Is is amazing here. I don't, I
don't even know how to fuck. Sorry.
I just unplug something.
I don't know if you know how to
fucking listen to my own podcast.
How pathetic is that?
Um,
okay.
All right. I'll definitely
be checking these things out.
He says there's a game called secret.
Okay.
That's pretty involved. I'm not sure
you'd have time in your schedule,
but it's worth looking at. Seek.
There's a game called secret Hitler
object.
Find the person in the game who's had,
who's starting the final solution again.
Um,
even the classics are fun to revisit.
Monopoly life, et cetera. Yeah,
I love that stuff.
And my kid gets a little bit bigger.
I want to start playing those games.
Have a game night.
We already have the night where we go out.
This will kill my standup career game
that I can't, I can't do that Gig.
I have game night. I can't do that
Gig. I have to go out for 'em.
Okay.
I you have to go out, take my family
out for dinner. Hey, by the way,
anybody who lives in La and you know
some really good mom and pop places,
it doesn't have to be healthy or
anything. What in the fuck is that? Oh,
it's a cat. Jesus Christ.
I thought it was a raccoon.
I just saw a fucking cat
just came up in the fucking
window through the blinds.
Who's was like looking in like
it was going to do something.
Okay.
Cat's a creepy man. They just, they just
are man. They just always think they,
they think too much.
You look at a dog, it's,
it does not fucking thinking about
anything. Catch just had that fucking,
that they're plotting,
you know,
very female energy.
You have,
you just sit next to your girlfriend
and you just feel them thinking,
you're like, fuck, here we go.
Here we go. What's wrong now?
What the fuck is wrong now?
Or at girlfriend forcing me to go vegan.
Speaking of which,
I bet that guy fell toward thinking.
Okay.
Uh, first of all, before
we even get into this,
okay.
Uh, your girl could friend
cannot force you to do anything.
You need to fucking eat a steak
in front of her and say, listen,
you either love me or you don't.
I already know the solution to this.
All right.
Hey,
Billy,
longtime listener and first time I've
written in as I desperately need some
advice. My girl and I had been together
for about eight months. She's awesome.
And I get laid about three
times a week. All right. Um,
weird sentence.
Uh,
things have gradually gotten more
serious and we now spend most evenings
together eating dinner even though we
don't stay over with each other every
night. Well, that's good. That's healthy.
That you'd still have a
little bitty independence.
We mostly eat dinner at her place,
so she does the grocery shopping and
she's also Vegan, which isn't bad dude.
She's, you know, provided
she's buying, you know,
I guess organic.
How do you even tell if it's organic?
Because I've heard from a lot of people
then this might come from the meat
industry. I've no idea. But I've heard
from a lot of people that, you know,
the amount of pesticides they spray on
sometimes actually eating some iceberg
lettuce might be more for you than
eating a fucking pig. Um, who knows.
Okay.
Also,
she's a Vegan.
She recently decided that she
was not going to buy meat for me.
So it's easy to cook. Plus it's
better for the environment and health.
Basically. All the fucking arguments
vegans use against us. Carnivores. Yeah.
All the cows farting it up into
the atmosphere. I do love me,
but also love this girl.
It would honestly go Vegan for,
should I just be done with it and cut,
cut it meat. Oh, see,
I think you might say cut out meat or
am I setting setting the tone for the
whole relationship to get treated like
a little bitch. Appreciate your advice.
All right. I like that you're
asking these questions, sir.
So you're still in a healthy
place mentally. Ah, that's
what I would say to her.
Just be like,
listen.
MMM.
I'm willing to do this for us,
but I'm also,
I would be lying to you if I wasn't
nervous that I was setting a tone that,
you know, if say you don't like
March madness that I'm Greg,
I'm eventually going to stop watching it.
So you gotta do it in a
funnier way than that.
Okay.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I don't think going Vegan if the person
knows what the fuck they're doing,
cause there's a lot of fat
vegetarians out there, um,
who are eating chips and
cheese made from potatoes. Um,
okay.
But the, you know, they're not
necessarily healthy, you know,
when the carbon it up.
Um,
I know there's a lot of fake meat and
shit out there now. There's a lot of,
there's a lot of ways to go.
MMM.
I am not nearly it read enough on this
subject to give you any sort of advice as
to which way to go.
But I think your concern is correct.
MMM.
I would just go slow. I would
just say, all right, look,
if you just want to cook Vegan here
and then I would just, which isn't bad,
it's not bad to take a break from it,
I wouldn't think.
MMM.
I Dunno, I, but I also
know that it to really do
okay.
Do the Vegan thing correctly.
Okay.
I actually, you know something
to be a mediator and, and
and, and just eat up too.
Just really eat well.
Is he borderline need a
fucking degree in something.
First of all,
you got to be half a fucking private eye
to try and figure out where the organic
shit is because everything now is free
range. Everything is fucking Oregon.
The amount of chickens that
they say a fucking free range,
but there's still those fucking Arnold
Schwartzenegger roid it up fucking
chickens. Cause I remember when I
watched a, that, that documentary, um,
I forgot what the fuck it was
called. Uh, not you are what you eat.
Okay.
Something about food. And I
saw, I was like, man, fuck this.
I got to go find an organic chicken dude.
I mean,
I had to go to a farmer's market and then
I had to sift through all the bullshit
there and get people to honestly
tell me this guy finally,
like he had the Cuban three actual real
Cubans in the back. And when he held up,
when he showed me a what a real chicken
looks like, it looked, I was like,
is that what does that a fucking
pigeon? It's like, no, that's, that's,
that's what they're supposed to look like.
It looked like a player,
a football player in the 1930s versus
one in the fucking eighties and nineties
when they were fucking all roid it up.
Not linkedin does not doing roids
now. Um, Oh, speaking of which, uh,
football players,
uh,
congratulations to rob Gronkowski
going out as a champion.
Thank you so much for all your fucking
everything you did over the years playing
for the Patriots.
And I actually think it's a great move.
Um, especially when you see, you know,
the results of playing
the game and all that.
I think he's leaving at a perfect time.
He's got his money.
MMM.
He was really taken a lot of
hits basically below the waist,
which was the only way to get them down.
And they would just chop
and his fucking legs down.
And he was probably sick of going into
surgeries and being hurt and all of that.
And just the fact that the last game he
played, he made the biggest fucking play,
that big catch that got
us to touch down that uh,
put us over the top and
one s our six super bowl.
Um,
okay.
Yeah. Hall of fame, New England
Patriot without a doubt. I don't know,
you know, I don't collect football cards
anymore, so I don't know what his, uh,
his numbers are.
But I got a good feeling about the actual
pro football hall of fame in Canton.
So, and I also did a roast with them one
time and he was such a fucking cool guy.
And,
uh,
there's a lot of people out there that
think he's his big dumb guy and he isn't.
I remember I was talking to him about,
MMM,
we've talking about going to concerts
and he was saying how much he fucking
hated how people will sit in,
they're videoing their experience rather
than having the experience he's going
like, it's like you're
there, enjoy the experience.
And I remember thinking in that going,
I wish people could hear this
fucking conversation. So, you know,
cause they always just think, they always
think that about big fucking people,
that they're fucking dumb. He was not, he
was not. And he did great on the roast.
Uh, Bandy was funny, you know. Anyways,
so plowing ahead here, I would, um,
you know, I would use this thing as
an opportunity to basically, yeah.
Set some boundaries in your relationship
in a funny way, and just be like,
all right, you know what, I'll
be beacon when I'm at your house.
Okay.
And if, um, you know, if she's pushing
you to become Vegan and your house,
just be like, you know, I, I
really enjoy a steak. I really do.
And, um, I'm going to keep eating it.
And if you're going to break up
with me over a pork chop, then, uh,
they're probably really wasn't love
here in the first place. Um, meanwhile,
you know, read up on fucking
nutrition. I mean, I'm,
I'm giving you advice
that I should be taken.
I should read up on it too because I've
been really well over the last year and
now that I've, uh, I should
say since July and I'm,
I had so many put together a diet for me
and I pretty much loosely use that with
some of my older bad habits. I'm
not going to lie to you and, um,
and just cutting out the booze,
it's been really easy to sort of maintain,
uh,
a decent body weight is probably the
smartest thing that you could fucking do.
Learn how to defend yourself and
learn how to eat right. You know,
figure out why you fucked up so you
don't take it out on somebody else and go
out and go find a great person
and then
work on the relationship
like this person's doing
rather than bailing. Cause I,
I actually have a theory about
divorce where I think a lot of them,
they could have fixed it if they just
were working on it along the way.
And then you just start thinking like,
oh, this person's a fucking asshole.
And then he just had this
fantasy that you're going to
okay
meets it.
You just basically chasing that feeling
you had when you both met each other in
the beginning and you're just
never going to be brand new.
Okay.
You just have to accept that,
but you can get back to different levels
of emotional heights if you actually
work on it. Like the dumbest
thing ever. Just doing shit. Like,
you know what family dinner night and
everybody puts away their phones or
whatever and it's just you. Or if you're
single or whatever, you be not married,
you can go out to a movie and uh,
I'm telling you,
turn it off your phone is a fucking
huge thing. Um, that I've discovered,
especially if you get fucking massive
add like me. Okay. Where are we here?
Big Sugar.
Okay.
All right.
I can't tell if this is a place to go
skiing or this is more stuff about food.
Hey,
Billy Ball balls.
Last week or so you went off on one email
proposing a massive tax on the rich.
No, I didn't. No, I did not.
I went off on a massive
tax on honest Americans.
Yeah.
Okay.
This is not a tax on the rich.
This is a tax on people who are not smart
enough or corrupt enough to have their
money in offshore accounts.
That's what I went off on.
He said that I learned about how tax
dollars are feeding billions to sugar
industry.
The US government has subsidized the
domestic sugar industry so much that
domestic sugar prices are up to 50% more
than their international counterparts.
Separate issue.
Separate issue
the government does is by establishing
quotas that limit imports.
So now more domestic production means
that there is more farmland did take up by
sugar. Yeah. Which is people are
starting to say as a carcinogen.
Okay.
Um, there's another thing too, when
you cut sugar out of your diet,
like I've been having this
fucking almond butter.
I know big Hollywood fucking phony.
You have to apologize for
trying to eat right. Right. Uh,
it's like when I drove a Prius savage
dude, dude, but he fucking, you know,
saint all homophobic shit to me cause I
was cause you're just reminding people
that hey man,
the way we're doing this shit is steering
us into the fucking sun here. Um,
anyways,
uh,
and my wife had bought some peanut butter
for my daughter and it was just the
regular kind and I,
you know,
we ran out of almond butter
and I put some on some toast,
I bit into it and I have fortunately
such little amount of sugar, my diet.
Then I bit into it like I literally am
like my fucking my mouth Packard like
Jesus Christ, I had no idea how much
sugar is in fucking peanut butter.
It's insane. It's anyways, he goes,
if you are wondering why kids
are getting beards at 10,
then this might be why these companies
don't want to pay for real sugar.
So they just make another sweet poison
and call it sugar free. The volume.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The environmental impacts are also dire
with sugar beets causing worsening soil
quality and water pollution that
is much worse than other crops.
The worst part of all is is the insane
amount of money these bastards get like
one Florida farm families getting 150
to 250 million that comes out of the
taxpayers' pockets. Separate issue. Also,
the increased sugar prices may
companies in food processing,
you have to lay off 10,000 to 20,000
employees a year while sugar growers can
usually make up to $750,000 a year.
Sorry, 750 million a year.
No, seven 50,000 a year.
That doesn't make any sense. I think
you put the wrong number there. Um,
uh,
the American sugar alliance is one of
the most funded lobbying groups with a
handful of companies bringing in the mass
amounts of the 4 billion in subsidies.
The taxpayer's give.
I hope you found this
important and interesting and
has always go fuck yourself.
Yeah.
Handful of look at that is one of
the most funded lobbying groups.
Yep. Then where do you
think all that money goes?
Do you think it just goes to the
lobbying or do you think it goes into
politicians pet projects?
It's fucking ridiculous
how corrupt that is.
And you're going to go after the people
who create an APP or people who start
movement watches these, these,
these people are the fucking, yeah,
they had a fucking problem.
You can ignore all the corruptions.
So here's a guy here who's basically
going to fucking tear me a new asshole.
Yeah.
All right. And I love the
title. Why I stopped listening.
Okay?
And this is the classic baby.
That exists. Now you know you,
you know you, you don't, you,
you have a difference of opinion.
So you're going to stop listening.
You fucking child.
Okay?
As if my words somehow affected your life,
like I said,
that and then what the IRS
is actually going to be going after these
fucking people did not. All right. Why?
I stopped listening. Bill, I've
stopped listening to your pod.
What are you fucking eight years old?
I felt that I should tell you why.
[inaudible] much like a restaurant
who loses a loyal customer,
wants to know why, what
went wrong? You, you know,
you love how he's putting
those words in my mouth.
Like I give a fuck that an absolute
child isn't going to listen to my fucking
podcast. Uh, so no hard
feelings, but here it is.
You should like flip your hair right
now. Like d Schneider, is that his name?
The guy from twisted sister, when
he made that point, you know,
when he was in front of
Congress about the PMRC man. Um,
I have never heard a more selfish
mouth breathing uninformed money.
Grubbing can't speak in my entire life.
This is what I love.
I don't even mean I don't
make $10 million a year.
I don't make $10 million a year.
So I was actually defending people
whose tax money would actually go,
I guess to help me.
And somehow I'm money grubbing because
this person's so up the ass of their own
fucking point. They can't even listen
to what it is that I'm saying. He goes,
sometimes you say something halfway smart,
but it is surrounded.
He says my so much bullshit,
he's calling me dumb.
He didn't even hit spellcheck
by so much bullshit.
It makes me feel you stumbled into
saying it by accident. Yes sir.
Because no one could ever be as smart
as you like how a monkey banging on a
typewriter might somehow
type out Shakespeare.
I don't think a monkey
banging out a typewriter.
It might somehow type out Shakespeare.
I think what you meant meant to say is
that he might accidentally spell a word
correctly, like might
accidentally spelled the or act.
I don't think you meant Shakespeare.
All right. You know what I'm finding,
I think you wrote this in a
very high emotional state here.
So I'll cut you some slack. And
uh, I've always said I'm a moron.
Okay.
And even now that I'm reading,
I'm reading like the fucking Beastie boy
autobiography. I'm reading the fucking,
which actually is I'm finding
out, uh, is, is a history book,
um, on a certain genre of music that
I believe the kids called hip hop.
Um, all right. The biggest problem is you
cannot see beyond your own experience.
Making $10 million a year
is not my experience.
I've never made $10 million in a year.
Okay.
And this is most evident in your
recent diatribe about the 70% tax rate.
I Dunno. I like to think I get, you know.
Okay.
I don't always, but I like
to think, you know, I,
I try to at least listen to both sides
I guess. I guess I, I guess I don't,
in case your memory is
blinded your own rage.
Yeah.
What about your rage?
Let me go over some dumb ass
things that you said on Monday,
March 18th first of all,
sir,
you calling me a mouth breather and
you're saying that I have rage and you're
literally misspelling words and you're
so angry at me right now that you can't
present your opinion without
calling me names anyways.
You called people making
10 million plus a year,
regular guys who are deserving of empathy.
Sure.
Some are your,
what was me lament of these poor,
poor millionaires made my blood boil.
Exactly,
exactly. It. Look how
you just phrased that.
Yeah.
Luca, these poor, poor millionaires,
you're judging them and who they are
because of how much money they make,
and you're going to turn it into a Disney
movie where anybody who makes money is
fucking evil.
Makes my blood boil.
Fuck you. This guy literally just
said blinded by rage. Fuck you.
You implied that money
tax from millionaires goes
directly back to lazy cons
making less.
Okay.
I don't remember saying that. Maybe
I did. Maybe I did. All right.
You said it isn't fair that people being
honest with their income have to pay
this rate. Uh, while rich people
hide their incomes overseas.
You also said that tax money
is being wasted, wasted,
and then he just says
corrupt the bullshit. I agree
with both of these things.
These are separate problems
that also need to be fixed.
You're often being,
you're often being dumb bullshit like this
up.
What as if the government
can't do two things at once.
Okay.
Okay. I think with your fucking half
written email, calling me a moron,
ser.
Okay.
They're not going after these people.
They're not
okay.
Okay.
It's been deemed too difficult.
Okay. Because what they do is be,
I already explained this shit,
is how was it explained to me in layman's
term? You have a fucking company.
Yeah.
Okay. You have a bunch, a pile
of fucking money. So you crew.
So you fucking either incorporate,
okay,
in a a a different country or you,
you create a,
a fake,
phony fucking company in that country,
which bills you're legit company a
ridiculous amount of fucking money.
So then you're then able to show
that your company somehow lost money.
So now you don't have to pay any taxes,
but now your money is in this fake
company. So how do you get it right?
You'd be having in this
foreign fucking island, right?
Which is a different country.
You pay some people off there,
so let the money go there.
Then you start another company in a
different island and then they build that
company and you just keep going hopscotch
and through the fucking Caribbean or
wherever the fuck this shit goes down.
All right?
And then the last company goes back
to you and gives you like 50 million,
$100 million in the form of alone,
which is untakeable and then you're
allegedly going to pay it back,
which you don't.
And when you don't,
that phony fucking
company forgives the loan.
That's the base in Layman's terms.
That's the way it was explained to me.
And the problem is, is that with each one
of those islands that it goes through,
it's, it's a whole new fucking,
it's a different country,
a different government, and you have
to go through a mountain of red tape.
So they have seven,
10 14 of these fucking companies,
all pink Pong and all through the
fucking islands. And it just, it just,
it's too difficult.
It's too difficult.
And then what you have is honest fucking
people who took a fucking chance.
Okay. And risk basically sleeping
alone on a fucking futon with no wife,
no fucking family maxed out there.
Fucking credit cards.
And most of those people lose.
And then you're going to come in to take,
there's no way you can present
an argument or $70 million,
70% paying taxes on one fucking dollar,
70% you cannot set that fucking
precedent by the government, okay?
Considering they are complete
corrupt pieces of shit.
A standup comedian is not
a corrupt piece of shit,
okay?
He's not looking at the other way with
all that shit that person just said about
sugar. These are not separate issues.
Once you have is a broken fucking system,
which is now going to take,
put duct tape on the fucking problem
and go after innocent fucking people and
for you to call me a moron because you
just sit there and you go, oh, these poor,
poor millionaires.
If somebody is fucking honest,
they shouldn't have to fucking pay for it.
Look at the cleanse.
Look at the bushes. Look at
the Obamas. Look at them.
Look how fucking corrupt they are.
The most they ever made was foreign of
fucking 500 fucking grand being president
of the United States and they're all worth
millions and millions and millions of
does go look. Go. Look at who they
fucking give this speech to go look.
Cause people who Obama's first two
fucking speeches were to like two of the
biggest fucking banks that
were behind the 2008 scandal
and they're going up vacuuming
up all that fucking money
is fucking Michelle Obama has the fucking
balls to put out an inspirational book
on how to be a better fucking person and
make your dreams come true is she has
all that corporate money fucking fallen
out from between her fucking Teddy's get
the fuck outta here. What
I want to, I want you to,
if you still listening what you,
I know you are.
Okay.
What a poor, poor millionaires. Well
why do you, why you judging somebody?
Cause they fucking had the balls to put
their entire future on the fucking three
zillion to one dog with the limp
at the back of the fucking race.
And the thing came in.
So now they have to give away 70%
of their money north of $10 million.
Listen, if you're saying that
that's what the number is,
and everybody's going to pay 70% north,
you know,
north of $10 million, which
once again, I'm not making,
so I'm literally arguing for
fucking people that I'm not okay.
But I plan on making more than that and
I'm in a country that allows me to do it.
Thank Christ.
All right?
And I hope that you fucking do it someday.
And it's not my fucking fault that you
don't have to fucking balls or an idea or
the charisma or whatever the fuck
you need to get to that level.
I haven't had it yet, but I'm not
going to just because I haven't,
I'm not going to fucking punish these
other fucking people. And it's the thing,
if every motherfucker in this country,
okay,
making north of $10 million
had to fucking pay that,
then you are going somewhere.
But here's the fucking thing though.
Here's the thing though.
Where is that money going to go?
Are you going to fix where
the fuck it's going to go?
Because are you going to somehow fix her
fucking foreign policy so we don't get
broke fight in 3,500 jerk
offs on a fucking jungle gym.
You're gonna ignore all of those fucking
problems and just take a select few
group of fucking Americans
who did nothing wrong,
made it in a sports, created a watch
company, created a shaving company,
fucking created some something in their
standup act that fucking made enough
Americans want to go to this
show that they're making it.
You're going to punish them.
You're going to cosign, sign on.
They have to give away 70%
of their fucking money. I
just can't get behind that.
Yeah.
When all of these politicians blowing
these fucking people who aren't paying
fucking taxes
and then they're going to come out the
other side and then go give speeches to
people who don't pay fucking taxes and
companies that don't pay fucking taxes
and take that money and stick it in their
fucking pocket and go buy themselves a
big mansion on fucking mouth has
been good. That's all fucking fine.
Unfucking believable and it sit
there and say that separate issues,
that's all tax issues.
That's all the same fucking issue
anyways.
Um,
you said it isn't fair that people being
honest with their income have to pay
this rate while rich people
hide their income overseas.
You also said tax money is being
wasted on corporate corporate bullshit.
I agree with Paul. Ira. Read this,
this half a fucking paragraph
that this person wrote.
You said we should pay
politicians. Fuck you money. Uh,
you don't think if that happens,
even every money grubbing corrupt con
will do anything possible to run for
office and win an election,
including promising corporation special
deals in exchange for campaigns.
So I do believe that. I do believe that
you've been saying this for years. Yes,
I believe that.
Yeah.
I can't believe nobody's called you
out on how fucking stupid it is. Dude.
What's you're doing is you're basically
going to be like this. Well listen,
we can't get these guys,
so let's get the people we can get
who haven't poisoned the food supply,
who don't, who don't dictate
our foreign policy. Yeah.
Fuck all of that shit.
Fuck the $20 trillion sitting
in the islands in the Caymans.
Let's go after the third basement on the
New York Yankees. Yeah. Fuck this guy.
This doesn't make any
sense, dude. What could,
you can put a name and a face on that
fucking guy and because he was better in
gym class than you,
you have this underlying resentment that
you call them a poor, poor millionaire.
Anyways,
he goes,
I think the biggest issue is that you
come from comedy and you can't see beyond
that business. I, I seem to be talking
about a bunch of business here is don't I?
I'm talking about our foreign policy.
I'm talking about the food supply.
Oh, we, how much further do I have to go?
I think everyone in this country should
be in the position where their success
is measured by how hard they work
and how much they contribute.
That is mostly true in
comedy. Dude. First of all,
I'll throw you a hypocritical
bolt. I'm gonna. I'll, I'll,
what the fuck do you know about comedy?
Right. I know as much about comedy. Is it?
I mean I know as much about your
job as you know about comedy,
so why is your opinion
on Comedians more valid?
Yeah.
Anyways, if you are a millionaire
and your daddy was a famous comedian,
notice how they use the word Daddy,
right?
That will only take you so far
in comedy if you're not funny.
This is not true in every single business.
For example,
if Donald Trump had just invested his
father's money in the stock market,
he would be Richard than he is now.
What the fuck is that based on?
Like what is the stock market
guaranteed you're going to make money.
The stock market is corrupt,
but he is a very successful,
hardworking man deserving
of all our empathy.
Just like every other rich asshole.
Okay?
Yeah. Dude, you know what
you have a problem with?
You have a problem with anybody
who's rich cause you're all,
you're putting all of them. You
using all the buzzwords. Daddy rich,
asshole, poor, poor millionaire. Anyways,
I graduated from Harvard in 2015
I'm a public school teacher.
One of the people you say tax
money should be going towards. Yes,
tax money that was already collected,
sir,
that was wasted on a
neverending fucking war. Yes.
Okay.
Yes. But let's not go after
the people that wasted that.
Let's take more tax dollars from
somebody who fucking plays fucking power
forward for the fucking
Cleveland Cavaliers anyways,
unlike my classmates making millions,
no matter how hard I work,
no matter how much time
I spend on my students,
I don't earn another sent
over my $48,000 salary.
Okay, and did you not know that
going into that fucking business,
Mike, what do you, what
do you want me to do here?
I don't think you should earn that. I
think you should earn way more than that,
but I don't think that regular fucking
people who don't stick their money in the
Cayman fucking islands are now required
to pay for you because all these other
Americans are paying no taxes.
I, I don't, I don't feel that that's
where that money should come from.
I feel that you should make
way more money than that.
Okay.
I think that you do one of the most
important jobs in this country and I think
you should get, you should
get paid, I don't know,
200 fucking grand a year to do it.
Okay.
And I think you should have all the
supplies that you fucking need. I 100.
I just don't agree with where
you want to get that money.
He goes, I can earn less than a
thousand dollars in the next year.
I can't believe you're a fucking
teacher by the way, by the way,
you read the wrote this fucking thing,
but I'm going to,
I'm going to give you the benefit of
the doubt and say that you were fucking
pissed off and fucking fired this thing
off. Or this is a giant voice text.
Um, like an earn less than
a thousand in the next year.
Pay Increase based on how my students
do on statewide standardized text tests.
In fact, if I want to spend
money on class material,
it comes out of my own pocket,
can deduct a maximum of $250 a year.
Meanwhile, some of the richest continents,
country are using their money to try
and make public schools worse. Yeah,
I got to tell you something,
dude.
These aren't the guys you're going to
get what that 70% tax thing and here's
another thing,
dude,
rather than call me a fucking dumb ass
and a monkey hitting a fucking keyboard,
you know an idea that I had was
I would like to to as a comedian to do,
there's public schools in my fucking
neighborhood here and I was walking by one
the other day and I saw an auditorium
and I'm thinking, wait a minute,
they have an auditorium, they
got seats, they got his stage.
Why don't I do a fucking
fundraiser for the public school?
That was my thought and I know I'm a
mouth breather and fucking moron, dude,
you and I are on the same fucking team
here and we should not be fighting with
each other.
We should be joining forces and demanding
that these corrupt politicians go
after all the,
all these fucking asshole corporations
and individuals who pay no taxes
rather than fucking as we're both like
fucking trying to scamper out of the
boiling water poet, pulling each
other down by each other's ankles.
All right,
but here's the funny fucking thing.
It's the second I thought
about doing that show.
All I thought was of the hashtags by
the fucking parents and all of these
fucking lunatics whose minds have
been poisoned by social media and all,
it's going to take his fucking
one of them to go out there.
I can't do my fucking act in a public
school auditorium in front of the fucking
parents.
How the fuck do I do that?
I know how I do it.
What I do is I get those cell phone bags
and everybody has to put their fucking
cell phones in the fucking
bag before you go in there.
That's how I'm going to
have to end up doing it.
And unfortunately that's some of the
money that I could've given that it could
have given back to the public schools.
So here's the thing. All right, sir,
and I know you're not listening anymore.
I'm going to start doing those fucking
shows. I'm going to start doing shows.
I'm going to pick a fucking school and
I'm going to give back that way, that way.
I would rather do it that way.
Then eventually having to pay 60% fucking
taxes on my income because I'm already
paying 56. That's just on my
income. That's not property tax.
That's not fucking uh, um, sales tax,
tax on gas is all these fucking
hidden taxes. Then I'm already pain.
I'm lucky at this point,
if I'm keeping 30% of my fucking money,
I would cringe to see what
the fuck I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm,
I'm paying and fucking taxes and I know
you have no sympathy for me cause I had
the audacity to half my fucking 300 to
one fucking greyhound come across the
finish line and I won and that
you fucking resent me for that,
you know, and you let me in to people
and I'm not even at that fucking level.
All right?
But I've been around the block enough
times to know to know that if that's 70%
thing gets fucking past dude,
they're not going to stop at 10
and they're gonna keep going down.
So what I got out of this is,
you know something,
I'm going to do one of
those fucking shows, um,
at the public schools and I'm,
I'm going to start doing those
fucking things and I'm going to get,
and I might get those fucking cell
phone bags and I'll stick them in there.
And that's the way that I'm
going to fucking give back.
And I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna get a positive out of this.
All right?
And I think what regular
Americans need to do,
which is what I still am,
and you can fucking demonize me all you
want because I'm the finally fucking
making money. 27 years into
this fucking shit. All right?
Where the fuck will you, when I was
sitting on the Futon, waking up,
having panic attacks when I had
no manager, no fucking agent,
and all agents were telling
me I had a weird look.
That's what he used to say to me.
By the way,
there is an unwritten rule in this fucking
business that if you are a redhead,
you are not the lead in a movie. Um,
I dunno if that's gradually changing,
but I remember I used to go to fucking
auditions and like they would be prepared
three seats. It was back when
I had a black and white photos.
So I kind of looked like I had brown hair.
It was the 90. They had moose in there.
Oh, right. And I would come
in and as they looked at me,
I would see the look on their
face. They'd be like, okay,
we're just going to read the first
scene. Yeah. It's like, dude,
you're redheaded male. You're
not the lead. You're the
friend. You're the friend.
You're the one who doesn't get the
girl and all of that fucking shit. Um,
so anyways, we should be helping
each other out, sir. Okay.
And is the thing, if I became a
comedian and I didn't make it,
I wouldn't be crying to you about it.
Okay.
So you were the one who went to fucking
Harvard and decided to become a public
school fucking teacher.
You knew what the deal was.
Okay.
That's what the fuck you wanted to do.
And I'm going to believe you that you
went to Harvard and that you are a public
school teacher. Cause you know on the
Internet people can be like, I fucking,
I hate Trump and I'm a republican.
People can do that all the fucking time.
I'm going to take all its face value and
that you're actually a teacher and that
you wrote an email that was filled at
this many spelling mistakes. Um, this,
this much fucking hypocritical behavior
where you're yelling at me that I can't
see past the end of my own nose.
And the whole fucking thing was about
you and your job and where the fuck you
sit in the world. I didn't really see, I
didn't really see how you were. You were,
um, stepping outside of yourself.
Um, so here's the thing, sir.
Or Ma'am who have a fucking wrote this
thing. I'm going to start doing that.
All right?
I'm going to start doing fucking shows,
raising money for suffer
some fucking public,
uh,
and our high schools or whatever,
get them some money for some computers
or whatever. And actually you,
no way I'd be helping myself because I
get a kid now and all the public schools
suck out here. So now you've got to go
to private schools from the beginning,
you know,
and you're like hundreds of thousands of
dollars down the fucking drain because
once again,
people who didn't pay taxes and all
the money that all the money that we've
already, all the money that they already
fucking collect does not go with a fuck.
It should be. Um, so I
appreciate your input.
I hope you're mature enough to see,
you know,
I hope you don't decide not to keep
listening to this podcast because of
something else.
Cause it sucks because it's not funny
because it got boring to you after awhile.
But if this is the reason why that
you're not listening, you're, you're,
you're a fucking baby.
You're a big fucking baby and you're
really not solving the fucking problem.
Um,
and I think it's really ignorant to,
to demonize people that,
that made it on their own,
made it in a sport, started
a company, you know,
but I draw the line at,
you know,
if you made it in a sport and you don't
pay taxes or you started a company and
now with that, your next move is to
get your money outside the company.
I don't support that. And if you're
a comedian, you need to do that.
I don't support that. I don't, I
love Willie Nelson not paying taxes.
Don't support that. Okay. And I have
no problem paying my fair share.
And I think at 56% plus all the others,
I think I'm more than doing it.
Unfortunately.
My tax money that I'm paying is
getting nowhere near your school.
And that is not my fault,
but that is the problem.
And those are not separate issues from
where I'm from. All right, that's the,
that's the podcast. Go fuck
yourselves. And I'm going to,
you know, I'm going to
make, do on my, my, my, uh,
campaign promise. I'm going to find a
fucking school and I'm going to do it.
All right. That's it. Go fuck
yourselves and I'll see you on Thursday.