Hey,
what's going on is Bill Byrd is time for
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
August 13th, 2017 what's
going on? How I, yeah.
Um, I figured out what the problem was
with the volume last time. You know,
all my podcasts,
I think I can't figure this out.
I had some guy how to a volume II.
I remember. I'm like, I gotta go.
Everything all turned up.
I actually had two microphones plugged
in and I was on the one that was turned
all the way down.
So you were hearing it.
I was speaking into a dead mic next
to him, Mike, that was live. Oh,
bill is so unprofessional.
Hey Man.
Um, I had a major breakthrough,
major breakthrough in my life.
I don't know if you've read
about it in the New York Times,
The Washington Post,
the fucking de Moines.
Uh, what would they say that
the morning Herald, I dunno. Um,
yeah,
I moved in my house fucking seven years
ago and one of the house warming gifts
that I got was a food processor
or should've said process.
Right? I got a food processor and
this fucking thing. Never worked.
I plugged it in. I did there, but that,
but dad just would not fucking work.
So years later I bought a smaller
one for when I was on the road,
when I was going to make myself
some smoothies. Hi Fellow.
It's going to make myself some smoothies
so I could get my abs, you know,
so I could show up at the clam
bake and everybody can be like, oh,
what happened to bill? He's still blinding
white, but good God. Is He chiseled?
Is He chiseled? Can't you can't
tell. That's one of the sad things.
No matter how good a shape I get it,
you won't notice because I'm
so blindly a white chalk white.
It just, you just can't see
it. You know what I mean?
Okay.
You don't put, you know,
where's my Hashtag? What
about me? What about my pain?
I'm
having to wear sweat pants all the way
through summer just to avoid the bullying.
Uh, anyways, he's fucking food
processor wasn't working, wouldn't work.
So I got the little one,
the little one worked a couple of times,
then it wouldn't work. Then sometimes it
work and that wouldn't work. Am like, boy,
what the fuck are these things short out?
What's going on with them?
So you know what, I fucked, you know.
So anyways, I'm on this diet right now.
I got a nutritionist. Every fucking
thing is, you know, uh, you know,
take some almonds in,
fucking dice them up with,
I don't know if you've ever tried to do
that on a cutting board with the knife.
They go flying all over the place.
But if you have a word
or a food processor,
I always want to call it a word process
of food processor. Why? Why? It's a Jiffy,
you know, he just put it in and it's
easy. You feel like fucking Rachael Ray,
you spinning around and you're like,
how come I'm not hosting a cooking show?
All that's right. Because the last
red head was out there grabbing.
So there's another black hole and this,
okay.
Foot judges.
Yeah.
First, the guy from Nyp de Bleu
takes off from his fucking series,
like after one season to have a movie
career in jade and all those movies,
which were good, they didn't do well at
the box office and then they would like,
that's it. Fuck redheads, fuck
redhead males in the lead. We know it.
We knew it from day one,
even when we were making black hat
black and white fucking movies,
fuck red heads,
you know,
and Eric Stoltz immediately
felt the effects of that.
Um, so I'll take one red head to go out
there and fuck it up and then they just
stick it on the bench for a while.
I'm just fucking with you guys anyways.
Um,
I'm on my own journey.
What I do and what I asked the universe
for. It's what I'm going to get.
You have to have blinders on yet.
Pay,
be empathetic and be aware of others.
Um,
so anyways,
I went to this kid's birthday
party on Saturday and uh,
it was just Christmas themed party,
which seem nuts to me.
And then I showed up, but it was
fucking awesome. They're the AC crank.
And they had the Christmas sogs going.
It was a kid's birthday.
It was incredible. It was
actually, it was a great time.
They had a basketball hoop. All the
little kids were out there trying to dunk.
That was funny. Every kid was
Dunkin cause that's all they show.
That's all they show.
Um, on the highlights,
you know,
you only way you can take,
the only way a jump shot makes a highlight
now is if you cross the other guy
over and he fell down and 30 people
have to run by the screen going,
ah,
after you did it. You know, like
if Larry Bird played right now,
he would never make an
under sports center.
Um, I don't understand the
running around all day.
Like somebody could literally take a full
water bottle flipping upside down and
if it lands on top,
hey buddy,
acting like the dude just levitated
Oh,
I'm an old man.
Whatever.
I'm slowly feeling it's slipping away
and I'm watching young people enjoy
themselves the new way that human
beings enjoy themselves and never deli.
I don't approve. How were the
millennial generation survived?
Do you have any idea what
the fuck my dad does?
So anyways, I, uh,
I come home all right. Everything they
had at the birthday party, I couldn't eat.
I was being that La
Douche that was on a diet.
These wonderful people made all this
amazing guy. It was fucking unbelievable.
They had gingerbread men in August.
Okay.
Gingerbread men that could
fuck with anybody's December
level gingerbread men as
a ginger. I wasn't even offended.
Okay. That's how good these cookies,
Alia cupcakes,
they're rice krispie treats.
Then they had this, this breaded
chicken that just, it just look bites.
I just looked fucking incredible. Right?
And it was also at the thing and, and uh,
one of the, the husband was a, uh, was,
was, uh, uh, uh, a bourbon
whiskey scotch guy.
And he's the only guy I've ever
seen that had a bottle of monkey.
And that's when I found
when I was over in France,
but that I finished in three nights,
by the way,
which is why all freckles are still
on the wagon. Okay. My fucking,
my liver is still, you know,
talking to me about that one.
Now they're going to let it go. You
know, just like you check, you know,
you did that one fucking
thing. Oh, they're going to
bring it up for years, right.
So anyway, so I come home and
you know, I'm fucking starving.
All I drank there was waters and um,
I had a Santa hat on. It was
fucking awesome. Anyways, so, uh,
come back to the house and now I'm
trying to chop up these God damn fucking
almonds. I'm like, fuck this, let me
get that little food processor right.
And it fucking put it together. And Lo
and behold, the fucking thing works.
I'm like, fine, great. So an pill,
I take the top off, whatever,
and I go to put my shit in,
I put the top back on and that doesn't
fucking work again and I'm losing my shit.
So my wife keeps coming in and out.
So now we have an outlet for my anger,
my poor wife. Right. You
know, it's one of these deals,
like I'm frustrated over here
and then just becomes like,
how many times you going to come
in here on a door, you know,
you do one of those and then look,
what is your problem?
I can't fuck Jesus Christ.
That's going to be a fucking 40 minute
conversation there. It goes my evening.
And that's exactly what
happened. Well, long story short,
I was trying to make some almond
crusted baked chicken breasts,
eight ounces to be exact,
saving the rest for my lunch
tomorrow with a Greek Yogurt,
yogurt and in fucking dill dip or
whatever the fuck I had, you know?
And um,
yeah,
you know, the whole, I just said, fuck it.
I'm just going to make this
chicken plane and I'll,
I'll just eat it with the dip. And that's
what I did. And I've stuck to the Diet,
right. So, you know,
my wife read me the riot act, what
an asshole I am. And you know,
I couldn't argue because
she was right at that point,
my stomach was full and I was able to
look back on what I had just done pretty
clearly at that point.
I was just like, yeah,
I don't think I would be
liking me right now either. Um,
so I sat down and he nodded and I agreed.
And then I tried to make some points,
which is always bad when you're that
much in the wrong, but you know,
it's just how I'm wired. You know, as I
said, you know, I'm down 40 to nothing,
I'm still gonna try to kick
a field goal. Okay. Um,
so
that took a day and a half,
still apologize completely for,
and I had to make her laugh a lot and
she already doesn't like me. You know,
we're having like a,
a rough time right now because I'm on this
diet and I keep making extra shit and,
but it's so my next, you know, meal
and she just, she just, you know,
she's coming by like it's a buffet.
She'd be like,
I like Veggie Tacos.
I'm like,
yeah,
but there's only like this is all measured
and they wait to after you fucking
make it.
Okay.
Oh good.
And then you gotta be like, no, you can't.
Well, you have to eat all of it yet,
but I might have it tomorrow.
This is how this works.
Okay. Turn your key does. It does.
There's a launch sequence to this.
It already started.
Um,
so that just keeps being a problem
because she feels like I'm not sharing.
And so when I keep doing is I keep giving
her a bite of this bland sugar-free
salt free shit than I'm eating. I'm like,
you sure you want some of this? You know,
she had some of my oatmeal and
Allman fucking pancakes yesterday.
Peaches in a peaches in it. The chopped
peaches in it. That was the tree.
That was the oasis.
She had to keep running to as you worked
your way through all of that stuff.
All right. But I will tell you, you know,
I feel fucking tremendous. My energy is
through the God damn roof. Um, so anyways,
the next morning I wake up to make my
fucking Allmond Goddamn motherfucking
oatmeal pancakes. Now I'm calm. You know,
I had my hot water with lemon
sitting there. I'm by myself,
you know, am I? No, no, no. I'm
never by myself. That's right.
I had already brought my daughter up and
I've fed her and she was watching puppy
dog pals and I had her in the
highchair. She was locked in, you know,
she had a little sippy cup and she
was fucking, you know, love and life.
So I went out there and I was just like,
I'm going to figure out how to use these
fucking work with these food processors,
not word processed food processor.
And I got this giant bin where I
keep all the instruction manuals
throughout the years, every fucking
thing I've ever owned. Okay.
Instruction manuals for my refrigerator.
Like what do you need to know how to
open and close the fucking door? Right.
I Dunno, I wanted it to
be colder temperature down
Arrow, Arrow, arrow. Right.
Um,
anyways,
I ended up finding the fucking,
um,
instructional manual for both of them.
And this fucking food processors
that I got seven years ago,
I realized always worked.
It's just with the food processor,
there's only way that it goes together.
And I know this is basics for a lot
of you fucking do you know people,
you know who don't think
outside the box the way I do,
who don't have faith in your own
abilities to just put something together.
You have to cheat and look at the
instructions. So what I'm doing here,
I'm making myself a
hero anyways. Yes, Bill,
we do see what you're
doing here. Um, so I, uh,
I got it out and it's like there's only
one way that it can go together where
it's still going to work because there's
no way they're going to let you put it
together wrong or have the top off and
have that blade spinning because you
know, somebody somehow fucking stuck
their hand or their face in it. Yeah.
And died. Right. You know,
or had the top off and then realize
they had some ingredient and on the top
shelf and the cover right above
it and they got up above it.
You know when they was squatting and
say we're going to stand up, you know,
and old Matt and Ben Hung Down there,
right? They've got all shredded.
Okay.
So what kills me,
what I've learned about food processors
is all of them will go together about
three to four different ways,
but only one way.
You can put it together and it will work.
And that's what the problem was.
The problem is really that I didn't,
um,
I didn't read the manual,
but now it's kind of fascinating.
It's sort of like this, it's like
this electric current fucking thing.
It's just like,
it will go to here.
Now we will go pass through the handle
and then pass through the top and now you
can fucking dice your goddamn almonds.
Get it fucking text message here.
What is the problem?
Yeah.
Oh, Jesus quitters. Anyways, Shell, I
now have a word processor in my life.
A food processor.
Fuck.
Okay.
Processes the food. And I gotta
tell you it's been fucking awesome.
And I got that little one.
I know how that works.
So now I can bring that on the road.
It makes some smell.
You know,
there's nothing worse than eating
right while you're eating right.
But there's nothing better after. And
when you eat bad, it's the opposite.
There's nothing better
than eating like shit.
And there's nothing worse than right
after, you know, for the next morning,
it's usually two days later. So you
look down and it's just like, oh my God,
am I preggers? Um, all right.
So anyways, that's, that's,
that's my food processor story. So if
you're like me, if you ever got a gift,
a food processor gift,
okay.
And,
uh,
it never quite worked for you and you
have like massive add or are you just a
fucking scatter brained moron?
Which I sometimes think
add is a euphemism for, uh,
just go back and look at the manual.
All right?
Usually the handle has to face you
and then the top goes on just so, uh,
then you have your, just, your life will
be so much fucking easier. So anyways,
the first week was detox.
I already did that.
And now this second week is healthy gut.
So it's a bunch of Greek yogurt that,
you know, it has probiotics in it,
which is great because you know,
when you drink booze,
I guess booze kills the good bacteria.
See there's good bacteria and
there's bad bacteria in your gut.
The bad bacteria is therefore who else
all day when you die, when you die, the,
that's the bacteria that then begins
to feed a jeweler as you decompose.
That's actually true man. And a lot it
turns into like gas and shit like that,
which is why they always find like a
headless torso floating in the bay.
It's the shit in your gut that turns
to gas and it's like a fucking water
balloon. And you'd go up not to
mention, you know what I mean?
If you've already got some blubber on you,
if that's probably another reason.
But I remember reading that
book, uh, the West East,
that that movie state of grace
was loosely, loosely based on,
and um, they used to do,
they used to, you know,
they kill somebody and they used to
call it that the Houdini because the guy
would disappear and what they would do,
they always made sure that they,
they would, they chop them all up, but
they make sure that they got them too.
So then he would never come back because
if he, if he didn't take the time,
but you know, get the guts out of them,
then, then they, they would, they,
you'd have a floater.
Goddammit. I'm, there you go.
Now you know how to murder somebody,
but not an emergency,
but you know how to get rid of them.
Okay.
Um, anyways, uh, what
did I do this weekend?
Red Sox, keep winning.
You spend enough money,
you can sweep the oriels.
That's what we paid for.
We've won nine of our last 10.
We won nine out of 10 games in August.
We lost one game to go. Blue Jays
swept the Yankees, uh, went to,
and one against Toronto. Is that
right? One for against the Yankees.
Okay.
21. That's three. Yes. Right. And
then what's swept three with a,
the oriels now we've got the fillies
coming up who always play as tough.
Got to games with them in leg excitement.
Then we got Tampa Bay and then
we got our uh, another big test.
We got the Cleveland Indians, uh, scary.
Terry Francona I still think is
the best manager in baseball.
He's got them playing great
with what he has and um,
yeah,
we'll see how we do against them.
We've got two series with them and then
the Houston before we play too with the
Yankees and then we're done. Then we
go into the playoffs. God willing,
God willing,
but evidently it's the whole fucking
thing is over because we swept the Yankees
in the beginning of August,
despite the fact that Yankees have
come back down 18 games against us,
we blown in eight,
we blew that fucking lead and 2012,
I'm never comfortable
until you won the division.
But then at the Yankees
get the fucking wildcard.
It's like you did not dispose of them.
It's just like,
well here we go now with zero,
zero.
So all that we didn't really didn't
mean shit cause the greedy cuts,
what fucking rounds of playoffs.
Playoffs. Everybody makes it.
Everybody makes it. Everybody makes it.
Hey,
if you want to hear something hilarious,
listen to Paul versus these Diversey
effect this week because he watched the
giants first preseason game and that
absolute beast that they drafted,
his name escapes me.
I saw him play in the rose bowl,
the running back from Penn
state. He said, he goes, dude,
you got to see his first run.
You said he fucking,
he went one way and then
he had it all sealed off.
He ran the other way for like 40 yards
and I guess uh, the giant faithful,
we're going fucking crazy or you will
not find a more loyal spill sports fan
that Paul Versey and I know it's been
easy to be a giant fair during the fucking
Eli days,
but he has been our hardcore New
York Knicks fan since I met him.
I can only feel so bad for him because
he is a giant set, a Yankees Fan.
He said plenty of success right in
his lifetime that he's remembered.
They have won five world series and
two Superbowls is pretty God damn good.
Right? He doesn't give a fuck about
hockey. They brain just won a Stanley Cup.
He's not a mets fan. They want
an 86 a, here we go. Belt.
Now you got to work it all out, don't
ya? Then who's left? Oh, the jets.
Jesus Christ and I think it
just goes downhill. Um, anyways,
he was all excited about that. I did
not see all my patriots were doing. Um,
this might be Tom Brady's last year,
maybe next year.
It's all winding down and I'm waiting to
see who in the AFC is going to step up.
I mean from the rumblings I heard that it
seems like the jets seem like the, the,
the odds on favorite to be the next one,
to have a run as long as bill Bellacheck
sticks around after Brady leaves,
at least within the next three years.
We'll see how that goes. But what a,
what to run til they got another
one in them. I don't know.
We won five out of eight, I
couldn't be fucking happier. Um,
speaking of not being,
could not be happier.
Did anybody watch any motorcycle racing
yesterday or these past two weeks?
Believe the one last, uh, two
weeks ago was in, uh, Berlin.
I think it was somewhere in Germany.
These last two fucking races
had been so god damn exciting.
Let's just talk about
yesterdays Austrian Grand Prix.
Okay.
Austrian. I believe birthplace
of Adolf Hitler, I believe. Okay.
Um,
okay.
You know, it's so fucking, well, I think
it's just because I live over here.
Whenever I go over there, that's
all I ever think. All right.
Whenever I'm in Paris or Mikey and I
walk up the shops, Elisa, I'm like,
Hitler drove down this fucking street
in a Mercedes Benz standing up fucking
waving to the crowd. Like he
just won a super bowl, you know?
And I think if you just
grow up over there,
it just seems like olden day shit because
you know when I sit out here in Los
Angeles, I don't think like a, there
was some native Americans here,
you know, living off the land dead,
not, not stealing any water. Um,
anyways, you got to watch that fuck you
get if you're going to get into racing,
if you're like, eh, it just seemed like
they ran, you ran the fucking circle.
You need excitement.
Motorcycle racing is where it's at.
Moto GP is the best racing out there.
Okay.
And the show the past two
weeks that Jorge Lorenzo, mark,
Mark Marquez and Andre
De vi Andres Divisio.
So I hope that's how you say
his first name, um, have put on,
it's been, it's been, I,
they had me off the couch
miming rolling on the throttle.
Yeah,
I was screaming at the fucking TV the
last couple of laps. They basically doing,
I don't know, 160, 170, 180 miles an hour,
almost bumping into each other
like they're racing on horses,
which is dangerous enough.
And what did they,
what I'm finding is,
is these Ducati's have an incredible
amount of torque that the Honda can't fuck
with Jorge Lorenzo and the
visio. So both are on the, uh,
on the um,
okay.
Ducati team, Jesus Christ
spaced took on the Ducati team.
A Mac Mac has is on the Honda and I
heard Latin that I heard yesterday that
Jorge Lorenzo's is going to go
to the right a Honda next year.
I don't know why the fuck he
would do that with his skills.
Why would you want to be on like a
slower bike? But Mark Marquez I think,
yeah,
I dunno. I, I think he, he just,
he just rides perfectly so
he gets them in the corners
and he just takes the perfect
line around the track beef,
literally the fastest
way around the track.
And then in the beginning of this race,
cars, uh, last week's right Keith,
he came in third, which is
a massive failure in his
world. And uh, Dubitsky Ozone,
Jorge, Lorenzo's just, they passed each
other like three times on the final lap.
And this week Mark Marquez
and Jorge Will Lorenzo.
There was three passes on the final lap.
It was fucking unbelievable.
Okay.
And,
um,
okay.
In the beginning of the race, mark,
mark has, I think it was just,
he kind of knew the power
that the Ducati's had.
So he was just trying to fucking put
as much space between himself and other
Ducati's as he could. It's so fascinating
that the tire that they're on,
and then Jorge was kind of like
laying back or Davinci also was,
I think was laying back,
couldn't get around Lorenzo.
But then you don't know if
that's a strategy, like,
ah, you're on soft to tires.
Go ahead and let you run a little bit,
let you chew up your fucking tires.
I'm on a heart attire and then I'm going
to fucking, you know, after the races,
like halfway over. Um, but they
do this subtle thing where they,
they hang back but they
still press the person. Um,
so hopefully the tires are all fucking
chewed up and they don't have as good a
grip and then they can, they can
run them down in the end. Uh,
I barely know what I'm talking about,
but I have to tell you,
it is fucking incredible.
Uh, you have to get into it.
And here's another great thing. Most
racist, it's like 25, 26, 27 laps.
There's no pit stops. It's a perfect thing
for an American to get into. It's fast,
it's exciting, and
there's no breaks. Okay.
Even though we have a bunch of
timeouts and shit, it's like,
it's like you fast forwarding
through the commercials.
It's like no fucking commercials.
Um, cannot say enough about it. Um,
and for those who actually pay attention,
mark has,
it looks like he's going to win the
championship. He's way out in front.
I don't know what happened to
Rossi this week. He, uh, must,
they had some sort of grid penalty.
Yuri crashed. I don't know what,
but he started in like 14th place.
But that fucking guy is,
he's second in points.
But as far as wins,
Golf Marquez says one five this year,
Lorenzo's one three.
[inaudible] has one too. And a Marquez
has been on nine different podiums.
He's like on the pony. He's been on
the podium every race but to, um,
so he's way out in front. He's like
200 points in the next closest guys.
Valentino, I think he has like 130,
140, so it's pretty soulful safe.
Barring anything, uh, major that
market has is going to win this again.
Uh, but I'll tell you that the show, the
three of them are putting on his fucking,
it's unbelievable. And I have, I
got to go to that moto GP race.
There's only one in the United States if
you want to go. And there's only one, uh,
formula one race.
If you want to see Louis Hamilton who's
going to go on to be one of the greats
of all time, uh, it's
an Austin, Texas and uh,
I highly recommend it. Um,
anyways. All right, let me do a,
let me do a little couple of fucking
reads here for the week there. Uh,
are right hotel tonight.
All right,
tonight is hotel tonight is the Goto App
for booking great deals at great hotels.
Unlike other hotel booking sites.
Hotel too.
No,
not going to do that the whole time.
It doesn't have long,
endless lists of a zillion
hotel choices installed.
Instead hotel tonight is shows you
only the best deals at the best hotels.
They partner with the top rated hotels
to help them fill their unsold rooms,
which is how you get such a great deal.
So they kind of like every other one,
but they're not going to
give you, oh, hey, here's a,
here's a motel four and a half.
They only gonna give you the best ones.
And even though the name is hotel too,
it's not just for tonight,
you can book tonight,
tomorrow or beyond.
It's perfect for plan is
as well as procrastinators.
You can book spontaneous weekends,
three day getaways,
staycations road trips,
business trips.
You can book a hotel just so
you can use the pool, et cetera.
Download the hotel tonight.
Apt to today to get great deals at hotels
you actually want to stay at and what
the Promo Code [inaudible] you can get
$20 off your first eligible booking.
That's hotel too.
Promocode burr policy genius dude,
he's fucking wicked smack.
Um,
life insurance is really important,
but it's also really confusing.
The one to four out of
10 people don't have it.
And maybe you're one of those people.
I have it. I have it, you know,
tell you right now I have such,
I have such an incredible
amount of life insurance.
I bet my wife last night when I was such
a dick to her probably thought about
taking me out. Um, but if
anything were to happen,
it's important that your
loved ones are taken care of.
That's so true because I know a lot of
guys that died unexpectedly and they did
not have their affairs in order.
And A to say that that's a
little bit of a curve ball is a,
is an understatement.
Besides life insurance,
besides life insurance rates are at
the lowest they've been in 20 years,
the best time to buy is now and
the best place to buy his policy,
genius.com policy genius is the easy
way to compare life insurance online.
And just five minutes.
You can compare quotes from
the top insurers to find
the best policies for you.
And when you compare quotes, you
saved money. It's that simple.
Policy Genius has helped over 4 million
people shop for insurance and placed
over $20 billion in coverage and they
don't just make life insurance easy.
They also compared disability insurance,
renter's insurance and health insurance.
If you care about it, they can cover it.
A, if you've been putting
off getting life insurance,
there's no reason to put
it off any longer. Guys,
I know a lot of you don't want to do it.
I didn't want to do it cause
you contemplate your own death.
But I have to tell you when
you get life insurance,
this is like this weight off for your
chest because part of it is, you know,
all right, I don't want to admit
that I'm going to die someday,
but no one that if you died,
everybody in your family is
going to be okay, is huge.
Okay?
So you don't have to sit
there like haunting the house
with the fucking tear in
your eye and she wants you, everybody
fucking sharing a bullet. Grape Netflix.
All right. If you've been
putting off life insurances,
no reason to put it off any
longer, longer, go to policy,
genius.com for all your dummies out.
Their genius is spelled g. E. N. I. U. S.
It was really talking to
myself. Get quotes and apply
in minutes. It's that easy.
You could go do it right now and
you should because rates are,
they're lowest in 20 years.
Policy Genius, P. O. L.
I see why GE and I,
U s.com the easy way to
compare and buy life insurance.
All right. Is there a promo code so they
know that I sent you there? All right,
the p n. Um, all right,
this is the last one. All
right. Victor Papa. November.
Simply safe home security is the home
security that finally gets it right.
Simply safe. Started 10 years ago
with a mission to the industry.
They cut out contracts, middlemen
and pushy sales guys. Uh,
they made it easy to set up your system
with no hard wiring or tools with simply
safe. Uh, you get
professionally monitored, 24,
seven protection for just $15 a month.
That's your home home protected by policy
dispatch and fire dispatch. Dispatch.
Sorry. Uh, everyone loves this
system. Everyone loves it. Okay.
They love how it works and how easy
it is to use today. Simply say,
protects over 2 million people.
They've one edit as choice
awards from c n e t PC magazine.
And why
go to simply safe bird.com today
to order your simply safe system,
you get a 60 day risk free trial trial
that simply safe [inaudible] dot com
simply safe bur.com. Ah, you know what?
I forgot to tape yesterday
on me TV on Sunday nights.
You know what they got?
They got all they got Colombel
hello? Let me, let me just ask
you one more question. I might be
confused me just a little bit
here. I just got, I love that.
I love the walkaway and then he would
come back. Oh, okay. I she, I she,
you didn't do it then, but uh, oh, I'm
showing you the body yet I'm show. Yeah,
you can get back to working out and then
he goes to walk away. I always, yeah,
we [inaudible] just one more question.
Yeah.
And then that's the question that
gets the guy's fucking brow sweating.
Okay.
Unbelievable fucking show. One of my
favorite memories of my adult life was,
uh, I was in Rome, Italy.
Okay.
As opposed to roam North
Carolina. Bill. I was in Rome.
I was getting ready to do a run of dates,
so I had to get acclimated to the time.
So I went over there five
days early because my lovely
wife and my mother in law
and,
uh,
we were all jet lagged and at three in
the morning we will watch and fucking
Colombo. Somehow it was
in English, I believe
add open because we were
watching it. And uh, we just,
it was a fucking greatest night ever.
It's just one of those fucking nights.
She didn't go on vacation,
didn't have anything to do.
And then Colombo comes on
at three in the morning.
Okay.
And, uh, we just had the best
time ever watched it. Oh,
it's such a great show. Um,
but is there anything else that I wanted
to talk about before I get into your
questions? For the week. I'm a
little pressed for time here. Um,
oh. So, oh God. You know, I,
I been going to the gym now.
Everything's going great. I'm turning
my, uh, my ass cheeks. I don't know if I,
I mentioned to this,
I did mention since you,
but people who might've
missed last week's podcast.
I figured out the reason why I kept
having this sciatic nerve problem was
because of 20 years of being on the road,
sitting in writer's rooms,
just sitting down in general and
not doing legs the way I have.
Um,
my fucking glutes turned into fucking
two pieces of veal cutlet and I'm just
sitting on skin and bones back
there. So, uh, after a while, the,
the Sadek nerve gets Impinj death.
So,
um, anyways, I, uh,
I been doing my legs religiously and,
uh, I dunno, I'm starting to have
a little bit cube steak back there.
Still a poor cut of meat.
But I am a,
I am dedicated to doing this as somebody
told me a long time ago that, um,
one of the great things to do is to
constantly to never stop doing squats
because uh, you know, as you become
like an older person and everything,
you want to be able to
get up and out of bed,
get up and out of a chair
and that type of stuff.
And then also your quads are
the biggest muscle in your body.
So it's going to burn the most fat
and all of this shit. So anyways,
I'm not gonna lie to you guys. I,
I've been, I've been really, uh,
talking to some people for the first
time in my life and I realized how many
exercises I did it,
the gym with terrible form.
So now I have my form down pat.
Like I have my shoulders down
and back and speaking to my back.
Like I've really been working all my
back muscles and everything because you
know, being a child of the 80s, it
was all do it working your badge,
what can your bench, right.
And it was all bench in.
And currently you do tries or whatever,
but you wouldn't do it and you would,
you would you do that shit, you know, like
I was talking about where it'd be like,
you know, uh, if you're picking
up somebody luggage, you know,
straight up to do your trapezius there,
but you wouldn't do the middle of your
back, your lower back or anything.
Your shoulders would get pulled forward
and up and then you'd be benching like
that and then eventually you'd
blow out your fucking rotator cuff.
So I now know not to do that.
I'm still not benching.
I'd bench now I do like,
uh,
eventually I'm just going
to do like dumbbells cause
it allows your shoulders to
move independently, you know? Uh,
so you're not married to one shoulder or
the other, you know, it's almost like,
you know, the different holiday
differential works and your car right.
It allows both wheels in the
back to turn independently.
So one doesn't get fucking around the
turns fast than the other for your
mechanics out there.
Um,
so I was watching this guy
at the gym today and, uh,
like the lat pull down is the big
fucking exercise that I need to do.
If I'm eventually going
to get back to doing,
be able to handle my body weight
to do a polyp again so I can,
when my bet of being able to
do 10 of those when I'm 70,
um, I have less than 20 years before
him 70. If you could fucking believe it.
That's how fast life goes by. Started
this podcast, it was only 30 days.
Um,
so this guy comes in,
he's probably my age,
but in my vein, Venus,
I probably thinks he's like
five years older than me,
but I do that a lot where I think
people are 10 years older than me.
They'd like three years younger than me
and it's obviously not because the way I
look, it's my fucking
vanity. So, uh, this guy, he,
I think he's in a hurry or whatever,
but he was doing these lat fucking
pull downs and it was like,
rather than sitting up, you
know, sitting up straight,
shoulders down and back and then not
letting your shoulders coming up,
standing up, grabbing the bar and
then coming down. And I do, you know,
explode down one, two and then
one, two, three, four going up,
right with weight that you can handle,
keeping your shoulders down and back.
This fucking guy was doing
almost the whole stack. And what,
how he would get it down
was as he brought it down,
he would like lean back and then he would,
he would use the momentum of
leaning back and then pull it down.
And I took video. Really, I would
never show this guy in the internet,
but just to show
my trainer and I was just like,
just out of curiosity,
what muscles is this person actually
working instead of their lats?
Cause it's the lat pull down and the
person looked at it and said he's working
his triceps,
his groin,
and he's on his way to
having a herniated disc.
And I got to tell you the amount of
fucking people that I've, I've seen in,
and I'm not trying to be, you know,
I know a couple, I know my form now,
so I'm trying to be like to Snob at the
gym. I'm just letting you guys know,
having worked through this fucking
injury for the last two years,
because I was that guy,
I was never quite that bad,
but my shoulders were up and all that
and I had this big fucking problem.
Um,
that ended up being a blessing because I
found out how fucked up my body was and
I needed to get it all twisted and I'll,
you know,
fucking yoked and all these different
places and now I'm trying to build it back
up again. But, uh, I was always
one of those people like,
why am I going to get a personal trainer?
Like,
I would always just look at somebody
doing an exercise and be like, oh,
what's that for? Okay,
I'll try those. And I, I,
it's fucking pointless
unless you get the form down.
So you really should get a trainer.
And then I imagined trainers are
just like comedians where you know,
you have your top 10%,
the David tells the Dave Chappelle's
those level and then you got a bunch of
fucking Dick joke hacks out there that
you've got to make sure that you have
like the right fucking person.
Um,
and I guess the red flag would be if
they just said, hey, do this exercise.
And they didn't work too
much on your form. Um,
make sure you get somebody that,
that teaches you the form and all of that.
And uh, so you don't hurt yourself in
an end up in the situation that I'm in.
And that poor bastard at the gym,
I wanted to say something to him,
but he had like this fucking crazy type A,
I'm in a fucking rush.
Fibe I think I have a,
I'm not gonna say,
it's almost like telling somebody that
they're working out wrong is almost like
going up to somebody you don't know and
giving them advice on how to raise their
kid.
I feel like this,
what do you guys think?
And it's just something you don't do.
I think if you will
like a personal trainer,
you almost have to come
in like an apology. Amen.
Not trying to get in your kitchen
here, buddy, but, uh, you're gonna,
you're gonna get a
herniated disc doing that.
Yeah.
But then [inaudible] going to have to
like go into his ego and be it, hey,
take half of what you're lifting
and then do it the right way.
And I just don't think he's,
you know,
you know what back
doctors need business to,
why the fuck am I going to get involved?
You know,
what am I good am I go there and start
mansplaining and then all of a sudden the
lesbians at the gym and
the feminist start yelling.
I actually should say lesbian,
I should say feminists. Right?
Yeah.
I'm sure there's some openminded
lesbians out there that wouldn't mind
a little lat pulldown fucking a
okay.
Explanation.
Yeah.
All right. If you were confused by
that, don't worry. I was to, okay,
let's get into the
questions for the week here.
MMM.
All right. Fresh box. Okay, wait,
wait. Let me see here. Okay, bill,
great emails for the week. A fresh
box 23. Got a lot of responses.
Your request for advice for the 23
year old virgin in London with strict
parents.
Uh,
I only included responses
from chicks because
that's who you asked, uh,
to get emails in from a,
but it should be noted about 50
guys wrote in with their advice.
Responses are from around the world
with different advice. Yeah, I figured,
you know, women would know better. So
anyways, there's this woman, she's 23.
She's working on her goddamn doctorate
or something crazy like that and she
wants to know she's a virgin.
She wants to know how to get out there
and meet a nice fella instead of, uh,
some guy on Tinder I believe is, is the
bad dating site. If that's a reference.
I hear younger comics using all
right. Fresh buckets. Here we go.
Here's some women
helping out fresh box 23,
uh okay.
Cause cause her vagina's fresh
as in any dirty dicks in there.
And she's 23 years old. That's right.
Fresh box. 23 was in the subject. Okay.
All right. Clam podcast listener.
All right. Uh, hey there,
Bilbo Baggins.
I'm a fellow clam podcast listener
of responding to the 23 year old lady
who wrote on your Monday morning podcasts.
Uh,
don't go on them.
Don't go on them dating apps.
Most of them just want to bang or they
are closet gay men or they are serial
killers who still live with their moms.
I also did not date until my mid twenties
for the same reason and I found that
the most effective way to meet guys was
to get a bunch of single girlfriends and
go speed dating.
You get to meet these
men in the flesh and see them
sweating in their shirts awkwardly.
Palming they're sweaty drinks.
Where do you go? Speed dating?
Uh, it's funny and endearing and you'll
have a better chance getting matched to a
human being. The fact that they were
nervous. I would think that there,
there's something about, and that
they're a better guy, you know,
I can't say it better guy,
but then you don't want to be all
nervous when they're going out in the job
world. It's a difficult, difficult thing
trying to pick the right person anyways.
Other options are to join a church group
that does charity work or meet affairs
at good day.
You meet somebody or as a fellow
studious working professional,
it's school but don't bang anyone at work.
That's how I am now. That's how I
met my now soon to be ex husband.
Oh my God,
she just gave all of this great advice
and then you have a failed relationship
at the end. What is she supposed to do?
I think there was some good things there.
Do you want a church group
that does charity work?
Maybe not to the church if you're not
into that shit, do some charity work.
But then, uh, just make
sure you, you have your vet,
cause that's also where I would think
a psycho Miko to try to get some,
you know,
some open minded slash a little
naive when it comes to street smarts.
Always have your guard up. Uh, oh,
did I mention I saw that movie eighth
grade? Did I tell you that? And I, I need,
I went to go see it.
I didn't even know Bo Burnham directed it.
I just heard it was good and God damn it,
I wanted to see a movie and I
went to go see it. And it's,
it's fucking great.
It's great.
There's one scene in there
that is excruciating to watch.
But I think it's important that,
uh,
you know,
like preteen, teen girls see it. Uh,
cause there's, it's really a, I dunno,
it's fucking brutal slot creatures out
there. All right. But it, it doesn't get,
you know, it gets creepy enough, but
not to the point where you're like,
I wish I never saw this fucking movie.
Um,
okay.
But it's a, you know, the way it
was handled, I thought was, was, was
perfect. And, uh,
it's quite to see a fucking comedian out
there directing a movie that good. Huh?
Everybody thinks all we could do is
jump around talking about our dicks.
Look at that. Look at Boalt burner.
Crushing it. Um, so go check that out.
Support a fellow comedian and
support cinema. Live cinema.
Uh, all right. Fresh box
23. Hey, Billy bobbled Dick.
That's a great one.
I frigging love your podcast.
You're truly the inner monologue in my
head for almost every scenario in my life.
I find myself in, I'm a 29
year old front door, right?
Sure.
Jada have dude, Dorchester, mass at m,
a biology student in a
committed relationship.
My advice to this broad from England
looking for love dating apps or what I
would describe as a last resort,
and I believe that's something
that I suggested to her.
Maybe I'm just old school.
But the reality is most people are
dating apps are most people in real life
these days.
Uh,
what you see on bumble is
what you see in real life.
There's not really one app
that's better than the other.
They all house most of the
Douche baggery in the world.
So what's the difference? Meet people
platonically is what I would suggest.
Who wants a baby daddy from Tinder? All
right, well how did she do this? But Hey,
who am I to judge?
Get some girlfriends.
Then they introduce you to single friends
at a fucking barbecue or some shit
like that.
I do know some girlfriends who have
met their husbands off dating sites,
but hey, come to think of it.
Their husbands seriously suck.
Seriously suck. Just so many dicks
on so many levels. All right.
So I think dating apps is out.
That's what I've learned so far.
Keep on keeping on. I can't wait to see
it. The garden. Oh wait, wait. That's it.
So what was your advice? Okay. Basically
stay away from the dating apps.
It seems like he get with
a group of girlfriends,
you go out in a herd, there's the
guys are in the tall grass peaking up,
waiting to find a weak one. And I
guess somehow your, I dunno. Anyways.
Um, right. Let me just
read the rest of this.
Keep on keeping on. I can't wait to
see it. The guide in October, Bill,
you red headed stepchild and Hey
England broad, it's, it'll get easier.
Just stick your tits out there and it,
it's like flies to honey.
You'll quickly realize how easy it is.
Uh, all right. There's a lot of advice and
a lot of different directions in there,
but you know she's studying biology.
She's from Dorchester,
so she's getting a lot of mixed
signals, sir. All right, fresh.
Brock's 23 from our lady.
The ability, big tense.
I just finished listening to your
podcast of August 6th and I have a few
suggestions for the girl
who's late to the dating game.
I'm only 21 but I'm certainly not fresh
out of the box that I know a few things.
Number one, use bumble, not Tinder. Okay.
Now she's saying she's saying
a dating app on bumble.
The girls have to message first
so you could do some flirting.
Okay.
Oh,
so you can do all the for flirting.
You could do some filtering out of due
to seem creepy without feeling pressured
to respond to a message. Tinder
is good. If you want to get laid,
if you're trying to weed out the guys
who just want to get their dicks wet,
tell them you're saving
yourself until marriage.
You can always change your
mind later. Uh, quote. Oh,
so you just tell him you saving yourself
till marriage and that just makes a
bunch of good. Most of the guys will
just, who are just looking to get laid.
I guess we'll leave you
alone anyways. Number two, my
friends love to pimp me out.
I'm sure if you asked yours, they
would, two, three, like bill said,
find an activity. Lots of cities
have sports leagues that could,
that could be a good place to spark
to start. Thanks and go fuck yourself.
I really think out of all the
advice that I just read there,
I would say stay away from all dating
apps and I, you need to get a hobby.
You need to carve out some time,
some social time and like,
you know, some sort of
sport, charity work,
um,
a cooking class.
Just get yourself out there where
it's like, those are really good.
I feel like there's a lot of a
decent people in those things.
Sports, you know, he could
find the controlling type a
dick, but you know that guy.
Who else is going to crush it a
lot of times in the real world.
So depends on if you want
an in ground pool or not.
I don't know what you're
looking for. Um, but they go,
there is some advice for you. Good
luck and don't settle. All right.
Don't settle for guys. Be a dick.
Fuck him. There's this, you know,
the, the, there's going to be
a good guy out there for you.
You don't ever have to fucking sell. Send
it back. It's votes too cold. All right.
Black Guy's perspective on
stand your ground. I dear bill,
I hope you the lovely Nia
and the tet talented toddler
are doing well. All right.
First off, there's a lot of white guys
saying they're black guys on the Internet,
so we'll see how this goes.
Uh, or there's a lot of, uh,
Republicans saying they're
Democrats and vice versa. You know,
I'm a Republican and I got to say no,
I hate Donald Trump.
And I'm a Republican.
They always do that shit.
So who knows if this guy is black
or not. But anyways, here we go.
I wanted to share my opinion on the
growing frustrations with situations like
this and how they are handled,
viewed and discuss.
No resist respect to you or your platform.
I respect where you're coming from
on this topic. I am a 28 year old,
born and raised in Brooklyn. That
may not mean what it used to. Uh,
but I know you're familiar
with what this detail implies.
Imagine Boyz in the hood,
but dial down to about four out of
10 that's roughly what I grew up in.
I had to learn how to avoid and resolve
conflicts like the one that led to that
disgusting and pointless loss of life.
I want to begin by disagreeing with the
shooter deciding to pull the trigger.
Yeah, it was ridiculous. He got
pushed down on the ground. Okay.
And the guy started to walk away.
I personally could not pull the trigger
on a person like that though I can
imagine being in a position
leading up to that moment.
I don't want to live in a world
where this behavior is condoned.
I'd also like to point out that people
where I'm from pulled the trigger for
less.
Yeah.
I'm not advocating that one group of
people shouldn't shoot people and other
people should. I'm just saying, okay.
That if you yell at somebody's girlfriend
or wife and the guy comes out and
pushes you down to the ground,
that's not a reason to use deadly force.
I mean that's like, that's like
wild west Shit. Um, anyways.
I think all of the adults made bad
choices that escalated to the situation.
100% agree with that first using the
differently labeled parking when there are
other available spots is a dick move?
Absolutely arguing in defense of a
move like that. This is even worse.
This is speculation,
but knowing what I know about my own
people in a certain type of black woman,
if I as a black man even politely
said something to that woman,
there is a very little chance she
respond politely. And this is where,
I don't know if this is a fucking
white dude or a black guy,
insert me in that situation on our demand
would have knocked me down just like
he did the white to the
white guy and fuck me up. Uh,
no news coverage. My own people would
have said, I should have shut the fuck up.
Yeah. But he didn't fuck him up. He just
pushed him down and started to walk away.
If he pushed him down and
started swinging on him. Um,
I gotta be honest even then.
Okay.
Even then I feel like to then pull a gun,
this guy's throwing hands,
don't you throw hands back
is just like the untouchables.
So brings a knife and you bring a gun.
I mean,
this is literally a fucking
gas station anyways.
This is why I wouldn't have said Shit.
I would have minded my own business.
That's the school I'm front, but that
is the pro and con of where I come from.
And the world in general.
I suppose you mind your own business,
but then you add to a culture where
people disobey laws bigger, small,
and no one is supposed
to stand up for decency.
Though it is not hurting
anyone in that usual scent.
It's not cool to park in those spots
and it shouldn't be tolerated. Yes.
But shouldn't that guy of step to the guy,
you know,
rather than waiting to the guy leaves
in the yells at the woman, then he put,
he kind of put them in that fucking
macho position to stick up for his lady.
Yeah. Everybody was wrong in
that, you know, but I mean
to then turn around and fucking shoot
that guy, I mean it's just, it's as he's,
you know, starts to walk away. It's just
fucking insane. And he was the black,
I should not have initiated the
physical contact. Uh, never wound what?
You can't kill. Uh, or the black version.
Don't start shit. You can't finish. Um,
it didn't even look like he tried to
dissolve the conflict in another way.
Also, you never know what a stranger is
carrying legal weaponry or otherwise.
Yeah, that's true. In New York everything
is illegal, but that doesn't stop anyone.
The black guy was about to stop that
white man out. Do you think that,
cause I thought he pushed him
down and then walked away.
I recognize that body language anywhere.
He only backed up after seeing the gun.
At which point the entire
situation should have been over.
That's another thing.
He could have waved the gun at him.
I'm not saying that the lady driving the
car or that guy did everything right,
but to just fucking shoot the guy.
Um,
okay.
It's not somebody who, who, who
continues to charge when they a gun.
I'm a detailed,
I'd like to point out is that the black
guy did not put his hands up when the
white man pulled on him.
This is because we,
black men have to look bad ass to matter
this or I don't fucking know about this
shit.
Yeah,
I dunno, but I dunno who fucking wrote
this. You said, this is because we,
black men have to look bad ass.
No matter the circumstances.
Whoever my hands would bent so high in
the air, I could have tickled God's feet.
The white guys supposedly known for
fucking with people over disabled parking
spots.
He also supposedly mentally unstable.
If those are facts,
he shouldn't have been on the street or
allowed to carry a fucking gun. Yeah,
well that's another thing too. They,
I actually do a bit about this,
how they shut down and not houses. When
I was a kid, you will fucking crazy.
They put you in the nut house and
you combine the fact that not houses,
they just have those people walking down
the street now and people who are into
guns don't want to wait more
than 15 minutes to get one.
You're going to have a
fucking problem anyways.
None of this shit should have happened.
I'm tired of seeing my people,
especially men die over dumb shit and
it only becomes news if there is a white
person involved.
Also,
men have to rise above getting into
goofy arguments on behalf of women,
especially when they're wrong. She's
likely not going to get hurt, but you,
you are as a dude. Yeah, that is true.
Not sure if you can feel
where I'm coming from,
but I want to make my fellow
black men to be smarter and safer.
Kids need their father's
best of fan for Brooklyn.
Ps met you once at the beacon
theater show. We'll see you at MSG.
You are awesome. Well,
thank you very much.
I agree with everything that you said
there. Uh, although I don't think it,
it looked like he was gonna stop him out,
as you said.
I also think that all you need, you just
take out a gun. If you take out a gun,
everybody fucking runs. I don't know
why that guy didn't fucking broad.
That'd be it.
Just stunned.
Although I remember being at a meet and
greet one of the last ones I did and
this guy fucking went to take a picture
of his girlfriend or wife wanted a
picture with me and he went to reach into,
pull out his camera in a fucking loaded
nine millimeter fell on the floor.
Yeah.
And this is how I reacted. I
went whoa. And pointed at it.
Then he picked it up.
Yeah.
And ran out of there because we were in
a casino and it was on native American
land and you're not allowed. It turned
out he was an off duty cop. You know,
they kind of fucking handled it.
But I remember saying to the
security guys at Jesus Christ,
I go, you fucking see that. He goes, what
happened? I go up, fucking guy, just,
I had a loaded nine millimeter,
just fell on the ground and
the security guy goes, oh,
he's lucky I didn't see that. And I
was like an almost 10 in the, but, um,
that's where my,
my culdesac suburban upbringing came
into effect where that was my first with
that.
So I was stunned.
But now I've played that over
my head a zillion times over.
Okay.
That ever happens again? Kick the fucking
gut wall. If it's a glock, you know,
she can kick it. Anything else that
might go off? I, I tackle the guy.
Run anything other than be like,
oh, your gun's right there, sir.
Um,
all right.
Okay.
Uh, out of everything you said, I
really, truly believe that whole,
the reason why I don't fuck with people,
aside from the fact that I'm,
I'm half a century old and you know,
never really took any martial arts. I,
you don't know what the
fuck you're running into.
Okay.
You have no fucking idea that training,
the weaponry, the level of psycho,
the kind of day they're having.
MMM.
If a loved one just passed away,
you have no idea what's going on to
somebody fucking life and you are rolling
the fucking dice with your life
when you make a move like that.
And um,
which I owned it,
I understand,
but I think it is fucking insane that
there's a state out there that allows
citizens like the fucking wild west
to solve their problems like that.
You know?
Okay.
That you could just shoot an unarmed
guy that pushed you down on the ground.
It's just fucking, it's just, it's, that's
such some shit out of like Wyatt Earp,
you know, and I, I, you know, all your
gun guys are going to flip out. Okay.
Just just picture how the,
imagine the,
like the average fucking person drives.
Okay.
Just watch the average person go through
a fucking security line at the airport.
Okay.
The amount of awareness, the
amount of empathy, the mouth,
a mouth breather and fucking morons.
And the fact that any of them
can go out and get a fucking gun
and then stand their ground using debt.
Fucking 20 year old laptop between
their ears. That is their fucking brain.
I mean, that is some crazy,
crazy level of fucking
second degree. I mean, second
Second Amendment fucking freedom.
That usually leads to fucking second
degree murder as far as [inaudible].
And I am, I am not an anti
gun guy, but I am also like,
you know, I just don't
want people, you know,
walking around like they're
in fucking Westworld.
MMM.
All right. Girlfriend's parents
know in defense of Florida,
you don't see that every day though.
You know, you do not see that everyday.
So I don't know if they'd be,
there's already,
there's always arguments on both sides.
Girlfriend's parents know, hey bill,
I'm 17 going into my senior year of high
school and I'm dating this amazing girl
who's about to be a Jew.
Yeah.
Uh, she's half black, half Filipino,
Filipina IA is that he said Filipino.
Um,
I'm a few days darker.
I'm a few shades days,
few shades darker than a
piece of printer paper.
Anyways, uh, Hey, welcome
to the club buddy. Anyways,
we'd been dating for about a month now
and obviously we've hooked up a couple of
times and neither one of
our parents even knew,
uh,
a couple of days ago her parents asked
her if I was a virgin and for some God
unknown reason,
she told them that I had been with a
couple of other girls during high school.
That wasn't a big deal until today when
they started asking if her and I had
ever had sex.
Apparently she didn't get the female
line gene and told them everything.
Well, I mean, sounds like she has a really
open relationship with their parents.
I don't know what to do.
I'm sure as a dad you can imagine
what you would do to a guy.
In my position and her dad is six
foot four 260 pound black dude,
I'm about six foot two
one 60 on a good day.
So I'm not stacking up well against that.
I'm not looking forward to going back
over to our house and talking to her
parents or meeting her older brother
that's coming to town on Monday.
Any advice from you and Nia and how to
not get killed would be great. Yeah.
MMM
yeah,
dude.
I would be a fucking man about
it and I would go over there
and just be honest.
Just say what you'd done and how you
feel about her daughter and then what?
What are they gonna give me? What
are you going to do? I, I don't,
I dunno. I Dunno. How old are you?
Is is how old? You're 17 okay. See,
I don't know what the fucking hell.
How old is your girlfriend? Do?
Don't listen to me. I Dunno what the
fuck to do. I don't know what to do now.
You got me all fucking nervous.
I would have to think that if she fucking,
if he asked her,
they asked her what she's doing
and she was just honest about it.
They seem a little fucking
open minded. Like if, if, if,
I dunno, this is crazy
thing to say, but if,
if she knew that he was going to
flip out and try to fucking kill you,
why would she say something? Uh, she
could be scared of him. I Dunno dude,
you got yourself into a little
bit of a quagmire. I have no idea.
I have no idea,
dude.
Okay.
I would go over there and when he says,
hmm,
what's up little man, I'd be like, Hey,
um, you know, I guess
that's when, as a man,
you get into your hypocritical years
when you meet another guy who is doing
or trying to do exactly what the fuck you
were doing when you were 17.
It doesn't sound like you'll be a running
around trying to dog at the checks and
do all of this type of shit. I don't
fucking know. You know what? I don't know.
I don't fucking know.
And now I'm thinking of what's going
to happen when my daughter gets that
fucking age.
I have no idea.
Um,
all I know is that I'm hoping she's at
least going to be a brown belt in Jiu
Jitsu, you know, which I
actually, I, I, you know,
I think every woman
should learn that shit.
You know,
it's perfect. It's in close.
And if a guy's, you know,
doing something you don't want them to do,
it's so fucking easy.
Okay.
Armbar get them in a triangle because
there, you know what the fuck, you know,
choke 'em out and then just call
the cops. There he is. It's perfect.
You know,
I don't fucking know. I,
anyways, Jesus' question.
I get me thinking all this crazy shit.
I, all I can say is good luck to you sir.
And, uh, you've got some
decisions to make. I mean, what,
don't you want to keep seeing this
woman? I mean, what are you going to do?
I feel like you kinda gotta go over there,
so the guy respects you.
Then what's he gonna do?
Six foot four.
He's gonna beat the shit out of a 17 year
old. Wait a minute. You're not Florida,
are you?
If you're in Florida,
don't go over there cause he
might stand his ground. All right.
I gotta go you guys.
Uh, thank you so much.
You're awesome for writing in
all you women who wrote in.
All you ladies are rolled in.
I really appreciate that because I wanted
to give that woman some good advice
and we needed to hear it from the ladies.
Um,
I'm going to be in Las Vegas
this weekend with Joe. Nick,
I'm flying out in the fucking helicopter
and then the day after I'm getting up,
before I go home,
I'm flying over to Utah to fly through
some like fucking canyons and all this
shit that I'm coming back.
It's going to be fucking incredible.
And I'm picking up eight hours on
the stick, creeping towards 200.
That'll get me up to about a buck 85.
Okay.
MMM.
And, uh, I'm very,
very excited and I've decided that I want
to get my instrument rating as a pilot.
Cause every pilot I talked to is like,
that is a fucking game changer.
I just have to carve out
some time where I can do it.
And I figure if Tom Cruise could figure
out how to point it at the ground and do
fucking three sixties as he stored it,
goddammit,
I could get my instrument rating. All
right. That's it. Go Fuck Yourself.
I'll check in on you on Thursday.