Hey, what's going on as bill burn his
time for the Monday morning podcast from
August 6th,
2018 what's going on?
How are you doing?
I am back.
I am back in Los Honga. Oles you
don't look at my last hanger lays now.
Everywhere else I go is just as
hot as here, but it's not as nice.
Oh everybody walking around
sweating their balls off. You know,
you might as well be out here in
Hollywood with all the real people.
The forward thinking, progressive
people. How we, we pushed the needle,
we changed the needle, we drive
the sled, whatever the fuck,
whatever the fuck we're, we're
always saying about ourselves. Um,
and you won't, you won't find anybody
out here more phony than me. Okay?
I'm telling you that right now. You're
going to meet me and you can take, wow,
that guy is so down to earth and I
want you to know it is all an act.
Okay?
You're not at my level. Sorry. Um,
anyways, I just got back from,
uh, I did Rochester, New York,
I believe that's the first time I did a
gig out there. Did it with Dean del Rey,
Dean del Rey, murdering, stealing the
spotlight. Everybody fucking, you know,
flipping out about him.
You know,
we so interesting with his glasses and
his tattoos and I just come out right.
Fucking old milk toast Freddy.
Right? Nobody cares. No,
I had a great time. Um, I had
a great time with that crowd.
And what a beautiful fucking
God damn town. Put a coach.
Why can't it just say it was a beautiful
town? What a beautiful f and g d town.
I have got to stop cursing around my kid.
I have to,
I have to do that. I'm starting to do it
with adults where I just say like, uh,
yeah, and the f the F and guys in a hall
and then I just go, sorry, I got a kid.
I need the practice.
But is that any better cause that my kid's
going to be walking around like, yeah,
he fine. He's an FNA hole, right? It's
people that are still going to be like,
I don't,
I don't know.
It probably would still be
adorable cause I have to tell you,
I just came home and uh, it
was her nap time, but she saw,
I was expecting her to be asleep but
it was five minutes into her nap time.
But we have her on a schedule and so I
figured for sure she'd be taking a nap
and I came home and she wasn't,
I was like tip toeing in the house and
he's heard these little feet come running
out. Dat, Dat, Dat, dat, Dat, dat. It
is the best. It's the best thing ever.
One of the few things in life that is not
overhyped having a kid is the greatest
thing ever. So anyways, um,
Rochester, New York, gorgeous, right?
So I get there and a first thing
I see is a giant brick factory,
giant factory, smoke
stacks, the whole thing.
There's a little bit of steam coming
out of one of them, but you know,
flying in and I'm looking down and
I, I, you know, I'm doing all this.
I have a private pilot's license,
so I'm looking at the clouds,
trying to guess what's going on here.
There's a bunch of like, you know,
patches of clouds, a little
poofy, a little puff,
they're little ports or what does that
tell me? That tells me that there's,
there's,
there's a lot of uneven air there that
we're going to have a little turbulence.
Okay. Cause there's, there's the, the
air is being pushed up in certain areas.
It's not just straight across,
straight across. And it was even,
and they weren't like all big
and Puffy, you think, okay,
that's kind of some smooth fucking air
there. Right. I don't know if I'm right.
Ground school was a long time ago and I
fly out here in La and there's really no
way that should go along the
coast every once in a while.
So I looked down and I see this factory
and like I said,
it's, it looks like an old school thing or
they, they, they, they Brewen some beer.
Are they making some steel? What
are they doing there? And uh,
and I looked down and it was this giant
empty parking lot, couldn't see any cars.
And uh, so I was like, ah, you know,
they'll just turn that into lofts.
Everything just gets turned
into a place to live. You know,
a place where we made something
or was a place to go do something,
they'll just take it and it'll
turn into lofts and was just like,
we kept a lot of the character of this
place where we used to make things.
So would you like to move into this
luxury apartment with your Gucci bags even
though you're only making 50
grand a fucking year or whatever,
the whatever the fuck it is.
People,
please don't be that person everybody
because a old freckles head.
I got a bear. I got, I
got a bad feeling man.
It's like things are
not adding up out there.
Okay.
Everybody is walking around with
these car Dashi and level outfits are,
a lot of people are
and uh,
the amount of fucking 20 somethings I
see driving around in BMWs. It's like,
does everybody have a
fucking rich dad out there?
You driving around in a BMW okay with
your fucking Gucci glasses and all of this
shit. And then this is the
thing, nobody's at work.
This traffic 24 fucking seven.
I looked at a census.
The population really isn't,
at least the legal population isn't
really growing in this country.
I don't think if you are an illegal,
I don't think you're driving around in
a fucking BMW attracting all kinds of
attention to yourself. So unless
everybody's a fucking Uber driver,
but then where are they driving?
All those people during the day,
they're all late for work.
I Dunno.
I Dunno what's going on it
this, this, this, this happens.
This happens like every fucking
once every 10 years. You know,
first time I saw it was in the 80s,
everybody was doing blow all the yuppies.
Everybody was fucking walking around with
a Rolex and all of this fucking shit.
And then right there,
Fred over
all of a sudden you fucking, yeah,
I had nothing left in your nose.
Like he'd been boxing for 20
years. Right? Skinny ties are out,
z caviar, Ricci genes are in,
you're a fucking coke head.
You're fucked up your whole life. And, uh,
they repossessed you BMW then in the
90s. Right? It was a little rough time.
They're a little rough time
there. And then, uh, you know,
Bill Clinton came in according to the
Democrats, he turns it all around.
He saved it. There was a zero
fucking, you know, we had no debt.
He got us out of debt, you
know, of course, you know,
he used a couple of vaginas as a humidor,
but you know,
everybody's gonna have their faults.
What was he supposed to do?
Balance the budget,
play the saxophone and not fuck
around on his wife. I mean,
something's got to give.
And I'm telling you that right now is
a sober fucking person who is not drank
since June. Something has
got to give, you know,
maybe you go out, you know, maybe
you don't give into the boot, okay?
Maybe you don't bang an intern,
all right?
But if he had made you lay off the ice
cream and you don't watch Internet porn
and you're basically, you're going
to paint yourself into a corner.
And next thing you know,
you're driving down the street,
talking to yourself going, am I
really going to go out here? And, and,
and I guess do a thrill
kill. Is that what I'm doing?
Am I going to kill a hitchhiker right
now to just somehow inject some sort of a
rush into my life, right.
Sorry. Um, anyways, I'm coming
off the wagon tomorrow for
one day. For one day only,
uh,
me and Joe Derosa Hall.
Ah, I'll tell you right now, if I live
as could talk, they would say, let me up,
throw in the towel, get off of me. Um,
I dunno what they would say, but it would
be, they would give us a fucking, uh,
a thrashing, um, if they
could speak anyways.
That sounds like a fucking book.
If you're Oregon's could speak right
and you just stretch it out over like,
you know, I'm, I'm the organs. Do you have
like 10, you know, one days your liver.
Next Day's your kidneys.
Okay.
You know, and then one day to
Dick. All right, what would you,
Dick Sadia you don't,
nothing smart. You know,
you Dick's never going to be like, why
did we fuck that girl? You know? Yeah,
you're fucking,
your brain says that.
Okay.
You, Dick Never says that. You
take good know me. She was there.
Um,
anyways.
Okay.
I'll try to pancreas is just would be
like the fucking, just the grizzled vet,
you know,
union toll booth,
booth workers just sitting there with
a cigarette dangling out of his fucking
mouth doesn't give a shit. Right.
It's getting close to retirement.
I think the, your kidneys would be
the most progressive and annoying.
He could just drink some more
water. Sorry. Um, anyways,
so then after,
what is it after a,
okay,
Rochester.
I then drove down beautiful,
beautiful drive from Rochester all the
way down into a western Pennsylvania and
then down into Youngstown,
which I'd never gone to.
And I was say Youngstown was
like three hours away from Ohio.
It's like an hour and a half.
I thought Akron was way down there too.
I thought they were way down the
fucking east side down there. Uh,
Pittsburgh and shit, but they're
not, they're right there. So I went,
got to go to famous Youngstown a, it
didn't get to see shit. I came in,
I saw that there was some sort of Italian
feast festival going on in the streets,
which I would have loved to partake in.
But I'm on my diet.
Okay. I'm getting my revenge
body. Everybody, uh, no,
I'm sticking to my diet here.
I'm actually doing really well with it.
Until this morning I couldn't
find a place in the, in the,
in the airport that had oatmeal.
So I just,
I got some bacon and eggs with Hash
browns, toast. But every other,
every other meal I ate, I ate the way I
was supposed to be eating. So whatever.
That was my one fuck up. And you don't
have a cheat day, you have a cheat meal.
So that was a cheap fucking meal.
I got on the plane and the, and,
and the fucking stewardess was like, uh,
you know, I always have my headphones on.
Right? And so she's got a wave in front
of me and I go, yes. And she goes,
what would you like to drink? I said,
water with ice. I got, that's all I want.
That's all I want. I'm good. All right.
In five seconds later she's waving at
me again. Would you like to breakfast?
I was getting mad at her like, how the
fuck did she know that that's what I meant
for the whole flight. So it was
like, no, Nah, I'm good, I'm good.
I'll just have the fucking water.
You don't want anything.
Did I say?
I didn't say that,
but I thought it and she,
I could tell she was good at reading
people and she sensed it and she's like,
this guy's a Douche.
And you know what's funny was I was
still wearing my suit and tie that I had
worn at the rough and rowdy taping the
night before cause I just didn't feel
like packing the suit.
And every once in a while if you have a
backpack and a little wheelie, carry on.
If you also have the garment bag, they'll
be somebody like the Dudley do. Right.
You don't like the cop in the middle
of nowhere. That has no excitement.
So they got to like fucking,
you know,
see how far away from the curb you
parked so they can give you a ticket.
Someone will say, ah, I'm sorry
sir, you have three items,
you know?
And then she puts me okay
in the position to say,
oh, excuse me ma'am,
I'm flying first class.
I'm allowed to break the rules.
Okay, I have, I have, I
go to your Sky Lounge.
Do you understand? Do you have any
idea what the fuck my dad does?
She puts me in that position or he,
but I never say that,
but I definitely think it,
and that's what makes me down to earth
is I don't say the things that I think.
So then the world has no idea
how fucking arrogant I see that.
That's how that works.
Um,
which you got to have a little bit
of arrogance in life. If you don't,
then no one's ever going to make a
statue of you. That's how it works. Um,
so anyways, so we're all waiting in a
line up and they're doing the usual thing.
Anybody active military duty,
anybody with kids?
Anybody with less than four limbs,
ghee,
you can board the plane now and all this
shit. Nobody budges I'm like, oh great.
It comes group one and all of a
sudden this fucking dude, right bald.
He's got the horseshoe,
you know, buzz down.
But he didn't shave the rest of it
walks by perfectly fine. No camouflage,
no fucking limbs missing,
no kids,
you know, can see he's not deaf. He
just walks by all of us. He goes,
hey, how you doing? The
guy go there, what's up?
And he just fucking beeps his thing and
it gets on the fucking place. It's like,
go on.
Do you going to put on his little
fucking outfit once he gets down the, uh,
the jetway there?
Yeah,
I dunno. Anyways, you would
know I had a great weekend. Uh,
so I get on the God damn
plane and I'm like, you know,
I didn't get a lot of sleep
because the rough and rowdy,
Yvette was fucking unbelievable.
I am going to talk to you
about that. All right.
But it's gonna be a great story here.
So I'm sort of teasing that.
So he continued. I'll wait. You could fast
forward through all of this. Well, um,
I, I'm really into me TV
and old movies right now.
I just go through these phases
and I was watching this. Uh,
the postman always rings twice,
which I remember from the 80s,
and I thought it was an original
Brian Depalma film film.
I didn't know he remade it,
but it kind of seems like he took
the name of the movie and then he like
switched it up. He did the Jimmy Page,
you know what I mean? Like if Robert
Plant just switched the lyrics,
they wouldn't had a fucking problem.
Cause for a lot of those songs that Jimmy
get in trouble for, he, you know, he,
he changed the arrangement enough that
of Robert just switched up the lyrics a
little bit here.
I believe it when he says that he,
that he wouldn't have gotten in trouble,
um, or sued that many fucking times.
So anyways,
plowing ahead and watching this thick and
just some of the shit that they say to
women in these things.
This guy was in love with this woman
and they were trying to plot killing her
and at some point they, I dunno, they,
they came up with the idea and they
thought it was a good idea and they could
get away with it and they were excited
and he just grabs both their arms and he
goes, now kiss me before I sock. Yah.
And that was considered a music back
then because guys didn't know how to
express love, but there were guys beating
women where the guy's beating women.
But when did beating women become a fad?
Like when did that first happen?
I know grunge was in the early nineties.
I'll have to look that up. Um, and I'm
going to leave that open. Ended to,
cause somebody is going to post that
and then somebody is going to be like,
you know, is bill per really dense. Um,
anyways,
and then I was watching 77 sunset strip,
my favorite fucking show on TV and I'm
into the first season where they have
like the, uh, the matinee idol look
at and Efram Zimbalist juniors is,
he's like not even an in episodes.
And what somebody was saying was he was
basically the Steve Urkel of 77 sunset
strip.
They got him in there and then he just
kept getting more and more and more lines
that he just fucking took over and
then they phased everybody else out.
So anyways, the, uh, the Dream Boat
Guy, they're the lead of the show.
He's a, he meets this woman.
She goes, I'm convinced my,
my husband's trying to kill me. He's
having an affair with his secretary. Uh,
you know, I, the brake
lines were cut on my car.
He almost accidentally hit
me with his boat. And, uh,
I think he tried to poison
me when he made me a drink.
And what's funny is this woman
is gorgeous and this, this guy,
he's gotta be 40 years
older than her and a,
which amaze me that this guy was
already going to trade her in. You know,
cause that's what those guys do. They
just sort of collect them like a cars.
So I'm not saying there's anything
wrong with that. You know,
there's nothing wrong with the
objectifying a woman if it's that obvious.
You know what I mean?
Cause she's uh, what's,
what's the material I guess
gold dig in you yet? Oh,
it's like I know you're here
for this stuff and you know,
I'm here so you look good on
my arm and I can, uh, you know,
fuck something that doesn't even
remotely look the way I do naked.
It's an arrangement.
But what happens because
there's no love there.
Somebody always ends up pulling the plug
first and then it gets fucking ugly.
So anyway, she goes, this guy's
trying to kill me. She goes,
I'm convinced these haven't, uh, you know,
he's having an affair with his secretary.
So he goes down over to the
office to investigate, right?
And he comes walking in and you know,
he's about ready to meet a woman
cause the saxophone starts playing,
which was what they always did back
there, right? They just play the song.
There's this beautiful Asian woman
comes walking out and they just,
it's his secretary.
She comes out and the Sax
[inaudible]
right. He's always hitting
on him and shit. And this,
this is his opening line
under it goes. Yes. He goes,
they told me you're Boston ported
oriental art. I have to agree.
This is what he said.
The sad thing is,
is that same shit is still set
in a Hooters every fucking night.
Bio by a man of a certain age. And
then he grabbed her and said, no,
kiss me before he saw you.
MMM.
You know,
it's funny.
That's one of the first things I
said to Nina when I first came home.
Yeah.
It's just something, some
lines of too good. You just,
you just have to repeat them.
Sweeney it was,
let's get into rough n rowdy
number four from Youngstown.
Um,
unbelievable night.
I don't think I'm telling you why I
can't even believe I get paid to do that
shit. It's just like, it's
so much fucking fun. And uh,
I dunno.
It's usually just hanging out,
watching people beat the shit out of each
other. What, what, what's not to like,
like I, I've just, I dunno,
do you just sit there watching the
fights and even the ones that are bad,
they're hilarious. First of all,
the, the, the fight card started off,
it had two brothers like blood brothers
fighting each other and in their promo
videos, one was saying that
my mother never loved me,
you know, and I'm like, oh, Jesus is
this guy's the victim of the family.
And then his brother gets on and confirms
it goes, yeah, she fucking hates him,
you know, always hated him. Right?
All he does is sit around and play video
games and I'm in the National Guard and
I'm out here crushing it. So the brother,
when is it is, you know, a little,
uh, what do you call it, ric
flair, sort of a promo video.
He said that the military is overrated.
They're a bunch of this soft
fucking hilarious trashing his brother.
And then they went out there and they
beat the shit out of each other now.
And I had to root for the
older brother because I,
there's this unwritten rule.
I don't know if it's something
somebody told me or I just, I just,
just how I felt. You can never let
your younger brother beat you up.
You just cannot,
you cannot ever let that happen.
You have to be in the mindset of,
you know,
you're going to have to murder me and
I know you don't want to go to jail.
That's where you have to be mentally. You
just can't have it. CanNot fucking head.
Let that happen.
And I sat there and I watched it happen
on pay per view and I got to tell you as
an older brother, it made me
sick. Great fight though. Um,
couple of Youngstown firemen,
Jesus Christ,
one went in there and just fucking
knocked this guy out to the,
it was the first time I saw a guy really
get knocked out where he went to get
back up again and went back down
again. First of all, he, he,
when he first went down, he was doing
that thing. Do you know Bill Gates to do,
what's that thing that the guy from
the Carolina Panthers would do after a
touchdown?
It was a really easy sort of move,
which is why white people
are ruined it so quickly.
You sort of bring your
arms out to the side.
Yeah.
[inaudible] is that what they call it?
Yeah,
he looked like he was doing
that the way Bill Gates did,
where he didn't have his elbow bent.
He just draped it across his eyes.
Like the sun was beaming down there.
He was laying there like that.
And uh, and then he rolled over
and he went to get up and uh,
he went fucking back down
again and, and it was a, yeah,
that happened. And then, uh,
what else, what were some
of the other highlights? Oh,
pig versus punk.
The cop fight in the skateboarder,
skateboarder proved he was a punk.
He didn't show up.
So at the last second they got a bouncer.
Yeah.
So you got a cop and you got a bouncer.
Who's kidding?
Who a bouncer is just a cop
that never went pro. Right.
So it's a lot of overlap.
So they fucking get it in the ring and
all my, that's the cop, first of all,
I didn't realize he had lost
his job because he did a
drive along or ride along,
whatever the fuck you call it. And
uh, somehow the mayor got wind of it.
And you didn't fucking like it. So they
fired the guy and I got to tell you,
a bar stool sports, uh, paid
two years of the guy's salary.
Um, and anyways, he went
in there and Jesus Christ,
and this was a,
he fought a bounce and a,
granted the guy didn't fucking
have any time to prepare and uh,
and it looked like it. Holy
Shit. This guy was fast,
strong, knew what the fuck he was doing,
had decent footwork. I mean, you figure,
you know,
the cops,
they teach him some of that MMA shed
will stand up a little how to choke a guy
out or whatever. And uh, he just,
he beat the shit out of this fucking guy,
but I got to tell you,
the bouncer could take a punch man.
He fucking,
he ate all of them until the last one.
And then that was kind of it.
And um,
then the cop,
the cop got ops of out of the ring and
everyone's going like really huge date,
three inch day.
Like give him his fucking job back.
And then he proceeded
in the post interview,
I think to ruin any chance of ever
getting a job as a cop anywhere.
They said to him, they go, hey, so are
you upset? You know, did you do that?
The mayor, you know,
uh, stepped in and said,
your police chief, either it's you
or him, are you upset with him?
Now what he should have said was like,
listen to,
there's a lot of variables involved.
Um,
I have respect for the office of the
mayor and the mayor himself. He was,
Dee did what he felt was best and a,
I'm not gonna argue with that.
I'm just happy to have the opportunity
to come down here and get the people in
Youngstown some entertainment. That's
what he should have said. But he did like,
are you upset with the Mary's just
like, I don't give a shit. Yeah,
I was fucking mad and I fucking,
I brought that fucking anger in there
and he said, it's just like, all right,
that's a wrap on the criminal
justice. Well, who knows?
I will just say the tape is out there.
So if anybody ever like
where to do some sort of, I
dunno, Internet search on them,
but I think they kind of
just check to see, you know,
if you were watching any porn, you
know, isn't that kind of where they go?
I have no idea. And then the end,
the uh, the highlight, the a,
the headlining match gay pat versus
the two time convicted felon homophobe.
Okay.
Oh, and I almost forgot to
mention, uh, Pat McAfee,
former puncture of the country,
any Indianapolis Colts to that guy.
Absolutely crushed it as he would,
he was the MC for all the, uh,
the major.
They'd like four or five major fights
and he would go into the ring and do the
announcements and he
was fucking hilarious.
Hilarious. This one guy
went in his name, just,
we'll just say his name was
Edward Robinson the second,
and he was like standing
in the red corner,
hidden the sloppy gray shorts and
you'd go, this is this whole fucking,
they would like make fun of you. And
then he says the guy's name, he says,
like he says,
Edward Robinson does second.
The second day was more than one.
I'm butchering his delivery,
but he did just the way
he fucking ripped apart.
The fact that this guy went by the second,
the fact that he repeated the second
again and then tagged it with there was
more than one just so intelligently.
It's so succinctly fucking
basically says what everybody thinks
when they hear the second. It's like,
I don't who gives a fuck why you acting
like you're Henry the eighth. You know,
like you use some fucking king,
you just some fucking jackass.
Nobody gives a fuck.
And they did that too with the felon.
He is a two time,
two time convicted.
He was fucking unbelievable.
Unfucking believable. Um,
so anyways, gay pat goes in there
and I'm not gonna lie to you.
Everybody was nervous cause it was, you
know, it was a, it was this guy, you know,
he said all his fucking homophobic shit.
I ain't know he was also playing a role.
He was also helping a, you know,
sell the fight and everything,
but like nobody wanted to see
that, you know, and I, and I was
okay,
really happy that the whole
crowd was on pat side.
They were chanting his name,
Gay Pat Gay Pat, right. And, uh,
oh my God, I almost forgot fucking
raccoon boy. This guy went by raccoon boy.
He would wear a fucking raccoon
hat like Davey fucking crocket.
And for whatever reason,
he came down the aisle in a Trashcan,
one of those recycle fucking trash cans.
He was in there peeking out like a
fucking raccoon and they wheel them down
while they did his intro.
And then he tried to get his big body
out of there with boxing gloves on.
And it was some of the best
comedy I've seen in a while.
He was very upset that they didn't let
him wear his, uh, his leather vest,
which I thought in a very subtle way
was him giving support to gate pat.
Cause it was very al Pachino cruising.
It didn't look like a biker vest,
I guess when you're shirtless, you know,
he looked like a fat Freddie Mercury,
you know, if like if Freddie lived and
continue to eat steak Bob's or started,
I should say, he was always in good
shape, right. So anyways, and uh,
he went in there and he got,
uh, he got exterminated.
Okay.
It was another one there.
These two fat guys fight and one of
the fat guys was beaten. The share,
the other guy who went by the Dale
show and his name was not Dale,
and he was getting the shit kicked,
shit checked out of them.
And then the other dude had
to stop because he was so
fat that the head gear was
choking up.
And what killed me was,
it was like sort of looked like it
was underneath the bottom of his job.
But who am I to say that it wasn't,
it was probably the combination of the
strap under the jaw and the eight pounds
of blubber around the guy's neck.
Um,
and there was a lot of fucking wild
eyed people getting pumped up and then
wasting their energy,
trying to turn fear into courage.
You know,
like there was one guy,
he came out and he's just swinging wildly
and he got a couple of punches in and
then like his headgear got messed up,
messed up. So they had to, you know,
have a quick stoppage. And as they
were fixing it, he was going like,
like flipping out. And we're like, well
this guy's fucking crazy. And then he,
I don't think it landed another punch
for the, for the rest of the fight.
I think he let out all of that fucking
energy and that was over. So anyways,
this is all coming from a guy who would
get the shit kicked out of them by any
of these people. Okay. Um, so anyways,
gay pat comes in and he was
just totally fucking comp.
Went in there and then I saw the convict
going. I'm like, he's not that big.
He's only five, eight, one 80. So he's
a little stocky, but he's not that tall.
Gay Pat is six for a buck 80.
So they weighed the same.
So everybody knew that the convict was
going to bull rush him and everything.
And uh, I got to tell you, I'm gay.
Pat fought a filthy fight.
Mayweather would have been
envious with the amount of elbows.
This guy through forearms to the face, he
was leaning on him. He used his height.
He had a tremendous fucking strategy.
His corner was great.
They trained him and uh,
he came out with the victory and he
got some good shots in there too.
It was a, it was great.
It was one of the, uh,
then it was such a fucking relief
that he wanted, because yeah,
I was getting nervous that if he just
came in and took an right and was knocked
out really bad and the crowd
was actually against him,
like that could've gotten
really ugly. So, uh,
kind of dancing between
the raindrops on that one.
But I want to thank everybody at
Barstool sports for letting me do that.
I literally, when I saw the arena and
just, I just started smiling like,
I can't believe, you know, I go
to a zillion sporting events.
I've always wanted to be in the broadcast
booth. I know this is, you know,
not at the professional level,
but neither am I.
So the next one is going to be
in Kentucky outside this one,
like the Thrilla in Manila.
It's going to be outside.
This is going to be at a baseball stadium.
I believe it's October 5th in
Kentucky. Unfortunately. Uh,
I don't think I'll be able to make
that one cause I believe I have gigs.
I think I'm in Connecticut and
Boston that weekend, but uh,
I'm definitely going to rent it. Okay.
You get it for 15 bucks a few days,
but right up until the day
of the fight day, the fight,
it's fucking 1995 I'm telling you.
Tremendous night of entertainment.
Uh, anyways. All right,
so now that I've done that,
I'm going to read a little
bit of advertising here and
then we're going to talk
red sox, Yankees at New York.
Thanks. Hang in there. Okay.
Don't think this is, don't think I'm
going to talk about this the way ESPN did.
All right. I am not in that business.
All right. Frame. Bridge everybody
okay?
If you've been listening to this show,
you've heard me talk about frame bridge,
they make it super easy and affordable
to frame your favorite things from art
prints and posters to travel photos
sitting on your phone. Here's how works.
I just did this for all my
fifth turn and 50, um, you know,
pictures of me and my wife and uh,
Paris and all that shit.
All that great trip that we had.
I just sent them all this stuff.
I'm supposed to be getting
it this week. Uh, all right,
just go to [inaudible] Dot Com and
upload your photo or they'll send you
packaging to safety to safely
mail in your physical pieces.
Come on, Bill. You can read out loud.
Preview your item online
in any frame style.
Choose your favorite or get
free recommendations from
their talented designers.
Well, what's your favorite color?
The expert team at Frey Bridge.
We'll custom frame your item and deliver
your finished piece directly to your
door. Ready to hang instead of the
hundreds you pay at a framing store,
their prices start at just
$39 in all shipping is free.
Plus my listeners will get 50% off their
first order@framebridge.com when they
use my code. Burr, give your personal
experience using frame bridge.
I already fucking Dick.
How dare you.
Ask me to repeat myself. Frame
Bridge. Get started today.
Frame your photos or send the
perfect gift for weddings, birthdays,
and special events. Go to [inaudible]
dot com and use Promo Code [inaudible].
You'll save an additional
50% off your first order.
Just go to [inaudible] dot
com Promo Code burr frame,
bridge.com Promo Code Bar.
All right, Robin Hood.
All right. What is this stealing from
the rich giving to the poor? Where was,
what was the upside for him?
Okay.
Um, Robin Robin Hood is an investing
app that lets you buy and sell stocks,
ETF options and Crypt
Cryptos all commission free.
They strive to make financial
services work for everyone,
not just the wealthy non-intimidating
way for stock market newcomers to invest
for the first time with true confidence,
simple and intuitive,
clear design with data.
Data presented in an
easy to Gi digest way.
Other brokers charge up to $10 for every
trade. But Robin Hood doesn't chart all.
That's why they don't charge as much.
They don't charge commission fees, fees,
trade stocks and keep all your
and keep all your profits. Okay.
Easy to understand.
Charts in market date data,
place a trade in just four taps on your
smartphone. So how do they make money?
Robinhood web platform also lets you
view stocks collecting collections,
100 most populous selections
like entertainment,
social media and curated
categories like females, CEOs,
what people invest just
because they have a female CEO.
Jesus Christ is just,
it's fucking nuts now
and analyst's ratings.
So you can just do it. You can start
buying stocks in a sexist way. Uh,
an analyst ratings of buy,
hold slash sell for every stock.
Learn how to invest to
build your portfolio.
Discover new stocks and track favorite
companies with personalized news feed,
custom notification for price move.
And so he never missed the
right moment to invest.
Robin is giving listeners a free stock
like apple for it or sprint to help build
your portfolio. Well that's
nice. Sign up at Bill Barr.
MMM.
Diet. Robinhood Dotcom.
That's bill burr. All caps.
Dot. Robin hood.com. I like how they
give you the stock when free stock.
It's like the drug dealer giving you a
sample. Now. You like how that feels.
We get some more over
here. All right. Zip,
Brett.
You know, hiring used to
be multiple job sites,
stacks of resumes, a
confusing process. But today,
hiring can be easy and you only have
to go to one place to get it done. Zip
burden.com/burr ZipRecruiter
sends your sense,
your job to over 100 of the
web's leading job boards.
But they don't stop there with their
powerful matching technology zip
oh scans,
thousands of resumes to find people with
the right experience and invite them to
apply to your job. As applications
come in, zip recruiter,
he analyzes each one and spotlights
the top candidates so you never miss.
Miss. Um, great. Again, zip
is so effective that 80% of employees
who post on ZipRecruiter get a quality
candidate through the site
within the first day. With Revit.
With results like that,
I can't talk.
It's no wonder that ZipRecruiter is the
highest rated hiring site in a mayor
rare car. Uh, right now
my listeners can try zip,
yeah.com for free and this
exclusive web address,
ziprecruiter.com/burr that's
ziprecruiter.com/ [inaudible]
ZipRecruiter is the smartest
way to hire that zip.
Are We cru I t. E. R.
I just imagined during that whole read
everybody's girlfriend or wife going.
This isn't funny.
I don't understand beyond these.
Ah though.
Toe brds B and e's.
Fuck your fucking wife to do to
toe brds beyond these teller.
The get a life stop. Listen
to me while, oh, this is shit.
I'll take out my deck.
It piss on your Ted and put on
some fucking soft on Delaware.
That rubs my balls better than
you since we've been married.
How about a blow job
every once in a while.
All right, you've heard me
obsessed over me, over me undies.
You've heard me talk about how they are
three times softer than cotton and come
with fun new prints each month.
But I've got a big scoop that I'm so
excited to share with you all be on these.
Just gave their membership a massive
upgrade. All those dirty, old,
whole written fucking disgusting
underwear you've hung onto.
It's time to throw them all
out and give you a top drawer.
The refresher it deserves
each month. Yeah. Yeah.
If you keep your underwear for a long
time and you're a single guy like you've,
you've worn those through relationships,
you've worn those,
probably that same pair of
underwear when you picked her up.
I broke up with her and then met the
next fucking check each month me undies,
we'll release a new executive
print that only members can get.
Well I gotta be equal opportunity women,
you've probably wore those panties since
you went down to the Virgin Islands.
Get your fucking hair braided and bang
some guy in the island but didn't count
it cause it was in a different country.
These could be
collaborations with artists,
brands or other unique designs.
You're going to definitely want to have.
Members will also pay less for everything
on the [inaudible] website with
special member pricing. That means
if you want a second pair of undies,
a bracelet or a law or lounge pants,
you'll play less than anyone else.
The membership comes with no strings
attached unless she wants some kinky pair.
You know when we get like the laces
up the cracker, their ass. Nah,
I don't think they make those over here.
You could switch style. I say kinky.
How old am I skip the
month or cancel at anytime.
I love these undies
according to this copy.
They are the softest underwear I've ever
put on according to them and they come
with fun prints that I can
match with socks or a bralette.
They come with a hundred
percent satisfaction guarantee.
If you don't love him,
then fuck you man.
Just send them back for a full refund.
Me undies have a great offer for my
listeners. For any listeners, for anybody,
for first time's person,
jurors, purchasers, purchasers.
When you purchase any me on these,
you get 50% off and free shipping.
This is a no brainer.
Get 50% off a pair of the most
comfortable undies you will ever put on.
All right, lastly but not leastly.
Thank God man. I cannot fucking,
my eyes are going, I, I just,
I'm old and I've never been able
to read out loud. All right,
stamps.com everybody,
the u s postal service is an
important tool for any business.
stamps.com is the easiest way to access
all the amazing services of the post
office.
stamps.com never closes.
Print postage for any letters
or packages at your convenience.
24 seven print postage for any male
class right from your own computer.
The exact amount of postage every time.
Never underpay our overpay stamps.com
saved you time and money which you can use
to grow your GDF and business you a hall.
See that I'm practicing,
not cursing around my kid. Buy and print
official US postage for any letter,
any package, any class of bail using
your own computer, any product,
they'll send you a digital scale automatic
that automatically calculates exact
postage stamps.com we'll even help you
decide the best class of mail based on
your needs.
No need to lease an expensive postage
meter and there are no long term
commitments.
I use stamps.com to send out all my
posters that I'm selling on this tour.
I'm a moron if I can figure
out how to do it. So can you,
and right now you too can
enjoy the stamps.com servers
with a special offer that
includes a four week trial plus
postage and a digital scale.
Go to stamps.com click on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinburrthatstamps.com
enter
bar
are
right.
Let's talk some baseball
bump, bump, bump, bump,
bought up a pop up.
Wow.
The red sox sweep the Yankees.
How about that for game fucking sweet.
We didn't have Chris sale
data and Aaron judge,
but the fucking luck was on our side.
I thought,
I thought if we were lucky we were
going to split with them, you know,
and it was going to be, you
know, I don't know what happened.
It was just one of those things.
We were hot, they were not. And uh,
they should have one. Certainly
the last game, the last two games,
they should have won.
They blew leads in.
They fucking had a
meltdown in the last one.
So the red sox are now
nine and a half games up.
So what does that mean
to people in sports radio
on ESPN and all that shit?
You know what it means to them?
The race is over.
You know why it's over?
Cause we're up nine and a half games.
There's 48 fucking days,
probably even more. I just, I just counted
the games in August and in September.
What in the fuck I'm sitting there.
What are these people talking about?
Then it's like, oh yeah, that's right
there in the job of overhyping shit.
Hype it up to the fucking God damn moon.
And if it comes in,
you look like a genius and if it
doesn't come in then you gotta be like,
what happened to the Red Sox? What
happened to this guy? What happened?
What the fuck happened? They
started asking why? Acting like,
like the teams that they hype said they
were going to do what the fuck they said.
And I understand it now because
they are 24 hour sports network.
So what the fuck are you gonna do during
these 16 hours a day when there's no
fucking games going on? What
are you going to do? Yeah,
you just gotta. You gotta go
big. You got to say crazy shit.
So guys like me lose their fucking mind.
Do the fucking red sox were up
by like 16 or 18 games in August.
In 1978 the Yankees came to town.
That was the Boston massacre.
We had the one game playoff
and then it was over
the fucking,
the mets were like 9 million games out.
They came back in 1969 I don't have time
to look all this. This fucking happens.
Almost like dude,
the red sox wrap by like 1213
games like four or five years ago.
2012 and we shit,
the bed
didn't even make the fucking playoffs
did we had Valentine as a manager. Then
the next year we won the world series.
So I, I don't even know what they're
talking about here. This is far from over.
We have six games left
alone with the Yankees.
We got two series,
I believe with the Cleveland Indians.
Everybody's sleeping on Terry
Francona and the Cleveland Indians.
I still think Terry is the best manager
of baseball. Uh, he, he, you know. Um,
and what about the Houston Astros?
Okay.
They're no slouches either.
And how about the fact that despite the
fact the Yankees a nine and a half games
out, there's still six
games up in the wild card.
Okay.
So according to what I was watching,
that dude Mike box seat Mike
from the old Mike and Mike Show,
now he's on a different show.
He was saying the tea according to him,
it's essentially fucking over despite
the fact that the red sox have blown
leads. Historically 1812 gay, we
fought, we fought, we fucked this.
This franchise alone is fucked it
up twice in my life that I remember.
Okay.
I don't have time to look up the
other ones. Okay. And then, okay,
so now using that logic,
I don't mean to just put it on him
because everybody was saying it all right.
Using just that fucking logic.
The Yankees being up
six games in the card,
they only need to be up six games for
another two weeks and then the wildcard is
over. Is that how the math
works? That's another thing too.
All the Yankees got to do is just keep
playing the way they've been playing all
year and they're going to
win the wildcard. Okay.
Which means then we all go to the
playoffs were all zero and zero.
Yeah.
So you know what happened this weekend?
A whole bunch of nothing
because the greedy MLB once or wildcard,
they want more people in the playoffs
so they make more fucking money.
Cause you know you can't make enough
fucking money in defense of Major League
baseball,
the Federal Reserve is a private
corporation that prints the money for this
country.
So they keep us all running on the wheel.
Even those guys was their mistresses
in their yachts and their masquerade
parties and all that. To the point they
have to keep adding rounds of baseball.
See like right now as a red sox fan,
I would be excited that we swept the
Yankees if there wasn't a fucking wildcard
that just negates the whole thing.
So
what is all that that meant was maybe
if we meet the, uh, the Yankees,
maybe 50, 50. If we meet
the Yankees in the playoffs,
if we continue to win the way we do,
the first two games of the
series will be played at Fenway.
That's all that meant.
Okay.
Everybody just stand down and
fucking relax. Dude. I got,
I got a bet with my agent and Paul Versey.
I bet him 50 bucks each and been
doing it the last two seasons.
We bet the, uh, the red sox Yankees
series, you know, whoever wins, you know,
the regular season series, right?
And then if we go to the playoffs,
I think it will bump up to 100 bucks
a game each. Right. Keeps it fun.
It got me back into baseball and I am
fucking loving baseball now. Right?
Um, those two guys, they had
their fucking head in the oven.
It was hilarious. Fucking
hilarious. It's just like
you guys a Yankee. We'd been up 18
games and you guys and you came back.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Jesus Christ,
just packing it in.
And maybe we maybe actually questioned
both of them as human beings.
I really hope to hear this,
you know, fuzzy right now.
You can't rob a bank with that guy.
The second anybody goes,
like if ric flair walked by
and went, whew, you know,
he would think the cops were coming and
he would just pack it and you would that
you think we would think it was over.
Now I've got to be thinking my agent,
you know, when a a a, a promoted
pushes back a little bit,
he's not getting me the
best deal. Um, anyways,
so there's plenty of time left. I
am really looking forward to, uh,
when the red sox have a, uh, the Indians.
And then we also play the Astros are the
two that I'm paying attention to. Oh,
pay the Astros and September 7th,
eighth and ninth.
And I'm hoping Justin Verlander is
pitching because I want to see how we do
against that best.
MMM.
And then we get some, you know, yeah, we
got to, we've got one series in August.
I don't have Internet access
here for some fucking reason,
but in September we got the Indians on
the 21st 22nd and 23rd and then I believe
we closed up September. I always think
that not they play for the first three,
four games in October.
But we have a,
the Yankees 28 29 30 if not October
1st maybe my cell phone will work here.
MMM.
Like how funny is that with
you have 48 games left Europe,
nine and a half games on
this one team that you're,
you're still going to play six more times
in everybody's gone. Yeah. Yeah man,
it's fucking over.
I'll tell you right now.
That's why most people's dreams don't come
true. You know, not because of the, the,
the patriotical fucking
structure. Whatever the fuck
people are saying nowadays.
It's cause you quit.
Yeah.
All right. And I'm not saying that things
are, are, are, are unfair out there,
but like nobody gives a fuck.
Nobody cares.
Everybody's too busy trying
to keep this shit afloat.
To have time to give a shit about you
and your fucking drink. All right.
So why don't you grow the fuck up?
I don't know.
I'm just trying to fill time right here,
people.
I don't mean to fucking come down on
you, man. What's the next October?
Okay,
no game scheduled. Wow. Look
at that. No Games in October.
I can't remember the last time they
finished the regular season is September.
That's kind of cool. They're playing
the world series in like November now.
I guess they got to get
ready for all the playoffs.
All the rounds of the playoffs. Playoffs.
Um, anyways. All right, let's read some.
Uh, so anyways, it was great to see
them when all those fucking games.
It's nice to have that kind of a lead,
but I am by no means thinking that this,
this is over by any stretch of the means.
I will think that it's over when,
uh,
we're up nine and a half games with eight
games left and the Yankees are out of
the wildcard to,
that's when it's over.
Other than that, it's, it's
gets game on there. All right.
Frame Bridge. Everybody. Uh, if
you've been listening to this show,
oh wait, what the fuck am I
doing? I'm reading the Goddamn
advertising. All right,
podcast comment. Hey Bill, on your
latest episode on Jesus Christ,
I really feel like I'm going
to get shit here. You're,
you said you don't appeal to women,
but just wanted to let
you know you have a des.
Okay.
That creeped me out.
Um,
all right.
Just for the record,
I'm 50 years old.
That was from a 23 year old son.
God,
if I fucking sat across the table from
a 23 year old, I give her a rattle. Um,
who's your will? Will
get bulky. Why we hated,
why we hate other redheads.
Jesus Christ. Hey, what's up?
Okay,
Billy,
no glutes.
I was listening to an old podcast when
you were talking about the paper planes,
music video, and that a group of
redheads made you feel weird. Yeah.
It was weird to see because you never,
you never see us.
You never see just a giant
group of redheads. You know,
we're like the spice in the stew.
You know what I mean? We're not,
we're not the beef in
the stove. Right. Uh,
I can say that I totally
agree with you on that part,
but I would actually go a
little bit further with that.
Of course you would say and say that
I hate or despise other redheads.
Oh, this is a self hating reddit. I
didn't say I was a self hating redhead.
Uh Oh Jesus. Here's my reason though.
They make me look bad. Simple.
I'm a normal guy, kind of tall.
Try to hit the gym often enough.
So I have what you once
called a standing six pack.
But most of the fucking red
heads are a fucking disgrace.
Just started shaped Dorky on athletic
unfunny losers with no charm.
Don't get me wrong. There are
exceptions, but not many. Anyway,
go fuck yourself and bring your balding
red headed ass to Iceland. You can't.
Um, I think with any
group that gets picked on,
you're hypersensitive in a negative way
to the way that people around you are
behaving.
Cause I know what it's,
I've seen the big pasty freckled shapeless
arms that for some reason they're
wearing like a, a a tank top.
I, I definitely agree with you.
I do feel that that necessarily women I
do feel with guys is a redheaded mail.
There's a certain level of
shape you have to stay in.
MMM.
Cause you're already going
to get picked on. So, um,
I and I do understand some
of that, but I am not a, uh,
I'm not self hating.
I don't hate the way I look.
I actually think I'm a good looking
guy. I do make fun of myself, but like,
mmm.
I Dunno. I don't get like, I
had never been anything else,
so I don't know what the fuck, you
know, that would be like, but uh,
I do feel bad for redheaded
kids now because of
mmm.
You know, that South Park episode, like
the level of shit that, that like, that,
that probably started, you
know, I can't, I can't,
can I play and I can't play them up.
Too Big of a fan.
I would say maybe whenever that
kick of Ginger Day came around,
like I'm so glad
I can't tell if I'm glad that that wasn't
around when I was a kid or I'm kind of
jealous because at least you knew
what date of fake sick on, you know,
as a redhead.
Like whereas when I was coming up there,
got to see like that was more
of a week rather than a day,
but a whatever it or what doesn't kill
you makes me, makes you stronger. Uh,
all right, Tom Cruise, helicopter. Um,
okay. Hey there. Billy Bald. The wise, uh,
Billy bald.
The wise,
I always feel like I should be figuring
out what the fuck that means. Bald,
the wise, the wise is, that's another
English word, kind of Billy Ball.
The wise, is that like a
character? I don't know. Anyways,
just wanted to hear your thoughts
on the new mission impossible film.
I have to see it. I haven't seen her
yet. I'm seeing three movies this week.
I'm seeing the Mr. Rogers movie.
I'm seeing eighth grade and
I'm seeing a mission possible.
All right.
So I'm seeing something from my childhood
and seeing how millennials deal with
being in the eighth grade and then I'm
just watching a big summer blockbuster.
So I feel like I'm, I'm, I
got a nice fucking, you know,
smorgasborg what the fuck's
going on out there? All right.
Just want to hear your
thoughts on a new mission.
Impossible and how Tom Cruise is
notorious for doing his own stunts.
Do people understand what the word
notorious means? That that's like a,
that's basically known
usually for a bad thing.
Um, I'd say he's famous
for doing his own stunts.
I feel like a lot of people don't know
what infamous in notorious meets. Uh,
anyways,
I read,
he learned how to fly a helicopter in
about three months for the film as a pilot
yourself,
that seems like a short amount of time
for someone to do the action sequence and
start work that was displayed.
Check out the link below. Thanks.
And Go fuck yourself. Well, I
think there's a, there, there,
there is a lot of this,
they're trying to sell a movie,
so whatever he did, they're going to,
they're going to shrink it down. Um,
but I don't care how long or how short
the amount of time he did what he did,
took an unbelievable amount
of fucking balls. And, uh,
I was talking to some director,
he goes,
I can tell you without a doubt bay
definitely shut that shit on the last day.
Meaning if he killed himself to think
that they could easily put a stunt man in
there and they would still
have a movie, I don't know. Um,
I, I've just only seen the movie clip, Eh,
but there is no fucking way ever in my
pilot and career would I ever do anything
like that ever.
That's how I can fucking
tell you no fucking way. Uh,
I like to live, you know,
that's my shit. Ed. Uh,
I don't have problem with
stuntman. I really, you know,
I don't want to see them act and they
don't want to see me jumping in front of a
fucking moving car and I
stay out of their laid.
I look how I'm acting like
I'm at Tom Cruise's level.
I just like that shit where you jumped
from one building to another and they
kept it in the film and he like broke
his foot or something like that. Uh,
yeah, that's like, like Jackie
Chan does shit like that. And then,
then Tom takes it to the next level
where he's, he's like, well, is he,
as far as I can tell you essentially just
knows the helicopter over and just was
flying straight down at the earth while
spinning. I believe, added that to it.
Uh, which I really believe is hard
enough to do on a fucking airplane.
Forget about an a helicopter,
like I don't understand. Um,
okay.
I don't know how that works, but
uh, you know, hats off to that guy.
That guy is, and he can also fly like
a, like a fucking jet, like a g five,
like just get in the
thing and fly to England.
Like I believe he's that level of a pilot.
Uh,
I would tell you though,
I would definitely rather fly with John
Travolta cause it seems like, you know,
he dresses up like the captain and he
just, you know, straight and level.
It just sort of flies
where I feel like Tom Cruise big oh shit.
Look at that.
And it would just do a fucking barrel
roll just to scare you so you can laugh at
you.
I remember having a long time ago telling
his story on fucking Letterman where
they,
yeah,
they were up front and they thought it
was funny and they deep pressurize the
cabin and they made the
guy in the back pass out.
They didn't like 100% but
they somehow made the,
the oxygen, I dunno, the mixture of it. I
don't know if there's too much to oxygen.
So he fucking overloaded on it and
got lightheaded and passed out. Uh,
I dunno,
but all I remember he was crying laughing
when he said it and I was like, yeah,
that guy's fucking guy's nuts.
But I,
I'm definitely going to see the movie
and I am a huge Tom Cruise fan. I had a,
I didn't, you know,
he's one of those guys.
I didn't realize how big a fan I was
until one day they listed all these movies
and I realized I saw like 80% of them.
MMM.
Yeah. Kind of like when you go to,
somebody dragged you to a concert.
Like I don't want to, I mean,
I know they are. I mean,
I'm a radio fan of them and then you
get there and you're like, oh fuck.
They sing this song to, Oh my God, dude,
he's fucking awesome. Next thing you know,
you come home, you're downloading all that
music. That's what Tom Cruise is like.
Well, I can't wait to see the movie.
Uh, it's perfect. Scott. Tom Cruise,
he's got helicopters and they shot a lot
of it in Paris. I mean, I'm in, it's over.
Um, anyways, lady asking for advice.
Hey Billy, no buns. I'm
loving this. You motivate me.
I'm going to the gym right after
this and I'm doing some squats. A,
I'm a 23 year old woman. Oh
by the way, I, I cannot, I,
I got one of those little fucking,
you know, you know, this little, uh,
foam rollers already had one of those,
but I've been using that religiously and
then I got one those little balls that
you could just roll out your fucking
legs, your glutes, your back,
the whole fucking thing when you're on
the road. If you're an old person like me,
it is a game changer. Game Changer. Uh,
anyways, I'm a 23 year old woman from
London and I love your podcast. Oh,
thank you. I'm crushing it with a
23 year old ladies this week. Uh,
you always say you want to
hear from more of US ladies.
I do cause it gets to one,
one side. So here I am.
I would love your advice
on my current situation.
My parents were quite strict when
I was growing up, so I never,
I have never been on a date before.
Yeah I would say that goes a
little beyond. Quite strict.
I would say suffocating.
I still live at home.
I'm studying for my masters.
They are less strict now as my brother
is now married and they are now more
comfortable with me dating.
Well what the fuck is their problem?
I do that. That's like
sad. You should, you know,
lets say go out and fucking you know,
get gangbanged here but I you know,
go out and you know,
go on a date experience finding love,
losing it and fucking
yeah
that weird thing when you finally
erased their number on their phone.
I mean I can't, I know your phone. I can't
believe you missed all that. Anyways,
I'm studying part time and I am
working for the rest of the time.
How do I go about meeting New People?
The people I work with are all in their
mid forties and don't really socialize
outside of work. Any advice would be
appreciated. All right. Number one,
don't fuck any of those 40 year olds.
Okay.
Your work with them and they're
rolled. Don't do it. Okay.
God knows where the fuck those old dicks
of Ben stay away from him. All right.
You like a fucking one of those, you
know those, those nerds by the uh,
Star Wars action figures and it's a big
thing of the box has never been opened.
Your box has never been opened. All
right. It's worth a lot of money there.
Um,
yeah,
and also you're asking me how to meet
people when I've been out of the dating
scene for like 15 years.
I'm 50 years old and at no point in
my life was I still living at home,
studying for my master's
while having a job.
I love that you felt enough about me that
you thought at some point in my life I
attained that level of success.
It was that pressed for time. Um,
how do I go about meeting New People?
Don't you guys just like
go on apps dating apps?
You know what? I'm actually gonna I'm
going to phone a friend on this one.
The rest of the podcast listeners guys,
how do you do it ladies?
I should ask the ladies how
in this day and age, good,
someone with a vagina, 23 year old vagina
that has not had the seal broken yet,
how can they go out into the dating world,
avoid the dirty dicks and have a
nice entry into the dating world,
a positive experience that's going to
make her not be jaded and think that maybe
her parents were right for fucking,
you know,
keeping her chained to a radiator for the
first quarter of a century of her life.
Uh,
how should she go about doing it?
I feel like dating apps is a lot of
guys on there just trying to fuck,
you know, and then they, there's
these, no, no, that's that APP.
That's that app where people just trying
to hook up this app is the more serious
app or what's to prevent someone to
go on there and just act like they're
looking for a relationship or they
just want to bang you. So, um,
the first thing I would say, if you have
the time is it you need some sort of,
uh,
activity that you're involved
in that involves you, uh,
socializing with
the,
you know,
men and women basically. I don't know
what it is. You know, going to bars,
getting hammered and shit.
That's usually not gonna.
You're not gonna meet a nice guy there
for the most part. Uh, I would say,
I don't know.
Join a softball league.
You meet a lot of women there. Uh,
volleyball. What it was, I mean,
I'm old fucking start riding a dirt bike.
Maybe you'll meet some guys out there and
the trail. Uh, they're dusty. Dick's. I,
I mean, I don't, I don't know
how to, I don't know how to
help you here. I'm sorry.
Uh, I, I, yeah, I got a, I
got a phone. A friend. Yeah.
You guys gotta help me out here.
Help this lady. Okay. Put on, on in,
in the subject.
Put A,
okay.
Uh, what do, what do you,
23 fresh box.
All right.
Fresh box 23, let's call it
that. All right. And you send it,
email me your advice. Okay. And
then we can fucking figure it out.
We can help this lady up
because, uh, you know,
I have empathy for you that
you're late to the game.
I showed up late to the game.
I showed up at above fucking halftime
down 40 points. Alright. Dilemma.
Would you rather get punched in the
head by Mike Tyson in his prime or get
kicked squared and the nuts by Bruce
Lee. Oh, easy. Bruce Lee. Dot. A. Dot.
L. Dot. A. Dot. I would
go to a sperm bank app,
my sperm frozen before I had yeah,
that happened. And, uh, you know,
then I would still have my brain intact
to intelligently be able to tell the
woman that I ended up falling
in love with why I allowed
the greatest Asian of all time
to kick me square in the nuts.
MMM. I mean, Mike Tyson,
I'd still have my balls,
but I might be drooling on them
afterwards as I sit down de de Lou. Uh,
that was a disgusting image. I didn't
mean to say that. All right. For the,
for the Tyson choice. Oh, I'm sorry. Your
hands are tied behind your back. Okay.
Now I know I have details.
Your hands are tied behind your back.
Tyson can wind up and is told to cause
maximum damage to your head with one
punch. It's going to be
his famous overhand, right?
Yeah, no, fuck that. Fuck that.
You know there's another thing too,
is this way better footage on Mike
Tyson than there is on Bruce Lee for the
Bruce Lee choice. You are spread
eagle and cannot defend yourself.
I assumed you can only wear a European
man Thong to give you a semblance of
dignity.
I appreciate that Bruce Lee is
told to cause Max maximum damage.
Jia manhood with one kick.
He will get a running start.
Do you choose Mike Tyson or Bruce Lee?
I still got to go with Bruce Lee.
You know what I mean?
What is my quality of life going to be
if Mike Tyson gives me permanent fucking
brain damage, but my junk
is still intact. All right.
If Bruce Lee obliterates
my dick and balls,
but I've already frozen my fucking sperm,
I could still have kids.
Um, I don't know. I let my wife fuck
other guys, I guess. I don't know.
I don't know what to do at that point.
Uh,
but you know, I, I could
still have my brain,
but then my brain would be all day long
in a loop going, you don't have any junk.
You don't have any junk. You
know what I mean? Junk. Yeah.
But you know what?
If I was still at my brain,
I could be smart enough to figure out how
to kill myself. All right? So I would,
I would go with the Bruce Lee.
Okay.
You know, it'd be funnier than
watching me get kicked in the balls.
Spread Eagle wearing a European man song
is,
you know,
the only thing is funnier than that
would be the yell that I let out as Bruce
Lee was running at me.
I think it would sound a little like this.
It would just be like,
and then watching my
inner thighs flexing is,
I tried hopelessly to
try to close my legs.
Um,
oh, that would be the worst too. If
your legs were tied, Spread Eagle,
I mean immediately get kicked in the
balls, you go into the fetal position.
I would not be able to do that,
you know,
which I would think it would make it your,
your body stay and even more of panic
mode because then you go into fetal
position,
you know,
it kind of covers up your junk unless
you have old man balls and they score it
out back.
Right.
MMM.
At which point somebody walks by and
accidentally kicked some, you know,
like when you fucking think you clear the
door and you actually stubbed your toe.
MMM.
All right. That was disgusting.
Okay. That's the podcast man. Um,
I hope you guys enjoyed it. Thank you to
everybody that came out in Rochester. Uh,
thank you to all the guys at, at, at,
uh, um, I want said rough and rowdy.
Everybody at Barstool sports,
rough and rowdy.
I had such a great time and thank you to
all the competitors that showed up and
entertained everybody. I
had such a great time. Uh,
if there's a way for me to get to the
one in Kentucky, I'm going to be there.
If I can't,
I'm going to be,
I'm going to be watching it
either in Connecticut or an,
uh, Boston, Massachusetts,
uh,
with a bunch of my friends.
MMM.
That's it. Oh, freckles
is in town this week,
and I think by next date
I have is in Las Vegas on,
uh, August 18th. I believe. That's it.
Uh,
go fuck yourselves and I'll
check in on, yeah, on Thursday.