Hey,
what's going on?
It's Bill Barr and his time for the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 3rd, 2017 what's
going on out? Yeah.
How's it going? Oh, Jesus.
What to talk about first?
Uh, no, I am not a father. That's not
why this is fucking late. All right.
Now I just lost all my female
female listeners. I was at
the rose bowl yesterday.
That's why I did not record.
Okay.
I watched a bunch of college
football this weekend.
Wow,
man.
Right. I watched a bunch of,
a bunch of college football.
Got into this huge debate with Jason Law
had before the Ohio state game going,
dude, I still don't get how the
fuck you guys are in the playoff.
And Penn state isn't, you know,
you guys lost to Penn State,
head to head and Penn State one
year conference championship.
That would be like if,
if the Yankees won the American league
east and the Red Sox won the wildcard and
then the red sox got to compete in the
playoffs to possibly win a world series
and then the Yankees didn't,
that makes no fucking sense whatsoever.
And he starts going, well, I'll tell you
what I know we had our, we had three,
the most impressive road winds of any
tea but bubble just all of this shit.
And I just kept going,
you bleed scarlet and gray.
If this was happening to your team, you
would say it was bullshit. And he said,
no I wouldn't.
I be asking why a Washington,
The Washington huskies were in it like
he would have no problem with a team that
his team beat. And when the fucking
camera give me a fucking break. Right.
And then what happens?
What happens?
Ohio state goes out and plays Clemson
and they go out and proceed to get their
asses
by a bunch of Goddamn nerds,
nerds,
31 to nothing.
Clemson just fucking
completely dominated them.
And in the end Bly had sends
me this fucking text, he said,
I can see blah blah blah blah blah.
And then I just sent him a picture
of Joe Paternal shrugging and said,
I didn't see nothing.
Maybe that's what part of it is.
Maybe that's why they still don't want
Penn state to be in there, you know?
Cause at the end of the fucking day,
the end of the day,
this guy kind of fucking,
you know,
it was a lot of shit going on in
the shower there. And the guy,
he fucking didn't say nothing.
It was so weird about being at the
game cause I was rooting for Penn state
yesterday at the amazing,
amazing fucking game by both teams.
The quarterbacks he bolts
set like tide or set,
I'm zillion fucking records is the
highest scoring rose bowl in history.
Uh, at one point both quarterbacks
had four touchdown passes,
which I don't think I think that tied
a record or not. I can't remember.
And then won the, uh, the red
headed kid there through his fifth,
I think it was ran and I was
fucking sitting way up there. Um,
he threw his fifth touchdown. So,
uh, final score was, what was it,
52 to nine.
The over under was 53 and a half.
So,
um,
Penn State score 28 points
in the third quarter.
It was just a fucking amazing game.
And two things bug me when I watched
when I was there though. Of course,
it's always something that
bugs me. Okay. Number one.
Okay.
The fucking, uh, at one
point they were showing all,
like the coaches were one
of the Roosevelt, whatever.
And Joe Paternal goes
up there and this is,
he gets a bigger operation
than anybody else.
Bigger ovation than anybody else.
How important are sports?
How important is fucking
winning of fucking Game Day?
These Penn state people?
Evidently that's more important than if
you look the other way is some poor kid
in a fucking shy. I'm, it's just fucking,
it's, it's unspeakable. All right.
I just fucking, I'm stepping
away from that fucking program.
I've always liked him. You know, I was
still kind of rooting for him. I was like,
wow, you know, these kids here in
the field, they didn't fucking do it.
These other people are, uh, they are
innocent of Alban and then they show,
you know, they show the fewer
up on the fucking there. Yeah.
Just like, all right,
fuck these people. Right.
But then USC and their fence,
you know,
USC fans of the classic,
all day Yolo Douche is,
you know what I mean? It's,
there's just so fucking hard to root
for it despite the fact, you know, um,
oh, Jay Marcus, Allen, Oj pre murders.
Like if they put Oj up on the screen,
you know, I wouldn't have fucking show.
I probably would've just to be a cunt.
All right. I'm a Penn state fan again.
I don't want to f I don't know. What, what
are you doing at situation anyways? Um,
so Penn state a USC, USC,
it looks at looking like
they're going to win the game.
Okay. And then Penn state comes
roaring back in the third quarter,
which by the way,
took like an hour in like 10 minutes.
It was the longest quarter of my life.
The TV timeouts,
we're fucking ridiculous in
that game. Actually said to
my buddy, I was just like,
dude, you know what?
This is the most boring,
exciting game I've ever been to
in my life. It was like every,
it was like if you watch
watching Goodfellas and
every fucking three seconds,
somebody just hit pause
on it for two minutes.
That felt like 10 minutes
fucking referee standing around.
They fucking reviewed everything.
Everything.
But the fucking coin toss they reviewed,
they take game was like four hour,
well over four hours long. So anyways,
Penn state comes roaring back.
Fucking USC fans, few of them left,
most of them stayed. And anyways,
long story short, they end up coming,
you know that they were down by like a,
I can't even,
it was like 27 14 the
next thing it was 35 27
then I think it was (353) 053-0520
seven Penn state than 35 35 then two
whatever, 35 then 49 35 and
that's right. Then Penn state,
I mean USC came back and
score two touchdowns. Right.
And when they tied the
fucking USCW USC players,
just the way they act, their program
is the fucking worst. They're the,
they like that type of a program.
I can't stand like,
do you remember the first game of the
year when they played Alabama and when
they were coming out of the tunnel,
there's a bunch of them acting like
they were these crazy dogs at the end,
the leashes and they were lunging forward.
Somebody pulling it back.
Oh you guys all, you wait to see
what the fuck's going to happen here.
And then they go out there
and proceed to get their asses
by a bunch of God damn rednecks.
Red fucking Alabama kicked to shit.
It was like 52 to go fuck yourself,
whatever the final scores.
And then after all that fucking shit,
then they just kind of hit good game,
good game. They just scurry
off the fucking field. Right.
And then yesterday you see when they win,
right? They like, first of all, when they,
they, they tied the game up, you know.
And I would say on some ticky tack,
fucking a pass interference calls.
But like USC was getting
fucking screwed earlier.
They had a couple bullshit.
It was just sorta we fucked you guys
twice and then uh, we'll, we'll,
we'll fuck the other guys twice. Okay,
well balanced it out here somehow. Um,
couple of pass interference thing.
So when they scored the touchdown to tie
it up with like a fucking minute left
or something, dude, all the
scoring that Penn state did,
I mean they jumped up and down. That
was it. Two fucking USC, the guy,
they scored one in zone.
This guy with no helmet on,
runs down the sideline to
the entire other end zone.
Like Ah,
doing that 300 Yelp,
like he fucking scored. Even then I
would have been like, dude, relax.
It's a fucking tie game
all jumping up and down,
all up on the benches
with their fucking Jersey,
spinning them around over their fucking
heads and it's a Thai fucking game.
And then in the end, right, by the way,
Penn state totally played fucking
Marty Schottenheimer ball. Marty Ball.
I swear to God. Like every time they
had a first down towards the end,
they just written the first play was
running right up the middle. Right?
Nia centers fucking ass for no, no
yards. We're burning out though.
Where were you know were taking time off
the clock? They would do when that shit,
I said I'm actually star. I'm convinced
that the prevent defense, by the way,
is actually a,
it's a scam that was come up with by the
heads of the leagues that is executed
by the coaches to make sure every fuck
as many games as humanly possible can
come down to the wire so people will
continue to watch that fucking thing.
Once again, did not work. I can't
even begin to tell you. They just,
you just going to give them
the first fucking 80 yards.
Then you're going to play defense and
hope that you hold them to a field goal.
That's a philosophy and the we'll just,
we'll take away the sidelights.
I'll give him the middle of the,
everybody knows how it fucking works in.
All it does is ensure that on the
final fucking three, four plays,
the other team now has a chance to win.
You've been playing defense,
you've been shutting them down.
You've been throwing the fucking ball.
You've been kicking their ass and then
all of a sudden hand up off the middle
every fucking time. I Dunno. Drove
me up the fucking wall. So then you,
when USC finally wins it right after
letting up 49 fucking points and then they
score 52 the second day when at the
entire team runs down the field,
not towards the field
goal kicker to celebrate,
who by the way was doing that stupid
dap thing, the entire fucking thing.
Trying to get like a sneaker deals, like
what kind of kicker gets a sneaker deal?
They got like half a deal if they
just get it for their kicking foot.
Then the other thing they give
him like a fucking Sandal,
so they don't even go out and celebrate
with the fucking kid who kicked the
field goal.
They just run right down at Penn state's
band and the whole fan section and just
screamed all in their faces.
And what's fucking hilarious is that
game obviously could have gone either way
and if they didn't win, they
would have been like, well hey,
good game [inaudible]
Penn state wouldn't done.
That was just a completely classless
fucking move. But that's how they are,
you know, that's, it's one of
those schools were saying, well,
the coach just doesn't take
any responsibility. And he's
just like, well, uh, the,
uh,
cancer,
this is very emotional team and they
like to express themselves and have that,
yeah. Yeah. When they, when,
when they, when, when they don't,
they fucking scamper off the field.
It's like that Richard Sherman
guy, whenever the Seattle
world's you mad, you mad,
Bro, you met. Right. And then
all of a sudden he loses,
he tries to be mister tries
to be the mirror. Hey, good
game Tom Brady. Good game.
And it varies like that
showed class. No, it did.
Anybody can be classy when you
fucking lose, you can't talk shit.
You lost the class.
Act is when you win and you're
not a cunt about it. Um,
but anyways, having said that, it
was a fucking amazing, amazing game.
Great comeback by a USC.
And uh,
is as much as it came down to the wire
and there was all those points scored.
I have to be honest with you,
I,
if I could have fast forwarded through
the last 45 minutes of the fuck,
that's how long the fucking game was
and how long these fucking TV timeouts
where I can't imagine how much fucking
money they made. Game started at one 15.
It wasn't over until like,
I want to say like five 45,
five 40. It was just way too
far. It was over four hours long.
It was like a fucking baseball game.
It's like this is,
this is what happened in
the national pastime. Bill.
You know what was one must as long as
you bitching about the fucking game. Um,
anyways, so we went to the
tailgate. I brought that,
uh,
that flat top grill that I
got the campfire one. Um,
this is not a paid advertisement dude.
Fucking thing was unbelievable.
It was unfucking believable. Lie head
was at, I didn't want to go to the game.
He was having so much fun. He
cooked so much shit. I make,
we had so much fucking food.
We had too much food. And, um,
that's why I felt like I got hit by a
truck was I ate so fucking much. And um,
I made these hash browns.
He made this crazy egg sandwich.
Then we had chicken wings,
then we had fucking steak and cheese
and we still have burgers and dogs that
we're going to try to do at the end of
the game. But I was just too fucking full.
But a law head was fucking hilarious man.
He was so excited to cook.
Right.
I'm back in the truck and he's outside
of it and this guy comes walking by and
you know, when they, they sell those
ticket holders, I always get one right?
And he goes, hey, take it all you took it.
I go, yeah, yeah, yeah. Let me get four.
So these guys sort of walking up to the
truck and I'm not doing a good job back
in it in cause the grills blocking
my view. I'm trying to look around.
I don't want to fuck
this thing up. And, uh,
so I had to do get to make a couple of
temps and rather than blaming it on me,
chase starts yelling at the
ticket guy cause hey buddy, hey,
think he could get out of way,
let the kid fun party.
And then I didn't hear the guy going,
hey bro, you gotta, you gotta relax and,
and Jay just starts fucking John Adam.
Like he's fucking arguing when a call and
I just yelled out, I automatic, I said,
Jamie, just shut the fuck up. I got to it.
I'm sorry. Sorry about that guy. You know,
he's, he's a little wound up, right? So
we have fucking buy the
ticket holder things.
The guy leaves and then
Jay setting up his fucking,
his little a canopy thing and t's
just fucking, he's just locked in,
you know, Jay's a fucking athletes
so he just fucking gets his,
he's got that focus right.
And as he sat in the thing up,
like these four people we've barely even
establish our space are just passing
through. And then Jay
immediately it's like, Hey,
I want you to walk from the whole area.
It just walk along like
freaking the fuck out.
I said to him later, I said,
Jesus Christ, Jay, I go,
you fucking dropped the gloves
before the game even started.
What the fuck is with you when he's like,
not a lot of guys, the guys walking,
right, and he types, what are you tired
people come through the whole fucking kid.
And I just started laughing. I was
like, Jay, you're excited to cook.
Say the cookie. You got a little
excited. Then he finally just fine.
Just relax and goes, all
right. I got excited.
Um, I don't know. We don't
know where we are. Just, we
had a great fucking time and,
um, I dunno, I still nodded off a
little bit in the first quarter.
You know, I can't get to sleep
after all these years of doing,
stand up till like fucking
a 12 midnight and get up,
you know, four hours later,
I'm an old. Um, I really felt
my age, the sheer man, uh,
speaking of which there was someone at
the Tailgate, I'm not gonna say who,
who was fucking slumped over the truck
because they had to go the bathroom and
couldn't. So we're like, dude, we
got to take you to the hospital.
We got to take you to,
Nah, I'm fine. I'm fine.
And five fugly ends up coming back
like 20 minutes, slide it through.
And it felt great because I eat,
I think he passed a fucking
kidney stone or subs.
I don't know what the fuck it was.
I don't know what to tell you.
Oh yeah.
So we almost had a fatality lie.
It almost got a game misconduct.
Oh, that was a bullshit one
on USC. That fucking, uh,
targeting with that was setting
that, that wasn't, I don't know.
Guy Jumps in the air, he's aiming for
his chest and somebody else hits him.
Then all of a sudden the guy gets
knocked down. Where is his chest?
His head is now we're just chest wasn't,
and the guy was already in the air.
Right. Does anybody give a fuck? I, I'll,
I will plow, I will plow ahead here.
Um, I also watched the UFC, I know this
is like an old story at this point, but,
um, you know, everybody, like
everybody else, I watched the uh,
Amanda Nunez and the Ronda Rousey
Rowdy Ronda Rousey fight Ed A.
Yeah, that was tough to watch. That
was definitely tough to watch. And um,
it was even tougher to watch all the
fucking shit talk and assholes on like
Twitter and all the means.
[inaudible] you know,
I've taken naps slogan the note,
they went to get a drink
and then it was fucking okay
over. And it's just like, like
all of these people that have,
have fought and competed and won in the
octagon and they have the right to talk
shit like that. It's just a, I don't
know why people do stuff like that. Uh,
you know, if that happens to every
champion, if they, if they stay,
if they stick around eventually somebody
younger is going to see you're the
champ.
Everybody's breaking down what the fuck
it is you do over and over and over and
over again.
And then eventually you get run down.
It happens to everybody if it can happen
to Muhammad Ali, sugar ray, Leonard,
Marvin, Hagler, all these
fucking guys, they last fight.
I saw 'em loose Roy Jones,
Jr Matthews,
George Saint Pierre, right? I think George
Saint Pierre might've won his last one,
but he was all beat up and everything.
But um,
and said he didn't
remember part of the fight.
So that's what happens to everybody.
So of course I texted it to my buddy,
he goes, well, not rocky or fucking
Mayweather, meaning rocky Marciano.
And it's just like, dude, all right,
I'll rocky Marciano. Absolutely.
But like Mayweather,
I dunno,
maybe owes me like 300
bucks in paper view.
Think about that guy.
All right,
I'm really going out on a limb here
cause I don't watch that much boxing.
I think one, obviously one of the
greatest fighters of all fucking time,
but like he's just also understood
that final third of his career,
I feel better than anybody else.
How do you still continue fighting and
not take that big fucking knocked down?
Part of it,
our blog apart was his amazing defense.
But the other is to fucking opponents
that he picked. You know what I mean?
That fucking Pacquiao fight should have
happened at least eight years before I
was on his side where I was like, yeah,
he, maybe he's on drugs. He probably,
I don't know, maybe he is,
maybe fucking isn't. But, um,
I dunno. All the boxing
isn't the way it was. Um,
somewhere in the 80s at died like a,
that Hagler Hearns Duran Leonard,
they all lost and they all fucking lost
to each other and shit. It's just like,
he had unbelievable fighters
for unbelievable fighters
and they all fought each
other. It's impossible to stay
undefeated, but, um, you know,
when you fuck it, you know, it'd be
like, I've just fucking, Ali fought,
Joe finally fought Joe Frazier
in like 1981. I'm like,
what?
Ali's last fights.
I think it was against Larry Holmes who
then was the fucking champ for like the
next four years or whatever his rule
until I think Tyson came along and maybe
there was one guy in between. I can't
remember. It's been so long ago.
Hagglers last loss was
to sugar ray Leonard.
I mean these guys fought champions right
up until the end of their career as
opposed to a, you know, fighting some
guy from England with weight issues.
You know that one Ricky,
Ricky, Ricky Hatton.
I saw that fight.
I don't like talking shit about
fighters either because you know,
they cannot beat the fuck out of me.
I'm, I'm just saying that, you know,
I think it's going to hurt me whether
the level of guy that he fought the final
third of his career. Um, cause
I know for one like just,
I just, you know, you'd watch his fucking
fights. The other guy couldn't hit him.
Mayweather could knock them out and
he just kind of a poop poop poop poop.
The whole fucking fight with is those
white kitten gloves. I'm just like,
this is fucking boring as shit.
Um, fighting not to lose
playing, not playing,
not to lose like Penn state, like Penn
state didn't the fourth fucking quarter.
Um, so that's, I know,
that's my own dumb opinion.
I don't know what they don't
know shit about fighting,
but all I know this is you're a fucking
asshole if you go on Twitter and you
start trashing somebody cause they uh,
cause they got knocked out
like they're a pussy or you,
you are overrated or any of that type of
shit. I mean, some of you probably say,
I just did that to Mayweather.
I'm not,
I'm saying he's one of
the greatest of all time.
I would never say that the guy's
a pussy or anything like that.
I would have just liked to watch
him fight a better caliber fighter.
Um, I dunno. You know what I mean?
I'd like to add that may whether patio
fight that should have fucking happened
at one oh five oh six something like that.
Bill. Shut the fuck up. All right,
I'll shut the fuck up anyways. Um,
you know what it really is, is the
adverse, he fucking said that may,
whether it would have fucking
beat Hagler Hearns Leonard Duran,
like he would have
fucking beat all of them.
It's like he would've beat all of them.
All of them couldn't beat all of each
other, you know, I don't know what he's,
I don't know what he's basing it on him.
You know what he's basing it on?
He's basing it on being born in the
late seventies. I just, you know,
I'm just an old fucking crabby men,
I'm speaking of, which, you know,
I've, I've been working on my anger. Um,
I got in the car today to return
the pickup truck and I, uh,
I fucking, uh, I don't know.
I made it down the street and around
the block before it got into an argument
with his fucking woman who just glided
through her stop sign in her white
Mercedes Benz.
I got to fucking,
I got to anybody who's got a white
Mercedes, a white, uh, people,
white cars,
high end white cars are
fucking entitled cuts.
I don't like, you know what I mean?
They think the car is a classy right.
I was confers he shit
like versus he loves,
you know,
it just,
it gets the class is fucking thing ever.
Mercedes and BMW, they've really fallen
the fuck off. You know what I mean?
They just went right down
to the bottom feeders.
Anybody with like Sukin afford 60 bucks
a month can lease one of those cars now
telling you when he used to see
a Mercedes drive down the street,
he used to be some fucking
guy like in his 50s,
who was wealthy or have a BMW. Even then
that was like more like the Yuppie guy.
Like I'm not having to fucking kids and
I'll pour shit in the drinking water
just to make another buck,
you know,
Cook the fucking stock market
and banker psycho, right?
We were just having rough sex, you
know, that fucking lunatic. Um,
now it's shit. It's like, it's
like fucking 21 year old kids. Um,
I think this podcast should just be
like a, some sort of theme of like,
things aren't the way they used to be
and I'm fucking upset about it. Um,
you know what it is, is I, I didn't have
a good breakfast today and at my age,
that's not a good thing.
You know, I woke up in the,
and we didn't have any fucking
real food. The fucking, my,
my frying pan was underneath all the
dirty shift from the fucking Rosebowl
that's in the sink. It's like, I'm
not going to fry up a fucking egg.
And a Nia has one of those fucking
little kid cereals in there.
And I was just like, all right, I'll
fucking eat this shit. And, uh, um,
I already had the fucking sugar high and
now I'm starting to crash saw and being,
uh, being a little harsh than
the millennials, you know,
in Floyd Mayweather and,
uh, people who drive white
cars. I can admit that in 2017,
I can admit that this is the new me,
the new bill.
I meditate now and by saying I meditate
means I tried it once last week
and I plan on doing it twice a day, but
I've only done it once so far, but uh,
but I've been thinking about
doing it, you know, and uh,
people have been sending me shit about
trying to get over my fucking anger
issues and uh, yeah, that lady like
gliding through the stop sign and I,
I stopped, I said, you gotta
Stop Sign, right? Then she
goes, you got one over there.
And I go, that's not it. It's
the other ones. It's just like,
you're just a fucking nother Douche
in a white Mercedes. I sweated. Got,
do you think if they stopped making
that car, people would drive better?
If there's something about people
when they get in a white Mercedes,
a white fucking car, like you
know, of, of, of that costs
a certain amount of money.
That's it. Look, I'm, I'm getting
upset again. Just relax, Bill.
Take a fucking breadth, you know,
go outside. Look at the birds.
We have a hell. It is, you're supposed to
do it. You know, somebody sent me this, I,
I should play it. No, somebody
sent me this fucking video on, uh,
you know how to get over my anger and the
risk of sounding like a hack comedian.
It actually, it didn't make me angry.
It fucking upset. Maybe though.
It really did.
Let me see this here.
See if I can click on this
fucking thing again. Oh,
how not to be angry all the time.
I wonder if I can play this and not
get in fucking trouble by some, uh,
some podcasting entity here. See if I
can turn this fucking thing up here.
So I look at this thing,
right? It's a cartoon.
So immediately it's on my intellect
level right? Here it is. This,
this is what they're trying to say to me.
I'll try to play this year,
my minimal fucking, um, abilities here.
Oh, for God's sakes. So you
gonna play it here or what?
I hit play.
Okay.
I refuse to get fucking angry during this.
Why won't this thing play? Oh, I know.
Because I'm in this room.
I'm in this room.
So the fucking in the internet doesn't
work or there's a little spin wheel.
It's gradually fight spinning around.
What's going to happen?
All I want to do is play this fucking
all. I want to do room a zoom, zoom, zoom.
I just want to play this fucking video.
How does it know?
How does the universe know when you're
trying to fucking do something? All right.
You know what? Fuck it. I'm not
playing to, hey look at that.
I'm not angry anymore because I just
gave him cause that's basically what this
fucking video told you to do.
It was talking about so and so.
This is,
this is the name of the video.
It says how not to be angry all the time
and I would love to read the fucking
comments on this thing,
right?
He says how not to be angry all
the time and it shows this guy,
it's like a William or whatever.
I think you guys actually name was bill.
I can't remember.
You know,
he likes to read the newspaper and he
tells his wife not to interrupt him while
he's doing that. And then it goes,
his wife finds this very upsetting.
So one time he's reading the
newspaper and uh, she says, Hey,
when are you going to a,
you know, set the table,
the Blahblahblahblahblah
and William flips out.
He gets angry and it says William
gets angry because he has hope.
It was talking about how angry people,
as much as they come off as a negative,
they're actually really positive people.
And it was basically
saying that they have hope.
So they present all these different
scenarios and they're like,
at each one of these cell,
you know,
he goes to the airport
in his plane is delayed.
He's one of the premiere fucking flyers.
He gets mad, he goes up, he flips,
he screams at the fucking lady behind
the counter because he is hopeful.
And it was basically saying that he needed
to be a little more pessimistic. Oh,
here's the video,
here's a video.
It's basically saying you needed
to be a negative cont. Here we go.
Like Boomi times.
We certainly don't usually
think of them as well,
why is it so fucking quiet?
They treat me.
You know what? I can't deal
with this fucking guy's
accent. I can't deal with it.
Oh, I know I had no, I had the fucking
microphone turned round. There we go.
Can you be paypal? The actually, aw,
hold on one second.
Sound like Fumi Times.
We certainly don't usually
think of optimists yet.
They truly march to them.
I can't fuck it. Oh my God,
I can't fucking listen to it.
Can He, why is he going to fucking
over it? And that's everything.
And that's the get everything.
Give me paypal actually
ported the people on the left.
Yeah. So basically he goes through
all of this fucking Shit, right?
And he says in it,
to be more positive is what you
have to do is you have to accept
the world that the world is
actually a very dark, gloomy place.
And most things fail.
And most basically,
most dreams don't come true. And, uh,
you know, be more of like a realist.
And like people who, you know, people
get upset. People who aren't angry,
people get upset, um,
when something happens,
but they get over it way quicker
and they don't get nearly as mad.
And it's basically because I guess they're
walking around going like, oh yeah,
why wouldn't this person in this white
Mercedes blow through the stop sign?
Of course they do.
I guess this part of me
that I understand that,
like I flip out about the moron drivers
out here and I literally say to myself
out loud after I flip out in
the car going like, yes, Bill,
you have established that
people out here suck at driving.
When are you going to stop
reacting to it? And um, you know,
I, I, I, I don't think ever,
I don't think it's because
unlike an optimist I don't have,
I'm not hopeful that someone fucking,
you know, if they're going
to make a left, that they,
that they'll get all the way over to the
left instead of sitting in the middle
of the lane and now I
have to fucking wait.
Where if you just were over
by the double yellow line,
I could have gone around you.
You fucking cunt.
I'm not like hopeful that
they're going to do that.
I don't have hope that
they're going to do it.
I just can't understand why you wouldn't
because I know that person has been
sitting behind somebody doing that.
It's like when you're,
you're in a long line at fucking whatever
and it's moving slow and everybody's
Yammer with the person on the other
side of the fucking desk. It's like,
just get up there and say what
you want and shut the fuck up.
How hard is that?
And there'll be a person in front
of you look at you rolling eyes.
Like I can't believe how long this takes.
And then they get up
there and what do they do?
They just fucking launch into all of this
shit that has nothing to do with what
you're doing
and it just fucking ads timed.
So I'm not, I don't have any
hope that people are going to,
maybe I do. I have hope, you know?
I guess I would hope you'd be a fucking
not a moron and figure out why this
seems to be taking way longer
than it should. I Dunno.
I don't think it's because I have hope.
I think the reason why I get fucking
angry is because that is my default
emotion. I think that
that's what it is. You know,
I came from one of those families
are like, shut the fuck up.
You sit there and take it. Right.
One of those things, which, you know,
if you're not allowed to express yourself,
you immediately feel like you're not
going to get what you want in life.
And I think that that's what I think,
that's why I flip up. You know,
I flip out because of that. Like, you
know, if something starts to go away,
I don't want it to go,
um,
no one's going to listen to me and I
don't have any fucking options other than
just sit there and fucking take it.
So I think that's what he's,
I don't think it's, cause I'm hopeful.
I get maybe a little bit, baby.
I'm such an angry cunt. I can't say
that there's some truth in this video,
but I don't think the solution
is, is to just walk around, um,
you know, just accepting that
people are the way that they are,
you know, that'd be like, if
you know, you're coaching a
team, it'd be like, yeah,
you know, we're eight and eight,
eight and eight next year,
you know, I will probably be eight
and eight again because, uh, I've,
I've accepted that this
is the way things are. Um,
I know a lot of positive driven
people and they're not angry people.
So I don't think being positive
as part of that. I think it's,
I think it's just how my fucking wires,
my mental wires had
been soldered together.
I think I probably came into the world.
Okay.
I Dunno.
Can you come into the world angry?
Okay.
I Dunno. I don't think he can. I don't
think you're born that fucking way.
I have no fucking idea, but I dunno
about this video where I got to now just,
I just, the solution is just to
be like, yeah, well you know,
people out here when they make lives,
that's how they're going to do it. I mean,
I guess if you just do that,
then you don't get angry because all
these years in me getting angry has not
made people stop doing that. It never made
the person in front of me go like, Oh,
I'm sorry, let me get over. They
just sorta look at me weird as I,
as I drive by yelling at them,
looking at me like,
what the fuck is he yelling at me?
Am I doing something I have no,
I have a white car.
How could I possibly be in the wrong?
Um, I dunno. I have no idea. I think a,
I dunno,
I dunno what my deal is,
but I plan on getting to the
bottom but at least understand it.
But I don't think a three minute fucking
youtube video with some guy with his
fucking,
you know,
I think in the United States
we like getting like people
with English accents to
fucking narrates shit. Cause then it
just sounds like it's true for smart,
you know what I mean? Which
is why I think all these, uh,
these English guys have been
Scottish guys have done well. Um,
maybe it's just women like fucking that
accent or just like a different foreign
accent. I don't know, like these
talk show people, you know,
for some reason that slot that
used to be after David Letterman,
you have to get an
English or Scottish guy,
like that's become like that time slot,
like an American accent.
That guy can not do well
in that.
That is the Great Britain accent.
Time-Slot um,
I dunno,
I I, but I, I all I know is, I
can't, I can't listen to fucking,
I can't listen to this again.
Friend Fred furious.
He's been married to his,
he's often furious.
He sounds like he's in the
fucking clockwork orange. Uh,
but I am off often furious. His name
was Fred. I knew it was one of my names.
Right. Um, all right. What am
I doing here? Let's, let's,
let's read some fucking advertising here.
34 fucking minutes into this podcast.
And I don't think I'm a, I don't think
I'm even remotely a better person.
What about you guys? Um, all right. Oh,
it's our friends here. No,
wait, let's, let's, let's stay
on this point here. Maybe.
Maybe that's what I should do.
I'm going to try that today.
I'm going to just try walking around and
what am I do is have my eyebrows up a
little bit. I'm going to do that
thing that, uh, people do. You know,
where they make their lips disappear?
Their mouth looks like it's closed,
but their lips disappearing on the car.
Just going to do that. Walk around like,
Oh yeah, of course. This thing that
should take 90 seconds. Of course.
Now it's going to take
six minutes. Yep. Okay.
Take my car over to the dealership to get
the, uh, the brake light done. I mean,
I know that I could change out a
break lake, but of course you've, uh,
have the screws.
They are,
they're inside the car behind a plastic
thing and I know when I go to take that
thing off that they are the head on,
the screw is going to be something
I've never seen before and requests and
requires a special screwdriver.
Then I could go down or maybe
order on Amazon, do you know?
And of course they won't
just sell me the one.
I'll have to buy the whole
set and then I'll be like,
well I guess I can pay fucking $35 for
a new set of screwdrivers and hope I
don't get a ticket over
the next few fucking days.
Or I could just drive down to this fucking
dealership and just pay 180 bucks for
a fucking like, boy, get
married, get mad again.
I'm just going to go down to the
dealership and just say, yes,
I have something that I could
totally repair on my car.
If you guys hadn't put those
aliens screws in there,
excuse me,
could I have the screwdriver that
I need to undo those four screws?
Could I,
could I have that please?
And could I then find the corporate guy
right as he's getting on his jet who
came up with this idea and could
I please just, I don't know,
just sort of stick it into the side of
his neck. I think that would be nice.
How does that work? If I say angry
shit, but I say it in a pleasant way,
ma'am.
Is there a reason why you're so not
focused as you work this cash register?
Is there a reason why you feel that
you were above a job that you stink at?
How does that work?
Shouldn't you be so good at this job that
I'm actually sitting there thinking to
myself, why are you working
here? You're way beyond this.
Why are you standing here reinforcing
that you're not even good enough to do
this job because you think
you're better than another job?
Is there any way you could open that cash
register door and I could grab you by
your ponytail,
shove your head into the drawer and then
see how far I could close it with your
head in it.
Is there a way I could do that?
Sorry guys,
you just know I have to
rehearse everything that I'm
going to go through today.
Okay.
Oh, hello. Staples. No, you cannot. You
cannot have my phone number. I mean,
I'll give you a phone number and I will
give you an alternate phone number. Yes,
I will.
None of these will be true.
Okay.
Oh, I'll, I'll give you
a, I'll give you a, uh,
you know my fake email addresses that
I give. It's, you know it at AOL,
aol.com.
You got to have a fake one.
You know it@aol.com.
Okay.
That's my fake. What? And that is a
reference to will Ferrell in old school.
Frank the tank when they go on frank
a tank, right? He's gone. You know it,
you know,
um,
the fake phone number I give out is a
series of area codes followed by the
number of five. That'd
be like, what's your,
what's your phone number? It's like,
Eh, three, two, three, two, one, two,
eight, one eight, five. That's what I do.
But they start to look at,
you have to two area codes,
you know when you go like three,
one oh two, one, two. They get that.
You get that little puppy look,
the gold cock of the head.
And then rather than saying
eight, one eight, cause
they're gonna know I go eight,
one, eight, five. So I
still get it in there.
A fake name I go with all the time.
Russell.
Russell, whenever I just need
a first name. What's your
name? Hey, what's your name?
Russell. Russell. What can I do
for you today? Well, you can, yeah,
you can start by not asking me
personal questions. All right.
That's what you can do.
And you can get some loafers.
Are that fit you fucking feet. How about
that? All right. Did tight shoes. Um,
I'm sorry. I don't want to
tell you. Oh by the way,
I, uh, you know, I got some video,
my old buddy cleo and um,
she seems happy as hell.
And this is unprecedented.
This person that I gave my dog
too is a dog trainer and um,
at like the fucking dog whisperer or
level. So, which is what my dog needed.
And he sent me video of
something I've never seen before.
My dog came in and wanted
to play with another dog,
which my dog never did.
My dog tried to kill other dogs.
My dog tried to kill another dog when
my dog was with the trainer that now has
it and he's slowly been working
with this fucking thing. And um,
what was amazing and the trainer said,
you know,
within a week to 10 days they will
probably be just like best of friends
sleeping together in the sun.
So that made me feel good cause
I think she's actually happier.
Um, and that environment then she
was with me even though, you know,
I miss her to death or what, but that
made me feel good. So there you go.
There you go. I'll tell you that
fucking dog has had an amazing life,
an amazing life.
Like a literally,
it should have been over like three
different times and it always survives and
its life has gotten
progressively better. So, uh,
they made me feel good as much as I,
uh, as much as I missed the thing.
That's cool. It's got a
Fred and I got nobody.
Ooh. All right. Oh, here we go. Let's
read a little advertising it. Oh, zip.
Are you high? You're in. Hey,
do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Posting jobs in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
Oh, you know, you want
to find the perfect hire.
You need to post your job
at all this shiny stone.
And now you can with ziprecruiter.com
you can post your job to 100 plus job
sites, including social
media networks like Facebook.
And Fuck it
all with a single click.
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your qualified
candidates roll into ZipRecruiter's.
Easy to use interface,
no juggling emails or calls to your
office quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire the right person
fast. Find out today. Why Zip
brewed up.com ZipRecruiter has been used
by over 1 million businesses and right
now my listeners can post jobs on
zip recruiter for free by going to
ziprecruiter.com/bird that's
ziprecruiter.com/bird one more time.
Try It for free.
Go to zip.com/burb oh,
give me the loop. Loot crate
everybody. Hey nerds. Listen Up.
Put Down Your fucking devil dog. Quit
licking the sides like a creep. All right.
Be The envy of your friends and get
your 100% exclusive crates@loucraig.com
slash burr and enter my code bur bur
are to save $3 off any new subscription.
Wait until I tell you. Oh wait until
I tell you about January's crate.
It'll take you back to the old
school, you know. All right.
Copy points mentioned at
least three times a spot.
Yeah,
I don't get like to,
Hey,
well maybe on these ads are so
fucking long cause I read everything.
Yeah,
copied mentioned at
least three times a spot.
Mention what?
Why don't you write what the fuck
I'm supposed to meet on? You know,
it'd be nice if you guys would just,
okay,
write down what I'm supposed to mention
and then I don't have to do the math in
the copy. I would really
appreciate that. Okay, Luke, rate.
Okay.
If fucking cards.
All right.
Luke crate offers an epic range of pop
culture items for less than $20 a month.
What did it give me a key change?
20 less than $20 a month.
That sounds like a bunch of shit.
If you're more I fanatical Fashionista
than try loot where? Oh, here we go.
Here's where you start
spending your money.
Monthly wearables and accessories
with cult classics and your favorite
franchises.
If you want to get fancy,
get a bigger box with even
bigger lute with loot crate DX.
This offer expires January
19th at 9:00 PM Pacific.
Get ready for January is
old school theme origins.
Everybody origins loot crate has awesome
and exclusive items from your old
school favorites. Can you just
fucking get to them this January?
You see where it all started and they
explored the iconic origins with historic
items featuring superman,
Captain America, Mario.
Okay.
Batali Mario who?
Super Mario Luigi and the
teenage mutant Ninja Turtles,
including as always our
monthly tee shirt and pin.
Go to loot crate.com/burn and enter
my code birth to save $3 off any new
subscription today. I have no
fucking idea what any of that is.
I don't know what just happened there.
Okay.
The origins,
like the first
comic book,
Do you need to explore the origins of
teenage mutant Ninja Turtles? It's, it's,
it's all on the Internet.
Superman.
I goes back to the 30s there
was no internet back then.
The Internet came out in the late sixties
right when Al Gore was in his fucking
eyes. Dorm Room. Ryan, he was in
there with Donald Trump and they are,
they both came up with it.
They should both hosted game show
called [inaudible] what I invented.
Did he know what it's like to tell
the truth and you got to guess, right?
Just the two of them. Just
sit there talking shit, you
know. All right. I'm sorry.
Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody Jarl is shave club delivers
amazing affordable razors right to your
front door every fucking month.
So you can get a great shave,
but raises it only thing
you need in the bathroom.
What about all this shower stuff? Oh yeah,
kid, you gotta wash your under carriage.
You know it's an old school thing.
Instead of saying you need to shave,
you know those older guys. Hey, you
need, you need to take a shave. A,
why don't you take a shave?
Take a shape like a shit.
What are you saying? They're
fucking GRANDPA. All right.
Turns out dollar Shave Club. Thought of
that thought of what? Taking a shave.
Oh Bye. Oh shower shit. Alright.
They just came out with a
new line of shower products,
shampoo and body wash called the wanderer.
Where are the type of guy
who likes to watch his balls?
The fragrances are unlike
anything on the market.
There's subtle and actually smell
like real natural ingredients.
There are a lot of body washes out there
that make you smell like a teenager.
This mint in Cedar Wood bodywash is
amazing and makes you smell incredible.
How has that natural to walk around
smelling like ice cream and like it just
chops. Yeah. It makes no
fucking sense to me whatsoever.
You know what I mean? I know mint
in cedar wood x exist in nature.
I don't know. You got
to give it a try. Uh,
once you're in the club, you'll see,
uh, the products work amazingly.
The surface is world class and you're
going to smell like a hummingbird's taint.
There's no longterm commitments,
no hidden fees and your can'ts.
You can cancel whenever you want and
best of all they give, giving you,
oh Kevin away a one month trial of any
razor for a dollar with free shipping.
That's not really giveaway. If you
given it away, you're giving it away.
You don't ask people for money after that.
It's just a few bucks a month.
Get your $1
trial@dollarshaveclub.com slash bird.
That's dollar shave club.com/burr.
And lastly, but not leastly.
Thank fucking God here.
Stamps, stamps.com.
Um, one great resolution you
can make for the new year.
Maximize every minute and every
dollar for your small business.
I know an easy way to do that.
I'm going to read this like a creepy
cult leader trying to get your money and
gradually bring into the fold.
I know an easy way to
do that with stamps.com.
Think about how much time you've wasted,
how much time you've wasted
going to the post office driving.
They're finding parking,
spending your own money on things
that you want to spend it on.
I think it's time you came
into my compound and started
spending your money on
me because I am truly the son of God
and not only that, stamps.com is
the better way to get postage.
Just use what you already have.
You don't need to go cause you're already
there. Your computer and printer, t,
t, I. N what the Fuck? I'm sorry.
Just use whatever you have. All right.
You can't use your computer
or your printer and get
official us postage for any
letter or package.
Send the mail man,
picks it up with stamps.com everything
you would do with the post office and get
it right from your desk and at a fraction
of the cost of one of those expensive
postage meter. I use stamps dot coms
whenever I'm sending out my posters.
I'm a fucking more and if I could
figure it out. So can you, so right now,
sign up for stamps.com and use my code
burp. You are our for this special offer,
a four week trial plus $110 bonus offer
that includes postage and a digital
scale. Yeah. All right. Don't wait. Go to
stamps.com before you do anything else,
you click on the microphone
at the top of the homepage.
You type in Burr that stamps.com enter
burr stamps.com never go to the God damn
fucking post office again.
All right,
let's do the reeds for this week
and then I'll get the fall Gatti.
All right. Sorry. Read
the anger one goodwill.
Hey Bill. Bill up the
podcast. Can't wait for F.
F is for family season too.
Thank you very much.
Last week on the Thursday podcast,
you talked about goodwill.
I worked goodwill for a little over a
year and you wouldn't believe the shit
that was donated there. Oh my God.
This fascinates the hell out of me.
I imagine they give you basically
everything short of a body. Um,
you are totally right.
They just throw all this shit and trucks,
but they, but instead of
throwing shit in the oceans,
yeah, wait a second. But they, instead
of throwing shit in the oceans,
put the trucks and warehouses and let
them set for at least three to 10 years so
the shit can get a lovely
scent of mold over them.
When they get loaded. They literally
throw this shit on the truck.
Nine Times out of 10 breaking
whatever you are donating.
Yeah. No Way. You know what the Shit,
you know what the shit thing
is about donating to goodwill.
You can bring shit with mold,
Piss,
shit or anything else disgusting
there and they have to take it.
Well then what are they
supposed to do with it?
I'd put it on a truck to nine times out
of 10 they will take anything but that
one time out of 10 if you bitch and
threatened to call corporate and complain,
they will take no matter they'll
take it no matter what. Okay. Oh God.
Someone's got to do a documentary
on goodwill. When I was there,
people would donate trashed. They didn't
want to pay to get rid of couches,
torn to shit with piss stains all over it.
Mattresses with literal shit on them
and a laundry lists of low of long gross
shit. Dude, this is like an expo as
a, and I'm taking this all is fact.
I have no idea if this is true or not.
They will literally sell anything.
I got to the point that when people would
donate things that were really nice,
I would tell them they should keep it
or give it to someone because it would
just be thrown away.
But of course the mouth breathing assholes
that would donate trash that they,
that they have to what,
but of course the mouth breeding assholes
that would donate trash that they have
to take. Dude, you're a bit of a
mouth breather here. You're, you're,
you're not speaking in full sentences.
Uh,
these people are hoarders that you can't
even open their car door without shit
falling all over the fucking place.
Fucking discussing.
The grossest thing that I ever saw gets
sold was either a mattress was shit and
piss stains on it or an anti dildo
that had white hair all over it.
Ah, come on. Come on. Come on people.
I can't believe this. This, this. I'm,
am I getting trolled here? Is this a
millennial? Is he giving me the business?
He says,
I know this is going to sound like I
am making myself in this situation.
What I know this is going to sound like
I am making myself in this situation.
The good guy,
this is a voice text,
but I seriously would look at them and be
like, why the fuck are we selling this?
This is really wrong.
They will respond with,
we have to sell everything
to try and make bonus.
The sad thing was we never made bonus.
I got to the point where I wouldn't
price shit because it was garbage.
And my last day I felt like grabbing
a trash bag from the office,
go around the building, picking
up trash than tying it, tie it up,
slap a dollar on it and write on the bag
mystery bag or some shit like that and
see if anybody would buy it.
But I didn't do, this is all,
that was all one sentence
on my last day.
I felt like grabbing a trash bag from
the office, go around the building,
picking up trash,
then tie it up,
slap a dollar on it and write on the bag
mystery bag or some shit like that and
see if someone would buy it.
But I didn't all one sentence.
Thanks bill for the labs and good luck
to you and Neil with the new baby. Um,
yeah, I kind of, I kind of get,
but people just use goodwill because
they want to feel like they're being
environmentally conscious. You
know, I'm not throwing this out.
It's going to end up in a landfill or
in the ocean and then you just bring it
down there and they just throw it up.
Yeah. Well it didn't take a genius.
She come down there,
there's a giant fucking 18
wheeler empty just park there now.
Like it's dropping off or picking up
shit. It's shit. It's there on its,
on its legs. There's no a tractor
trailer there and you know,
they just come over there like once a day
and just drive that thing away. Where,
where's it going? All
right. Drama Queen Dad.
Dear Billy, red nose. First off, I'd
like to say thanks Megan, but thank you.
Thank you. I'm a lady. Oh my God.
I have a female friend in high school
and lately I've been listening to your
podcast whenever I'm stressed out or
just looking for something to laugh at.
Okay.
Now onto the story.
My father is a middle aged man with
bipolar disorder and likes to blame
everything on his mental illness
as he calls it. I liked it.
You're already taking them to task here.
He's going to blame everything
on his mental illness. Yeah.
There's no reason to not do your dishes.
All right. All right. They'll loopy. Um,
he's very dramatic and claims that his
bipolar is the reason he hasn't been able
to hold a job lately,
even though he kept the same career for
about 10 years and is now working for a
new company by parents are divorced.
So whenever my father can't
have us over to visit,
he claims it's because of his
illness. Ah, man. That's the greatest.
That there's nothing like
a fucking builtin excuse.
That's gonna be great when I have a kid
here in a few fucking days, minutes,
weeks, whatever, uh, uh, you
know, I'd love to, but my
kid, my kid's a, yeah, I can,
I got a kid.
Um,
I don't want to tell them him that
bipolar disorder is not a mental illness
because he, he'd go ape shit on me. Um,
is bipolar? I don't know. I thought
it, anytime your brain was fucked up,
he had a mental illness. I haven't
met the limitless with my anger. Okay.
Bipolar,
bipolar, is it a disease?
Well, let's see here. Oh, just
give me the fucking answer.
Oh, Geez. Is uh,
fuck you.
I'm not reading all this shit.
Okay.
This is the Internet. I don't
want to expound. Expounded on,
just give me the yes or no. Is there
a yes or no.com? Can you just do that?
You just answer a fiasco. Fucking,
it's like, I don't want to know why.
Yeah.
Is this blah blah blah, yes or
no? And then you have your answer.
So then when you go to the bar and
somebody says something like, no, it is.
Yes it is.
Did you know that bipolar
disorder develops with during
a person's late teens or
early adult years? Do you know?
I didn't ask that question.
Never trust a fucking doctor with
a goatee. Where the fuck is it?
You know? Oh my God. Jesus Christ.
Look at these fucking eggheads.
Y'All got nice full heads of hair though.
I've got to give him that.
All right. Anyways, um,
I don't want to tell him bipolar disorder
is not a mental illness because he'll
go ape shit on me for some reason.
He seems to enjoy making me
and my sister feels like shit.
It makes mountains out of molehills
whenever we correct him or stand up for
ourselves when he bullies us.
Yeah.
I don't take any shit for
you sound like an asshole.
What's even worse about this is
that his bullying always works.
He's very manipulative and I'm scared
to see him because of the things he said
and done to me in the past.
Every time I'm,
I'm informed I'll have to
spend the weekend with him. Um,
I nearly piss myself with anxiety.
My question to you is,
how the fuck do you deal
with someone like this?
I know my dad is ridiculous
and uses underhanded tactics,
tactics to make me feel like shit,
but for some reason I'm not
able to just get over it.
None of my friends seem to relate
to being so terrified of one person.
Like I am of my father.
I would like to hear your take on things.
Thanks for reading this
and go fuck yourself. Um,
all right. How would I get past?
Well, this is the hardest thing to do.
You have to stop giving a shit about the
guy to a certain level at some point.
You know, when you, if you
have a parent like this,
you have to look at them and remove
mentally that they're a relative and you
have to just say to yourself like,
if this person was a complete stranger,
would I be friends with this person?
Would I interact with this person?
What I waste another minute,
my fucking life dealing with this person?
You know? And when you got to ask
those questions, usually it's like,
absolutely not. This would have been
a fucking one and done situation.
But the thing is, is is your
dad, she can't write them off,
but you have to kind of,
that's the toughest thing when you got
to write off a parent but still interact
with them. You just gotta
be like, I don't know.
You kind of have to find the humor in it.
I think that's a tough one,
especially at your age.
MMM.
I Dunno. I would just, I dunno,
I would probably could do some passive
aggressive shit where I would just say,
oh yeah, is that how it is? Okay, I'll get
right on that. You know, Shit like that.
I don't know what to tell you.
I would just basically, um,
okay.
I would still like, what is he going
to do other than get mad? He does.
It doesn't sound like
he hits you anything.
So he just mad any flips out or whatever
and just I stop who gives a fuck?
That's what he's going to do. The
guy's out of his fucking mind. Right?
Maybe he's got bipolar, maybe it doesn't.
Maybe it's a disease. Maybe it isn't all,
you know,
they just,
okay,
oh man, this is Tom. This is fun.
This is a fucking rough
one because it should dad.
And the last thing you want to do is
then go out in the world and start dating
somebody who then treats
you like ditch that,
the exact fucking thing you don't want.
And then you end up with that and then
you have that same nervousness in a
fucking relationship. That's all I
can say. You know, you got to do,
you're not going to be
able to fix this guy.
You got to deal with them
because he is your dad. Um,
but the big thing that you could do is
in your life is you create a life that
does not involve this.
All right?
You need to go out and
go marry a fucking story,
right?
And then your fucking house is great and
it's peaceful and it's what you want.
And then every once in a while this
fucking tornado tornado blows through and
you deal with it and then it leaves and
then you go back to your peaceful life.
Um, that's all you can
do. You really, as a kid,
you really can't do anything about
your parents. You can't pick them.
You just get the ones
that you get. But, uh,
the thing that you could do is create
a life that does not involve that.
And then you don't do that shit to your
kids. And then you break the cycle,
then that's it. You know? But the
weird fucking thing is, is that your,
your decks still always going
to be in your life, you know,
so that lunatic will then be around
your kids and it's just, it's a,
it's a motherfucker. It really
is. But fortunately they,
for the most part, die before
we do. And then, you know,
you don't have to deal with them anymore.
So I guess try to find
the fucking humor in it
while you're dealing with it and then
think of how exciting your life is going
to be. Um, by not having
that in it, you know,
you might want to just
Skype with them for awhile.
Get yourself in a situation would be
like, why? I think the screen froze hello.
And he just click. Uh,
but that's really a,
that's disappointing to hear that an
adult would manipulate a teenager.
Forget about his own fucking daughter.
That's sucks. So I don't try that,
but just know that you can go out in the
world and have any life that you want
to have, uh, simply
by, you know, you know,
he's showing you what you don't want.
All right. There you go. Oh man,
that's brutal.
You fuck you fuck up so bad as a parent
that your daughter goes outgoing.
I want to marry a man who's the
exact opposite of my own dad. Oof.
That's game set. Match. You fucked up as
a father. All right. Sister's girlfriend,
dear bill, the red bitch birth. Uh,
my twin sister is a lesbian and
she's dating a lady who was bisexual.
Okay.
She was bisexual.
And then what,
then what became totally homosexual and
went back to heterosexuality or it's
just she asexual. At first we
didn't, we weren't close or anything,
but we did get along with your twin
sister, not the bisexual woman. Right.
Then about a year ago, we ran into
each other at a club in the end. Oh,
I know you're talking
about the bisexually.
My sister is a lesbian and she was
dating a lady who was bisexual first.
We weren't close or anything,
but, but we got along. I mean,
I'm assuming you're talking
about the bisexual lady.
Then about a year ago we ran into each
other and a downtown club. Uh, we,
we had a few draw. Jesus,
we have a few drinks.
Just start talking about random
stuff. Uh, she came back,
she's going to try to fucking,
she can try to finger bang the whole
family here until a friend of mine invited
us to a party. At some guy's house.
We went and had a lot more to drink.
And then one thing led to one.
Now that w what it, what it does,
anything good ever come out it. And
then, you know, one thing led to another.
That's when you're fast forwarding through
such a piece of shit thing you did or
something you're embarrassed of, hey,
you know, one thing led to another.
No one ever talks about fucking a hey,
how did you hit that when
they're winning game shot?
Well the inbounded the ball and uh, one
thing led to another and uh, you know,
I hit the, I hit the shot
the way the, and chip,
you will tell every fucking detail I was
running down the court with every step.
I can feel my IP. I knew somebody
had to step up, let to do this.
I'm always going to be me. Right.
That's how you tell it when you fucking,
when you did some good ship,
he did some bad shit. Yeah.
One thing led to another and the guy was
on the ground and he wasn't breathing.
So I dunno what happened.
Okay. One thing led to another.
We ended up having sex.
The next day we came,
we came to and both fell the
horrible about what happened.
You both came to, I just
pictured that fucking, you know,
take my picture.
Smack my bitch up.
Remember that Madonna was
in the background going on.
She was saying like the
fucking opening to star Trek.
The next day we came to in both
felt horribly about what happened.
She then told my sister
that she slept with a man,
but didn't tell her it was
me. Oh, wait, you're a guy.
I thought this was a lady.
Yeah.
Oh, okay. Okay. I'm bisexual. I
Dunno. All right. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. All right.
Your twin sister is a lesbian.
She's dating the lady's bisexual, Yada.
Ya. At first we weren't close or anything,
but we got along okay.
And then you ran into her and you fucked.
You fucked your fucking sisters
girlfriend.
No wonder you went with
one thing led to another.
Then we came to like, you
were both drugged. Oh,
these are classic. You feel
horrible about this, sir.
Or you don't. And, uh,
but you want to get away with it so
you're blowing through the details.
What is very, this is very underwritten
for what the fuck is just gone down here.
Jesus Christ.
Uh,
she then told my sister that she slept
with a man but didn't tell her it was me.
Dude, this chick is a psycho, uh,
for the past year I've
been torn up about it.
I need your unbiased style
of advice. Should I tell my
sister that was me or not?
Thanks. Ps, come to blah, blah, blah. I
would love to see you again. Um, dude,
no, don't say a few.
Die with that. Secret,
that secret and hope that woman fades
away and then if it should ever comes back
around,
she said it was you and just be like,
it was the fire.
One time he had got with Drake's.
Oh,
what they let you went down there?
I wouldn't say a fucking word.
Don't say a fucking word. Okay.
The fly in the ointment here,
it's just bisexual lady. Okay.
She's jumping all over the fence.
She's fucking sister. She's fucking
brothers and she's fucking white people.
No Kid.
She's fucking two people that she's,
she's the flying the fucking
ointment. Okay. She said the shit. Um,
I don't know why she's doing that. This
is like this and she's like Glenn Close,
um, in, in, in fatal attraction.
If she fucked both Michael Douglas in
the Hottie who was married to and the
rabbit. Okay. She just fucked this lady.
Just, you know, you just sit tight.
Okay. This is like in a sub and you cut
the engines and you're just hoping that
they're not going to start dropping
depth charges and you just hope you get
through it sometimes in life. You just
shut the fuck up. I, this was one,
I wouldn't say anything.
Okay.
And if she brings it up, yeah, you
slept with her. I would just, I mean,
what are you going to do?
This is the thing, you just,
this lady's out of her fucking mind.
There's no way your sister's
going to end up with her. Okay.
Okay.
There's no way she's going to
end up with her. All right.
This one was out of her fucking mind,
so she's eventually going to fade away.
Uh Oh. You have to do is just hope that
when it comes time for the breakup,
that the crazy bitch is breaking up with
your sister because your sister goes to
break up with her in that highly
emotional moment. She might drop the ball.
Okay. And then you would just, you
just gotta play it. Like she said, what
now had never have cheese,
just you've just breaking up dead.
She said that's why she was saying it
because you broke her and that she walks
in the room and be like,
oh, I right. I did it
because one thing led to another.
All right, Carl, my pants
down a Billy blue lungs.
I Dunno what that means.
I'm 24 years old and I'm dating a woman
that was 34 years old. Uh, alright.
See fucking and all the lady you're not
dating. Come on. What are you gonna do?
Wow. What were you going
to have your first kid with
her when she's like 96 we've
been dating for close to three
years now and I couldn't be happier.
We recently bought a house.
Oh Geez. You, you're 24,
you're dating a 34 year old and you
bought a house with her recently bought a
house.
I would be nervous if this was flipped in.
The guy was 34 and it was a 24 year old.
He's still a wild horse man.
You've got to run out on the range.
Um,
we recently bought a house and it finally
came time to put down the down payment
on the house and all that extra stuff.
I'm going to be honest and ego
issues on the down payment.
She knows my financial status
and she was cool with it,
but I just wanted to provide more
because she does so much for me.
So I dropped my car insurance without
her knowing to give her the extra money,
even though she said I didn't need to.
I felt like,
what sort of man would I be if I didn't
contribute my part? So my luck has it.
I got into a car accident literally two
weeks after I dropped my car insurance.
I'm between a rock and a hard place.
Now we want to start a family,
but I'm guessing my license
would be suspended for a year.
A lot of burden will be
put upon her now that I'm,
I'm assuming my license will be
suspended for some time. Bill, any,
if you could do me a solid on
this one, that would be great. Ps,
longtime listener, first
time email. Oh Jesus. What do
you, what are you asking me?
Like, yeah, you're fucked. You
are fucked. I agree with that.
Um, well I, um,
in life sometimes you learn a hard lesson,
sir, and you'll learn in right now.
I'm sorry. I don't know what to tell
you. You with this woman, I mean,
the solution, you, what you learned is
the solution is not doing what you did.
You don't expose yourself
to that type of a liability.
He didn't really ask me a question.
Okay.
Uh, all right. So you love this
person. You want to start a family,
that's all good and you fucked up. Uh, I
would, I guess if you haven't told her,
I would come clean. Tell her
what you did, why you did it.
Say you're sorry. And, uh,
and I don't know what
your, what's your fear? 24.
And you want to be able to provide,
she's 34 and you're going to get married.
You're going to start a family. I don't
know. How would you be able to provide,
you've got to get your career going?
I would think so.
That would be my biggest concern once I
find out what the judgment against me is
going to be. But, uh, here's the
deal, dude. She's 34. You're 24.
She should be making more money than
you should have more money than you.
Her life should be further
down there. You know, uh,
you can't try to catch up
to a 34 year old. All right.
Cause the only way for you to do
it is to do what you just did.
And you end up fucking yourself over and
in the long run, you fuck her over too.
So, um, you have to respect the
fact that you're the age you're at,
you're at. And, uh,
I would try to figure out what the fuck
I wanted to do with my life and I'm
gonna try and get that career going.
And I would hope that there would be a
bus close by that I can take to get me to
that because you're, I think you're going
to get fucked here. Sorry to say that.
But um,
yeah,
my advice would be stop trying
to measure up to a 34 year old,
just be 24. All right. I
hope that helped you out. Um,
but that's all I got. Sorry. Okay. All
right. That's the podcast for this week.
If you'd like to donate to the podcast,
you can always do that anytime you shop
on Amazon. Well, how do I do that, bill?
Well,
you just go to [inaudible] dot com you
click on the podcast page and there's an
Amazon link you click on that takes
you right to Amazon. You know,
it doesn't cost you any extra money.
I get credit for driving traffic to that
site, Yada, Yada, Yada. Pulled to do,
to do to whatever, whatever the fuck
you want to say there. All right.
And they'd give me a little bit of
money. All right. That's it. That's it.
Go fuck yourselves. And I'll
check in on you on a, on Thursday.
Congratulations to USC. Congratulations
to Clemson, Alabama. Oh No,
we're going to see who's going to
fucking win that one. And a NFL playoffs.
Playoffs are coming. Bruins had a nice
two game win streak over the sabers.
And then we fucking lost yesterday. I
missed that game. Got fucking smoke.
Three to nothing.
But what do we play?
Played fucking the Carolina Hurricanes.
Um,
that's it. Hey everybody, the holidays
are over. It's a brand new fucking year.
Don't deal with bipolar people.
All right?
If you've got to make a left to get
over towards the double line, uh,
don't liquidate your
fucking insurance. So, uh,
you try to fucking bang a 40 year old.
Uh,
I think that's it. Yeah. And if you
bang your a lesbian sister's girlfriend,
keep your fucking mouth shut. All
right. Talk to you on Thursday.