Hey, what's going on is bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast. And I'm just checking in on you.
That's right. I'm not yelling it.
I'm fucking up my voice doing that.
Every God damn week I'm starting
to drink throat coat tea.
I need to take care of
myself in these next,
this next chapter as I peel
off another layer of the onion,
whatever stupid artistry thing
I've just decided, you know,
a few people in my life, you know,
I'm kind of seeing it. I'm seeing it,
I'm seeing what living a certain
lifestyle leads to and I'm like,
you know what? I need to clean up
my act a little bit. All right,
it's time to grow. Ah, and Ah, so one
of the first things I'm going to do,
I'm not cutting out the booze or
I'm just going to stop yelling.
I'm checking in on you. You
know, it's baby steps. You know,
when I'll gradually work towards
laying off the heroin, you know,
I like it. It helps me, helps
me go to sleep. You know,
the amount of times that I always want
to take a nap when I'm standing up
outside in public and I just can't do
it because my mind just won't shut off.
You know, that's, that's
when the heroin comes in.
That's when it comes into play.
You're gonna have to listen to my phone,
Ding Dong and cause I got a phone call
coming up and I don't want to miss it
here. Um, anyways, let me see here.
Uh, uh, Jesus. Now I'm going
to be looking at text messages,
message messages, messages, while
I'm trying to do this podcast.
This is really gonna fuck with my
add here. How's your week going?
I'm going to tell you something, right?
All but Billy booze bag and all right.
I had, I had family in [inaudible]. Some
of you guys guessed the movie by the way.
Um,
it's something you do with a car.
You can't figure it out.
Now I can't help you.
But what I love is now everybody
knows what the movie is,
but there's still going to
treat me like the long, long,
long trailer starring Lucille Ball.
Um,
why don't you guys ask me if it's every
other movie that you could do with the
car other than the one you notice.
How about that?
How about switching it up a little bit?
Is it Herbie goes to Monte Carlo?
You know,
I realize all these years I've been
using that as a reference. Like,
cause it's the one at the first or
second movie I saw, I suffer lover Benji.
Then I saw Herbie goes to Monte
Carlo and my mother was just like,
my mother told me, you know, I, they're
just, those kids movies were stupid.
I wasn't going to take it
anymore though. So, you know,
basically there wasn't
anything there for her.
And she just was looking at it like,
you know,
there's really nothing here for these
kids. It's a fucking talking car.
It's a talking dog. You know, how long
are we going to keep the lie going?
All right, the fat fuck doesn't come
down. The chimney. Dogs don't talk.
And the VW beetle, it's an, it's an,
it's an economical car. But you know,
at the end of the day it's not respect
itself. That's it. Let's go see stripes.
Um, anyways, uh, completely forgot
what the fuck I was gonna say. They're
on a fuck that I get to that.
I have no idea.
Do I need to go on burn any
to play some brain games?
Saturday is what the fuck was out.
Eat more healthy.
I don't know where the [inaudible] but
the family back east. I got it. I got it.
Rebeck right.
He'll be those outtakes on Casey Casey
when he flips out screaming young.
Now God damn it. I'm not fucking reading
about a fucking dog died. You know,
this is basically like those outtakes
except I don't edit them up and I also
don't have his iconic success.
Yeah. Other than that,
I think it's the exact same thing.
But anyways,
I had family come in fee and we'd kill
me and probably a quiche twice in this
past month. And um, I had to
take him out to the spots.
We had to drink a little toast
for the little one, a little Nini.
Dude, she's laughing her ass off
now. It's the greatest thing.
It's the greatest thing ever.
Um,
could not be in a joint
more in its June's first.
And for the first time in my life on,
someone can actually look at me and say,
happy father's Day. Right. And I
don't have to be like, oh my God.
In what Comedy Club did you work?
How old is it? Um, anyways, no, I
was never like that on the road.
I was a good boy, sort of. I had my
moments anyways, plowing ahead here.
Um, so because they came in,
I kind of got off my diet.
I was still doing the cardio every day,
so I stepped on the scale and the
unacceptable second number in my world is
eight. Okay. If it's ever a
nine, I'm telling you right now,
I am going to jump off a fucking building.
Um,
I won't do that.
I'll just buy really comfortable.
I'll keep wearing the golf clothes that I
wear. They'll just get bigger. You know,
I'll was getting to the
John Daly line. Um, so,
uh, I'm back on it. I'm back on it.
Jumped on the scale today. One 78.8.
Still unacceptable.
I have been having the worst fucking
time trying to get down to my fighting
weight. I wanted to be one
72 by my birthday, my 49th,
the end of the forties. Wrapping it
up. If I was a professional athlete,
I would be 10 years for tired.
And once I was Tom Brady with my senior
we muscles or whatever the fuck he's
doing with his spongy muscles,
um,
I don't know what he's doing. Sorry,
I'm drinking the throat coat. Oh, Geez.
It's bill. You're just annoying on so many
different levels today. I apologize. Um,
so anyways,
so I'm just,
I'm going to try to just lay
off the booze for a little bit.
I'm going to San Francisco,
uh,
this weekend and uh,
I'm working with fucking my dean
off my Dean Martin Joe to Rosa.
Okay. So that's going to be, that's
going to be a Mulligan that night.
Joe.
My friendship with Joe to Rosa in his
friendship with me is one of the great
friendships in show business
history and it's all,
it's all alcohol fueled.
You know,
I don't think we've ever hung around
each other sober and I don't think that I
got to get him on the podcast.
I really got to get all fucking Joe to
rose or whatever. His background is,
Egyptian,
Italian.
He doesn't know that man was left at
the doorstep of a funny bone way back in
1977.
I believe he showed up on a
nowhere a baby. Nobody wanted,
he came out of the womb already
wearing those dark frame glasses.
Um, it's sad, but said,
um, anyways, plowing ahead.
I'm sure I'm going to hear
about that from old Joey. Um,
I'm guessing two drinks in they do it.
There was something I want
to talk to you about. It's,
I know you were just joking, but you know,
to bring that up, it's just really, um,
fuck him. He trashed my dog on stage.
Oh, that's coming out. Fourth drinking.
I'm trying to guess where the
argument's gonna come from this weekend.
Why drink with Joe? We really don't argue
anymore. Once I discovered, fair enough,
you know, I grew up a little bit. He grew
up a little bit, and that's all we did.
We start to argue and then one of books
just goes, Hey, fifth, fair enough.
And we laugh and it just
diffuses everything. Fair enough.
Fair enough. Could stop
wars. You know what I mean?
This is our borderline now we think it
said, hey, fair enough. Fair enough.
I understand why you would take
that, but I mean, you know.
Fair enough.
Well, you're going to give it to
us law. Yeah, I didn't say that.
Okay,
well then I'm going to fucking start
shooting, I think. Fair enough. Yeah.
That's what you feel you need to do.
It just diffuses the other guy.
Then the other guy standing there
going like, no, you're supposed to,
you supposed to get mad.
Then you get mad,
and then I get mad and then I lied to
my people and you lie to your people.
We dehumanize each other
that don't we start shooting.
Stop saying, fair enough.
All right, fair enough.
Anyways, anybody watched the, uh, the
penguins were still fucking predator.
I'll tell you something about these tcs
penguins from Pittsburgh is they know
how to fucking win a goddamn series.
Jesus Christ,
the predators in an o two hold for
those of you bad at math when it's best.
Four out of seven, you're down. Oh two.
That means you have to
win four of the next five.
All the coach isn't going to tell
you that. What's he going to say?
All right guys. All right boy, we
got to take it one game at a time.
Okay. Are these crossed the
hall in that Locker Room Day?
They put their escape too.
I bought it at a time.
Okay.
We've got to start winning the battles
at one period of time.
Do they are beating the shit out of
Sidney Crosby? This playoff series.
This playoff is just this,
this, this playoff run.
I don't know what he did to the refs,
but they had done protecting that guy.
Okay.
This slashing and they hooking them,
they're fucking hitting him in the head.
Anything that they can do. Um, I dunno.
I think that they, uh, they, they should
have brought a goon up or something.
Okay.
Somebody to do something.
I don't know. But anyways,
how about fucking Malkin's goal?
Absolute fucking,
you know, and I know
that they, uh, pulled Oh,
pito today or whatever
his fucking name is.
For some reason I can't remember
his goddamn named Pekka. Rina,
the hell's his name. She
says, I can't cock suck.
I came up with some about a dick is the,
is the Predator.
I fucking watched every game and
I still can't remember his name.
Okay.
The fuck is his name. He's a pecker
arena. Was that the guy from San Jose?
Was he on San Jose then? He
went to Nashville. You don't,
once I stopped collecting cards,
you know, and I turned to scotch.
I just never been able to, I've never
been able to handle the names anymore.
But anyways, I don't give a
fuck who you are. Ken Dryden.
Patrick Wa Terry saw chuck.
Nobody stops that fucking puck.
That was an absolute filthy,
filthy fucking goal.
Um, so my prediction, way back
in the day, what did I say?
What did I say before I flip flopped
and set said audit was going to,
was going to win. Game
seven, before I did that,
I said the penguins were going to win
the whole thing. So when it happens,
I'm going to ignore the
fact that I thought auto was
going to come back and win
game seven, cause I was questioning
the goaltending in Pittsburgh.
I'm going to ignore all of that and I'm
going to pull up Paul Versey and say,
dude, what did I say
dude? I called it, um,
just out of, uh, you know,
jealousy. I want to, uh,
I want to see the Predator does
tie up the series and not jealousy.
Just thought of like selfishness.
I want to see the, um,
the NHL season goes as many
games as possible, but uh,
they'll tell you right now the
way the penguins deploying, uh,
I mean I don't even see there's
Walberg the brickwork. Uh,
we'll see something incredible has said.
How about,
I don't know who the fuck shot that goal,
that baby face kid there.
I mean that was like the,
the,
the puck had ice it like there was one
little fucking just puck sized space for
a split second between old peck,
a penis there,
whatever his name is.
It just opened up for half a second.
The puck literally turned sideways like
some Matrix Shit and went in the car.
I remember when I, when I saw it live,
it's like how the fuck did that go in?
I Dunno man.
I'll tell you the hockey gods are
smiling down in Pittsburgh right now. Um,
who knows, we'll see what sorta home
home ice advantage they have. But uh,
and also the NBA playoffs not play
offs. The uh, final starts tonight.
Is that the NBA finals in the Stanley
Cup final or is it Stanley Cup finals in
the NBA final? I think
it's the NBA finals. Um,
every time I say something stupid, my
phone rings. That's it right there.
Does a little bing.
All right.
I have a call here in fucking a,
let's see,
10 minutes, 10 minutes. So I'm
gonna have to hit pause here.
It's not gonna matter to you guys
cause I'll just pick it up. You know,
they'll give me 10 minutes of silence.
Like I'm trying to do some artsy,
um, that starts tonight. Um,
okay.
I Dunno, I don't have a feeling on this
one. I want the Cavaliers to win. Um,
I want the capitalist to him cause I
still feel like they don't get their
respect.
People aren't talking about them like
did the defending like they are the
defending NBA champions and
[inaudible] went to the warriors.
I think that that's why nobody
seems to be able to talk about it.
You know what I mean? Just to be able
to see like, hey, not for nothing.
These guys beat those
other guys last year.
So I hope they keep disrespecting them
cause I always root against the pylon
team. You know? And I even did
it with the red sox in 2007.
I just, I don't even think
I watched the world series.
I mean obviously I was happy that we won.
Obviously.
I'd rather see us win then
the fucking Colorado Rockies.
But I was just lie, this
is, that's not competition.
You know, having said that,
having said that, when the, uh,
okay,
when the base, when the basketball
and hockey season ends, okay,
I'm getting the the MLB package and I'm
watching my $210 million Red Sox who are
in second place,
three games behind the evil empire that
has nothing but their own homegrown
talent.
And I'm going to watch that collision
course and see how that goes. Um, I,
I've learned this is what you have to do
if you're a sports fan with some fairly
big east is the baseball
is such a great sport,
but the problem is,
is the first,
almost the first half of the season is
the most exciting time in basketball and
hockey and your emotions as a fan.
I was so heightened,
even if your team is out of
it, just to watch, you know,
there's always something great
happens in the, in the final,
unless you enough the fucking ref called
38 files on one team at 15 on the other,
then it sucks.
Okay.
Letting it go.
Um,
and then all of a sudden it's
over and then you settle it.
Yeah. Just a bit outside on a
beautiful day for a ball game.
Yeah.
I'll tell you his on base percentage is
six 45 or that he's really seeing the
ball right now. I can't be
played the game. What was
it like when you had just a,
what do you hit a zone like this?
Well, I'll tell you, you know when you
hit a zone like this, I mean that ball.
I mean your eyes are as big as Chris in
at. I mean it just, it's like you can't,
you just stick in the bad out there and
the ball's going where it wants to go.
But you know,
how do you, how do you try to stay
in that zone? How do you try to,
I try to keep it going.
Well, you know, it's one of those
things you can't control. You just,
you learn as you,
as you mature as a player to just try
to enjoy those moments and a while,
you know, your hope it goes, as
long as it can put a grouchy,
it is going to swing back to the other
way. And you just hope that that says a,
you know,
that the slump
doesn't last as long. So,
uh, you know, you could, uh,
keep your house in that gold dig and
horror that you met in Tulsa when you're
coming up in AAA that you knocked up and
you don't really love, but you like her,
you're hanging in there for the kid. Um,
you know, you've got to settle into that.
So what you need to do is,
uh,
what you got to just immediately,
you got to slow everything the
fuck down and what you have to do,
what you got to watch a day game,
you got to keep score
while you smoke a cigar.
You know, you get your lineup,
you get it all ready to go.
You just fucking sit there and you
like the cigar, but the third, any,
you know, and he'd just sit there and
you fucking maybe even on the radio,
listen to it on the radio and you just,
it's like sports yoga.
He just have to totally
just calm your mind,
fucking relax and then slide
into the dog days of baseball.
Right?
And then you ride that out for about six
weeks and then all of a sudden it's NFL
preseason. All right. And
as a pre season comes along,
you're excited about football
cause every week's exciting,
cause they only play 16 games. Right?
But baseball's also ramping up.
So then when September comes
along, it's like April, May,
June with basketball and hockey.
Cause now it's like you're so excited how
fucking NFL football, college football.
It's coming back. I have
a reason to live. Right.
And the baseball race is heating up
before you go in with Joe Buck and all the
great October baseball. That's
how you do it. All right,
so these next six weeks after the finals
are over, you know, I'm telling you,
I'll walk you through it on the podcast.
You know,
you pick a couple of alternative sports.
Maybe you watch a little Roland Garris,
little Wimbledon,
you get into Formula One,
maybe a little a Moto g
p right? I don't know what the
fuck you got to do. It's not,
it's not my business. It's
none of my business. What time
is it? Nine 55. Let's see,
I can read advertising
in five minutes.
I don't think I can do it.
Especially when I got to
type in my God damn password.
The family bag.
He sched kidding.
Um, all right. What do we
got here? Oh, love supreme.
All right,
worry Indo dean.
Don't cheat a talk about how every
man looks better on a suit. You know,
when I'm checking out of Fella, I love
boy shorts, just like the next guy.
But what really turns me on is a
nice sharp look and fell in a suit.
You know what I mean?
Grab him by his tie or Indochino is
making it easy to get a perfectly tailored
suit and an incredible price.
You can choose from hundreds
of top quality fabrics and
personalize your suits,
your fucking initials on the pocket,
uh, just the way you want it.
Don't you pills to whether it works,
uh,
whether it's for work or a wedding
or another special occasion.
Indochino has suited up hundreds of
thousands of men and are now the largest
made to measure men's wear brand
in the world world, world, world.
Here's how it works.
Visit a showroom or shop
online at Indochino, I.
N d O, c h, I n o.com. Um,
like the indigo girls,
if they went to China Indochino uh,
pick your fabric.
Went to the warehouse.
I picked out a fucking suit.
I went with three piece.
I talked to Wei am a man.
Um,
choose your customer customizations from
lapels to pleats to jacket linings and
more submissive.
Submit your measurements,
place your order and wait for it to
arrive. And just a few weeks this week,
my listeners can get any premium
Indochino suit for just 379
dollars@indochino.com when
entering Bert at checkout,
that's 50% off the regular price for
a made to measure premium suit plus
shipping is free.
Uh,
that's indochino.com promo code birth
for any premium suit for $379 and free
shipping.
Incredible deal for a suit that will fit
you better than anything off the rack
ever could. Nine 57, how many more
do I got? I got two more to go.
Five. Four club. Yo,
you like a short pitch.
This is the five four club.
I'm kidding. Um, looking good.
Doesn't need to cost a fortune five
four club is revolutionizing the way men
stop at five four club.
They found a way to make a great look.
Great looking clothes
affordable for everyone.
Five Photo Club also understands
that your time is extremely valuable.
Why?
One wasted at the mall or wandering
around in stores each month.
They send you a crow,
a curated box of two to three items.
That just means somebody else picked
it out. I hate that word. Curated.
If somebody gives a shit the fuck does
this guy want tank tops aid you fucking
tank tops. Why wasted? Oh,
what the fuck am I handpicked? Match
the current season and your style? Oh,
they call an early. Oh God.
This is from Montreal. Quebec.
All right, I'm back. I'm
in between interviews.
I mean between fucking interviews here.
I got around the wrong fucking headphones.
All right, here we got back back.
I got another interview and four
minutes with the fee. The big east.
Um,
all right,
let's put the fuck was I talking
about trying to type in my password?
This is a mess. Why would I do this
before I hit fucking set it? Yeah.
There we go. There we go. Oh
five four club that I finish.
Five four club.
Um,
they've been helping men with fashion
for over 15 years and shipped over a
hundred thousand men every month.
Chris,
Paul and Mark Walberg use five four club.
If fat photo club is featured in Gq,
vice and instyle among other publications,
they know what they're doing.
So if you don't think that's okay,
five four club will help you. What?
They know what they're doing. So if you
don't also, if you don't, that's okay.
Thought they were getting a little chip
on itself so you don't think that's okay,
that fuck you get,
you got damn suit somewhere else.
Five four club will help you build
your wardrobe one month at a time.
Because when you look good,
you feel good brother.
And they'd think he knows she's on her
knees. It's a fact of life. You get $120.
What the clothes for?
Just $60 a month. You can.
That doesn't make sense.
80% of the time it works 100% of the time.
You can pause or cancel any time,
no commitments.
And as a fivefold club member,
you'll receive up to 50% off your items
in their online shop and access to
exclusive members only items in a members
only jacket for 30 bucks free shipping
and CISE exchanges.
Go to five four club.com right now and
enter your Promo Code [inaudible] and
they'll give you 50% off your first
month's package plus a free pair of
sunglasses.
That's 50% off your first
package at Fido club,
spelled f I. V. E.
F Oh now you are club.com Promo Code
[inaudible] five four club.com Promo Code
Barb.
All right,
see so everybody see so you
know I've had funny feelings.
I've gotten funny looks,
I've eaten,
I've even eaten funny smelling Sushi.
But let me tell you,
none of those are as funny
as CSO streaming library
of standup television and
original content,
especially not the Sushi.
Why would they try to write comedy for us?
Let me do a quick rewrite of this.
You know,
I've had a funny feeling in my gut.
I've gone down on a funny smell in Twat.
Get Out.
I been in a parking lot late at night
and felt funny like, you know, is,
is someone gonna fucking cut me up.
But nothing compares to watch and a
fucking six feet under run on a CSO.
All right,
maybe I should go with this shit next,
please mention the talking points below.
I'm going to mention all of them.
If you fucking give him to me again.
Damn cans over them. Um, with Cecil,
you get unlimited access to seeso
original series next day, late night,
hilarious. Standup sketch
specials, binge worthy classics,
including 42 seasons of Saturday night.
Live the entire money pond,
python catalog,
the it crowd in more.
I don't understand why more people
aren't watching. See, so I mean,
they've got some fucking, every episode
of Saturday night live is on there.
The entire Monty python cat and I
don't know what the fucking ieCrowd is,
but shit, if it's following those
two, it's gotta be good with Cecil,
you get binge worthy classics,
British called comedy original series
like Harman quest and bajillion dollar
properties. Not to mention the entire
SNL library. I just fucking said that.
I'm supposed to pick one of these or
watch your favorite sets from Comedians
like Louis C,
k a me fucking shoe and Hannibal Buress
access CSO content from anywhere at
anytime using Ios, android,
Roku, apple TV, Amazon Fire TV,
stealing cable from your
neighbor windows or x box one.
Ready for the punchline. CSO
is just 399 per month. No joke.
Three 99 per month for all the
comedy you want. Anytime anywhere,
add fucking free.
Go to Seeso,
s e s o.com right now to sign up for
one month for free with the Promo Code
[inaudible] at checkout.
That's seeso.com spelled s e e
s o.com Promo Code [inaudible].
All right, what else did I
want to talk about? Um, oh,
by the way, tiger woods, who was arrested?
Everybody said was arrested
for drinking and driving,
blew a 0.0 point fucking zero
at Jesus Christ is another one.
Hang on a second.
Hello.
Oh Man, those are two fun interviews. I
just talked to a guy who goes by lights.
Camera Jackson.
How do you not love that guy?
That is old school showbiz.
How do you ever forget that name?
Lights. Camera Jackson. All right,
let me type this in here.
Your family,
Becky might fucking password.
Why won't you work for me?
Why won't you work for
me? You know, it's funny.
If somebody has enough time at some point,
the fucking splice together every time
I'm trying to fucking put together my
password yet, by the way, tiger woods,
tiger woods
blue is 0.0 the dude was on pills.
You know what I mean?
The level of shit that that guy's getting,
that guy sacrificed his fucking
body to become great. Okay.
Now his body's breaking down and
everybody's blaming it on the fact that he
cheated on his lay right,
and that's what did him in
his laser focus. He couldn't block out
the fat I the first two years. Yeah,
I'm sure bugged. But I mean, at
some point you move on, right?
His body blade said
from the very beginning,
they said the way he swings the club,
his body's gonna break down at some point.
So now look at him. Now look at him.
You know, he's trying to come back.
He's on all these painkillers.
He wants to win another one probably
before he hangs it up and goes to the, uh,
the senior tour.
He's doing what he has to do.
These fucking drugs that you can get
nowadays are completely out of control.
When I was a kid, when a drug came
out, bear or any of this shit,
they didn't have 9,000 side effects.
What happened was people used to
be in the pharmaceutical industry,
got into the fucking FDA and they're
the ones who police to pharmaceutical
companies. And those cons
just waved everything around
that the third bass coast,
it dead, lost his vision, right?
So then they let opiates
end of the fucking world.
Now you've got a goddamn heroin epidemic.
Okay.
And now tiger woods is taken too many of
those fucking things and he pulls over
to the side of the road and everybody's
saying it's because he did the fucking
blonde hair, blue eyed woman, whoever
he is, a saint who took his fucking his,
his master's money,
bought a giant house,
not the fucking thing down
to buy something else. Where
did all that material go?
Where did all those fucking
gold plated toilets go?
They went right into the fucking ocean,
you know, but she's a victim. Oh,
give me a break. That's it
for the podcast. Signing
off. Not fucking with you.
I'm just trying to energy my way
through the last bit of this. Uh,
what else do I have here to talk about?
Oh, you know, he has a great new bits,
a new bit I brought,
his name is Charlie,
Charlie Watts drummer for the rolling
stones as a great new book out that it's
just a drummer's that influenced him.
And if you're a drummer and you're
into that shit because he's a,
I guess a jazz drummer at heart.
He talked about all these
fucking great drummers that I've,
I've heard most of the names and didn't
know enough about them and the fact that
he could break down their styles
and what they did has made me a,
I was already listening to a lot of that
shit through some of my drum lessons,
but really just trying to listen to the
shit that he's saying. It's a great book.
Um, let me, let me look it up here. I'm
going to fucking hype his book here.
You know, we've been trying to get Charlie
Watson this podcast for a long time.
I know he doesn't do a
lot of interviews and uh,
but I know he'd want to come on my
podcast. I'm joking. Charlie watts book.
Let's see what we got here.
Jolly.
You know the fucking Internet works
in like two rooms in my fucking house.
I spent all this money like can you give
me the nuclear level fucking Internet
so I can send out,
beat out my neighbors and you know,
it works for a little
while then that's it.
Well was sown. Shelly watch 10 things
you didn't know about. Shelly Watch.
Why no books about Charlie Watch,
you know,
I'm usually good about
front Charlie watts books,
drummers influence book.
You know,
I nailed the John Daly
search the last time.
Okay,
come on for fuck sakes. Oh Charlie, watch
David drama. So it did come up, dude.
He can get it for 12 bucks,
$12 and 37 cents. Um,
whiplash, the film that puts the
drummer in the limelight. I did.
I ever tell you guys how much
I fucking hated that movie.
I just hated watching somebody getting
berated. It's just like fucking quit.
Go join another band.
Why would you sit there and taking that
level of shit from the guy and then not
to mention the kids fucking technique.
I,
you had to look away when he
was fucking playing real fast.
He's making those faces. You could just
feel the guy's forums taken up. This guy,
this guy's going to have carpal tunnel
trying to please this complete cunt.
You know,
and I got to tell you,
the best drums from that year was not
in that movie is great as the drums were
the best fucking drums. And some of the
best drummers I've heard in a movie,
a mainstream moving a long fucking
time. Was that Michael Keaton movie? Um,
what the fuck was that movie where he
was the former superhero? The bird.
Do you not long.
I watched that movie before I realized
that was him in the costume talking to
himself. Spoiler alert.
All right, Michael Keaton.
I'm just going to write bird.
Fuck you spell his name.
I've only been watching his movies for
30 fucking years. Built Jesus Christ.
Michael Keaton,
bird bird man.
Yo Birdman five fo.
Um,
who the fuck is the drummer in that?
I know I talked about that before.
The drums in that movie
are fucking incredible.
It's like,
okay,
like that. That's what just a whole
other level of drumming would.
That guy is like,
he's playing like moods.
They supposed to just play a 90
million miles an hour all over the kid.
That guy is, he's, he's piece creating
peaks and valleys. I mean that was like a,
that was literally a movie score
just done with drums. I mean,
how many people can have that level of
talent? I can tell you right now. I know.
I don't,
I already knew I didn't in for the last
three weeks because I've been so damn
busy. I've just been playing like,
you know, not on a real drum kit,
you know, a little practice pad kit that
I was playing on and I thought I was,
you know,
I thought I was doing something and
then I went down and I played on a real
fucking kitten and Jesus
Christ, everything that you
think he could, you can,
you can do drops by like 50 bps.
You know,
it'd be basically like if you would
just jogging on a treadmill being like,
wow man, I can run a seven minute mile.
Then he'd go out to run down the street.
You know, when you forgot about hills and
shit and all of a sudden, you know, you,
you can't run a seven minute mile anymore.
Even if it was flat,
flat level. Okay. He'd
be, if it was flat level,
all of a sudden you run like a fucking
11 minute mile. That's what I was like,
it was extremely fucking
disheartening. And, um, I'm doing the,
uh, the comedy jam this weekend up
in San Francisco for cluster fest,
which is just completely
like one of the biggest,
I don't know how they afforded to,
to,
to get all of those comedians
and bands and all of that.
They must've had a lot of ad money.
Somebody is doing something to
establish that comedy festivals on.
We're going to go fucking,
you know,
nine zillion dollars in the
hole to start it out. But uh,
you might want to go this year
because they're going big. Um,
oh, I had moments forgot
before I sign off here.
Thank you to everybody who
has been watching season
two of F is for family. Um,
got nothing but great reviews. You know,
there's always a couple of cunty once.
What are you going to do?
But overall you guys not only like it,
but you're saying you think it's
even better than the first season,
which for the amount of work that we put
in, um, to hear that kind of feedback,
you know, I know I'm a jerk a lot.
That really means a lot to me.
So thank you guys for
not only watching it.
Thank you for the people that took the
time to let me know how much you enjoyed
it. Please let other people know about
it. The more the people know about it,
the more people watch it and the better
chance we have of possibly getting a
third season. Um, and that's it.
That's the podcast for this week.
Have a great weekend.
You can stare and a is a little bit of
a bit of music from Andrew Feminists and
um, dealt. We'll play a little half hour,
some greatest hits from the Thursday or
the podcast or whatever those day gone
by a medium Monday morning.
I don't know what. All right,
that's not my part of the podcast.
All right,
I'll talk to you on Monday,
coming back.
Oh,
all right. Hey, this is
the longest fucking revenge
story I think I've ever read.
Let me see if I can, uh,
see if I can fucking just,
I'm going to blow my, read that one next
week when I have the energy. All right.
Questions? All right, Bill.
Uh, I have a question for you.
I was hoping you might be able
to shine some insight on this.
I have this great friend
that that's a girl mistake.
Um,
and we get along great and we have never
had any sort of sexual tension walking
up or interest despite
her being attractive.
Okay.
All right, dude. Right there. You're
either gay or you're, or you're an idiot.
And I'm not trying,
I'm giving you some tough love here.
That's a fucking stupid
situation to be involved in.
Okay.
That's stupid.
All right.
Unless you're using her to attract
other females to get you fucking late.
Let's see if this is the case.
I will continue reading.
So she has this smoking hot
friend. Oh, there we go.
That I had met a few times and
always flirted with. But uh,
but it's just been overall friendly.
So this checks calls me up one night
and I'm at the bar at like midnight and
asked if I want to stay up drinking
with her and she'd come pick me up.
So obviously I agree. Thanks. Go very
good. And we have a few drinks and flirt.
And when I make my move, she gets
all upset. Like I should have known.
She just wants to be friends.
When she calls me up at midnight to say
to stay up drinking with her alone after
the incident, the bitch still has the
balls to slow to ask to sleep over.
Uh,
since then I have noticed all of friends
are trying to be my friend when all I
want to do is rail the shit out of them.
Bill, I was hoping you could, you should,
you could shine some light on the
situation and help me out. Yeah, dude,
never have a friend as a,
as a female,
you know,
you always gotta be
fucking him. That's the only
reason to be around him, you know?
I know that sounds really
sexist, but you know, I, I just,
I'm speaking from me.
There's no fucking point
in hanging out with that
level of frustration if you're
not having sex with them.
And if there are actually like a good
friend and that's the one that you should,
uh,
I mean that's the ultimate,
if you're banging them and
they're also a great friend,
that's the one you marry cause you got a
connection there. Right. But if you just,
I mean they're using you
as like a live teddy bear.
Okay.
And um, yeah, the next time they call up,
just be like, no, I'm, I, I'm not, I can't
hang out tonight. What are you doing?
I'm going to go out and try
to get some ass tonight.
I know I'm not getting any from you and
it's frustrating because you're hot and
I want to bend you over every piece
of fucking furniture in my apartment.
[inaudible] I can't believe you
said that. Yeah. Well I just did.
Are you going to come over here and
fuck me? Well then great. I have to,
why are you being so mean? I'm not
being mean, I'm being honest. Okay.
Do you have any times I've jerked off
to you. It's fucking, and it's annoying
that you just, you just, I'm telling
you, like that's a little aggressive,
but that's what you have to start doing.
You just have to be straightforward
and honest and don't do it.
Like I just said it, do it, do it
how you can do it and pull it off.
And you just say it like that and
just be like, Hey, I want to go out.
I want to try to get laid tonight.
All right.
And I go out with you and
you're not fucking me.
And then other girls see me with you
and they think that I am fucking you,
which I'm not. And I ended up
going home, a dry humping my futon,
you know, and it's really fucking
with myself to steam. Okay.
So that's it. So basically he
ready. You say you say that,
um, if I had a sack your cock,
you know, I hang out with me. Yes.
That is what I'm saying. That's what I'm
saying. Your conversations are awful,
you know, I'm sure they're interesting
to other females, but not to me.
I don't want it to,
I don't want to talk about that shit.
I could give a shit about the hills,
the Osi,
the ocean or whatever the
fuck I was stupid. Show you
what? I don't give a fuck.
I don't give a fuck. I
want to fuck you. Okay.
It's world's Ed, right day
in artist. You have a seat.
Well watched the world series of poker.
When you go all in, that's what you do.
Just say what the fuck you want to do.
You push all your chips in and you
stand up and you start walking around.
You wait for that next car to drop.
Steve. What the fuck happens? Yeah,
dude, that's my advice. Get
out of that whole circle of EA.
He's like a big teddy bear.
Fuck that. Fuck Dad. All right.
United Teddy Bear. Well, you are one right
now. You've got to stop being that guy.
So fuck all of them. Go. Uh, where
your guy friends, what are they doing?
Go hang out with them.
Go get a fucking wing man.
Get yourself back in the game and uh,
go out there and talk some shit.
Hit on some girl you
don't give a fuck about.
So you can practice not giving a fuck
and just say a bunch of shit that you
would never say to some girl
that you gave a shit about, eh,
because you don't give a fuck if the
girl says no, start with that, you know,
always wear a condom. And uh, and
that's it. That's what I would do.
That's what I should've done.
I didn't,
I just have that knowledge
now cause I'm fucking, uh,
and I have been the funeral psalm.
I was never the front,
but I was definitely the Douche
bag. I was definitely the, the uh,
not even pussy whipped wasn't even pussy.
What does just,
I couldn't fucking speak up for myself.
I was afraid of having a confrontation
and then by the time I had the final
confrontation, I was like, ah, I know.
It was like fucking a year with
the shit and we broke up. Um,
but that's a whole nother thing.
[inaudible]
[inaudible] up everybody.
It's bill bar.
This is the Monday morning podcasts and
I'm recording for the third time this
week.
Praying and hoping against hope that g
CAS will actually upload this one because
I've already spent 90 minutes doing
podcasts this week. So anyways,
if you're hearing this,
it means I successfully uploaded it.
So there's no sense complaining,
unlike the rest of the people in my
fucking life. You know you have it.
Just have one of those weeks where
everyone's just bitching at you.
That's what I got.
You know,
that's what I'm dealing with right now.
Like today's my girlfriend's birthday
and she's, she was fucking pissed at me.
She went absolutely psycho
on me this morning. You know,
it had nothing to do with me. Had
nothing to fucking do with me. You know,
I gave her a piece of cake last night,
right at midnight,
sang her happy birthday because
technically it was a birthday.
I gave her a pre birthday slice of cake
and then I gave her a bag of Fritos with
a little bow on it. Right.
Just being a silly jackass.
Like that's all you're getting
for your birthday. Right.
And everything was going great.
I was a big sweetheart.
And then I woke up this morning and made
the mistake of telling her that I had
made a dinner reservation yet.
And then she starts flipping out acting
like I'm just throwing her God damn
birthday together when I gave her a pre
birthday fucking slice of birthday cake,
you know,
starts flipping out.
I don't know why she was flipping
out. It's like, it's fucking Tuesday.
It's a Tuesday. It's not a holiday.
This who the fuck is going out tonight?
June 2nd. Oh Shit. Was it
Cinco de Mayo? You know,
is it a fuss? I'm fucking New Zealand
holiday that I don't know about.
There's going to be plenty of fucking
reservations and lo and behold,
after she flips out, you
know, screaming at me. Right?
So all my neighbors think that I'm
beating her. Women love doing that Shit.
They just put on this big fucking show.
Right? And then afterwards they just guy,
I'm sorry I got a little crazy.
I don't know.
I think just he don't hate
me, dare you. You forgive me.
And they do that shit. Right. Meanwhile,
you know your neighbors
don't hear that part.
They don't hear the part where they sort
of say really quietly that they flipped
out for no fucking reason. You know,
all they heard was to scream and yell.
And so now I'm going to get the looks
today I'm going to go down to the garage.
You know,
like it's the 1920s like I should become
walking out with like a fucking wife
beater, you know, as I
reattach the belt to my pants.
So this is what happens, right. I ended
up calling up this fucking restaurant,
is this not one of the nicest
steak houses out here in la?
I call him up. I said, hey,
I'd like a reservation for
two people. Hang. Okay sir,
what time would you like? I
said, how about eight? Ah,
can't do anything at eight.
How about eight 30 and I said, you know
what sweetheart, that would be perfect.
And she said, okay, and that was it.
That's all I had to fucking do.
But for some reason,
because I didn't do that
before her birthday,
that means that I don't give a fuck.
That's how fucking nuts women are.
She absolutely, she actually
flipped out on me. Okay.
At 10 o'clock in the
morning on her birthday,
she didn't even give me a chance to fuck
the day up. She did a preemptive strike,
even though I gave her a pre birthday
slice of cake, I sang happy birthday.
I made a shutter arise, I put, I put out
the lights, I lit a candle. I came in,
I sang happy birthday and
I gave her a bag of Fritos,
which is fucking ridiculous and silly.
It was great.
And tonight she's getting the real
gift, if you know what I mean. Oh. Um,
you know,
so it's one of those deals
where I'm laying in bed and
then all of a sudden she,
ah, it's just fucking ridiculous,
you know? But I didn't back down.
I didn't back down. I, you know,
actually when she really got mad,
why is she started flipping out is
because she, when she was screaming at me,
I was laughing.
You know,
I don't know if any other guy out
there has that problem you ever had.
Like when your girlfriend
starts yelling at you,
you're first instinct is just to
start laughing. I don't know why.
Every time my girl yells at me,
I instantly feel like I'm in
school again and I'm like,
and in second grade and I'm
getting yelled at and it's just,
and my friends are laughing at me.
That's, that's what I feel like.
I feel ridiculous. Okay.
I guess that's what it is.
When when a woman yells at me,
I always feel ridiculous.
You don't want a guy yells at me.
I get mad because I think, oh fuck,
this guy's going to beat the shit out of
me. So you got to get into that energy.
But when a girl,
a woman is just sitting there,
what are you supposed to do? You know,
I'm not going to yell back at you.
You're a woman.
I don't want to feel like a bully.
We're not going to get physical.
You're a woman.
You know it's stupid.
Stop yelling that fucking high pitch
voice. You sound like a fucking,
he's all like Mickey
Mouse. Sit Down, relax,
collect your thoughts. Make a list. If
you have to tell me why you're upset,
you know,
but don't just sit there fucking yelling
at me like you just took a hit off a
helium balloon because
it just sounds hilarious,
especially when I haven't done anything
wrong and I got a great fucking gift
this year.
That's what was killing me that actually
I actually had that moment during the
fight where I said, you want your gift,
fine, and I went out and I pull it out.
It's already wrapped with a bow on it.
You know,
sitting there acting like I'm not fucking
prepared. There's your fucking present.
Bam wrapped with a fucking bow on it.
Jesus,
everybody giving me Shit.
I remember last week when I called that
woman a douchebag remembered the Douche
bag of the week last week because
she was giving me shit. Once again,
a female surprise,
surprise was giving me shit that when
I read the underrated overrated or the
questions people have,
I wouldn't say what sex they were.
And she somehow found out a
way to kind of, I don't know,
make me look like I was some chauvinist
that I guess she felt if it was a good
question,
I credited a guy and uh,
you know, it's a free podcast. All right,
stop being so fucking cunty.
So she became Douche bag of the week.
So evidently she didn't like it.
And what does she do?
She sends me an email, his
email, she sends me a bill.
It's nice that you named
me Douche bag of the week.
I don't really give a shit because
I always mean what I write.
I don't even know what that means
cause I always mean what I write.
I'll really one of the
rest of us just faking it.
We're just joking around but not
you yourself fucking serious.
It's anyways, evidently this psycho. This
is a new segment. This is cy. I can't,
I can't figure out this is a love letter
of the week or psycho or the week.
I don't know. You guys name it. I
don't give a shit. So anyway, she goes,
I don't really give a shit because I
always mean what I write and it seems
you're just talking shit about two
things that I wrote that seemed bitchy.
Now I was talking about your entire email.
Don't try to knock it down. All right,
continuing here. She goes,
call me. [inaudible] but I
really don't give a fuck.
You've read a lot of my
comments previously and
agreed with them or had a good
response to them.
I'm literally fixing her sentences because
she doesn't know how to write here.
But it's nice that you, uh, we'll consider
telling the gender of the person who,
uh,
who the comments are from.
And I know you have a shitload of
people who listen to your podcast,
but I got you some more since my friends
who heard the podcast thought it was
fucking hilarious and then
they started listening to you.
So you really should be thanking me.
Isn't this just typical?
This is just all going to be
a woman bashing this week.
Isn't this just typical of a fucking
female? You know what I mean?
She's getting something every week,
every week that is free.
And she still found a way
to bitch about it. Okay.
And then when I call her
out for being a douchebag,
now she's actually trying to make
me feel guilty. You know, I just,
you know, you call me a Douche bag,
you know, whatever. I mean, he's just,
even though I got a whole bunch
of friends to listen to you,
I mean probably shouldn't be thanking me,
but you know, I thought, okay, shut up.
Just Shit. I swear to God. Why? Why
can't you just slap women? You know,
back in the day, how great
did that feel? You know,
you have on the wife Beater,
the wind blowing through your
armpit hair has you just crack.
I know it's evil. I don't give a fuck.
Fuck all you guys. I don't give a shit.
This is the rest of her email. Okay.
Before you think I'm an asshole.
This is what she wrote. This is
actually so psychotic. It's hilarious.
She writes and yeah,
I do know that the name shows up on
the email even if I don't sign it,
but you just make it seem like you
that much of a retard to notice.
That's literally what she wrote.
And then she wrote your over 40 and
have the vocabulary of a seventh grader.
Your is spelled y, o u. R. All right,
for you morons out there,
your y o u r is possessive,
meaning like that's your shirt.
Okay.
If you're saying your over
40 that's you are. Okay.
So that means if you're gonna say your,
it's an apostrophe Wyo you a
pause to free our [inaudible].
So if you're a dumb fuck like this woman,
if you don't know the next time you go
to write your just stop and see if you
are would still fit.
All right?
Like your over 40 you are over 40 okay.
Right there.
You know you got to use the apostrophe
as as opposed to saying you're over 40 so
what is over do I own over you?
Dumb fuck.
But I do have the vocabulary of a
seventh grader, but you know something,
you have the fucking vocabulary
for a third grader. All right?
You're over 40 and you have the
vocabulary of a seventh grader.
You can't recognize real words.
How hilarious is this?
And she's misspelling stuff.
You started when you read,
and I hope your dog outlives you
and you die lonely because of your
inability to commit and therefore never
achieve the comedic fame
of the Great George Carlin.
So Simon says,
go fuck yourself.
Since it sounds like you
have major brain damage.
All right sweetheart, I'm really going
to try to help you out here, okay?
If you hope that my dog outlives me,
and then you say,
and then I die lonely. Okay. If
I'm going to die before my dog,
mathematically the fucking
dog is still gonna be there.
So how am I going to be lonely?
You know,
the dog would have to die first or
run away. So what you should say is,
I hope you dug out lives.
You then runs away and then you died
by yourself as opposed to saying,
I hope your dog outlives you
when you die. Lonely. Now,
I would die before my dog and be sitting
there licking my face and my last few
pathetic moments,
and then evidently because of my
inability to commit to a relationship,
I'll never achieve the comedic
fame of George Carlin. Oh,
that totally makes sense.
It has nothing to do with the fact that
I wasn't blessed with his gifts as a
comedian.
You know,
all you have to do to be as good as
George Carlin is just commit to a
relationship to some psycho
fucking chick like you. All right,
lady. These are podcasts. These are
jokes. When I call somebody a Douchebag,
I'm just fucking around, so don't
take it seriously. But if you want to,
you and your friends can
go fuck yourselves and go
listen to another podcast.
All right. Stop trying to
threaten me. Like you're going
to take podcasts. Listen,
listeners away. I don't
give a shit. This is free.
What are you guys going to take
away advertising dollars from me?
I don't give a fuck.
Fuck you and your friends.
I hope you're all listening together.
Fuck all of you. Look around the room,
look into each one of your eyes.
I'm saying fuck all of you.
You know what's funny is your friends
are probably laughing at you right now
going, you know what she is? She has
kind of a cunt. She really is like that.
She does have a tendency, I know I
shouldn't use that word, but I'm serious.
She has,
she can be real counties sometimes and
she has a tendency to exaggerate things
that aren't really happening. In
fact here, hair here. All right,
so that's the first hate mail. So I
figured, you know, why don't I seek out,
I'll try to find some other hate mail.
Here's one that I got on youtube.
This is a nice one. Um, basically I, uh,
there's a clip on there from
me from about eight years ago,
which he'll obviously notice cause I'm
skinnier and have a full head of hair.
And I'm doing this bit about joining
the military, saying how, you know,
when you watch the commercials for the
military, it makes you want to join.
You know, they make it look like
everybody gets their own jet.
Everybody's driving a tank.
Everyone's doing some top gun shit.
Everyone's having a, uh, you
know, you're a fucking navy seal.
You get your face painted
and you're clinging to that
raft and you coming up out
of the water like fucking Rambo
disappearing into the mud and shit.
That's what they make you look like.
Right?
But what they don't show is all
the other jobs that you, you know,
you go in there and you think you're
going to be like, you know, Tom Cruise,
oh my God, my dog just
farted. Jesus Christ, Cleo.
You know?
Could you at least like,
you won't kills me about this
dog when it farts, is it,
it doesn't even have the decency that
fucking kind of make a face like, yeah,
that was me. Sorry about
that. She doesn't lays here.
Good Lord. Least it's silent. You know,
it's the worst is when
you have a dog that far.
It's like a person ever
been over somebody's house
and the dogs and the corner
and they just go like
it. Just like really.
Anyways, so that was the bit, so
the bid is, yeah, you, you, you,
you see the commercial and you
sign up, you thinking, yeah,
I'm going to be like Tom Cruise in top
gun and then you show up and he ended up
being that guy.
You know when the jet takes off,
you just like point in the same direction
that the jets going or they give you
those, those orange glow sticks from a
rave. You know when the plane comes in,
you're that guy, you put the air
in the tires on the jet, you know,
you join the next thing you know you're
standing there with like a camouflage
weed whacker going week gave me hack.
Hack, hack. Yeah. That was the joke. Okay.
Simple joke.
I actually did the joke at a military
base and I also did it at one of the VA
hospitals and in fucking killed,
you know what I mean?
So this guy of course has to
go all Fox News on Youtube.
And this is what he writes is
actually kind of funny. He writes,
you grateful bitch and then he puts in
quotes if you're dumb enough to join the
military. Dot. Dot. Dot,
which is classic of somebody who wants
to take a joke seriously is they don't
write, the whole joke is they
just take not even a sentence.
They just take a part of a
sentence. Okay. So he writes,
if you're dumb enough to join
the military dot, dot, dot.
And then he writes in capital
letters. Fact, fact is,
if it wasn't for the bravery
of the American servicemen
and the American spirit
throughout history,
I like the American spirit.
What do you mean chicks who go to
a fucking bake sale? Um, anyways,
you wouldn't even get,
you wouldn't even have the right to mock
those sacrifices which have been made
for you.
And if you did,
you would probably be doing it in German.
So respect your American servicemen
because it is him in which you owe your
freedoms to take to that what people came,
you know,
half the time people think I'm a moron
cause people can't even write a sentence
because it is him in which
you owe your freedoms too,
that you take so foolishly for granted.
That's word for word or appreciate
the sacrifices of other you coward.
Uh, you know, at what point did I
make fun of servicemen? I didn't,
I was making fun of the how fucking
whatever. You know something.
If you guys want to take joke seriously,
I don't give a fuck and I am really sick
of that hacky thing where someone goes,
you know,
and they did it for you and if you didn't,
you'd be speaking German right now.
That's how dumb people are.
You know,
they're just used to say that you'd be
speaking German right now is a hacky
fucking reference. You just saying that
because you heard someone else say it.
You know, why wouldn't I be
speaking like I was from England?
Why wouldn't I be speaking
Spanish right now? You know,
we did fight other countries,
Mexican American war.
How come that one never gets brought up?
How can I wouldn't be speaking Korean.
I mean, granted they weren't over
here, but you know what I'm saying?
I'm so sick of fucking idiots who speak
in sound bites like I everyone who like
makes fun of France.
Yeah,
we fool conceived jurors and were to you
full can Poussey's read a history book.
We were paying them back for saving
our ass with England. You'd dumb fucks.
So now we're even all
right. Whatever. Look at me.
I'm getting all upset here cause
people are morons. All right, let's,
let's move on to, you know, let's, let's
get to some information here for the week.
All right. Um, last week I was
at, Oh, here's it going out.
Last week I was at teasing firefighters
and I was talking about how, uh, you know,
20 trucks show up to every fire.
Why does that happen?
How much of those trucks costs?
And a volunteer firefighter wrote in,
he said a up it up. A, Ah, I, yes.
How much a fire trucks cost fire engines,
which put the water out.
Uh Oh wait, put the water on fire
engines, which put water out.
I think I'm dyslexic.
Um,
typically run between
300,000 and $600,000.
Fire trucks also called ladder trucks
run between 400,000 in 800,000.
The two main differences between the
low and high numbers is the make of the
truck and the equipment.
It comes with a fire engine
with all the hoses at and on.
And the breathing apparatus is more
expensive than without. All right.
Well here's a question I have with for
you. You say the make of the truck.
So, uh, I guess what Mack
truck, that's a reputable bank.
Reputable brand as opposed to what?
A high and a fire truck.
I guess that that's what it is.
I don't even know what the fuck
they are. But anyways, you asked us,
you asked why so many pieces of
apparatus show up to a call. Uh,
there are a few reasons for this.
Sometimes it's manpower and my case,
we have three fire companies
consisting of six pieces of apparatus.
Since we volunteer, they may not be
enough volunteers in town at any one time.
So all three companies get banged out,
banged out,
equals called out in firefighting terms.
Typically at least four
pieces show up for a call.
This allows us to have all the
equipment we need at the scene.
Sometimes you just never know what you're
going to need. All right, fair enough.
Uh, but perhaps the best
reason this is great here,
but perhaps the best reason
is that sometimes we are
called for what amounts to
be in the end. Absolutely
nothing. About six months ago,
my pager went off your
pager. Jesus Christ. Dude,
is your firetruck pulled by a couple of
horses? Who the fuck still has a picture?
I know he's going right back around.
Should we would special fork in nine
11 page or for firemen? All right.
I'm a moron. I get it. All right. About
six months ago, my pager went off for a,
for a working house fire at 2:00
AM I jumped awake and flew down.
Uh, to the firehouse. We got on the
scene, we saw no smoke or flames in,
uh,
in speaking with the residents,
they had just woke up and saw a reflection
in their mirror that they thought was
a fire.
So here's all six of our apparatus showing
up for absolutely nothing or the time
we called for the,
for lightening hit lightening,
hitting a house on a clear summer night,
the woman heard something and thought
it was lightening hitting her house.
People are fucking idiots all over.
Hope that helps.
And even though I am a firefighter,
you're firefighter jokes were funny. See,
there's a cool guy. He see
there, sweetheart. Even
though he's a firefighter,
he sees the joke. He realizes I'm just
telling jokes are right. There you go.
People how we learned something this week.
All right,
you want to learn something else then I'm
going to wrap up this fucking podcast.
I know it's really short this week,
but at WWE,
I don't understand what the point of me
keep babbling for fucking 50 minutes.
If G CAS won't upload,
the files are a,
here's some computer tips for the week.
Uh,
here's some computer tips on
web searching. All right, Bill,
when you want to find that,
uh,
that you are Google it. What?
That makes no sense. All right?
When you Google use the plus and the
minus signs to find the shit you want to,
this is how it works.
If you want to search something
with a plus in front of it,
then it will have to contain the word.
And if you want to put a minus in front
of it that were removed the word from
the listing.
So basically put the plus in front
of the word that you're searching,
that you want to find an a minus in
front of the one that you don't want.
For example,
I want to see how many sites have bill
burr on it while limit while eliminating
bill burr from, uh, from the search.
So you would Google the plus sign,
plus my name bill,
then the plus sign,
and then you write burr
minus bill [inaudible] dot
com and the results, we'll,
uh,
we'll show sites that can have content
with bill burr on it and not include bill
bird.com. Huh? Isn't that interesting.
I didn't know that shit. And he said,
I'm listed on seven hundred thousand
seven hundred six thousand web pages,
not including my website.
706,000 websites have my name on it and
I still can't sell out the third show on
Saturday night. What the fuck
is going on? All right. Um,
if you find some shit out, like, uh,
if you want to find some
shit out like to do to you,
I can't read what you guys, right?
If you want to find some shit out,
like to you do when you are on what?
I can't even paraphrase that.
If you want to find some shit out like
two you do now like you do when you're on
the podcast. All right? You had
an extra word in there, dude.
If you want to find some shit out like
you do when you're on the podcast,
use the above option, the plus, minus, or,
or use quotes.
All right?
You wanted to find the names of
female serial killers a few weeks ago.
Just put quotes around a phrase and it
will only show sites that contain all
phrases. Okay, I get it. You know,
like you guys ever go to search
something and you'll like,
you'll just write female serial
killers and then a bunch of uh, hits.
We'll come out and you'll have a bunch
that just say female and a bunch of that
we'll just say cereal and other ones
just say killers or whatever. Yeah,
I guess if you put quotes around it that
puts it all together. You know what?
That's very helpful. I know this part
of the, the podcast isn't that funny,
but God dammit, we, we, you know, we
got to learn something here. All right.
I should have got some water here. My
fucking mouth is dry as hell. All right,
let's wrap up the podcast here. Uh, this
is the, a serial killer topic. Bill.
If you want to be a serial killer,
uh,
and use the best weapon
you have to use ice.
If you stab someone with an icicle
or beat someone to death with ice,
then it melts and you have no
murder weapon or fingerprints,
no DNA or fingerprint problems.
Oh yeah. That guy who, uh,
that talked about tracking you down with
the type of soil where it was located
and the type of wood used and all
that shit is exactly that bullshit.
They watch too many shows. CSI does
not do that shit. I know, Dude.
We all knew he was just fucking around.
He was making fun of how,
when you watch those shows. Um, all
right, what else did we get here?
Question a bill. You say that you
play the drums. Um, if you could,
uh, play the drums in any band living
or dead for one show, one night,
only in any city in the world,
who would you play and in what city?
Fuck.
Um,
Jesus Christ.
It would either be led Zeppelin.
You know what's funny is I
think I would have a better,
better chance faking one John Bonham does.
Then what Phil Rudd does and ACDC foot
fill red does is so fucking difficult.
If you play drums to just sit
there and go boom, crack, boom,
cracked for fucking two hours straight.
Um, yeah, I think I would play,
I would play with led Zeppelin.
I do it in England at Royal
Albert Hall and a I would,
and I would play on that, that the Ludwig,
uh, that maple drum kit that he played,
either that or his green sparkle kit.
I don't like the Vista Vista
light kit he had or the, uh,
the stainless steel when I liked
the first two ones that he had.
I play on either one of those and somehow
I would sound as good as can I, can I,
can I have that as part of the fantasy
that I would actually sound as good as he
would sound, you know,
that's what I would do.
Um, and then I'd get fucking some
1969 croupy pussy afterwards.
All right, next question, Bill.
Um, would you rather be respected,
be respected comedian who
never makes it really big?
Like so and so and so and so? I'm
not going to name the names. Uh,
he named two people who are
millionaires playing theaters,
but I guess who can still
walk down the street, he said,
or would you rather be a one trick
pony, like a blah, blah, blah?
Who has written a one catchphrase to
fame and fortune and as more cash than he
can ever spend.
I Dunno,
I'd much rather be respected by
my peers without a fucking doubt.
Without a doubt. I would, uh, you know,
you can become a really big comedian
and not necessarily be super like,
that's the great thing about
entertainment as you, it's easy to become,
I can't say it's easy, but you can become
a millionaire and still not be famous.
You know what I'm saying? And I
always use this, this example,
like that Sitcom Caroline in the city,
they actually made it to syndication and
the entire cast could walk by me on a
walking down the street and I wouldn't
recognize any of them. So I would,
you know, Dude, you're a millionaire.
How much fucking money do you need?
And I also think the more I look
at these people being super,
super famous is I just doesn't
look like a good time to me.
You know,
I think I would,
I want to be a millionaire
who has notoriety,
which means maybe two, three times
a month, somebody goes a year.
That comedian, I really like what
you do and the Yay, thanks a lot.
Then I go back to eat my omelet.
I'd rather do that then fucking, uh,
I dunno. You know, I don't,
I don't ever want to fucking have to
step out of a limo with no panties on.
You know what I mean?
Just so I can maintain fame
at that fucking level when
you think that would just
anything that, that would
be miserable. I mean,
other than when you're at the fucking
Celtics game and you have court side seats
in that moment, that's fucking
awesome. You know what I mean?
I've always used this analogy,
but it's someday at some point you're
going to have to fucking blow out a
bathroom in public and you don't want
to be famous at that point. You know?
You just want to be like, dude, you can't,
for some fucking guy just blew.
You don't want a bill.
Berge just blew out the bathroom.
They literally put a fucking name to it.
It's brutal. Um, all right. Overrated.
Underrated. Really quickly. Overrated
beer with the lime already in it. No joke.
It just tastes fucking gross.
Um,
what else do I got here? I'm sorry, this
is really fucking unraveling here. I just,
I, I, I've done, I've done this too many
times is fucking week. I don't know.
I lost my passion. Like if Pau
Gasol was doing a fucking podcast,
this is what it would sound
like right now. You know,
and I'd be thumping my chest acting like
I'm giving you entertainment right now
and I'm not, you know, that's what
I'm going to end with this week.
What do we got here? I'm 28 minutes in.
Good. I'll keep it under 30 minutes.
I'm going to end with this prediction.
I think Orlando is going to beat the
Lakers and I think they're going to beat
him in six games because, uh, they don't
have anybody to stop. Dwight Howard.
And I think Turco Lou is, uh, I dunno.
I think that guy's going to get enough
points and then they got that other guy.
Then the number two or is he the point
guard? I don't know shit about basketball.
I just fucking hate the Lakers.
So I'm going to go out on a limb
here with no money down or nothing.
I'm not going out on a limb.
I just,
I just think I got a feeling I
got to fucking feeling all right.
I think Van van Gundy's going to, ouch.
He's going to out coach Phil Jackson.
Phil Jackson, he's making home
videos with his girlfriend,
his new hot young girlfriend on the,
on his way to the staples center every
night. They're soft, they're fucking soft.
All they have is Colby Colby
[inaudible] the shit. I Love Colby.
But I think his teammates
are scared of him.
I think they're scared to fuck up around
them. They're scared to disappoint him.
Uh, and they just get freaked out
and they just pass him the ball.
That's what I think's going to happen.
Pog Saul gets the most quietest,
15 fucking rebounds and the quietest 20
points a game. I think he's going to,
he's going to take a fucking Dwight
Howard elbow to his bearded chops sometime
in game two and the Orlando
is going to win game two.
They get three in a row in Orlando.
They're going to win two out of three
and then they're going to come back and
they're going to beat the heartless
Lakers in the staple center. Game Six.
What the fuck do you guys think
about that? Huh? You liked that one?
You know, what do you guys think about
the two, three, two playoff format?
I think it's bullshit.
I think the,
they give the advantage to the weaker
team because the Lakers should have home
court. Right? And I don't think
they do with a two, three,
two format because when it's two,
three,
two the pressure is on the home
team for the first two games.
Right. If it was two, two, one, one,
one like they used to do back in the
back in the day you open the first two
games.
The pressure is our on our Lando
to steal one now when it's two,
three to the pressures on the Lakers,
they have to win both of those
fucking games. They can't go one,
one and then path to play three
fucking games in Orlando. Right.
My outta my mind.
And this is this all get boring.
Well I don't give a fuck cause
this is my third one this week.
Listen to my goddamn mouth
is dry. Um, so anyways,
I might do another podcast this week
cause I might have a very special
announcement of something that I might
be doing next week that might be on
television. How do you like that? I'm
leaving you with a little cliffhanger. Um,
and with that I don't have any gigs until,
uh,
the third week in July when I'm going
to be at the comedy works in Denver. Um,
why is that?
Um,
I booked a very small part
in a very big movie and um,
I don't know, I'm shooting
like five, six days on it,
but they had to clear out my spa,
my schedule because they're working
around famous people schedule.
So I'm low man. On the totem pole.
So, uh, I gladly cleared out my Spec,
my schedule. So, uh,
I'll let you know what the name of the
movie is and all that type of shit. Wow.
When in fact, I know that I haven't been
cut out of it. How's that? All right.
And that's the very short, very succinct
Monday morning podcast this week,
the third fucking time I'm praying to
God that this thing is going to actually
get published. All right.
You guys have a good weekend.
Thanks everybody who came
out to the Improv a couple
of weekends ago out here in
Hollywood. All right.
That's it. Take it easy.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible].