Okay.
Hey, what's going on? Is Bill Burn?
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
just checking in on you.
I'm just checking in on you.
Duda Duda I only got one more
fucking day before I fucking go home.
One more day in the film. I still
got three more after this, but uh,
I get to go home and see
my little daughter is here.
Very excited about that.
Um, and by the way,
I asked the director if it's okay if I
tell you what movie this cause I never
know, you know, fuel leak out
information. He said it was cool.
So the movie's called front runner front
run out and it stars Hugh Jackman and
uh, directed by Jason Reitman.
Okay, there you go. So,
oh, freckles has a little part
in there. Don't blink your eyes.
Your mind miss me. But uh, that
is what I am working on out here.
And um, every time I go down
to set, I'm telling you,
they show me something that they shot
and it looks really, really fucking cool.
So I'm very excited to be in
a, in this movie here. But,
uh, yeah, so I got one day one, uh,
like I got one scene today site and
I'm the first one out of the gate.
That's about as good as it gets.
You know what I mean?
Sometimes you the first
scene and the last scene,
but you get to see everybody else act and
everything like that. And that's cool,
right? The only thing that's bad about
being there the entire fucking day is for
whatever reason, um, when
you're on a movie set,
you just eat like a fucking,
I don't even know why.
You don't even know why you're eating.
You just sitting there going,
why am I eating right now?
Just standing around and all of a sudden
they bring around some fucking, uh,
oh Halloween's coming up here.
Some fucking Halloween cookies.
They start eating like you're in the
fifth grade, literally eating it,
looking at another adult who's also eating
it. And you both say at the same time,
what the fuck are we doing?
Um,
I've actually been pretty good on this
shoot and the food's been awesome. So, uh,
and I did lay off the Halloween cookies
and I'm doing my fucking catio today.
Being a professional.
God dammit.
You guys all know what a freckled
booze bag bag I am. Right?
You all know how I can't lay off the
booze. Um, I've been doing it man,
70 fucking days. So a, I don't know,
think on day 73 already be 20% of a year
already have that in. I might go a year,
I might go a year. I might fucking
bows tonight. I don't know.
Who knows? It's exciting.
It's an exciting time.
Do you think that world series game
last night was fucking riveting?
That that was, that was a joke compared
to watching me try to walk by a bar.
Um, I was on set last night,
so I didn't get to, I saw,
uh,
it was three
to one and then,
uh,
we were shooting the final thing and I
checked the score and I saw it was three
to three. I was like, Holy Shit.
The Astros came back and um,
we ended up wrapping and uh,
it was like five to three
Houston. So I, you know,
we go down there, we get out of our
fucking clothes and all that shit.
We had get back into the regular clothes,
they head back to the hotel,
everything's shut down here.
And me and another actor went into the,
this bar that we saw that was open and uh,
try and get something to eat.
I think it was like after 12,
at that point it was going to slip pickets
around the area that we're staying at.
And uh, we walked into the bar and saw
that it was five to five. I was like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me.
Well, maybe it was seven to five.
Seven to five.
Yeah.
The last I saw it was five to three Astros
and the time it took me to get offset
jumped in the van and head back, it became
seven to five Astros. And I was like,
what the fuck happened?
I'm missing one of the greatest
world series games probably ever.
And um, so we go in there and we
asked the guy behind the bar, right.
You know, and the guy's like, he's
like, sorry, fellows. The fucking,
I can't even explain how
high this guy's voice was.
I Dunno if he was in the middle of
transitioning or whatever. I have no idea.
But it was like,
it was like Michael Jackson
level high inexplicably,
and the guy had stubble on his face.
I don't get it right.
Um, do you look like a giant?
Like marionette puppet is going,
sorry fellows, if you brought
a guy in here, you gotta go.
So fortunately this guy with the
high pitch voice told us where to go.
We ended up going all the way down the
street and I'm like four or five blocks
down and it was really cold for Atlanta.
I thought even I'm sitting with a little
fucking sweatshirt and we went down and
found this bar that was still open and
we get in there, it's seven to five.
And as we walk in the, the,
the Dodgers hit a home run,
I think to make it seven to six.
Okay.
They didn't only down by a run.
It's like, you gotta be kidding.
This is unbelievable.
And um,
unfortunately the game ended day.
I was sitting there because I wanted the
Astros to tie it up cause I want more,
more baseball. I want to see a, I want
to see a seven game series here. But uh,
I wanted the Dodgers to tie it up
cause I was hoping like, you know,
I wasn't going to bed.
I was fucking wired.
I was hoping to get like
15 innings of baseball,
but congratulations to the Astros.
You know,
and things are getting a
little chippy out there.
I guess they're imitating some guy in the
Dodgers. The guy with the Blue Mohawk,
I don't know anybody's fucking name.
I guess he flips the bat and sticks his
tongue out so they're like, oh yeah,
we're going to flip the bat.
We're going to stick our tongues out.
These are adult male, 70 buddy. Um,
stupidest shit ever. But it's
been a, a incredible series.
So I'm hoping game three,
I'll actually be, uh,
I'll be home and I can sit down and
watch it. Now watch game three will suck.
You know what I mean? The pitcher's
duel, not even a good one.
They leave stranded base
runners. Um, and that's it.
That's all the fuck I got.
I don't, I don't know what
to tell you. I'm just been,
um,
yeah,
working like a maniac.
So I'm in the first scene tonight today,
which is great because,
um, I'm actually going,
I can do a little promotion here.
Um, there's a 30 for 30 coming out,
an arguably one of the greatest,
if not the greatest entertainer of all
time and wrestler of all time ric flair,
the ric flair.
30.
The 30 is coming out and they're
having a premiere tonight and uh,
I'm going to go to it and I think
ric flair is going to be there.
So I'm going to go a little Jim Norton
Herr and try to get my picture cause I've
had a Twitter photo up on my,
uh,
my Twitter account since then. That was
taken in June of 2014. I still remember,
I got to meet him,
talk to him.
He was the coolest fucking dude
ever was telling stories and uh,
just an awesome guy. So I'm hoping that
tonight I can update my photo. Cool.
That'd be haven't updated it in three
years because it was a ric flair photo.
Hopefully I can update it again with
another one. Um, and if I don't,
who gives a shit? I get to
watch the ric flair. 30 for 30,
which everybody should watch.
I don't care what's going on in your life.
I don't care if your wife's
going like tying together.
We go to the pumpkin patch.
[inaudible] you got to say lady,
this is one.
I'm not doing the Tivo. Want this
one. I'm going to watch live.
Fucking what do I lie?
All right.
You got to see this one live.
And um,
how do you, how do you wrap up
ric flair story in 30 minutes?
Is that what it means? Right.
30 stories, 30 minutes long.
They've already done way more than 30, so
they should, you know, I already saw Dan,
the Dan Marino football life and that
was 30 minutes like with commercials or
something like that was her day. You
should have been at least 90 minutes. Um,
how much the game has changed.
Okay.
And how much the game had the change and
how would it had his big dad to become
borderline illegal to cover a receiver
past, you know, your first little,
you know, two yard chuck or
whatever you're allowed to do.
Now all of that had to happen.
NFL had to try to go global and
try to get all these fucking,
you know, halfass fans by,
by running up the scores.
All of that had to fucking happen for
Dan Marino's records that stood for 30
years to start the fall.
That's all I'm saying.
You that should have been 90 minutes.
No, I guess she can't do that.
Cause then all the other
legendary players who'd be like,
well how come [inaudible] he six,
he's talking about flips to bat and
then they'd get on fucking upset.
I did things too, you know. So anyways,
I'm looking forward to that
and um, I dunno, and that's it.
Other than that, I'm going out of
my mind, uh, being stone sober,
remembering every fucking
waking moment of the day. Uh,
every day that I'm sober,
I'm reminded why I drank.
You know,
I got to go to an AA meeting.
I got to hear people talk
positively about being sober.
Cause I gotta be honest with you,
I don't fucking get it.
And when I fucking lay off the booze,
all it does is make me want to try drugs.
You know,
I never smoked weed. I don't
smoke. I'm not into it. I
just don't, I'm not into it.
But then if I don't drink everyone,
then a couple times a month I'm just like,
I got to fucking do something
to break up the monotony.
I have such a respect for the straight
edge people. I don't know how they do it.
Guy Tried to tell me what being sober,
he goes, you know, you don't understand.
Is that like, you know, alcohol kills.
I see endorphins.
I don't know what it is that actually
makes you feel good about your life.
He goes, I don't drink. I'm actually,
I don't need it. I don't need a bill.
I'm like high on life, you know? And
I was just looking at him. I was,
I couldn't help but think
you're full of shit.
No you're not. You know, when you're
high on life, when you're a kid,
you know, and you never throw out your
back and your shoulders not fucked up.
You don't have a sciatic nerve issue.
Your feet don't hurt.
He just get out of bed.
You're brand new.
You're jumping around the fucking
house doing cartwheels and shit,
running around. Hey, let's
go in the living room.
You just get up and you'll run to the
other room. Then you high on life.
You don't have any credit
card debt, right? You know,
got a lady in your life going to wish
they didn't have a date night, right?
None of that bullshit.
Then you can be high on life.
Then you don't what happens? Uh, you
know what happens? You become an adult,
all right? And all the sudden
you start understanding why,
why it is that technically,
you know what I mean?
If you live in down on the equator,
you're actually standing sideways,
okay? And why you don't go
flying off the fucking planet.
You start to understand it.
It's the weight,
the weight of the universe being on this
thing that's fucking spinning, right?
And all this fucking debt you're fucking
accumulate and it's all Cohen down on
you. And the holidays are up right
around the holidays. Fun Anymore, Huh?
Did you get into the Christmas spirit
the way you got to start going around and
fucking seeing everybody and
getting on a fucking plane,
watching some Douche bag
after they just said,
only one thing per person
in the overhead compartment.
Stick three fucking bags up there.
You know what I mean?
And that's when the stewardess comes
by and she just cause can I get you
something? Could you like something
to drink? It's like, yeah lady.
You know those little
bottles of booze you have?
How many do you think you
could carry in both your arms?
Why don't you stuff a few in your fucking
breezier over the year and bring them
over here so I can get through
this God damn flight. Right.
Um, or maybe, you know,
maybe you would still
enjoy that time of year.
It's that time of year when you could say,
look at that.
I was just singing a Christmas song when
I was still in the fucking was a head
fall as a beer commercial
head for the mountains.
That taste is smooth then it's Busch beer,
Busch beer.
I live how they have the balls to do a
commercial now as if their beer tastes
good.
Everybody knows that Busch beer is for,
that's what that's like when you're hung
over and you want to get back in the
game. You know that's that.
You know, could be big.
They fucking slit your fucking eyelids
cause you were all swollen up from the
boost the night before and
that's what that beers,
let's put Busch beer and all those
fucking beers, cores, light, Busch,
Busch light,
all of those fucking beers are when
you drank so hard the night before,
you know,
and you just don't have it in you not to
drink the next day and you need to get
back in the game. It's the cortisone
shot of alcohol. That's what it is.
It's fucking stupid fucking commercials
with the guy standing next to a goddamn
river.
What does that all about?
To let me know how watered down that
fucking can pisses that I'm going to be
drinking. But God bless you because
it still gets me fucked up. Um,
anyways. I don't know. Do I need
therapy? I don't know what it is.
I think I just need to
get home. Um, so anyways,
um, yeah, I just been going on in my
mind here, unless I'm down on the set,
if I'm just fucking hanging out and it
keeps saying I keep threatening to myself,
then I'm going to go down under
the college football hall of fame,
but I don't think I'm going to make it
again today because I gotta get out of
the fucking elliptical,
burn off all the food I ate
yesterday. I didn't do bad. I,
I eat the fish yesterday
and I got to tell you,
the catering on this movie has been out
fucking standing. It's been delicious.
You know,
I dunno what,
what catering has gone to another
level since I started doing my, uh,
my three lines per movie acting career.
You know,
why don't they have awards for that?
For people like me on movies,
you know,
they,
they have best supporting actor.
Right?
But you mean you still got to be
like a major part of the movie.
What about people like me?
Where's my award? Not even
my award. Just an award show.
They should do that. Just have it on
youtube. And they just have, right.
You have a house nobody's heard of and a
bunch of actors you can't fucking name.
You know, and then you
let people vote, you know,
best two lines in a movie
for 2017 and I dunno,
whatever award you, you win. It's like
made out of chocolate or something.
He eat it or something. I don't know
what it is. Maybe it's a little,
it's a shot of, it's
a flask. I don't know.
I don't pretend to understand
these fucking things. Anyways,
guess what I'm doing next week? Everybody,
other than seeing my beautiful family,
spending every fucking second with them,
um,
is I am going to be playing the surf
ball when ballroom, I'm sorry, in Iowa.
And this is where, uh, you
know, uh, uh, buddy Holly,
the big bopper and Richie
Valens all did their last show.
It's a little fucking more, but
you know, but I want to go there.
I want to see it right.
And I'm flying right into the same airport
that they took off from and crashed.
And everybody is dude, what
the fuck? And it's like they,
they had ice on their wings.
That's what happened.
That's why they crashed there to enter
an experienced pilot and they had ice on
the wings and they didn't have the,
they didn't have the technology back then,
the spray,
the chemicals.
So I'm going to go out on a limb and
say that I'm going to be all right. Um,
so anyways,
I'm going to be doing that
on a Thursday of next week.
And then Friday, Saturday, I mean one of
my favorite God damn cities in the world,
Milwaukee, Wisconsin. All right.
And a Dean del Ray's going
to be doing the Thursday one.
And then I got forsee and nick
in Milwaukee,
Versie,
Bart,
nick and myself and one of
my favorite cities ever.
And, uh, I have to somehow try to
maintain being sober. I'm going to do it,
I'm going to do it, but I don't know
how much fucking longer I can go.
I get 70 days in.
All right.
You know what it is,
is I know when I have that next drink,
then I'm just going to be on again
for another two fucking years.
That's what I'm hoping.
What I can do is I'm going just what
I'm going to do when I come back,
when I returned after this injury,
right.
When I make my return to
the big leagues of Boosie,
I would like to fuck and I would like to
boos the way I smoked cigars now cause
I got that under control.
Like I smoke a cigar like
once every fucking three
weeks or something like that.
That's how, right, right. 12 to
15 a year. I'm so full of Shit.
I've smoked more than that this year, but
whatever, I at least I make an attempt.
Okay. The third base coach with with
the cigars is holding people up.
All right.
But that fucking lunatic with the booze
is just waving me around every time.
Um, I dunno, I gotta be honest with you,
having a kids a great way to fucking
not drink. You know what I mean?
You can't just sit there getting drunk
when you have a kid in the house.
And plus even if you do like a moron the
next more and your kid's going to wake
up at like seven in the morning and
they don't give a fuck about a hangover.
Um, so I guess it's just one,
I'm on the road.
I don't know what it is or maybe
I just like booze and do you know,
it's all of that shit. I really
enjoy it. I miss it. You know,
I think I'm going to sober dial
my fucking my booze itself.
Um, anyway, so I'm going to be doing that.
And then I go up to Green Bay and uh,
and then that Monday night bump up bubbles
though to go to green bay as a Monday
night football game that I was going
to go to with fuzzy and Bart. Nick. Um,
you know, I can't even say, unfortunately,
I got to get back to do my last
three days on the movie and um,
so I can't make that one.
But Jesus Christ,
if you're not going to go to Lambeau
field, it's a pretty good excuse, right?
Because you're going to be in a great
fucking movie starring Hugh Jackman called
front runner. There'll be coming out
in 2018 please tell all your friends,
please go to the movie
theaters and go see it. Um,
who knows if the schedule changes,
maybe I'll get to go.
But I think for ASEAN part, nick is
still going to go. Um, and that's it.
Other than that,
I don't think I have anything left
to tell you other than my shoulders
completely fucked up again.
Uh,
I turned the corner with
my rotator cuff and um,
that I went too far.
I don't know if it was cause I did dip,
so I tried to do a pull up with
one of those fucking assist bands,
things, you know, I tried to do,
I just pushed it too far and then
I got to start all over again.
It's fucking frustrating, but how are they
going to do what? You can't do it. Hey,
you know,
it's fucking annoying.
So two years sag nerve last year and
I got my fucking shoulder, you know,
but fortunately I had been eating like
a lady, some staying in shape here.
Alright Indochina, everybody. Ah, we're
doing the reeds here and don't cheat.
Oh fuck you. Fuck the
reads. You know something?
I was reading this
thing about this couple,
that mountain climbs and they were
trying to climb one of the more difficult
ones where you're literally
walking in the jet stream.
It was wind was blowing so bad
they couldn't sleep at night.
So of course one of these fucking morons
gets lifted up in the air by the wind,
slammed down between two rocks.
Her foot gets stuck in between the rocks
and then the wind is blowing so hard,
it twists her body around and
she breaks her fucking leg.
Now the other two fucking jerk offs who
were also completely safe before they
decided out of out
of the bucket on a nowhere
to put their lives at risk,
right?
With absolutely no respect for anybody
else in the world who gets tortured,
who lives in these horrible fucking war
torn conditions. You know what I mean?
And all they want to do is just
be able to come home and be safe.
These two fucking free morons
decide that they're going to go up.
They were deliberately put their lives
at risks and now the other two assholes
have to carry this lady down with their
spiral fracture taking turns while
walking into the jet stream.
And I don't know what I'm supposed to be
doing during this when I'm reading this,
my supposed to be thinking, wow, what
incredible human beings. I don't,
I just think what a couple of fucking
morons because then some poor bastard has
to fly a helicopter up there and try
and meet them and risk his fucking life.
I just, I dunno, I don't know how
people in the coast guard do it.
I don't know how these people in like
helicopters around the fucking world,
their job. What is your job, sir?
What is your job man? We on what is
my job? Oh, I rescue fucking morons.
Okay.
You have, I mean the fire department has
that too. To a certain extent. You know,
somebody sitting there
smoking a cigarette,
eating a pop tart and bed nod off and he
lights his fucking bed on fire, right?
Then they got to go in there and go
get the guys he's hiding in the closet,
you know with the frosted still around
his lips. It's starting to melt.
They have to go in there.
They got to go get the guy.
I don't know. Do you want to talk
about fucking hero? How does,
how do they do that?
You'd have to go risk your
life to save a fucking moron.
Is there making the call? Yeah. Hey, what?
Hey My, my wife broke her leg. I got,
Oh yeah. Where are you?
Where's your house? Oh Nah,
we climbed up a mountain.
The fuck did you do that for it?
Oh God, I would love to take those calls.
What the fuck did you do that for? Great.
Great. So now that, let me guess.
Now you want us to go up there
and go get a fucking moron.
You know, we should leave
you up there, right? You, you
know, you deserve that. Right?
Do you understand the person flying
up there and the helicopter, isn't it?
It's expecting it.
It's becoming a father and another month
and he might not make it because you
fucking idiots left a perfectly good
hotel room and decided to climb up there.
So what? You could talk loudly about it
in a bar with your frostbitten cheeks.
You dumb cunts.
Tell you what?
Walking of a thousand feet down the
fucking mountain, I'll check the forecast.
Maybe I'll pick you up in a week.
I guess you got to be cut out for
that job. I don't know. All right.
And don't cheat.
Okay.
All right. Talk about how every man
looks better in a suit. You know,
every day I'm checking out
guys walking by, you know,
you know,
I like a nice George Michael Stubble.
I'm not going to lie to you, right?
But I gotta be honest with you.
You know,
nothing makes me want to give my number
to another man, like a man in a suit.
Jesus Christ or they look good.
Um,
Indo Chino is making it easy to get a
perfectly tailored suit and an incredible,
I was just picturing a guy in his
suit doing that. Stupid Michael, uh,
whatever his fucking name is. Is it
Michael got ahead, fade the faith,
the faith when they're polled on his too.
I like to wear his shown.
Anyone like fucking Joe
Pesci in Goodfellas. Endo.
I was making it easy to get a perfectly
tailored suit and an incredible price.
You can choose from hundreds of top
quality fabrics and personalize your suit
just the way you want it.
Who the fuck knows about fabrics?
Yeah.
Well then I got to learn about
that. I know. I don't want wool.
I know. I don't want it to
be so shiny that when I walk,
you can hear me coming as I
come down the fucking I'll,
um, anyways, whether it's for work,
a wedding or other special occasions,
Indochino has suited up hundreds of
thousands of men and are now the largest
made to measure men's
wear brand in the world.
Here's how it works.
We get a bunch of silk worms.
Okay.
All right.
And we booed him right in the ass.
And then I'll come to the fucking silk,
right?
Isn't like silk from like
this spittle of a God. Damn.
You got to admit
intelligence. A human being. So, you
know, I'm not saying I'm one of them,
but how the fuck do you see?
See some God damn little worm minding
its own God damn business making a little
spider web, whatever the fuck it is
they do. And you like, you know what?
I bet I could take that stuff
and make a shirt out of it.
Um,
visit a shoe.
Visit our showroom or
shop online@indochino.com
do these fucking brutal
silkworms realize that
they're working in a factory.
They give them a little cute lunch pails.
Did they get two weeks vacation a year?
That's what I'm asking you. I'm sure
somebody is doing a documentary on it.
Pick your fabric.
Choose your customizations from lapels
to pleats to jacket linings in more
pleats.
What do we know Molly Ringwald movies
of those pleaded fucking pants, that
dead guy from uh, the two guys in,
in fucking Charlie Sheen in a pizza place.
Sitcom pleaded suit right is that when
they put like quotations around your junk
with front of your pants,
submit your measurements,
place your order a wait for it to
arrive it just a few weeks. You know,
one of the loneliest things you'll
ever do in your life is take your own
measurements.
You know
Jesus is the cops.
Maybe they're going to arrest that
Mary and Ed Guy for speaking too high.
Now Bill burr listeners can
get Indo owes best deal ever,
ever at $359 for any premium suit when
you enter the code birth during checkout,
that's 50% off the regular price
for a made to measure premium suit.
Um,
that includes plus the shipping is free.
That's indochino.com promo code bur for
any premium suit for just $359 and free
shipping and incredible deal for a suit
that will fit you better than anything
off the rack ever could. All
right, frame bridge everybody.
Frame Bridge is the easiest way to
custom frame your favorite art in photos
without ever leaving your house.
You fat fuck with their simple
online ordering process.
Yo can order a fully
customized piece in minutes.
Here's how it works.
You go to Frame bridge.com you upload
your photo from your computer or directly
from your Instagram feed. For the life
of me, I can't get on fucking Instagram.
I signed up years ago. I can not figure
out how to get my fucking password back.
They say they're going to email me. They
never do it. I checked my junk photos.
I check off, uh Oh, not
photos, my junk files.
I do fucking everything I'm supposed
to do and I can never find it.
Or if you have a physical item,
they'll provide secure prepaid packaging
so you can mail it in for free.
Preview your photo online in
any frame style. Choose you.
You know what? I want to
do this cause I, there's I,
I got a great one with me and my
daughter. You know what I mean? She's,
we're both looking into the mirror,
you know, and she had a little fat.
Hand is grabbing a handful of the back
of my shirt is she's laying her head on
my chest. It's the cutest.
It's my favorite picture
than I have of me and her.
Oh God,
I got to get home.
Preview your photo online in any frame
she was your favorite or get free help
from their talented designers. Uh,
the expert team at frame bridge.
We'll custom custom frame your
item in days, not weeks or months,
and deliver your finished piece directly
to your door ready to hang the best
part instead of the hundreds
you'd pay at a framing story,
their prices start at $39
and all shipping is free.
Plus my listeners will get 15% off their
first order@framebridge.com when they
use my promo code bar frame bridge
even offers a happiness guarantee.
If for some reason you aren't 100%
satisfaction satisfied with the order,
they'll make it right.
Um,
you should send them a picture
of your junk and then call up,
complain about the frame that they use,
telling me that it doesn't,
it offsets your pubes rather
than complementing it. Uh,
give your personal experience using frame
bridge. I've never used it. The site,
the ease of order, how your piece turned
out and how easy and affordable it was.
Go to frame bridge.com
and use Promo code bar.
You'll save an additional 15%
off your first order frame,
bridge.com Promo code birth.
Thank God somebody fucking solved
the problem of the digital age.
You know what I mean?
I get all these great photos and
I don't even know where they go.
They just go into a fucking
hard drive somewhere. Um,
like I was just thinking if I get a
picture with ric flair tonight and I
replaced that photo that
I have on Twitter, I don't
know where the original is.
Oh, I know it's somewhere. I don't
know what the fuck it is. Um,
that was cell phones ago.
Thought Ofi it's probably in the
ocean right now. You know what?
Ours is probably in Thailand. Some
kid has it, you know what I mean?
And he's going, who the fuck is this
white guy with this even older white guy?
Right?
Thought the everybody thought fee meow.
Everyone had thumb point health,
wished they could have beer,
wine or liquor delivered.
Oh God,
he's going to test my sobriety while
someone finally decided to do something
about it and no legged alcoholic who
lost both his legs to the disease.
Uh, next please mention all the
talking points both below. Well,
I'm going to read it. You wrote
it. Introducing thought me out.
The alcohol,
the alcohol delivery APP,
saucy delivers your favorite wine, beer
and liquor, right to your door on demand.
It's Uber for alcohol.
Now, if you live in La,
San Francisco, Chicago, San Diego,
or Sacramento, I love Sacramento.
You know what I mean? What a major
dropoff la, San Francisco, Chicago,
San Diego or Sacramento,
you know,
Sacramento's when you go there,
that's one of those towns you feel like
you're in the Truman show, you know,
or maybe in the first season of the wire,
depending on where you are.
I'm fucking with the Sacramento. But you
know, there's an element of truth. Um,
I'm Hella fucking with you guys up there.
Your thought,
the order will arrive at your
door in 30 minutes or less.
Ready to drink for the rest of us.
Saucy. We'll deliver beer, wine,
and liquor to your door. In two days
or less. Nationwide. I like the length,
the degree of difficulty
that one week got a time.
What booze you're going to need two
days. Um, there are no order minimums,
no delivery fees, no running to
the store. Who's kidding? Who Know,
driving to the store, shit faced.
Um, if you've got the thought,
the meow APP,
you've got a fully stocked bar on your
phone and for a limited time you can get
$15 off when you download this stuffy
or Al App and enter Promo Code Bar.
That's the soft,
the APP spelled f a u s t y honey.
And enter your Promo
code birth for $15 off.
Get the saucy me yell
app today and use your,
my Promo Code burpee. You are,
oh, here's the last one. Oh,
but oh, pope pope me undies. Me undies.
No more fucking booze.
Doo Doo Doo Doo me undies.
We undies you live is going to fucking
lose if you booze too fucking much and
then you, yeah, can you soft underwear?
I don't know what I'm saying
in this makes no sense.
The vice president's name is Mike parents.
Me undies makes undies.
Your Butt will be proud to wear.
Are you sick of your
ass being disappointed?
It's time to make your ass proud again
with a pair of me undies and check this
out. I'm not the only one who loves
me undies. You know I love me undies.
It's not even their underwear. I
just like singing, you know? Um,
you know I could barely carry a tune.
Listened to what my longtime listeners
in me undies enthusiast George has to say
a note from George and bill,
burr listener and be undies fan.
This is how much you guys,
so how much you guys have
done a solid with me on this.
You guys actually write them,
telling them how much you liked my songs
to the point they're now sending me
your fucking tweets or
Instagram's whatever the fuck
you sent it to him and now
this is part of the copy I guess.
Anyways,
this is from George and who allegedly
exists and wrote this and this is not from
some advertising company.
I decided to try me undies because I
love Bill Burns me on these jingles.
I smile every time he sings it.
A man wrote that.
Now,
if this was a lady,
I believe that a lady would be emotionally
open enough to say that I smile every
time he sings it. I think
this has been edited. Um,
although it's so easy to
skip ads in a podcast,
I always capital's listened to bill's
reads and I'm so glad me undies has stuck
with them.
It's probably been two years since I
first bought a pair of me undies and now I
have a monthly subscription
because they are that comfortable.
Doesn't this Raul read is
phony before me undies.
I used to buy the three pack of underwear
at the retail stores until I realized
that I wanted to treat my junk to
something more comfortable and that starts
with a great pair of undies,
cradling my family jewels.
This is so fucking written
by their advertising teams.
I know you guys are right in a men.
I know you're writing these
guys telling you like,
I mean that there's no fucking
way you write it that eloquently.
This was totally edited. I'm
calling bullshit. But anyways,
to get 20% off the best, softest
underwear and socks you will ever own,
free shipping and 100% satisfaction
guarantee. You know, we have to go,
you have to go to [inaudible] dot com
slash berm. That's me, undies.com/burr.
All right, what are we up to? Oh,
that's 35 minutes. Okay, well I got,
I got to work in my little workout.
I'm going to go put,
put on my pink legwarmers you know,
and do a couple of,
but blasters
all I do now is I just get on
the elliptical. That's all I do.
And I put on my fucking, uh, you guys
want to hear about what? My Cardio,
this is my cardio. I like to listen
to mindless music when I'm on,
you know,
I finally have given into gym music.
Like I used to walk around the gym and
I'd be like, oh, why are they playing?
Pour some sugar on me? It's like, you know
what it, cause it's actually, you know,
I go through different periods.
Sometimes I even want to listen
to a fucking absolutely genius,
um, album or something like that.
Or I just don't even want to think.
And lately I don't want to fucking
think and I know what it is,
is because I'm missing my family.
That's what it is that I mentioned
that 5,000 fucking times.
So right now I just want to go into
like, you know, it's like, why, you know,
I like washing dishes. It's fucking
mindless. You know what I mean?
The gray bar by the water in the tank,
what the top and I fucking scrub
until it's clean and it's just gives you
something to do, something to focus on.
Like why can't I get
that fucking brand flake?
It looks like now it's been
sandblasted under this bowl here.
Why can't I get that off? You know,
you get a little anger out. Um,
here, here is my, um, my mindless music.
I listened to feel it's steel feel.
It's still from Portugal, the man
[inaudible] [inaudible] bag up
and my common add a left field,
he kind of got, got, got, got Goo Goo
that gets me,
it gets me through the first five minutes.
And then I listened to mark
Ronson, uptown funk. Ugh,
this is the same song, the same
song they write every summer, right?
Boop, boop. Do we do, oh, I listen to
that shit, right. Slightly embarrassed.
But I listened to it and then I listened
to the honey drippers rocking at
midnight.
And uh,
then I just have a bunch of Tom Petty,
and this isn't mindless music,
but I'm Kinda stop and listen to that.
I kind of switch off.
Then I've listened to three mindless
songs in a row and I love Tom Petty,
but he just died. So it makes
me sad. So I just saw primus.
So after those three mindless songs,
I then go into,
I go into awesome music
music that I really like.
I'll listen to prime mis or Mars Volta,
my new favorite band.
Fucking dope found out about him fucking
15 years after they were together.
So stupid. Um, so anyways, and that's
when I have to go do so everybody,
you guys want to share with me your
little cardio fucking lists. I need you.
I need,
I need another three fucking songs as
mindless as those first three that I just
sent to you. They're
silly. They're happy in.
Next thing you know, I looked
down and all I had, you know,
I only do like a half hour,
you know what I mean?
I only do a half hour because these needs
have to last me a lifetime. All right,
I'm done. This bullshit. Um,
there's gonna be a little music here and
you're probably not going to know what
the music is and I'm not going to
know what it is either because Andrew
Feminists, uh, you know, he goes deep,
he goes deep into the music world.
So if you have any questions,
just ask what song it is on our
Twitter app at the m m podcast.
All right. And ask Andrew and they very
polite, respectful way, what the song is.
I'm sure he'll get back to you. All
right. And uh, then we'll play after that.
There'll be another half hour of this
podcast, a classic half hour, uh, of,
of classic clips from my Thursday
afternoon, just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast that, um, I
dunno, maybe from earlier this year,
maybe from three years ago.
I have no idea.
You might even listen to me talking about
how much fun I had boobs in the night
before, you know, uh, that's
it. All right. Have a great
weekend. Your cuts and uh,
I'll talk to you on Monday.
Yeah.
Anyways,
I get them into the biggest,
dumbest fucking fight last
night with my girl, right?
We had this great day, you
know, everything's going great.
So I stay in, I take a night
off from comedy and I said,
hey, why don't we watch,
why don't we watch a movie?
You know what I mean?
Cap Off this wonderful fucking
day. Everything's going
great. What could go wrong?
This is like the beginning of a horror
movie where they just show like the
perfect family and everything's great
and people are wearing like white linen,
you know,
and then all of a sudden they just start
showing the camera and the bushes like
a POV of like Mike Myers. This
is basically what happened.
So 60 minutes comes on,
right? Who doesn't want to watch that
show and pretend they're smart? You know,
I like it some more Morley
safer comes on and you know,
we smells like an old person. Some old
people don't smell like old people,
but he looks like he smells
like an old person, you know,
smells of cigars, ash trays,
you know, couple of wars,
maybe a date rape.
Um,
so he's interviewing Meryl Streep,
all right.
The Great Meryl Streep,
and they're going through all our of
oral frigging life and all the movies and
all the different characters that she's
played. Oh, first of all, they start,
they start the report off with
Morley safer just sitting there,
right. Smelling a fucking Ben
Gay in whiskey. Right. And, uh,
he says, how, you know
how over in England, you
know, they, you know, I dunno,
they make their,
their actors,
they award them by calling
them lords and they night them.
But over here at America,
all we do is just give him the
shiny statue and it's just like,
starts off right off the bat for
some reason just shitting on America.
I don't know why like an
Oscar is somehow beneath sir,
uh, Anthony Michael Hall. I mean,
or, or Lord what it Lord of what,
what a what lease.
You can fucking hold our statue,
your lord of what kingdom.
That phony horse shit that you have
with Prince Charles and the popper or
whatever the fuck is going on over there.
You know,
look up the Rothschild's night you over
there, then that fucking means something.
Then you can come become part of their
yacht convoy as they go around the world
figuring out how to take over another
currency, right? Then you're in with them.
Okay. But if you're, if you're fucking,
you know, Lord of this and your,
your wing man is the Duke of Elton John.
I mean it's a whole thing
is fucking stupid, right?
So right off the bat
it's already bugging me.
But I know Nia hates when I talk
to the TV, right. So I, you know,
I keep my big fucking Yap shut and they
start talking about Meryl Streep up the
buck on to the whole thing.
And then I'm the old guy
there smelling of a, you know,
prescription meds goes, uh,
you know, whenever they talk
about the roles you play,
they always say, you know,
you play independent minded
women, very strong women.
And Merrill goes, I know
that's, yeah, that's what they
say. You know, when a guy,
they never say to a guy, oh, you're
playing a strong willed character,
Yadda Yadda Yadda. I let that go.
Whatever, no Biggie, I'll take dead.
It's probably true. The fuck do
I know I'm not a woman. Right.
But then they show her after she played
Margaret Thatcher and she's given a
speech to a bunch of women's young girls
and she's trying to inspire them and
she,
she takes a quote from Margaret Thatcher
and it was something along the lines of
if you want a bunch of
people to talk around,
talk is staying around and talking
about doing something. You know,
something, a goal, you got to talk to men,
but if you want it to actually get done,
you got to get a woman and then all the
chicks go, Woo, like flipping out. Right?
So I laughed and I'm like,
Yay. Reverse sexism, right.
Just seeing, you know, my,
my whole fucking theory,
how everybody is just a piece of shit.
You just don't have the power to act
out what the fuck you want to do because
that, that right there, if
you flip that around as a guy,
if you're running for president,
it's fucking over. He can't be like,
let me tell you.
I'll tell you what,
after I get you jobs and after
I fixed this economy, okay.
And I'm the man to do it
because I'll tell you right now,
if you're looking for someone to stand
around and talk about doing something,
you get a woman.
You want to get it done.
You gotta get a man here on my nuts
right here on the podium, volt from me,
November 4th go fuck
yourself. Right? You did that.
Your presidential campaigns over.
She does it. It's fucking adorable.
And it's just as fucking ignorant.
You know what I mean?
What a fuck do you get off saying
that we stand around and do nothing.
Meryl Streep. Huh? Or quoting Margaret
and you knew to Margaret Thatcher.
Okay,
let me tell you, you bitches something.
Alright, we faked a fucking lunar landing.
Okay? You think that's just talking.
Anybody can land on the fucking moon.
That's easy.
But to pretend you did it all right and
get everybody to shut the fuck up about
it. That, that, that, that right there,
that takes skill. So what happens?
So I make that little comment and um, did
I just go with that? That, that, that,
that, that's the only
fucking porky pig. So,
so I make that comment and like,
you know,
I've been with Nia long enough that I
can tell by the side of her face when
she's just thinking about like,
what if I just grabbed everything I
really cared about and walked out of this
house right now.
She got like that fucking mad at me,
you know?
Yeah.
And I'm like, she's just like,
right after the story was over,
she just shut the fucking thing off.
And uh,
I don't happen excel. I'm walking to
seven 11 to get some ice cream. I haven't,
I have not. I mean, what happened
was all going great. You know,
am I the asshole there?
What am I am I suppose to just fucking
sit there with my mouth hanging open with
drool coming out when I watch TV,
if somebody says something Douchey,
I'm not supposed to say it.
Yeah. Whatever, whatever.
So I just finally just said, you know
what? Fuck this. I take the dog out.
I go around the block. What do I do?
I'm calling my guy friends. Right.
They're all backing me up. I'm not saying
who I called, I don't name names. Right.
And they're all laughing their ass
off and they are 100% agree with me,
which is all I'm looking
for at this point.
I just want people to say that I'm right.
I don't want to learn anything from this
experience. Just tell me I was right.
So it can be an ignorant ass again.
I don't know.
Why don't you guys weigh in on that?
Am I a Dick for saying that?
Should I just let that one go? You
know? Uh, you know what she said?
That fucking drove me up the
wall. She goes, why are you
okay?
She didn't say intimidated.
Okay.
She used one of those words.
Why are you threatened by what she said?
It's like I'm not threatened.
I, yeah, Jesus Christ. Then
I take the bait. You don't,
it just sends me right over there
like threatened about what? Oh my God.
This person that I don't know who has
never called me, nor will ever call me,
who has no effect on my life.
How do you get threatened by that?
I'm just calling it for the bullshit
that it is, cause you know what?
This is what fucking drives me nuts.
I can't stand when somebody tells me
that they're shit sandwich tastes worse
than my shit. Okay? Go Fuck Yourself.
At what point am I supposed to have
empathy as I'm sitting here eating a shit
sandwich and you're telling me how
much worse yours, yours is. You know,
at the end of the fucking day, you know
what I mean? Sure. Mine might be on,
you know,
a better slice of bread,
which I guess would make it
taste a little bit better,
but at the end of the fucking day,
right the end of the fucking day.
All right, I'm going to end up
in a FEMA camp with you. Okay?
You think when the next fucking a psycho
comes along, I'm going to make the cut.
What the fuck the wife, but what do
I bring to the world? Huh? Exactly.
I'll be standing right next to you. So
go fuck yourself. You just fucking woman.
Every time she sneezes, they
give her another God damn
award. She still pitching,
still fucking bitching.
You know?
I remember when I did this
Oscar nominated part out,
go fuck yourself with your wigs.
The whole thing. Just, you know,
that's what fucking pisses me
off when I watched this shit.
If you really want to know my
perspective is from where I come from,
I can't bitch about shit cause
everybody's like, oh go fuck yourself.
You hit the lottery. Right. But I got
to sit here and listen to you bitch.
Even if you're fucking killing it,
even if you're killing it, you know,
Yale School of drama and
he's still doing the bull.
Go Fuck yourself with your
God damn yachts. Alright,
there you go. That felt good.
It was probably ignorant.
[inaudible]
dental assistant billion.
I recently,
I recently watched a talk show appearance.
You posted on your Twitter you
mentioned. Yeah, I did the, uh,
the Willie Hunter show.
MMM.
And I think that that's what I posted
when that fucking Twat that I'd like to
choke to death with a garden hose
sent me that tweet. Um, yeah,
it was on the Willie Hunter show.
And he said,
you mentioned you were a dental
assistant, um, for your father.
Did you ever consider becoming a dentist?
Did you ever,
did your father ever have ambitions for
you to become anything in particular?
Um, no. My Dad, my parents
were great. Like they,
they wanted you to base,
they didn't force anything on you.
It was like whatever you wanted to do.
MMM.
They supported it 100%.
And I remember being working with my
dad in the dental office when I told him
that I was going to become a comedian.
We were in like the break room.
And I remember I was sitting
there like going like,
how is this guy going to take
this when he has such a classic,
okay,
like stable job here.
Okay.
You know that I'm going to tell
him that I'm going to fucking
basically make a living,
try to make a living doing exactly what
he's been yelling at me for for the last
fucking 20 years of my life,
which was fucking off and acting like an
idiot and screwing around all the shit
that you know when he
would give me Christ,
you're in a town cloud,
what do you would be giving me shit,
which I totally deserve because if you
ever saw the grades I got in school,
I mean they, they, they are. They
are horrific. Fucking horrific.
The high water mark for me was
like a c minus or a c like I was.
It was brutal.
Yeah.
I went to,
I had to go to summer school every
fucking year of high school except my
sophomore year because my math teacher
hooked me up in my senior year.
I should have gone. I just didn't give
a fuck. I was like, what's the point?
You know what I mean? That's like, you
got the ball with 10 seconds left and you,
what are you going to do?
You just fucking, you know,
you're down by 30. Yeah.
Just throw up a half court shot. Did it go
in? Who gives a fuck? It doesn't matter.
You know?
Um,
yeah,
so no, I mean for half a second. You
know what, you know what I did like,
I liked the,
uh,
I liked the pouring up
models when I was in a,
when I was in the dental office, that
was my favorite thing. I was in the back,
I was isolated,
I wasn't around anybody and it tapped
into that little kid thing of playing in
mud
and he used to pull it up
models and they had this vibrating thing
and you had to tap on it to make sure
you got all the bubbles out.
And I prided myself on not being able,
you know,
of having it without no having no bubbles.
If you got bubbles,
if there was bubbles on the
bottom, basically, you know,
when they stick that pink shit in
your mouth and they got to take a, uh,
an impression of your teeth,
then somebody's got to take that out
of your mouth going into the back room.
And then you got it.
You got to mix this powder with water
up in those little green rubber balls.
Jesus,
this is all coming back to me.
And then you poured it into the
fucking impression you took.
And then there was this,
this thing that sounded exactly like
your cell phone vibrating on a table and
you just, you just tapped it on that
to get all the air bubbles out of it.
And if you didn't do it enough after one
of the things set and you took it out,
um,
if the bubbles were at the bottom,
that's where the teeth were
the most crucial thing,
the exact fucking thing that trying
to get a gauge on so they can,
you know, whatever the hell
they were trying to do, make
a bridge or something. Um,
the whole thing would be fucked.
And then you couldn't go and just rapport
the model into that same mold because
somehow like it had shrunk up a little
bit and it wouldn't be accurate.
And my dad used to flip out.
He would, he would take them
off and he'd be like, Christ,
there's air bubbles and this,
you know, and it was beyond your boss
yelling at you. It was also my dad.
So I already had,
you know,
I was going through my fucking
teenage and early twenties.
When you're rebelling
the most against you.
If I already had the live with the guy
and then I was working with the most
fucking hilarious and he
used to give me shit like,
you know,
like I was his kid.
Okay.
But we, we really have, we
actually talked about it,
how we had to tone that shit down because
it didn't come off as professional in
front of patients, so whatever. But um,
but that was a part I thought if I ever
got into dentistry that I would, I would,
I would work in the lab.
I liked that part of it, like, um,
and not just pouring up the models,
like the actual, I don't know, there
was a precision to it that I liked.
I didn't like to fight.
I didn't like the, uh,
the front line shit going in the mouth
with all that crap and look at people's
fucking horrific teeth,
just horrible fucking teeth.
All my jokes were about that shit.
When I first started.
I told you guys that story,
right?
I used to work totally clean
when I first started stand up.
Um, and not because I want
it to be this comedy purist.
I just was afraid of offending
somebody in the crowd, getting heckled,
not having a comeback,
losing my place in my act and
then bombing horrifically.
Okay.
And, and just having my career
and total fear catastrophizing,
like way of looking at it and um,
yeah. Oh, Jesus Christ.
Okay.
That really just fucking
brought me back to,
I was standing on stage at stick stitches.
Fucking somebody heckled me
was that the vault and Boston,
somebody had called me and I completely
lost my fucking train of thought and I
had nothing and I didn't. And it took
me like basically three seconds to, to,
to re to remember what the fuck
I was talking about. And um,
it was the longest three
seconds in my life.
And I didn't know enough to
just say to the crowd like,
what the fuck was I talking about? Because
they'll tell you, they'll remember it.
They're not nervous,
they're listening. They,
they're not having like this outer
body experience. Um, but anyways,
I remember people would come into the
dental office in their teeth would just be
just,
just what an absolute fucking mess.
And they can tell you right now,
I hate coming to the dentist. And
it's like, yeah, dude, I can smell it.
You don't have to smile. I can tell
you don't like coming to dentist.
You only like fucking brushing your teeth.
Okay,
well just one guy said this, one of the
first jokes I did. Oh, that's right.
So I will work totally fucking clean. And
then my last, at my end, just, you know,
when I've looked like a young Ron Howard,
I looked like Richie Cunningham and I
was totally clean and I was clever and I
had these perfect talk show monologue
jokes and everyone was gone. Like,
oh dude, you're going to do
the tonight and this is going
to be perfect for and blah,
blah blah, blah, blah. And
then the last joke in my act,
I quoted this patient who kept having
to get fillings and root canals and he,
and he said, doc, you know, I don't
understand what's going on. I mean,
I brushed my teeth almost
every day and then my,
my snappy comeback to that,
that I thought of that later became the
last joke of my act. I said, really deal.
Wipe your ass almost every
time you take a shit.
And that's what I would close
with after working totally clean.
I would say that disgusting lie.
Do you wipe your ass almost
every time you take a shit?
Having everybody in the
crowd after looking at this
fucking Norman Rockwell come
to life,
fucking character wholesome is hell,
right.
Yeah.
And I really was back then.
Okay.
As opposed to the piece of shit that I
am now after 20 years on the road that I
became,
um,
okay.
And I literally, they had to conjure
up pictures of somebody skipping,
wiping their ass. And just that whole,
and they would just literally recoil.
Then I would just be like,
you know,
thanks a lot. Good night
everybody. You were great. And um,
okay.
I had another horrible one that I did
where I actually brought a prop on stage
and if you'd like to,
to see that I tell the story on the
Willie Hunter show and a willys and up and
coming comic at the comedy store.
If he's the guy who threw the Hula Hoop,
took the hula hoop from that girl in,
fucking threw it into the street.
I tell that story too. If you want
to see that shit, check out his show.
Hey, what's going on? It's built.
And this is the Monday morning
cast for Monday, October 26th, 2009.
Holy Shit. Halloween's coming up. I
haven't even bought a pumpkin yet.
What the fuck is that all about?
Um,
how come there's not pumpkin's the whole
time of the year? All those things.
Seasonal, you know, like tomatoes.
Evidently tomatoes are seasonal.
We just don't realize that, which is why
they taste like shit 90% of the year,
or according to Jimmy Dore,
they pick them before they're even
ripe and they just paint them red.
Um, is that true? I mean,
how long would that take to sit there
with that little fucking Crayola?
It wouldn't, they taste like
wax wants deal with Pumpkins.
You can get Pumpkin Pie, the
whole euro, but you never see, um,
I've gone out of my fucking mind.
People, my voice is killing me.
I have something to do here
and fucking 40 minutes.
So this is gonna be a quick podcast and
this time actually mean it because it's
going to cost me money if I don't get
off the phone here in 40 minutes. Uh,
uh, where to start. Why
don't we just start with what
the hell is bugging me? Um,
I almost got into a fistfight yesterday
and uh,
I realize that I'm at the awful age of,
okay.
It's basically anytime there's
going to be a fist fight,
I have these two options.
A,
I lose and get the shit kicked
out of me, which really, you know,
there's no end to that shit kicked out
of you. Could be, I got a black eye,
I lost the Tufa, you know, or it
could be I'm in a coma and you know,
the left side of my body doesn't
work anymore. You know what I mean?
You never know cause you never know
who you're fucking with. Right.
So that's option a and option B is I win
and then I get the shit suit out of me.
Okay, I see. I'm so fucking
still pissed about this.
I have to give you the abbreviated
version of this because it's,
it's been eating me up inside.
Um,
I was waiting for my girlfriend
to come out of this diner.
It's one of these places. There's only
one way in and one way out. All right,
so there's a parking lot,
parking spot way down,
which is actually closer
to the fucking diner.
And this Douche bag is sitting there
cause he sees my reverse lights on.
So I'm waving at him to
tell him to go by me.
So I can just back out of the fucking lot.
And he's just sitting there sitting
there. He wouldn't do it. It's a fight,
you know, I pull out real fast. It's like
a gravel parking lot, slam on the brakes,
slide backwards and then fly forward.
Slam on the brakes. So he pulls in,
obviously knows a piss and I back up and
I put the window down. I'm like, dude,
there's a fucking spot right up there.
And then he immediately goes, oh,
you're so tough with your hybrid. And
he really caught me off guard, man.
He got me with a great money.
Went with the hybrid.
My Dick is bigger than yours because,
um,
he's driving a fucking lime green
four door sedan that he looked like he
borrowed from his fucking ant, right? Oh,
this guy, he's just this, this fucking,
you know what this guy looked like?
Remember those coming of age movies in
the 80s where there was the good looking
chick, ah, that the nerd wanted and
she was dating this impossible asshole.
Like that blonde hair Douche from a back
to school who gets all intimidated in
the end and fakes a leg injury after
fucking a 90 year old Rodney Dangerfield
does a triple, triple Lindy. That's
what this kid looked like. All right,
and he's gone fuck and blah blah
blah. And I'm like, Hey, yeah,
we'd get fucking tight shirt and your big
nose. Go Fuck Yourself. And he's like a,
and then he goes out, go back
to jersey, you piece of shit.
That's what he said to me. Right?
And I wanted to go like, dude,
I'm not from New Jersey, but my girl
jumped in and said something fucking,
you know that a civilian would
say rather than a comedian.
So I actually started losing
the argument a little bit.
So then he turns around and then I
was just like, where are you going?
Where you going? You know, like,
like I was actually going to fight
them because I was so fucking mad. I
okay.
But I, and the back of my head, the whole
fucking time, I'm thinking like, two,
what are you going to do? What? What do
you, what are you going to do to this guy?
When was the last time you had a fight?
You're fucking 41 you're a year older than
Brett Farve. What are you going to do?
It's, it's not even on level ground.
It's in a gravel fucking parking lot.
You know what I mean? I knew
I could have, I swear to God,
I know I could have fucking
killed this guy, but I will.
I can't do it. I'm going to die. I
already, you know what would've happened?
I would've fucking started fighting him.
Even if I started winning,
his girlfriend would
have jumped on my back.
And then if you do any sort of get off
my back with a woman, I'm going to jail.
You know? I just, it was
this fucking stalemate.
There was nothing I could fucking do.
And then I'm driving home and all I'm
thinking about is how much I want to
fucking kill this guy.
And it got to the point,
I literally dropped my girl off and I
drove back to the diner and his fucking
car was still there.
And I'm circling the diner in a hybrid
waiting for this guy to come out thinking
about what I'm going to do to him.
And then also reminding myself that I
have not had a fight in about 20 fucking
years.
Okay.
And then also reminded myself legally
the ramifications for leaving and then
fucking coming back.
I am in no danger whatsoever and I am
going to get the living shit sued out of
me.
So fortunately a friend of mine happened
to call up and I started telling her
the story and she was laughing her ass
off and she told the story of south.
Some girl didn't hold the door,
you know,
it's one of those really
heavy doors and sort of,
and it's sort of slam back in her face.
And she said, thank you, you know,
sarcastically tour. And then
the girl goes, uh, what?
I don't have to hold the door for you.
Go Fuck Yourself.
And how she just wanted a
sticker timberland through
the back of this fucking
chicks back. I guess. Look
at me, I'm so fucking mad.
I can't even say simple anatomy.
So,
yeah,
I just, I dunno, I was able to
just kind of talk myself out of it.
And the real thing was I didn't
want to go back and fight the guy.
I really didn't, you know what I mean?
I really didn't. I did, but I didn't.
There was just no, when it wasn't going
to do, you know, I got meetings this week,
I'm going to show up with a loose
tooth and a fucking, you know,
nobody bleeds like a redhead,
you know what I mean?
I'm going to look like fucking
ric flair walking in there.
There was nothing I could do.
I had to sit there and,
and I think I actually lost the back
and forth verbal thing, you know,
I'm so fucking shot from being on
the road. I just got off a flight.
I wanted to go straight home. My girl's
like, I'm hungry. Let's get some aid,
you know?
And I made a mental note to be extra
nice to my girl just because I've been
an asshole lately,
you know,
which is probably why I got
into the argument to begin with.
But it's, it was, it, I literally there,
there's a,
there's a fucking reservoir or a lake,
whatever the fuck you call it, near
where I live. This is how mad I was
after my friend talked me out of not
doing what I didn't even want to do to
begin with. Right. Not to mention
the already had another guy with him,
I would've lost. I would've
fucking lost. Right. So, um,
I had to go drive to the lake,
park my car and walk around the lake
in the first 90% of the walk around it.
I was fantasizing about all the different
ways that I was going to murder this
guy.
I had one where I was body slamming
him onto his own fucking car,
screaming some shit about hybrids.
I completely like, I haven't been
that mad in so fucking long. And uh,
it wasn't until the last 10%, you
know, I was kinda going like, you know,
you really took this walk to try
to forget about this shit. So what,
what is wrong with you?
You need to calm down.
So I started a fucking calm down and
then I saw my car again and reminded me I
was driving a hybrid in a fucking piss
me off again, be to just be one thing.
If the guy was driving a corvette,
you should have seen this car.
It wasn't lime green was actually
kind of a nice screen. Okay.
If I can actually extend an olive
branch to this fucking cunt.
But I mean it was, it was a
four door sedan. You know,
there was no excuse at his age.
You know,
he's like in his twenties there was no
fucking excuse for him to be driving that
car or certainly talking shit.
Right.
Also, I love that whole go back to Jersey
you piece of shit and like how he's the
typical La Guy, you know, judging you,
you know you are what you drive out here.
Cause I'm in a hybrid, therefore I don't
know how to fight and what you hit.
You know my car,
my car runs a hundred person I'd
guess fucking bring Bruce Lee on.
You know, he, what does he
got? A Rick Shah, you know, so.
So the last 10% I
started talk myself down.
It just so happened there was
an open house out here and a,
there happens to be a zillion houses
available out here because the state is
bankrupt and we live in a city without
a water supply and they still want $1
million for a house that is about the
size of a decent one bedroom apartment.
So a [inaudible] is a lot of open houses.
So I actually said,
I actually went into the open house and
looked at it and was thinking the entire
time that if I had gotten out of
the car and thrown the first punch,
even if I won the fight,
whatever downpayment I would have
had to actually get a fucking house,
which is something I'd like to do at some
point in my life that would have been
out the fucking window
and as much a calm me down
today, it's still hasn't made
me feel any better. And, uh,
this,
this should be like some
sort of gentleman's agreement
of I'm not going to sue
you and my friends aren't going to jump
in or maybe even go down to the gym.
You just put the gloves on so
you can just get it out of here.
Because I got to admit it's
still fucking in me. And uh,
I've been here,
this is how much of a cunt it's
made me and I'm trying to get,
I'm trying to get rid of this, this,
this little ball of hate that is in me.
When I was, I looked at the
one house, right? And I, and
I felt better and I'm like,
I still need to look at another
house because you know, I'm on a,
I'm still in a bad mood and
I was driving up the street and
as I'm driving up the street,
this white lady is like waving her hands,
like telling me to stop.
She's got no uniform,
no uniform on or nothing.
So I kind of, you know, I'm,
I'm deliberately driving pastor a little
bit before I slowed down cause I'm a
fucking control freak and I don't
like people telling me what to do.
So she comes up to my window and I
go, what? And she's like, I'm a tree.
Fell on the road around the corner.
I just didn't want you to hit it.
And I was just like, oh my God, I am
the biggest asshole ever. I really am.
He know if I'm really going
to be honest with myself.
The whole fucking reason I had that
fight with that guy is because I'm in a
grumpy mood because the less seven out of
last eight weeks I've been on the road.
All right there. All right. I
admit my fucking part of it.
Uh, do it that you could have seen
where that guy was just standing there.
Then fucking shark fin of a noses Hibbs
coming out from those awful sunglasses
that's going to harm me for
another couple of days. But, um,
thank God I am a little bit older
and I actually know how my brain,
I'm telling you that's what I've been
older is, is knowing how your brain works.
Okay?
Because the moment is gone.
So now long gonna do is just walk
around hate in this fucking guy.
So what I have to do is every
time I think, and I just,
I just fucking think of something else.
Um,
and I've been able to do it in my
apartment, but when I get in my car,
it's like a Vietnam fucking flashback.
So I'm just going to give myself
a week to get over it. And, uh,
and that's it. All right, so there's a
story for you that took a nice 12 minutes.
My fucking voice is killing me.
You know,
I actually bought a book on how to
fucking use your voice properly on stage.
I should really read it. I do drink
that throat coat, fucking, uh,
tea with honey now.
That's how old I am.
Um,
what I really should be doing is giving
my voice arrest and shutting the fuck up
rather than yelling about some dude who
doesn't even matter in my fucking life.
Ah. All right, let's
get on with the podcast.
So this is the Monday morning podcast.
Everybody, if you're new to this,
you're probably in some sort of a,
I dunno what you would,
what mindset you would be and it's all
fucking ceiling fans drying out my throat.
That's what's going on.
Um,
okay.
Isn't it something really
intimidating about a ceiling fan?
Do you ever not think that it's just
going to come flying off the fucking
ceiling and decapitate you
it's unreal how it just stays there.
Yeah.
Our pumpkin seasonal, I didn't even get
back to that. I got to get, I, you know,
you know what happened last year
is I carved up a couple of them,
but I carved them up too early and uh,
they started to dry out.
Okay.
And the thing that I,
I had carved in there,
this scary looking face and I had carved
like a whole silhouette and the in the
background, you know what I mean? It's
like a carved out, like a big circle,
three cores the away.
And then on the bottom I carved the
head into the bottom part of the circle.
So then the candle was behind it,
fucking lift this thing up.
It looked like it was awesome. But
the weight of the, uh, the face,
considering it wasn't connected
to any other part of the Pumpkin,
it started to fall into the
hole. Is it dehydrated? And uh,
it really wasn't scary come Halloween.
It was just kind of sad.
It looked like a defeated demon. Like
he, he's looking up in the air like, God,
what do I have to do to scare people?
Um,
yeah.
Yeah. So anyways, I just came back
from the DC Improv, everybody and uh,
I want to thank everybody in Washington
DC and the surrounding area of Baltimore,
Richmond, Richmond, Virginia, Georgetown,
wherever the hell you
came from West Virginia.
I just want to thank all
you guys for coming out.
That was the greatest turnout I have
ever had to any stand up a weekend I've
ever had.
I actually had to add a show people.
I did a second show on a
Thursday night and it's sold out.
I did six sold out shows and uh,
three days and um,
had the time of my life.
Okay.
Ate at this restaurant. Posh, got
hooked up there by chef Chris.
He's fucking dude. Brought us out
all his food. Want to thank him.
Oh, it was a great time, dude. You
know what else I did? I actually,
we got a football,
it's a long fucking story.
This is the Peter Pan
Lifestyle I'm living at,
which really gives me no excuse to get
mad at some guy in a green four door
sedan in the parking lot
of a goddamn diner. Right.
I played football on a Friday afternoon
around two in the afternoon. Like,
I was still in like the fifth grade,
you know, that she's fifth grade,
be more around four and I'd be blowing
off my homework or whatever, you know,
and uh, ended up spraying in my
finger cause uh, Paul Versey,
the comedian who opened up for me,
it was, we were so fucking hilarious.
Like typical, you know, he's
still a younger guy, but you know,
I'm 41 so I'm stretching and
doing all this shit and uh,
we're sitting there lying to ourselves.
We though we could still play.
That was a great pass to do. You hit me
right in stride, get me right in stride.
He's getting all excited that he's
hitting a 41 year old in stride.
Like the defensive back couldn't catch up
in fucking run the thing back for
six the other way. But uh, Nah man,
I was psyched.
I was really impressed with how fast I
can still run and I'm gonna tell you why.
It's because I've kept myself in shape
and I stretch on a regular basis for all
you guys out there.
As you're getting older,
you have a look at
older guys and you like,
you just look at him and you get to an
age at some point where you can't fucking
run anymore and it blows
your mind when you're young,
like why can't you run anymore?
You just send them that brain
signal to your legs to run.
And as the problem is, because it hurts.
I mean, look this, this part of it is,
yeah, you walked on your legs,
your feet and you use your body,
the wear and tear of 40 years.
But I swear to God,
it seems like 80% of it is not stretching.
If you don't stretch,
you get atrophy and your muscles shrivel
up. And that's when you literally,
somebody throws you a ball and it's a
little out of your reach and you go to
reach for it and all of a sudden you
fucking your kidneys up by where your
fucking shoulder blade is. The
kidney attached attendance. I know,
fucking knows.
You know what I'm trying to say?
I went from muscles and tendons
to Oregon's, um, I'm telling you,
uh,
I have this power yoga tape that
I've been doing forever and forever.
My friends had been teased and we do
that gay, what are you doing yoga for?
Where you trying to suck
your own Dick, Eh, right.
All those fucks continued to eat and they
didn't stretch. And I was never fast.
I could always catch,
I always had great hand eye coordination.
I can fucking catch anything.
I don't give a shit what it is.
My thing is that there's just going to
be somebody in front of me because I was
never fast. So this is hilarious.
I was never fast. Okay.
But I kept myself in shape.
And about seven or eight years ago
when I was in my early thirties,
I was playing pickup football and we
had been playing for about 20 minutes.
And for the first time in
my life, somebody on the
opposing team actually said,
they said, hey, watch
out for bird. He's fast.
And I almost burst out laughing because
I was thinking of what a statement,
what that was to the horrific shape that
they were in because I was slow when I
should have been fast.
I ran like a 30 year old
when I was 17 so when I'm 33,
I got to be running like
I'm 45. Um, you know.
So anyways, we had a great
time and uh, I got to tell,
you know what I realized when I
was throwing that football around,
and this is one of the sad things
about being an adult and getting
responsibility and not being able to have
a fight because you could get sued is
there's a lot of other fun things
that you just stopped doing,
like throwing a football.
Do you know how much I love football and
how much I loved it when I was a kid?
And you know how long it's
been such I threw a football,
I can't remember the last,
I think the last time I threw a football
was that day I was talking about what
they said get berries fast,
which was like 33. Like,
I honestly in the last eight years cannot
remember ever a football do you know
fucking tragic that is.
We were out there running post
patterns is fucking, you know,
cutting across the mill.
I was having the time of my
life until I sprained my finger.
But even then it was all right.
Just say it looks like when a
Elton John's fingers, everything,
an Elton John Concert and he plays with
those little fat little sausage fingers
he has and he always talks about it.
He doesn't have piano playing fingers
cause he can't really reach that far.
But he's still the shit cause he's
so gifted. That's what I have.
I have one Elton John Index
finger or Mario Batali.
Anybody watched the food network and you
watch him when he did after he does the
well method making the pasta, which is
something I really want to fucking try.
I always want to try and
make my own homemade pasta.
I really got into cooking for a minute.
I used to watch that show multiple Mario
everyday because he seemed like the
real deal, you know, not only
did he understand that dish,
he had been to the country where it
it, you know, he'd been to Italy.
Okay.
Hung around with Italians and they taught
them how to fucking make this stuff
after they gave them a ton of shit
for not knowing what he was doing.
He could explain the part
of Italy that it came from.
It's just a tremendous show. And I liked
that. He does it in his own kitchen.
He just has like a couple of
friends over, you know? And uh,
I don't know,
I just looked at it and like a comedy
kind of way where he just seemed like a
comedian who's really a comedian.
Like they don't need props.
They don't need a catch phrase. He's just
standing there doing his shit. Right.
As opposed to other shows where you got,
you know, like, uh, I was going to say,
Emilio Estevez what the fuck's that
guys? Emeril Lagasse, you know,
there's so much,
just so much I got into the food network.
I could actually tell how much happier
Emeril Lagasse was when he was doing
essence of Emeril as opposed to being
in front of the crowd. You know,
who doesn't like working in front
of a, uh, uh, a live audience,
but you could see the sadness in his
face when the crowd just sits there and
then he has to do all that extra shit.
All of a sudden he got to
turn it into like, you know,
I've got some butter and everybody's like,
Eh,
start screaming where I essence Amarillo.
You can just sit down and cook the dish
and not have to sit there throwing flour
over his shoulder and sugar
into the eyes of his drummer.
He's got a fucking drummer on a
goddamn cooking show. Um, so anyways,
that's what I'm saying. Like,
look, if you love football,
you haven't played in a while.
Stretch out and throw the ball around.
I'm telling you, you got to do it. Do
it before you fucking t plays on Sunday.
That's one of those silent silent
competitions I have with, with other guys.
You know,
you're going to a sports bar and you
just look at the horror that is a sports
bar to complete audit shape,
fat fucks,
the bloated alcohol and wings face that
you see every time you turn around.
You know, I always go, I'm going to
have to empty. I go to a sports bar.
Like I always try to work out before
I go there, you know, burn off,
whatever the fuck I'm gonna eat in there.
Cause I don't want to look at like
those people that are in there.
So that's what I'm saying. There's a
fun way. If you hate the fucking gym,
go get a God damn football dude.
I felt like I was in the fifth grade.
Like when I was done, I was looking for
my book bag. You know, it was ridiculous.
Of course, two hours later, I
did not feel like a fifth grader.
I felt like I was 48 but it
was fun nonetheless. All right,
so let's get on with the podcast
questions and, and, and whatnot. Hey,
here's a great thing. If any,
anybody else has like a, um,
had a confrontation. Like, what?
I had and for whatever reason,
you didn't have the fight.
And you know,
it was funny when I was
saying I was so mad and I say,
I was telling Nia I have to go back there.
When I was dropping her up,
dropping her off, she goes, just
go back and slash his tires,
which really took me back to the whole
revenge thing of how damaging somebody's
car. I literally said that too.
I got, that's the bitch move.
I could slash chuck Norris is tires.
If he wasn't standing
there and ruin his day, no,
go back and fight the
guy or just fucking or,
or don't
go back and rip his antenna off like a
fucking pussy fight or don't fight. Oh,
take a walk around a lake
and calm yourself down.
It admit to yourself that you're 41 years
old and you probably had a fucking 50
50 chance of losing the
thing to begin with. Ah.
And it would have been on the ground with
that gravel embedded in the side of my
face. You know, just taking
a boat shoe to the head.
He didn't have him on boat
shoes. He wasn't that bad.
All right. Okay. Here we go.
Here's a podcast. All right? Last week
I was telling you guys about how I have,
I discovered the magic
word when complaining, um,
to corporations that the
word is a unacceptable.
All right?
And just in case you guys feel that
I don't know what I'm talking about,
which is exactly what you should
feel because I am a moron. Um,
I got this great email from somebody.
Who the fuck is it? God dammit.
I thought I had it. You
know what? I am the worst.
Why do you guys listen to this
fucking podcast? No, no, no. I know.
I put ahead of right fucking here in
front of me. All right, it's back on.
It's back on track. I actually
got, I actually got a,
an email from somebody who answers the
phones for one of those big corporations.
All right?
If you want to learn how to do what I
explained it last in last week's podcast,
at least my story of how I went
about, um, getting my money back. So,
so this guy sends me, it's
really nice letter. He says, uh,
just want to say your podcasts a fucking
hilarious. Keep them coming. I'm,
you should do a show in Omaha
sometime. Uh, that's a rough one, dude.
Omaha's or rough one. I will
at some point. All right.
I just have to get psyched up for that.
The 28 planes I'm going to
have to take to get there.
That's one of those like fucking states.
You have to fly past it to
fly into a hub city, you know,
to finally get there. You know, I'm
flying to Omaha via fucking Tampa.
What? All right. Um, here we bill. Um,
also I wanted to say when dealing
with corporations using the word,
the unacceptable line does work.
I am a support agent for a well
known financial comic company.
If someone is continually a pain in the
ass about something and are persistent
about it, eventually they will
get their way. You guys hear that?
I know it's morning. For some of you, you
stirring your coffee. Did you hear that?
If someone is continually a pain in the
ass about something and are persistent
about it,
eventually they will get their way.
Usually as a customer
service representative,
we are encouraged to try and steer
the conversation away from the,
from things like credits and
try to offer other suggestions.
And that's the part where you get mad
because you're not getting what you want,
but that's what you have to keep. You
cool. All right. So anyways, he says, uh,
basically we try to bullshit them a
little and try and put them at ease.
Yeah. Lie to them. Okay. But if
a customer is still not happy,
we will give a credit or whatever
you want. As long as it's reasonable,
that's fair. Um, just to get
you off the phone. However,
if you start using profanity,
um, while on the phone call,
chances are we will try and find ways not
to help you or disconnect the call all
together.
Regardless of rules and procedures.
Representatives do have the ability
to make judgment calls. Basically,
if you call the customer
service rep a Cunt,
I will guarantee you they will not help
you stick to using the unacceptable line.
Don't give up and you eventually will
get what you want. See that people,
there you go.
Now you have the information you need
from a professional rather than some moron
comedian who almost got in a fight
outside of a pancake house. Um,
I actually want another one this week.
All right? I ordered the NHL Package,
the center ice package and
ask them, hey, you know,
so I says to the guy who I just sound
like I was doing fucking a Vaudeville.
So I asked the guy, I says, hey buddy,
what's with the chicken
soup? Um, I asked, I asked,
I asked the lady when I ordered it,
does it come with the NHL Channel?
And she says, hold on, let me check.
And she says, why? Yes, yes it does.
And I said the, and then you know
what? You got yourself a deal.
I will take the center ice package with
the NHL channel. So she says, okay,
all right. So they boot the fucking thing
up. And the next day, Lo and behold,
I don't have the NHL channel. So I call
up and what did they say to me? They say,
hey, hello sir, what can I do for you?
And I tell him I deal. And they said, oh,
we actually shot in her notes.
She left.
She said that you hung up before the call
was over. And I was like, no, I didn't.
I immediately got pissed too.
I kind of fucked this phone call
up a little bit in the beginning.
I went the [inaudible] route,
but I didn't say it, but then I,
I got it back on track. I was like,
no, I didn't. And he goes like, well,
according to her notes you did. And I
was like, well, according to my memory,
uh, I was on the phone call and you
weren't okay. So now what? I'm like,
so now what?
She gets to just say something happened.
She writes it down to cover her
ass, you know, and you know,
so that's when I kinda got mad.
But then I was able to bring
it back and just say, look,
the conversation ended with her going,
thank you very much.
Is there anything else I can
help you with? What do you think?
I was halfway through ordering it and
she was going, hang on a second sir.
Hang on. I was like, too late. Get
by. I didn't do that. All right.
And the guy's like, well, I have to
charge you $5 a month for this channel.
This is, this is like the zero tolerance
I have. I am arguing $5 a month,
which is going to be 30 bucks over
the course of the six month season.
And I'm like, no, I'm not paying that.
Okay. And the guy goes, why? I can't.
I can't give it to you. I don't
know what to do. I go, all right,
well then cancel the center ice package.
And the guy goes, I can't do that. I go,
what do you mean he can't do that?
And he goes,
you can't cancel it once you order it.
I go,
see you mean to tell me
that I ordered something?
It's in what you told me it was,
it isn't,
and now I can't cancel it and
you can't rectify the situation.
Is that any way to buy a business, run
a business? And the guy's like, whoa.
And I go, that's unacceptable.
I want to talk to somebody else.
So I get this next guy on the phone.
At this point,
I finally calmed down and I was able to
use that line, sir, I understand you.
You know you don't make the rules.
I know this wasn't your call,
but this was the scenario. Okay,
but blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
If he can't give me the channel for free,
like I told it was,
you know that it came with the package,
I would like to cancel center rice.
The guy goes, well, I can't do either
one of those, but this is what I can do.
Your DVR costs you 10 bucks a month.
How about I give you three free months,
a DVR that'll be 30 bucks discount
and the whole thing will be a wash.
And I was like, you know what?
You got yourself a deal. Bam.
Two one I'll turn it
this franchise around a perennial losing
franchise and just like the fucking
saints, I am now a factor.
I am now a fucking factor.
So,
and the last two weeks I got 25 buck
dollars back and I got $30 back.
I am plus 55.
I'm like a degenerate that the mush and
a a Bronx tale and I'm finally winning.
Oh I'm plus I saved myself 55 bucks.
Do you know how many tubes?
Sops you can buy with 55 bucks.
It's a lot of fucking socks.
How great do you feet feel when
you got a new pair of socks?
You know I never whistled.
The only time I ever whistle.
If you ever see me whistle and you know
I got a brand new pair of fucking dress
socks, a tube socks on your feet
take tingle in that right Clia. Ah,
they tingle.
I was hoping she was
going to make the noise.
Let me see if I can get her moan this
week. You guys haven't heard in a while.
Yeah,
she too busy sniffing on
microphone. Um, anyways. All right,
so let's get on with the fucking questions
here because I've got to start this
up. I'm almost done here. Um, say,
you know what? I feel great right now.
I feel great. I told that fucking
story about the guy at the diner.
I got to laugh at it.
I got to laugh at myself.
I got to be honest that chances are he
probably would have lost the fucking
fight. You know? That's why
stand up as a great thing.
It's a great fucking thing.
You get to make a complete ass out
of yourself filling a Douche and,
and laugh about it. Then you feel better.
All right, so he needs advice. All right.
Hey, Bill. Uh,
I got a couple of questions and comments
or stories about Bubba and went out
with this girl last year before
I went to the prom with her.
It wasn't really a date,
but it was just a chance to go
out with her and get to know,
to get to know her before we went to prom.
We ended up having a great
time that evening and it,
and at the prom I proceeded to Facebook
her about a week later and asked her if
she wanted to go out again.
She basically shared,
said she would like to go out again, but
not in a romantic way. Bombbomb, BombBomb.
All right, so now you took that
emotional kick in the chest.
After hearing this I backed off and
didn't pursue her for a month or so.
In this time she got a
boyfriend, booboo, Badu,
which honestly pissed me the fuck
off as well. It should have. Uh,
I had to talk to her.
Um,
I had talked to her for about a week
before she went out with this guy and when
they finally were officially dating,
I told her I didn't want to cause
trouble and then I didn't want to bother.
She replied by saying that she,
she said she didn't want to go out again
with me is because she was confused
about how I felt and seen when we
first went up before prom that I wasn't
interested. Isn't that funny? After she
said, let's just go out and be friends.
Right. Didn't she? Did I already
forget the first part of this?
We saw each other maybe two or
three times again through birthdays,
graduation parties until I went off to
college and she went back to high school.
I am now a freshman in college and have
and have made no friends on account of
my horrific people skills. I feel
like I should go after college girls,
but I can't stop thinking about the high
school girl and feel like she is light
years ahead of these big
tented shallow college girls.
I also feel like she's the first girl
that I ever felt comfortable hanging out
with,
although she seems like she would be a
hard girl too to wool as she is really
intelligent and I am still am
unsure if she likes me at all.
I was wondering what you think and if you
have any tips on how to really impress
girls besides the cliche, confidence
are expensive. Shit. All right dude.
You said something back here that
really just rang a bell wasting.
We used two or three. Two. I am.
Okay. This sentence right here, dude.
I am now a freshman in college and
I've made no friends on account of my
horrific people skills. All
right, dude, that's right there.
That's the money right there. That's
what you need to work on. All right.
Through this girl's still in fucking
high school. You're off at college.
You know what I mean? You were college.
You are college. You're living at college.
That is the ultimate fucking
nightclub for the next four years.
It's the greatest nightclub of all
fucking time is living at college.
Your, there's just women everywhere.
They're on every fucking floor.
They're in every goddamn class.
You don't even have to, you know,
you don't have to walk into a nightclub
like, hey baby, what's you sign?
Did somebody steal the lights out of
this guy and put him in your eyes?
Right? You don't have to come up with
stupid shit like that. You have a,
you know what? I always find it's easy
to pick up women when you're both,
there's a reason that both of
you were there like at the gym.
You're both there to work out. You're on
a train. You're both going home, you know,
they don't have their guard up as much
as when they go into the fucking Texas
chainsaw massacre. Fucking
meat locker. That is a Goddamn
nightclub. All right, so this is
what you need to do. All right.
I think right now you're saying like
you just said that all basically all
college girls,
a big titted and shallow and I think a
lot of it has to do with kind of your,
your um,
your,
your hopeless failing right now that
you don't know how to talk to people and
you don't know how to get things going.
Okay? That's part of being a freshman.
It's supposed to seem like a,
a bigger universe than you can handle,
but what you need to do is you need to
work on your horrific people skills,
all right? And it is a skill
that you can work on, all right?
Just like catching a football.
I'm never going to be able to
catch a football like Jerry Rice,
but if I fucking do it enough times,
I can catch the fucking thing, right?
Maybe imitate somebody is end zone dance,
but you're going to get in the game.
So what you need to do is understand that
you kind of putting that girl up on a
pedestal, you don't really know
her. And I think that that the,
the comfort of kind of already
having your foot in the door,
I bet you were a lot more comfortable.
I bet you were real comfortable with
the fact that you're just kind of being
friends and the pressure was,
was,
was kind of taken off the whole prom
and that type of thing. You're, you're,
you know, you're shy, so you take
like baby steps, you know what I mean?
Instead of taking the big step and trying
to grab her titty on the first date.
I'm joking,
but you know what I mean?
So this is what I would
do if I was use seriously.
I'm kind of fucking around here,
but I know this is like a,
a serious subject for you.
So this is all seriousness.
Just what you gotta do is just you gotta.
You gotta force yourself out of
your shell, you know, I mean,
if you say hello to a girl,
she's not going to punch
you in the face or whatever.
Just really write down on a
piece of paper, what's, what the,
the humiliation or whatever, the fear you
have, what you think's going to happen.
I'm telling you, a lot of times when
you do that and you actually read it,
you realize how ridiculous it is.
And
I'm telling you,
they're never going to be better
looking then when they're in college.
All of you guys, you're at [inaudible],
you fucking, you're right off.
You have right off the assembly line in
Detroit. Dude, fuck that college girl.
I mean, whatever, God bless,
I'm sure she's a nice person,
but you got to get in the game and you
got to start a crush and ass as they say
in fucking old school. That's what you
should be doing there. And, uh, you know,
go out with as many girls as you can,
see what you like and be coming up with
the list as far as what's the kind of
girl you eventually want to stay with.
And in the meantime,
you bang a couple of big titted shallow
girls. You always wear a condom.
Unacceptable not to wear one dude.
It ain't fucking worth it. And uh,
you know,
then you got your stories,
then you got your fucking stories
and when you get married, you know,
and he'd go down to the Dunkin donuts
and you want to bang the girl behind the
counter, you know, the temptation won't
be as great because you're fucked.
All those big tented whores at college.
All right, so psych yourself up.
Do it even tell even like, you know, if
you got some friends there at school,
just be open about it. Go. God Damn
it, I got it. I got no game with girls.
Just say it. Get it out there. I got no
game with girls. Come on, help me out.
You know, be a wing man. Do
something. I got to get fucking laid.
Just get it out there and I'll tell you
as much as cock block and assholes as
guys can be when someone's open
and honest about like that. Yeah.
If I have some guy ever said that to me,
there's no fucking way I wouldn't try
to help him out. So you'll be all right.
Plus it's your first
semester, so you're, you're,
you're making everything bigger than
it is. All right. So there you go.
Let you miss him. Get Out of
your shelf and forget about
that girl. Okay. And then,
you know what, after this, you know,
your first two semesters you're going to
come home with a little bit of swagger.
You might be able to bang
that broad. They're back, uh,
when she's done with their little
fucking pottery class, you never know.
Might come all full circle.
All right,
I only got time for a couple
more questions then I got
to get going here. Um,
Oh, before we get going,
why don't I just do this?
I'll save the questions until next week.
Or maybe I'll read a couple of
quick ones just to let you know.
These are my upcoming gigs for November.
Um,
November 6th, sixth, the thought
thought, thought, thought.
2009 I'm going to be a
town hall in New York City.
People tickets are going fast.
All right, and if you act now,
I will throw in a bill. Burke
can opener. No, seriously.
It's 1300 seat theater.
And last I heard we'd already
sold a thousand and that
was a couple of weeks ago
and I just had a flashback
to that Chappelle show.
Shit sketch. Ah, and
word. That was weeks ago.
Remember that you slapped me in the
face and he said that was weeks ago.
It's one of the greatest
lines of all time. Um,
all right,
I'm going to be at the town hall in New
York City and the next day I don't have
it on my website. November 7th, 2009 I'm
going to be at Boston at a Gyno, Serena,
wherever the bu terriers play during the
Denis leary comics come home the 15th
anniversary.
It's going to be great.
Going to get to see a bunch
of friends of mine. Um,
what else do I got? The improv in
Tempe, Arizona. The 19th 20th and 21st.
And then what else? That's
it. That's all for November.
Then I'm in Cleveland and in Seattle.
And then I do my special.
So please come out. Please continue
to support me. I really appreciate it.
And I didn't have time to
talk about Rick flair video.
Somebody brought up the ric flair chop
and I had not watched Rick flare in years
and two,
if you really want to laugh,
please go on youtube and just
watch ric flair. Hypen is matches.
It's one he said to that, he said there's
one of him holding up these loafers.
Did I talk about this last week? I
can't remember. Look up ric flair.
Golden Spoon.
There's another one where he tells this
guy that this fucking dude that his
shoes are worth more than his house.
Um, and then there's a great interview,
you know, where he talks
about the movie, the wrestler,
and he just seems like the
greatest guy ever. Like, you know,
his wrestling career is over. He's
not bitter. He's really thankful.
It's just like, I, once again,
I became an even bigger ric flair fan
watching and it's r I c f a flair ric,
the ric flair flop ric flair chops,
ric flair flips.
He's got some of the greatest fucking
videos out there and you just realize what
a true legend.
What a fucking show man.
What a what a just a fucking unbelievable
entertainer athlete and everything
that this guy was in the fucking things
that he put his body through. Man.
I would, I would love at some point
that guys ever doing a signing anywhere.
I'm fucking all over it,
you know? Um, that's it.
And that's it for this week.
I hope you guys enjoyed the podcast.
Sorry it was a little bit short.
I'll get to the questions next week.
Hope all you guys have a good week.
Um,
oh man,
there was another great question.
This guy was asking why is tranny
porn on heterosexual websites?
Fuck, I wanted to answer that one too.
I got to get to that one next week.
All right there.
I'm leaving you on a cliffhanger.
I'll talk to you guys next week.
Uh,
that's it.
Don't take any shit.
That's where she
died.