Yeah.
Hey, what's going on is bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
Just checking it on you.
Just checking in on your fucking
red line in the goddamn levels.
Here we bring this down here. Ah, Jesus.
I got shit to do today,
so let's fucking get right to it.
You see these? God Damn
digs. Fuck it by him.
I found that youtube clip the other day,
man, when the fat kid would review food,
that was my favorite one. Fat Kid
reviews, girl scout cookies. He goes,
sees a girl scout mint chocolate
chip cookies and I fucking love him,
right?
He sits there and he teach eight some
looks up in the air and then he goes,
if some you see somebody selling these
goddamn things, fucking buy them.
It's one of the greatest
food reviews ever.
I totally believed them and I want
to girl scout cookies. But anyway,
so I'm not here to talk about this.
I'm not in to talk about that.
I'm here as a casual
fucking fan of the NBA,
meaning I've probably watched seven whole
games in the last seven fucking years.
And I watched the second half of
last night's Cleveland Cavaliers,
first the fucking Golden State Warriors,
um,
in a bar with the sound out.
Now here comes my analogy,
my favorite fucking moment
of last night and this thing,
I don't have a dog in the fight.
I'd love to see Lebron win a
championship for Cleveland. And um,
I always like the Golden State Warriors
because they, they stuck, you know,
and their fans fucking hung in there
and I liked their floor and all of that
shit in that old piece of Shit stadium
they play. And I went to a game there.
I went to a game there about fucking
10 years ago and there was like nobody
there and they had the sickest
fucking live band there.
They were playing Herbie Hancock.
What does that sound?
Well down there and what Bob?
Wow Dude, dude, dude at the beep,
fucking sickest shit ever ate was
way better than mine. I just did
the fuck was the name of that song.
I got that on my fucking phone somewhere.
Oh, Jesus. You know, and I'll
play it for you here in a second.
Maybe you guys understand
what this one is.
Herbie Hancock or wasn't watermelon man.
What the fuck was it called?
Headhunter her be head cock.
I'm going to hit pause while I look
this up so I don't torture you here.
All right. I got, they were playing. They
were playing Herbie Hancock Chameleon.
I met a professional basketball game.
There's nobody there.
There's fucking live band is crushing
this song right here. Come on,
play it for fuck sakes.
Okay?
That'd be stuck around like, just fucking
game sucks. Listen to this band though.
They're killing it.
Harvey Mason,
right?
Black people all start moving around.
White people start getting uncomfortable
and then the guitar player comes in,
maybe comes in and the next spot,
very calm.
I felt like it was in a fucking
movie, so I was like, you know what?
I love this franchise. You know
what this is? This is if you shut,
this is what you should be
doing. Saying, listen man,
we're only going to
win eight games a year.
Let's fucking get a killer band
to come in there and people,
can Lisa have a good time?
It was a fucking party and they lost
by like fucking 30. So anyways, I got,
I don't have a dog in this
fight and I watched this game.
MMM.
I watched this game with the fucking
sound on that was Herbie Hancock Chameleon
by the way,
before you try to shit it,
point your phone at your fucking dashboard
while you're driving down the street.
Killing a fucking mother has six.
Um,
I have to tell you this over the last
couple of games that I've watched,
like the NBA has fucking changed so much
the way Steph curry just runs around
the court. Like it's his,
like the whole thing is his,
it's his fucking showcase when he was
sitting on the bench and that dude hits
the three pointer and he did
that little jazz hand thing.
Yeah.
Whatever
the fuck he was doing,
you know,
dribbles out the game and then
it looks at the crowd, goes,
starts fucking screaming. I'm
just looking at them, okay,
now I know this guy could fucking
body slammed me. I'm just a comedian,
but I'm talking about NBA player
to NBA play at this fucking guy is,
he's built like an honor roll student.
All right.
And I know he can shoot the fucking lights
out from behind the three point line.
Fine. You know, you do the
best she can back there,
but you let that little motherfucker
just glide down the God damn lane like
clear path, clear path.
Today's Nba don't touch him.
Don't fucking touch him.
That guy needs to get his head taken off.
Get one of those fucking giant white
dudes from fucking eastern Europe,
some Transylvania guide. Get him
out there. He's got six files.
Just, you know, you know what
would happen? He do fucking
one. They'd be like, Ooh,
Ooh. 32 channel. Which the trade
or whatever the fuck they call it.
Was that a hard foul? Was he trying
to hurt his feelings with that fall?
Oh, let's go over and look at the
tape. What do you think was, was,
was his face snarling too much when
he did that? Uh, we can't have that.
Get him out of the game. You know
it's still worth it to fucking do it.
Cause I could take back in the day,
you know the Rick Ma Horns that John
Sally's all at all of these fucking got
John.
Sally passed away unfortunately.
But all of those fucking old school NBA
guys gotta be this fucking kid and just
be sitting there going like, yeah, there,
there, there weren't a half. All right,
wait,
that guy would have got
his fucking head taken off.
Do you know if you watch highlights of
Jordan all you young millennial fucking
Yolo people out there. If you fucking
watch him, it's like he's skinny,
he's skinny,
and then all of a sudden he's filled out.
That was because the Pistons beat the
shit out of him. EPFL like fucking two,
three years in a row in the playoffs.
He finally had enough
guy had to go to the gym because the
NBA reps weren't protecting them.
They could come down there.
They'd fucking do remember one time
fucking bill and beer, one of the,
it was like all Samuelson without skates
out there who hilariously and the 30
for 30 years to be like, we used to
like to try to get in people's heads.
It's like, like he was playing this
high level fucking mind game. It's like,
no dude,
you were just out there waiting for
people to leave their feet and you'd take
their fucking legs out.
How'd you come up with that?
It's your major in Calculus.
Um,
so I remember one time he was
hacking the Celtics so fucking bad.
Robert Parish finally couldn't take it
and the players go on up the court and he
just fucking gave them two,
four. I'm smashes over the head.
He chopped them down
like a fucking jealousy.
Like when a guy who does not a chop down
a tree chopped down a tree and it falls
into his house. That's the way he was
hacking away at Lam beer and lamb beer.
Just put both his hands
up like, oh, you know,
like George Michael when he was with
wham and he just fucking went down.
All right. He gave him to fucking ruin
your friends. Right. And he went down,
the refs didn't see it.
It was like wrestling.
And then when they back they went back
and looked at the tape. You're like, yeah,
well, you know, we should've called
the file and there was no fines.
There was no objections, there
was no nothing. He just, you know,
live by the sword, die by the sword.
Um, there was so many of those.
I just was thinking of another one that
I saw. They just, it just nowadays,
you just Curry's out, they
just fucking gliding around.
He's built like a muppet.
I just don't understand in this
day and age how that has happened.
And the only thing that I can come up
with is that the leagues are so fucking
guilty that not guilty.
Greedy is that they
realize that, you know, um,
that offense sells tickets to the
casual fan. You know what I mean? Like,
let's take the most boring game ever.
And I'm not talking about horseshoes.
I'm not talking about Shuffle Board.
I'm not talking about darts.
I of course am talking about soccer.
Okay.
Which the entire world has embraced except
for us and when you really look at it,
that's probably why we're number one.
You know what I mean?
The rest of the world is too stupid to
realize how boring that fucking game is
despite the fact that it's so fucking
boring that even their fans have to have
campfires singalongs as they
wait for something to happen.
I walked some matter what age,
right? Just sitting there,
they're fucking scarves and shit.
This is the thing about,
Oh man, I'm going to get
some fucking emails in this.
This is the thing about fucking soccer,
right?
If they just let the forwards run
pass the final line of defense,
like in any other competitive
fucking gang where it's like, hey,
I'm faster than you.
I understand like offsides to a point,
but it's got to be it just a line
like in hockey and then after that,
if I'm faster than you, if I can see
the play developing before you do,
I get by you.
I don't have to fucking wait for you.
Okay.
If they would just adjust that and you'd
start to have some fucking 10 to eight
games,
I'm telling you that game would blow up.
We blow up here in the United States,
we would sit down and fucking watch it.
You know why?
Because we don't understand the game.
You know what I mean?
If I was watching cricket right,
I guess they score a lot
in that fucking thing.
That's a good one to just
sit around and booze with,
but any fucking game than I'm not into.
If somebody is crushing it and everybody's
flipping out, I'm going to be like,
what's going on? I'm going to actually
going to sit there and watch it.
Like nobody.
Like when I walked by.
Okay.
You know in soccer is on, I don't even
look at it, but if I hit this guy go,
he's doing that. I stopped
when I watch, you know,
and I read all the fucking advertising's
all over there fucking uniforms.
I got to tell you,
the premier league has the worst fucking
uniforms I've ever seen in my life.
You can't figure out who the fuck any,
it doesn't say man United,
it doesn't say Liverpool.
It just says Exxon and fucking
Joey's fish and chips fucking banks.
I heard they're going to do
that in the NBA. But anyways,
I think that that's what
happened in the game.
And I know I don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about.
I'm too fucking busy to pay attention.
And at the end of the day I never
really excelled in sports anyway.
So who better to break down?
What's wrong with the fucking NBA then
some Sutter and fucking prick like me.
Okay.
I think you got an entire generation
of people that grew up playing Madden
football and all of this shit and
everybody was the globe trotters.
And now that just doing like the
real version of it. All right.
I love Steph Curry. He's the greatest
shoot I've ever seen in my life,
but watching him just glide down
the fucking lane is ridiculous,
which is why last night after
the fucking whistle blows,
he just decides like, Oh,
I'm just going to fucking,
I'm going to take a little lay up here.
Okay.
You know right next to Lebron James.
And I loved that Lebron blocked
it and looked at him like,
what the Fuck Outta here? That's
what they need to do. All right,
you're not going to beat these fucking
guys play in their damn game trying to
out shoot fucking three pointers or
whatever the fuck it is they're doing.
Granted, I washed it with the
sound down in the second half. Um,
they need to fuck they got it.
They got you. I'm telling you,
they got to give him the old right there
for it. That's what they got to do. Okay.
That's what you do. If the other team is
faster, the other team fucking, you can't,
you have to play fiscal. I'm not saying
play dirty Pittsburgh Penguin fans.
I'm not saying you hire a
fucking knee breaker and,
and the career of the best player on
their other team. I'm not saying that.
All I'm saying is when the
guy comes down the lane,
your whole team should be
yelling clearer path, you know,
and this guy looks like he's in
the fucking globe trotters. Um,
now, now that I'm done with
that little fucking Soliloquy,
most of that was based in what
happens is you get older, you know,
and you start realizing
your own mortality.
And there's a couple of panic
thoughts that you have is, you know,
the world is churches. Oh, I'm
gonna die and it's gonna keep going.
Part of it was that, that the game
has changed. You know what I mean?
I am kind of the old man going,
why can't they have shorts,
shorts again and close line somebody.
It's amazing.
Somebody balls didn't come out
like during that Rambus play.
It's unbelievable that his
junk didn't come out the side.
He fucking literally did. Like,
you know, like, uh, he did,
he was doing like a Thomas
flair in the air and do it.
I actually retweeted the other day,
it was enough game Jack Sigma elbows,
Kareem Abdul Jabbar in the fucking
like right in, right in the right.
Inhale solar plexus zs
to say in wrestling.
And Kareem had to like fucking
just run it off like, fuck.
So whatever happened on
the play where the sea, uh,
the sonics hit the shot or not, they're
going back up to court or whatever. No,
they didn't cause what's his face?
Sigma was still setting up.
Corinne walked back into the play and
just got a little in front of Jack Sigma
turned around and punched
him right in the face.
And sigma had that great hair,
you know,
that hair that like moves around if he
get hit, you know, he had whip lash hair,
the white version of it.
We had Thomas Hitman Hearns had the
black version when he fought, uh,
when he fought Marvin Hagler. You know,
if a black guy, he's going to get
punched in the head in a boxing match,
you want them to have a Jerry
curl because it just adds to it.
When all that liquid just
shoots off his fucking head.
And Jack Sigma had the white version
of it where he had basically a Beatles
haircut.
So it just enhances,
you really get to see like how much you
know, whiplash, somebody who's enduring.
Um, all right, there we go. That's just
the end of it. I, I, you know what,
I'm going to, selfishly, I
want to see seven games, um,
and uh, I would like to see, all
right, one teams of finesse team,
the other teams of physical team,
I don't want to say any dirty play,
but I don't see one team,
you know,
putting on their Tutus and trying to
out fucking spin the other team. Right.
Isn't that what I'm saying?
Then you know, sorry,
I'm trying to plow my way through this
podcast. So they got to go a table reader.
You want to join the podcast? He
just coming in to say hello. No,
I just called Tuesday.
Has a day.
Not Today.
I got one more day and I'm doing today,
but tomorrow it's your birthday.
Oh yeah. Where are you taking me?
Chucky cheese.
I get to work here. Come
here. I do. I feel about it.
How do you feel about your
birthday? This is a weird one. Why?
Because usually at my advanced age,
I start going like, oh
God. And I was this number.
Now I'm that number, right? This one.
I, I don't, I've just sort of, uh,
you know, somewhere when I,
during my year of being 47,
I realized it's over
what's over my sex appeal.
My, uh, my dream of being
one of the People magazine's
50 most beautiful people.
Uh, yeah, that might
be in the latter rains,
but a sex appeal I think is,
oh Geez.
Is everybody gets a ribbon nowadays.
Um,
so I just have settled into a,
I went and I got glasses the other day.
Yes, he did. Cleo, get out of
there. That was a grape nuts.
Those are not for you. Go
Fat. She's getting fat.
She's fat. You're fat, and
you're not going to get a
date. No one's going to love,
you know, I've been so busy,
I haven't been able to walk.
Grab a microphone here cause you're going
to drive people nuts off off the thing.
Go get a call.
You're gonna drive me nuts cause
a microphone in the closet. Huh?
I feel like de Niro and knock and I'm
Goodfellas now kick on right down there.
Yeah, it was scaring me, Karen.
Um, no, this one I'm just
now like, I'm Kinda like,
all right, I'm old now. It's all
about, and because I had sight, Erica,
Erica,
um,
I realize now that all I give a shit is
that if I just can sit down and not have
pain, I'll be fine. And I want to thank
everybody that's have given me all their,
their, you know, remedies
and all of that stuff.
You know, it's funny. It's, yeah,
it's funny as hell how they fucking do
it, where it's, it's done with love,
but in a Twitter way, like, hey
fuck it. Just if you have Sciatica,
just do this. Get or get one of those foam
rollers and roll out your [inaudible].
And it's like, I did that, I did
that, I've done all of that shit.
I actually went to the chiropractor
again yesterday and he said that the
swelling on my spine
has gone tremendously.
I am now on the next level of healing.
Well now I don't have pain.
I just feel like, uh, it's a little
tingly sometimes my foot falls asleep.
I've been doing these stretches.
A buddy of mine at work got in this.
You don't like do any of those things
where you hang upside down? Yeah,
he got one that's actually
not legal in this country. Um,
but you they sell it in Canada,
Canada and you just basically, uh,
you're more hanging from like your
waste as opposed from your ankle.
Dad was talking about,
my dad was talking about the one
where you hang from your ankles. Yeah.
And what my chiropractor was
saying was that that one,
it puts stress on your joints cause
you got your whole body weight,
puts like your ankles,
your knees and your hips because your
whole body weight with this other one.
He had loved that thing
though. Yeah. I don't know.
A lot of people love
it for whatever reason,
but I've been using the other one
and that one would be like, uh,
say like you're at the zoo and you're at
the gorilla and closure and you want to
bend over and look for the dime.
You just fucking lost. Very timely.
Just imagine that except you don't
fall in is the thing and an adult,
if an adult fell in there,
would they have shot at
with a tranquilizer thinking
that maybe the adult could
handle the fucking thrashing that he was
going to get? I think that they had a,
would have had the presence of mind
to like slowly try to back out of the
situation as opposed to a baby that's
just kind of like sitting there.
Can you give us an example of how you
would slowly back of a situation with the
gorilla? Alright. You fallen, I
god, what would you say? Hey Man,
like easy, easy. Well, you know,
I'm terrified of primates.
Like they just freaked me out in general,
so I don't really know what I would
do because I just feel like, oh,
I know what I would do common like Dna
wise or something with a chimpanzee than
they do with a gorilla like
date. That freaks me out. I know,
I know exactly what I would do.
I don't like it.
Actually I would curl up in the fetal
position and I would cover up my face so
he wouldn't rip it off
and I would just be like,
if I got to take some
gorilla fucking kidney shots,
I would much rather take the ESV comes
over and just fucking whales on me,
like from fucking ankle
to the side of my head.
I will take that before I will.
I will just stand there with my face
out waiting for you to rip it off.
Well I do they, yeah, I mean I feel
like that's probably the best way to go.
So they don't see you as like a threat
or something like you just sort of submit
to them or something? I don't know.
But then I don't want them to be like,
I'm sure this information
is on the Internet wife now.
Like it's just so weird.
I don't know. They just,
they really freaked me out.
I remember when we went to Australia,
you know they're going to grab you by
your ankle and just drag you around like a
fucking, like they did that little
kid. I haven't watched it. Oh,
remember when we went to Australia and
I was telling they have video of it.
I don't want to watch that.
I did. I did watch the,
one of the naked guy that walked into
the line and closure and he's trying to
kill himself and the fucking his,
his neck is in the guy in the
fucking and naked. I mean,
I was talking about that on the TV. Oh
my God. Yeah, a little. Yeah. It's like,
go ahead, grab my neck, but
I still got a cup of my junk.
You still got to keep your boxes on,
right? No, but this is the thing.
The thing was just handled by his neck.
But you survive. Yeah, but cause I,
they must have just fed the fucking thing.
So it just had him around the neck.
She and the guys literally,
he's got his arms around the things that
blinds neck and then he's basically in
any wrapped his legs around his body.
He basically had it in the guard,
like a Jujitsu guard and the
fucking lion around his throat,
but he wasn't shaking him or anything.
And everyone like, you know, going,
Oh my God, I'm a God and you
know, whatever fucking language.
What if a country was in
their film in the guy,
that guy was completely
fucking naked and um, yeah,
he obviously had like mental
issues because if you're
in sound mind and you kill
yourself, you just like
jump off something, right?
Yeah. You don't wander into a land on
somebody naked Volkswagen Passat. Wait,
but I wanted to say when we
went to Australia that time,
were you with me when I was in
that monkey exhibit or whatever,
and it looked like planet of the
apes and it was freaking me out.
And then we went into that other little
side room and there was a monkey behind
the glass and everyone was looking at
it and taking pictures and he started
rocking back and forth and I was like,
that thing is about to freak out.
And then it threw itself up against the
glass and like screamed and yelled and
everyone was like, and then
the other chimp came in. Yes.
And like tried to come and I hugged it.
Yeah,
we thought they were going to fight and
then they embraced each other and then
they like put their backs toward the
glass with one of them's arm around the
other. Like it's going to be okay. Like
we're going to get out of here some day.
Like it was so emotional and it
was so scary. I just, I can't,
I don't know. I can't deal with it. Like
that scene in the trailer for Tarzan,
the legend of Tarzan or the monkey comes
in and like see as the Tarzan and the
bassinet and then picks it up and
then leaves with it as just like,
I don't know. I don't
like that shit. Yeah.
I just think it's really weird.
I mean,
if that was in the wild,
they would,
they would eat that baby and
they would actually leave it,
keep it alive as long as they could
because they enjoy the screaming cause. It
is that true that they get off on it,
man. Two chimpanzees are fucking evil.
Grill is a chill.
Gorillas don't have anything to prove.
Chimps have the short man's disease.
I feel like men are a little more chill
and then he got those tweaker monkeys.
Yeah, right. The meth head ones.
Those ones that throw their shit out.
Yet
the chimpanzee was the one that like
threw itself up against the glass and was
like really loud and screaming.
The other girl is seem a
little bit more peaceful.
Those are the ones that are handsome.
Like you saw that one gorilla
that everyone was freaking
out about in the zoo in
Japan because everyone
thought it was like a good,
it's actually a very good looking
gorilla, but yeah, that was weird.
It was really weird.
You will never find
another gorilla like me. I,
yeah, like sexy gorilla. That's
why they freak me out there.
So human like that is just,
it's unsettling to me.
And I don't like when they make gorillas
have agendas like that commercial where
the little girl is deaf and she's doing
sign language with the other gorilla.
It's like all,
oh, rang a Tan. What? One Orangutan? My
hope is that that's the ones that, look,
if I was a fucking chimp,
that's what I would,
oh the ones with all the stringy hair.
Orange ones look like old men,
but they're like sign language in each
other and it's like, oh that's sweet.
Like they're communicating through sign
language and then all of a sudden that
orangutan is like,
oh,
but like the way you live is destroying
my life. And it's like, wait a minute.
And it was like for about palm oil
or peanut oil. And it was like,
don't get the monkey. Everything's
fucking cause now did you see,
I told you this morning, I
didn't see that. You get it,
but don't bring the animals into it.
And deaf children,
like I just felt like that was his fucking
monkeys with their agendas. I didn't,
I didn't see the clip. It's,
I just, I just read about it.
Some reporter as Bernie Sanders,
the fact that he's staying in the race,
they asked him if he was being
sexist by staying in it. Yeah.
Like he couldn't handle
lights into a home.
And why is that sexist
for him to stay in there?
Because the reporter wants
Hillary Clinton. They want
him out. They want him out.
They want Trump out. Even Republicans
like where the money's at thick.
They are going to accept Hillary
Clinton before Trump and before,
um, uh, Bernie Sanders.
And what I love about Trump and Bernie
Sanders was it showed that enough
Americans are sick of the
standard Republican Democrat.
Like Hillary Clinton is the
standard fucking Democrat.
She's got the same money in our pockets.
The Republican,
the General Republican candidate
would have had. And he goes,
all the fucking guys that was running
basically, um, and it's, you know,
it was just,
that means just the 1% is going to get
more fucking rich and going to push down
the middleclass the same fucking bullshit.
They're going to stay the course.
They don't want somebody that's
off to the side. I got, uh,
I just had a scary thought.
What was that? Trump president?
No, I was thinking about, I don't
know that around your president now,
that orangutan thing. And I just
literally got a picture of an orangutan.
Yeah. Like I said, Tang, like the drink
of my whole life isn't an orangutan.
No, it's a rang a Tan. It is. Nobody's,
I don't think that's
true. Well, oh wait, is it
rang a Tan.
I just,
it was making me think of planet of
the apes where it's like take over.
Oh yeah.
Yup.
And I got to made everybody made fun of
what's his face fell and potato with the
knee. I always did potato Po. Tay
told, I think I used to smell,
I mean spell tomato with an e
at the end. Cause the, the toe.
Yeah.
It's like there's a toe.
So are both dumb.
Well
that's why we found each
other. That's right. Because
there was no one to be on the date going
like, oh my God, this person's an idiot.
We were both going like,
wow, this person gets me.
I'm excited for your birthday tomorrow.
You'll never find Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo.
Yeah you are.
You're very resigned this year. I've
noticed even now talking about it as much.
Oh, cause I'm in the writer's room. I
know what's going to happen. My birthday.
I'm going to fucking go to the writer's
room and stare at a computer all day.
Oh yeah.
Well if this person says this and then
called back to that story til still
track. Yeah, that's, but they'll
probably give you a cake at the office.
No, cause there's somebody's
birthday was yesterday.
That was the oh yeah.
You guys have some of these first date.
Today's the ninth and mine is Friday.
If they get a cake,
you know, if they get me a cake,
it's because they all want cake. No.
Um, no. I know what I
wanna do for my birthday.
What do you want to do for
your birthday? Um, tell me.
Well, you know, in a perfect world,
my back would be fine and I'd take you
up in the helicopter with an instructor.
Of course, you know. Oh,
that would be fun. Yeah.
And we'd fly over the ocean and I'd be
singing where no more nurture our Lord.
The more
I would do that.
My name is John Dacre.
That's my favorite fucking thing ever.
I just more than any
question in the world,
[inaudible] Mori,
what's the first religious
song you sing? So, Oh,
I'm Rosa Lord,
or it was really
good.
It goes when he ends up here.
Oh
Hey had a fucking meltdown.
He was on TV and he just got in his
fucking head and I don't think he'd ever
been in his head in his life that he's
a really cerebral guy and he couldn't
understand that for the first time ever.
His head, his brain was failing him.
He was really looking around like,
I'm just as confused spot this as you are.
Did he choked and I feel like
in church or wherever it is,
because the woman playing the piano,
she is like,
I guess she gives lessons
in that town and I,
I'm sure that in charge he kills it,
but then he's in that public access duty.
I don't think it kills her camp.
I think he can change changes,
like just he can carry a tune and they
bury them with like 40 people around
them. Right, right, right.
He's probably still weird.
What kind of car you think he drives?
It's something very old and something
like tragically unhip it's Brown.
Yes. Brown. He drives a
brown, a brown interior.
Like it's just brown on Brown. Yeah,
it's like an old Pontiac Bonneville.
Then old Napoli.
[inaudible]
my name is John Dacre.
My name is John Dacre.
Let them fuck.
There's so much. You guys have
to see this. No, no. I already,
I already talked about that.
I do love it.
We got a table read. So I got to go over
my lines here today. They're Nino. Um,
Bebo let me a, I got to do a
little some reeds here. Alright.
Helix Hallux. I don't know. Uh,
your helix. Sadly. Helix. Helix.
Your unique.
You don't walk like anyone else talk like
anyone else or sleep like anyone else.
So why is your mattress one size fits all?
I don't know cause we're all
basically the same height. You know,
unless you're like an NBA freak because
a truly customized mattress will cost
you five to 10 10,000 bucks until now.
Now,
now my name is John Dacre.
Go To Hague,
calyx sleep.com answer helix,
sleep.com I keep thinking of the band
for a answer, a few simple questions,
and they'll run a three d biochemical
model of your body through the proprietary
algorithms they've developed with the
help of the world's leading ergonomics and
biomechanics.
It's like just a troll me biomechanics
experts as a mistake or you know why?
Because my brain is already gone.
All right,
so they take a three d image of your
body and then that's on the Internet
somewhere, right? It's
a custom mattress. Yeah,
but any information goes on the Internet.
People can hack in,
so someone hacks in and see what they
take that five 11 right now and then they
make some blowup doll of your body and
then someone's fucking a rubber version
of the Pacific with the
Ville. Birthdays. All again.
Yeah. This is, I have a theory about the
internet. I don't give a fuck what it is.
Somebody's jerking off to
it. I don't care. Yeah.
There's somebody that
gets excited about a,
a kid getting dragged around by his ankle,
by a fucking gorilla.
I you used to say that
about the goodwill to like,
you didn't like it because you just
assume that everyone just just done
everything.
Like all the clothes and all that.
It's like really cool vintage stuff.
You're like,
I don't want something that
somebody just on. And I'm like,
why do you automatically go to somebody
just on something cause of people or
animals? Cause people show go out
to public events in their bare feet.
That's why you want this sweatpants.
You want somebody old couch,
everything's been fucked on or it's just,
that's gross animal. Sorry. Let's
continue with the advertisers
helix. Yeah, I doubt the band was
called a Hallux also, by the way. Yes,
they were. Oh, I you sure? Like
you've heard of like a double helix?
Like that's not what they're talking
about. Oh No, it wasn't that deep. Oh.
Gimme an Har, r o, c. K.
And what'd you gonna do?
Rock. You don't remember that?
There was deep lyrics back in
the eighties helix, Helix, Helix.
Customers report a 30% improvement
in overall sleep quality.
I should really do this with
my Sciatica and for couples,
they customize each side of the mattress.
Ooh, wow. We can along so much better.
Your mattress arrives at your door in
about one week and shipping is 100% free.
That's why everyone from Gq magazine
to Forbes are all talking about helix
sleep. You have 100 nights to try
it out, and if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free,
gross and give you 100% refund.
No questions asked. I want to try
this. You're ruining it for, hey,
what is that state? I thought
you said, no question my fault.
Go to helix,
sleep.com/burn and get $50 off your order.
That's helix. sleep.com/burr he leaks
sleep.com/burr. I'm sure that great.
I, you know, I gotta fuck around so
people keep listening. Oh boy. Here we go.
Clubbed. Gabby, what Glib. Debbie club.
Debbie w club. Debbie. I'm
like Bush club. Dami okay.
I speak Spanish. Convenience club. Debbie
and my dad's down to South America.
Delivers wine straight to
your door. Personalized. Uh,
we send you whan that is
personalized to your palate. Slash.
Taste through our pallet quiz.
Our recommendations become even more
personalized with every bottle your rates.
See now they already have your body for
the rubber thing right now. They know.
Now they know what your Palette's like.
I mean they literally know what's the
next thing of it can be. What's your,
is the um,
unique,
sorry if everybody's ears though.
Sorry.
We work with the top wine makers and
grow up wine makers and grow fro is from
around the world directly to make
all of our y high quality and value.
13 dog dollar bottles would
normally retail for $20.
No risk.
You choose type and quality of balls with
no membership fee or cancellation fee
and 100% satisfaction guarantee.
Uh,
we partner with local artists to develop
why labels that are unique works of
art.
Right now at club Debbie weapons and mass
destruction is offering listeners $20
off your first order.
When you go to club Debbie,
don't have to do that to them and
never really won the election.
That's dot com slash burr
and it gets even better.
I know y'all hate pain.
Why is it blowing out here?
I know you all hate paying for shipping.
Some club Debbie,
she had voted for Jim will actually
pay for your shipping on orders of four
bottles of more. So take some time off
your to do list. Just go to club, Debbie.
I never really did anything.com/
[inaudible] we see from
my watch to get $20 off
your first order. Now that's club
Debbie at.com/burr oh and the last one.
Oh our old friend Zip.
But
are you hiring?
Do you know where to post your
jobs to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place is not
enough to find quality candidates.
Do you want to find the perfect hire?
You need to post all of your jobs on the
top job sites and now you know you need
to post your job on all the top
job sites and now you can with Zip
[inaudible] dot com you can post it jumps
to 100 plus job sites including social
media networks like Facebook and
Twitter, man, all with a single click.
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch all of your
qualified candidates roll into zip
recruiter's.
Easy to use interface,
no juggling emails or calls to your
office. Quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire him, right? Uh,
how I enter the right person fast.
I like your titties. Come
on over. Find out why is it
recruiter has been used by over 800,000
businesses and right now my listeners
can try zip
but corona for free by going to zip
[inaudible] dot com slash bird that's
zip recruiter.com/part of this,
too many of these. One more
time, ziprecruiter.com/birth
all right, there you go.
And that's your podcast. Just chicken
in on you. Please go to all things,
comedy.com to listen to more
podcast and see some fine, friendly,
funny faces and an apology from the
Great Andrew Feminists last year, uh,
last year, last week, he accidentally
Ted some repeat material. Um,
he wanted me to apologize on
Monday for that. I forgot to.
So his sincerest apologies and condolences
during this difficult time for all of
you. Please enjoy this feels of you,
Andrea. Please enjoy this music.
I'm gonna Actually gonna tell him to play
her. You can't. Cox Chameleon a wow. Wow.
Wow. Happy pre brand day
baby. Oh, thank you very much.
Happy Birthday to me.
Happy Birthday.
Happy Birthday to you.
You frack old con. All right,
I'll talk to you guys on Monday.
Have a good weekend.
You sons of bitches,
eh.
Okay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's still the Monday morning podcast and,
uh, I'm in Raleigh, Durham airport.
I don't know if it's,
I think she had the balls to call
this an international airport.
I'm not sure. I don't think
it's international cause
the lines went that long.
Uh, that's one of the dumbest
things I've ever fucking said.
Let me consider last. And the
lunch went that long. Really?
He didn't see anybody on
a fucking Jeannie rug.
So you don't think that flies
anywhere else? You idiot. All right.
I'm not in a good mood. Why?
Bill? Why aren't you in a
good mood? I'll tell you why.
Because a hair cut them in Raleigh,
North Carolina.
There's no fucking connects.
There's no direct flights to Los Angeles.
So for some fucking reason,
high after God,
The lady with the voice
either hang on a second.
Every five seconds. Yes. Okay. All right.
Okay. Terrific. Phone message.
You don't have a cell phone with
friends who have that number.
Unbelievable.
Pick up a courtesy phone.
It's so fucking stupid.
Everybody has cell phones.
Why would you use that archaic
form in an airport? Okay.
Whatever. Uh, anyways. Yeah.
So I'm in Raleigh at the,
I want to get to La for some fucking
reason. I have to fly to Cleveland first.
And, uh, it's annoying enough
when you have a connecting flight,
but you know, why can't it be in a
city that's at least going in the,
in the direction that I want to go. I'm
going to go fucking West. I want better.
They make me fly north. It's a
little bit west, but you know,
at the end of the day, it's fucking north
going north of the Mason Dixon line,
you know, Mason Dixon Line
just to keep, uh, yeah.
What is that late in the lady's
talking so fucking loud over there.
Why is it, you know, in
society, why can't I just like,
can you just lean over to her right now
and just be like, hey, Hey lady. Hey.
Yeah you do.
Could you shut the fuck up please?
Or at the very least get you talk a
lot quieter because no one gives a fuck
about whatever the fuck it is.
It, you're yelling about it,
but you stupid fucking board meeting.
You know what I mean?
Who the fuck are you talking
to? It's fucking, I guess
it's 10 25 in the morning.
You know what's annoying me?
And she's talking really loud and her
eyebrows are at full fucking mass.
Uh, Jesus. Is there anybody even
listened to these announcements?
I look at this person
by, she's got the, uh,
the p diddy syndrome or the
Shaquille O'neal Syndrome.
You know those, you know
those people. Uh, okay.
It's on a Cosby shirt.
You know those people who fucking,
their mouths are open even when they're
not talking. I call that PDD syndrome.
Is that what you call it? Bell? Yeah.
That is what I call it. All right.
I have a flask of time on
pm that I'm going to be,
I'm going to be taking, but I can't take
it because I have a connecting flight.
So I'm going to stay awake till
I get to Cleveland. By the way,
my flight to Cleveland is delayed,
you know, they said because of wind,
you know what I mean? Really rough wind,
which I don't really understand. You know,
it was like, isn't that how the
fucking plane gets off the ground?
You wait for a gust of wind and you
drive into it, you know? I mean, granted,
I never took a physics class.
I was getting you.
I know you got to know how to
fucking plane gets off the ground,
which is one of the reasons why
have such a fear of flying take.
If I actually understood it,
if anybody listening to this could
actually explain in layman's terms how a
fucking 10 ton piece of metal
with a bunch of people in various forms
of physical convinced condition can get
off the goddamn ground, actually
get out, gets off the ground.
I just don't understand how
it stays off the ground.
Like I can get off the ground, I
can take a running leap, you know,
and for good 0.8 seconds,
I am actually airborne,
but I quickly come crashing down to
the ground and roll my fucking ankle.
You know, it's kind of like a boat to
how the fuck does a boat not sanction.
You know what I mean,
Dave,
you just displace the weight
across the water and spill.
I don't, I don't, you know,
then a bunch of people get on
and then it still doesn't sink.
It just goes down into the water
a little bit more. All right.
I think we've established that Jesus
Christ, look at this guy, he's dressed,
he's got some guy,
he looks like he should be yodeling.
He has on khaki shorts than
about five inches above his knee.
Chancellor of Brown,
low cut suede hiking shoes
with ankle below the ankle.
Black thought he just needs like, I
think, what do you call it? A shaft.
One of those sticks with the,
with the curl on it.
Jesus Christ.
He's probably going to a whorehouse
and just looks like he has some sort of
twisted fetish and wonder what's in
that briefcase. He's drinking coffee,
but he's trying to appear
normal. Um, anyways,
if you're a new to this page,
this is the Monday morning podcast.
I do one of these every single
week I hype upcoming gigs,
I rant about bullshit and people send me
questions and I tried to answer to the
best of my ability and uh,
yeah.
And that's about it.
And I gotta admit my computer is tucked
away in my bag and I don't know what the
fuck the questions for the second,
second week in a row.
You know what it is? I have one of
the, I have one of those g four Max.
I'm at my laptop was about
four years old and uh,
actually have legs on it,
like an old TV and a and an
antenna fucking old. All right.
And uh, the battery evidently
is defective. So, uh,
when I turned it on it, it loses
battery power and about nine seconds,
actually it will say I have 75%
battery power. And then it says, um,
two seconds. I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about. All right,
let's just get to the shit I
have coming up in my career.
I had stand up on the guys' choice awards
for Spike TV and that is going to be
a,
it's going to be airing on June
22nd Sunday night on Spike TV.
Uh, it's actually a pretty big
award show. I was very amazed at the
level of a celebrity that was there.
It's like Harrison Ford, Cameron Diaz,
Jeremy Pivot, you know what
I mean? Spike TV, no offense.
But I thought it was going to be
like Lee Majors and Micky Dolenz uh,
and me, you know, that's what I thought
I was going to be. And then I showed up.
I was like, Holy Shit. You
know, sent Steve Carell's.
Yes, it is. Isn't that amazing?
And uh, I was not sitting
seated at his table. I was uh,
I was seated at a table.
Well I dunno what the fuck one,
one guy was a reality show director and
the rest of them were a seat filling
horse. I think. Um, at
least that's what it said.
And then the name tag.
Um,
so anyways, all right, let's get
to the podcast questions that, uh,
that I can remember. Ah,
fuck with the announcement.
And he retains [inaudible]
fucking airports.
They make you hate.
Have you got the in flight is delayed.
I'm actually looking a
horrific thought I had at the day.
I have the USA Today taper
in front of me and, uh,
one of the pictures they have is of,
uh,
this guy looks like he's in the bowling
Joey. I can describe them all right?
He's got a checkered shirt on with
a t shirt underneath it. And uh,
he's about up to his man tits and water
hanging onto a rubber raft that has
some, uh, coast guard looking guy in it.
He's basically too fat to
get in the fucking boat. Um,
and he's walking along and it said Midwest
storm turns deadly and it says seven
reported after tornadoes and heavy
rain pounds states in the heartland.
So I'm like, wow, that's, you know,
at least I'm not fucking up to
my man tits and a rainwater,
you know, it's probably eels and
fucking water moccasins and shit.
But then there's a part of me because
there's so many goddamn people is a kind
of happy, you know, wash away a few,
let the traffic go down a little bit.
Isn't that a fucking terrible thought?
But I actually,
I actually think that shit
underneath that it says a
FDA's tomato warnings grow.
This is all the happy
news I've looked at today.
Outbreak of Salmon Nela from raw tomatoes
spreads to 16 states with up to 150
people reported ill.
You know,
now a lot of people would look
at that like that's a bad thing.
But I look at it like,
look,
those 150 people fucking die from eating
tomatoes or at the very least get some
horrific cases of diarrhea or they're
not going to get into a car. Uh,
you know, the roads would be a
little bit clearer. You know,
somebody, I guess, uh,
this is all the happy news.
They don't have one fucking happy thing
on the front page. What do we got here?
US gas average $4 and rising and then
they have a cartoon picture of a hand
squeezing a house with money
falling out of the bottom.
You know what the funny thing is is if
they didn't even bring this shit up,
I wouldn't even know it was happening.
Who would know that housing
houses were fucking, uh,
the values dropping? How would you even
know that if they didn't bring it up?
Why don't they just stop talking about
it and we'd all walk around like Happy
Idiots.
We've continued to spend our money in
malls and they won't be a recession.
You know what? That might be the
second dumbest thing I've ever said.
You know something?
I really resent the way fucking pilots
got to dress like they were on the love
boat. You know what I mean? What is that?
What is that awful fucking uniform? Now?
Of course he's going to sit next
to me so I can't make fun of them.
You know what I mean? I hate
like the, the, the, the,
the shoulder pads with the stripes
on them. You know what I mean?
You could if they just came back from
battle as opposed to a round trip to
fucking Seattle, you know
what I mean? I don't know.
There's a golf shops at target,
you know it's going to go
shiny golf shirts on and
most Seinfeld white sneakers.
You know what? There isn't one well
dressed person in Raleigh, Durham airport.
I keep thinking everybody has on a Cosby
share, but it's the same fucking guy.
He just keeps pacing back and forth.
So every time, you know, I look up,
he's on my right and then I
look, looked down, I looked up,
he's on my left and I think
it's a different guy ladies.
Definitely a mother you
got here. What? The little
personal size pizza, mothering,
hips swinging to and fro.
That guy's a psycho. Look
at him. He's got a backpack.
Probably tried to hike the Appalachian
trail. Get fucking Ricketts.
Umm. All right. So, uh, yeah,
the fuck was I talking about?
My girlfriend wants to see Kung Fu panda.
That's what I have to look forward to when
I get back to la. Just want to see it.
God damn cartoon about
some fucking martial arts.
Why would it fucking pen to need to
learn Kung Fu? You know what I mean?
Why would it need,
how to throw kicks when everybody knows
that a bear naturally just has that like
you. Have you ever see like
a watch discovery channel?
My show up bear killing
like a, uh, I don't know.
Fucking Yak, whatever. What the
fuck did they kill an elk or deer?
They don't come up and grab it by
the throat. All right. All messy.
Like all those other predators, they have
the bears come up. They have like that,
that fucking, how do you describe
it? Got fucking bionic bitch slap.
You know what I mean? Just
Bam. Just breaks their neck.
So right there, that's the grizzly bear
proof equivalent of the one inch punch.
We've stopped yelling.
I think she kind of heard me on that.
She's literally looking at me screaming,
can you hear a voice?
She's one of those fucking women.
I hate women who were like 40 years
old and they talk like the eight
probably like guys kill their wives
while they just get sick of their voices.
God, what a stupid fucking
thing to say. You know what?
This is the bills and more on podcast
today. I'm just done a bad fucking roof.
Fucking plane was supposed to take off
at 10 15 and 45 I got some 40 year old
lady with a kid's voice screaming
and then I got the the pie. Oh fuck.
My plane's here, Valerie, that, you know,
it's funny, the plane that I'm flying
from Raleigh Durham International Airport,
Esquire is uh,
actually it looks like the kind of
plane that Tom Cruise flies by himself.
You know, I always get excited when I
see those cause I imagine that, you know,
I'm a fucking rock star and I'm getting
on it by myself as opposed to the fact
that I'm getting onto it with 40 other
people. This is how fucked up Raleigh,
North Carolina is as
far as a airport goes.
The plane,
I actually flew down here from New York
City and I flew down here on I, yeah,
a plane that had propellers.
I'm not even lying to you,
but it was a new plane and I was like,
wow,
this [inaudible] still going with this.
You know what I mean?
And it was one of those,
there was so few people on the flight
that I was sitting in like feet five a and
they go, sorry, excuse
me, excuse me there.
And I'm like, bitch, fucking bitch. What?
Excuse me, bitch. And she's like, sir,
I don't need to listen. I'll get it.
And say that that's what I was thinking.
I just said, I said, uh, I said yes,
but the underlying, the way
I said it was like, what?
And she's like,
I need you to move to the back of the
plane so we can redistribute the weight.
You know what I mean?
And it's like really,
you basically telling me if I don't go
to the back of this plane that it's going
to like what fucking tip over when we go,
when we go to take off.
That makes me feel as a
customer, you know what I mean?
But you know, they don't give
a shit fucking hilarious.
She makes me move back, but she
sits up front, you know what I mean?
And when that stupid little fold
down stewardess chair, it's like,
why don't you sit in the
back? I'm a customer. Okay,
I want to stay here and this lady to
dress like my fourth grade teacher.
Wow.
Black on black pants to Bruce Lee
Kung fu shoes and a shiny pink blouse
underneath it.
I Dunno if she's dressed like my fourth
grade teacher or a Nancy Reagan one or
the other hand.
She did
you dress like a first lady?
Uh,
all right. Wow. Ooh, let's
go with this talking. Oh,
he guides in the points.
That's why shirts so bright.
So I shared so bright and
his mustache is so short.
That girl does not trim her Bush.
You can just tell,
just tell us going all natural.
I don't know what it is about her.
That lady there has an above ground
swimming pool and her husband. Yeah,
we're going that shoulder tattoo.
I fucking nailed it. I know it.
Above ground swimming pool
made stuffed crust pizza
guy there was good at
basketball cause he's in shape.
He's black and he has
dreadlocks right there,
which means he's like the sixth man ever
noticed that the black dudes with the
dreadlocks, they like rebound
guy. You know what I mean?
There's never been a Michael Jordan
style player with dreadlocks,
dreadlocks. And you play
in the NBA. You, uh,
you get like fucking 12
rebounds a game and uh,
knock out 12 old ladies with your fucking
elbow. I don't know what. All right.
I ran out of references
there. Wow. Capri pants,
Khaki Capri pants, they
ago. You're married.
There's no reason to give a fuck anymore.
Why would you dress like that?
Look at this black guy. Hey, go. Huh? He's
still doing with the extra baggy shit.
Wow.
That look was like 10 years ago.
Remember that one black guys would go
to footlocker and they would find those,
uh,
quadruple fucking XLT shirts even
though they were five foot six.
I always thought they look like a,
you know,
like after you bang a broad
over there in the next morning,
now she gets up and put some
money, a tee shirts. Uh,
all right. I'm just making fun of
people, not because I'm like, well,
I am kind of a con,
but I'm just making fun of him because
I don't have my podcast questions in
front of me. So, uh,
why don't we hide some upcoming gigs
and lady looks like Robert Plant from
behind. Oh, it's the same fucking lady.
She's got all kinds of lists going on.
What happened to Robert Plant
Man, Jesus Christ. Like,
I look great right after age 46 and all
of a sudden now he looks like he should
be in like a children's book.
Like, like one of those, uh,
it looks like a troll. I don't know what
a fairy tale. That's what it looks like.
Robert Plant looks like. It
looks like he's in a fairy
tale. You know what I mean?
Is this, this is a cruel thing about
life is even if you stay in shape,
life is still going to make you
look awful because for some reason,
even if you stay at your high
school, wait, your fucking
head never stops growing.
So if you don't get a little out of shape,
if you look fucking ridiculous,
you look like a,
I just lost my train of thought.
The fire stop taking this
time on a pen. No, you're not.
You look like if you, have
you seen that fucking guy? Uh,
he's like 45 years old and he's shredded.
I might have talked about this last
week again with the Mike Epps had, um,
you know that guy late, late at night.
He does all the physical fitness shit.
He's like 46 years,
years old and he's shred it,
but for some reason he still looks weird
and it's his head because his head,
I know it's not the head,
it's your fucking knows it's
your ears or something like that.
Something about your head.
It just keeps getting bigger.
Like classic example is Ted Kennedy.
Okay,
Ted Kennedy's been in the news lately,
has got a fucking brain
tumor or something. Right.
He will get that guy's head
and the 60s for granted,
all those Kennedy's had big heads.
You know what I mean?
It's one of the reasons why two of
them got, got, got assassinated.
It's like there was no way to miss
I, that's just fucking me. It really
is. But I got to tell you something,
man.
I saw Ted Kennedy,
I shook his hand one time and his head
is as big as the seat that I'm sitting
and he has been the biggest
fucking head I've ever, it wasn't,
it was unbelievable. I was just
staring at it. I couldn't fuck.
And I got a big head,
but this guy's fucking head was huge.
And, uh, you probably want to, how
did I meet him? I actually, uh,
I fucking shook his hand and Bill
Clinton's hand, the long fucking story.
Just remind me, I'll tell it to
you next week. Let's stay on track.
You without biggest fucking head is,
I just kept looking.
I just could not believe,
decided like I just want it to like a,
I wish there was a way to just like
hold his head just to see how much it
weighed. You know, I, I'm not even joking.
I bet his head ways like,
like 27 pounds,
27 fucking pounds. When we think about
that, you know who got the less weight,
you know that when you're doing
your warmup set and you grab like,
let's go with 35, the 35
pound plates, you know,
you can do with one hand.
You know what they should have.
They should have like a part
of the strong man competition.
So those little kettle balls there,
they should have like little Kennedy
hats and each one of them gets a,
it's a stupid idea. You know that, that's
why I don't have a fucking show on TV.
All right, let, let's, let's get the,
get the hype and the upcoming Gig. Um,
first of all,
I just was in our Raleigh,
North Carolina at a good
night's comedy club.
I want to thank everybody who came out to
the shows. I had a great time. And, uh,
I got drunk every night down at the bar
downstairs and I watched my Celtics go
up two games to none and a,
I'm not going to lie to you,
I didn't know how much one Celtic
game all year. I fucking hate pro hoop
pro who is the worst?
Like it's just too God damn long.
You Watch college basketball.
It's exciting. The crowd's
into it and it's over.
It seems like it's over in an hour.
Pro Hoop with,
with the fucking files and the timeouts.
And I mean, that's final five minutes,
final five minutes. It takes like
45 minutes to play to the point.
You don't even give a
shit anymore. But, um,
I put to the test to Phil Jackson
for bitching about the files.
You know what I mean? Fucking
baby. I can tell you right now,
if your gamma definitely
bet on the Lakers,
you definitely bet on the Lakers on game
three because they are going to call
9,000 files on the fucking Celtics
because Phil Jackson's a fucking baby.
You know what I mean? Give
me a goddamn break. What?
What about that guy in the Lakers
who stop dribbling at half court?
Ran The west rest of the way and dunk
the ball and they didn't call travel.
And what about that? Okay, you'll get
in calls to, I don't want to hear it.
Um, and also the two, three,
two playoff system is bullshit.
You know what I mean?
You give home court advantage to the
fucking visitor through game five.
It keeps saying the Celtics
have home court. They don't.
The next three games are in la. We get
to spend a fucking weak out there. Me,
I had,
he made tension.
Please would the person
who has the current next to
the deal jail please report
to the fucking front office.
All right.
I'm starting to talk way too
loud with Tourette's. Um,
I dunno man. I thought the Lakers were
going to beat us and like six games.
I thought they were going to crush us.
I'm really impressed Ray Allen
keeps getting his shots. Uh,
we're just going to have to weather the
storm. I think Colby is going to get 30,
40 every game.
And if we can just somehow,
whether that storm, uh, I dunno,
I still think it's going
seven games and uh, I dunno.
It's gonna. It's gonna be
great. It's going to be great.
I just don't watch ESPN any most fucking
jackass. So overhyped everything.
Look at this lady,
Jesus Christ.
She's never committed a crime
in their life and gave my cat,
I go to church every week.
I have a little tote bag.
It's like the egg and I pack the
exact perfect amount of clothes.
I don't swallow. Um, man, I'm
getting crude on these podcasts.
I got to stop with this. Okay. All
right. Well that was a good 25 minutes.
They go visit.
There's a good damn near half hour of us
silliness to get your week started off,
right? Football, you guys
have a, have a great week.
And, uh, you know, something,
you know, just, just be happy.
You don't travel for a living. And
Andy, if you travel for a living, ah,
you know my condolences because
this shit is ridiculous. Um,
but anyways, upcoming gigs,
uh, like I said, Spike TV,
the guy's choice awards,
uh, June 20 seconds.
First Time I ever did award show and uh,
I killed on it.
Hopefully it will come
across that way on TV.
You never know what
happens in post production,
but I was really excited to do that.
And uh,
I'm going to be at the punchline in
Atlanta on Jesus Christ is test my memory.
I think it's June 19th through the 21st.
The date should be right there. Uh,
what else do I got?
I got Pittsburgh coming up and uh,
fuck. What else do I have the
Improv in Miami in August?
That's all I can really remember for
the summer because I'm getting old.
Speaking of which my 40th
birthday is tomorrow and oh,
for the love of
the person who let the,
what we have a bag of
button down near the,
the con coy, Oh, is this me?
This is me. Okay. That boarding my flight.
Thanks for hanging out with
me as I waited for my, uh,
my trip back to La via Cleveland,
flying the fucking Cleveland.
I just wish, I don't know.
I wish I wasn't going to Cleveland.
All right, that's it. Um,
please keep the podcast questions coming.
I'm going to do,
I'm going to answer like 9
million podcasts questions
next week cause I do have
all of them and my fucking,
my old ass laugh,
my laptop is made out of wood. Thank you.
That's how fucking old it is. All right.
I'm getting on the plane. I'm
going to take some more. No,
I can't take Tylenol pm cause I'll sleep
through my fucking connecting flights.
I'm going to take it after I get
a, after I get on the uh, like,
oh you want to get
something fucking hilarious.
I called my dad yesterday and I wished
him a happy father's day and he's like,
son, I love you to death but it's
next Sunday. Get dumb. Fuck. So,
and then he wished me a happy birthday
for tomorrow and I was like, yeah,
well my birthday's on Tuesday. That's
where I get it. You're old dumb fuck.
And that's our relationship.
Uh, a cute family. Little story.
All right. I'm elite access
me and 90 other people here,
so I'm going to get on his fucking,
what are you saying? Okay. All right.
That's it. Thanks for
listening. Uh, please keep the
questions coming and please,
somebody explained to me how
a boat floats and how a plane.
All right.
Thank you.
Oh my God.
I have to tell you the story.
So I'm flying,
so I do what have to sort of close show.
Um,
and always working with Nick Kroll.
You're guaranteed you're going to
laugh your ass off. I'll fucking deck.
Can I kiss the kids ass? I
fucking love him. I think he's,
I think he's a fucking
genius. So anyways, um,
I go,
okay.
I go to the airport and I'm taking
the red eye, taking this 10 55 flight,
nine fucking stop.
Cause that's how I do it.
All right,
I'm on a good plane.
Why would I want to get off it and switch
and roll the dice and get on another
one.
Okay.
You know, let's just
fucking get there. When it,
when I drive up to San Francisco,
I don't pull over and fucking, uh,
Burbank and then get hit one another
cup. We get it bill. All right.
Okay.
So I get on the fucking
plane, right? I use my miles,
bump myself up like a fancy
person. You know, maybe,
maybe I invented the cheesecake factory.
People are thinking and then they
see how I'm dressed and I go, oh no,
he didn't invent the cheese cake factory.
Um,
and I go to go to sit down on my seat
and I go to set my bag down and I was
going to set it down right in front of
me and the Nice fellas sit next to me
cause why don't you stick
it in the middle, this room?
And he moved his bag out of
the way. I'm like, all right,
this guy's a solid dude or whatever.
And then all of a sudden the waitress
by a stewardess, whatever, she comes by,
flight attendant, whatever the
fuck you supposed to call them,
she comes up and she, uh, can I get you
gentlemen and Drake? And I was like, yeah,
I can, I get a, let me get a
water please. Ice or no ice. What?
However you make it.
Stop acting like it's a fucking
Martini. It's war, right?
Just give me a water
with ice. Thank you. Um,
and the, the guy next to me, he orders
it doers. Neat. No, I, no nothing.
Just put it in there. So they bring our
drinks. All right. And I'm really thirsty.
So I start sucking mine down
and he just throws his back.
Like it's nothing like fucking John Wayne
right before he's going to turn around
and beat up three guys, three
mustachioed guys in the 1930s. Right?
So, um, I'm just sitting
there and everybody's getting
on the flight, you know,
and I'm looking around at the passengers,
you know,
fucking doing whatever I'm doing and
all of a sudden the guy next to me,
Mr doers goes to me. Uh, he
goes, excuse me? He goes,
are you afraid to fly? And I
looked at him, I was like, what?
He goes, are you afraid
to fly? And I go, no,
no, I'm not. And he goes, he goes, all
right, but you know, it's, he goes,
it's okay. It's okay to tell
me if you're afraid to fly.
Okay.
And it's immediately getting weird. And
I'm like, no, I'm not afraid to fly.
And, and I'm thinking in my
head, wait, is he afraid to fly?
And that's why he's drinking
the way he just drank.
And now he's hoping that I'm going
to be afraid to fly. So he, you know,
he just wants to open up. That's what
I'm thinking. And I got, I'm like, yeah,
no,
I'm not afraid to fly.
Yeah.
And he won't leave it alone. He goes, all
right, cause you know, you're, you're,
you're fidgeting,
you're looking around at other passengers.
Okay.
And I'm sitting there looking at it like,
is this guy fucking serious? And I go,
no. I go, I'm not afraid to fly.
So now I'm like, fuck this guy.
I'm not talking this guy for the rest
of the flight. This guy's weird man.
It's like a 30.
Just get paint the pictures like
32 year old winery in shape,
but like,
why are we white dude,
he's got a skully cap on
with fucking glasses. Um,
you know,
and uh,
okay.
He goes,
uh,
like there's like a minute of silence
and people still getting on the plane and
then he goes, hey, sorry
about that. So we, we just,
we just got off on the wrong foot. He's
like, my name's So-and-so. He goes,
what's your name? And then I'm thinking
in my head like, what's my name?
My name's frank.
I wanted to give them like a f by just
some reason I just wanted it's bill.
And he goes, oh, hey bill
Nico's nice to meet you.
So we shake hands and I'm just looking at,
I don't have any poker face.
I'm looking at the guy like,
what the fuck is your problem?
I'm not even trying to not,
I'm not trying to be pleasant.
I'm already done with this guy. So then
the guy goes, oh, hey bill. He goes,
why are you going to Indianapolis Bill?
Right.
Like he's fucking interrogating me and I,
okay.
I'm like,
is this gonna fucking serious?
And I start doing the
math in my head going,
when is this guy like an air marshal or
something? And I'm like, no he's not.
He's fucking slamming bows over here.
Fuck this guy.
So I just go, I go, look, I don't, I
don't have to answer your questions.
That's it. And I just look
straight forward. He goes, okay,
now I'm concerned. Okay, I am
concerned and I'm looking at,
I'm like concerned about what he
goes, you're fidgeting your, you, you,
you have issues with other
passengers and blah blah blah blah.
He's such a Peyton like, like this. Like
he's been, I don't know what the fuck,
like psychologically breaking me down.
All right, so now at this, by this point,
they've closed the fucking the door to
the fuselage and we're starting to taxi.
Okay.
And I just finally look
at the guy and I go,
okay,
I go, you know, I came up
with the five one point.
I literally stick my hand out cause he
kept saying I was nervous and I stick my
hand right in front of his
face and I hold it level.
Well that's what I did the
first time. Yeah. I hold it
level. I go, I'm not nervous.
And he goes, well, anybody can do that.
And that's when I was like, fuck this guy.
I'm not talking to the guy. Sorry. Fuck
this story up. Then Denny Denny came back,
got my name. Now he's going, why are
you going to Indianapolis? And I find,
look at them. I say, listen pal, I'm
drinking waters. You're drinking doers.
Okay, there's no issue over here.
And then he goes, it wasn't doers.
What she gave me wasn't doers really.
What was it? Some sort of spy juice.
You fucking jerk off this point.
I want to punch him right through his
fucking stupid wirey glasses. Right?
So he's going like,
you look around hostels and I said
something that just ticked him off.
I was just you that dude I got, I don't
have to answer your questions. All right,
leave me alone. And then he
goes, uh, he goes to, he goes,
he starts going like, okay,
now I am really concerned right now. He
goes, why are you going to Indianapolis?
And I just look at him.
You know what I start doing?
I start doing like this Ryan Gosling,
you know that little smirk that fucking
Mona Lisa smile he has is his smarts his
way through all this fucking movies.
I do go. I go full on Ryan Gosling.
Now I'm not talking to this guy and I
just keep looking at him and I give them
that little half was smart and I
just shake my head. That's my game.
Now that's,
this is Mike.
It's like if you're going to be a Dick
Right now with your fucking delusional
authority, right? That
you're going to like,
we're in fucking Guantanamo and you've got
to waterboard me. Ah, there's no water.
There's no board. Go Fuck
Yourself. Here's my smart,
and I'm just going to shake my head at
you like you're a fucking pathetic human
being. This is what I'm doing, right? And
this is the funny thing. I'm such a Dick.
All I have to say to the guys,
I'm a comedian,
I'm going to do a sold out show there
and that would make them back off,
but I'm a dick. I'm like, fuck this
guy. I want to see where this is going.
So now he's all fucking amped
up and he starts droppingF ,
you know she's saying the
f word. He sitting there
going, if you don't, he goes,
you don't fucking answer
my question right fucking.
Now I'm going to hit that
call button was sitting there,
taxi and down the fucking getting in line,
I'm going to fucking hit this fucking
button if you blah blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I'm just fucking Mona Lisa.
Smile smirk in just shaking my head
like you are a fucking retard, right?
So now he sees saying the f word so much.
The lady who's sitting in
front of me diagonally in
front, right in front of him,
turns around and looks at us, and
now my heart's racing. I'm like,
where's this going?
This is going to be great.
I am a hundred percent fucking innocent.
This guy's drunk,
and I think he's going to hit that button.
He's going to hit that button.
What's going to happen? Right? I want
to see what the pilot looks like.
Let's see where the fuck this is going,
right? So he goes, you'll fuck you.
He starts eating such bringing
his hand up to the button going,
I'm going to hit that button.
You don't have to go fucking do it.
I'll hit that button and I'm sitting there
smirking and I'm thinking in my head,
go ahead and hit the fucking button.
Let's see what happens.
Let's see what happens. Right? So finally,
now he wants to hit the button
and he can't fucking find it,
and it's an in defense of him. I couldn't
find it either. I was looking up there,
I half wanted to hit it myself.
Then he finally,
he finally finds it and he hits it right?
And now I'm just like,
Holy Shit, what's going to happen? And
he's sitting there going, yeah, Huh,
you want to fucking play this game and
you want to fucking play this game?
And I was surprised.
I mean it took like fucking like 30
seconds before a flight attendant,
the one who gave him the booze,
which evidently wasn't booze comes over.
And at this point we're like doing
that shit where we're behind the plane,
we're almost ready to take off,
like we're pulling up and
then stop and pull it up and,
and stopping as planes are
taking off. So she goes, yeah,
what's the problem over
here? And he goes, ah,
I'm not comfortable to fly with
this guy. This guy, he's fidgeting,
he's looking around at other fucking
people, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
He's doing all this thing right?
And then the stewardess looks at me and
I'm just sitting there fucking my little
smart,
just shaking my head and I just looking
at this dude just shaking my head like,
this guy's out of his fucking mind.
I don't say a word,
and this guy goes on and on and on about
his fucking psycho babble about how I'm
the security risk.
So she goes to, so she goes, okay. Um,
any other passengers?
Have you noticed anything?
She's talking to everybody first class.
This
is,
anybody noticed anything odd about this
guy and the lady who was sitting right
in front of the dude diagonally from
me turns around. She goes, yeah,
I've been listening to this guy,
bright berating this other passenger.
She's on my side and I haven't
said a fucking word. This is great.
And I'm just sitting there smirking.
Then they'll let students looks at
me and I shrugged my shoulders like,
I don't know what to tell you.
It's a finally she said, sir,
do you have anything to add to
this? And I just said, look,
I'm just a guy trying to go to
Indianapolis. This guy over here,
he starts slamming his doors. I kind
of felt like a rat when I said that.
I go slamming his doors. Next thing you
know, he's dropping the F bomb to me.
Then I'm thinking, oh fuck. I just
said bomb, right? Fortunately,
nothing happens. So now another fucking
the male stewardess comes over right now,
he's going like,
what's going on?
And the captain of the fucking now at
this point we've pulled over in the plane,
has stopped.
Okay.
250 people trying to get to Indianapolis
and jerk off over here who can hold
this fucking alcohol who just
watched a person of interest every,
every August. Evidently I have no
fucking idea. Now the plane is stopped,
is fucking jerk off,
has stopped the plane
interrogating a Goddamn comedian.
Like I'm in the fucking Taliban and
like he works for the CIA, right?
So now we're just sitting there
and the captain is up front in the plane,
like saying to the stewards
is going basically relaying,
do I really have to
fucking come back there?
This is the last flight of the night.
Is it really a God damn problem?
And that was the vibe. And they finally
said to the doe, sit next to me,
are you going to be okay to fly with him?
And at that point it appeased his fucking
ego that he was somehow in control.
And he goes like, you know what? Okay,
it's fine. It's fine. It'll be fine.
It'll be fine.
Yeah.
So they go, okay. So now the plane's
going again and now we're now,
we fucking come around and
he's sitting there fucking,
he's in my ear and at this point I
am la like to fucking laugh. He him,
me doing the podcast, that's what I'm
doing. And he's sitting there going, I,
he goes, you know what? I'm glad.
I'm glad. I hope you fucking do.
I hope you fucking try something. I'll be
fucking try something. One more update.
I really hope you fucking try something.
And I'm just fucking like gut bust
and laughing, shaking it. Like,
what are you going to fucking do to me?
What are you gonna do to me?
How are you going to punch me in the face?
You fucking winery jackass.
You get fucking glasses on. You
know, that's a federal offense.
You're going to go to jail if you do
that or something. I Dunno what, right.
So I'm just in a fucking laughing
at the guy going, I actually,
at one point I put my fucking
little I pill thing on. Do you know,
like I'm going to sleep.
Oh, I had that out too.
When the stewardess was talking to me.
I was like,
putting it on is this total mind fuck.
Like I don't know what this guy is.
I'm just trying to go to Indianapolis.
I'm going to sleep. And um, so I got,
I got my fucking eye thing on, right
as he's sitting there threatening me,
just I was going with total passive
aggressive. It's like, dude,
I'm so not concerned with
you. I'm literally putting
a blindfold on. All right,
so this fucking guy, he
starts going, he goes, yeah.
He goes, you think you're fucking one
this, you fucking won this. He goes, my,
you know, my dad is my dad.
He started saying his dad,
some major CEO in Indianapolis, doesn't
sound like a fucking made up story.
I swear to God, this is
all true. He Goes, Mike,
my dad is such a major CEO in Indianapolis
and I'll have you fucking arrested.
And The lady turns around again.
How have you fucking rested the
second weekend on the ground?
I'm thinking like for what?
For what?
Okay,
sitting here, you fucking loser.
Learn how to hold your alcohol. Right.
And he starts describing the view that
I'm going to have when I go to jail,
like some fucking law and order
episode. Oh, you're going to love it.
You'll be able to see Lucas oil
field in battered by the bar.
And I'm just sitting there cracking up
laughing and then there's this pause,
right? And I'm thinking finally he finally
shut the fuck up. It's like a three,
four minute pause. He finally just gave
up because I wasn't giving them anything.
I was just laughing and shaking my head.
I was being a dick to him.
I was cause I was enjoying it.
And then there was like a three minute
pause and then all of a sudden he just
goes,
why are you going to Indianapolis Bill?
So we're like 20 minutes into the flight
and am I going to be honest? He's,
my adrenaline was so going during all
of that because I knew I didn't do
anything wrong,
but I thought we were literally going
to go back and there was going to be
fucking cops there. And
if like, if, if, if,
if the fucking stewardess or the pilot
asked me who I am and where I'm going,
I'm going to tell him I respect your
authority. You're just some, Gee, I don't,
you don't have any fucking authority.
I don't have to answer your questions.
It was pro was one of the most
fun experiences I've ever
had with another human being.
Like when somebody thinks that they
have power and you know, they don't,
and all they can do is try just keep
bluffing and raising their voice and start
cursing at you.
And if you just start laughing at them,
the look on their face
is fucking priceless.
So
blessing. He said, he said, why are
you going to Indianapolis Bill? Right.
And I fucking started howling,
just fucking holding my stomach,
shaking my head
and with my fucking eye
pillow thing on right.
And I know I'm going to get a ton of
shit that I wear one of those eye,
they're fucking underrated.
Get the one at Brookstone where it's
literally a pillow. I'm telling you,
you could fall asleep 12 noon
facing the sun. It's awesome.
So anyways, like after he
asked me what, what, you know,
where are you going bill? You're
like, there was like a 10 minute,
like probably 10 minutes had gone by and
I can't fucking sleep because it's so
fun. And to me I can't wait to
tell the story. Every comic I know,
I can't wait to try it on stage to
see if it's funny or whatever. Uh,
so finally I just like our fucking,
maybe I'll just get on my computer and I
bring up my pillow and I like,
I got to look at the guy cause I
know he's fucking staring at me,
waiting for me to do something right.
So I lifted up,
I get my fucking Lisa smile going
and I look over at the guy and dude,
he is fucking passed out.
He looked like he got shot.
He was sitting there like his head was
just hanging straight down and anytime
the plane move like his head was,
I mean he looked like he got knocked
out for the rest of the fucking flight.
All fucking uh oh. What's Matt
Damon's character? Jack Ryan.
Hold fucking Jack Ryan over here.
It's just, you know the sky marshal,
the fucking bows bag and God
knows what else he was on.
He was just completely out passed out
for the rest of the fucking flight.
And this is why I want you to dick. I am.
I was having so much fun with this guy.
I start,
I can't sleep.
So I start slamming waters because I want
to have to get up and take a piss just
to see if this guy's going to freak out
because this security risk is getting up
and this is, the joke was on me.
He never regained consciousness.
And then I really had to take a Piss,
but I'm such a stubborn fuck.
I was holding it because I wanted to
make sure he was awake when I got up,
cause I was going to give him a little
smirk and then I was going to get out to
see he hit the call button
again. Um, but he did,
he didn't wake up till
we hit the ground and um,
and then it's funny, then he woke
up and it was like four hours later.
So now he had kind of slept off,
whatever the fuck this guy was on. Okay.
And I'm sitting there SmartQ and
wait for the guy to start talking.
I mean he won't look at me and I,
and I think at that point
he kind of fucking realize
that maybe he got a little,
uh,
a little extra little too patriotic.
So we stop,
we stopped at the gate and
everything and we're going to get up.
So I grabbed my shit.
I get up and I'm just kinda looking
at him and he won't look at me.
And then the lady who was
sitting in front of me,
I had this big smile on her face. She
goes, hi. She goes, how are you doing?
I don't want it good. I go, there
I go. That was an interesting one.
And I said it really loud. So the
guy heard and he didn't say anything,
and this is what he did
to try to save face.
His pillow was kind of stuck behind this
kind of stuck behind his shoulder and
like a weird place.
So he was frustrated with it.
So he ripped it out from behind him and
kind of threw it down on the floor when
he tried to do some caveman grunt to try
to still have some sort of, yeah. Uh,
I don't know what, so, so that was
my flight to Indianapolis people.
Um, you know what, how, how far into the
fucking podcast down here. It was a long,
that was a long fucking story.
Yeah.
Okay.
I
will.