Hey, what's going on is Phil Burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
Just checking in on you. Just
checking in, seeing how you're doing,
seeing how your week's going.
Right out of the break out of the gate.
I got to plug something from my best
friend in the world. Paul Versey,
the pride of Trenton,
New Jersey.
Oh, the the fucking tulip in
the garden at the garden state.
Paul Versey.
It's going to be playing the Gotham
Comedy Club in New York City this Friday,
eight and 10:00 PM shows and this
Saturday eight and 10:00 PM shows.
That's August 10th and August 11th best
friend in the world with the best club
owners in the business. The
[inaudible], the [inaudible] brothers,
straight shooters.
My whole career,
they always gave it to me straight
right from the very beginning. Bill,
you're not funny. Find
another career. Okay.
Stop bugging us for spots.
Always was straight shooters.
MMM.
You know, it's funny, he's actually
in Scarface. They actually,
that the first pass or that
first cut of that movie, uh,
he actually said the fuzzily brothers.
Hey,
fucked a fucking miss. Ellie brothers,
right. And then they're like, Nah,
it's got a sound.
It's got a soul sound more Latino.
And it was a bunch of white guys
standing around and they were like a ds.
[inaudible] hey, it's still it.
It's fucking throw that in there.
Um, speaking of things Latin that
white people don't understand, uh,
what the fuck is going
on over at Taco Bell?
Okay.
Can somebody explain to me how in such
a sensitive day and age where people are
just,
you know,
having to apologize and over any little
fucking thing how they advertise on TV,
that they're bastardized version
of Latin, Latin? Probably the,
fuck you supposed to say it.
Latino cuisine. What is God?
What is that fucking incest you with?
Shit that they keep,
but every time you think they can't
get us one of their sandwiches,
the fuck another sandwich should make a
new sandwich. They somehow do it. They,
they, they'll fucking than pay first.
They just had tacos. They had Burritos,
they had case studies,
which I don't even know if case of d
is that they even have those in Mexico.
I don't know.
I'm just a white guy who grew up in
white schools listening to white history.
Right.
They never took my entire time at school.
They never,
they didn't even bring up Mexico,
I think it was the Spanish American war.
They would bring up.
We thought it was in fucking Mexico
and evidently was in the South Pacific.
We didn't fucking know all, they'd all I
history every year started the same day.
It started with the fucking pilgrims
coming over on the May slow up
the Nina, the Pinta, the Santa Maria, and
I don't know who was made flower. Was,
was that the,
the fucking Pete Best of the ships
there or was that the Diana Ross?
I have no fucking idea. All right.
And then there was that other guy, uh,
Jones or some shit. He's settled
down there and, uh, Virginia,
if I remember correctly, he
settled down to Virginia. Right.
The fuck is going on with my mix it here,
I don't know.
And he started banging that, a
native American check, right.
He got a fucking Mohawk, got some
moccasins, started using a bone arrow,
and then they suddenly stay, stay, stay.
Tried to say that the native
Americans killed them.
Right?
I guess cause they didn't like a bang
one of their women. But you know,
I bet I actually think it
might've been the white people.
They came over and they thought he was
a sell out. They're like, hey dude,
how come you don't have about
buckle on your hat?
You know,
how come your gun isn't flaring
out like Elmer Fudds at the end?
You know,
why is your girlfriend got such
a wonderful, beautiful tan there?
And then they took them out and then
he blamed it on the native Americans.
And then they said that,
you know,
they were standing their
ground and they wiped them out.
And then afterwards they
all moved to Florida
and they fucked each other. Incestuously
just like the food at Taco Bell.
And that's why you now to this day you
have to stand your ground fucking bro.
You know, I finally saw the footage of
that latest stand your ground thing. I,
I just, I don't fucking understand
how anybody can't say that.
That's just fucking murder.
Second Degree fucking murder.
But I, I, you know, you watched this
guy will get acquitted. Two things.
I'm always wrong on the stand.
Your ground footage and,
and the,
did he or did he not make a football move?
I never get those. Right. I'm like,
that's a fucking touchdown there.
After further up the hill,
you know,
that's murder after further ideal.
Yeah.
The white guy was,
was
clearly felt threatened as
the black guy was walking away
through this latest one. Right? This,
this, this guy, right? Black Dude.
What is his wife or girlfriend? I think
there was a kid in the car. Not sure.
Right. They pull in the park in a
handicap spot. So the white dude,
like the pussy that he is weights to,
the guy goes in the store and then starts
yelling at this guy's girlfriend or
wife. The guy comes walking out,
the guy's yelling at his wife.
So he goes over and he pushes him down
like a big brother sticking up for his
little sister.
He pushed him down like they're on the
playground and this fucking asshole
pulls out a gun.
Like this guy standing over him with an
ax or something and the guy literally
starts to turn to walk away and he sees
him take out the gun and he turns and
looks back at him like, what the fuck?
And the guy shoots him in cold blood
Coldplay.
I guarantee you he's going to get off.
He will get off fucking unreal.
It's unreal.
But that's what happens.
That's what happens when you
have a bunch of people fucking,
you know,
in the same puddle the way that they're
doing with the food over there and Taco
Bell.
How do they get away with it?
All this shit about appropriating
culture and everything and they just,
they just, I don't know. I
think they've just gone so fuck.
It's like the island of Doctor
Moreau meets Mexican food.
It's kind of like Hanna Barbera too,
where they just,
they only had like two or three ideas
that somehow they spun it into like 40
different cartoons. All right.
We got an idea for a cartoon.
You ever seen the honeymooners? Yeah.
It's that acceptance in the stone age.
It's called the Flintstones.
Oh, we love it. We love it.
You got any more ideas?
Yeah.
You know the honeymooners that we
stuck in the stone age and it was the
Flintstones now would stick it in the
future. It's called the Jetsons. Oh yeah.
You got any more shows I
had. It's a fucking, uh,
is a bear.
I Dunno.
Then this one is, was a lying there. All
the animals. This one's a fucking, hey,
there's always going to be one tall,
one on one short one.
I think the high watermark
was jinxed the cat.
All right.
Um,
I like chunks of cash. He was, he was
real. He was, she was fucking cool. Yeah.
Like a,
what'd she scram Outta here?
I'm sorry. I literally doing a jinx.
The cat impression. Well, what do you,
what do you want from me? Huh?
What do you want from me up?
Just a white guy, man. All the
doors swing wide open for me. Um,
I watched an episode of Max the other day.
I'm loving me TV.
I'm loving it.
You know,
it's just TV shows. There's
commercials, there's a schedule.
It's how I used to watch TV.
Okay. There's, there's auto shape,
old white guys chasing
down people half their age,
rolling over hoods of
cars. It's just like, yeah,
there's a live band that played the
soundtrack. I mean, it's just, it's,
I'm doing, what I shouldn't
be doing right now is I'm,
I'm turning the wagon around and I'm
going back to where I fucking was and I
will quickly become irrelevant, but
I, I can't, I can't lay off me TV.
I watched this episode of Mannix,
right?
He drives a dodge dart,
like the fucking
gt version of some shit.
I never even heard of that car.
You always had to have the cool car,
right? He's a loner. He's not married,
they're always loaners.
Zoe's not married that way they can
get laid in every fucking, every shelf.
Okay.
Told this. The show is just totally
designed for unhappily married guys,
right? Like, why did I get married?
I should've stayed single
it fucking solve crime.
Driving around in a cool car and just
fucking banging somebody different 34
times a year. That's basically
how many episodes they did. Right?
So I'm watching Mannix and this episode,
well,
this hit hitman in a fucking phone
booth and he's talking about a murder.
He just committed and this
woman's staring at him.
Then she starts staring at his
lips and shit. Right? And I'm like,
what the fuck is this? Right? It turns
out she's deaf. What? She's deaf, sorry.
Easy joke. Um, so she knows what's up.
So they go to the cops. The cops don't
let, what's the guy look like? What?
Get out of here. You Deaf Lady, right?
They don't listen to her, but man,
x happens to be walking by.
He's a private,
I don't know what he's
doing down at the fucking
at the police station. Maybe he's
down there fucking, you know,
trying to get some work, you know, get a
couple of fucking free donuts and coffee.
I don't know why he's down there,
but he was down there.
He was fucking down there.
Right.
So,
um,
he just, what he sees them yelling to
the chick and he's just like, hey man,
you know, uh, that's an interesting story.
I think I can help you out with that.
You know,
cause she was like so surprised that she
sought you so upset she couldn't really
give them any details.
So many x because he's Mannix because
he's a loner because he has no woman in
his life that he has to answer to.
He actually has the fucking time spur
of the moment to take on this fucking
case.
Right.
And what's funny is I just like,
who the fuck was paying him the whole
episode? He did, he did the, he did it.
Was it pro bono? Was that free?
Is that the right to expression d?
Okay,
you don't, they will go down to report a
fucking crime. They weren't saying, Hey,
help solve this fucking crime.
He takes it on.
So they cut to the next scene and
he's still, the deaf woman is,
is freaking out because Manix
is yelling at her, go, come on.
You've got to remember, we've got to
look through this again. Right. And,
and her friend is going, Jesus
Christ, dude, take it easy. He goes,
it's a woman's life at stake.
And the deaf lady,
she's fucking hold her head and shit.
He basically just verbally abuses or
until she can fucking remember what this
guy looks like at a inch.
It kind of goes from there.
And I dunno,
I don't even want,
I'm talking about the shit. I'm
just saying, you got to watch me TV.
It's fucking tremendous. It's fucking
Fermentis especially, you know,
you go on all these other shows and it's
like 2018 and then you just turn the
fucking channel and it goes back.
Then I swear to God,
the way they treated women back then,
the parts that they gave them,
the way that they talk to
them, their idea, like,
like the women would walk in and
they will nothing but sex objects.
Every fucking woman right comes in and
they just start playing a saxophone.
Trying to think what they play for.
The deaf woman probably played
like a muted trumpet or something,
but still they played it in a sexy way.
Um,
I don't know what I'm talking.
Well, how about those Red Sox,
MP Buddy dropping 20 runs,
10 a night on the Toronto Blue Jays.
Like Getty Lee.
You liking that shit? Huh?
I'll never forgive that guy.
I remember reading an interview when
he was at a blue jays game and he was
fucking make it fun. Are Red Sox
fans? They were up there, you know,
I'll never forget that. I was
just like, oh, okay. Getty.
That's how you want to play it.
Huh?
With your fucking 12 string bass guitar
and your songs about space or whatever
the fuck you talking about up there.
MMM.
Honestly I have legit
like a sports dislike.
Not An, I'm not an not an honest dislike,
you know? But if I ever met the guy,
I would definitely bring
it up. Um, because I am a,
I'm childless anyways.
Red Sox keep winning.
Yankee suggest one to,
you know,
all the Yankee fans had their
fucking head in the oven.
Then all of a sudden what happens
to get a new picture? He goes up,
he strikes fucking everybody out and
then the next night you're the guy you
bought from the fucking Marlin's
was opposite field for a grand slam.
You know,
I was checking out our fucking
schedule, man. I can't wait.
I cannot wait for that
fucking astro series.
I can't believe how excited I am about
baseball. I don't know what happened.
I had given up on the,
I know it happened,
all the fucking steroids I gave
up on it. I was just like, look,
either legalize them or
get them out of the game.
Stop having me get excited for shit that
you're going to then tell me a fucking
five years later that
it didn't really count,
you know?
Um,
anyway, so excited state Indian series.
Oh, I can't wait. I can't wait. And then,
and to sit here and be this far ahead
of the Yankees knowing that it means
absolutely nothing because
of the wild card is just,
it's just such a wonderful feeling,
you know,
knowing that you're counting
down days that mean nothing.
What's your magic number?
Uh,
17 more games plus four
games in the playoffs.
They ruin it. Fucking
greedy. Cons ruined it.
MMM.
You know, back in the day, I've told
you this before, back in the day,
if you had the best record in the American
league that was winning the pennant,
there was no playoffs to win the pennant.
It was the regular season.
And then you immediately
went to the world series.
So what you had to do was you
had had the best record and they,
and all they had was like, there wasn't
division. So it was just, you know,
like eight teams in this division,
eight teams in that division or what and,
and that, uh, sorry, not
division. Um, in that league,
like eight teams in the American League,
eight teams in the National League and
whoever the top guys were at the end of
the season, you, you won the pennant
and you went to the world series.
So that's why like,
no one's ever gonna win the way the
Yankees won way back then. First of all,
there's no way you're gonna,
you're gonna fucking,
someone's going to be dumb enough to sell.
You're babe Ruth then.
Then you're going to draft Lou Gehrig,
Mickey Mantle,
a Joe Dimaggio writing a fucking row.
Um,
and then you go to the playoffs.
You only have to win four games
and you got the fucking title.
You know what I mean?
But it,
but I'm not just shitting on the Yankees
cause I know like, uh, back in the day,
um,
in hockey,
all he had to do was you had to win eight.
You had went to playoff series.
Now you have to win twice as many unsure
when the Celtics are winning all of
theirs.
I can't imagine you had to play any
more than one or two rounds of 'em
Oh uh, playoffs. Playoffs. That's
actually interesting. Let me see.
Nine team,
50 ml,
be steady things,
the standings, this standings. All right,
so here it was all right. 1950.
There was one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight. Just like a guest.
All right. The Yankees, of
course one that won the pennant,
one had the best record, won the
pennant. Tigers were three games back.
Red Sox were for the Indians were six.
And that's the top four.
And then the bottom for this works out
mathematically cause you didn't have
inner league play.
The twins were 31 games out.
The white sox were 38.
The Orioles were 40.
And the probably Philadelphia
athletics at that time.
We're uh,
46 games up. If not, maybe they weren't
Kansas City at that point, and then,
and the national league,
the Phillies were in first place,
then the Dodgers, then the giants,
then the Braves, cardinals, the reds,
the cubs and the pirates.
That's it.
So then the Phillies in the Yankees played
for the world series and we all know
fucking one that right.
All right, let's go.
NBA stand day eggs,
the IBA standings.
Okay.
All right.
What do we got here?
Yeah,
there was,
there was, there was, they call them
divisions. There was western divisions.
There was 19.
So the Lakers,
well they Minneapolis, then I think
now they, they moved to la by that.
Then there was the kings who
I believe back then were the,
the
Rochester royals
that became the Cincinnati royals
and then they became the Sacramento Kings,
I think.
What are the royals become? The San Diego
Clippers that became the La Clippers.
I always forget that. Anyways, the Detroit
Pistons, Atlanta Hops, St Louis Hawks,
sorry.
They might've been in Atlanta at that
point. And then the Washington Wizards,
which really looked bullets. That's weird.
They were on that long. I had no idea.
And then in the eastern division,
it was the Celtics,
uh,
the San Francisco Warriors,
the 70 sixers in the Knicks,
31 games out.
MMM.
Yeah. So that's it. So you just, yeah,
I guess you just won and then you play
four games to see who was the champion
stuff. That's something that people don't
fucking bring up a lot. They always go,
oh, there's a bunch of fucking white
guys from the YMC a fair enough.
Fair enough. But also you didn't have to
win 20 rounds of the fucking playoffs.
And the only reason why they
have all these rounds now is, uh,
well mostly for money. But
you know, in all fairness,
when there's only nine fucking teams,
I mean,
do you really need to also make
the playoffs if you came in second?
MMM.
I know they just kind of made a lot of
the regular season null and void and a
lot of these sports, why am I not getting
any fucking volume here? I just seen it.
I hope this isn't too quiet again.
Okay.
You know, I think I'm gonna have
to break down and actually get it.
God didn't produce on this fucking thing,
you know, and then what do I do then?
What I do and I got somebody
else I got to fucking talk to.
That's not what I want to do. Um,
all right, let's, let's back up here.
All right, let's read a little advertising
hymns. Everybody. Here's a problem.
66% of men lose their hair by age 35.
Hey man,
that's offensive
thing is when you start to
notice hair loss, it's too late.
Uh, well shit, where the fuck
was that when I needed it? Easy.
It's easier to keep the hair you have
then to replace the hair you've lost.
Is that hairline slowly starting
to move backward, backwards.
Any bald spots yet?
How will you feel a year from now
if it's business as usual up there?
Why do you guys turn to weird solutions
or do nothing when they can turn to a
medicine and science?
You know, I'm really,
what do you mean weird solutions?
Like what?
Just fucking aging naturally shaving
your head and all of a sudden everybody
thinks you know Jujitsu or possibly you
have a fatal disease, right? Either way,
you know people are clearing a path.
What hymns does is connect you with real
doctors and medical grade solutions to
treat hair loss,
well known generic equivalents to name
brand prescriptions to help you keep your
hair. No snake oil pills or gas
station counters. Supplements,
prescription solutions backed by science.
No waiting room,
no awkward doctor visits.
Save hours by going to four hymns for
h I m s for him.com answer a few quick
questions.
Doctor will review and
prescribe you products or
shipping or shipped directly to
your doctor.
I always feel like those guys when they
ask questions about hair loss is the
first thing that has how
much hair is on your back
so they can guess how quickly
you're going to lose your hair.
Cause those hairy mother fuckers,
they lose it.
Like you know those kids who can grow
a beard and like fucking junior high.
The second puberty's ended.
All of a sudden,
you know, they start looking
like, like, I dunno, I dunno.
Fix somebody picked somebody
that Bill Murray or something.
All right,
order.
Now my listeners get a trial month
of him of hymns for just $5 today.
Right now while supplies last.
See websites for full details.
This would cost hundreds if you
went to the doctor or the pharmacy.
Go to Hims [inaudible] dot
com slash bird that's for Hii,
ms.com/burr for hymns.com/burr for him,
[inaudible] dot com slash Berg all right,
what's your box?
And I fucked up when I say that
you get free, big and full life.
You get free bacon. The first
time that was a, there was a typo.
That wasn't my fault. Somebody
fucked that up. All right.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and heritage bread.
Pork,
the greatest pork chop I've ever had.
The incredible quality of butcher box
meets starts with the commitment to
raising animals humanely and
free of antibiotics and hormones.
Each box comes with at least nine to 11
pounds of meat with which is enough for
24 individual sizes unless you're a
fat bastard. Then you got three meals.
You can choose from five different
box types. All beef, beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed box.
Custom box lets you choose your own cuts.
All right,
so the conservative guy is
going to get all beef right?
The liberal out here in Hollywood
is going to get a mixed box.
Antibiotic Slash Hormone Free Books.
Your box believes in hell I healthier
food system where everyone has access to
meets the way nature intended,
free of antibiotics and hormones and
humanely raised on an open pasture before
they kill him.
Selection,
butcher box carefully cure rates
the finest selection and cuts.
It makes it a breeze to
customize your own delivery.
Build your own box to get exactly
what you and your family love.
Choose your delivery frequency with the
customizable subscription with a cost.
With the customizable subscription,
sorry.
Recipes are available on the butcher box.
Websites and videos are
available to follow along on
butcher box youtube channel
to receive free bacon for the,
with the first order
plus $10 off your order.
Go to butcher box.com.
Click on the big bacon banner
on the homepage and use burpee.
You are are at checkout.
Go now.
Limited time off of Oh
Postmates everybody.
Postmates,
Postmates when you want food but
don't want to get up your Ras.
There's Postmates, they're
eating your fries. Um, as usual,
your stomach and the rest of your
life are at war. You need to eat,
but you can't stop what
you're doing to deal with it.
And the only fast things that
deliver are not what you want.
Introducing Postmates, the APP
that adds a delivery. Option two,
your favorite restaurants. I actually
use this shit. It's fucking great.
Especially when you want to eat healthy
because a lot of times the healthy
restaurants don't deliver
the Postmates got them,
but they'll go down and pick it
up for you. Bring it over to you.
Next morning you wake up, you stomach's
a little flatter. Thank you. Postmates.
Imagine anything you want
to eat, delivered. Anything.
You don't have to drive, park, or
even talk on the phone to order.
Just download the APP in order
24 hours a day, 365 days a year.
Postmates will bring you what
you want within the hour.
You can even see where your
food is and track your driver.
You forget you forgot
to get eggs and milk.
No problem.
Craving a tasty burger.
We got you looking for a book,
the perfect bottle of red wine
or a summer beer order up.
Postmates is your new
longterm munchies booty call.
I like that they're getting the weed
people in the drunks all at the same time
and that sentence for a limited time,
Postmates is giving you $100 of free
delivery credit for your first seven days
to stat your free deliveries.
Download the APP today and use the code
burned 100 but you are our 100 that's
code for 100 but $100 of free delivery
credit for your first seven days.
They save the hassle.
Get the food you love fast at
Postmates with code burr 100 all right.
Lastly, but not leastly. Oh Geez.
Is Dollar Shave club everybody do you
got stubble on your nuts that you want to
get rid of without taking them off?
Dollar Shave Club delivers
everything you need to look, feel,
and smell your best dollar shave club.
Everything he has,
everything that you need to
get ready in the bathroom.
Any particular product that have fallen
in love with outside of the razor and
why? I guess that's for me, right?
I'm allegedly getting the one wipe
Charlies dollar shave club. Yes.
That's dollar shave club delivers
everything. Yeah. Need to look,
feel and smell your best. You
name. Oh yeah. Dang. Shampoo,
conditioner, body wash,
toothpaste, Hair Gel.
Even a wipe that Olivia Tush
elliptically clean there.
Evidently according to the copy,
I am a big fan of their amber and
Labrador calming body cleanser.
Okay.
I want to use that.
Put it right on my fucking head.
Never smelled anything like
it for just five bucks. Yeah.
Can get their daily essential status set.
It comes with the body cleanser one way.
Chari they're amazing,
but wipes,
they're world famous shave
butter and their best razor.
The six blade executive.
Sure. You're wondering why.
I'll ask you to be here today.
Keep the blades coming for a couple of
bucks more a month and add in shampoo,
toothpaste, or anything else
you need for the bathroom.
Check it all out of dollar
shave club.com/burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/ [inaudible].
All right.
Can I talk about everything
I wanted to talk about?
Um,
I think that's it.
Football season,
starting up.
Oh, you know what I've got, I always
in the morning, my job is, I get,
I get my daughter out of bed. Right? You
got a whole little ritual. I carry over.
I let her turn on the light,
you know,
let it turn off the light when we
leave the room and all of that stuff.
And then whenever I bring up neat,
my wife always stays in bed.
You know what I mean?
Um, I'm really learning. I'm
learning how to, how to get along.
I'm telling you, it's, it's actually,
it's not that hard to get
along with your class.
This is what she got to do.
All right? In the morning.
All right?
You just snuggle up behind them.
I know this is sounding,
it's going to be weird and all you
do just caress him a little bit.
Five minutes, you do that
five fucking minutes, right?
The second you start
doing it, they go, oh,
and you just fucking do that.
Keeps him in a good mood.
All right? But you know,
starts to that, that'll get,
that'll give you peace until
about 11:00 AM positive.
You get up and you make the breakfast
[inaudible] you feed your kid, right?
You're sitting there like fucking,
I always feel like Joe Pesci in casino.
You know, cause I'm sitting here being
a sweetheart, I'm totally calm, relax,
you know, totally enamored with my
beautiful daughter, right? And I,
and up in my head I'm like, I'm a
piece of shit, right? So I always,
I always have like that fucking,
I'm a lunatic, right? So anyways,
but here's the thing though,
and this isn't just a woman that just
people in general, they get used to shit.
So you can't do it every day,
all right?
But you got to do some version
of that, okay. Just to,
just to fucking, you know,
they're like rescue dog. She just,
you want to keep them calm.
You want to keep the ears down,
keep the fucking ears down.
All right.
You're going to be good until
about 11 in the morning. All right.
And I ran around 11 in the
morning. They're, they're
starting to read their texts.
They got a couple of phone calls
they can get crazy. So your job is,
you have to get out of the
fucking house before that happens.
Okay.
And this is another thing that I learned.
When then bitching,
just shut the fuck up and listen.
Every once in a while you
have to make a noise or else,
then they get weirded out.
They'll just be like, oh,
I feel like it just like just
staring at me and judging me.
And then you got to keep your voice
down that you can't be like damn fucking
listen to you. You can't do that. Cause
then it's a fighter. You can't do that.
You know you're going to want to do that
because for the last 42 minutes you had
the solution.
You had the logical solution to whatever
the fuck they were talking about,
but you can't,
you know that that was the old me.
I would just break eight seconds
in. I would just be going, what?
Then don't be friends with her. Don't
pay well, tell him to fuck off. Yeah.
Just stopped hanging out with her and I,
you just can't do that.
You just have to fucking,
you just have to sit there.
Right.
You know what Song I,
you know when the,
when they're in one of those things
where they're just going to go for 40
fucking minutes.
Okay.
Is I just think of that
white stripes song,
uh,
Flight Paradis,
you know,
and I just had that fucking
playing in a loop in my head.
Not even the part where he sings,
it's just the guitar while Jane Blue,
it's like haunting and calming
all at the same fucking time.
And every once in a while I
just go like, wow, that's,
that's terrible. Then what
happened? And you just,
you just fucking stay in the pocket. If
you can do that, I'm telling you, you,
you're going to immediately,
40% of your fights are going to go out
the fucking window. Now that other 60%,
I don't know how much I
can whittle that down,
but I am telling you guys right now,
I am 40% happier just doing that.
Yeah,
they're rescue dogs.
Remember that you, you know,
you have no idea what the fuck
happened to him before you got it.
Okay.
Okay. So you've got to figure out
what the fuck makes them tick.
Okay. Cause if you don't, they're going
to be, they're going to be on your neck.
Thank you guys so much for listening and
as I want to especially thank anybody
who took anything I said on this podcast.
Seriously, um, have a great weekend yet.
Cons and I'll fucking check in on
your, Nah, I'll talk to you on Monday.
Um, Oh, you know what? I
talked to [inaudible] who is
going to be headlining the,
the puppy down there and fucking go see
a guy who's played every fucking Romy
had to, to get that Goddamn
Gig. A guy who didn't need it.
He didn't take any fucking
shortcuts or yard day.
Go down there
and go see my buddy. Do some comedy. All
right. If he can't, I would appreciate it.
All right. And uh, that's it.
I think the giants have their
first preseason game tonight.
I also heard that football's back at
the boys. A bad gay down. Yay. Yay.
All right.
Listen to the music and enjoy a a
bonus half hour by Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast,
a classic episode from a Thursday from,
I dunno,
years ago or maybe a couple of weeks
ago. I don't, I don't know how it works.
See you on Monday.
Market share. I got Sharine Sharon,
Sharon. I'll look on the topic.
Like he had a picture of the car and
Bobby was a readiness. They were all,
my mother was dying and they
were doing Tommy plays piano,
like a kid out in the of
any logs and login palace.
He was dancing with the train.
They were all in love with dye and they
were drinking from that was more like a
app
calming down,
Hi,
my flight
Los Angeles in the Logan
Airport. Everything's going,
everything's going fine.
Right. We take off from a lax. Yeah.
When you look down to the left,
you see that little fucking barrier where
Marine Del Rey is where Bravo airspace
is.
You know the helicopters go 150 feet off
the fucking surface to transition the
bravo airspace. We're fucking up
and over those cuts. We Bang a left,
we're climbing up. You know, going
back over Hollywood was so high up.
I can see over the Hollywood hills.
I can see into the valley. You know,
I saw it at Ucla campus.
Then you see a la coliseum went right
over the fucking rose bowl and then right
off into the Mojave desert, flew
right over Vegas. I looked down,
I saw this strategy.
Right.
Then you're into Utah.
You go over the continental divide,
the fucking rocky mountains, and then
we out, we're out of the great plagues,
the food supply. Everybody,
that's where they poison it.
Bright there from the halls are Martez.
Oh my God.
Bless America. Right. Flying Right over
our food supply that for some reason,
some reason we're letting
these cunts poison it.
Right.
Some reason we're going after
the terrorist over there,
but the fucking ones in the suits
over. Yeah, it's okay. So, okay.
Spray the big casino all over it.
Keep the bugs off at fantastic. Ah,
just rinse it under a faucet.
You'll be fine anyways.
Hey,
feed that cow some more cow.
MMM.
Cut The beaks off them.
So you fly over that shit right then.
I don't know.
By then the sun started going down and
everything was fine and uh, you know,
I was working on writing some stuff.
Yeah.
And a shooting the shit with this guy and
I was telling me he's got this room he
has and he's got a garage
right with a room over it,
which is my dream fucking house,
man.
I always wanted to have an old house with
a detached garage with a rum over at,
I already told you this shit.
I turned the upstairs into a drum room
slash cigar bar slash hooker lounge slash
sports bar like every man wants,
right?
MMM.
So he basically had that minus the
hookers, minuses, the Gaba minus to drums,
whatever. He had his, his fucking
new pool table and all that shit.
So we're just having a great time.
Just a good guy shooting the shit with,
he wasn't coughing, he didn't seem
like he had a boa. It was a nice time.
So all of a sudden we,
we started our initial offense,
the Santa to the Boston area, and,
um, we're out over the fucking wall,
you know,
and all of a sudden would, we're just
doing like this circular pattern.
I think we went north of the city
up by Newbury port in Marblehead,
and we're just doing
like this fucking circle.
And we go around and we go around
again and I'm thinking, uh,
this is a home pattern
that seems really low.
Yeah.
And, uh, the guy comes on and
he's like, Eh, we have a knee,
a little mechanical issue,
and try to work it out.
And then we have the ground shortly.
But I love that we're having,
we're having a mechanical problem. Uh,
but we expect to be on the ground shortly.
That can be taken two different ways.
Either we're going to fix it and I'll be
able to land this fucker or it's going
to be a catastrophic failure of something,
at which point gravity is going to take
over and land this plane for us. Right,
right. Somebody back deck there. Um,
so long story short,
um,
I wasn't even paying attention. That's
the weird part. I wasn't nervous at all,
which was another weird thing. So, uh,
he comes on the fucking thing and he was
going in for the landing and he said,
uh, okay, we're gonna begin our initial
to sent to a final whatever, blah,
blah blah at Logan airport.
Uh, just to let you know,
there's gotta be some emergency
vehicles on the runway.
There's nothing to be concerned about.
This is just standard procedure, bup, bup,
bup, bup, Ba. It's like
what the foot fucking mean.
It's nothing to be nervous about.
They brought up the fire trucks.
I know what this is for.
This is in case we're all covered in jet
fuel in eight minutes and we're on fire.
At which point you can't
really save any of us.
You just preventing this airplane from
burning down the rest of the airport is
we cartwheel down the fucking
runway. So anyways, long story short,
there was a flap that was stuck.
Um,
somebody said it was stuck up,
but we had the land faster than normal.
So I don't think it was able, I
don't think it was moving, you know,
don't you go flaps down or whatever to
slow the fucking thing down when you go
to land. Isn't that what, how
all these years of flying,
I believe that that's
what happens. Um, what,
what have we had the land faster than
probably what you're supposed to.
Probably outside the envelope
is the pilot say landed not,
it didn't even land that heart, you
know, and everybody in the back of plods,
nobody in first class applauds, you know,
cause they don't have any Sol's, uh,
including myself, you know,
and as we land and uh,
we pull over whatever and it
was a pretty fucking awesome,
pretty awesome feeling knowing
that the guy was that good.
He basically just prevented
us all from dying.
I guess they all do it every
time they landed safely. But uh,
to be able to kind of handle that,
I just can't imagine
being that pilot up there.
You only like comforting
feeling I would have, which you,
you'd have more concerned for the people
in the back then you did for yourself
so you can kind of stay
relaxed and just be thinking,
I have to keep my wits so I don't kill
these other people. But other than that,
what if, what a responsibility can
you imagine that if I fuck this up,
I'm going to kill 350 people,
you know? And then even worse,
whenever, you know, a plane
goes down, they examine it.
And if it comes down to being like, even
though that was a mechanical situation,
you know,
at some point they try,
they'd put it on the pilot
and insurance companies.
So you know what it was Chucky's fought
he fuck he wore the wrong kind of shoes
and I was pushing too
far. Right, right, right.
They figure out something that some
out of blame it on the pilot, you know,
so they can kind of keep the lawsuit.
Yeah. At a minimum, I don't know.
I W I don't what the fuck I'm
talking about. So whatever, um,
this guy landed us there safely.
Thank fucking Christ. And, uh,
so I've been back here in my
hometown for the last, uh,
since Friday and I've been, I've
been pretty good. I have not, uh,
I have not hit one of my old,
uh,
eating haunts cause I put on a little
bit of fucking weight there. I was,
I was sitting in the Writers'
room writingF is for family,
are pitching jokes as the
writers write it. And um,
okay.
You know, you know the
deal. I get like five,
10 outside the fucking zone and I f I
stand in the mirror and I fat shamed
myself. I give myself a little
fucking halftime speech, you know,
what the fuck was that today?
You know,
and then I get,
I get myself back on the stick.
So, uh, I'm telling you
all this shit that I say,
despite the fact that I don't know why I
didn't know anything about nutrition or
I know very little.
I'm telling you my tricks fucking work
when you just can't stop yourself and you
know,
you've got,
you want to eat a large
pizza and you fucking know it
and you know you shouldn't,
you're actually stepping
outside the craving, you know,
to be like, dude, what
the fuck are you doing?
Do not shove that fucking wheel
his shit down your throat.
Walk away. All right, drop the fork
or walk away. Right. You know it,
you know what you supposed to do, but
she can't that, that craving, that sugar,
salt,
fucking craving it just having you,
it's like you're not even controlling
your body. You walk over there,
that's when you just have to fucking
override it with common sense and order a
fucking salad
as quickly as possible,
shoved that down your fucking
throat and immediately,
not immediately take about five
minutes, you levels, whatever that is,
that craving levels off because you're
full fills you up and then you look at
that page and go, what the
fuck was I thinking? Why the
hell would I ever do that?
So I did that to myself.
I made a game plan before even left.
Um, I went to the airport and they had
one place you could actually get a salad,
right? And I fucking shove that down
my throat before I got on the plane.
And then I got on the
plane and then I was fine.
Okay.
And I had a banana for the flight,
shove that down my throat.
I kept pounding the water
is to keep the stomach full.
And at one point he had to give in. I
bought, I got a fucking whiskey and uh,
and then that was it. I was like, all
right, you did a great fucking job.
And then all of a sudden the plane
broke and I was like, Oh fuck,
I should've got the sun.
Yeah.
Is it too late to order some fun?
Uh,
keep the drinks, come
in their sweet hat. Um,
whatever. We ended up fucking landing
safely and a, I'm back on the stick.
Fiery auto crashes,
some old guy and hopper through.
We'll send things through my actions.
Some will fall in love of life and
drinking from a fountain that is foreign,
like an avalanche and
coming down the mountain.
[inaudible]
yeah.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
August 9th, 2010. How the hell are you?
Are you doing good?
Are you feeling okay?
Um,
I actually tried to do this podcast last
night and I was just too fucking beat
from doing the road, but
uh, believe it or not,
I had one of my best
road gigs of all time.
I worked the comedy store down in
La Jolla, California, La Jolla,
La j o l l a I think.
I don't know for all you fucking
Caucasians out there. Hey,
I'll come at eight fucking Lajolla.
Lajolla okay. No one of the guys
such difficult time assimilating.
I know you're not a fucking spell.
Well,
Jolla is Ala fuck and h
ow fucking why a buddy,
um, la Jolla, California.
And I performed down at the comedy
store and I had a tremendous time.
I stayed down at a hotel
right down on Pacific beach,
underrated Pacific beach.
I had a great time.
Evidently I heard late at night though.
The kids can get a little bit rowdy,
but that's what kids do. They don't
know how to get pussy. They don't,
they're young.
So what do they do?
Walk around with their chest puffed out.
They can,
that's going to make some
broad come over and touch it.
And then when she doesn't, you
start drinking more, right?
And then you see somebody who is getting
some and then what do you do? Ah,
you take off your button down, you got
your stupid fucking tank top on. Oh,
a little bit.
The folk have muscles all week and then
next thing you know there's a fight is
that hour goes down,
Bill.
I have no idea how it went down
in the fucking eighties. You know,
everybody had their feathered mullets,
you know,
they are Bobby Brown
steel toed dance shoes.
You know, back when Bobby
Brown was fucking Bobbi Brown,
Mark Walberg, it just started
lifting weights. Talk in the 80s,
talk in the fucking eighties. Um, yeah,
I had an unbelievable time this weekend,
this week after two
weeks of alcohol abuse.
I'm actually sitting here
drinking a smoothie like a fag,
and I'm loving every second of it.
I'll tell you,
it's two days down on the beach. I'm
just like, I get it. I totally get it.
This whole east coast angry,
you know, spend your life,
you know, get teeth, grit,
holding a fucking shovel,
waiting for the next nor'easter.
It's just not the way to live
was fucking people down there in La Jolla.
Lajolla,
whatever the fuck you want to call it,
they have life down.
Everybody sat down there was
in great shape, you know,
people riding bikes,
people still rollerblading,
jogging, doing yoga. Sun was shining.
So I went out and got a smoothie.
He said, fuck it. You know,
when in Rome put on some yoga
stretchy pants and some flip flops.
And I didn't do that. I didn't
take it that far. But uh, yeah,
I was talking to a buddy of mine down
there and he was explaining to me why, uh,
why sound like a fucking,
well,
why should you worry?
What's wrong with that? Um,
he was telling me why, uh, starting
off with juice was a good thing.
Kind of equated it to an, to an
engine. You know, you go out,
you let your car fucking warmup first
before he'd drive it a hundred miles an
hour down the street,
don't you?
So rather than take it one of those
fucking Goddamn breakfast sandwiches,
that'll be the death yet,
you know,
having some Nag and broaden your life
and you compound that, compile it,
something with the sea.
That means in addition, um,
you have a breakfast sandwich
with the bacon or the sausage,
which form of dead pig do you want
on this fucking thing, you know,
that'll kill you. So last, like three,
four days up in drinking the
smoothie to start off the damn day.
And I'm feeling great and I know right
now all you guys are going to fucking go
onto the m podcast and continue your
fucking threads about what a pussy on
becoming. And I gotta be honest with
you, I don't give a shit. You know,
I'm like that fucking astronaut who
just think spaces, beauty, beautiful.
And I just let go of the
ship and everybody else is
sitting there and horror,
you know, is I just sort of float away
with that stupid smile on my face.
At least he floated away
doing what he loved.
Yeah. That's where I'm gone. I got a
lot of shit last week on my alleged fan.
You know, only I would get trashed
on my, my, my alleged fan page,
the MM podcast.com if you
haven't visited there, uh,
you're missing out because that's
where all the cool kids are, you know,
with the jeans rolled up,
listened to at the hop. Um,
no,
I,
I recommend youtube videos and all that
shit when rather than having to go on
and search them yourself,
you can actually just,
we do it for you at the m and podcasts.
It's sort of a mom and pop store
with no mother or no father.
It's a tragic story and I'm not
going to get into it. But anyways,
I got trashed on my own
alleged fan page about my,
uh,
my alcohol tolerance because last week
I was hung over because the night before
he had two whiskeys and to Miller
high life. And uh, everybody's,
but yeah, basically, you know, doing
what people, that's all you had, dude.
I can fucking drink a fucking case and
you know, go unload a fucking truck.
So can I, when I was in my twenties,
it's called pea and 42 people.
Do you think I'm proud of that shit?
This is the deal. If I have one beer,
just one beer late at night,
I wake up the next day.
If I didn't drink a tall glass of water,
I feel the effects. All right. I'm like,
it's fucking 14 year NFL vet.
That's what my livers like.
My liver is like the
entire late seventies,
Pittsburgh Steelers brains right now.
What's really fucking
bad, whatever. Um, if I,
I can't handle it the way I used to.
All right.
You know what an evil Knievel due
at the end of his fucking life.
Was he still jumping off his shit or was
he fucking lane in agony? Slumped over.
A fucking Ottoman. I mean, you ask
yourself the tough questions people,
you're going to get the answers you need.
You need to hear
God damn it. That smoothie is delicious.
So that's why. Yes people so you know.
But I am a man and I am competitive
since I got to tell you some fucking
drinking and not even drinking stories.
I'm just going to rattle off some striking
stats from earlier on in my career.
And this is no steroids
by the way, people, okay?
This is pre steroids era in baseball.
Um, what a fucking joke by the way,
Huh? God Damn a Rod. I don't get,
I don't get this shit. The fucking
20 minute memory sports fans have.
Why were they doing the countdown
to a rod 600th home run?
Can anybody explain that to me?
Oh,
you mean the Gao did roids
and patted his fucking stats.
A monumental achievement.
Look good babe.
Ruth looked like he was
in his second trimester.
He's eating a fucking hot dog at
the plate and he banged out. What,
713 is that what it is dependent,
not be 713 if I actually got that right,
that the level of,
of patheticness to my social life.
Um,
yeah, I used to, back in the day I could
drink a 12 pack, no fucking problem.
And then I'd go on to Mcdonald's.
I get a quarter pounder with cheese,
a cheeseburger, you know, large
fry, never liked in nuggets.
Coca, what else would I get? I'd
have to get maybe two cheeseburgers.
I needed a lot of bread and they
fucking squirrel meat. And then I would,
you know, go to bed and I
would wake up literally three,
four hours later go to my job.
And other than being sleepy,
I felt fine and I would go down
that I unload trucks, you know,
kind of felt like shit.
But when the Roach coach showed up at
10 15 I'd go out there and maybe get a
slice of pizza,
you know,
just to kind of sop up the rest of
the alcohol. And I was good to go.
I was good to go. But let me
tell you something. You do
that for 20 fucking years.
It catches up with you,
catches up with you.
So one day you're 42 you have a
couple of fuck whiskeys, you know,
couple of high highlights and you banged
up the next morning and I'm not gonna
apologize.
Okay?
There's too many people in this country
that are obsessed with the youth culture.
Now shame when people say that,
you know, says that old people,
because they're not fuckable anymore
and they can't emotionally come to terms
with it. We are a youth obsessed
culture. Tell me another.
And then they always got to bring up
Japan. How they respect their elders,
you know, really, how much do
they respect them? Are they,
are they walking up to them at a
fucking single's bar? You know,
I've always been turned on by 80
year olds. You know your wisdom,
your fucking chicken neck.
Yeah,
I got to have to understand,
I'm like Brett Farve. Okay.
Every time people think I'm
going to fucking retire,
I come back for another God damn round.
You know, maybe if I took
the roids that guy's taken.
I could actually fucking drink
the way I used to. You know,
I'm actually going to debate a debate
with a buddy of mine. I think he, he,
he took something for last season.
That guy was on the jets. Okay.
He looked, he looked
like Nilo Donald. Okay.
And then all of a sudden he has air
quotes off season surgery and this guy
fucking comes back and
when he was like 39 he looked
like fucking George Blanda.
Then he comes back at 40 and all of a
sudden he looks like that kid who took his
helmet off and the Superbowl was it
[inaudible] 97 I blocked that out.
And you don't have to tell you
guys I was at that super bowl.
I was at that super bowl and Brett Farve
took his helmet off and ran down the
street like a Douche. Huh?
That's back when, you know,
I think he's the reason why you're
not allowed to do that anymore.
Right in the middle of the super bowl,
he takes his fucking helmet off and
runs down the fucking field, you know,
with an ear piece in his agent going,
yeah.
Now smile real big and
yell weedies you know,
to fucking sad in sports. Did you guys
watch any of that hall of fame game,
by the way? What was it? The fucking,
the cowboys versus the Goddamn Bengals.
How awkward was it watching a t
o and o Cho Sinco when he goes,
uh, I'm Batman. And then the other
dude's like, and I'm Robin. Oh,
all right. So you're his ward. I mean,
haven't they long talked about the gay
relationship between Batman and Robin,
this fucking teenager
who's have no relation to,
uh, Adam West, whatever his fucking name
is. Am I really gonna do that hacky bit?
I think I got to start boozing again.
I give this podcast a half a
fucking thumb down. All right,
let's get into this shit here. Um, so when
he was, I was down in, uh, Sandy. Oh fuck.
All right. Start off a bill. Regroup.
You actually have some information.
You know what? I got jury duty,
so I need your guys' help. Okay.
This is a free God damn podcast and I
would appreciate a little bit of fucking
reciprocation. How to fuck do I
get out of this shit? You know,
I was thinking of memorizing the
Mel Gibson tapes and just go in
and just,
when they say my name,
I'm just going to start reciting
some of his dialogue. William Barr.
I'm just going to go sit in here with
you pussy hanging out of the back and get
dress.
Look,
we all know the line. I all you're
not line I need to mutter is, is the,
the over the top racist one and
I will never get jury duty again,
but uh, there's gotta be a better way.
Okay. There has to be a better way.
Is there a race of people out there left
that you can sort of go off on where
you can come off as racist but it
doesn't hold the same weight? You know,
I mean I think the Yankees and red sox
of race or or blacks and Jewish people,
you know, you trash either one
of them, your career is fucked,
but then you know you got the
middle of now of level ones,
you know like the twins,
you know you go off on Italian people,
I do it all the time.
Oh look at my full can tank top.
Oh nobody gives a shit.
Jersey shore is an entire show making
fun of Italian fucking people telling you
fucking juice heads and all this shit
and half of those consonants show they're
not even Italian.
You know what I mean?
Could you do that with blacks
at Jewish people? You could not.
That's what I'm talking about.
That's why they are the upper that,
that's why the hair, the tier one,
they're the Yankees and red sox. Alright.
If you want to destroy your career,
say some shit about either one of those
groups, that shit is over. All right.
You want to dip your toe into a little
bit of racism. I'd go with the Italians.
Irish people, you can go
off on Polish. You know,
cause that's sort of comes into way ya
now he just sort of making fun of white
people in more of a specific
sort of way. But uh, you know,
when no one really knows what the fuck
bad shit happened to any of us, whatever,
what a bad ever happened to Italians.
You know, they've got gorgeous women,
you know, some of them a little
hairy. I will give you that, you know,
especially in the tramp stamp area.
Never seen that.
Ever see a girl with a little little
extra hair there and you're like, Jesus,
Yo g,
you know,
just thinking of what
that God damn fucking
who has going to look like
it's going to look like decided George
Michael's face and about fucking 1987
so a looking at this, going off on
Italian women, I'm not even nervous.
I'm not worried about it.
And then you move on to,
I'll tell you know who's
moved up in the rankings,
sort of like a Texas tech that turned
its program around there with some genius
new coach was agents.
When I started in stand up comedy,
you could do a half hour on
Asians and nobody gave a shit.
She's fucking going off going off on
agents and then somewhere along the line
they were like, wait a minute, didn't
we teach you guys martial arts?
You know when did the master,
but I mean the student become
the dose and start yelling at us.
So then they turned it around.
I think they've leap frog past the fuck.
I tell you it was a problem with fucking
Italian people is if I can be so bold,
they should pussies are hanging up is um,
the bad shit that you guys do.
I don't even know if it's cool,
but it's been so fucking
glamorized that, you know, I mean,
look at good fellas,
at least the beginning of Goodfellas.
I love that. I hate when the second
fucking, uh, Henry becomes a rat,
you know. I know I've talked about that
before. You know that fucking asshole.
Like, she has the balls to come
out in public now and he signs shit
I want to go to.
And you know,
and the MP I if people like equate
that guy with Ray Liotta character,
this guy was,
was he fucking ran in everybody out at
one after he did exactly what they told
them not to do. He got himself into
that fucking situation. Granted,
if the movie is exactly how
it went down a real life,
so why would you go down
there and get, get the, uh,
get the autograph to somebody who
told on his friends. I'm asking you.
So anyways, what I'm saying is, uh, yeah,
as much as Italians or Ricoh or
acquainted with fucking organized crime,
I think people look at it the way
you look at the beginning of, um,
of good fellas when they're all hanging
out in front of the coffee shop,
breaking balls, they got on nice suits.
They got the cars, they got the women.
They're not taking any shit.
You know,
it's like fucking Walker, Texas ranger
with dot. I mean, it was even like Walker,
Texas ranger was annoying because he's
such a fucking do good are all the time.
It's on the right side of the law. He
wears a condom. He's annoying those guys.
They don't give a shit.
Joe Pesi, you know,
sitting there having a fucking business
conversation and he pushes that girl's
head down onto his dick.
Who doesn't want to do that?
Let's talk about racism this week.
People.
Out of all the stereotypes I
went to ft say that Italians,
they have some of the best
stereotypes out there.
Irish, what are we got? Pasty faced
drunks, potato, Wheaton, shitheads.
I'm half a, mostly German. And
then I'm, I'm Irish. So basically,
what are you a fucking
Nazi? I got that. And uh,
and then everybody else is
just a fucking booze bag.
Going to church every week.
A and having like 18 kids.
Alright. Okay. So now we got to go
all the way down to the cellar here.
The fucking Kansas city royals.
And I'm not equating this to, to,
to the people. I'm just saying as far
as the standup comedian, like the team,
you can just fucking,
you know,
you can just score seven runs on them and
there's nothing they could fucking do.
Um,
I don't really know if that exists now
the way it's so politically correct,
native Americans just because of the odds
of one of them actually being off the
reservation and in the crowd is,
hey, you know what, so many, uh,
um, sent me an email this week and,
uh, this is just a great fucking
email and it's just classic,
just shows how full of Shit I am is,
I'm,
I always compared like the Yankees and
the red sox to what they're doing until
like, you know, a Walmart
or like a best buy. Um,
and evidently this guy sent me an email
and of course I didn't do the research,
but one of the higher ups are,
one of the owners of Walmart
actually owns the Kansas city royals.
So he was basically saying that if that
guy wanted to win as bad as the Yankees
and the Red Sox, um,
do that actually they,
they would say Bruton for Kansas City
is like rooting for Walmart or something
like that. And uh, I think there
might be some validity in that point.
Um, I mean God knows I can't back it
up because I didn't read about it.
So, uh, once again, once again,
I am exposed to how full of Shit I am,
but there's a passion in my
full of shitness. All right.
I feel like this is fucking winding
down again. Let's go to, uh,
let's go to the board here.
Um, last week I discussed, uh,
clapping in the airport for veterans
when they get off the plane. You know,
that point they walk by letting and
everybody's just like, whew, you know,
good game, good game. Uh,
and it was one of those, you know, one
of those weird things where it's like,
it just felt I didn't clap cause
it just felt weird and it was like,
and I'm sitting there feeling
guilty why I want to show this guy.
I appreciate the fact, you know, that
he went over there and everything,
but it's like,
I don't want to Wa
I know clapping isn't it?
So we actually had a couple
of veterans chimed in here,
um, or people in active service. Okay.
And here's what they have to say.
All right. Listening to the late
Yara, your latest podcasts. Uh, yes,
it was a little weird getting
off the plane in Atlanta,
coming back from 13 months in Iraq and
having strangers clap as I was going up
the escalator. Uh, that being said, I
couldn't keep the rice smile off my face,
my face, I guess it's better than
nothing or the Vietnam scenario that you,
uh, that you described. Um,
so I wrote the guy back,
so I was saying clapping
is okay. And he said, uh,
he goes, yeah, absolutely. Again,
it's weird leaving that militarized
environment and trying to
readjust to stepping foot in America.
So it's a little weird to have
people actually happy to see you,
let alone clapping a random
hugs and kisses. Not so much,
unless they're from, oh, Jesus, I'm the
worst that can read unless they're hot.
And then all bets are off
of course. Uh, all right.
So that's that guy's opinion. Um, oh,
did have a guy shake my hand and
thank me for this time. I, uh,
time in the service guy looked like
he could have been a Vietnam vet,
so it wasn't a patronizing 20 year old
douchebag handshake or a 50 year old
cubicle farm farm secretary.
A guy looked like he might've actually
meant it and understood what the term
service meant.
I'm sorry,
I don't have the light on in my bedroom
when I bring this over to the fucking
window here. Okay. Um,
this didn't really, was supposed to
be interesting and the way I read it,
that sounded like I was fucking
reading a spelling test.
All right. Here's another
guide Shiming in, uh,
I served in the Marines as a radio
operator. One of the guys in the,
one of those guys in the war
movies with the backpack radios,
that invariably invariably die within
30 minutes of the opening credits. Uh,
my unit participated in the evasion
and returned to Camp Pendleton,
California via a stopover in Baltimore.
As we came into the main terminal,
we received the awkward standing ovation.
Uh,
if I had had one of those cyanide pills,
the spy pilots carry between the cheek
and gum, I might have gone for it.
They're asked to be a happy medium
between spitting and being an ass.
I know you're clapping
so you can tell you,
tell your friends that you support
the troops. Just knock it off.
I know you're really don't care.
We don't care that you don't care and
we'll all be better off if you don't.
What does it say?
UN
athletically clap and or something
like that. Like it's the end of topcon.
Uh, what's more is that every guy in
the world internalizes other guys,
military service and wants to tell
you about how he almost joined.
But a promising job in
the food industry called.
So these clowns not only make ya
your walkthrough, the term terminal,
super awkward,
but then they follow you into the bar
and ruin your first experience around
women in eight months. See that's
what I felt like it was. I mean,
what are they supposed to do?
Smile and wave. Thank you.
Thank you. 14 confirmed kills right
air and made the altar all star team.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
It's fucking weird. So I don't know.
One guy says he doesn't
mind it. Uh, I dunno.
This is how I do it. If I'm in a
bar and I see people in uniform,
I'll send out around a drinks.
I don't even walk up to him sent down.
They look over, you know,
I give them the, uh,
more black people used to do when they
do it. When the height of the, the, the,
the fucking a salad.
Remember that Shit.
Anybody else used to watch
fat Albert back in the day?
It's not like the full on 1968 Olympics
or that stupid puff daddy advertisement
in Times Square. It's not like
dad, you know, I love that one.
That puffy has in there like he's fighting
the power in the fashion industry for
is Sean John Close. He's
fighting the power. Everybody,
those goddamn eight year olds who
sewed together as track suits,
they keep repel it and they
keep rebelling, you know,
but he stay in strong.
Ah, must be great to always get to
play the victim. God Damn, I'm jealous.
I'm really fucking jealous of that. All
right, so there you go. I don't know.
We got one for one against,
so it's a tie.
So I need more veterans to chime
in here. Yes. On the clapping.
No on the clapping.
And this is the thing,
you can't just say yes and the clapping.
Why don't you come up with creative ways
that people can thank you and I don't
care how filthy they are.
Have Fun with this for the love of God.
So I can actually maybe be funny on my
own God damn podcast and actually have
the nerve to get upset that
fucking people were uh,
trashing me on my own fucking alleged
fan page. I think I need another sip,
a smoothie so I can
become even less funnier.
This really is anti funny juice. You
know, you have a breakfast sandwich,
you're fucking hilarious. You
breaking balls, you have flies down,
you don't even know it. People
laughing with you and Ya. Um,
so anyways, so let's get onto some
youtube videos of the week. Um,
I'll wait. Did I talk
about jury duty? I did.
Didn't I did I guys,
how the fuck do I get out of jury duty?
I don't want to do it.
I've already done it.
I've done it fucking three.
I don't know how many times I've done it.
I can only remember once,
but I'm gonna say three fucking times.
This is one of these weird things
where as an American I want to do it.
It is my God damn duty.
All right.
I would rather do
community fucking service
then do jury duty.
I'll tell you what buddy.
You don't show up for that fucking shit.
You just, Jack, what you going to get?
Does anybody know anybody who fucking
blew off jury duty and actually got
arrested for it?
You know,
I figured California's a broke state
so you know, they, they gotta be,
they gotta be like stretched
pretty thin right now. You know,
my problem is,
is I fucking responded to it when I was
living in New York and I actually sat on
a juror jury as an alternate
juror and this dude,
they busted this dude trying to break in.
It was actually hilarious trying to pick
a lock to break into a building and he
was trying to say that he was taking a
piss and one of the best part, you know,
and that's why he was turned
into the doorway. And, uh,
one of the funniest things was
when the cop was testifying saying,
do you think there's any way
that he was actually urinating?
And the dude was working
on the deadbolt locks.
So his hands were basically up where
his chest was. So he goes, well,
unless he was trying to be in his
own face with the longest dick ever.
No, he wasn't trying to pee.
He said it much more, uh,
a much more cleaner way. But, uh,
I sat there as an alternate juror and I
felt bad. I felt bad for the fucking guy.
You know,
I don't have it in me to send someone to
jail for doing some shit that I've done.
You know, it's just
fucking ridiculous. Uh,
well cause I never got caught.
Now I can judge this guy.
I never tried to break into somebody's
house, but I did other things.
I had a couple failed attempts
to steal cars. This is,
this is what my attempts to steal cars.
I would check to see if the door was
unlocked and if it was unlocked then I
would get in it. And then I
would look in the visor for keys.
And when that didn't happen,
I just got out because I had no skills.
You know, you can go on youtube and learn
how to hot wire a car. And it's funny,
they show you how to hot wire a car all
under the guise of in case you run out
of gas or a case, you lose your
keys. That's it. Run out of gas.
That's stupid in case you lose your
keys and you're in the middle of fucking
nowhere and a, you need
to hot wire your car. And,
uh, you know, you can
actually fucking do it.
You know when you can drink a fucking
juggle your own urine in the process.
They try to make it like that.
Like it's a survivalist thing and there's
all these comments underneath it. Hey,
thanks a lot man. I just got that 68
Mustang I always wanted. You know,
who knows if they're
joking or not, but I dunno.
So anyways, how do I get out of it? See,
this is why you want to have as
many friends as possible. This is,
this is a true belief that
I have come to in my life.
You cannot have enough
friends who are cops.
You just can't.
All right.
And I don't give a fuck how much you
hate authority. You're going to loose.
All right?
You've seen those guys.
Those guys can accidentally or on
purposely kill you and be like,
oh Yo, I, I had a muscle
spasm. Sorry about that.
And they walk.
So you want these guys on your side,
there's a cop lives on your block.
Bake a cake that works two fold.
One,
you get on his good side. And
two, if you do some bad shit,
if he doesn't recognize you, he's
too fat to catch you. You know?
And maybe when he reaches
down for his gun, his did,
he is his fucking love handles,
you know,
are pushing the gun a little bit back
around to the s area and he can't pull it
out. His old service revolver.
Um, no actually, you know,
I know a couple of cops out here in La
and there were a couple back in New York
and yeah, when I have new DVDs that
come out, I fucking send them out. Hey,
you go fellas,
remember this face,
remember this face for,
I'm speeding around in my fucking hybrid.
I really am a Douche. Um,
anyways, it's fucking plow ahead.
I'd also make friends with the
veterans on your street. You know,
maybe they actually smuggled
back a grenade or some
shit and you'll be privy to
see what it looks like when he fucking
throws it at somebody on a 4th of July.
Just for the fuck of it.
Um, anyways. Yeah. Okay.
So those are my two questions this week.
Veterans. I want you to chime in, okay?
Cause it's a tie right now. All right? Um,
about how people are supposed
to show appreciation, okay?
It's one guy says he
doesn't mind the clapping,
but both of you said it was awkward.
The other person said he wanted to
take a fucking cyanide pill. All right?
So we're all over the map here and if you
can come up with a creative way that a
legal or not legal way that people can
thank veterans as they get off the plane,
please let me know. And I actually,
uh, what do you think of mine?
You send down a round of drinks and then
you don't go down there and have the
fucking awkward conversation with them.
You know,
like, what am I going to say to
you? I never went to war, you know,
just start fucking doing
quotes from platoon.
All right, let's fucking
plow ahead here. Um,
youtube videos of the work of the
week, of the work of the week. Uh,
youtube videos. All right, guy
search. This guy walks into traffic,
gets hit.
This guy is such a fucking moron.
I actually thought that this was fake
because I don't know how he doesn't see
this. He walks into traffic doing
a silly dance, and I swear to God,
I believe he gets hit
by an ice cream truck.
And I'll tell you right now,
if that doesn't put a smile on your face,
you're not American. You're not
American. You're a fucking commie.
Pinko son of a bitch. Do you know in
Russia the ice cream trucks are gray?
Slate Gray.
They don't even have a picture of the ice
cream on the side of it and they don't
play a fucking happy little
pedophile jingle has a drawer.
They drive down the street. They
don't, they just played the,
I am Bra shy of Russia.
I'd take out a comb and then I brush up.
That's what they do.
Just something fucking like that,
you know, except they sing it. Um,
slayer goes to church.
I think I might have recommended this one
before someone else did. Um, but it's,
it's just awesome. Um, next one,
our best judge Judy ending ever
best judge Judy ending ever.
And this actually made me watch some of
those, uh, like I fucking hate judge Judy.
I Hate Judge Carol. I hate all
those mother fuckers. Okay.
This one is some lady screaming
at this guy going, you know,
you don't come in here and
disrespect this quite like that.
Disrespect what court?
It's a fucking TV show.
You dump cunt.
You're not a fucking judge.
I'm so sick of these fucking people who
get TV shows about a job and they think
that that, that their, their fucking job
now is still the job that they're show.
No, you're a TV star. It's
not a fucking court. A law.
Even though it has the
authority of a court of law.
How many quarts do you know out there?
Okay.
That cease to exist if
they get bad ratings.
You know what I mean?
Actually left that comment on one of
those fucking youtube video. Thanks man.
It was fucking girl show boat.
There was show boat and slam it down the
hammer screaming and yelling and then,
you know,
they go to the commercial and then the
producer comes up and whispers in their
ear like, yeah, that was great television.
That was great. Tell them, hey,
do more yelling, yell more. ESPN is
making a killing with the yelling.
I fuck ain't out. Maybe it's my hatred
of women. I don't know what it is.
But those fucking women judges, that's
my nightmare of what being married is.
You know, cause you're legally bound to
them and they can take half your shit.
So now they can fucking
yell at you like that.
Banging a hammer hammer on
some fucking coffee table.
Oh, I'll tell you right now,
you can take half of my shit.
I'll fucking walk just to get away
from you and you fucking goddamn
menopause. Chicken neck fucking screaming
at me. Go fuck yourself, Judge Judy.
There's no fucking way I
would stand there. Okay.
And get yelled at like that because a
third of my swing set is on my neighbor's
property.
You're gonna fucking yell at me like that
cause cause why are you yelling at me
like that? You don't even feel
it, Judge Judy. All you, Oh,
you want to do is get good ratings.
You're fucking grand standing.
Go Fuck Yourself. Please tell me you're
not naked under that robe. You Amaze.
She ate it. Old Whore. Sorry.
I don't like those fucking shows.
That's the same thing with
like that Donald Trump.
If you actually think Donald Trump
is rich and you're a fucking idiot,
you're a goddamn idiot.
He needs that job to keep his,
his face out there.
What do they call it? Your Q rating.
Is that what they say in the business?
How recognizable you fucking faces.
Go Down to Atlantic city and talked to a
couple of people about Donald Trump and
his fucking, he, you know, he is,
he is rich. But he's like, you know,
he's the rich version of that
guy who lives on your street,
who has like four old cars and different,
uh,
levels of restoration in a fucking old
refrigerator just rusting out on his
front property. That guy, the
guy who makes you a fucking
property value go down.
He does that at like the skyscraper level.
I'm not saying it doesn't
have more money than you or I,
but you know what I mean enough already.
If you really had all these
successful businesses going on,
you don't have time to see if Ozzy's
wife is better than Cindy Lopper do you?
I don't think you do. All
right, last week on the podcast,
um, I read some hate mail
from single mothers, uh,
who got mad at me when I was talking
about stay at home moms with husbands who
give them money. And uh, I
actually got some shit from a,
from actual stay at home moms. So, uh,
one person chimed in on that actually
brought up a decent point that was
delivered in a very extreme way,
which is how we do it on this podcast.
But I think that this is a little
bit of point in here, said,
I just listen to the August 2nd podcast.
He says,
isn't it funny how martyred the
women who choose to bang some loser,
he's talking about single mothers here
who they probably bitch at incessantly.
This guy sounds like he's
going through a divorce. Um,
and they end up single parent.
Wait a minute.
I really can't read this week. People.
It's a lack of alcohol in my system.
All right, let's start over again. Bill,
isn't it funny how martyred the women who
choose to bank some loser and end up a
single parent like to make
themselves and in his quotes,
I am a single mom. I do it all by myself.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And the guy goes on to say,
who told you to get knocked up
before you got an education?
It's a great fucking point.
Who told you to let some loser
who won't even stick around?
Oops.
Stick it in you.
When you know what is going to come of it.
You got loaded.
Found some hottie who works
a part time construction job.
Hang on, let me keep scrolling
down and let them knock you up.
You chose the loser.
You didn't do birth control.
You didn't wait till you
had your education or your
career going and we need to
celebrate you for being the
poor, pitiful victim. You are.
Cry me a river cunts.
I have no more sympathy for you than
the people who complain about having no
money but never run out of beer cigarettes
or lottery tickets and our sporting a
pony keg for a gut from
all the overeating they do.
There you go. People, that is the extreme
opinion of the week. We might've had a,
a new segment there now obviously.
Um,
what makes that thing funny is it is, it
is so extreme, but he's also, you know,
he's ignoring the fact that there's a,
there's different levels of information
that is passed on to people at different
levels of, uh, uh, you know,
look at super rich people have access
to all the fucking information you need.
And even their kids could get fucking
knocked up. But you know what I mean?
As if you really look at the educational
system and the inner city schools and
that type of shit. I mean, Jesus Christ,
it's fucking horrific
what goes on in there.
And it's absolutely pathetic.
I Dunno that w that people in general
don't give a shit that the more poor you
are, the worst, the fucking free education
that you're supposed to get. His.
So I mean I, I, I do great
it a little bit on a,
on a, uh, what do they call that?
What was that shit when you a scale
grading scandal. Fucking remember,
I'm a moron. I don't know. I grew
up in the suburbs, so I had a,
I had a decent education and I remember
when I started working in a warehouse
and I started working with
these other kids from Brockton.
And uh, the education that they got
was a way more street education.
Then they got like a, you know, the
x's and o's from school, you know,
and a lot of them had fucking kids
real young just like their parents did.
And for all you fucking people out
there were picture and blacks and Puerto
Ricans. These kids were
white. They were white,
but they were listening to that hip hop.
Now I'm fucking around.
No, seriously. So, but that
there is, there is like a, uh,
there,
there is a great point in there where
it's like you weren't born a single mom,
you know what I mean?
Like if somebody is handicap,
I'd never make some fun of somebody
fucking handicapped. Okay. I wouldn't,
all right. It's just, you know, it was
an accident or you were born that way,
but you weren't born
pregnant. I don't know. Yeah.
And it's,
and it's really hard for me from where
I came from to imagine why someone would
want to be, there's actually people
out there who want to have a kid at 16.
MMM. I guess a lot of it comes
down if their parents did it.
I have no fucking idea.
MMM. Yeah. I Dunno.
But yeah. Any single moms
out there, I mean, did it,
is there any sort of
responsibility on yourself?
Do you ever sit down and just be like,
wow, I, you know, no pun intended,
really fucked myself over here,
you know,
I dunno. I'm of that opinion that
that's how you grow in life. Okay. Okay.
You know, you can't blame
other peoples for your failure.
Like Peyton manning does every
God damn Sunday he loses.
We had protection issues.
Oh, that actually works.
That's what the single moms should do.
They should come out just like at the end
of one of those Peyton manning fucking
bad games. He has come out with a
towel around your neck and just say,
hi, we have protection issues. Um, I don't
know if there was a hole in the condom.
Oh wait. He didn't even wear one. Um,
it was because look,
he had a condom on initially and then
he went and he put it in my ass and he
wanted to go back to my vagina. So I
made him take it off because, you know,
I didn't want to get an infection,
so I didn't get infected for anybody.
One drink.
But now I have a child and you have no
idea how difficult it is to try to raise
this child. I know it has to be
unbelievably fucking difficult,
but at the end of the day,
you're the one who laid on your
back and took a hot one. Okay.
So for all you ladies, all
the foodies out there, um,
yeah, don't do that.
This is what you want.
You want to get married first so you're
legally bound to that son of a bitch.
So when he knocked you up and then leaves
like the piece of fucking garbage that
he is, he's going to
owe you money. You know,
and I know what you're saying, but what
some of these guys, they just blow it off.
They become dead beat dads.
They'd rather go to fucking jail and he
was then you married a fucking loser.
Okay. Do you understand that
you're married a fucking loser
and I think this day and age women have
no business complaining about a what?
They make an hour.
Okay.
Cause if you listen to the beyond say
catalog of music that she's put up,
if you could sit through that hours
and hours of shit that she has put out,
evidently you guys,
your booty licious you're independent
women and a, if you like it,
you got to put a ring on it.
I mean right there is the trilogy.
That's all the information you need
to get ahead in life. I don't know what
the fuck I'm saying. Look, you know,
I'm trying to be, uh, uh, not devil's,
I'm trying to be mediated here.
I understand that shit happens.
I mean,
who out there in their fucking
career never had a girl who was late,
never took a chance.
You know, we all have,
so this guy is wrong for
judging them that harshly,
but these single moms to 100%
paint themselves as these fucking victims.
You're not all right.
You know God damn well,
it's not easy to raise a kid.
How do you not fucking know that I
knew that it's 16 that was the horror,
the fucking horror when I was 16
to get somebody fucking knocked up,
you know? And I was so fucking
nervous about knock at somebody up.
I didn't get laid till I was 19.
That's the only reason I
could have got laid at 14.
Me coming down the fucking hall
with my orange hair and my freckles,
I was beaten. The ladies off
me. He was like, listen ladies,
I'd love to have a threesome in the
seventh grade. Okay, I get it. You know,
I'm like that White Rhino,
um, rare, um, desirable,
like the hope diamond.
Oh,
it was pathetic.
But even then in 19,
I started my fucking
bang and career and um,
I'm so full of Shit.
All they would do is just make
sure the girl was on the pill.
This is back when we thought I aids.
You could only get if you were
gay or if you were a trucker.
And um,
you know,
I'm completely full of Shit.
I think if I was a fucking woman,
I probably have six kids by now.
All right,
there you go.
We need veterans and we need single
moms to fucking chime in here.
Do you think that guy's being too harsh?
Obviously. Obviously he's a little harsh.
All right. Um, oh, here's this thing.
I wanted to re, uh, about the royals.
I actually saved this here. If I
can go back for a second. I bill,
I've heard you many times talk about
how the Red Sox and Yankees are ruining
baseball with how many stars they
are able to buy. Unlike other teams.
I agree with you to a certain extent.
I think there should be a salary cap to
make it more fair for everyone in the
league. However, here is a fun fact.
The owner of the royals is
a recent CEO of Walmart.
The royals are one of the few teams.
Hang on here.
One of the few teams used as an example
of how teams without enough money can't
compete yet their owner is
a multibillionaire dude,
that guy's not a mall.
You're not United CEO of Walmart
and you're a multi billionaire.
I bet as a CEO he probably makes some
disgusting amount, like 10 million a year.
Um, well, and I don't
know if I agree with this.
You're acting as if
Walmart owns the royals.
It's a CEO of Walmart.
Can we find out how much those guys make?
Hasn't,
one of them written a book like the secret
to success and he sits there and his
fucking seersucker suit with his hand
on his fuck his head in his hand.
And that, that, you know,
that smile that Jay Leno smile where
you don't show your teeth, you know,
that's supposed to be like the relaxed.
It's EA. It's easy. I mean he's going,
you interviewed them many in it
and he talked to the guy who uh,
please a trumpet, um, how teams can
compete with a number of about, yeah.
It's not about how much
money the team has.
It's about how much the owners are
willing to invest on the team. No,
it is about how much it is
about how much money you have.
You don't have enough money to
invest into the fucking team.
Listen to this standard. It's not
about how much money the team has,
it's about how much the
owners are willing to invest.
So I guess he's making the leap now that
because this guy is a CEO for Walmart,
that he's now a multibillionaire.
God dammit. I love when I list,
when I find out my listeners
are just as dumb as I am.
He's not a multibillionaire.
Walmart itself takes in
billions of dollars every year.
And I know that because I've
never looked it up. Okay.
But they don't pay a CEO
multi billions of dollars.
I bet the Walmart family, the
upper echelon, the JP Morgans,
the incest you was family that
continues to fuck each other.
So the money stays in their family.
I law the fucking Rothchild family.
Right.
That's how you end up with a kid in
the attic, if you know what I'm saying
though yet. Cause I don't know what
I'm saying. All right. So anyways,
he says the Walmart guy doesn't
give a fuck about baseball,
so he doesn't risk the money on his. But
see, this is why I love being in bars.
This is what this guy's doing right now.
He just assumed that because the CEO of
Walmart is one of the owners of Kansas,
the Kansas city royals, that that
guy's a multi fucking billionaire.
And then with that knowledge that
he just pulled out of his ass,
he's now going to complete the
fucking dismount with this statement.
The Walmart guy doesn't
give a fuck about baseball,
so he doesn't risk his money on his team.
Yeah,
he doesn't give a fuck about baseball.
He just bought a God damn team. Um,
if he had the passion of Steinbrenner,
we would be talking about how the royals
and Yankees are ruining baseball and
see now that right there, if you
don't know what my podcast is about,
it's that email right there.
What you do is you start off with a piece
of information that actually is a fact,
and then you just run with it. You
know, if we were smart on this podcast,
what we would do is you'd be like, Oh
wow, that guy's a CEO at Walmart. Well,
let's find out how much he makes a year.
Does he own it by himself?
You know, let's find out what it
takes to run a fucking baseball team.
I mean,
you completely ignored the fact that
Kansas City is not a major media market.
That's another way that a,
the red sox and Yankees make a ton of
cash with the yes network and Nessun.
I mean, how many people even
live in Kansas City? Huh?
With your fucking rib
shacks out there. Um, I,
I do know what you're saying
because I know people in Pittsburgh,
they went through the roof when they
found out that the pirates were one of the
most profitable teams
in the league because a,
they don't spend shit on the team and
then they get all that welfare money from
the Red Sox, Yankees and whoever else
goes over the fucking salary cap.
Um, so there is an element of truth in
that shit. But uh, I'll tell, you know,
my favorite baseball team is right now.
I mean, I always root for the Red Sox,
but I fucking love the devil race.
The devil rays remind me of like the
orals in the 70s you know what I mean?
Where they just were a fucking,
just an unbelievable franchisee.
Orals in the 70s I
swear to God, they, the,
the level of pitchers that
they just one after another,
I don't know how they ended up
getting him. Frank Tenana, Jim Palmer,
they just always had these, these
potentials. Cy Young winning, I'm
winning pitchers and then like the
fucking third baseman in shorts,
shorts starts for like almost 30 years.
They were bringing up a
fucking hall of Famer.
They had like Frank Robinson,
Brooks Robinson,
cal Ripkin jr from the sixties
seventies into the 80s.
I guess frank and Brooke retired.
There was a little bit of a gap there.
Who to fuck paid poop play third base
for the Orioles in the 79 world series?
Uh,
going back too far,
I first thought thought I had
was Doug to Sensei Bobby gritch.
Those are like angels, I believe.
California angels, Rod Carew.
Why am I thinking of those guys? You
know, it's funny as I can remember,
all of the fucking pirates from the,
I guess cause they won.
Okay.
Eddie Murray played first base.
Willie Stargell played first
base for the pirates. Lily.
I can go right around the infield.
Tim Foley was second base. I can't,
I can only do half the fucking ed art.
Omar Marino,
Dave Parker. John Can Deliria
Kent to Colby. How come?
I can't remember even the fucking orals.
Remember that guy?
You remember that guy in the Orioles?
Maybe you can find this
picture on the MM podcast.
There was a guy in the Orioles who broke
his jaw and through the whole world
series he had half a football helmet.
Literally like the gray face mask.
I can't remember his fucking
name either. Ah, gives a shit.
I love saying is the fucking that
the devil rays in my God damn team.
I think that that they're the shit.
They don't have a lot of money.
They got a low payroll and they just
have the best prospects in the league and
they're doing it the old school way.
I got nothing but respect for him and
I'm slowly getting back into baseball.
Most of you know when David Ortiz
tested positive for some shit, I just,
I had to tap out.
You know what I mean?
That was like finding out the lone
rangers. A transvestite. It's just, yeah,
there's too much information. I
don't want to know that. Okay.
It's one of my heroes and it, it just,
you know, part of me died that day, so,
but I'm gradually coming back and I'm
coming back because of teams like the
devil race. I just want those teams
to fucking knock off the bigger teams.
I don't give a fuck. What do you can
chant 2007 at me. I don't give a fuck.
All right. Hey, Ron hit
his 600th, whole broad,
Eh,
you mean the Gao took steroids and had
a good 400 of those fucking home runs on
roids that guy.
But Gal came back who's allegedly clean,
but he's just as big as he
was when he was on roids.
Does any doctors out there can anybody
for the love of God explained to me how
the fuck you do roids get off a roids
and you come back and you'd just as
fucking big.
I think that means you're Rhonda,
then you're onto the next shit.
Although somebody I know who's really
into baseball stats was telling me that
when,
when he was on the shit,
he was hitting a home run
like every fucking 14 at bats.
And then,
uh,
he got off the shit and then it went
to like 18 at bats and now it's down to
like every 23 at bats. So maybe he's
not on the shit. I don't fucking know
why. Why am I just openly trashing
people with no information?
Cause that's what this fucking
podcast is about. All right.
A few weeks ago I talked about how
I, uh, or maybe it was last week,
how I was really into breaking bad and
that made everybody want to come out here
and start telling me what
their favorite TV shows are.
So here are some of
you guys can check out.
This is one I didn't even know
exist existed. Uh, moral Orel
and that was like a claymation show.
Is that what it was?
And it was on adult swim
and it got canceled,
but it really attach religion I guess.
Then I watched a little bit of it.
It was so fucking depressing.
I don't know if I can watch it.
I have to watch it now.
I guess it's just available on DVD.
Go on Youtube and check
out a couple of clips.
There's one where the fucking father is
walking around and it's a first person
shooter. Um, for those of you play
video games or watch porno, um,
it's in the first person and he just
keeps looking down at this whiskey glass
and he keeps drinking it.
Any hears his wife talking to their
child behind closed doors and the kids
going, why does daddy drink? I don't like
it when he drinks and she's just going,
oh, you got to understand
he's just a different person.
When he drinks it's okay.
And she's giggling and laughing
like he has no drinking problem.
Then she walks out into the hall,
does not see the father and she breaks
down crying for like 20 seconds.
It's fucking brutal. And then she looks
up and sees him who the whole time,
by the way, keeps taking sips of his
whiskey. When she finally sees him,
she immediately stops crying,
shuts down all of her emotion and
walks the other way down the hallway.
It's fucking, and I have to watch it.
All right, here's some other ones.
People recommended true blood.
I don't know what that is.
Psych and somebody
recommended honor entourage.
Evidently they still haven't picked up
the fact that it always ends the same way.
There's a problem and then they all
get on a jet and go to Vegas and it all
works out. Um, underrated.
Overrated for this week. Uh,
overrated. The dollar menu at fast food
joints, underrated, illegal immigrants.
Um, person. It did not give an
explanation on either one of those.
And I'm going to actually chime in.
Um,
overrated. This is cause I was in
a touristy place down in San Diego,
La Jolla. Um, overrated would be, uh,
any breakfast place that you have
to fucking stand in line for.
You know, that's the one
that the chick usually went.
All right,
I got another fucking a underrated for ya.
Underrated a fucking device that like
you let you know the batteries are gonna
wear out.
Sorry about that.
I was right in the middle
of the underrated overrated
in my fucking Olympus ls
10. Just fucking conked out on me.
Sorry about that. I was saying,
let me continue here.
Let me just give you guys a breather so
you can figure out what the fuck just
happened. Because the way I'm going
to edit this thing, I know it's,
it's just going to be really
choppy. Basically. Uh,
my battery's ran out so I was in the
middle of the underrated any of those
fucking breakfast places that have the
long lines at cause they have the best.
It's fucking eggs. It's never
worth the long line. Okay.
I'm not saying to go to some
shit place that has rubber eggs,
but there there's a, there's
another place close by, you know,
and every time he'd go to those
places with the long lines,
it's usually for the chicks because they,
they're just addicted to sugar and
they want to go in and get the fucking
stuffed French toast with the chine
cream cheese and the fucking ice cream on
top. Fuck all of that. All
right. You're a goddamn man.
Go get bacon and eggs at a fucking
diner and get on with your morning. Um,
I, and, uh, underrated,
I would say is a surfing.
I was down there, I am absolutely in San
Diego, absolutely fucking terrified of,
uh, the ocean. And I
watched these guys surf.
I had my little flip camera there cause
I was hoping someone was going to get
eaten by a shark or at the very least
attacked and I could have this fucking
awesome video of this guy
getting eaten by a shark.
And then he'd stick my
head in and be like,
I'm going to be at the Hampton Beach
Casino this fucking Thursday, you know,
the ultimate fucking promo video or
I guess Friday I'm going to be there,
you know? But, um, yeah, I
actually, I came real close.
I was going to actually do a,
I was going to take a surfing class when
I was down there and become the world's
first redheaded surfer,
you know,
and if I actually dominated in that sport,
do you realize that redheads would fucking
be dominating the surfing world from
fucking snowboarding all
the way to fucking surface?
And that would be it.
And when that ever happened,
you'd know that Jesus was
coming. Um, all right,
that's the fucking podcast for this week.
Uh, just to let you guys know this week,
on a Thursday, August 12th,
fuck, I'm going to be at the, uh,
Newport Yachting Center in Newport,
Rhode Island.
And on Friday the 13th,
I'm going to be at the Hampton
ballroom casino and a Hampton Beach,
New Hampshire. Um, please come out. Uh,
these are big venues, so bring as
many friends as you possibly can.
Tickets are selling well. So I want to
tell everybody I really appreciate it.
All the support out there and a,
and next week I'm playing a brand
new comedy club in Portland,
Oregon.
And I'm hoping there's a lot of you in
Portland right now out there in Oregon
going, Holy Shit, I don't even know. I had
no idea that there was a club out there,
nor did I know that bill's coming out
there where I'm letting you know I'm going
to be in Portland, Oregon.
Um, not this weekend,
the following weekend, Thursday,
Friday, Saturday. So let's see.
This Thursday's the 12th.
So that would be the night when I
just look at the fucking calendar.
Why don't I just look at the fucking
calendar? Yeah. The 19th, 20th and 20.
First I am going to be at the,
um,
at the, at helium helium
comedy club in Philly. Well,
the same guy opened one out there
in Portland, Oregon. All right.
Helium Comedy Club. I'm going to be out
there on the 19th 20th and the 21st.
So for the love of God, come
on out, check out the new digs.
I got a brand new hour.
And once again,
thanks to everybody who listens to the
podcast and also please don't take the
podcast seriously. All right. There's
always people doing that shit.
I got an email from somebody who
came out to my show down in La Jolla.
It was saying how he
had to drag his wife to,
to my show because,
uh,
all her girlfriends was saying that I
was misogynistic and anti fucking won
women because a,
their husbands listen to my podcast at,
uh, you know, I'm not
anti women, I just, I,
I just trash them.
So why don't you lighten up fucking horse,
uh, come out to my shoe. All
right, my house phone is ringing.
That's probably the landlord.
Where's the rent? I will talk to you guys
next week. Everybody have a great week.
Second,
he's
arguing with her diet and natural death.
He caught a nasty virus.
There was the ever present
football player, rapist.
They were all in love with time. They
were doing. Holly caught a bullet.
It all in head his leg. Well, why? We
should have been up there and got him.
And they were all in love with dye and
they were drinking from a fountain that
was pouring like an avalanche
is coming down the mountain.
Cheesy it show taste
my glows.