Hey, what's going on is Bill Byrd
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast, and just checking in on you.
Sorry. That's all right. I'm
just checking in you all.
You have a special guest who,
I don't know if you've ever heard that
intro before. We have Bret Ernst from the,
you're on the list podcast just added
to the all things comedy network.
He's got a ton of shit here. He also
has a, a standup special, hilarious,
special principal's office that you
can watch for free, free, free at, uh,
Brett comedy.com.
B R e t comedy.com.
You can watch it for free. God knows
all you fucking millennials. Love that.
You don't want to pay for shit. And
he's in the new, uh, Karate Kid,
Cobra Kai on youtube.
Red. Tell me about that.
That's a in route my
CIOs. Yeah. Wow. May 2nd.
Yeah, it was pretty cool, man.
Uh, yeah, the, the guys, uh,
I actually had him on the podcast, uh,
yesterday, uh, that executive produced,
um, hot tub time machine.
They did a Harold and Kumar,
and they're doing this too,
and they're doing this. Do you know
what's going to be quality? Yeah,
it's pretty cool man. And, and uh, uh,
basically it just picks
up with Johnny and, uh,
and Daniel when they're 15.
And if the FTC had Daniel Daniel runs a,
a car dealership in the valley and
Johnny's just down on his luck.
I'm fucking in now. Do they have the, uh,
what was the name of the actor who
played the Billy's app? William's ATPCO.
Is he in it? Yeah, he's in it. Fuck
yeah. Johnny's in it. And uh, it's,
it's pretty cool cause it's, uh,
they're given the,
they're screening the first two episodes
and theaters like across the country,
but like select theaters. But,
um, it just, it got into Tribeca,
which a Tuesday this
thing, you know, sometimes when they
reboot something, I'm just like, why? Um,
I'll just pay that. That's kind of weird.
I thought they kind of completed it. Um,
and you know,
there's some instances
where they literally have to
bring characters back from
the dead. Yeah. But we don't
have any CGI Miyagi in the, yeah,
but this one here,
what I like is they're not like hiding
the f the time that went by and that,
okay. Picks them up. They're in their 50s.
And I think that's a really, uh, you know,
interesting thing just as far as being
finally in a writer's room after all
these years on a show that I do is,
is just getting to write to that and
you get to fill in all of this cool like
backs
story. What happened if you
learn more about Johnny?
Like nobody ever really touched on,
you know,
cause people forget he was still a kid
in high school, you know what I mean?
But now, um, you learn a little bit
more about him, you know, and then, uh,
I play,
actually,
I don't want you to give
anything away, but he was, he
was a kid of divorce, right?
Yeah. His Dad wasn't around that, which
was perfect because that eliminated,
why wouldn't your dad,
she had a fight. They got rid of that
all. I mean, he had this, uh, what, 16,
17 year old kid with this, you
know, horrible Sensei and all that.
That was so impressionable on
them. But, um, it's pretty cool.
I'm talking to,
I don't know the character's name.
I thought you were talking about
the crime after you taught.
Ralph Machio is not named Johnny.
Johnny. Johnny. Johnny is a bed. Well,
I mean it's pretty,
I think a decorative,
I guess at that time where
I was a latch key kid.
Everybody had single moms and yeah.
Well Daniel's both your Penn.
Both my parents worked. So
we all had, we all had keys.
And I remember it had all the names of
the kids right by the door and we would
all grab our keys and then,
yeah,
you'd come home and whoever was the
oldest was running shit. Yeah. And uh,
could tell,
you know,
just had total fucking authority
could tell you to go to bed.
Like my older brother would tell
me to go to bed and I had to do it.
And if I did, he'd beat the shit out
of me. Yeah. The, you're like, dude,
you're only a year older than me.
Two years older than me.
But I started fighting back. So then
what he understood was like, all right,
I'll keep him under my wing.
And now I got a four year of
buffer between the next kid.
And then that's when his power
was solidified and I sold out.
I sold out all my younger siblings just
so I could stay up and watch fucking
deputy dog. Now. I was
the middle man, but, um,
my older brother had all the authority.
You and I would come home and you know,
he was like the man of the House at 1208,
nine 10.
I was a c sky was four years old.
Oh eight was a three or five. Five. Yeah.
So,
you know,
that lasts a pretty much most
of my taught you about power.
How quickly can become corrupt somebody,
how most people can't handle it. I said,
I'm really fascinated about the, so
Johnny is the Cobra Kai guy. I'm sorry,
but you're both, you're
right on both ends. Um,
I do think Johnny's father wasn't
around either, but Daniel, yeah,
Daniel had to learn from the
fucking maintenance because
he's got no father who better
than the guy that fixes the sink.
I think this is a, that's a
really brilliant way to go. And,
uh, I, I this, this seems like
a cool youtube thing cause I,
I feel if this was on a more major
network, they will be like, yeah,
but who are we gonna root for
and Blah, blah, blah. Like let's,
let's stab at based around the Ralph
Machio character. Well apparently,
I mean the, there was a lot of, you
know, there was a lot of offers for this.
I think, you know, the,
the Netflix of the world,
maybe even including Netflix that they
kind of bid on it and youtube red got got,
you know, they got the nod. So, uh,
Jesus, they, well they were telling us,
because I was asking them yesterday on
the podcast, the producers, I'm like,
you know,
through the process and everything and
they said they went into youtube red and
just figured, all right, this would be
like the practice pitch. And, but as,
as you know,
as they sat on it some more and saw the
interest in what they were going to be
able to do and it just became
more appealing and they went with,
I'm a big believer in that. I'm a
big believer in not taking the money.
If somebody else will give you more yeah.
What you want to do.
Cause then he goes down swinging
with what you want to do. And I,
I also, you'll get, you'll get
more control. You get more of a,
I saw this great thing one time,
uh,
this heavy metal band that
never made it and it just,
I forget what the name
of the documentary was,
but it just took them through
their whole career and uh,
how they just stayed together and
stayed together and stayed with that.
And Phil Hill just kind
of knows everything. He's
like Google. Oh, thank you.
Aaron and Aaron in the corner.
Um, Advil and this guy,
he just set this thing. He said
at the end of the day, he goes,
you'll better to own 100% of something
and sell 20,000 copies then to own
nothing and sell 20 million.
Like that's how bad you get fucked with
like all of the expenses and all of that
type of shit.
That was my thought process and giving a
special away for free is that, you know,
I put my own money into it and you know,
it wasn't cheap. I mean for me at least,
you know, as a comic, you know,
you're always check the check. So, um,
it basically like, I think
my next special, I'll try
and shop it, but excuse me.
Well, don't ever give up
ownership. No. Well, I, well the,
the thing for me was that this was
kind of a personal thing for me.
Like it's kind of like a one man show
in a standup format, but I only had one.
I only had enough money for one take.
I did it in a colony fitter in Burbank,
but the concept was basically I want to
own it because I found that dare you.
Well, all my other, that's
how, how dare you, well, the,
the thing that, that kind of,
there should be worried about exposure.
You're going to pay you an exposure.
Well the thing is too is that like all
this stuff that I did before on comedy
central show, I didn't own any of
it. I wasn't even able to share it,
you know what I mean?
On Facebook.
So I released it for free@brettcomedy.com
and you could go there and,
but the thing is you could just watch it.
You don't have to,
I mean you can give me your email if you
want. If you want to donate or I mean,
or own it,
download it for $5 or buy a tee shirt.
You get to download if you want to,
but you don't have to do anything.
I just want you to watch it.
And if you like it, you like it.
If you don't put your head on the desk,
you know what I mean?
We'll move on. It's fun. It's fucking
free. I remember early on I had a, uh,
I made a CD. I just stand up CD, that's
how long I've been like, you know,
way back in the day. And uh, I,
you know, put all my money up,
paid to have a recorded,
edited the thing,
the thing was done and then these
big guys came around and uh,
they were going to get it into stores.
This is 2006 right before every virgin
closed. And I was such an old school guy.
I was like, I want my CD and r
records store, you know, and,
and with the power of these guys feel get
me under the display towards the front
of the store. Right. And uh,
but I knew enough that I wanted to
retain ownership and they just kept,
they kept trying to get to own it and
it was like, I don't need you to own it.
It's done. I don't need any
money on this thing. I just,
I just need you to distribute it. And
this guy goes to me, he goes, well,
ownership shouldn't be that
big a deal to you, which it,
it cause what you should be concerned
about is exposure. So I said to him,
I go, all right, fair enough.
But if ownership shouldn't be
that much of a big deal for me,
why is it such a big deal for you? And
my manager was in the room and he goes,
great fucking question and this
guy stammered for about 15 seconds.
And then basically said, well, you know,
we got in business with these other comics
to make cds and their CDs bombed and
we have to make up the
money. It's just like, well,
it's not my fault that you got into
business with those fucking guys.
And the greatest thing I ever
did was retained ownership.
I ended up getting in business with
somebody else and that was like, you know,
hey, you get 60% we get 40% I'm like,
hey, that sounds like a good deal.
And then all the expenses come
out of my end. Yeah. And they get,
they get 40 off the gross.
I got 60 off the net and they end
up making more money than I did.
And to this day they tried to tell me that
that was a good deal. It's like, dude,
this thing came.
It's like we,
you always think like we're getting in
business together to make money off them.
And that's not how they do it. Of
course, like we're getting an, yeah,
they're going to fuck the people and
you and all the one he's going to go to
them.
My favorite thing is I get in business
with somebody else and all the money goes
to them and then when I get my cut their
names on my check and it's just like,
so how the fuck do I know what came in?
And then if you audit them,
then you get labeled as difficult to work.
It's like difficult to work with,
a difficult to steal from. And that like
I hadn't done one of these deals I had,
it was like,
um,
it's one of the DVD companies if I was
to audit them and they were off less than
like 8% than I had to pay for the audit.
And it's like what?
You just gave them a license to
steal seven and a half percent. Yeah.
And it's just like I'm telling you
the number one commandment of the 10
commandments that's fucking, uh, that's,
that's, uh, broken. May I've, maybe it's
line, but what I've seen is stealing,
like all of these fucking idiots who
are out there who are stealing on the
illegal side of stealing,
selling drugs. I mean,
anybody who's in the mob who
was smart eventually went legit.
So you could steal on the legal side.
Then you didn't have to hide your fucking
money and you could drive down the
street and you're fucking Bentley.
Well, I've never look, I
love our business. I love
the people in our business,
you know, but there's a good amount
of them that are just fucking garbage.
And I don't even know if the
garbage is just the weight, the,
it's like the way it was set up. Well,
when you first way it was set up,
you fit just clay in the game.
Like when you first come in,
this is why I love this era
of comedy and where we're at,
especially with the digital and the
Internet and stuff. Like, I always say,
I only need 1% of American a like
me and I'm good. That's it. Yeah.
That's then you know, even if, uh, even
if I can say a joke on stage, you know,
in a room full of fucking
adults and somebody's like, oh,
I don't fucking, somebody just
sent, somebody just sent me this,
this fucking article.
Somebody just sent me,
sorry article like this, I can't eat,
I can't even fucking read this. Uh,
but there are some scumbags,
every guy checks himself a little New
York comedy clubs adjust to me too.
And it's just like,
this is just like such like a,
you didn't even stick your head in the
comedy clubs, I'm seeing the opposite.
Yeah.
This like this backlash and there's
this time now to be more irreverent than
ever because you know, not all
feminists a bad, but these extreme ones,
like what they're doing now with these
articles is like the way we left Vietnam
where we go, hey, we won and they're
leaving. That's what this saying. Like,
I'm finding myself,
I'm saying shit on stage now.
I never would have gone that far. But
it's just like, cause you have to,
I mean we're all co you would have to
agree that we're contrarians by nature.
Yeah. Which would be funny
if you disagree, but I'm just
saying no, no, no, I don't.
He totally loved it over and
I missed it. No. Um, uh, but,
uh, even some of the women
are going the other way too.
Like I've been noticing a lot of comp,
a female comics doing jokes, you know,
where they wished, you know,
like in other words, now they're,
now they're not getting any action,
you know, and, and, but it's just
becomes inevitable where it just one
thing just gets it get, becomes exhausted.
Like it's all been said, we get
it. And then it's just like,
how many times can you keep
reiterating the same point?
I really believe that if con comics,
you know,
we're such a great think tank because
we really don't, I mean good comics,
you know, uh, cause you could sit around
and you have no real skin in the game.
It's more about the joke or the
perspective or, you know what I mean?
Anytime anybody
tries to fucking do that thing
where they go like, uh, you know,
like where they try to put
too much weight on a joke.
I always just gotten out to, no, it's
this, this is what I always say to them.
Like if they sit there like what you're
saying does influence people, blah, blah.
I just say to them, I say,
look, are you homophobic? And
they of course say, no. I go,
okay.
And during a 60 minute set that I do,
what Joe could I tell that
would then make you homophobic?
How could I undo everything that you
were taught in 60 what, how many,
how many of those jokes where I
have to do so my point of that is,
is is people come in, I'm so sick of
talking about this too. People come in,
okay, they're, they're, they're adults.
Their brains are fully formed and they
have their ideas and you amount of times
I say shit and it's just like people
take it a completely different way is one
of the cool things about like somebody
listening to the music comedy or anything.
It's, it goes into your brain and your
experience and how you interpret it.
But like it's not my
responsibility to babysit you.
And if you take it in some really bad
fucking way, you walked in with that shit.
Cause if I had the power to undo your
26 years of experience with a couple of
fucking jokes than standup,
comedy would not be legal.
They wouldn't let a fucking
moron like me go on stage.
Hey, I haven't read about shit.
You know what I think about Syria?
I mean I always not disarm myself,
but I always, I am a jerk off.
I know I'm a jerk off. I'm not, I'm not
like, you know what I mean? Like I don't,
I don't take myself seriously. I have
the high school transcript to prove it.
You can always go and get it,
dude. You're, you're, you're,
you're not as dumb as you
say. I was like, yeah, I am. I
am. I, I'm good. You're just,
you're watching the one
thing that I'm good at,
which is basically acting like a
fucking idiot. But if you got me on, uh,
and I could do like a, like
basic jobs, you know what I mean?
Like I was a fucking like,
workhorse.
If you told me to go over there and pick
up all those boxes and stick them over
there,
I would fucking crush that.
But if you wanted me to come up with
a machine that could fucking make that
easier to do that, yeah.
I'm out. I'm like, well,
fucking lunch pail Louie.
I'm a moron.
What makes me laugh too is that even
the comics that take themselves so
seriously in a sense is like, dude, like,
you know that the exact game that we were
on as take themselves seriously hacks,
think they're fucking change in the
world because they're too fucking,
we're just realized they stink here.
I realize.
So I was on a plane that
we had to emergency land.
Okay. And um, was always fun.
Some do, try to kill another two next
to him started choking him and shit.
Like we were literally five minutes in
the air and, and I'm like, fuck, cause I,
I was going to miss my gig that night,
you know, that's all I care about. Oh,
we not crashing now I will. Why are
we going? I gotta I gotta make my Gig.
You know, he tried to kill the
gun and he starts choking to dude.
So a then the guy who had proceeded
it was all way in the back.
I think the guy just flipped on him.
It was like some dude that wasn't,
I'm going to go with the armrest.
There's an armrest fight guy.
So, uh, anyways, long story boring. The
guys obviously playing it up now that he,
you know, so they start now else in the
back, don't know what's going on. Okay.
So the, the stewardess
runs back. So we do,
is there anybody here in the
medical profession, you know, in,
in the medical field,
a couple people get up.
I see a guy that was a cop get up, a guy
who was a fireman. She should've said it.
Attention everyone. There's nothing wrong
with the plane. Well, they made that day.
Say they came back, it came back to us. I
mean, this is after they were asking for,
for everybody.
That would have been the back.
How the fuck is a cop
going to fly the plane?
But the point being is that they said
all these people started getting up,
and that's when you realize that your
job is just so fucking useless. Oh yeah.
It's like I, in any I, I'm not
even, I just need to watch and may,
you know, unless they're like, hey,
can you come up and do five minutes
to cheer everybody other than that,
what the fuck? All these people have a
real purpose. And I'm not saying we don't,
but you know, if you're doing the Maslow's
hierarchy thing, comics are not like,
we're like junk food. Absolutely. You
know what I mean? Is this a comfort food?
Kind of fuck it. That's what we are.
We're Mcdonald's not nutrition. Yeah. So,
well, I would say you're
going to be hungry again for
knowledge 10 minutes after
watching my act. Yeah. Like, if
you're, if you're learning from me,
that's there's some off. It's sad.
And if anybody ever said that to me,
I'd be like, oh no, no, sorry to pointed
towards the library or something.
Like all these comics
think they're Carlin, but,
and I don't think there's a lot of that
though. There's a lot of political,
I was going to say,
especially in like the
open mics where,
and even not,
there's a couple of younger comics that
were talking to me that they coined a
term called clap there. What is that like?
These college has all, they don't laugh.
Well, they just, Larry just makeup, make
a statement and everybody's like, yeah,
you know,
like I used to call that was the Oprah.
You do need to get a job. Just
started. Fucking clapped her.
Well, I think, uh, you know, if, if
you're online all the time and like,
you just get stuck into that
fucking swirl, a rabbit hole of,
of that shit where it's
just like, uh, you know,
when people just start posting these,
this information that you need to know,
it's like, where did you get this?
Who the fuck are you? And uh, uh,
there's a couple, two words I hate the
most on the as curating and algorithm.
If I see that anywhere, I just fucking,
I just, cause I gotta be honest with you,
like even like I, as much as I love
Netflix and everything like that,
it's like you watch one season of Narcos,
your whole fucking thing is just now
going to be all drudge or dealers behind
many scenes of prisons in San
Quentin. The real, the real fucking,
it's just like, you know, you
almost get offended. Like,
you know this more to me than just that.
So I actually looked at it, but like,
um, when my, when I did my last special,
when I went in there and they showed
me how the algorithm worked, I mean,
I was fucking blown away, but like,
so maybe it isn't their fault.
Maybe I'm such a fucking moron that I
watched too many. They're just like,
we give up on this guy, let's just,
well, I'll share one with my wife.
And she's always like,
oh, I watched Carter
serious. She's like, what? He fucking 12.
You know, I would love them
to bring back as Johnny quest.
Johnny quest was all right. I wasn't,
yeah, I gotta be honest with you, man.
It wasn't a big fan of that.
You know what I loved about Johnny Quest?
If you fell off a cliff, you'd died.
And that blew my mind. He got shot.
You fucking died. Like people were
dying. You were used to bugs bunny where,
but just came back. Yeah. Wiley
Coyote turn into a fucking accordion,
gave you a look like, well that didn't
work and then it comes back totally fine.
It should have been in a
fucking wheelchair. Um, let's
get back to, let's get a,
by the way, I saw a meme talking about
the Facebook shit real quick. Um,
I was dying laughing. It was a
general and it says, uh, well, we,
we bombed Syria. Let me go into
Facebook and see what the experts
need to know what our next move is.
I go to Facebook and find out
what all the experts say. Yeah.
I'd be honest with you. I don't understand
that whole part of the world. I,
the people that were
fighting and all that.
But I also know that I
haven't read up on it,
but I just look at it like the people
finding don't have a plane or a boat,
I just don't get how they're going
to get us. I know nine 11 happened,
but they caught us with their pants down.
So all you have to do is just,
what does Israel do? Israeli hasn't had
a hijacker unit of a plane and like,
I don't know how many years in the front
and then when they watch the planes all
night so it's not even a fucking option
and they're sitting right in the middle
of that Hornet's nest over there and
they're able to survive it. So, uh,
I dunno, I might host, I'm just
worried about us financially.
Just I feel like those,
these fucking jerk offs that dragging
us into the deep water here and uh,
you know,
the whole,
there's more than one way to skin a
cat and it's just because, you know,
realistically,
why would you ever try to fight us?
We could literally blow up the whole
fucking thing with one push of a button if
we wanted to. But um, I dunno. Maybe
somebody over there as good at math.
I can and knows it better than I do,
but I just sit there like this
debt debt wakes me up at night.
That's why I tried not to. I try
to like, uh, keep all of my shit.
I'm not good with it. So like anytime
I see a store channel that stuff, no,
no, I do. I am a fucking
onestop operation.
I handled the whole fucking thing.
Oh, it's a couple of days later and
now I'm doing the advertising. Oh,
Billy sniffles. Oh, Billy
sniffle got a cold. All right.
Me On [inaudible] I can't breathe out.
Mind knows to do through to me all these
me undies. I'm going to use my mouth.
That's how it goes.
Both breathing more on in the south.
Shut the fuck up. Just close your
mouth. No one cares about your ar 15,
or the fact that Trump's gonna build
a wall. Put on your Randy's. Sorry.
Um,
fuck. Is it, uh,
beyond ace me undies.
You've heard me talk about [inaudible]
and you know that I am a big believer in
their products. I believe that when you
put them on, they cover your privates.
They're the perfect
balance of comfortable fit.
Every month they have new and exciting
prince and they arrive at your door in a
fun bag.
Me undies uses Lenzing micro modal,
modal and their underwear.
It's a sustainably sourced natural soft
fiber that starts with beechwood trees
and ends with you not giving
a fuck what they do with it.
You balls will feel great.
That's what you need to know
beyond the Oreo clam me undies.
Adventurous prints and designs are all
limited additions and new patterns are
released every few weeks
on a rolling basis.
100% satisfaction guaranteed me undies
guarantees you will loves your undies or
you'll get your money's back. Me undies
has a great opera for my listeners.
Anytime you purchase me a fear what the
first time purchase you get 20% off free
shipping. This is going to be
too long to send via phone.
Me undies is so sure you'll
love their underwear.
They offer a hundred percent
satisfaction guarantee.
If you don't let the first pair,
you get a full refund and you give your
old underwear to some tweaker out front,
this is no brainer.
Get 20% off your pair and the most,
the most comfortable undies you'll ever
put on to get your 20% off first pair,
free shipping and have
sense aspect guarantee.
Go to me undies.com/ [inaudible]
that's [inaudible] dot com slash Barb.
Yeah, I'm somehow, I'm still an
asset. You know, even do dishes too.
It's just,
it's just fucking,
I actually enjoyed doing dishes and
cleaning up because I'm a fucking lunatic.
I can't sit still. I don't
know how to, you know,
time I could fucking relaxed as if I'm
smoking a cigar and I'm off him right now.
Let me ask you this question added,
uh, uh, if you were to say you had one
of those, uh, the popular
three that comedians have,
the add a check. Oh, CD don't have that.
Um, depression. I had a, I
didn't have the chemical one.
I was just walking around
bummed out for a long time.
I didn't realize it cause I was always
like that. Well there's depression,
throw intelligence, you know,
like, like in other words,
and not saying you're intelligent but
not saying like you,
you see all these patterns and you just
see like what the fuck is wrong with
people. Like, you know, uh, and it
just gets to you because that used to,
but I know how to, I know how to talk my
way out of that. I got, as I got older,
I co I just see, oh two we
used to get into it. You and
I was just sports. I mean,
and that's what, no sugar,
sports politics. So we get
into a politics solitude.
We would, we would just have
her eyebrows all the way up.
I thought we were on the same page with
that. I think it was mostly sports.
I think the one time
we got into it as I do,
I remember I had to like literally tell
myself the next time you and Brett get
going,
you have to be the guy that taps out.
And I started tapping out
and we have, we've been good
ever since. Well I said no,
it never got ugly, but we would, it would
be like Unitus. We both agreed on Johnny.
It was something important.
Like that was,
I think he wanted to kill me at the time
cause I think I said Elway over Brady.
I went, I went Montana La Brady
and you went, what do you know?
I don't know problem with that.
No.
At the time he did know I did it because
now I do remember I hit you. Oh No.
You know what?
It was some different cause I was
always the guy people going like Brady's
better than Montana. Once he
got four rings, I said, Dude,
Montana needed four tries to get
four rinks. Brady needed six.
And then once he got his
fifth I said, okay, now we got
his faith. But my holistic,
my whole list has changed now because
the, the year that they, that, uh,
Denver went is when I texted you and
I said this this year Brady, really,
not that it matters that he impressed me,
but I'm like,
this year I was really impressed with
what he had to deal with. And you're like,
yeah, but it was always over sports. I
mean, the, the politics stuff, I don't,
I think we were on the same page
when a lot of it, if I can recall,
there was some huge fucking, Oh, who
cares? Football logging. I can't remember.
All right. I didn't know. I
forgot you played drums too.
You said you do on your podcast.
Like, I mean, I'm, I'm, I
am, I used to have a set,
a trap set. I played for years and then,
uh, my grandmother salted, but you know,
every once in a while I'll go into the
guitar center and, and start, you know,
playing on the, Oh, you got it. But when
I opened free, get those Fucking v drums.
No, you got again, you get those fucking
things, man. I'm telling you like, uh,
you know, um, and like when I lived
in an apartment in New York, I,
I just put like this, I forget, it was
some sort of foam rubber thing down.
And then I built like a little riser on
top of that and then foam rubber on that.
And then I put the kid down or something
like that. And what I want to know, wait,
it had to be solid so that things
would stand out. I don't know.
It was a home run to that,
but I,
and then I went downstairs to the
guy below me and say, hey listen,
I played drums as a hobby
and he's looking at me like
you motherfucker. I said,
no, here's my phone number.
I go, I work at night. You
work during the day? Yeah, go.
I'll only play between 11
and two during the day.
If for whatever reason you take a day off,
you have a day off,
call me the second you call me,
pick up the phone, Sam downstairs,
I will immediately stop. I mean, how
could you have a problem with that?
And you know what?
This fucking asshole did.
Fucking three months later I'm playing
like two in the afternoon and my phone
rings and I go, hello. And he
goes, we can knock it off. Yeah.
The first time I said,
hey buddy, I got you. Fuck
fucking saying that. Like you said
it to me 20 times. Go Fuck Yourself.
And I hung up. I never talked to
him again and he never called again.
But I still only played during the day
and I wouldn't play weekends either.
Now if he's watching Conan or something,
he's like this tight desta drummer
guy that lived upstairs from me.
He must've switched careers. The thing
cause he sucked it drums. It was terrible.
You said you do on your a,
you're on the list podcast.
You do a lot of top 10 stuff. Yeah,
we just list shit. I mean again it's,
it's arguing with your friends over
dumb things, which is all right.
You got one for me. Well let's start it.
Let's try to get the fires going to get,
we can do fine. We can do top five.
I mean this is more your opinion.
I might show him, you know, it's not so
much me sometimes. Although a, I've, I've,
I've gotten a little hot hot
headed like over dumb shit.
Hockey I keep for over rocky three, you
know, stupid shit. That's important.
It is very important in the
scheme of what matters to you.
You're living your truth. You should start
a blog about it. Um, I was gonna say,
did you want to discuss who
and who the top athletes,
Boston athletes are of all time?
Like would you take Brady over bird,
do you think he's number one.
Oh,
and then the next one could have been top
top. We don't have to do 10. We can do,
he can't get rid of Larry.
Larry's like in that,
especially now looking back 30 years and
his stuff is still amazing and I know
Brady is going to be amazing
too, obviously, but uh,
and I know he's won two
more than Larry One. Uh,
my thing about Larry was
if I could go back in time,
the second he started to do the blacktop
on the driveway, I'd be like, Larry,
let me, let me do that. Let me do that.
There is such like a fucking call
a guy and cheap. Well, the, the,
you remember those when you blacktop or
driving that little fucking brush they'd
give you? Yeah. Yeah. That was not
made for a six foot nine, six foot,
10 inch guy and he blacktop
his own fucking driveway.
Rather than paying somebody that whole
blue collar, I'll do this myself.
And he fucked up his back. It was
never, it was never the same after that.
I was going to say, uh, uh, or I tell
them if we're doing, if smoke coke,
if we're doing a, if, yeah, if we're,
if we're doing championships, I mean,
then you gotta you gotta
Throw Bill Russell obviously
no bill Russell's the top.
Yeah, it would be bill Russell is
the same and he's got 11. Right.
So a lot of people leave him out.
I put them in my top five and then,
then you got Ted Williams and then you've
got Bobby Orr who totally changed the
game. Bobby Orr was, Wayne Gretzky
says, that's the Guy Wayne Gretzky goes,
that's the guy. So, um, you
know what it is at this point.
There's so many people at Boston
now. Well, I just love arrogant. Now
we're off and, and you're, you don't
have to go that far back last. No,
you don't have to know and don't.
And uh,
and that was going to say two or why I
would put my top 10 in Boston athletes
cause he's my, he's, he would be your don
Mattingly was wade Boggs. I like books.
I used to like, wait. Yeah, no. And I
might throw Andre tip it in there as well.
Andre tip though also there's a, there's
all a lot of great guys that never got,
uh, I mean, I mean Jim Rice, we had to,
we had rice, Fred Lynn call your strengths
ski. We just had all straps, keys.
Yeah. All of these great guys that,
uh, you know, and I always hated that.
Um, I always make fun a day. I don't
hate people. I hate dance show and see,
I just like breaking his boss.
Um, but like he wrote that book,
the curse of the baby and it was just
such a cop out where you just don't even
address, granted, I never read the book,
but I just looked at the title and I
judged a book by its cover and, um,
it's just, was such a cop out. It's just,
I thought that we were just
a really bad franchise.
We were a bad franchise and we would
like the flyers with the flyers,
got two one, two cups by beating the fuck
out of the league. And they were like,
that's what works and that's
what the fuck we're going to do.
And now they're finally coming out of it.
But do they had like a 30 40 year
fucking hangover of trying to continue to
debate.
The third is more fair that
that trajectory bullies
a doc is fucking amazing.
Incredible. Yeah. But they were so
successful winning back to back.
You've got to stand.
They will only in the league since
67 and they won that first cup. It's,
they went back to back 74 75 they're
seventh and eighth year in the league.
And everybody's like, this is the future.
And that almost destroyed hockey. And um,
they just continued.
It was okay during the 80s cause it was
still a lot of that left. But in the 90s,
early eighties,
it was still,
I remember going to Brendan Byrne Arena
and watched the devils and flyers go.
And it, we, we just went just for that.
For the fights. Yeah.
Dude, it was, it was crazy.
The first like nine
Bruins games I went to,
I would only go if they
played the Canadians cause
I knew there was going to be
a bunch of fights. And there's a
classic one on Youtube where, uh,
there's a bench clearing brawl back
when the benches facing each other,
the old Boston Garden and I,
Chris Island was walking off the ice
and according to him somebody threw
something at him.
I don't know what happened.
He pushed Ken Lindeman and
then a little Ken Lindemann,
the rat goes down after this heavyweight
Niland and all of a sudden to those
like cops involved in that, the bench
is cleared. And I was at that game.
See, the thing was sports to me now and
again, man, I know the athletes are,
you know, better, but the uh,
no, that's, that's what it,
Papi, I got to put pickpocket
again in the 10. Yeah,
he might even be five. That's what
we were arguing. And he turned,
I remember when Ramirez
know that Jerry Rice thing,
that he was faster than lightning and
you were like, how the fuck is a facet?
And I said, I saw this sports. That's what
it was. And like how the fuck is that?
Yeah, you can't be. But it
was a sports that I saw.
But getting back to the athletes
today are not a scientist thing.
What's more document or you moved your
hands around? It's a sports thing.
Like be like, hey, we're
wizards. No, uh, uh,
but we saw m o w o get back and believe
I and I wasted a good 40 minutes of my,
almost a headlining set, which is
technically 45 minutes, 45 minutes.
This argument. Do you though that? I
mean there's a part of me that enjoys it,
especially with people that are,
uh,
I mean not when you get worked
up over stupid shit, but I mean,
but that's just inevitable.
Maybe the cause the German in us.
Maybe that's what it is. But I do like
that the mental, the mental chatter.
It's like, like the, the point for
point. Because, you know, I don't,
I don't really do, you don't really
get that a lot. That's why exactly.
We're comics like regular civilians.
I hate going. I haven't done it.
Have you ever done it? And
you're, and you're in it. Yeah.
Having a great time and all of a sudden
you look around at the other people's
faces just walking away
or worse laughing at you.
What are they arguing? But comics
get it. I like, I, I don't,
I don't do well with civilians.
That's like when we go out to
dinner with like some random couple,
I'm just so fucking bored,
man.
Care about your kids and oh no,
no conversations on idol the whole night.
You got to act on my kid and the kid
playing soccer, I blah, blah, blah, blah.
That's great. That's wonderful. Yeah.
And you try to re thinking about going
to Mexico and all of a sudden they have,
or what do you think of Trump's okay.
Shift policy.
And my wife just starts kicking me and you
know, like, we need something here now.
You can't, yeah, you can't do that.
And I started telling you about some
fucking w winery that you can visit and
it's good for the kids because
they have a little zoo,
he can feed pigeons and there's
a fucking horrible, I know.
And then the worst and they see
you and just like, I just haven't,
it's on my face. I can't do it. Like
I need to stop doing this to me.
But like there was this time,
every time we would go to a fucking
party afterwards on the drive home,
I would get like this whole breakdown.
Well I guess I do actually I'm a bit
where I talked about the report card. Oh,
is that what I needed to
tell you that before we get
into it? Oh yeah, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no. They all do it.
You get this fucking report and you think
he had to go, what is your report? Yeah,
I know I had a good game,
but, and then they're like,
you think and then they break out this
fucking report card and you're like,
what the fuck can you think documented?
Here's the thing,
can you fucking imagine the hell
fire if you ever did it to them?
You can't. You can't. You can't. It's so
funny. My, my wife tells me what to wear.
Sometimes. You look, why
are you always dressed?
She always tells me that you're
dressed like a bouncer. Cause I just
know it's the thing about women,
they will step up your fucking wardrobe
as I'm dressed like a complete book was
I was going to wear my Adidas tracksuit
and I said, if I come in with this,
he's going to fucking murder me. No,
no, no. You're and your record with, no,
I'm wearing this because I'm doing one
of those all things, comedy, poker thing.
So I'm like a fucking, I was
born, but I had an Adidas one day.
No. Um, but you know,
it was funny. We were,
I Sebastian's a party,
remember, uh, for the,
for the baby. And uh, you were
fucking hammered and, and we were,
we were hanging out in town, you know,
I was 22. I went to go take a picture.
I was by his pool and
somebody backed into my hand,
like barely touched my hand and I dropped
a full whiskey into his fucking pool.
I was so empowered. It's a bad school
now, dude. It's fine. It's fine.
Was I had hammered? No, it wasn't. No,
I always, I'm seeing that a good way.
Cause we were all, we were all
drinking and it wasn't a lot of drink.
I was watching our wives and they just
look at us from a distance and my wife's
nervous. I can tell when we were
having a great time, I like, dude,
we're going to run a fucking
yacht in the Mediterranean. We go,
all of us that we made, we made the
plan guys, it'd be 300 bucks a piece.
We have an a great tire. We'll get the
fucking NFL network. We'll film it. Yeah.
And I'm just like, you're
special. You are like, yeah,
we were having a great time and I'm
watching my wise and they're just nervous.
They're just watching going,
what the fuck is going to happen?
I really don't think women
get our relationships. Uh,
like I, I find that men, we,
I mean, at least me and my friends, we
bond through conflict in a sense. Like,
like if I know you're an eagles fan
and you know, I'm a cowboys fan,
I'm expecting you to go on
your soup, you know, uh, uh,
it's weird to say like watching
them argue on real housewives. Well,
they loved the drug when we act like real
housewives over sports for some reason
that this is the thing they, uh, I've,
I've been really, uh, I've been trying,
uh,
I guess the most accurate way to describe
this as I've really been trying not to
be me in my relationship.
It's so fucking hard as I like, I'm
starting to feel like that is the problem.
Like, no, we get along
great, but when there's,
when there's work to be done in the
relationship, it's, it's always now,
Bill, you're this, this and this. And
like one time I was hanging out with this,
this, uh, we were treading on hard hit.
What trend? We got to be careful at this,
at this party. And I don't give a shit,
but like my wife's cool. She'll fucking,
she doesn't listen to me anyways. She
has, I forget what the other way might.
My wife hasn't been to a stand up
show of mine like three fucking,
she doesn't need her. She lives with me.
Shit. My wife is sick of it. Yeah. I mean,
and it's not conducive for what? Like,
you know, it is for like, you know, that,
can you imagine having to watch your wife
talk for an hour? Can you imagine two?
Why would you do that? Why would you do
that? That the person is same thing, ah,
over it. Why would you put
them through that? I have,
I have total fucking empathy for
my work when it comes to that shit.
It's just knows. So what other
stuff? That's why I do the dishes.
What I also found that I got to get
something in the good and the good side of
the ledger. On the scorecard.
Yeah. Something. I, I,
uh, I, um, I've found that
my wife, uh, you know, when,
when the one thing I've found attractive
about her is that she was not laughing
at some of the Shit I was saying. And
I'm like, okay, this girl's, yeah,
like in my Robin Shit when I was
younger and stuff and you know,
cause I was kind of a bad kid and a bad
early adult and you know, and she's like,
you know, I, I don't find that, you know,
I mean, I get why people think it's funny,
but, and I'm just like, all right,
this is a normal person because
I grew up in so much dysfunction.
You have morals, it's this,
this, this is new. I said,
I grew up in so much dysfunction that I
didn't realize I grew up in dysfunction.
Like you think your shit's normal
until you meet normal people and then,
and then you're like, you
know, like, oh, you know, you
have a dad saying to you, you,
you meet dialed down people. Yeah. They're
not normal because eventually you just,
you realize that on some level
they're out of their fucking mind.
It's just not the kind of automated mine
that's going to get you arrested. Well,
like nobody in my wife's family knows
anybody that's been to jail and I know
like 15 people, you know, and tell me
what you know, circle. So I don't know.
But I'm saying to me and my friends,
you know,
you think that shit's normal and then,
but it's not like I've met people.
Those are like the tips you're getting.
Like how to survive in jail as a part of,
it's supposed to.
You need two years of a language and
I have a couple of extra curricular
activities so you can get
into a good school though.
There are people that are around it,
people that are in it and
people that are about it.
I was just around it and I kind of dip
my toe in it and I, and I actually, uh,
again, not to preface it by saying
on stage that, uh, I'm, I'm, I just,
because I committed crimes as a mean,
I'm a criminal and yes it does. No,
it doesn't. Millennial Shit.
No, it's not. If you ever,
if you ever hang out with a
fucking criminal, it's just
a whole different breed.
And when you're like saying,
I played high school football,
I'm not a football player. Yes you are.
You're not a pro. What do you got to kill?
Somebody says why? We argue. I'm
saying is that like, yeah, okay,
you commit crimes, you know, you know,
but when you're younger it's not,
you're not a, there's a certain type of,
all right, how about this Joe? Bob,
you don't get a fucking party.
Doesn't make you a comic. Okay.
But it makes you funny. Oh,
worked. If it worked this,
I just want a picture and you want like
the, you know, the draft day for the NFL,
it's for the mob and you're waiting to
get that call and it's like the seventh,
eighth round. He just didn't get it. You
got on the taxi squad that League folded.
Yeah. You got on the taxi squad
and everything and you would never,
you just weren't, uh, you
didn't quite make it to the mop.
So you weren't like you were in
a career criminal. But a few,
I just like my wife and she's normal
and her families, uh, you know, norm,
that was the point you were trying to
turn into a big argument. Okay. No,
but I get what you're saying.
I'm not trying to sugarcoat and it just,
it is what it is. What, say you,
Erin, what would you say? It's the,
because there's different levels.
Cause there's, there's a punk,
there's a dirt bag,
and then there's a criminal and then
as a career criminal and then there's a
psycho. Where would you say
he, he's on that spectrum.
It's like he was a punk.
He, he grew out of it.
Know that was a juvenile delinquent.
Yeah. James Fairness to him.
He never said what he did.
But I have to figure if somebody said I
committed crimes that's beyond, you know,
writing, just stealing, shit, stealing.
Like I stole a car in middle
school and then that's a
felony. I know. And then, um,
me and my brother, we on a car is he
like, you'll go to jail for that. But my,
I just rode shotgun and
laugh. The whole kind of car.
I don't even remember. It was like
an 85 80 I tried to steal a car.
She was actually a truck. We've tried
to steal a truck. Did you? This,
we got in it and then we were looking for
keys on the visor and we couldn't find
it. So then we just pushed it
down the hill into a river.
And I see now that's just being dumb.
And you know what I mean? That's not,
you're not a criminal.
I remember,
I remember we were pushing all the
wheels were like locked and then when
something snapped and it was going, I
remember pushing it and laughing so hard,
I couldn't feel my legs and we almost,
we will,
we was shit faced and trying to
run back to the car drunk laughing.
It just what you did.
And then I remember we all had to get
ruined some but then we all had to get the
fuck out of there. God, I haven't
thought about that in tribe.
We all have to get the fuck out. And I
remember the next day my buddy going,
I feel like we got cheated out of that
laugh cause we all had to fucking just
will you the funniest side of
your friends during the day too?
Well I've got broad daylight and
you were drunk and we were drunk.
Was it summer or some shit?
Nah somebody somehow that was the winner.
It was the weekend and somebody somehow
had got a case of beer and you know one
of the steels you just start drinking
like in, you know I got an idea.
Well you know how like you're uh,
like the way you drink when you first
drink is like give me that shit about like
it's way worse to like if
there's a poisonous snake
its way worse to get bitten
by a baby one than a,
an adult because the adult knows it'll
give you just enough to fuck you up.
But the baby, just a baby just like
both barrels. That's how you drink.
Like when you're an adult and you drink,
you're a gentleman, you sip and shit,
you know, you like Gleason in the
fucking the hustler. Right. But Nike,
when you're a kid,
you're fast Eddie,
and you're sucking it down your fucking
mess. That's the way we were drinking.
And we ended up, you know,
and we were under age.
So you end up in a
parking lot of the woods.
Now here's when we were in a parking lot.
Here's the difference. To my point now,
let's just say that I'm, I'm
with my friends and there's
one kid that's like, hey,
I have an idea. Let's break
into this dude's apartment.
Okay. And then you're like,
okay, cause it'll be fun to
break in somebody's apartment.
But this guy has got other motives.
Like he's like, he's like, Nana,
I know we're going to take the credit
cards, I'm going to take the keys.
Like he's got it planned out, but I'm
in it just because I think it's fun.
You're in it for the story.
Yeah. And the last, yeah, the
story. Absolutely. You know,
when you're a young dude and you're
trying to get a rep, you know, and,
and you're just so,
that's when you commit the crime.
But then there's the guy
that's like, no, no, no. Oh,
he sees a future like he's when he's
like here's what you're going to need to
put a house on this. Yeah. And then this
other guy's going to have to pay for.
Absolutely. It's a different city.
We're never going to get caught.
That would be a huge,
that would be the difference between like,
cause when when my buddy pulled up with
the car I jumped in the car and we just
went cruising and then we ended
up wrecking it. It was four of us.
I would love to tell this story one time
about that night cause it was four of
us,
me and my,
well you should tell it on your podcast
if you're on the list and I won't do it
now. Yeah. Is that a
passive aggressive way?
Is Asia it shut the fuck up with
the story or is that it like,
cause it seemed like he didn't want to
tell it now if you want to tell it now,
I will say no,
it's not even that long.
I'm just saying like if I could ever
write a short film or something. Oh,
it was just an interesting night
that the two of us, the four of us,
two of us got pinched
in the other two didn't,
and they didn't rat you out or anything?
No. Did you ever, I'm the only time we,
we still a case of beer out of a,
out of a fucking liquor store
and the whole thing was like a,
as soon as the deal. So we
came up with this idea of, oh,
I can't tell this story because we just
don't use names because we're, we're,
we're, we're doing some of it, uh,
on a project that I'm working on,
so I can't, I can't give this away, but
we bet we're fucking, we're given these,
these people like blue ball story,
blue blow, Paul's here. Um, you know,
the deal says basically you fucking walk
in the oldest guy looking kid and you
just fucking, you walk in,
you stay online, you know,
you act like you're going to pay and
it'll last second. You fucking run out.
And uh, yeah, it was one of those things.
You're going to grocery stores when I,
I mean, I had no money, man. And, um, I'm
like 19. I was washing dishes at Hooters.
I had like three, I was bouncing at a
nightclub, washing dishes at Hooters.
I was trying to do something with my life.
I was going to have to clean the
grease trap. That's the fucking worst.
I mean we don't do it every
night cause cause that's not bad.
Ours was every three months.
It be three months.
Agree to clean the fucking fryers,
man.
That was a pain in the empty all the
oil out. I was a prep cook. I robbed,
I robbed every place I worked
for. Man. That's how I ate.
I used to kangaroo pouch,
my apron. And then when I was like
prepping food, I would put it in my apron.
I had a few. Fuck you mean that's
how you ate? Uh, well I was,
I was pretty much on my own.
I mean I was,
I was one of those losers that
went away to community college.
I'd never heard of that. You
know, I never even went to, no,
it does it. That's the point. I'm
crashing at some other dude's apartment.
And then, um, I was trying to go to school
and just try and get my life going, man.
And, and um, when I worked there,
I just used to stack up on food out of
cooler and the trunk. Oh, you will bro.
Okay. Okay. All right. But
I've told this story before.
I was working in this restaurant and
there was this guy who worked there and he
fucking,
he lost his license for drinking and
driving so many times that there was no
date that he was going
to get his license back.
And this was the 80s and he had lost it.
This is right when mothers against
drinking or driving came out.
Like he did the level of fuck up.
You had to be,
and he was about 34,
35 and he already had the gin.
Blossom knows, he looked like
he looked like WC fields. Yeah.
And he was 34, 35. Right. And, uh,
so he used to ride this moped to work.
I was living in North
Carolina and he survived this
moped to work and he lived in a
trailer park. So this fucking moped,
he didn't have a driver's license.
This was it. This was it for this guy.
Like this was his motive.
Fucking transportation.
I remember he taking like
an on cold winter days,
he would come to work and he would
always be drunk and hungover,
see which shower late.
And he would come to work and
his hair would still be wedding.
Even had frost on his hair. He was
like fucking Grandpa Munster. Right?
So time he parked it back there and
this other kid who was Emma was into
Metallica, classic burnout
teenager. He had like,
he like never shaved his upper lip.
So we had that awful prepubescent
and fucking mustache.
That little looked like somebody
said a little tip on those. Yeah.
It's always blonde. No matter what
color you got. Jet Black. Hey,
that little blonde mustache,
right?
So we thought it'd be funny if we took
his moped and hid the thing and he thinks
that it was stolen. Watch them
freak out and be like, oh yeah,
we'll tell you what it is.
So just to freak this guy out.
And this guy had like nothing,
right?
So he was in waiting tables and we took
his moped and behind the restaurant was
this, this little shed
built into a hill that we,
they kept all the extra kegs
of beer and all that stuff.
So we wheeled it around and put it up on
the roof cause you could just walk out
and it was like a driveway.
You went up and we just stuck it up on
the fucking roof and just left it there.
And he came out and he saw it
and he was fucking freaking out.
I remember pretending to wash dishes and
my shoulders were shaking watching this
guy. I mean, this was like
his fucking hope diamond.
And then finally we couldn't stop and
we just all started laughing. He's like,
you fucking assholes. And we'd go, yeah,
it's up on the roof. When we walked out,
we went up on the roof and it was gone.
Somebody still,
that's so fucking awful.
No, it gets better.
So he reported it stolen.
They ended up catching the kid like
two days later and the kid had tried to
paint it,
I'll never forget it was a silver one.
And he sprayed all this black on it,
did a shit job and it
looked like fucking shit.
And I remember like three days later the
Guy Riding Back to work with Frost and
his mustache and this horrible silver and
like fucked up black paint all over it.
I actually really felt bad.
I felt bad about that.
Do you remember the kid growing up at
the minibike that kid was always going to
equal scumbag like he did
you guys make many bikes?
I have that kid that had the
mini bike without the lawnmower.
I remember while my parents were like,
you're not riding those fucking things.
They both in the medical field.
So uh,
one of my brothers bought one and
had it hid by was another shed.
It was always a shed
when I was growing up.
He wasn't sh he had it hid behind there
and just the pressure of it cause he had
to keep it away from us and he
thought I was going to wrap it up.
Did he buy it from a kid that made it
or was it like a legit don't always a
moped and he bought it. It wasn't a,
it wasn't a dirt bike, but my, uh,
my parents were like,
you know,
in the medical field so
matter what you wanted to do.
If it was remotely dangerous,
my dad's thing was Christ.
They had it paste in the other day. It's
riding a moped, a blah, blah, blah, blah,
and he's gone. He was always dead. No
matter what the fuck you wanted to do.
He had a patient in the end of the day,
you know, and it's just like [inaudible].
It was just so fucking,
well, what a coincidence dad.
Every fucking thing I want to do,
it's like one of those,
they always play that worst possible
scenario game. Ladies. The thing,
now that I've got a kid, I
totally get it. I told you that.
They tell you that like once you have
a kid, you'll understand. No, no.
My parents were great thing about them
is they let you figure out as much as
they stayed on you on the big shit.
Don't do drugs and all of that. And uh,
stressed education, they let you
figure out a lot of shit. Um,
and I think that that's why,
you know,
people in my family are
like self sufficient and
have that fucking, you know,
you don't stand around looking
at the Rock, you're like, oh,
I guess I have to push this fucking thing
or it's not going to move. Yeah. Uh,
I remember like, like the life lessons,
remember, uh, I, this piece of shit,
pickup truck I bought and it was
my first car and it broke down.
So I got on the pay phone so long ago,
this wasn't,
I fucking called my mom like mom,
but talkers and stored and Uber
with the whole fucking scenario.
When I got to be a workable bunch, she
listened. The whole fucking thing was,
is saying anything. And then I
finished that. She goes, well,
what would you have me do? And I was
like, Oh shit. And I looked down,
there was a phone book right
there and I was, you know,
somebody fucking ripped all the
pages on. And I said, all right,
I guess I got to call a tow truck.
I mean,
she was one step away from
calling me a pussy and my mom.
Yeah, like why are you fucking
like, what am I a fucking mechanic?
All of that was in that. You have
a dime. Why didn't you fucking,
it was a dynamic that, why
didn't you fucking call me?
Call the fucking tell what?
Am I going to go down there and pick
the truck up? You fucking moron.
I know you suck at math.
Are you bad at life too?
I heard all of that and I felt stupid.
I remember I was mad at her and then,
but was it tough love or was it no,
no, no, no, no, no, no. It
was, it was all planned.
It was tough love because it was just
like, this kid's got to learn. Yeah,
because one of these days
you're going to be on your own.
And like I saw at Dana Carvey dual
hilarious bit about that, where you know,
his kids were calling them up or something
like that because something wasn't
working. Rather than calling
the landlord. And I guess,
I guess that's a thing with
kids nowadays. Like they, uh,
his generation went too far
over correcting because like,
you know, if you watched like his
comedy, you know, the old guy,
I had a game called stare
at the sun, you know, like,
I think his was so tough that then
there was maybe like a bit of an
overcorrection, but I remember when
he was doing that bit, it's, uh,
I'm not going to try to Redo it.
It was fucking hilarious,
but it reminded me of that story
and that they can like, once again,
how right my mother was being like,
all right,
well you have a fucking brain
use it. The, the thing that, uh,
I found the difference,
like the way our parents were raised
and the way they raised us is like,
my mom, when she was younger, you know,
you stay outside, kids played outside,
you come home when the lights
came on. I mean, you're, you're,
you're a little older than me.
Um,
and where I grew up is also was a little
different too in North Jersey at the
time, you know, it wasn't, our
parents raised me the US the same way,
but the outside wasn't safe,
if that makes any sense.
When they were younger it was safe.
But then like come home when the
lights are on. Right. You're like,
okay and I'm Ryan, bye bye
fucking crack heads. And you know,
because to them they were raised that way
and then I think our parents saw a lot
of shit they shouldn't
have seen at a young age.
People our age and now there
are over protective. Yeah.
I don't know how to like, I think
it's like kids like your kid your age.
I know you guys are going to be a happy
medium. You don't really fucked me up.
Was you know that remember
that to catch a predator? Yeah.
Like class that like makes it seem that
there's a fucking creep behind every
tree.
And I dunno if back in the day,
cause back in the day you just say he's
a dirty old man, stay away from him.
But I think that there's
a, with the Internet, yeah.
And the ability for people to act on stuff
and feed shit and watch all this porn
and all of this type of stuff. And I
think it draws these fucking people. Well,
the Internet is like the one big
fucking neighborhood and, and,
and there is no really securing,
I mean,
there's shit that I see
in my feet and I'm like,
what the fuck are you kind of
getting away from kind of getting,
but the thing about it is, so the Internet
is fucking incredible too. If you,
if you try to learn shit,
they'll write shit. Like, dude,
if you want to get that Fucking v drums,
if you want to learn a bunch of Shit, uh,
you know, there's some, there's everybody,
there's always somebody
doing a drum cover.
We'll break down something that
you can't fucking figure out.
And now there's like some monster
fucking teachers out there. Uh, uh,
Mike Johnston, uh, uh, the guy
take lessons with Dave Ilitch,
just started doing shit.
And these guys are like,
these guys are like legit fucking,
like, they know what they're doing. Uh,
and, and like, so if you stay in
those areas, learning how to cook,
you're good.
You're good.
The Internet is, it is an exact, uh,
what's the word I'm looking at it,
it's just an exact replica
of human nature. Is that
like, you know, first of all,
the idea that we're going to build this
information highway working to connect
people all over the world.
We're going to learn from each
other and like 80% of it is poor.
And then click bait.
He got these fucking scumbag
people and these fake articles and
that's human nature man. And it's an
exact replica of, I've kind of been,
I've been awake, I'm, I'm trying to be
vice lists here in April. They're like,
no, no. Poor, no cigars, no
booze. I fucked up the other day.
I took a couple hits a week cause I
jerked off to side while smoking a cigar.
Um, dude, I haven't had a drink since
new year's man. Oh, you don't to do it.
I think what we're going over here before,
uh,
before I just saw in the next podcast
guy look into here, um, before I, uh,
get out of here,
I do have to address the fact that the uh,
congratulations to the maple leafs.
You guys finally fucking showed up
and played a hell of a game. Uh,
but I feel good,
but this is going to come out Thursday.
I feel good about our chances
Thursday considering, uh, you know,
I just don't see us getting 40
shots on goal again and losing.
So all we got to do is when this
next one went up three games to one,
but it was a phenomenal game and that
was the first game in this series that
felt like playoff hockey where, uh, both
teams will fucking out there killing it.
So I look forward to tonight's
game for a Brett Arts.
He's a got a new series on youtube red
decks debuts May 2nd the Cobra Kai kid.
Uh, if you want to watch his standup
special principal's office for free,
you can get it at Brent B,
r e t comedy.com.
You could also go on Instagram
and also subscribe to my podcast,
that [inaudible] comedy.com and,
uh,
you can also listen to this podcast
right here and all things comedy. Uh,
you're on the list podcast.
All right, Brett, thanks so
much to love you, brother.
I love you too.
Thanks buddy.