Hey, what's going on is bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon?
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
mmm,
check Indian on you.
And I woke up this morning,
but I do have a dual boot and a,
that stupid fucking song was in my head
and you might want to fast forward or
it's going to be in your head. I'll give
you three seconds. Three, two, one. Right?
I fucking wake up and this stupid ass
song. I hate this fucking coach got.
Damn it. You don't just, how do
you make a couch uncomfortable?
It's the whole fucking point is,
that's the whole fucking job of a couch.
He said it's comfortable.
It's better than standing anyway.
So I wake up in the morning,
well let's the shape of a couch.
I thought that's all you
needed for the record.
It's not my couch. All
right. It's not my house.
I'm out of my fucking house.
And they, you know, you know the whole
fuck. You know the whole thing. Oh,
we're going to do this.
We're going to do that.
We'll be in and out in
two fucking seconds.
I've gone over my house like
three days and wrote a workout.
There's nobody there.
Oh,
the guy who at the door,
he got tied up at another job guy
I know, I know. I know. Been
down this road before. Um,
anyways,
so song that was in my fucking head.
Remember that fucking song?
Whoa. Buddha, Buddha, Davy d, uh,
something jumped in and I showed
him then to blah, blah, blah, blah,
blue, blah, blah. Blue.
We had joy, we had fun.
We had seasons in the sun,
but the salmon that's
been in my fucking head,
Data Dda Bada but it's such a creepy
fucking sock or still don't really know
what it's about.
Every time I hear the song,
like once every 15 years and then I
really listened to the lyrics. I'm like,
what the fuck?
You don't want me to look it up right now.
Got The guy just sings real creepy.
Like, Oh mother, dear. Why did you die?
And I'm sure he doesn't say that,
but yeah,
the fuck we had joy. We
had fun lyrics. All right,
here we go.
Goodbye to you. My trusted
friend. I knew it was creepy.
We've known each other since
we were nine or 10 together.
We've climbed hills and trees,
learned of love and abcs.
Skinned our hearts and skinned our knees.
Okay,
so he's got the creepy
childhood out of the way.
Yeah.
Goodbye my friend.
It's hard to die when all the
birds are singing in the sky.
Now that spring is in the air.
Pretty girls are everywhere.
Think of me and I'll be there.
Would they both gay and now
they're trying to like, you know,
they weren't accepted.
Yeah.
So like,
you know,
they're feeling the pressures to try to
live a straight life or did this person
die and if he's dead,
how the fuck is he singing this shit?
Yeah,
we had joy. We had fun. We had seasons in
the sun, but the hills that we climbed,
we're just seasons.
Hi, good pot. Goodbye
Papa. Please pray for me.
I was the black sheep of the family.
I was a drug user.
He tried to teach me right from wrong.
Too much wine and too much song. Oh yeah,
he's partying. I wonder how I got
along. Good bipap. It's hard to die out.
Jesus Christ shut the fuck you
know, at. This guy's not dying.
He just wants attention. You're not fuck
that song. And I'm sorry, I brought it up.
How are you everybody?
How's it going on this
Thursday afternoon? Oh, Jesus.
What happened last night?
Well, the, uh, the,
the national hockey league
started their season.
Not [inaudible]
do what? A fucking game. Austin
Matthews, Austin Matthews,
Austin Matthews,
one more time,
but the amount of goals he scored Austin
fucking Matthews for goals and his
debut in the NHL was so fucking cool
as his parents were in the crowd.
It's a mother started crying after
the hat trick. And, uh, you know,
no one knows who he is.
Nobody's paying attention.
Then all of a sudden it was just
like, whoa, Whoa, whoa. Hey. Right.
Next thing you know,
you guys got four fucking goals.
So immediately after the game,
of course, they going like,
do you feel a pressure now that you're
going to have to score four goals every
game? Um, you know what it
is? It's his second goal.
Okay.
There was just too many moves to many
people's fucking legs. He went around,
it's put the puck through,
lifted the fucking stick,
and then there was like half an inch
between the goalie and the post.
He somehow found it. I mean, it
was just fucking amazing game.
So I bet everybody Toronto has
to be really excited about that.
And my Boston Bruins start tonight.
See what they got. I don't even know.
I just know they start tonight. Boston
Bruins. Hey, we go, bro Wins. Here we go.
Jesus the Columbus Blue Jackets.
Why does Columbus have a team and why
did they name it the blue jackets? Well,
you know, it's named after the union
soldiers is civil war. Oh, is it? Is?
Is that what it is?
You know,
I believe a long time ago
you guys had a fucking team.
Then they had a fucking team
and the Cleveland something
or others and then they
fucking ice.
I know that name.
But Cleveland barons of something
and the whole fucking thing. Uh,
okay.
It like, it didn't even move
to another city. It just died.
Alright.
Cleveland Barons yet the Cleveland Barons
were professional hockey team in the
National Hockey League from 1976
to 1978 that's all. That's all.
That's all the love.
Click.
Cleveland's a big 10 fucking state and
then professional sports. All right.
How state's been around longer than
any of those people? All right.
There was a relocation of the California,
all the Real California golden seals.
That's right. Moved. Um,
which you played in Oakland
since 1967 then they moved.
They basically can't blame Ohio for
that. They died in California. Man.
Talk about it.
Out of the frying pan into the fire,
they moved from Oakland to Cleveland.
Had the owner of that team ever watched
hockey and kind of got it's, I mean,
I guess it is a cold weather state,
but Jesus Christ,
after only two s two seasons,
the team merged with the Minnesota north
stars. Now Dallas Stars. Oh, they merged.
I thought they just thought they just
folded as a result. The NHL field,
it only 17 stirring 17 teams during
the 78 79 season as a 2016 the barons
remained the last franchise in the four
major North American sports leagues to
cease
variation.
Ohio did not have another NHL team
until the Columbus blue jackets join the
league in the,
in the year 2000.
Um, so there's that,
there you go. Now. Now,
now you know what that's
about. Um, all right, so I am
chomping at the fucking bit.
Everybody. You probably wondering
why. Bill, what, what, what's,
what's different about this day
than any other day in your life? Um,
I'm taping my next standup special
standup special number five,
I believe. Right? Why do I do this?
Let it go. You people are all the same.
I'm sorry you feel that way.
I don't have a name for this one yet.
How about old freckles? You've done
it again. Oh, Magoo. You've done. Oh,
freckles. He have done it again. Um, yeah,
but I am a, I've been doing some
spots around town last night.
I have not been drinking. I've
been fucking working out, you know,
trying to get fucking into HD shape.
You know what I mean?
That's the thing about all these broads
bitching about here in Hollywood.
Hollywood creates these body images.
It happens to everybody.
Nobody wants to be a fat fuck on
television. Forget about this. The,
the new HD shit, we can literally see
the cartilage and somebody fucking nose.
I mean, you can't go. You can't be boozy.
You can't be anything. Everybody though.
What the fuck happened to you,
right?
You gotta go out there and shape. All
right ladies. So put your fucking whining,
get on the God damn treadmill
like everybody else. Um,
it's just hard. It's harder for
women to lose weight again. Yeah.
It is definitely harder for women to
lose weight with all those free fucking
drink she gets.
Okay.
You know, those are empty
calories. You know what I mean?
Think about being a manager.
You have to pay for your empty calories
and the fucking person you brought in a
lot of the times. Um, or who knows?
Maybe these new, the millennials now,
now that they're,
they're more progressive than I've,
I've just sort of left the herd now and
now I'm the old guy spouting crazy shit
from yesteryear.
Maybe the ladies go in now
and they just walk up and
they say, hey, good looking.
I like your stubble and your
suspenders. Uh, would you like a, what'd
you do? What do they call a micro brew?
What do they call it? Do they call?
Those fucking things does ridiculously
stupid fucking beers that all tastes the
goddamn same. They all have way
too many hops in them. You know,
they're heavy as shit. Every fucking
wonderful brewed right down the street.
Yeah. It tastes like it. To
do it in your bathtub. Um,
Mike, not micro brewery. They call those
fucking does. Not Micro Bruce. It is that,
but they got a new name for
it. Ah, you know, it's amazing.
I know this is going to surprise you,
but, but the name escapes me. So anyways,
I'm going to be warming up for my,
uh,
my special starting Saturday night in
Washington DC, our nation's capitol.
Okay.
Um,
I'm just going to walk around to
anybody who's in government, right.
And I'm just going to scream
really in their face. That's,
that's my goal during the wickets,
walked down the street,
just saying that to everybody.
I'm just blaming them because my choices
are Hillary Clinton or Donald Trump.
That's,
that's just what I'm doing.
Anybody with the fucking blue
blazer and a red or a blue tie,
I'm grabbing them by the shoulders.
You're not going to do that.
But I would love to do it. I
would like to do it, but you know,
post nine 11,
you can't walk around doing shit like
that and he and I don't want to get no
fight. I'm an old man, you know,
I going to tell you that time I went
down and I looked at the Pentagon like a
couple,
about six months after nine 11.
I must've told you that story. Right?
By the way, I met the national theater.
I forgot to say that.
Uh,
there are still tickets left cause I'm
kind of doing this weird run in this
theater that usually has
like the lion king. Um,
and I'm also doing like a Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday and there Saturday and a
Wednesday. So it's kind of weird.
A lot of school nights
shit. So, uh, you know,
she want to come down to
watch me fucking do the,
my pregame analysis on
my fucking standup set.
I'm going crazy cause I got to tape
this fucking thing because, uh,
I have all this other new shift that wants
to come out and I feel like I'm stuck
in time here so it has to
happen. Um, but anyways,
post nine 11.
All right.
I was in New York on nine 11.
I was on the upper east side,
the 70s all the way by the East River.
And uh,
you know,
there's a lot of like old wives tales
told by people who lived in New York
during that time. Dude, you wouldn't
have known anything was going on.
It was a fucking beautiful day.
And even as it went down as a collapsed
and all that, when I walked outside,
I didn't see anything in the air.
And if they mean that was like a couple
of miles away and if it wasn't on
television, I never would have
even known that it happened.
All I remember was walking
around the upper east side
trying to block out what the fuck just
happened. Like a typical Irish, German,
Irish Catholic. I'm sad
feelings, block them out,
act like nothing's happening.
And uh,
I just remember walking around up there
and like the fucking, there was people,
it was so weird to me
cause upper east side,
they're a bunch of people who actually
could afford to buy an apartment.
You know, a lot of them came
from fucking money or what?
I don't know what the hell they did,
but they were,
I remember them sitting outside on a
beautiful sunny day with that horror was
going down there and they were
eating, uh, know breakfast and shit.
And everybody felt it had
that weird sort of like,
I feel like I should be doing something,
but what can I get the
theremin on the eggs benedict?
Um, I remember one time when I went
to a fucking wedding, this asshole,
it's rich cunt. I told me, I said, yeah,
I just moved to New York City. He goes,
where do you live? And I was like, I
lived on 97th, between third and Lex.
And he goes, Oh yeah, what building? I
remember thinking like, what do you mean,
what building can I told him the address?
And I didn't realize what a fucking
conti rich person question that is.
Cause you know,
when those giant high rises,
they always have to have a
name like the Gotham, you know,
the Bilderberg or whatever.
But if you just, you know,
that's like a big thing in New York.
It's a doorman elevator building. Uh,
you know, a ridiculous amount of
square footage with the fucking view.
Or you had what I had on the
upper east side, which I actually,
I mean the only thing I hate to,
I lived on 79th and York,
if you live in New York,
there's a cluster of buildings over
there near that park where they have that
pool. Um, it's great fucking park.
And they had like pull up bars and shit.
I don't know. I hope they still have him.
He's to go over there
all the fucking time.
And occasionally when I go to New York
I still go to that park if I'm in the
area, cause most gyms first whatever
reasons don't have pull up ours,
they'd like monkey bars placed to do dips.
Um,
and then they had this pool and
they had like a time and shit.
It was fucking great. So he could swim
laps with all these other old people.
It was awesome. But it was this
cluster of old buildings and um,
I think they would like six floor walk
ups and I lived on the fifth floor and
you had to like fucking
walk like city blocks.
I had to walk up to York over to first,
second,
third and then was at Lexington was
next and then down two blocks to 77th
street. Which prop four months
of the year. It wasn't bad.
It was actually a nice walk,
but all the rest of it,
either the humidity or how cold it was.
It was a motherfucker.
I used to wait for the cross
town bus just to stay out of it,
just to have a little bit of air
conditioning or a little bit of heat. Um,
except when the kids got out of school,
I don't know what the fuck it
is about New York City kids,
but they are fucking lunatics.
They have fucking lunatics.
I don't know if it's because
they see too much or whatever,
but they had just completely
fucking out of control.
Okay.
Like their behavior is just fucking,
I just remember just sitting there like,
none of these kids have
ever gotten spanked.
Okay.
Or something. Jesus. I mean, I just
would be sitting there just like,
I want to beat the shit out of every
fucking kid on this bus. The girls too.
So anyways, I'm fucking
digressing here. So,
you know,
I went down and I saw like after
nine 11 one or that one piece of,
of the world trade was standing up,
I went down, I saw that. And uh,
I remember down the comedy
cellar for months app,
like a month after it was still burning.
I'll never forget that smell.
So on went down to DC.
I mean,
I knew that by then you knew that this
was a changing moment in history and it
was just like, you know,
I wanted to see like a,
okay,
you know, go over the Pentagon
and see how bad the damage was.
So I didn't realize I was such an idiot.
I didn't realize that the
Pentagon is like the Pentagon.
I thought the Pentagon was also
kind of like the Lincoln Memorial.
Like you could just kind of go to it as
a tourist, which she can, but I just,
there's like a subway stop and you just
get off at the Pentagon and I'm walking
around,
there's all these people and like playing
close and then you'd see people in
like air force outfits over marine
outfits. And so I was thinking all right,
they work here. But everybody
else in plain clothes is like me.
I didn't realize that they all kind of
fucking work there and nobody gives like
an office. It's a giant fucking office
building and the shape of a Pentagon.
So I start looking around.
I mean it's basically a circle with,
with points on it, right? That's
what a what a what a Pentagon is.
How many sides to a Pentagon bill? Oh, I
don't, I don't know. It's more than five.
It's a triangle. Then there's a hexagon
and then there's a pro Plexxikon.
I don't know what the fuck it is.
You do?
Didn't know what I knew when I had to
know it for the test and that's never come
up in my life. You know what
I mean? You've got a quartet,
you got a quintet that's jazz,
Mata, math. I'm into jazz,
but isn't music just numbers put
together beautifully. Sorry. So I'm like,
I'm standing there and this
point he fucking circle going.
Do I go to the ride too? I go to laughed.
I kind of go laugh, then I go right.
Then I started walking back left and then
I'm just fucking start walking around
this thing. I'm trying to peek
around the corner and they go,
maybe it should have gone the other
way and are basically not realizing it.
I'm looking shifty as hell. And of course
there's like 50 fucking cameras on me.
Like what the fuck is this dude
doing? Right? And I'm walking,
I'm looking around where all
of a sudden this fucking,
was it a jeep or a golf cart?
I Dunno what she says. Ooh.
Pulls up next to me in this.
Fuck. This fucking guy gets out.
Like he, you know when powers
booth ever plays a military guy,
he was like that with a baret. Like that's
how much he was decorated, it seemed,
no, no, no, he didn't have all that shit.
But he had some shit on his fucking shirt.
All right.
And he had the bra and I remember he
got out and he was like doing thing,
you know when someone's a Bowery to snap
your neck and they're smiling at the
same time.
Like that was the look on his face.
Like he was showing me his teeth smiling,
but everything else just basically said
is I'm going to pull you fucking thrown
out like macgruber. And um,
he came up and he's just like,
hey buddy,
what are you doing?
And he was like looking
through to the back of my head.
And immediately I was just like, Oh,
you know, I was just, and I was just,
then I didn't know what to
say and I was like, oh my God,
what if he knew one of the people
that died here and an ah, just go.
It was just a, you know, a comedian.
I'm in town playing Teddy's house,
a comedy,
and just then he fucking
took my name and then it,
then it dawned on me why
they were coming up to me.
And the whole thing just
made sense. Like, oh,
this is like a military building built.
This isn't the Jefferson Memorial.
Um, you're walking around one of the
most top secret fucking places and you're
looking around and you look
like a crazy white guy. Right.
So then it just struck me as funny and
then all I was trying to hold back a
laugh, right? Classic White
Privilege here. Right.
I could actually have this guy come up
to me outside the Pentagon and I can
still find the humor in it because I know
I'm not going to get arrested. Right.
Is that what white privilege is?
I don't know.
I'm stuck in this
wonderful fucking position.
I'm just going to stare into that now
and people just say white privilege.
I'd be like, Oh yeah, it's unbelievable.
Wow.
Ah. Anyways, what was I saying? Okay,
so the fucking guy,
um,
he's taken down my name and then I kind
of have like this shit eating grin on my
face. Cause you know, at that
point they both, they all kind of,
cause it was the guy who drove the jeep
who is like fucking Tom Cruise and taps.
He just couldn't let it go.
Right.
So I kind of feel him staring at me like
a fucking lunatic. And I'm like, well,
if this guy here with all this shit on
his shirt, I can feel him letting me go.
You're not going to arrest me,
the driver of the jeep,
join the military to be a fucking
show for go fuck yourself.
So now the comic in me is starting to
come up and I want to irritate this guy,
so I really start fucking smiling or what
I was again, man, sorry. I go, hey man,
you want to come out to the show and blah,
blah blah. And the guy see, you know,
he's,
he's Kinda gone down from,
I'm going to fucking rip your throat out
to kind of like, I'll, maybe I'll just,
you know, I don't know what stick
a bayonet and your side, he's,
he's Kinda down to that. Is that less? I
don't know. Whatever the fuck it is. A,
I'll just waterboard you, he sees,
sees is look as craziness is,
I'm just gonna waterboard you now.
And um,
I get to the end and he's that guy,
right?
And he gets in the jeep and the other
guy was just stare and fucking, uh,
like daggers at me,
the jeep.
And I was just looking right at him
smiling and he goes, no, he goes,
you're free to keep walking
around this thing, you know,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I was just like, Nah,
man, I'm cool. I'm cool.
I can only nobody else driving
up to the fucking jeep.
So they go to away and as he would drive
away, I remember the Chi in the jeep,
the guy drive and like yelled,
I think he was trying to make me jump,
like it drove wearing just like that.
And I didn't jump. And I just sort of,
without like looking back,
I just put my hand up and waved at him.
And, uh, and that's my fucking
Pentagon story. So anyways,
I'm going to, uh, I'm going to DC and, um,
this is the greatest thing
flying in Friday. This is
the greatest fucking thing.
Every mother fucking time I
fly into DC like an asshole.
I forget that Washington Dulles airport
is like 30 fucking miles. I don't know.
I don't even know where it
is. North, south west of DC.
I don't know what I just know.
It's 30 fucking miles away.
All right. And if I leave here
at like nine in the morning,
by the time I get out there,
it's going to be right in the middle
of rush hour and it absolutely fucking
sucks. And every time I do
it, I always go, ah, fuck.
I should have flown into
Reagan Reagan's right downtown.
Every city has a cute little
mom and pop airport like Dallas.
You don't fly into the fucking Bingo.
Bango one. You go to love field.
Just like John Kennedy did way back
in 1963 you're flying into that one.
That's where you want to go.
You don't want to go to the big ones.
You fucking get in. You get
out. It's lovely. Lovely.
It's cute little fucking airport. So
I'm not that. Reagan said small. I mean,
it was a fucking, was a giant airport back
in the day and age. I think they just,
I don't know the population or was too
close to the White House, have no focus,
kind of a fucking watch list. Am
I going to be on, on this podcast,
all these buzzwords, nine 11
twin towers. I said Pentagon,
Pentagon,
and White House,
and I named both candidates that are
running for president and I'm going to the
nation's capitol. All right. You might
not want to want to go to Saturday show.
You might want to wait until I
get out of fucking being detained.
God knows that guy driving in the chief's
probably worked his way up, you know,
probably motivated them. You know, like
Obama motivated fucking Trump. You know,
when he trashed him at that fucking rich
person breakfast or whatever the fuck
it was. Fuck, I gotta take
this phone call. Hang on one
second. Hang on. Hang on.
Okay, I'm back. So anyways, yeah.
Obama made flake when Obama made fun of
fucking Trump at that senior breakfast,
whatever the fuck it was.
And I think that that,
like there's theories that that's what
motivated him to run for president, which,
you know,
as much as I don't like the gun,
it's pretty fucking awesome that he
was like, you know what? Fuck this.
I'm going to take that guys who didn't
fucking just sit there and think
something like that and then to
actually do it, even if you are a Trump,
that's fucking amazing. Um, anyways,
I think I got to read a little
advertising here. No, I don't want to,
I really don't feel it. Some days you
just don't feel like reading. And for me,
that's been my entire adult life I
had of it and when I was in school,
you know, so like, yeah, just
handing you shit to read.
Yeah.
You know,
in the words of that English woman,
when that Saudi Arabian kid
drove by with his fucking,
okay,
gold wrap, the Lamborghini going,
Whoa, Whoa, Whoa, Whoa, stop it.
That's what I wanted to say.
That was the inner me.
Okay.
They'd hand out and you need to read the
chapter one and did champion chill by
Monday. Stop it. All right.
The Zip. Wow. What's up friend?
Zip.
Are you high or red?
Do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Posting your jobs in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your
job on all the top sites.
And now you can with zip.com you can post
your jobs to a hundred plus job sites,
including social media. Now, social
media networks like Facebook and Twitter,
all with a single click.
Find candidates in any industry,
any city or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your
qualified candidates roll.
Does it
easy to use interface?
No juggling emails or calls to
your office quickly scrapped.
Fucked up my voice on that one.
Quickly screen candidates rate them
and hire the right person fast.
Find out today.
Why Zip?
Okay.
[inaudible] has been used by over 1
million businesses and right now my
listeners can post jobs on Ziprecruiter
by going gyp accrued at.com/burr.
That's zip recruiter.com/ [inaudible]
one more time for free. Go to is
tip
recoded Dotcom. Slash. Burr.
Alright. What the fuck is this?
How do you say this? W. I. N. C. Okay.
Wic whip finding great new wine is tough,
but that's why I've been telling you
about our sponsor club, Debbie Kalib.
Debbie Hamish to here.
I came down when the towers went down.
I went down there and I said,
I can hear you and how they make it so
easy to get wine personalized to your
palate and delivered right to your door.
And here's a little update for you.
Club Glib, Debbie. Debbie,
I never shot me in the face.
I could data. Dick Cheney is now
called [inaudible], spelled w.
I. N. C, a new name and
an improved the look.
Okay?
Okay, I'll go. I'll go with
you with the improved look,
I don't know about an hour and improve
name. I don't know how to say it,
but here's the important part.
It's still the same amazing wine company
introducing you to new wines and you'll
love, you know what? I bet fucking
George W. Bush said, hey man,
I'm Debbie as my club.
I used to own the rangers.
Um, please include all of the fun. I'm
going to include them all. All right.
Branford reference your wine ordering,
drinking experience with wink to cuss.
I only time I've ever ordered wine is
when I'm in the restaurant and I used to
feel pressure when they would pour it
and look at you and everything and I just
look, I just sent it right back. I'm like,
yeah, dude, it's, it's wine. It's fine.
You know what I mean?
You gotta stay sticky,
knows and it's Florida around and fucking,
you know,
have it roll around your mouth
and then swallow than you. Um Hm.
What kind of unique he realized how
much of a fucking Dick you have to be to
send back a bottle of wine. That's it.
That's a confidence move right there.
You know what I mean?
Like if I was,
if I was a lady and I was on a date and
my dude sent the bottle of wine back,
I would just, that would be, that would
be the end of the date. All right.
I would just be like,
this guy,
he's a cunt and I don't think no means
no in his world. And he's getting drunk.
I'm fucking Outta here. He just sent
back a bottle of wine. All right. Wink.
Wince when you know, when I do
web, you know what I'm doing.
I'm doing that fucking that guy who
fucking choked the fuck's his name when he
went to go sing that song.
Um,
that's a Mori where the Buddha
churros and when he started to go,
when he just goes whip.
All right.
What works directly with wine makers
and growers from all over the world to
create delicious wine and deliver
it right to your door. Wink, wink.
Wex 100% satisfaction guarantee means
if you don't like the bottle they send
you, they'll replace it. They'll
replace it with a bottle.
You'll love no questions asked.
Oh,
you can send it back via the
mail so it's not as crazy.
You don't have to stare at the waiter.
He walks back going, all right,
I'll get you another bottle
with my dick in it. Um, I don't,
I don't get sent random bottles.
That is true.
I don't just get random bottles.
Oh,
they're acting like I signed up for
this shit. I didn't sign up for it.
I drink enough.
I don't need booze delivered at my door.
At least I can work for it.
But you got this is this,
I mean it's a great company here.
If you,
let's get this back on the rails for the
artist formerly known as kind of Benny
Winc is a personalized wine membership
that recommends that recommends wine
specifically for me based on
results of my palate profile quiz.
I don't drink wine. I drink, I drink
booze. Why do they keep putting words?
I also re listen to this. I also write
all of the law. Is this like my fucking,
is there a robot version of
me out there drinking wine?
I hope it's brushing his teeth.
I also write all of the wine I received
from the club, Debbie and Winc.
So they learn about me with every order
and constantly personalize the wine they
send.
Crepey.
Sign up for Winc right now and gain
immediate insider access for the best wine
from all over the world.
Find out for yourself why yours truly
and thousands of other satisfied wine
lovers are raving about Winc. I
have not raving about them. Alright,
listen, if, if Mila, Mila highlife comes
out with one of these fucking things,
not only will I sign up for it,
I'll be,
I'll for the first time ever be
more than 200 pounds. Um, no,
it's great duty.
It's a waste it this way too much fucking
copy for someone who's dumb as I am.
You want, you get it
right, you're into wine.
You'd tell him what you like and then
they send it to you. If you don't like it,
you fucking send it back.
And then they, then they go,
well, what was wrong with it?
You say, well, it was too much
of this, and they go, all right,
and then gradually they get you in the
crosshair of your fucking booze hound.
[inaudible] right, and then,
then you have it. That's perfect.
All right,
call to action.
The best part Winc is offering
my listeners $20 off right now.
When you go to try winc.com t r, y, W, I,
N c.com/burr, they'll even cover
the shipping. Think about that.
You'll get fine wine, baby.
Personalized to your palate,
delivered right to your door.
Try Winc and get $20 off
complimentary shipping right now.
When you go to try winc.com/bird
that's try, we tried Wwi,
nc.com/ [inaudible]
um,
all right. How many more of these fucking
things are there? Two more. Two more.
Hang in there, people hang in
there. All right. D s t l d genes.
No one could that possibly stand for
those same titties.
Like damn jeans.
Uh,
the problem with jeans is
that really, Oh, it's, oh,
it's pronounced is stilled distill genes,
everybody.
The problem with jeans is that the really
good pairs cost two to $300 easily.
And the bargain brands just fall
apart or look terrible. Yeah.
The Dad jeans distilled genes
pronounced distilled Dstl d
I came in. What I said just said
those titties look damn right.
No Damn. See titties looked at, I
can't remember if the fuck I said,
it has revolutionized the fashion
industry by creating timeless luxury grade
denim. There's no such thing
as timeless denim. Okay.
You go back and you look at the genes from
10 years ago, they're like, oh my God,
I can't believe your war.
Those that read the fucking hugging your
nuts are hanging off your ass either
look like you only have eight kids
or you were an orphan every 10 years.
Genes changed that much. Okay. We'll
decide whether they're timeless,
luxury grade denim,
so you get genes that would cost you
hundreds of dollars starting at 65 bucks.
Oh Jesus.
How do they do it?
By refusing to work with the department
stores and retail middlemen. Yeah,
and some eight year olds
sewing them together.
That's the only way you could sell it for.
If you're selling me a three and fair
dollar pair of jeans for 65 bucks,
fuck outta here.
I'll tell you,
there's a kid somewhere in some fucking
country with really tired fingers right
now.
He probably got the old school thing
where you gotta use your foot is just sew
it together. Sorry. These are wonderful
cheats. There's no markup, no bullshit.
Just great jeans at an unbelievable price.
Go distilled.
No DSTL d.com spelled Dstl d.com.
Uh, define the perfect
pair with the perfect fit.
They'll ship them to you for
free and guarantee the fit.
Or we'll send you a new pair until
they are perfect. See for yourself.
Why a list celebrities have been spotted
and magazines wearing $65 jeans in
vogue,
Gq wearing distilled jeans.
Even see celebrities like
me. Oh, look at that.
They're making me be fucking
self deprecating. See,
I'm one, I'm one level above Kathy
Griffin though. She's on the d list.
It's why she never wears jeans. Um, I've
got a pair of the raw denim. No, I don't.
Why do they do this?
All right, let's just get to the
fucking brass tacks here, right guys.
Do you want fucking cheap jeans that
look like they're more expensive?
Go to distill jeeps. They start at 65
bucks. I have no idea how high they go.
All right. Half a high you look is
how great your pants fit. All right,
so let's start fucking having your balls
get brought out in the crotch and puts
your Dick Right there to the side.
You know,
and it's stop having people
looking at unique caps.
Just go to distill.com/bar right
now and get $10 off your first pair.
Now we're down to 55 bucks.
D S T l d.com/burr for $10 off right now.
Five letters. Uh, let's see
here. Delta, Sierra, Tango,
Lima, delta.com/burp. All right, we're
going to end with this song. Everyone.
This is the longest fucking advertising
ever. I just got to get through this.
Bateau pope
me undies. Andy's walk
around, the Panna gone.
Boudou due to me undies.
Biondi is he grabbed your balls.
Now they're gone.
But when he grabbed him,
he realized quick how fucking the
soft they were up against your dad.
Cause you had on me undies before he
ripped your fucking balls off. Yeah,
cause you're recruit be all right.
[inaudible] is picture a world in a
world we're putting on a pair of new
underwear isn't just fresh.
You stepping into a better day.
Think about it.
Underwear, it's the first thing you
put on in the last thing you take off.
Why the fuck would you settle for anything
less than the best feeling underwear
on the planet? Do you not value your
balls ladies? Do you not? You know,
want to put a nice
fucking flap on your clap.
Whenever the fuck he call your thing,
your little who ha.
Please include all of the following
points during your rates. Absolutely.
Me undies focus is solely on production
and producing the most comfortable
underwear you've ever experienced.
I just pictured them kidnapping homeless
people. Make them try it on right.
And they got them in the cage.
Try on these.
I don't want to do it anymore to try
them on. Are they comfortable? Yeah.
That comfortable dot.
Ly.
My friends at me undies sent me a pair
of while back. Yes, they did. And I,
one of them I felt like I was Greg
Louganis stay with that tight,
but the other ones were nice. One
of them was a little too, uh, um,
uh,
um,
and now I can't imagine wearing anything
else. So of course I can, I can,
I have an incredible imagination,
but I'm not going to lie to you.
They're very comfortable.
It really makes each day that much better
for the price of two cocktails. Me.
Oh yeah. And then you'll have your
fucking me. He's around your ankles.
It'd be like, why is my Dick Cole? But
my ankles feels so nice. We under use,
we'll deliver your new favorite pair
of underwear right to your doorstep.
Better Day,
guaranteed a try them on.
Try them on right when they cried in front
of the postman when he delivers them.
Wait a minute,
I got to retire days.
Don't profit from it.
They are the most comfortable,
best feeling me undies you've ever had
the refund you and let you keep your
first pair for free.
Included the included in the
price is the sweet touch of
modal gross.
Oh,
the creepy uncle you didn't know.
Didn't know you had just
hanging out in your crotch.
A special fabric made
of the best in class.
Raw materials that are scientifically
proven to be three times softer than
cotton.
These Uber Cozy undies are
sold exclusively on the
[inaudible] site where you'll
enjoy free shipping in the US and Canada.
I gotta be off to.
How often do you think he have
balls during the course of the day?
You know what I mean?
I think when you first were under where
you're aware of your fucking balls.
Okay?
It's kind of like the fruit.
When you put on a wedding ring you
put on on wedding day like, dude,
what the fuck? And Blah, blah, blah, blah.
Now there's like times I have a panic
attack that is gone and I never take it
off, right? Um, just like my
underwear, I never take it off.
That's why I lost my friends. All
right, and for a limited time,
everyone in my audience can get 25
20% off. Sorry, off their first order,
but you have to go to our special URL,
[inaudible] dot com slash [inaudible]
with me undies. Keep better day guarantee.
You have nothing to lose, so don't
they? Got It. Just fucking get to it.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bar
right now for 20% off your first order.
It's kind of like what I just
said eight seconds ago. That's me,
undies.com/birth Jesus.
I was a fucking long way to go. Um, hey,
guess what I haven't done since Monday?
Yeah.
I have not flipped out a technology.
I've had a couple of issues. I relaxed.
I tried to figure it out. I was actually
able to figure out how to, uh, you know,
just when I download some music, how to
have it automatically go to my phone.
You know, cause sometimes it would do it.
Sometimes it wouldn't. If I was on Wifi,
I didn't know how to do it. I was like,
how can I get it to automatically do it?
And I just, I, I just googled
it like a normal person
found out the fucking answer,
like a normal person.
And it all went to my phone and I
said, well, I got to give this a try.
I want to download that
new green day album.
I want to see what's going on with that
fucking thing. Right. What's his face?
Trey cools on the cover. I don't
know if it's modern drummer drum. Um,
we were in a hounds tooth fucking so,
right. And I'm like, that's right.
They got a new album out.
This advertising is working.
So I went and I downloaded the thing and
boom, went right to my phone, you know,
and then I sinked up my
address books and now my fit,
my numbers are all
floating back and forth.
I now know that I could scroll down
and see how many contacts I have,
not only on my fucking
phone, but also on my computer.
But now I can't figure this out.
Why is this doing this? Oh, see that.
I just figured something else out.
You hit the little x thing. I have 193
cards people, I gotta tell you something.
Um, overrated. Alright.
The panic of losing all your phone
numbers and all your contacts.
Here's the deal.
Within 10 days,
anybody who's in your life is
going to text you like, hey man,
I haven't heard from you. What's going
on? Then you get them through them.
You just get the, you know, you get
everybody else. I have 193, sorry,
my eyes are going, it's
not one 98, one 93. Um,
and after today that'll be up
over 200. And uh, you know,
I still haven't turned
on my other phone yet.
I'm going to wait until it just
completely fucking dries out. I mean,
what's the point?
I have all the numbers that I really
need and I was able to get a few that I
didn't think I was going to
get. Um, and like I said,
if you know me and I haven't texted
you when you listen to this podcast for
whatever reason, texts me cause
I don't have your number anymore.
All right. And I've actually had like
three or four people going, hey man,
listen to your podcast.
I heard that you lost all your numbers.
Just reaching out man. I was like,
Hey, thanks. I really appreciate it.
Do you have so and so's so and so's
and so and so's? And then I just,
I just build it up. You
had built, we get it.
You basically doing exactly what anybody
else would be doing and your situation.
You're, you're talking about
yourself, like you're doing
something groundbreaking.
Okay. You got me. All right.
Let's end with this. Um,
I told you I went down to fucking iron
maiden rabbit hole for some reason.
Right now I'm listening to James
Brown in early iron maiden.
I don't know why.
And I'm playing drums along with it and
I'm having the fucking time of my life.
And, uh, I've been
playing to the prisoner.
I still can't do that popup a
bat with a fucking Bass Drum.
How fast Clive bird's foot was. I
can get it up to speed though. Um,
I've been fucking with that. And then
of course, um, where eagles dare,
which is just fucking ridiculous.
But that's the great thing about youtube.
You know,
everybody breaks everything down and then
you don't even have to fucking develop
your years as a musician.
So then you learn how to play shift
that you didn't really figure out some,
he gave you the answers to the
test. Every, he's like, wow, man,
you're really fucking good.
And then all of a sudden,
Sunday somebody writes an
original song and they say, Hey,
come up with some drums to this and you
have nowhere to search. And then they go,
oh, that's who you really
are. Um, all right,
that's the podcast here.
Lay Ladies and gentlemen.
That's the Thursday afternoon podcasts.
I was just checking in on you.
I hope your, uh, your, your, your, your
week's been going good. Even if it isn't,
it's already Thursday. Look at
that. Look at you. Get Your paycheck
today. You cash it. You have a
couple, two or three. You know,
you put on your fucking me undies. You
know, you go out, you get hammered,
you bang the chick down the fucking
way. Right? Next day she comes in,
she fucking Rad. Shout you get
fired. And then your boss goes to zip
the recruiter and he fucking
advertises a position.
He gets somebody better than
you with more me undies. Right?
But he's got clubbed Debbie, your
breath. So they got to get rid of him.
Gone call back to all the fucking things,
you know,
and they kick him right in the ass
if it's distilled James. All right.
And then that's it. I think that's it.
They mail his ass home through stamps.com.
All right,
go fuck yourselves. Have a great
weekend. You can't enjoy the music.
As we sort of segue into,
uh,
some Monday morning podcast greatest
hits from a podcast from a different time
in a year going by or maybe earlier
this year depending on how funny it was.
I had no fucking idea.
I'll see you
exactly that.
This reality
grinding to a memory of a time.
I want to do that ted.com just look up
robots and try to find the one with, uh,
with this, this, this
lady is sitting there.
She's fucking talking about,
you know,
having robots around the house.
Okay.
You know what I mean? It is the
stupidest thing. Okay? First of all,
she's whoring it up for no
particular reason in the beginning.
I don't know why she's wearing
like these hooker boots.
She sitting there talking about robots
to a bunch of egg head nerds and she's
still got a horror it up.
It's like,
can't you just stand on the merit of
the fucking speech that you wrote?
Do you really got to get
people's Dicks half full?
Just so they'll keep listening to you?
How fucking insecure are you?
You're talking about robots in the house,
walking down the hallway. What's up?
Fucking high five and a God damn robot.
That right. It's not like it's
a movie. It's fucking real.
That's not compelling enough of a subject.
You can't hold the audience's interest.
You still have to put on
your street walker boots.
Okay.
It's weird. She has on street walker
boots, but she has on a modest skirt.
It comes down a little or maybe cause
the boots go up so fucking high.
Okay.
You know what I mean? I mean
the, isn't that basically a rule?
If you're going to wear the
fucking thigh high boots,
you basically have to
have on a mini skirt.
All right, so she starts her
speech, right? Not a whore,
just dressed like a whore.
Like she put on half of our call and
Wean costume and then, oh wait a minute,
I have to give a speech. So she
goes down there and she's just like,
she actually sounds,
what she's talking about is smart,
but she doesn't sound that smart.
So I don't know if some nerd wrote the
fucking speech for her and got like,
I dunno
fucking broke out in hives right before
the speech. So they sent her out instead.
But she's just up there like,
you know what,
I always allow Gol I remember just seeing
star wars and seeing thethey po going,
wouldn't that just be
awesome to have like a robot?
And that's like two jobs that just to
like kind of talk to and like joke around
with.
And she starts talking about how she
feels that robots should be in the fucking
house because she wants her own
c three Po my saying that right.
Am I pausing at the wrong time?
I go into the c three p
o c three Po c three p o
don't know,
whatever.
That's such a stupid fucking movie
because one of the most overrated fucking
Goddamn motherfucking movies,
a vault.
I would rather watch
muppets take Manhattan.
I think that that holds up better because
at least there's adult humor in there,
you know, you know, totally
ripped off. Use the force,
Joel Olsteen that fucking skinny dad gay.
When you were in a tee shirt cheese,
won't she a half a t shirt?
Just think about it. It's going to
happen. He totally stole that whole vibe.
I don't even know what that makes sense.
So you're not, furthermore, I don't care.
Plowing ahead to this lady sitting there,
lady sitting there talking
about these fucking robots.
You got to watch the video and about,
I don't know, 10 11 minutes in,
I can't remember where the fuck it is.
They cut to somebody shooting the shit
with a robot and it looks like it's
basically a head coming out of a giant VCR
and he's like sitting there like
it's be like if you had a VCR,
their head coming out of it but like a
robot head like bolts for eyes and shit.
But it has like eyelashes for
some stupid reason like blinking.
Like it needs to blink.
Right.
And he's sitting at it
like he's at his desk,
like almost face to face with the thing.
He's just like,
Hey fucking r two d two look up.
My girlfriend bought me and he
showed some sort of fucking,
I dunno what the hell.
At some macho chain of a watch.
I can't remember what the fuck it was. And
then the robot is just like, oh my God,
that's real. A actress thing, dead shape
and it's movement. It's fucking head.
Can I ask either,
this might be the dumbest question
ever or just painfully obvious.
Why the fuck would I need that?
Well, why would I need that?
Like why?
Why won't I just to my friend,
you know what I'm saying?
It was,
it's like the baseball kid from way
back in the day. Remember that Shit.
I talked about it here when the podcast,
one of these Mondays,
these have the baseball kid, it's
called baseball kid, the baseball kid,
a baseball, his work, you're
willing to do baseball, cable,
Phd and it was a cardboard cutout of
a friend basically that you don't have
throwing a fucking baseball to you.
You know?
It was basically for
the kid with no friends.
So now they've upgraded that to the
person who has no fucking friends.
You. What's great is that I bet that
guy didn't even have a girlfriend.
I bet he bought the watch for himself.
And now he's now part of the sickness
is he just fucking lies to this robot
about this life that he doesn't have.
And you know, once you start doing that,
it's an inevitable,
it's an inevitability.
It's a fucking a cirrhosis of the liver
that that guy's eventually going to
stick his fucking human dick in that
robot mouth in the second dead fucking
happens.
That's it.
Okay.
It's the end of the fucking human rights.
I'll tell you right now, this fucking,
the scientists out there
fucking robots right now,
they're out there banging robots,
you know,
under the whole platform
of fucking research.
It's actually really scary. Like,
cool, go watch this shit on ted.com.
They've got another one showing
how we're fighting wars now.
And like these guys sit in Arizona,
they go to basically go to work,
they go to war and then they come home
after fucking blowing up some bad guys.
Uh, hopefully bad guys, right?
And then they fucking go and they sit
down and hang out with their kids and
they're sitting there talking about how,
uh,
okay,
you know, now the bad guys are getting the
robots and blah, blah, blah. It's just,
it's fucking inevitable.
All those drones,
they're basically eventually all
this shit. They use it over there.
I think eventually they're
going to use over here.
Yeah.
You know?
Okay.
In the future there'll be
no more skipping jury duty.
Okay.
The second you skip it,
you're going to wake up in the morning,
peek out the window, and there's going to
be a fucking drone just hovering there.
You have seven x to get to
court or you will be vaporized.
It's going to be one of
those fucking things.
Is this the least interesting
thing you ever heard in your life?
I mean it didn't. I just basically
do every science fiction movie.
Has there ever been a science fiction
movie where they predict something great?
That's what I'm going to do.
I want to be original here for once in
my fucking life. Let's go the other way.
Okay.
It's going to be a friendly drone.
It's going to be outside that window.
Go back to sleep.
It's okay.
We shut your cloud to go
down to the Jerry Dodi
it now. We don't need you,
so you will be vaporized.
You will be vaporized. That's the
way to do it. I think that that's,
that's gonna be the,
the,
that that's going to be the funeral in
2020 I think by 2020 we're going to know
definitely where you go when you die
and if it's anywhere other than here,
people are just going to
choose to tap out. You know,
it's going to be like getting a vasectomy.
Just getting fucking vaporized.
Still an intense fucking procedure that,
that needs a serious
talking before you do it.
But you know, Eh, you know, I'm
just getting 70 to change. You know,
like when people on the east coast moved
to like Minnesota or fucking San Diego
just needed a change.
That's what's going to happen.
People just going to get vaporized
here in the future. It's fucking true.
You know, I know you guys are
rolling your eyes right now,
but you don't have access to
the information that I do. Okay.
So please reserve your
judgment or whatever, whatever.
Temper your judgment. Don't be hasty with
you, judge. Whatever that point. Yeah.
Can expression is human
caused
by the stars in the sky.
Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's still bear.
It is the Monday morning podcast that
I'm doing at eight 30 at night Pacific
coast time.
I uh,
apologize for the late
recording this week.
I had a,
I had a really busy Monday and uh,
I had one window where I could have a,
I could have recorded,
but I was so fucking pissed at my health
insurance people that I just didn't
want to, I didn't want to go
on screaming for the weekend,
trying to be more mellow. I don't even
know what the fuck that word means.
But anyway,
this is the Monday morning podcast.
I do one of these every God damn week
can still, I'm still a little pissed,
you know, people send me questions
and if you have any questions for me,
just send them to bill at [inaudible]
dot com or you can go on my myspace page
and send them there. Any questions
you have, I'll answer them.
If you have a list of stuff that
you feel is overrated or underrated,
I will read that.
And if I say something you think is
stupid during the podcast and you need to
correct me,
you can correct me.
Like this feller last week I was
talking about that creepy commercial,
you know that commercial where they
got the mothers did their advertising
batteries and they've got the mother
and the park and she can't find her kid.
She's like Michael and uh, you know,
well since she takes out
this little device that the
doo, Doo, Doo, Doo, Doo, Doo,
Doo,
all of a sudden a kid comes over the
fucking hill and they don't show wearing
any bracelet or any sort of hat
with an antenna on it. And I'm like,
they're getting you ready?
You ready for the future where they're
going to want to put microchips and your
kids. Okay, so this guy
says, you know what bill,
I was listening to your podcast and I
actually looked up that commercial to see
what the deal was.
And it's actually the brick house locator.
It doesn't use it ship, sorry to
shoot down your dreams of the future.
Instead it has a key chain type receiver
that the parents clipped to your
children's shoes,
jacket or backpack.
And it's a homing device to let you
know their location in second. Okay.
Well,
you know what,
I wasn't saying that there was a chip
in the kid and what I was saying is that
they don't show that he has the clip and
it's very subtly getting you ready for
them to put a chip in you in the future.
And uh,
I don't know why, I don't even thought
you're arguing with me on this point,
but you're being a little company.
You know,
I realized that the kid
didn't have a chip in it,
but haven't you seen the stories on
the news where these people who work at
corporations are like,
yes,
my company put a chip in the and I
don't have a problem to it. I with it.
I have access to very sensitive materials.
I happened to know the secret
formula to a Kentucky Fried Chicken,
so I need to have them in bed, a fucking
code in my fucking microchip in my og.
Really? You know, Colonel
Sanders knew the fucking recipe.
They didn't have to put a chip
in. It's fucking goatee. Did they?
You know something. This is
just, I'm not going to make it.
I'm not going to make it in the future.
When they become more and
more of a fucking police
state and they're doing this
shit, I swear to God. If people
just line up like fucking sheep,
I don't know what I'm going to do and I
swear to God, they're going to be like,
well, he ain't doing nothing wrong.
You shouldn't have a problem with it.
You know that,
that fucking argument about how the
government can listen to your phone calls
now. And that was people's big argument.
They would just like, well, dude,
if you're not doing anything,
then why would you,
could you please wrap the cord around
your throat and choke yourself?
Read a little bit of history before
you open your fucking mouth. You Moron.
Every fucking period in history just
has horrific events of maniacs with too
much power. Putting people
to death constantly happens.
It's happening right now.
Genocide.
Has genocide ever took any
even taking a weekend off?
It's unreal. It's not happening over in
fucking Europe or over here. People just,
you know, am I getting preachy? I'm
going to shut the fuck up. All right,
let's move on to the next thing.
Um, oh, is a question. Hey Bill. Uh,
will you be on the Jim Norton
Hbo Show? Why? Yes. Yes, I will.
Um, I had the privilege of performing
with little Jimmy Norton in May.
We taped it and it's going to be airing
October 23rd Friday night at midnight.
So, uh, set your Tivo because I
imagined you guys all have lives.
You all be out there partying and up come
home, shit faced and watch it. And I,
speaking of which,
let's plug little Jimmy show a down and
dirty with Jim Norton is on every Friday
night, HBO at midnight
and a, I got to tell you,
I was really impressed with the
level of a comedian that they had.
There was a lot of guys I didn't know
and I had to gone go on after this dude
Sean rouse,
who I had worked with before
and I thought it was hilarious,
but when I saw him,
when I had to go on after him,
I was literally standing
in the wings going like,
I don't think I could follow
this guy because, uh, I dunno.
Absolutely fucking brilliant
comedian Sean routes.
I think it's s e a n r O. U. Sfe. I Dunno,
he opens for Doug. Stan hope a lot. So
go over to Doug Stan hopes web website.
I'm sure he's got something on their
own link over there or check Doug.
Stan hope.
Look at me hyping other comedians.
There's three fuck fucking hilarious
people that you should go see,
but not this weekend
actually go see him this weekend
unless you're an Austin, Texas,
because that's where I'm going to be
at the cap city comedy club, goddammit.
And uh, I'm really, really
excited to do this Gig and uh,
but a little disappointed. I kind
of asked some sad news. Well,
let's give you the good news first.
The good news is I'll be working
with my good friend Joe to Rosa,
who I do a uninformed
with my XM radio show,
our XM radio show,
and he'll be opening up for me too,
man show and uh, Joe
fucking hilarious. Um,
it's going to be a great
night of comedy this Thursday,
Friday and saturday@capcitycomedyclub.com.
You can get all the information. Now.
The reason
I booked myself in Austin this weekend
was because the longhorns had a home game
and I've always wanted to go to a,
I always wanted to go to a game
there since way, way the fuck back.
I watched the longhorns game
and for some reason I like,
I think the guy's name was cherry
gray or something like that.
He's one of their defensive backs and
either the late seventies, early eighties,
must've been early eighties,
because Earl Campbell wasn't playing
for him at that point. So anyways,
I always wanted to go to a game there.
I'm a big time sports geek.
And uh,
in fact when we were booking the
show that the cap city people,
we're talking to my agent going,
I don't know if he wants to come down
here that weekend because there's a
longhorn home game and people really
go nuts for those games. And uh,
we don't want it to affect his
numbers. So I was like, well,
I want to go to the game so
I don't give a fuck. I'll,
I'll make less money so I can go to the
game. So this is what ends up happening,
the longhorns and up,
uh, being undefeated,
kicking the shit out of people and
everybody else starts fucking losing.
And next thing you know.
Then the number one team in the country,
and I swear to God,
earlier this year,
the fucking game was going to be on in
the afternoon and now I believe they call
it the flex schedule.
They've moved the game time.
They pushed it back to 7:00
PM and my show's at 8:00 PM so
I don't know what the
fuck I'm going to do now.
Does that mean nobody's going to come
to my show and I don't get to go to the
football game? I'm such
a fucking, this is why
I can't even talk. I'm such as Sports
Geek that I'm actually considering.
You know what? There's a dog.
I'm sitting in my car right now.
There's a fucking dog looking out
at the window looking right at me.
I got the windows up,
that son of a bitches behind the window.
It's like he can hear
everything that I'm saying.
Cody. Yes. God, yes.
You just fucking staring him.
Maybe you know I was using some
hacky command. Oh, he left. He left.
He left his, then another person
come up to the window. Right now.
I look like a freak. Okay.
The fuck was I talking about?
I'm actually such a sports geek and
I'm actually considering going there
tailgating
and watching like literally the first
hour of the game because then I'll be on
until eight 45 and that, you know
what? Fuck that I'm doing it.
I'm going to the Goddamn game.
If I just see the first fucking quarter,
I don't give a shit.
God Damn it.
That pisses me off the whole fucking
weekend screwed up. Now you know,
I was driving up,
I was going to go up to Houston because
I was going to go to south park guitars.
It's as they got nothing but lefty
guitars out there and I'm Jonesing to buy
this, this new reissue gold top
Les Paul Because uh, I don't know.
I played drums and guitar. I'm
done. My life is ridiculous.
I'm like a fucking 12 year old. I'm
not married. I don't have any kids.
I go to sporting events,
I played drums and guitars and I babbled
for a half hour on Monday and I tell
shit jokes on the weekend.
It's like
sometimes I wake up feeling guilty. How
fucking great my life is. It's just,
I can't lie to you. It's
fucking awesome. I just,
this is what fucking
level of sports nerd I am.
This is just for my podcast
listeners up in Canada.
I've always wanted to go to cocky games
up in Canada and I never, you know,
I always want to get booked up there,
but you know,
my fucking bookers always like, oh, the
money isn't good, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Blahs is back when the dollar was
worth more than my fucking shoe laces,
so I'd never get booked up there.
So this year,
in December, you know, the industry
shuts down. I said, you know what?
Fuck this. I'm gonna, I'm gonna, I'm
gonna take a hockey trip up to Canada.
Three Day weekend.
I fly up Friday,
Friday night I go to a Calgary game.
Then Saturday I drive up to Edmonton.
I go to an Edmonton,
Vancouver Canucks game in Edmonton.
And then a Sunday morning I fly over
to Vancouver and I go to a Vancouver
Canucks game. That is my fucking
weekend. And I know there's a lot of,
you know what, and I bet I'm just
dividing you guys right now. 50, 50.
There was some people right now going,
dude, that is the stupidest fucking,
most moronic waste of Goddamn
money I've ever heard in my life.
And then there's other people who
either they get it or they'd
suffered the same sickness.
I don't know how to categorize
it. I like, dude, that's the shit.
I Dunno. It's ridiculous. And I'm like
geeking like I'm fucking site the Gulf.
So you guys, we know what, why don't
you let me know next week, okay?
And don't be on the fence. And I'll
be like, you know, I'm not into it,
but if you're into it,
I want you to go one way or the other.
I want you need to say, Bill, that's
the greatest shit ever. Defend that.
I totally get what you're doing. Or just
call me the biggest douche bag ever.
And I'll read out all the funniest
ones. I'll read next week. There you go.
That's your homework
assignment for the week.
So with that, let's, let's
get to some overrated,
underrated stuff. Um,
all right, overrated. Uh,
I got a new job in Everett Washington,
so this past week I drove
cross country from Worcester,
Massachusetts.
I don't know if you've ever had the desire
when you were a kid in high school to
drive across the country, but I can
honestly say I didn't really like it
and it's hilarious to this guy saying
driving across the fucking country is
overrated. Anyways. He says driving
west is a constant uphill battle.
I had no idea.
I figured once you were out
of the Appalachian mountains
that it would be flat.
It is flat,
but not level.
You are constantly driving up no matter
what going through the plains states
suck too.
I was driving through
somewhere in Minnesota at night
and I slammed into a deer
standing in the road. My truck was tall
enough that it didn't get too fucked up,
but still a wow. That's hilarious.
This guy, so you know what?
I bet you'll never listen to those
American songs the same way you get,
like they get annoyed when people sing.
God bless America or what is the,
what's the one for Purple
Mountain's majesty page?
He's going to be like, yeah,
dude. Yeah, it fucking sucks.
So are you from those corporations?
If you get it,
here's one for you and you can look this
up. The same guy I looked up the uh,
the microchip commercial,
they actually got a machine now that
rather than digging into a mountain and
they'd take the coal out, they
actually, it's as big as a school. They,
I don't know how the fuck
they get it up there.
They get it basically to the top of the
mountain and they just filed a mountain
all the way down to the ground.
I know that sounds crazy saying
you're out of your fucking mind.
I saw it on 60 minutes.
This wasn't one of those youtube or
Wikipedia crazy things that I've seen.
So sir, with any luck corporations, we'll
get rid of all the fucking mountains.
Can you imagine if they do that?
Can you imagine the fucking hurricanes
that were going to have absolutely
nothing to twisters? It's just
going to be a, I'm telling you,
I really think the second half of my
life is going to be like a fucking will
Smith movie. Except will's not going
to show up cause he's just an actor.
All right. Underrated. Um, oh I
didn't even answer the question. Yeah,
I've actually driven cross country.
The first time I moved back from La
and I decided I wanted to get back into
being a comedian because I wasn't ready
to be in la and I packed up all my shit
and I drove from La to New York City
and a three and a half days if that,
like three days I drove
like a fucking maniac.
I drove like 16 hour days at 80
miles an hour, like a fucking maniac.
No radar detector,
La all the way into New Jersey
did not get pulled over.
And I forget how I did this.
I was trying to go around some traffic.
I did a fucked up,
you turn and I got pulled over right
before the George Washington bridge
and I'm thinking,
isn't this ironic?
Maybe the police officer will share
in my seeing this as a comedic,
ironic moment and he didn't give a fuck.
It was one of those deals where he
was Dudley do, right. He was like,
whatever you did was so douchey.
I'm not even gonna say anything other
than license and registration came up to
window licensing, registration.
Oh, like, you know,
this is me as I'm handing the stuff
to them. You know, it's amazing.
I drove all the way from La and I did and
he just snatched it and walked back to
his car and I was like, Alrighty then.
Yes, I'm getting a ticket. All right.
Anyways, let's get to underrate
year. Underrated a good mechanics.
There are a few shops
out there that give a,
there are a few shops out there that give
the good guys the bad rep of few. No,
there's a ton that's like me saying,
you know,
there's a couple of comedians out
there that give comedians a bad name.
Now there's a ton of us standing
on stage go and what's the deal?
Men and women has this crazy,
yes.
Smell your own farm and to do that,
look at this guy over here.
He knows what I'm talking about.
Um, speaking of which, yeah,
you know what a good honest mechanic is
underrated and actually found one out
here. It's a good fucking guy.
Uh, what do we got a couple more?
I'm actually speaking of farts.
Overrated. Your farts. Underrated.
My farts. All right. A
little myopic, but I get it.
I get it and want to say there
was something else for that.
Oh, and he had a movie review bill.
Whatever you do, don't watch Cloverfield.
Jj Abrams should be beaten for
this monster shit bomb. You know,
I heard that movie sucked. I'm
going to steer clear of it. Um,
all right. So when he was, let's
start wrapping this thing up here.
That's the flats.
You just spend like the inner
goddess Devita is a fucking podcast.
Um, I do have to get to a
couple of things that people,
last week I said Japanese ballplayers
are overrated and I want to,
I want to retract that
statement. Um, I dunno,
I just watched a couple of the guys that
the Yankees got in dice k for the red
sox drives me fucking nuts.
And it wasn't until game two,
I think was the game to know game
one of the devil race series that I,
I understood the guy. It's
like I get this guy, he went,
he loads up the faces
and there's nobody out.
Then he has the other team
right where he wants them.
He doesn't give a fuck until the
whole thing could go down the shitter.
So I actually was able to relax that
first game when I watched him pitch.
So maybe I was a little bit
harsh and I think I was hard,
harsh to white guys cause this guy says,
your comment about white guys
can't play baseball pretty untrue.
If I were to field an all
white baseball team, uh,
that might give any all whatever,
all star team a run for their money,
you know what,
that'd be a great fucking idea.
It really would add to a lot of racism.
They should have the all Dominican team,
first of all, Japanese team, you know,
or versus the all white team, whatever.
You know what the winner of the all white
teams should all white versus the all
Japanese team.
She played the ultimate and cut team and
each team is allowed to have two Puerto
Ricans. Um, anyways, CNC, his,
his, uh, his is all white team.
I'm not reading all these fucking names.
Lance Berkman,
chase Utley chipper Jones,
chipper Jones like 98 years old.
You can say next. Uh, who
the fuck was that? Ah, Geez.
I just went blank.
Who the fuck was the guy we used to
play center field for the Braves.
Keep Thinking Darryl Dale Evans.
Dale Evans.
Wasn't she fucking Cowgirl Bill Murphy?
You're going to go back that far?
I'll wait. Josh Hamilton. Okay.
That's a good one. Uh, might
be seen it right there, right?
There's some guys. Yeah. Okay. I
mean there's no Manny Ramirez there.
You know Josh Hamilton could be all
right. You're right. You're right.
I was just trying to be funny.
If you price going to defend
the white man anyways.
Okay, let's go. What are we doing
here? What does the left anything? Oh,
the op Ed piece.
Last week some girl did some rant that
she can't find a good guy anymore.
She's saying that all
guys were pussy fide.
And is that because of rights and all that
type of shit? So here's your rebuttal,
man. This guy has some advice
for you. For the woman who said,
there's no good guys out there.
There's no good guys that you can find.
They've all pussies. Whereof all
the real men gone. Okay. All right,
so here,
first of all,
he starts off with his explanation as to
why so many guys are pussies. He says,
well, most guys are just trying to get
laid seriously. They will do anything.
They are varying techniques for this.
Some work better than others. Um,
first you have the manly men, a
men. This girl was talking about,
they act like complete fucking assholes.
They're abusive emotionally
and even physically.
Sometimes girls fucking love asshole guys.
Not all,
but an overwhelming majority of the
female population population definitely
gravitates towards these fucking Douche
bag men and the drama created by they're
being assholes. I got to admit,
when I started being a Dick,
I definitely, uh, did I get
more women? I just think I got,
I got a higher quality woman
as far as looks anyways,
but they all ended up being psychos.
Um, all right. There's another one.
Most women like asshole guys because it
provides them with an infinite amount of
bullshit to whine about.
Okay,
I'll be getting some responses to
this also. They love the whole, Oh,
you don't know him? Like I know him.
He's different when we're alone. Shit,
that's fucking funny. Uh,
it makes them feel special.
These guys know this and they get tons of
girls is fucking works. I got to admit,
being an asshole doesn't work.
Not Literally being an Asshole,
but if you just act like
you don't give a fuck,
it gives him something to work at. I
can't even explain it. It's basically,
I think I did that joke in my,
on my special,
which is basically in the beginning
you actually know what to say,
but your brain keeps saying, don't say
it because you don't want to offend him.
It's when you shut that,
that like sensor thing off
and you just start saying,
you know what I mean? I give them with
the girl and you just want to fuck her,
but you make the mistake of acting
like you like her. So now you've,
you're taking her out to dinner and it's
like Ben never had to happen because
believe it or not, some women you
know actually just want to fuck too.
So if you kind of thrown out there and
all you want to do is fuck a lot of times
that takes a lot of that bullshit away.
So you stop acting like a nice
guy and they stopped backing.
Like they don't want to jump on a
cock and a, you can have a good time
anyway. You know what? I don't even know
what the fuck I'm talking about this.
I'm sitting in my car with the windows
up cause I don't want to wake the
neighbors here and it's starting
to get hot in here. So, uh,
I don't really stand by anything
else that I saved the red.
Why don't I just read the rest of
the shit that this guy wrote without
commenting on it? All right.
Second is a second group of people.
You have sensitive artsy guys.
The guys that movies and television have
trained to be timid and understanding
guys like this,
guys like this at first,
but after a while becomes
thought that girl,
sorry girls like the
sensitive guys at first,
but after awhile it becomes boring and
this guy inevitably falls into the friend
zone.
The guy musters up the courage to tell
the girl how he feels and he gets the I
really like you but just as a friend shit.
Then he goes home and hangs himself.
This strategy doesn't work as well
as the asshole method. All right.
I guess this is a final one. Then there's
the guys were above the whole macho,
territorial pissing shit and our email
pussies either these guys never get laid
in high school because they usually don't
deal with these fucking stupid girls
that are gawking at the asshole
upperclassmen with cars and roid rage sky
something has got some unresolved
high school issues. Um, anyways,
they go up to girls but
like idiots as themselves,
they almost always get passed
over for asshole job guys,
I dunno, basically wraps it up. So I don't
think this girl's looking hard enough.
There are macho assholes everywhere.
It's the dominant strategy for getting
laid that I've noticed if she's looking
for an actual relationship and doesn't
want to just get boned by tons of
insensitive pricks,
then maybe she should rethink what
she means by saying men are pussies.
Well, there you go sweetheart. In your
face. What do you think about that?
It is going to sit there
and not type something.
I like both of those things because they
all touched on truth and they also were
unbelievably generic and you also kind of
learned a little bit about both people,
you know, and I think they both have
some anger towards the other sex,
which I think is healthy.
You know what?
I think I should arrange a meeting where
you guys can both get together and hate
fuck each other.
What are you think about that?
He's screaming at you different points
I think. I think that would be awesome.
It just allow me to videotape it.
I'll fucking squiggle out and he sort
of private parts and I'll do that black
line across your eyes so no
one can recognize you. Like
on the ACBC dirty deeds,
done dirt cheap album,
speaking of which,
I'm going to see ACBC December
6th at the La Forum. Anybody else?
Anybody else? Um, all right,
what's that worth at? That
is a, you hear that beep.
That means my car just started up and
that is the end of the Monday morning
podcast. Sorry it took so long
for me to put it out there.
I really try to get them
done in the morning cause I
know I'm on west coast time
and uh,
and I really appreciate it.
Everybody who listens to
these things every week,
please keep the questions coming and
uh, and that, that isn't everybody.
Have a good week as a congratulations
to the devil rays. Man.
You're up two games to one. You
bastard. You got a great fucking team.
And uh, I dunno, I kinda like
all the teams that I left,
I'm actually driving right now, which
is illegal out here. I actually,
with my lights off on a fucking
moron. Okay. There we go.
Actually like all the teams that I left,
I can't figure out who I want to,
who I want to win
out in the West.
I really liked the Dodgers because they
got a bunch of old red sox. No Ma, Manny,
uh, Derek Lowe. And I
liked Joe Torry. You know,
I hated the Yankees, you know, still
hate the Yankees, but you know,
you got to respect Joe Torry and you've
got to admit the Dodgers and making the
red sox and the Yankees looking a
little stupid, you know, red Sox,
obviously getting rid of Manny's,
he's too much to deal with and look
at the fuck he's doing out there.
And then what's the ama pain is
fucking salary. Jesus Christ.
But then you got, what's his face?
Uh, Joe Torry, the Yankees were like,
you know what, we're so sick of going
to the playoffs for the love of God.
We need to take a year off
from the playoffs, so we're
going to get rid of you.
And, uh, what's the name of the Dodgers?
Because they haven't been there in while
and then the Phillies, I don't know. I,
uh, I like the Phillies. I liked
that team. I liked the new stadium.
And I know everybody talks
about that youtube video.
I could really give a shit about Philly,
like I don't hate them or whatever. But,
uh, I dunno. I Dunno.
You know what?
I think I might want to see the Dodgers.
I wouldn't mind if the Dodgers,
the Dodgers were playing the Red Sox,
then I'll root for the Dodgers.
All right. That's it. That's it.
So right now my red sox is still in
until I got to root for the Phillies.
They are thrown down. All right.
And not being wishy washy.
I'm rooting for the fucking fillies.
And uh,
obviously the red sox, but I can't get
mad at the devil rays. You got to love it.
Not spending money.
Got All these fucking stuff's coming up.
They're kicking the shit out
of a pitching. But, uh, oh,
and I want to thank everybody who's
trashing my patriots right now. You know,
you punch your pussies. How we come
in, they're limping into your town.
Everybody's injured, and now
you're going to talk all your shit.
You bunch of fags, you know what
I mean? I'll tell, you know,
my favorite team is for fucking talking
shit has to be the San Diego chargers.
I've never seen a team
celebrate more than they do.
You would think that they had actually
won a championship rather than they just
want a regular fees and game in the
middle of October. Those mother fuckers,
they gain like they stopped a guy for
a four yard gain on first down and they
all start line dancing.
Remember that a couple of years ago
when the Patriots beat him again in the
playoffs
and they all did Shawne Merriman
dance right there on the 50 yard line.
Remember that? And then lt got all upset
saying that we didn't have any class.
I could just made no sense to me.
It's like really your guy has been doing
that the entire game he's getting in
everybody's face. Every time he makes
a play, he's doing that stupid, uh,
started motorcycle dance that
he does live by the sword,
die by the sword. You're going to be a
con. People going to be a cunt to you.
And now,
look this week we come limping into town.
They kicked the shit out of us to
look at lt at the end of the game.
He's all smiling. Hey, good game, good
game. Slapping everybody on the ass.
He's got no problem with all the
dancing at his teammates were doing.
I'm telling you, I don't
like that. I don't like that.
You know what I mean? That's uh, that's
really annoying. And you know what?
I think it starts with the coach.
My really talking shit to LTE right now.
Like you can't kick the shit out of me
or that he even listens to this fucking
podcast. Um, I dunno.
I was still sticking by it. The
Patriots are going to win the AFC east.
Go Fuck Yourself. I'm not reading any
of the emails to trash me all you want.
They're going to win it. All right.
That's it. That's it for the podcast.
I'm going to go buy some fucking Cheerios,
have a good week everybody.
And uh,
and that's it. Keep the questions
coming. I'll talk to you later. Bye.
I felt my heart
light.
I expanded.
It was just the shadows.
Then a voice spoke in mine.
She said,
dark is not
the APPS.