Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
I'm just checking out on you.
I'm taking time out of my day to read
advertising to make a little more scratch,
just to make sure that your
week is going okay. All right?
That's all I'm trying to do here.
Jesus Christ.
If I hear one more fucking asshole, bring
up that stupid Michael Jackson video.
I don't know what are they going
to dig them up and arrest them?
Okay.
You know, and I, I love what anybody did.
You see that thing on murder mountain?
Did you see the making of a murderer?
And you go in there and you listen.
You basically, you are watching,
you're watching the prosecution's case.
That's not our case works. Then
you hear the defense. All right,
and I think it's kind of fucked up that
you can have something come out about a
dead guy and then everybody's
just going to be like, all right,
now we know definitively
that this guy did.
He should be allowed to refute
moonwalk Outta the grave would be like,
listen,
just because I talk like this and I
like castles and have a giant ice cream
machine and like 17 doors that lock on
the way to my bedroom designate in a
fucking a child.
He should be able to say that.
Yeah
and that, because I think he's innocent
a it, it's, it's for you and me. Right?
So we get the chance to do that. So some
day, you know, somebody can't just say,
Hey, I saw this guy with
this tally whacker fucking
wagon out of a zipper there.
Right.
You have a chance to defend yourself and
what this new fucking bullshit of the
Internet where they just all do
processes thrown out the fucking window.
The amount of people that I've
seen accused of this me too shit.
And then people just immediately go.
Like I always knew he was a piece of shit.
It's just like you haven't heard
if you've heard an accusation,
but having said that,
okay,
having said that, it makes me feel
better about the suffering of humanity.
Right? Cause when you look
at human being suffering,
if you're any sort of a human
being, it bothers you. All right?
But when you see 90% of them on
the Internet, right? You get,
will you be you at that point
you're like, well maybe, maybe,
maybe they don't need that much food.
Oh, that was just me, Bill, that
was to meet for the morning.
I hit him a little bit of
a disappointing morning.
I was going to go fly a helicopter and we
couldn't get the fucking thing started.
It's our 22 I don't know what the deal is.
Like if,
if you try to start it before eight,
the magnetos are too cold.
It's too cold outside this time of year.
It just doesn't want to start. So we,
we brought a car up to jump it, which
we've done before and it has been fine.
It looks funny as hell.
But if you just don't look at the fact
that it's a car and it's a helicopter and
you just look at the
engine, you're like, oh,
it's the same fucking some fucking
gas combustion engine. All right.
Same fucking principles here.
Um,
I was really looking forward to flying
and I know what a lot of you guys are
saying, like, oh my God, I,
why there's no fucking way I want to
floats up that I had a bug, a jump shot.
I know,
I know.
But you'll get in your car that fucking
every time you drive over a puddle at
fucking Jesus in your face,
right?
Coming up to the rusted out
floorboards as you texting,
driving 90 miles an hour right down the
fucking street. We'll say 50 driving,
50 looking down at your fucking phone
and there's no guardrail in this.
Somebody driving 50 miles an hour, just
one, not even a like three feet up.
You haven't you ever noticed that when
you drive down the fucking street,
just on a two way street,
like the fact that you're going 50 and
the other guy's going 50 and it never
dawns on you like what does that
guy just fucking swerved over?
We'd both be fucking dead.
It's like you're doing like what the,
how the blue angels fly at each
other the last second they turn away.
You're doing that with complete strangers.
You're not on the radio talking
to each other and every day,
every day somebody is
on their fucking phone,
they drift over headlight
to front headlight, Bam.
Right brain smashing on the inside
of the skull or what do people say?
What do people say? Oh my God,
it's a fucking shape. That's it.
But the next time you go to get in a
car and nobody says like, Hey, I'll go,
maybe you should walk. You're
going to fucking die. Sorry.
I'm trying to preempt everybody who's
going to sit there and the end for fucking
say a bunch of fucking shit
here. Anyways, plowing ahead.
Guess who finally figured out how the
Moto GP website works. Not this guy.
Somebody gave me the link and show me.
Then I was able to put in my
password and a so thank you to the,
to the listener who helped me
out and I got to watch that race.
The first one of the Aaron [inaudible]
or a, what do they call k Tar?
The English guys.
Okay.
Like every little fucking word
they say different than us.
It's amazing that we speak the same
language over here. We say Ducati,
they see do catty Oregano or a Gyno,
tomato,
Qatar,
k tar or I didn't know at the scene I,
Kantar Kantar is they think
how they were saying it. Um,
I dunno when I just hear shit like that.
I really wanted to start to understand
how difficult it is to be a spy because
that's, that's the shit that gets
you caught. You get the accent down,
you know,
you watch a little peaky blinders and he'd
go over there and next thing you know,
you're in Buckingham Palace and you
fucking snooping around to find out what
those balding concert do it in there
with all the goddamn money. Right?
And then all of a sudden, what do you
do? You let her do care. You go to a,
a Ducati, a Ducati, I
forgot how he said it.
A Ducati slip then that's it,
right? The queen pushes a button.
You go through the floor right
down to the royal alligators. Um,
there's the, I'm gonna tell
you right now, but moto GP,
this is the best fucking racing
that is out there. All right.
On the final lap. The two, the
two people, Andres divisio.
So in Mark Marquez in first and
second place they change leads,
the delayed change three
times in the final fucking,
even though I knew it would happen,
I was still up off the couch
and everybody was asleep.
So I was screaming quietly watching it.
I'm an amazing race.
Um, a little bit of
controversy though, Huh?
Yeah.
The Duke cattys the Ducati's,
they got this new little piece that
they have underneath the bike that uh,
allegedly is kicking up air to cool
off the rear tire. And these guys,
I guess they chew up their tires big time.
So if he has just a little
bit of an advantage.
So divisio so one Ducati,
one,
uh, the team and immediately
four teams complaint,
which I'm guessing is Honda Suzuki.
Okay.
By the way, how come there's no Harleys
are fucking Indians in the Goddamn race?
What, what happened? My country,
we started making real fucking
motorcycles before all of these constant,
constantly.
I gotta look this up.
Yeah.
It's so funny that like Indians in like
Honda's, it just for like fat fucks.
Not Honda's Harleys. Essentially.
It's for old guys want to sit down.
I like the pegs up nice and high.
It's my fucking air up my old fucking
ball bag as I drive down the fucking
street and all the Japanese
bikes and the Italian bikes,
they're all for the young guys who think
they're going to live forever. Right.
Having said all this, having
talked to all this shit, you know,
if I was going to get a bike,
which I would love to, um,
if I wasn't, you know, living for
somebody else now, but even then,
even before I had a kid,
like I always liked my legs.
Um, I like my feet pointing
in the direction they're
supposed to be rather than
turned around like I'm fucking like
daffy duck's bill. Every other cartoon.
Um, all right. What the
hell was I looking up?
Okay.
Oh,
first motorcycle
built. All right, let's
see who built it first. Oh,
I got the bad internet. Huh?
Sometimes you get the bad cocaine.
Sometimes she get the bad internet.
Okay.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Can we wait one first?
Okay.
Fucking
okay.
Motorcycle ever built.
It's going to bring a porno of,
as I said, fucking in it. Come on,
come on. You can load. You can,
you could load if you want to.
You can answer my fucking question.
What is the Jesus fucking Christ?
How much do you have to pay?
Okay.
How much I am fucking pay nine
grand a month for fucking night.
The first motorcycle, international
combustion petroleum field motorcycle was,
was the, damn, you're right.
Viagen that sounds like German.
It was designed and built
by the German inventors. Ah,
you fucking son's up.
Is there anything worse than when you,
a man did something or America did
it and you find out they didn't?
It's the worst. I feel like the
world smiles when that happens.
A motorcycle often called a
bike or a motorbike or a cycle.
I know what that is. Okay. 1894
Hildebrand and Wolf Mueller became the
first series production motorcycles and
the first to be called a motorcycle in
2014 the three top motorcycle producers
globally by volume or Honda?
Yamaha.
And they hear a motor Corp,
I don't know. It's an India.
All right. So we're not the only ones
making motorcycles that on in Moto GP.
Okay.
What is it about like Italians in,
in uh,
Japanese motorcycles that they just
make the fastest ones they got,
they got that unlocked that and look
at fucking Japan. They got Honda,
Suzuki and Yamaha.
So what I'm finding out is a
Suzuki's are the best in the corners,
but then the Ducati's and Honda's just
have too many horses when they go down
the straightaway, which is
fucking weird to me. You know,
I guess it would depend on the track
because the one they were riding,
riding on had like two long straightaways.
So when he sort of fucking ground
the dude and the Suzuki would gain,
he would just lose it every time he
would go by the grand stands over there.
All right. Enough motorcycle
talk. But I really enjoyed it. Uh,
if you want to jump on board,
there's only like 20 fucking racist.
They're like 22,
2124 laps.
They fly by and you're watching guys
going 200 fucking miles an hour on a
motorcycle, like an eighth of an
inch away from each other. It's done.
I'll tell you,
it's unfucking believable.
I've been given Yannis Pappas Shit,
one of my favorite comics out there.
Absolutely brilliant guy,
but he's like the classic fucking New
Yorker where he did this Instagram post,
right?
And uh,
okay.
He's like in Philadelphia and he goes,
look at these,
these go and look at the
buildings, looking at buildings,
look at the buildings.
And he goes, every city looks like New
New York City for a block and a half.
And then the whole thing falls
apart. You know? And I this,
there's something just so fucking
funny about the way New Yorkers travel.
Okay.
You know,
every place they go to,
if they can't do exactly what the
fuck they can do in New York City,
the place sucks.
It's like you're in Philadelphia.
Why would it look like New York
City? That's why you travel. Oh,
where are all the fucking bill day?
The tristate area is arguably the biggest
collection of meatheads in the United
States of America.
And I,
and this is saying something cause I
grew up in Greater Boston, you know,
and if you want to see the level of meat
had just watch a Boston sporting event
when they pay into the crowd.
Yeah.
All right. And I'm not talking down.
I know I'm part of the problem.
Okay.
So I've just been leaving
all these fucking messages.
How New Yorkers just think everything
sucks. This such fucking moron.
Oh, I went to fucking used
it, right. I mean Houston,
Texas soil linguine and it fucking,
it was fucking terrible.
Okay.
Can I get good Italian? A Houston, Texas.
Why didn't you get the barbecue? You dumb.
Fuck.
Okay.
Why did she get some Tex Mex?
I went to Buffalo. Right. I fucking
went to the buffalo wild wings.
Fucking wigs.
That good
fucking morons. They are fucking
morons. And you know what's funny?
I um, I went to the Brody
Memorial, right? I can't remember.
I talked about this on Monday.
I still can't get over this.
This guy was eulogizing. Is that
the right word? Brody Stevens,
and he somehow was able
to trash Boston twice.
It is fucking eulogy. It was one of the
high points of it cause it was, you know,
it was really uplifting,
but it was sad.
But it was kind of funny to see that New
York fans are that fucking annoyed that
we won some championships finally,
you know,
finally one oh couple,
and that it's bothering them so much
that they're now reduced to making fun of
our skyline.
Uh,
and that stupid shit that ESPN came
up with where they would like say that
Boston had an inferiority complex is one
of my favorite with New York is one of
my favorite thing ever. I don't have the
heart to tell Him New York is that like,
yeah, we don't even, we
didn't even know what the,
we didn't know what the
fuck it looked like.
He'd given us too much credit. Um, I,
I want to say I already talked
about this on Monday, but you know,
like whenever they
fucking show New England,
whenever there's a game in New England,
they're always showing
some sort of foliage. Uh,
something about the revolutionary war
and then somebody is eating a fucking
oyster or something and it's just like,
that's really, that's, that's not a good,
uh, that's not a good
indication of what's going on.
You know, so somebody in a dive bar with
a beer in a fucking shot that, yeah,
maybe. And they don't, they
don't go to the bull and finch,
that stupid fucking cheers thing or
whatever the hell it is. Anyways,
having said that to all the New York is
listening, I absolutely love your city.
I love the people. I just don't
like the Yankees. That's it.
Everything else about it.
I absolutely love having said that,
I love Philadelphia too.
I enjoy Washington DC.
Milwaukee's one of my favorite cities.
I don't fucking, cause when I go there,
I don't try it.
Get fucking,
don't,
let's get some fucking little fucking
clam chowder shut in green bay goat.
MMM
Dude. I, I fucked in. I go to, I go
to fucking Argentina, right? Dude,
I'm fucking down yet. And I, and
I say to the, can I get a fucking
Sam Adams?
He got an email he had no Sam Adams.
So I told this fucking place sucks.
MMM.
The anybody else.
Do you have any stories like that?
I shouldn't really just blame New Yorkers,
but does anybody else have like a cause?
I think country people are like that too.
Where they just cut off
to on now y'all deal. There's all these
bugs and playful out here, man. Give,
give me the wallow for the
spice is a mild property.
Get me a four wheeler and a good woman.
It does.
Now the self esteem to walk
off [inaudible] she knows
I'll fucking club or over
the head and feet are numb up pigs.
I've done it before.
Okay.
She knows it.
We never talk about it,
but she knows that she goes out
when she goes to feed the pig.
She sees a couple of thugs hanging
on a nail. She knows what that means.
I told her I'd been married twice
before she gets it right? MMM.
Yeah. The purpose of traveling is,
is, is the when in Rome, right?
When in Rome do as the Romans do.
That's what you do. All right.
You fucking go over there, you go over to
fucking, you know, uh, the U K alright.
Premiere League.
See,
get yourself a fucking pint in a
scarf and start singing some socks.
All right?
Yeah.
You know,
pull a VRC like an a Stoney and you talk
to some 90 year old woman over there,
you know, blazing fast
English. Go in like, Hey,
do you know where we can watch
the NFL divisional round playoffs?
Yeah.
You know what it is?
I think about New York is they've just,
they've just some too many fucking
songs about your city and then all these
meatheads who really didn't
do that well in school,
they think they're part of
the success rather than the,
they're just background in the
movie. Um, as I've always said,
Frank Sinatra was bridge and tunnel.
He was at Jersey Guy.
Okay.
Breaks and he lives in no work. There's
no buildings and fucking place sucks.
Okay.
Um, alright. Plowing ahead here. Uh,
I did some stand up the other night,
first time since Royal Albert Hall.
I had a good time trying out new shit.
Just like just nothing. I got nothing.
So I'm going to go down to the comedy
store possibly this weekend or maybe not
this week and maybe next weekend.
And I'm just gonna fucking,
I'm just going to do
20 minutes of new shit.
I'm just going to have like four or five,
six subjects written down and I'm going
on stage and I'm just going to stand
there and fucking take it.
Um,
and it's one of my favorite
things in the world to do. Um,
I was just listening to a Brody special,
the one that he has on fucking
iTunes and uh, I just, I dunno,
just listening to that guy
plowing through, it's just
one of my favorite things.
Definitely going to miss that guy. Um,
but it was an incredible memorial service,
which I really would think that I talked
about it on Monday. I believe I did.
I just kept no fucking short term
memory. So anyways, Hayden was funny.
It was right before I started.
I asked my wife if she could just go
talk in the other room because she was
talking,
she had a phone on speaker.
Okay.
And you know, I'm just recording. Just
didn't want that shit in the background.
Oh my God,
the fucking look she gave me.
It's unbelievable.
You know,
like she's asking me to do shit all
the fucking time. Can you go here?
Can you pick up this? Can you do
this? Can you do that? I'll ask.
The Jewish just moved down one room
closed the door. She just looked at me,
cause I know what she's gonna say.
You fucking talk so fucking lad.
When you learn the fucking third
kick it the khaki cookie to kill you.
You know it's always, it always
comes back. Always come back. Hey,
de Rosa sent me some,
I guess they got this new fucking Charlie
Manson movie that's coming out with it.
They're trying to make the women
that Charlie convinced to
kill those people. Victims.
I don't give a fuck if
you're a victim or not.
If you're dumb enough that you let
some fucking psycho look in Jesus talky
window murdering a pregnant woman
and then trying to cut the baby out.
Yeah, you shouldn't be
walking around in society.
This is the new fucking thing.
The new fucking thing now is to go back
in time and find a bunch of selfish
cunts and then somehow blame it on guys.
And you know what I had started with it
started with that stupid movie monster.
Well,
that fucking lunatic was a serial killer.
And I'm watching the movie and they're
trying to make me feel guilty. Like I'm,
I'm, I'm part of the problem.
I'm the reason why she became,
when I saw the Jeffrey Dahmer movie,
they didn't do that. They just like,
this guy's out of his fucking mind
and he's eating people. Um, I dunno,
but it's a woman.
There has to be a reason.
Okay.
Maybe she just came out of the womb
a complete fucking psycho. Right?
Maybe that's what it was.
I don't fucking know.
I think they tried to like find some
sort of trajectory in the madness of
Jeffrey Dahmer, but at no point
that they blame women. Um,
although in fairness to the lab,
they, um, who's that
guy? That Ed Geanne Guy,
the guy from fucking Wisconsin.
Uh,
they did try to s they did say that his
mother fucked him up. So, I don't know,
maybe I'm just being a baby,
you know,
maybe I should have moved
to a one room over. Is that,
is that what I should have done?
Um, all right. So as I mentioned,
the Bruins lost two in a row, two in a
row, hoping to get back on track here.
Um, I'm going to the fucking Gad
and a dreams April 2nd. Everybody.
April 2nd,
I'm doing the God and the dreams with uh,
John Stewart. Oh, this is in New
York City by the way. Oh my God.
The read is unbelievable.
It's so much nicer than a Rita's
another fucking shit cities. Um, I'm
doing, it's Jerry Seinfeld. Jon
Stewart. Alijah Schlesinger's or your,
uh,
who else? Who else? Who
else? I forget who else.
Those are the names that I remember.
Oh, and yours truly. How could I forget?
Lovely me. Lovely baldy.
None even balding balled me.
Um, as the name of my one show,
one man show, lovely balled me.
I've chosen me.
I've decided to ignore
all the advertising does,
saying that I'm not good enough and
to say that I, I am good enough.
How fragile is your fucking psyche
that you fucking sit there looking at
advertising and it,
and it fucks with you to that level
that you're walking out behind a fucking
Papa John's throwing up into a
handicap parking spot, right?
I know what you think of bill.
Why would you suggest that Papa John's
puts the handicap parking behind?
I've never eaten at Papa John's.
All right.
Hm?
I like Papa.
Ginos Nice fucking Italian.
I don't want some guy named John
Making my God damn pizza. All right.
I want someone who can get a fucking tank.
That's someone that Burns
in fucking April. Um,
what was I talking about?
The, I've just, yeah, I mean,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
First of all,
the arrogance of you that you look at
a Victoria's secret model and you feel
like you'd have to compete with that.
First of all,
you can't any more than I
can compete with a Brad Pitt.
So what is the fucking problem?
And the second of all,
once the last time you saw a Victoria's
secret model walking to the bar that
you're drinking at all,
right?
You fucking regular looking person.
You're an irregular looking person bar,
you know with me in the second
and eight walks in the room,
everybody fucking turns like, like Bo
Derek just k walking in and that movie 10
Hollywood just create season.
Possible Standard. Yes. It's a movie.
I don't understand. Like when they
do this reboot boot a top gun,
I'm not going to feel like I need to
learn how to fly a fucking f a teen or
wherever the fuck they're flying.
Was it [inaudible] they up to the 19.
What are they up to now?
Let's see.
Uh,
you as a top fighter jet.
All right,
what do we got here?
Don't even fucking tell me.
It's called this the Sukhoi sue
57 what is it made in Japan?
Do we make anything here?
Please tell me.
In Asian American came up with that
and they make this an Indiana please.
For the love of God. Do you guys
have fucked up? That was if,
if all our fighter jets are made in Japan
and then we have beef with them again
and it's like, hey man, can you
keep making it? Making it as jet.
So like we can get you back for
bombing the other part of Hawaii now,
a top 10 best fighter jets in the world.
The top seven US fighter jets.
I'll come. They're not, they're
not doing the, uh, the f anymore.
The JTTF 22.
Yeah,
dude, I'm so old. I remember,
I remember the EF 60.
They have 60 was the Bob and I remember
a two 40 [inaudible] before the two 80
[inaudible] before the 300.
All right.
I remember the f 100.
I don't,
who's the F-150 enough to 50.
I just needed another example was another
one where they just kept going up the
Mazda rx seven. What are they up to? Nine.
I love how they just,
they don't start it.
One like Jordan's like the sneakers,
you know, then there's the Jordan twos,
Jordan threes.
They started like seven.
Okay.
Or a hundred. Um, if you wonder what
the fuck I'm talking about. I don't,
I don't know either. All right. I have
no idea. But anyways, I'm doing the guy,
ah,
no dreams on, uh, April 2nd.
It's in the, uh, it's the
theater at Madison Square Garden.
As I mentioned on Monday, this is where
Eddie Murphy did, uh, the raw special.
So I always think about that.
So I will be there and I'm also the day
before I'm going to go try to go to a
Brooklyn Nets game.
Now I haven't gone to a pro game in a
minute as far as checking another one off
the list.
And I had forgotten I only need like six
more teams and I've been to a home game
of every protein in all
four fucking sports.
Now there's a very select few of you
that thinks that's awesome and that's who
I'm talking to right now.
The rest of you could just fucking zone
out because this part of the podcast,
it's not about you
any more than,
than an average look at woman. It has
to feel intimidated because you know,
there's another Cindy Crawford coming
along or daughters now going to make a
whole other generation of
people not feel pretty enough.
And I got to tell you something there,
there is a beauty in coming
to the realization that you,
you aren't pretty enough.
And just embracing that,
just being like,
you know what?
I'm going to be the coolest six
that walks into this bar tonight.
It's all right being a six. Then
just add, add to it. You know,
tell a couple of jokes, learn how
to juggle. You know what I mean?
It's like you ever see
somebody when they get a three,
a Chrysler 300 and they try,
they try to make it look like a Bentley.
That's what you do.
But at no point do you actually say that
you're a fucking Bentley or do you get
mad that somebody is making a Bentley?
Does any of that makes sense?
I don't fucking know.
Um,
this is usually a point here when
I would read some advertising,
but I didn't get any so far.
I wonder why.
Probably because I shit on every
God damn one of them, you know,
and they fucking sensitive. I think
these women today have fucking sets it.
If you think these millennials
get their feelings hurt,
see these fucking advertising companies
get see a goddamn thing.
Um Oh, I do have a read. Here we go.
Dollar Shave club dude has
everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best and you
never have to go to was still war.
That's because they delivered everything
you need right to your front door.
You're lazy bastard and they keep
you fully stocked and what you,
what you use so you don't run out.
Here's how it works.
Dollar Shave Club has everything
you need to get ready.
They have your you covered from head to
toe for your hair, your skin, your face,
you name it, they got it.
Deodorant for your taint.
They have this new program where they
automatically keep you stocked up on
products you use.
You determine what you want when you
want it and shows right up your door from
once a month to once every six months,
however you want to do it.
Plus they're handsome discount.
The more you buy,
the more you save and right now dollar
shave club has a bunch of status sets.
You can try for just five bucks like
their oral care kit. Ladies after that,
the restock box ships regular sized
products@regularpricegetsyoustatussetforjustfivedollarsrightnowatdollarshaveclub.com
slash burr that's dollar
shave club.com/bar so,
so here we are
and it's now time to talk about soccer.
I guess Liverpool,
my adopted team is still down a point
to those man city cons. All right.
With their uh wait, where did they get
their money from? Somebody told me,
God damn it,
it's not Saudi Arabia,
is it?
Did they get it from our Air Emirates?
Is that when they get it from the airline?
Throw some of their first class fucking
ticket money at them. I don't remember.
Anyways, they're down a point that
down a point and they got a game.
Liverpool's got a game on Monday.
They pay full of is I would say so
they're probably full hand full.
You go buy Bulla Wall on Saint
Patty's Day. Oh Saint Patty's day.
You got to get out there. Where
your green plastic cat. You know,
where's my Hashtag on that
day where I get offended?
Everybody's going at [inaudible]
alligator. The low net goes, okay,
everyone's getting shit. If you
don't realize how fucked up that is,
you know how funny it is?
Irish people are part Irish people.
They go out and they'd just like,
there's no other fucking holiday.
Okay?
You know where people go out in, in
people who are, are that nationality,
literally go out and do the most like
negative stereotype of themselves.
You know,
black history month,
everybody's on their best
behavior, right? Jewish holidays,
everybody's fucking Shelan. Saint
Patty's day one app, it's high.
Everybody goes out,
gets drunk in the fucking street,
dresses like a Leprechaun and passes
out in the gutter. That's what happens,
right? Fucking corn, beef sandwich
fucking hanging out of the Saudi of mouth.
That's why I always
hated about that holiday.
It's like one of the prides of the
Irish is not only do you drink,
he can handle your fucking liquor. Don't,
but don't. Can you guys just don't,
just don't make a mess yourself.
Fucking sitting there drinking green beer
the fuck he you doing?
Oh Shit.
Odell Beckham Jr goes from the
giants to the Cleveland browns.
Cleveland Brown fans beside themselves
can't believe their good fortune.
Now they got a, they got that
kid there. What's his face there?
They got the quarterback. I just
spaced on his name. Baker Mayfield.
Right.
He's got a little bit of a swagger.
He likes talking a little bit of Shit.
Right.
He likes doing something
and doing a little dance in
front of the fucking crowd.
Now he's got a wide
receiver. Right. So what's,
what's this might work if they have like
an Al Davis old school sort of thing
because this reminds me of
what the Raiders used to do,
where they would take the fucking people.
Everybody said don't take are the outcasts
from other teams and then they would
go in there and everybody would just be
themselves and they would have a good
time.
Okay.
I hope it works out for the browns.
My Gut says I can't say that it won't.
It just all depends on the coach.
Okay.
The personality,
like that's a good rex Ryan team.
Cause then he's talking shit.
Oh Dell's talkin shit.
Baker's doing what the fuck he does. Uh,
but it's definitely going to be exciting.
But I actually think of, I think it
was a good move from, for the giants.
He didn't kind of fit into their,
they have vibe,
defensive minded organization.
You look at Eli shows up,
he's got Khakis on, he tucks
his shirt in. I mean that's,
that's what the giants I guess
have become, I don't know,
you listened to some of those lt
stories. Oh, Dellschau fit right in.
But um, I dunno. It was a big move and I
don't, I don't think they had to give up,
give up too much for the guy.
And they got a lot of draft picks.
So see what they do. And A, I've
got a couple friends of mine that,
a Cleveland Brown fans and they're all
saying they're GM knows what he's doing.
So who knows?
Hmm.
The only thing I need are to Cleveland
plans is to stop calling you stupid city.
The land, the land. Ugh.
Fucking Midwest people.
The land,
the Berg
did they call the natty
get on the bus.
You're in Columbus,
you get it the day.
Welcome to the day.
So what they say in Dayton? Uh, uh,
all right. Sorry, I'm being a cunt, but
it's what I do. All right. That's it.
I'm going to be,
uh,
out and about in La doing some
spots bombing this weekend,
uh, probably down the store on
Friday. That's the deal. All right,
so go Bruins,
go Celtics baseball is starting up.
A interesting stat here,
and this is something on the
success of the New York Yankees.
Do you realize in New York
Yankees are so fucking successful?
That sense they got babe Ruth
all right.
From the 1920s to this decade,
they've only gone one decade
where they didn't win a war,
at least one world series. And
that was the 1980s. And even still,
they went to a world series in
[inaudible] 81 and lost. Right.
If they don't win this year,
this'll be the first time that that's
the only second time this has happened
since women were allowed to vote.
Okay.
Which was another huge,
huge fucking mistake by this country.
Okay.
You should have kept those fucking
prides in the kitchen. No. Um,
I think it's great that
they could talk more.
Um,
anyways,
am I the only one who's like not
looking forward to this next election,
presidential election? I
just, I just don't see this.
I just didn't see it being a repeat of a
few years ago and it's just going to be
a fucking train wreck.
MMM.
Until you get that cancer
out of the locker room.
I just don't know what it's
going to be. I, if I, you know,
if I was running for president
on the democratic side,
what I would learn how to do
is talk some shit. All right.
Stop trying to talk about issues.
What you need to do is you need
to go in there and you need,
you need to make fun of his hair.
Make Fun of that to pay.
Make Fun of his fucking big motherly hips.
You gotta you gotta go after him
like that. All right. Why is,
why is your face orange and
underneath your eyes, his ghost white?
Do you have a tanning bed?
Is that some sort of cream that you
put under your eyes for puffiness?
That's what you do.
Do not go up there and try to talk
policy and interrupt the shit out of him.
Just do what he does.
Completely ignore all the fucking rules.
And then when you get called on it
just act like a victim. All right?
That's what it's going to be. This is
what politics is fucking become. Okay.
MMM.
I mean, I'm acting like it was on
the up and up before that, but uh,
I don't know.
We shall see.
Although I do have to give
Trump some props grounding
that, that airplane, right?
He did do that. He did try to
pull the troops out of Syria.
You saw the Democrats and
Republican. Whoa, Whoa, Whoa,
Whoa, whoa. Don't do that.
You biting the hand that
feeds bite net corporate cash.
I'll spill it out of their pockets.
And you watch all you ladies out
there loving your girl there.
The 29 year old checky watch you fuck it.
Well,
how soon before she gets a book deal,
how sue before she somehow
a multimillionaire only
making 150 200 grand a year.
But she has a vagina. So, so do you,
so you should vote for it, right?
That should make you feel good. All
right. That was a country way to end,
but that's how it's going to happen.
Enjoy the music.
And there'll be another half hour of a
greatest sets from a Thursday afternoon,
just before Monday,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast from earlier
this year or years before I, and I know,
fuck it.
All right.
Have a great weekend. You can go
live a pool. I'll see you on Monday.
Convenience street by
you and me.
They
give me a hard time.
She
shouldn't come around here,
you know, and that show
and I, Naomi Campbell,
she's like 52 and she's still affects me.
So it's like Tyra got a
lot of years to go day.
Who did we see walking away
from that hotel that day? Oh, I,
Cheryl t is Cheryl Tiegs. They're
looking good. That time is a bitch, man.
Dime is a bitch.
No,
I doing, I'm wasting my mental. And I
think you got a bit of a fetish. No,
you for awhile.
And older white women.
And he picked some bad
with Hillary Clinton. I,
my favorite number one is Carly Simon.
I will still pop Cory Simon.
I don't know why.
I know why everybody got
their fucking fetishes.
Alvin cow cover alone, which
she was on all fours, I suppose.
That big mouth. Yeah, that's what
I'm saying, man. That bitch is,
by the way, a lot of people backed us
up on that one. Wow. Yeah. Backyard.
A lot of people calling
and saying, Lord, we
saw moving back though. We saw Cheryl
Tiegs leaving the Donald Trump roast.
Yeah, Cheryl Tiegs. We had the great
seats from Voss. Well yeah. Alright.
Fairly in the buildings and thanks rich
and I cocked your checkers for the Trump
roast section. Oh, I'm going to be, we,
we were behind a monitor that was
showing the rows behind it on the second
floor. Dude, everyone's going in
the main ballroom and we headed,
our tickets I got were going
to be hobnobbing with the,
the top celebrities in New
York. Right. Awesome. The usher,
it looks at our tickets and
goes, Oh God, take that elevator.
But W and then you're thinking,
all right, well, you know,
it's an elevator you ever see a roast
with is an upstairs. It's always,
it's the, the day is and the
table upstairs that are roasted.
So at first we're like,
all right,
well we'll follow all the other people
that have seats in that area. No,
there were maybe another 20
people that had sciatic area.
And we sit down and then
I have my seat stunk.
I had him stand up and look over
this video screen to see anything.
I couldn't tell who was up at the,
they were tiny day.
Everybody gets in the elevators,
like holding cable and Shit. Yeah,
that's what it was. They
were all tech guys. Gaffers.
They were heading for the
fucking beat mixing board.
So we're heading for the walkways
high above. That's, so we leave.
The roasts were walking back
towards the station and uh,
we're right behind Cheryl Tiegs
and her white old saggy ass.
Like how bad does it look though?
I mean tears and I'm
saying for an old old lady,
she probably isn't that bad.
But when you compare her to the Cheryl
Tiegs poster that was on everybody's wall
with the netting that she was just
wearing a neck and her nipples were poking
through. I mean you wouldn't
fuck Sophia Loren. No,
cause she exists 60 something years.
There's got to be just a glimpse
of just young Sophia's one trial,
half a pussy lip, paint
enough. Believe me.
And when you see these people out,
remember they are looking
at their absolute best.
This is the best they can possibly look.
How old is Cheryl Tiegs?
50 gotta be,
she's got to be in her in her fifth
phase five and no redeeming sexuality.
She's not drunk.
I didn't see any redeeming sexuality.
I saw an older woman
that you look at and go,
all right, she's an older
woman that doesn't look like
she's ready to fall apart.
What do you,
you know the old broad women like who
continue to dye their hair like that.
It becomes like a fucking
birds nest right out.
And also like as you get into like you
get into like your sixties it's like the
smell of rotten pending death. So he
started having that old person smell.
So you see the top of their head because
it gets to what you tall it and see
right through that Kenny hair.
It's like that fucking white
cotton candy hair and scalp price.
Low box to the back of her hand.
And she kept jerking you off.
You gotta you gotta fucking old Sophia
Loren and fucking movie on the TV.
Trying not to look at the what happened
in that whole Rod, don't you got back up?
Oh Shit.
Close your eyes.
So an open the Ark of the Covenant in
front of that Bitch. Right on man. No she,
she,
she looks like you know a nice older lady.
But you know you have a view of just
against, you're just against old bitches.
I could feel it. You know
what? I disagree with that. I,
I when, when it's because the
hardest old bitch you could just be,
cause he's compared to the
memory has been what it is. I'm,
I'm remembering what she looked like.
Oh who's the hottest old bitch we knew
her was because she was a sex symbol.
So already there. Your old bitch. I know.
And and and his is,
the criteria is Diane Sawyer.
It's not one that became,
that used to be hot and super hard and
just maintain it, but like, oh wow.
She used to wait.
She's,
she used to be super hot but now she's
all bitch like Cheryl Tiegs but she,
you still like what's up? God knows.
I mean now motherfucker now lack then
not when she was old in 80 I remember
goofy makeup on my right this second.
She's a bad bitch.
God Damn. At least
what's, what's old enough?
Go back to the seventies and think who do,
who did I want to fuck back then
with China? But they were all,
I never wanted to pop gripe mom's back
then it was never a hot looking at arm,
which that you would now Pam Greer,
Pam Greer,
a Jessica Simpson
and sees all the old side,
the, I took the bid and went the other
way. I can write, I think I'm trying,
I'm going through like old 70s TV show
kind of things cause I'm in [inaudible]
80 minutes or area.
And so it seemed like a filthy lucre
Merriam mother from happy days.
Then I like Karen grassle
for House on the prairie.
The mother from little house, Mary Ross
was a bit of a whore. Well there's, yeah,
there's always answer that is hot as shit.
Something her and Fonzie going to go.
No. I'll talk about my mom that
there's always ads. Mom, shut up.
Anthony's mother's hot.
Never talk about my mom like that
takes care of herself. But you
know, she's no spring chicken.
Awkward moment. I have with a good friend
of mine the other day he came to town,
I took her to a Knicks game. Right.
He's sitting there, right. And I go,
uh, and he, he, he's talking
about my little sister. He
goes, well, how, how, uh,
how old, how old is she now? Huh? And I'm
like, uh, he goes to see in high school,
you got to go do it if you can believe
it. She's graduating high school. He goes,
good Lord, we're getting old. Like
A, yeah, it's just here. Sure.
She knows beautiful girl.
And he goes, he goes, well,
the apple doesn't fall
too far from the tree.
Your mother was always really attractive
and it was just kind of silent,
so used to jerk off to my mom.
That's great to know. Yeah.
You got to fill in the blank.
And Dan,
Lynda Carter,
Pat Benatar,
Lynda Carter.
Now Lynda Carter.
Linda fucking, yes. Let me say something.
I would want to limit card function is
wonder woman. Let me tell you what else.
Dad Bitch from buck Rogers
and [inaudible]. Erin Gray,
she was very hot during that time.
Now she's still a hotbed.
She dumped on my Suzanne Summers,
but she got that carved her
face that she is really old man.
Let's go to a gym in Waco.
Jim. She kept those too.
I hated those fucking big
bloomer panty things. She wore
her out with those.
Now have a nice set of
Victoria's secret spy. Now
that big blue,
my bitch with those boots,
I was never into higher even as a kid,
like when she was Mondo woman,
she was too motherly looking.
How about Lani and too old?
She's just biting Ivan hot. She's just,
she's, when I was fucking married,
when I was 10 I was
into 10 year old girls.
When I was 12 I was at a 12 year
old girls, 1414 year old girls.
That's how I went.
I was never like 14
into 38 year old women.
I never found them attractive.
They were like moms is your whatever.
My age was up until 15 and then
it was always just 15 year old,
so, so forth. Just did. He just May. Okay,
so 14 you weren't into 28 year olds.
Nine means though,
so let's double it.
He's not into something double as age.
So it was Anthony's by eight so how
old was show? Got To be 122 again.
I was trying to back you into that corner.
I know.
Voluntary out both. Derek is covered load.
Derrick still hot. Bo Derek now. Okay.
If you got to point out a hotter, older
woman. All right, I'll give it to Bo.
Derek still looks good.
That doesn't look like she's
trying to keep yourself young.
Would fucking surgery in ship.
There's nothing worse than these duck
billed fucking old broads walking around
the lips thinking it looks good.
It ladies, you look freakish.
You look like ducks as
creepy. He talked like, God,
please kind of had a short
appointment for next week when I,
oh, there's a creepy, I
don't like that. Look at all.
Amen.
Finds a street.
The sound of the shape.
You and me buddy.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
okay.
[inaudible].