Hey, what's going on?
It's build bar and a jet.
Yeah.
On a Thursday afternoon.
What's going on? How White?
I am a, as you're listening to this,
I'm probably already on an airplane.
[inaudible] fade you
think is my aero plane.
Ooh.
Is that the fucking album that uh,
the chili peppers, they don't like.
I liked that album.
I'm a little pee.
I love this guys and the tree,
I like it right until he goes,
you're homophobic reggae leg kick.
And then he just sounds like he
should be beaten with his base.
And I liked fleet,
but that's one of the lines.
I was with them right up until then. And
then I was just kinda like, you know,
fleet maybe just maybe,
do you ever think maybe you're bringing
it on yourself just a little bit.
MMM. Anyways, so this is the
Thursday afternoon podcasts.
It's just a quickie, just a little
half hour, just to half hour on payday.
At least old school pay day,
pay day. When I was a kid,
I think before me,
you know,
all those people used to sell
their own pants together.
They used to get paid in like
lambs and sheep and shit whenever,
and then after them,
then people got those little Buller caps,
those fucking clockwork orange things.
And then they got paid on Fridays and
then some point and moved to Thursday.
And that's when all freckles
came down the pike. Oh.
I've looked on loads of trucks.
Right. Next thing you know,
I'm getting paid on a Thursday.
So I assumed that that's
the way it was going to be.
Um, but unfortunately they moved it back
to Friday. I don't fucking know why.
I have no idea.
God knows.
God knows it wasn't for the working man
right there where we just fuck it over
to work in men, every guide, da Da. I
don't know nothing about real wobbly. MMM.
So anyways,
I just fuck around on this
one and basically the last
half of the podcast that
play a little bit of greatest hits,
you know what I mean?
Get you over the fucking Humpday
there, uh, before it gets,
um, speaking a staton. I'm on
my way to Boston here, you know,
for my, my, my, um, homecoming,
going to wear one of those little fucking
crowns and the sash and playing the
fucking Wilbur. I'm doing it
from a, what the hell am I doing?
Me Check out my, uh, my pit bulls
calendar here in the corner.
Like I'm fucking nine years old.
Oh,
look at those cuties jumping through the
little fucking thing together. Right.
Enjoying themselves,
not trying to kill each other.
No sign of Michael Vick or anybody with
the fucking neck tattoo that they'll
live in the life.
I am there from this Saturday,
May 8th until Tuesday.
Hang on.
Who's they the fuck gay 19th.
Tuesday the 19th.
I'm doing like a week and a half
run two shows every night, but
during the Wilbur run, so,
uh, it's gonna be great.
I've got a bunch of family
and friends coming out.
It's going to be like a mini high
school reunion on some nights.
Some of my old drinking buddies
and people I went to school with.
It's going to be a, uh, it's going
to be a phenomenal time. But, uh,
if you can't make it up to Boston,
you can't jump in your car.
Can't get on a plane,
but you live in the New York City area.
I have a show that you should go to.
Right?
Why would you want to come see me when
you want to see somebody on their way up,
right?
You don't want to see some fat pasty
freckled jerk off who's was just a little
bit too impressed with himself.
Why would you want to watch that for an
hour when you can actually go to a show
and be like, Hey, I saw them when
that's always the best, right?
It was fucking old hippies be like,
yeah,
I saw Hendrix would like fucking five
people. You know, he's, he's, fuck yeah,
he walked up, he's a to swing my guitar.
Like, yeah, you know, he seemed cool.
Whatever you want to fucking go
down there before they get famous.
That's what you want to do.
So you can seem cool.
Like you knew what the fuck was up.
All right.
Why don't you go to the Gotham comedy
club this weekend with this monster show
New Jersey zone.
The pride of trend at Paul Versey,
is that his name now?
Paul Versey Rosebowl tailgate legend,
the don himself.
All right.
From Pittsburgh via San
Francisco, Joe Barton, Nick.
And then rounding it out.
All right.
First Generation Greek.
Yannis Pappas.
You've got three headliners for the
price of fucking one at the Gotham comedy
club. Did perform in Friday and
Saturday night tickets are going fast,
which I knew they were going to. I'm just
trying to help the boys sell it out. Uh,
push the last few over.
It's a great fucking club and a,
the Mozillas who run into just the
salt of the earth. Fucking people.
They got so many. Someday somebody is
going to do a fucking documentary on them.
And um,
Steven Christmas silly and uh,
I'm telling you, they,
they just fucking, I dunno.
Christmas facilities got some of
the most classic fucking lines ever.
The shit that he said to people,
he doesn't take any shit.
If you come in there and
you're a fucking prima Donna,
he just fucking gives it to you straight.
He's not even a fucking asshole about it.
All right?
He just in the most
eloquent dapper way ever,
if it's a dapper with this a possible way
in a dapper wait to tell somebody that
they're being a cunt Muzzillo he can
do it with one eyebrow. You know,
he's looking down at
his shit and then you,
you fucking come in there
with you fucking, you know,
Diana Ross and the Supremes vibe and he
will just fucking lift an eyebrow up and
look at you. And that's
it. You just submit the,
and you immediately know
that you're out of line.
But if you're a sweetheart and
he doesn't need to do that,
the guy will treat you like
a fucking king. So, um,
please go down and check
out that show if you can.
All right enough with the horn it out.
Let's get into what the fuck we want it.
I want to talk about this week. All
right. As I keep an eye on game.
Three of the Canadians,
Tampa Bay taping this on a Wednesday
first period has ended Canadian zero
lightning one huge game.
Huge game.
Does Tampa Bank put their
foot right on the throat? Oh,
those silly software and Montreal
Canadians or Canadian crawl back into this
series reaching back into time when
they used to be successful to draw some
inspiration. But to fuck the Iq.
I don't have a dog in the fight.
I'm actually enjoying.
Um,
I'm actually a join all the
hockey that had been watching.
I can't even like watch a Canadians and
hate him right now cause we're not even
in the fucking when I'm in in it. So,
um, I'm actually watching the game.
I'll see PK do something. I go and I'll
just inadvertently be like nice play.
Like what am I doing? Um, so anyways,
fuck the world of sports for a second.
Let's get into the world of nothing that
actually includes the world of sports
today. So have a deadly, there
was still investigating, um,
the under inflated balls.
Where would that game,
the Patriots won like fucking nine
years ago. Way Back in January.
Do you remember that?
Let me refresh your memory.
They one 45 to seven
okay.
And at the end of the game,
Jimmer say said, okay,
that's what he said. A grown man
shed that at the end of the game,
he had the nerve to say that we cheated
a man who sits on the rules committee of
the NFL and on numerous occasion has
changed rules that were advantageous for
rezone fucking team because he couldn't
beat those patriots, right? New England,
he did that fucking 10 years ago.
They changed it.
They were covering our receivers to horde.
Him and Peyton manning
made a fucking tape.
They whined about that after the game.
They whined about it
during the super bowl.
They whined about it at the fucking pro
bowl, paid madding brought that shit up.
And then at the draft they was still
crying about it. And next thing you know,
this is new fucking rule saying that
all you can do as escort people down the
fucking Goddamn turf.
And next thing you know,
all of Dan Marino's records are falling
left and right. And Lo and behold,
the cults finally beat compatriots
and when a God damn Superbowl,
that's what old freckles here said.
Wait a minute,
why the fuck did they change that to
have what kind of fucking pull does this
guy have? One fucking owner
complaints. They make a tape,
they wind for a couple of months and all
of a sudden the entire game of covering
a receiver gets changed.
Who sits on this rural committee
and one name stuck out like that?
Fucking Oliver Stone's movie who's sitting
there dressed in drag with a powdered
fucking wig talking to Joe Pesci with
lipstick on his fucking lips. Ah,
old gym.
Or say this fucking jerk off is sitting
here whining about the New England
patriots. First of all, the ball. Okay.
If they were under inflated, right?
Like they're suggesting,
I don't even know what they're saying
because they keep going like Tom Brady.
He could know he could possibly,
there's no proof,
but we think he might have done it.
Do you know how fast you would get laughed
out of court if that was your opening
argument? Yeah, you're on air on
the night in question. We are,
uh,
we are proliferating that the defendant
in the proximity over there that wasn't
table could possibly have been involved
in something that he didn't do but maybe
know about.
And we would like to press forward with
this trial and waste more fucking time
and money.
Now granted,
having absolutely no fucking proof
what's so fucking ever whatsoever fucking
ever has never stopped sports talk
radio or ESPN from marching ahead.
They'll be like, there's no proof. We
can't say it. But having said that, yeah,
if they'll sell stro one
is this, say, what does,
what does this say? Sorry thing turned
out. What does it say about his legacy?
What does this say above the game
about competition? What does it say?
What does this got to do?
What does the sake of the children
is how you do sports talk radio.
And all they're doing is staring at the
phone lines to try to get it lit up.
And the more it doesn't
light up, the bigger they go.
What does it say, uh, about,
uh, how we conduct our
foreign affairs with Isis?
I'm a, I'll be enough fuel if
you can, if you can have a ball.
That was his bills fully a floater.
Okay.
What's to say that Isis isn't right off
little shore and a sub that they bought?
Yeah.
Awful. The Russians were second
calls right now. One 800.
Who gives a fuck here on Fox sports?
West first caller,
Michael from Indianapolis.
Every dirty joke about Derek.
Oh wait my pigs.
I already knew about it. You'll do,
you'll do like he knew about it and that.
Oh whoa, whoa, whoa.
Do you have any sort of
football background beyond
watching your pig fucking a
chicken. Is there any sort
of sports professional or,
or possibly just down at the y? No,
I played terribly wake up on time.
I like playing corn hole and uh,
you know,
play horse shoes every once in a while
we got Tom, you know, but you know,
the banks were really trying to foreclose
on my property here, so I don't know,
man.
I'm just Kinda mad my team whilst in or
if there's any fucking excuse I can make
six later I made shit. I'll call
it shit man. I'll throw some buck.
I'm manure on that fire. I'll do it.
Bucket. We're taking them all calls here.
That's all they're going to fucking do.
This absolutely fucking,
there's nothing going on
here. It's over. You know,
I think know I want to tip my cap here
that I'm not wearing to fucking Seattle
for just saying, Hey, great game.
You know we throw it to him.
Malcolm Butler fucking jumped around and
yeah, and you beat us. You know what?
But you know what?
We're going to come back next year and
we're going to try to kick your fucking
ass. So I hope you guys, you'll
help you work out this weekend,
this fucking off season.
You know that's what a team of men does.
Okay.
That's what they do.
But when you fucking owner is up there
with the God damn wearing adult diapers
and has a rattle, that's what they
did. Underinflated fucking ball.
This is a funny thing too,
cause they said, well,
we noticed it by the half and then we had
the fully inflated balls and we scored
even more points and kicked
their ass even worse. I don't,
I got to tell you something,
man. I don't know what,
I don't know what the Patriots have done.
I don't know what the fuck
they did to these people. Okay.
And it's really only two people. It's
fucking gym or say, and it's fucking,
what's his face there? Uh, Tony, uh, uh,
main genie, man. Jeannie, who by the way,
you notice is completely out of football.
Completely out of fucking football.
Did you see when he tried to
commentate about it on ESPN,
he sounded dumber than I did in
this guy actually coached a team.
Who the fuck would hire him as a head
coach? That j e t s just jet jet's. Um,
anyways, you know, give me a fucking
break. Okay. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
We want again. And by
we, I mean the Patriots.
I don't have a dog in this fucking fight,
but um,
have added all you guys on Twitter
and all you people in sports bars.
If you want to say what you say, I
don't give a fuck. He's got the rings.
If you want to whine about some
underinflated fucking balls,
if you want a bitch,
I mean,
you know what's the dumbest thing ever
is that don't film the teams on the
sidelines, but there's nothing to
say. You can't do it up in the booth.
There's no rule against that.
I hope you guys realize that there isn't,
as far as I know, as far as what
I've overheard in sports bar series,
and I remember when that shit
was going on, I would did it.
I went to a football game in Georgia
and I met somebody that used to play for
one of the teams.
I'm not saying Georgia,
the other team not trying to get anybody
in trouble and he laughed. He goes,
do we used do that shit all the fucking
time? I love what people just think like,
oh,
you got to do is just filmed somebody.
You're going to win four Superbowls
just under inflate the fucking ball.
Do do you realize if that
was a guaranteed victory,
let's just say under inflating the ball
in an AFC championship game or just in a
professional football game in general
would cause you to beat a better team?
45 to seven what the fuck do you
think they would be doing every game?
You know when the fucking coach,
when he runs during halftime as he was
sitting there talking to the reporter,
you know, you know they always have the
fucking, the little lady out there, coach,
you know your dad by 17
points you haven't scarred.
You've punted every play that you didn't.
You didn't turn the ball over.
What would you like to do? And
the second I have, well you know,
we'd probably like to stop doing that
Shit and put some points on the board.
They're fucking cutie pie.
All right.
And in the meanwhile you'd
hear in the background. Yeah,
they would just be letting you know. I
know we're going to do on the second half.
We're going to go with,
we're going to let a half a fucking
cunt hair out of the ball and all of a
sudden our fuck,
we're going to beat these guys.
We're going to score 45 points to this
seven. Give me a fucking break. All right.
Okay.
Jesus Christ.
You know,
we can't really prove
that, that, that he did it.
Um,
this Eric Walden coat cults,
linebacker,
I told TMZ that it's gross that
Tom Brady would resort to cheating.
He hasn't been there. There's nothing
that proves that he did anything.
Okay.
Well,
his report stated it was more probable.
Okay.
They're not that the Patriots quarterback
was at least generally aware of the
inappropriate activities do.
This is the most vague horse shit ever.
It's unfortunate that they did this,
but there's still the chance.
What a fucking good Lord.
You got to give them credit.
They did it and they got away with
it and they won the Superbowl.
It's this fucking Walden guy.
Serious. You lost 45 to fucking seven.
Wow. I, I can, I can I actually, uh,
how about you guys? Can you guys,
you guys who aren't colts
fans or a patriots haters.
Can you guys maybe a update the patriot,
the colts logo
two,
I don't know.
Maybe put like one of those little baby
bonnets on it and a fucking rattle.
Okay.
Yeah, that's what it is. Everybody. Wow.
They've been under under a deflating
balls for the last 15 years and he finally
got caught because Tom Brady is actually,
he really is a six round pick.
Any absolutely stinks.
And all those throws that you saw make,
you know what most of the people in the
stand could make them if you just under
inflated it just a little bit. It's
incredible. It's absolutely incredible.
And then,
uh,
Andrew luck who had the disadvantage of
playing with the ball that weighed the
same as every other ball he's ever thrown
in his fucking professional career.
You know, because it was the right
weight that caused him to throw,
pick sixes and incomplete
passes and all of that.
It's because of the weight of the ball.
See a lot of people don't know that it
really has nothing to do with athletic
ability.
What it really has to do is what the
ball ways and all you need to do is just
take a little bit of air out of it and
all of a sudden you'll beat the cult so
bad that you actually beat Seattle.
Isn't that incredible? That's what,
that's the level of cheating that's
going on here right now. In fact,
what I'm going to do during
my run of dates here is a,
I'm going a little blood,
a little bit of air out of the theater
so people get a little lightheaded and
I'll see him. They'll get a little high
and I'll see me even funnier. Meanwhile,
I'll secretly have,
you know,
pure oxygen going up my fucking nose.
So what I'm going to do this weekend,
you know, and then maybe someday, uh,
Nick's comedy stop across the street.
We'll investigate it. All right,
let's get off this dumps subject. By the
way, I am playing the Wilbur theater.
And what's great about that is,
uh,
doing this whole run of dates is my
comedy career started right across the
street on warrants and street.
Nick's comedy stop March 2nd, 1992.
Sorry about the phone there. 1992. And uh,
to be right across streets.
Pretty cool. I swear to God,
if there was a show at Nick's comedy stop,
you know that I can run over
and do a quick five minutes,
I'm going to try to do
it. Um, but anyways,
I want to thank everybody that's come
out and uh, that's actually, you know,
bottle these tickets and everything.
It's really insane. And I'm, Oh,
I'm coming with a poster. Oh, you know,
I am and I'm bringing my fucking a game.
It'd be nice to be around some patriots
fans who actually fucking, there's,
I can't say the only patriots fans,
cause there's so many sports fans that
I know just sitting there going, dude,
this is fucking ridiculous.
But I know people hate the Patriots,
so they'll try to say that's why they won.
Yeah.
So all you guys out in the West who
can't beat Seattle these last two years,
what you want to do is
right before you play him,
deflate the ball a little bit in the
first half when 45 to seven against an
incredible opponent and then
somehow you'll beat Seattle.
That's all you have to do. And
then you to, you will have a ring.
And I want to commend the
colts for, uh, you know,
for never cheating on any level,
no gamesmanship whatsoever.
They've always been on the up and
up over there and, uh, you know,
I'm surprised they don't have those little
girl scouts sashes going across them.
I mean, they just sell on the up and
up and wholesome Indianapolis, Indiana,
Indiana in general. What it, what a
great state, you know what I mean?
Still keeping the clan alive despite
the fact that they are up north. I mean,
that's, that's, that's a special
kind of hatred. Um, all right.
Anyways,
you know,
one of the cool things about
traveling and meeting other people is,
uh, is, uh, just, I dunno, I,
I grabbed like newspapers and shit like
that. I got to find this fucking thing.
I was sitting there reading like,
you know,
I'm one of these fucking liberal
comes out here. I'm not really,
I thought it was liberal til I moved out
here, but I'm, I'm sort of a, uh, no,
j law had,
I'm not going to say when he calls
himself because I don't want get them in
trouble,
but like liberal is in there.
But it's actually a funny way
he defines himself. But, um,
I don't, I'm one of those guys where
I said, you know, I call people cons,
but you know, I'm also interested in
having chickens in my backyard, you know,
growing my own food, right?
I don't fucking know.
I Like v eight engines, but
I also drive a, I'm a fucking
Weirdo, man. I'm all over.
I'm all over the fucking
map. Um, so anyways,
so I saw this thing says mother hen
raising backyard chickens teaches life
lessons.
And this was at the Hamburg journal and
I can't remember if I got this. And,
Oh, I got in Kentucky,
Lexington, Kentucky, uh,
where I had the great time
or the seersucker suit had
a awesome fucking show and
they really treated us right out there.
So I'm reading this thing and this woman,
this lady, she did what I did.
She watched one of these, uh,
you are what you weed or
fucking food inc and you know,
basically bought into it the way I did
where I saw, I was like, Holy Shit,
I got to make sure I go
down to a farmers Ma.
Yeah.
And um, get myself, you know,
some shit that doesn't have a little
bit of cancer spray on it, which I get,
I mean, I kind of get with it do when
you got to feed 7 billion people, I mean,
you've got to take out some bug spray.
It's just how it works.
But I'm trying to lessen the bug spray.
So I did that maybe for about three
days and it was, it was really hard.
It was really hard. And I
quit. You know, you know,
like a lot of these women who consider
themselves feminists like, oh my God,
I'm a feminist. No, no. You
know what you really did?
Life was hard and you quit and now
you're looking for a scapegoat.
I'm not saying all of them,
but I'm talking about the bottom feeders.
You know the ones I'm talking about,
right?
The ones that want the world to buy him
a drink and then give them the credit.
Those ones, you know, the
ones who don't think that,
they just think being a guy is easy and
you don't have to work for anything.
You just walk in and gum drops fall from
the fucking ceiling. Oh, you got a dick.
What dream would you like to have
come true today? Right. Anyways,
so this woman actually was like,
she went the whole fucking,
which she actually planted a garden.
Granted she had a fucking yard. Um,
she planted a garden but still raised
all, you know, raised all this,
grew all his fucking food.
The kids loved it and all that.
So then at one point she's
just like, all right, fuck it.
I'm going to get chickens and uh,
you know,
the chickens lay the eggs and they started
selling to the neighbors and all that
type of shit.
And here's something I did not realize
because I actually was thinking like,
you know, facts. He had
the space or something.
I'd love to have some fucking chickens
running around a goddamn goat. You know,
you fucking bend over to
pick up the morning paper.
He comes in and you across the yard and
exhale your flock and wrestling with it.
Huh? Sweeping. It's four
legs and having a great time.
Little farm action in the city.
Um,
this is something I didn't know is that
chickens after a while can't lay any
more eggs. Right? Like they went through
menopause or something. Sorry ladies.
I'm just, you know,
whatever. I'm, I'm, you know,
I never took any of those fucking
biology classes help me out here. So, um,
anyways, their kids love the chickens
and everything. So what happens is,
is once the chicken
can't lay eggs anymore,
that's when you gotta make a decision.
What am I going to do with
this fucking thing? Right.
Does it come and TV sit next to me and
asked me for the fucking collect or do I
take this thing up? Um, so let me just
read a little, as she said, she goes,
this is the middle of this story. She
said, uh, my daughter does her part too.
It's her job to pick through the leftovers
and food scraps and tossed them out
to the chickens.
Soon after I signed her that jobs,
the chicken learned to come
running whenever they saw
because they knew she had
something for them. Uh, but
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
She wants to treat them as pets though
I Warner that chickens are for making
food first eggs and then one day meet
because hen stop laying at some point and
I'm not running a chicken retirement home.
This is so refreshing to read because
I would never read this in La.
This person would get
tarred and feathered. This
woman's like you that pets,
they're fucking food. Make me some
goddamn eggs. And when they'd done,
I'm lobbing your fucking head
off and where it happens,
where I'm a chicken dinner.
So anyways, she goes,
I've only had to kill one
chicken from me before too.
I killed because they were suffering
from in injuries. And it was kinder. Uh,
that chicken was death beak.
That's what she named him.
So named by my husband because she was
jet black with BD red eyes and look like
trouble from the get go, uh,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Let me get to this stuff. Um,
so anyways, she could've paid. So
anyway, so the moment of truth comes,
it's fucking, thing's not laying any
more eggs and she's got to take it out.
Right. She's got to stick an ice
pick in the back of his head.
I thought I'd never shut
up. Um, so she goes,
I could have hired a guy to do it
for me for five bucks. All right.
But that roll around your
fucking head for a second.
There's somebody in Lexington,
Kentucky who's five bucks a head,
just goes array, makes five bucks
to kill a chicken every day.
You know what I mean?
That's like when that's in Kentucky,
that's like an Uber driver.
Your work. I work
whenever I want. You know,
I just fucking turn on the APP and they
tell me to come out and go kill a couple
of chicken. Five, 10, 15, 23rd,
I'm at one day I made a horror and $27.
I've got a $2 tip and I ain't telling you
for what, but I'll tell you right now,
I still rub one out to it.
Um, so anyways, she goes,
I could have hired a guy to do it
for me for five bucks. She goes,
but I'm not squeamish.
So I decided to do it myself.
The kind of thing that made this
country great, right? You Get up,
you put your pants on one leg at a time,
you go out and you murdered
somebody else that's in the way.
You don't hire somebody else
to do your dirty work. Right.
Uh, my grandfather left.
My grandmother laughed yourself sick when
I confessed that I had learned how to
do the deed,
basically killed the chicken from an
ultra ultra crunchy youtube video called
respectful chicken harvest. And
yes, we will have a link. Um,
but it did, uh, it did at
least show me the ropes.
When I announced to that death
peak was about to meet her doom.
The kids were appalled
for about a hot minute.
Then they remembered how mean she
was and weren't so sad after that.
This isn't fucking regular publication.
They insisted on sticking around to watch
when I wasn't trying to avoid getting
clawed in the face by a
chicken's death throes.
I watched the kids faces to basically,
when she's holding this
fucker down lopping it's God
damn head off or choking it
out, whatever she's doing, passing
its guard. As far as I can tell,
she's occasionally glancing over at a
kid. So this is like some fucking, uh,
what's that show about?
The castle and the little cunty kid
runs it and he puts people to death.
Okay.
Ah, fuck. What's it
called? Lord of the flies.
Lies gimme back my crown.
Yeah.
Duty. You're watching. Are you watching
Lord of the Rinat Lord of the rings.
What does it call come on and
everybody fucking loves that show.
Uganda and Queen,
I can't remember what it's called.
I want to watch it medieval times. You
don't what it is. It's on fucking cable.
They're there. They're in
their last scene, right?
There's a dragon or some shit,
I think. Anyways. Uh, she thought,
okay,
can't, he's got the, the
little fellow there, Fox,
all the women crushing it.
Full head of hair.
He's got that fucking Eddie Rabbitt beard.
I love a rainy night. Who Do? Ooh.
Why do I keep thinking Lord of the Rings?
I can't get it out of my head. Fuck.
All right. Anyways, she said, I asked
her if she wanted to stop eating meat.
Oh, wait a minute. Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Sorry. I missed this thing.
I looked at the kids' faces.
I could see how deeply it affected
my daughter in particular. Yes.
You fucking murderer in this chicken. Uh,
she had never seen an animal die before.
She never saw you kill one either.
I could see the awareness of mortality,
mortality,
shadowing across her face.
She cried at bedtime and said she
hated that death beak had to die.
All right. The death die. Got to
give it a more sympathetic name.
I asked her if she wanted to stop
eating meat because all meat comes from
animals who must die for us to eat.
She thought carefully and said
she's still wanting to eat meat,
so we lay there late into the night and
talked about the food chain and informed
choices.
My son was far more practical about it
when I interviewed him for this story,
he shrugged and said,
Eh, at first I was sad,
but then I was okay because that
was some good chicken and dumplings.
So you're right there. Isn't that
great. That's why you travel around.
I swear to God, man, if
anybody out here in Hollywood,
yeah,
fucking ever did that with a chicken,
held the fucking thing down.
It's it's fucking leg
fucking freaking out and you
got your kids watching it.
You probably get arrested,
at least down here in Los Angeles.
You get a little bit north to Bakersfield
in between San Francisco and Los
Angeles,
Reagan country where they're growing the
food and they're actually dealing with
the fucking drought as opposed to
the conch down here, myself included.
Okay.
Trying to take a shower. Can, can we
get Fiji water polo into our in shower?
Um, anyways, I just thought that that was
interesting. Like just to read it. And um,
do you think you could do it?
Huh? Did you get killed a chicken?
I could fucking kill a chicken.
I just take out a meat cleaver.
I would,
you got to get like those
fucking psycho gloves.
Like I'm picking up something
crazy that could scratch me.
You just got fucking boom Bam really
quick. I would think. You know what?
I'm going to watch that
fucking video anyways.
Whatever the fuck do you want from me?
You know, I was just checking in on me.
I had a great day today.
Everybody, I took the,
I'm getting ready to get my
pilot's license here and I,
today I had the written examination,
the one I've been studying for,
for like the last month,
600 questions of which they snagged 60.
And, uh, you know, you got to
get a 70 or better, you know,
sounds a little bit easier than it is,
but there's all kinds of math and charts
and all this fucking density altitude,
that fucking wind correction angle and
all of this shit. And you know me. Okay?
You guys have heard me read out loud,
read out loud, read out loud right there,
right there. You know how hard I was
struggling with this shit. So I studied,
you know, for the last couple of
weeks. And uh, even on the bus tour,
I'd go in the back of the
bus and I would just go,
I gotta I gotta put my two hours in and
I took it today and obviously I passed
or I wouldn't have fucking brought it up.
So I'm psyched.
Although the couple things, I got
an 85, I wanted to get the 90.
I got an 85 and I fucked up a couple of
those. I'm not good at that. Uh, you know,
taking out the little fucking slide
rule and graph and shit. I, I, you know,
I just blew it off. It was on my
computer screen. I'm like, yeah,
I wouldn't have lasted me
like one or two of those.
And it was like fucking three of them.
Yeah.
Um, anyway, so I passed that.
So the next thing I got to do
is I gotta I gotta talk to uh,
one of the representatives from the FAA
and he grills me for an hour and if I
pass that then I go out and fly
and that happens on the same day.
And if I do that Bing
Bang, boom, I got it.
So that's what the fuck
I'm up to after my show.
So that's what I'll be doing
during the day when I'm in Boston.
You can eat the food.
No,
I'll be studying my fucking ass
off and saying the shit out loud.
So it sounds like I know what I'm
talking about. You know what I mean? Um,
as opposed to being
like, ah, yeah. Um, wait,
that's a translational lift
when the coming out of a horror,
I don't sound like a fucking
moron. I just want to be like you.
What kills me is when I'm taking this
thing is they have so many students from
China.
They opened up something over there where
I guess they wouldn't let people fly.
Now anybody, not anybody, but you
know, way more people can do it.
And they had an overflow of people
in their schools couldn't handle it.
So these kids flight all the way over
to Los Angeles and in a second language,
not only learn how to fly a helicopter,
but sit down across from some hard nosed
person from the FAA that's going to put
you in the air if you don't pass the test.
They do this in a second language.
And every time I see him, like I just
feel like such a pussy. I'm just like,
could I go to chuck? Can
I go to Beijing? Right.
You know what I mean? Not Hong Kong where
they actually speak English, you know,
a lot. Um, can I go into mainland China?
Okay.
And fucking learn how to fly a
helicopter. He fucking unreal. You know,
the instructors are amazing.
I was like,
some of them can't even speak
English that well. I'm like, so
okay,
if they can't understand you, like how do
you communicate? And this one guy goes,
they understand tone.
It fucking killed me because I know
God damn well if I was in China and the
fucking dude's talking to
me, I can understand them
and all of a sudden he goes,
I know. It'd be like, Hey,
you got controls buddy.
Well, the terrifying thing is it's
like, I know I'm doing something wrong,
but what?
Fuck,
you'd have to immediately learn. No, stop.
Oh my God.
What the fuck does the first four express?
If I was learning how to
fly a helicopter in China,
those are the first four things that
I would learn how they say that.
And if anybody who's speaks Chinese
could tell me, spell it out phonetically,
I would love to learn it. I would
love to fucking learn it. Just,
I don't know for what it'll,
it'll come up at some point.
At some point you're going to need
to say that. Right? Um, you know,
next time you're in China or fucking
Chinese food, it's taken a while.
Okay.
He'd be like, oh my God, what the fuck?
After you just ordered an English,
you could hit them with that and Chinese,
they can't tell me not getting a
laugh there. Anyways. All right. Um,
before I get Outta here, uh, Bombas socks,
everybody chances or if you have
some fucking feed you like to wear,
nice saw half socks and face it,
it says,
chances are if you have feet,
sorry,
I want a little Johnny
Mathis there and face it.
Socks haven't changed since they
were invented. They fall down,
they wear out and they always,
and there's always that toe scene
that's never in the right place.
Our new fucking spots of Bombus
has changed. All of that.
Bob has dedicated two years to
engineering socks engineer's socks said,
stay up and last forever and
feel amazing on your feet.
I have a pair of bombers and you
know what? They feel great. You know,
I like to do,
I like to wiggle my toes in them.
Okay.
Going off
of that and a Goodfellas, ah, CIBC.
I do that when I put on my bombs
in the shower, if my feet all wet,
the prima cotton they use is so soft.
It's amazing to know
what I'm talking about.
You really need to try a pair
for yourself. Come on, man.
You put on a pair of socks, you feel like
a winner. You got a spring in your step.
You'll have a smile on your when
you get fired. I don't care.
I'm going to click my heels as I walk out
of here grabbing Mog deck. But listen,
Bob has doesn't stop with your comfort
with every pair of socks. Bomba sells.
A pair is donated to someone
in need because socks is,
it turns out and the number one
requested item at homeless shelters.
So I helped us it some over to India
after that earthquake. Speaking of which,
I'm doing a benefit tonight. Hang
on one second. Right now for all,
and for a limited time,
Bombas is offering my listeners 20% off
their first order and free shipping.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com
slash burr all lowercases do it now.
Do it now for 20% off the most
comfortable socks on the planet.
And a pair for someone in need.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bar
that's bombas.com B o m B a s.com/burr or
you know,
they could pick up somebody homeless here.
I think a lot of times we're always
thinking about people in other countries,
but you know what,
I had such a great time and a Mumbai,
India and uh,
you know,
it was awful to see what
happened over there as always.
So a Judd Apatow put together a benefit
tonight at Largo and a actually by the
time you hear this is going to
be over, but, uh, it's sold out.
We made a bunch of money.
You know, we made some money.
I can't say a bunch of money,
the amount of money that's going
to take to fix that, but uh,
I had a great time and they really treated
me right over there and met a bunch
of great comics. So, uh, it's good to
be able to do something. All right.
That is it. That's the podcast for this
week, not the podcast for this week.
I'm just checking in on you. All right
guys. Have a nice fucking weekend.
You can't, Eh, uh, here's a little
throwback from back in the day.
Back when I was like,
cool, younger, smarter,
had a little more flows on top of mind.
I don't know.
You know what?
This podcast fucking sucks.
I'm going to call it out before you guys.
This is a podcast is just
sucked this week. All right.
I'm all over the fucking place.
I'm fucking exhausted.
It's a Goddamn holiday weekend.
You can you guys, everybody,
how hard are you working
this week? You know, has it,
somebody's gone come in
and brought a pie in.
Somebody is wearing an awful brown and
orange Thanksgiving sweater. You know,
maybe it's your manager to show
that he has a human side, you know,
he's not the worst when you hate your
boss. And then around the holidays,
all of a sudden he just lets up a little
bit and tries to act nice, you know?
Or it's a female.
She gets a little bit nicer and you know,
and the whole time she's sitting there
wishing you a happy thanksgiving.
You just want to fucking
kicker right in the box.
You know,
but you can't you fucking chance.
Okay,
well that was sad.
What the fuck is it?
It's one to one 1515 minutes left
in the third period. You don't,
one of the hardest things to do I think
is to be an announcer for hockey now
that they took, I've taken out the red
line, the fucking game you breaking next,
sitting there watching the fucking game.
That's why I like it.
Watching it on TVs cause I don't have
to keep turning my head. The camera,
it's a camera
moves for me. It does all the work.
What I'm literally out of Shit to say,
you know,
I feel like
right now this how bad this podcast is
when you bomb is a comedian is that works.
When, when, when shit is going great,
when everything is saying is killing,
when you're on stage,
basically what happens is,
is you've done about 20
minutes of material and you
look down at your watch and
you watch says you've been
up there for 55 minutes.
That's when you know that you're
fucking killing. And conversely,
when you're bombing,
you will do an hour's worth of material
and 17 minutes and all you have left is
your closing bit.
And you look down at your watch and you
realize that you've been on stage for
just under 20 minutes and you're like,
wow, now what the fuck am I doing?
You know your mouth gets dry. That's
when you start going into the crowd.
Hey Z. You know, so what's there
to do around here and a Raleigh,
North Carolina. Huh? Look
at this guy over here. Huh?
What do you do sir?
Okay.
Oh, you're a plumber. Really? Oh, so a,
I bet your butt crack is always
show a fucking kill me. You know,
and you just, you just fucked. Hey,
how about a round of applause for the wait
staff? You know, keep it going for him.
You know, and I just want to
thank all you guys for showing up.
I know it's a recession and I appreciate,
uh,
you know how bad I am for the
tropes. You know, you know,
whether you support going to war or not,
you know,
these kids are out there that laying
down their lives and they're away from
their families in thanksgivings this week.
I think we should all sit back and give
thanks and be appreciative of that.
I've already done an hours worth of
fucking jokes and you conserve and left in
anything.
So now I'm technically in overtime
even though contractually I already,
I owe you like another 40
minutes of fucking comedy,
you know,
and let's not forget all the people who
have died in boating accidents this year.
You know,
a lot of people don't know that boating
accidents is one of the leading,
leading causes of death when
human beings are out in the ocean.
Okay.
Start remembering jokes from the early
party or act and you start telling him,
you know,
yeah,
they did a study
the other day. They said, you know,
90% of shark attacks actually
happened in shallow water.
No Shit. That's where the people are.
It's called the fucking beach. Oh,
one of their people swimming to Europe.
Let's go to France. You pussies. Ah,
you like that joke.
That's a joke for my act in 2001
I'm do fucking old jokes in my act.
What else did I used to fucking do?
Okay,
I already did one of my original jokes.
You guys see these uh, rap group.
Criss Cross. What would up Chris? Warm
it up, Chris. Hey, go to bed. Chris.
What do you like nine years old.
Oh.
Oh my God.
I had horrible jokes.
He's do jokes about working in a dental
office. A people. I got news for you.
Six years. Neglect is not cured by
a tic tac in the waiting room. Hey.
Ah, you guys ready for
your next deck? Too Bad.
I still got another 30 minutes to do.
Yeah,
ladies back me up.
Guys are crazy rise.
I mean, you know, where are we?
We don't give a shit that's going to
be searching for shit to say what,
but I'm here. It's great to be here
in Raleigh. You know what I mean?
Okay.
It's scary. You know, you come out
here to Raleigh, you know they got a,
he got a mall. All right folks, I'm
not gonna lie to you. I'm out of jokes.
I wish you could just do that and
just fucking become honest. I'm a,
I'm not a fucking material.
I don't know what the fuck you guys want.
I've actually been talking about this
shit on stage. I don't give a fuck luck
because it's such a topical bit.
I don't even know if people are gonna
think it's funny in a month. But, uh,
can we please talk about fucking
Bill O'reilly going on the view?
Um, I gotta I gotta tell
you something right now.
I don't like that guy's politics.
I don't like his face.
He has, he has that
racist face. You know his,
when he gets mad, his
fucking, his face gets pointy.
He just looks evil.
He's just not a pleasant
human being whatsoever.
But I gotta tell you,
he fucking destroyed on the view,
you know,
and I,
somewhere in there was a victory for men
because he took on for fucking women.
They were all yelling
and he got two of them to walk
off their own fucking show.
How do you do that?
I as a comedian,
I was embarrassed to, to stand
up. Comic comics just quit,
which is why I'm nominating Joy Bay Har
and Whoopi Goldberg is Douche bags of
the week. What, what did you think was
going to, do you think he was going to go?
No, wait, don't leave.
That's exactly what the
fuck he wanted you to do.
I was actually hoping at that point that
the other two women were going to leave
and then he could just start hosting
the O'Reilly factor on the view.
That would have been,
he just totally 100%
dominated at the very least,
that segment, because I don't,
I don't watch that fucking show,
but just, he just came on. First of all,
he sits down and he's got
on that shiny fucking, uh,
Joe Pesci shoot Joe Pesci Peshy suit.
It's difficult to say Joe Peshy suit and
he's got his fucking leg spread like a
with his ball bag, hang his shiny ball
bag. He locally, if you ever see like, uh,
when Kennedy debated Nixon, how,
if you listen to it on the radio,
how everybody said Nixon won.
But if you watched it on TV,
Nixon was all tanned up.
He had his legs crossed,
he looked like a winter and Nixon sat
there with his fucking legs splayed and
cross like underneath the chair.
He looked like a fucking moron.
That's what bill O'Reilly looked like.
And he, he just, he still dominated.
I love when he turned to joy and was
just whatever I, I'm paraphrasing here,
but he was just like,
be quiet and learned
that she had nothing,
a fucking standup comic.
She had nothing.
The whole segment was fucking
hilarious. And when he goes, uh,
another gem of a moment was when he goes,
you know,
a lot of people don't realize this,
but 70% of Americans don't
want a mosque at ground zero.
And joy goes. She goes,
well, I'd like to see that,
that poll or something like,
and as she sang that the crowd is
applauding what bill O'Reilly just said.
So you really don't need to see
the pole at that point. And,
and getting beyond that,
what he really should have said was 70%
of Americans don't realize that they're
not building a mosque
at ground zero still,
that they're actually making a rec room
with a ping pong table and an area to
pray kind of like they have an area to
pray it every fucking airport, you know,
three,
four blocks up the street at a God damn
coat factory is where it's actually
being built.
But the fact that he said that they're
still building a mosque and that he got
an applause break,
joy is so wrapped up into her own fucking
opinion that she doesn't even hear her
own studio audience backup the
guy that she's trying to shit on.
And the fact that this fucking guy is
still putting out inaccurate information,
that people are still back in Abbott.
It just was fucking awesome
on all of those levels.
And a, I liked how Barbara
Walters was old school. Cool.
And she didn't walk off.
She gave those two Douche bags of the
week shit for walking off their own show.
And then she got him with a nice
little classy Zinger. He said,
Bill O'reilly's on here this week. Uh,
when we come back we're going to talk, um,
or he's on the show today. We're
going to, when we come back,
he's going to talk about his new
book called pinheads and Patriots.
And then she looked at bill and
she goes, at this point I, uh,
I'm not sure what you are or something
like that. It was a great little zinger,
but she wasn't like judging
the guy. I Dunno. The,
the whole thing was funny and
just how bill O'Reilly is, is,
is viewed as this intolerant person.
And then he comes on the show of a,
I guess mostly liberals and then they
show absolutely no tolerance for him and
then throw a fucking temper tantrum and
walk off their own God damn show. I mean,
you can't tell me.
Everybody over at at Fox News wasn't
literally jerking off to that moment.
I, Bill O'reilly Bomas became a fucking
rock star in that moment. That was,
that was like a standup comic
moment that he did to two comedians,
which blew my mind.
Okay.
You know, and I know I'm always
trashing the brides on this show,
but that really was a chick way of
handling, losing an argument. Like,
I'm just going to get off up in store,
Ma.
He is so used to people paying for your
drinks and holding the Goddamn door for
you.
You actually thought that as an adult
that you were just going to walk off the
shell and this was going to be this big
moment and he was going to be like, oh,
wait a minute,
let me stop.
Okay.
I loved it. He was like, go ahead and
leave. I don't give a fuck. I'll continue.
I'll take over your fucking show.
Um, so anyways, there you go.
Douche bags of the week.
Joe Bay Harbor and Whoopi Goldberg for
walking off your own fucking show when
his shiny suit fucking I,
I can't say he's a moron
because he, he does. No,
I mean, I look, he, he, he's very red up
on that. Yeah. I don't know. I am
too stupid. This is why I would,
this is right here.
Why I would never engage as much
as I disagree with his opinions.
I don't fucking pay attention
to politics at all. I don't,
I find it frustrating.
I find it to be it just a rig fucking gay.
I don't give a fuck, you know,
and I, so I would never try to,
as much as I disagree with Bill O'reilly,
I would never go on his show and try
to fucking one up the guy and think I'm
going to, uh, beat the guy in an
argument about politics. It's like he,
he's paying attention to these politicians
the way I give a fuck about football.
I'm not gonna, I'm not going
to win that argument. I mean,
why don't I bring fucking Roy Jones Jr
and start debating him in about boxing.
Okay.
I know. It's just, it was, uh,
it was fucking hilarious at
the whole thing was just,
it was hilarious and a big,
big fucking victory for that fucking,
I dunno.
I Dunno. As a stand up comic, you fucking,
you just tap out. That
was embarrassing. Anyway,
so let's get on with the God
damn podcast for this week. Um,
I kind of liked that you
guys liked that format.
Just getting the Douche bag
of the week out of the way
right off the fucking bat.
[inaudible]
yeah.