Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. Yeah.
Oh,
just checking in on you. I'm checking
in to see. Oh, how's your week going?
You're almost there.
Okay.
Fucking Thursday, man. You're on the east
coast. It's almost lunchtime. All right.
By the time this comes out, it'd be
lunchtime. What are you going to get?
You're going to go out and get something
heavy or are you going to start the
weekend? Right? Go out
and get something healthy.
Bring the stomach down a little bit. You
feel a little more comfortable, right?
A little more confident and you go out to
the clubs that he buttoned down, shirt.
You Belize, not pressing
against it, right? While you're,
yeah, I used to do a bit.
My aqua,
your buttons are doing like the iron
cross hanging on to both sides of your
shirt. Like, Hey, yeah,
you don't need that.
Okay.
Make life a little easy. Why is this
fucking thing only on one goddamn channel?
Oh, I'll figure it out. That's
it. You're not sitting up.
The elevator only goes
to the fourth floor.
It's where I am right now with my anger.
No more going to the penthouse. Okay.
I've downsized my anger life.
I've moved down to a floor that I feel
is just a little more affordable and
everybody can relax the round me,
you know what it is,
is I don't have any time.
I think that that's something I feel like
that triggers me. Bailey, no. Tam Bailey,
no time Nicole and Billy.
No time because you've got no time.
Yeah.
You know, my wife knows I don't
have any time. Don't shut a, yeah.
You know I don't have any time,
but what does she do
the fuck was it? Was it yelling?
Just set off one of my kids' toys.
I like that. It's like a sound
effects. What did I just, Yo,
I'll see if I can make that.
But you're now
okay.
She's got this one frigging toy.
It's fuck, it's fucking crazy.
I like it.
Cause there's all these different musical
instruments and it teaches the kids
about it,
but I swear to God the guy's energy.
It's like Willie aims and
Charles in charge. You know,
he's like Charles the same thing.
It's like pop and rock up and rock
up and Brooke dig for instruments.
It's a Trump. It's like, buddy, relax.
I don't want to hear you
played an instrument when
you're all fucking wound up
like that. Now that constipated fucking
sound coming out of your instrument,
miles Davis turning around,
giving you that look on the bandstand.
Yeah,
relax a little bit.
Okay.
Pop and Rock Bob and rock his scooter.
Liberal booboo. Is that a trumpet?
Right? You want to live in there?
I'm not a musical guy.
The fuck you goddamn comedian.
Speaking of which I want to thank
Madison Square Garden for a,
an Rory Rose Garden for having
me on the garden dreams.
And um, this is really great. Um,
charity where they basically,
you know, underprivileged kids,
kids who were sick and all that,
they got a dream and they come out and
they make it. They make it come true.
It was really nice. He was funny. As
I was doing the, uh, the press there,
I was doing the press and I'm, Jeffrey
Gurian was in, I always fuck with him.
I always have a great time with him.
But, uh, one of the ladies in lines like,
do you know what this, you know what
this charity is about? You don't,
and I just seen some kid,
you know,
in a wheelchair kid on a walker or
whatever, and it's just like, Oh God,
do you know what this charity is? Forest?
I just was like, no, no, I don't. No,
I don't.
So I'm going to come off like an asshole.
But the reason why I said that was
because I really didn't feel like talking
about it. You know, once you have
like a kid, it's just, it affects you.
Like you could have something to apply it
to where before it was like, oh my God,
it felt bad for that. And I'm just
like, I felt the whole fucking thing.
The parents, the whole thing.
Tell us about the charity.
Can you cut through the emotion
of it? Ah, no, no. I won't be,
I don't know what it is.
It's Madison Square Garden.
They asked me to come on here.
So why don't we say go on.
And I do the show fucking
monster lineup of a,
of comics. Everybody fucking
killed. Fortunately, um,
I went on during the middle.
Seinfeld had to close it out.
John Stewart went on a second
to last and, uh, Michael Change,
Jesus Christ, he came in fucking
murdered, came into from SNL,
still at his jacket on, just
walked on stage. Fucking murders,
leaves a fucking joke assassin.
Uh, who else was on it? Um,
John Malaney.
Yeah.
Fucking murdering lies a
Schlesinger murdered Brian Regan.
Brian was how big the
show Brian Regan opened.
That's how fucking amazing the
show us. Um, so I was happy.
[inaudible] I forgot somebody. I know.
I did. I know there was more than that.
Who else was on it? Come on, Bill.
Think I don't fucking know.
Okay.
Steve Surepost hosted the thing,
uh,
one of the crew guys at Madison Square
Garden. His name was, um, you know,
it was cool. And we were going through
the bowels of the place going over to the,
uh, the theater at Madison Square
Garden where Eddie Murphy recorded Ra.
I always think about that
when I was there. And, uh,
when I'm there and we were going through,
we had to go up the elevator and they
had all the Ottawa senators like hockey
bags. They were loading them in cause
the rangers were playing, playing.
Then the next night and lo and behold,
the next night I'm back in La Cause I got
up at 4:00 AM to get back to my lovely
wife and kid as you do as a dad.
It's
not about you anymore.
You've worked out the depth chart.
What do you think you're going to get
some sleep? Their dad don't think so.
Ain't no time.
No time.
MMM.
I got on the fucking plane,
flew back here and then I
ended up watching like a
period and a half of the game
and lo and behold, they cut to the, uh,
they cut to some highlights from the
garden. Got In. It didn't show the show.
Thank Christ. Um, that was a little
rusty. I'm not going to lie to you.
I hadn't done much standup up by, I
have to, I did the, uh, did my special,
I was like, I'm going to take some
time for me. You know what I mean?
Put my feet up and just thought of
just what it was, that fucking word,
those kinds of people use that regroup.
Okay.
Just allow myself to
just realign my synopsis.
Okay.
No, I just didn't feel like going out or
anything and I was, I was fucking, yeah.
Wiped out.
And uh,
I felt like a fighter that didn't spar,
you know,
just be like, man, I'm the
champ. I got the belt right.
I just knocked out, you know,
my last set was my, uh, my standup
special. Fucking knock that out.
I'm going to fucking champ over
here and I got the old right there,
Fred the second I walked out there. So I
meandered a little bit in the beginning.
Then I got to go and, and uh, oh my
God, this fucking hilarious moment.
My set where,
you know,
I was making fun of Michelle
Obama because how do you not,
yeah.
You know what I mean? The level that
she's been gassed up to. Oh yeah.
She's the president's wife.
All right. Let everybody relax.
Okay.
Um, that was basically my
angle. So, you know, you know,
you know, fucking, you know,
all the women are going to
fucking lose their minds,
especially white women who also don't
have jobs. You know, they get, you know,
who are, you know, it was a lot of rich
people there. Right. So I was a, you know,
I was pushing their buttons. Yeah.
I mean, in fairness, the audience,
I was being a cunt
and I was saying,
you know how being a first lady,
it's not a job that extending standing
what all the excitements about,
it's not a job. Right. And the
hey those guys. Yes, it is. It is.
So I keep setting off that toy.
Um,
so I say, I just thought, you know,
I can't see into the crowd. Right.
So I just look into the
blackness of like the 10th row,
this voice that I just said. I'm like,
do you think it's the Jami? It's, yeah.
I'm like, all right, ma'am,
I'm going to do me a favor.
You tell me how the fuck that's a job.
And the woman goes,
first of all, it third turned
out it was a dude. Right.
So then immediately you feel like
this fucking post me to tension.
He a gender neutral bathroom,
all his fucking energy.
And I just went like, well,
you know, guy tell you you got a high
pitched voice. You sound like a woman.
I, you know something. I was
really not enjoying this time.
And now I've realized that this is
one of the greatest times ever to be a
fucking comedian.
The amount of fun that you have,
and there was not,
you know,
you sound like a woman and you know
what the nowadays is just say, well,
what is a woman's sound like?
You know what a woman's sounds like?
You know what a guy sounds like,
you know the base fucking thing.
I hate when people do that.
They'll remember during the Oj trial when
that guy said it sounded like a black
guy. He never, he's like, what does
a black guy said? You know what?
The fucking black, what is an Irish
guy sound like? What does a German guy,
what does a French guy sound like?
There's accents.
Not saying everybody sounds like that.
You know what I mean?
But if you met a black guy going like,
oh,
how are you a top of the morning
[inaudible] you'd be like,
this guy is fucking with me.
But because it's trial and somebody
you have to take into consideration
that this might be the anomaly.
Now I understand that. But to say
that somebody saying, you know,
that sounded like an Asian dude,
that there's something like fucking,
I dunno clannish about that.
I guess there could be,
speaking of that where it tell you one
time I was in San Francisco, right?
Visiting the bath houses. Um, and uh,
I got into a cab.
Okay.
And this Asian dude was driving.
And he had the, he sounded
like he was on fucking, he hot.
Okay.
So there is always that exception. I
swear to God, straight up Asian Dude.
And he was just going like,
man, I'm obtain. There's
traffic out hairs. Ridiculous.
And I'm looking at the dude, man, it's
this guy fucking with me. Hi, I'm alone.
Y'All gone be out here in San Francisco.
Okay. And I was just like, dude,
I got to ask where the fuck are you
from? And he laughed. He's like, man,
I grew up in Tennessee.
I know it's fucked up to hear me
talking like this bowl where I grew up,
everybody dead.
Then he started telling me how he did
all this extra work and how he was an
extra and cleaning clean Eastwood's uh,
one of those dirty Harry movies.
And I got his phone number and now bags
when I was back on Opie and Anthony,
I was like, oh my God, we got to
get this guy on the show. MMM.
So there is an exception,
but I mean it's all but this also,
that's not a reason to,
uh,
okay.
What are the kids call it
now you've been canceled,
um,
you sound Latino.
Just exactly.
What does that mean?
Did I tell you that time I was going
to Charlie Murphy's funeral and I, I,
I had packed hastily.
You know what I mean?
Cause you never know when
someone's going to pass away.
All of a sudden it's like,
shit, we gotta go. So I, I,
and I forgot to pack my underwears there.
So where I was staying in New York was,
uh,
head become the gay part
of town, right. And, uh,
because it didn't use to be gay,
used to be fucking shady,
and then all the gay moved in,
and then, you know, what happens?
All of a sudden this nice restaurants,
there's a nightlife,
there's fucking mood lighting.
It's, it's, it's awesome, right?
So right across the street from where
I was staying was this clothing store,
and I'm not going to lie to you,
you know, in the fucking windows.
They definitely had like the,
the mannequin with the leather underwear
in the hat. But I mean, I had to go,
but I saw they had other
fucking tee shirts in there.
So I went in there trying
to find some onto west.
I figured that was just like an aisle,
right? The dog collar, gimp aisle. Right.
So I go into this fucking place.
Yeah.
And I'm trying to find underwear and
all that. God is like the fucking under,
like I finally find an underwear
cut that I can wear to a funeral.
All right? Rather than wearing the,
uh, Greg Louganis goes to Brazil,
fucking cut, right. So, okay,
I finally find the cut and then on,
on, I know I've told this story before,
but there's always new listeners,
right on the waistband it said nasty pig,
you know, in, in the funeral,
you know, the, the, the,
the service is like
fucking 90 minutes away.
It's out in Jersey and in
time is becoming an issue.
So I walk up to the counter and there's
this dude standing there talking to the
person behind the register and I kind
of interrupted. I was, excuse me,
I don't mean to interrupt. I
go, do you have any like, uh,
like mainstream underwear?
That's what I said.
Do you have any mainstream underwear?
And the guy got offended.
He's like, define mainstream.
I just stayed in the
pocket. I was like, Oh, I dunno it, it
doesn't say nasty pig on, on, on the waist
band.
And then he had nothing.
He was trying to do that, like, you know,
trying to make me out to
be like homophobic. Okay.
Fucking come over to my wife off the road
with underwear that says nasty pig on
it, honey. I swear to God,
I was going to a funeral and I,
I need some underwear.
There was a glitch. They had his
blow. Right. Oh, set. I'm Gus Grissom,
a fucking underwear.
Anyways,
um,
so that ended up being a lot of fun.
And I finished my set and I said,
thank you God bless everybody. Including
you sir, with your high pitched voice.
I guess I was a bit of a cut, but
um, so last night, right. And I,
and I really did not
like that feeling of um,
okay.
Being like rusty or whatever. So
I mean already look rusty. Hey,
I remember Rusty Jones.
Hello. Goodbye. Hello Russ.
Did Jones good by rusty cars know,
just be able to make a living doing that.
Writing jingles. Eight second songs.
I'm a pamper. He's a pair of
shoes. A pep where a pair,
but wouldn't you like to be a
pepper to be a pepper Drake?
Dr Pepper Bam House in the
Hollywood hills whores by the pool.
Cocaine on the piano
stays are all gone. I said,
the second you make it,
somebody takes it on the Internet
and then they do a mashup. Right.
With the fucking, I
dunno, the Coca Cola song,
I don't know how to fucking works anymore.
Okay.
That was a job when I was growing up.
You'd have a,
you'd have a party and that there
would be somebody at your house.
One guy was a milkman and another
person wrote jingles for commercials.
I then there was always somebody in
actuaries to sizing everybody up,
trying to figure out when
you're going to die. Oh,
he's already a 22 pounds overweight
for as far as my visual estimate goes,
and that is a second
helping of cream of spinach.
I can't be good for the arteries.
I'm going to want to say that guy's
going to tip out around 57 it was a
dangerous age when I was growing up.
57 you know,
that's when you were in the red
zone of having a heart attack.
57 fucking 63 61 a lot
of guys dropped at 61
mmm.
Which didn't seem like a big
deal when I was like five, six
you know,
fucking guy was born in like the 19
early 19 hundreds he had a great run.
Right? Okay. I was alive when
Babe Ruth, this was in shape.
But when you all of a sudden you have 50
staring down the barrel of 51 in June.
Oh my God. Oh my God. I was a, I want,
so I go to the airport, right? Like pick
up 10 to five is what it actually was.
Right. And I get to the airport like
five 30 crews right out to fucking JFK.
All right. I got my, I got my ticket on my
cell phone. All right. I'm a modern man.
I'm not checking any bags.
I'm a little fucking Mr Technology.
So I'm precheck Tsa, right? I
fucking go through that shit.
And I got my ticket and I just fucking,
I go,
I just put my phone down
to the thing and I, and I,
I set it down on the thing and
I, on my cell phone case, I got,
I got this cluster of pictures of
me and my lovely daughter, right?
So I set it down and you know,
there's a woman there, so you know,
they can't resist the kid.
She sees it. She just goes,
oh,
I go, yeah, isn't she a
beauty? And she goes, yeah,
she goes to set your granddaughter.
Ah,
Oh, did that hurt? And I laughed.
I said, no, it's my daughter.
I go, I got a late start. Oh.
And then I just limped
through fucking security.
I had such a fucking spring in my step.
I'm Mike,
I haven't boozed kind of 130 days.
Right.
My skin's clearing up. Oh, I'm
drinking fucking smoothies.
I'm looking younger than den. My years in
sheesh. Oh my. She just said, she sent me,
she fucking s fucking strapped me in
right on top of the rocket.
Just shot me right back to the reality
of my fucking age, man. Oh man,
that that killed me.
Okay,
fucking kill me.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
I thought I'd tell this story and
then have a joke at the end of it,
but all I have is just the raw emotion
of that, that really fucking hurt.
You know, see, see, you go
ladies there, there's a pressure.
There's this stigma when you're a bald,
redheaded male. Granted, but the
reality is is I am, I am old. I am.
If I had a kid at 25,
my kid would be coming up on 26 and if
my kid had a kid about the same time I
did, then fuck it. I would, I would be
old enough to be a grandfather. See,
so I'm not going to get mad at her.
I'm not going to write
tsa.com and be like,
I was so triggered when somebody
stated a fact about my age.
You know what? I'm going to take it.
I'm going to do good luck with book. Um,
what did I want to talk about here?
Oh, I got so much. Not so much shit.
I got a couple emails to these fucking
F1 snobs because I was talking about how
ruining for Ferrari's, like rooting
for the, uh, the Kansas city chiefs,
and it was painting them as an underdog.
Now, even though I clearly stated that,
I just started watching like
fucking three, four years ago,
Ferrari has not been doing well.
Okay.
All right. Second place, eh? Yeah.
That's your, you're the first loser.
So what I said was accurate
and it shouldn't hear it.
Talking down to this father who looks
like a grandfather talking down to me,
this person who has
difficulty reading out loud,
talking down to me the
hero of this podcast,
the greatest person on this
podcast right now is me.
Okay.
And it's not because I'm,
I'm the only voice.
It's because I'm the only one who votes.
Um,
yeah, giving me shit. Like I
didn't understand that Ferrari is,
I know what a Ferrari is. You fucking
morons. Everybody knows what a furry is.
I know their history. I actually
read a, I read this book called, uh,
the limit about the first
F1 American f one champion.
One of the great fucking books I ever
read. I wish I didn't give it away.
I always give away the books.
Um,
absolutely fucking love that book
and I understand. I understand. Okay.
I know where it's at. All right. I'm just
saying the last couple of years, I mean,
ever since I've been watching
this sports since like 2015, 2016,
whenever the fuck I started,
it's just been Mercedes.
Okay.
All right. I'm getting
sick of it. Or you know,
the same way you guys
are sick of the Patriots.
I would like to see Ferrari make a
run. Although since then I did see, uh,
that new guy, John, what's his face
there? The, the, the uh, the new drivers,
not Kimmy raking it in the new, the new
guy, a driving for Ferrari. He's like, ah,
man, you know. Well,
I guess we got lucky that the safety
car came out and he was really positive
about it and that made me,
that gave me some hope.
It gave me some hope.
By the way,
we're going to have a fucking benefit
for fucking Daniel Ricardo yet, you know,
they're always doing standup benefits.
I want to do a standup benefit to get
that guy a fucking team that can give them
a car that's going to be able to finish
the fucking race, that poor bastard.
I swear to God,
if they take the smile away from that man,
you know, that's really going
to be a difficult fucking
thing to watch somebody so young,
so full of life,
you know, twinkle in his eye. How many
fucking times can you just be driving,
crushing it and all of a sudden
your car just shuts off, you know?
Or for some reason somebody puts
a mogul in the God damn grass.
You try not to get side swiped when you
go over just to Cantera under the grass
in the front of your car,
fucking explodes. I don't get it.
The guy's fucking snake.
Bitch, snake, bitch. Snake bit.
Sorry. Oh, so I finally, I saw the, uh,
did I tell you guys, I saw the, uh,
I saw the moto GP from Argentina.
Um,
I got a lot of questions.
All right.
Is I take a sip of a green smoothie.
Okay.
A green smoothie, guys want a good
recipe for a smoothie. Green smoothie.
Here it is,
a cup of Ice Cup of almond milk.
Sorry. Starting over
again. Quarter Cup of ice,
Cup of almond milk,
a banana,
a cup of spinach,
a cup of all that.
I mean on a cup of a, uh, a
tablespoon of all natural honey.
Two tablespoon of a instant oatmeal
and one tablespoon of almond butter.
Just try to get all natural everything.
And this is how I do it.
I put the ice,
the almond milk and the spinach in first
and then maybe like some of the honey
because what happens is,
you know, the way you do it,
like sometimes it can turn into
like a shake if this too much ice,
but there's not enough ice in here.
Then I blend that. Then I put the paint,
I put the banana in there
first and then I put in the uh,
the peanut butter, knocked the oats
and then the peanut butter or whatever.
And that way it stays on top of the
banana and it doesn't sink all the way
fucking down cause it's, it's really
the peanut butter and the honey.
It's going to stick down to the bottom
and it won't be part of the fucking mix.
So however I just said that,
don't put the honey in where I said that
flipped the oats and the honey and mix
it up that way and you should be.
And I do like to two separate Mexicans.
Yeah,
there you go. Drink that
fucker. Drink your breakfast.
Be a champion. Be like a dad.
Looks like a grandfather.
Oh God. That fucking killed me. You know,
I swear to God just for men actually
gave a shit about men with red beard's.
I would have gone out and bought some,
like if they was selling it on the
plane and I would've been quite quietly
crying to myself as I
combed in into my chin.
All right,
here's my question about the moto GP.
I don't get what the fuck is with mark.
Mark has his fucking motorcycle where
it's just, they even called it, you know,
he might just take off and
this could be a boring race.
And then the guy quickly correct himself,
not saying that it's going to be boring.
The guy just fucking,
he got a good start and
he got out front end.
He had like a fucking 15 second lead
by the middle of the race or something.
Some crazy.
I don't understand why his
bike is so much faster.
I thought that the Ducati's and the do
caddies were all unlike the same level,
but he just pulled away like,
you know,
he had the IROC Z and everybody else
had the rally sport or the Berlinetta,
you know, the Firebird versus
the Trans am I've, I've,
it's the exact opposite of [inaudible].
So then the whole fucking race,
the exciting part of the race was
watching a du Fitsi also. And, um,
uh, Valentino Rossi battling
for second place and he would,
Mark Marquez was so far out into the front
that they just had them in a little square
on the upper right hand side of the,
of,
of the uh,
my computer screen here while we just
watched everybody else battle and I don't
understand what happened
to or Halo Renzo did.
He pushed the wrong button cause
he's also drive riding a Honda.
Okay.
And then they were all bitching about the
visio zone is little aerodynamic thing
that cooled off his back tire. They
thought that was a ridiculous advantage.
Okay.
And then the very next race,
all of a sudden this guy,
you know mark mark has just
takes off and it's, it fits.
He also still has that thing.
Cool. And his back tire,
I guess what they should have done because
they were so busy fucking with each
other trying to pass each other racing.
What they should have done is just
accepted that the visio so wasn't second.
They all got in behind each other
like the Peloton and is that I said in
bike racing and eventually they would cut
through the wind and catch up with the
guy and then once they caught up with
them, then it can be like, all
right, let's start racing again.
Is that legal to do that,
to actually become a team,
to catch the fucking guy who was already
eight seconds in front of you? I Dunno.
And then lastly, uh, cow
crutch. Lowe says name.
He got fucked on that race.
He got fucked. All right.
He had an incredible fucking
start and to the naked eye,
he didn't start too soon. And the fact
that there's a God damn computer now,
like people's brains are not as good as
a fucking computer. Can't see that thing.
So he doesn't know he's cheating. He just
started, he got a good fucking start.
Hey. Oh Man, they fuck that guy over.
They fucked him over. All right,
so there you go. There's, there's
my little motorcycle talking.
I'm going to read some advertising.
And then I'm going to wrap this fucking
podcast up and I'm going to get on with
my, my busy day here. All
right. Oh, here we go.
[inaudible] don't dupe me undies. Mandy's
Bailey is old in gray, dude. Dude, dude,
dude, me undies, me undies.
That's what the lady say.
You have a beautiful
fucking grand daughter.
That's not my granddaughter.
I nothing rhymes with daughter.
I'm too fucking old to
make it sound fucking work.
Somebody get me a Gera Gella tool
and some soft fucking underwears.
Okay.
Buzzfeed said this about me undies.
They feel like actual
heaven against your skin.
We're going to assume heaven
is really soft in this context.
Well don't you pay bud buzzfeed or do
they just review shit? I don't ask men.
Well isn't that a nice magazine?
I'd like to be asked things
feel like I'm being heard.
Askmen said they feel like
silk drenched in hand.
Lotion grubs.
Okay.
Silt trenching. Hand like I know
hand lotion makes your hands soft.
And I know silk is soft,
so if you combine both of those,
but you also jerk off with lotion and if
you to, if you put that on the fabric,
now the fabric is wet and it's going to
be sticking to your balls. All right?
This is why you don't ask men.
Thanks.
These Andries are so soft, they make Bob
Ross's voice. Sound like Gilbert Godfrey.
They are so soft that Kenny g thinks
about them to get inspired to write his
next song.
Kenny g taking a hit there.
What did Kenny Dope me undies uses?
The coveted micro modal modal fabric
that is a full three times softer than
cotton. Take that big cotton.
Your big puffy. Oh yeah.
And cotton's also white to you.
Fabric.
Toxicity fabric. Patriotical
cunt. Speaking of Prince,
why not match your bottom half with your
better half and get a matching prince
for you and your partner?
Uh, me undies is also,
do they have like underwear for
alternative a couples lifestyles
says nasty pig on one and says a
nasty pig too on the other one. Uh,
[inaudible] is also the Goto for the
softest loungewear on this side of the
Mississippi hang out and they're super
comfy lounge pants and one's ease.
Yes, me, Andy's makes onesies
and they're incredible beyond.
He's has a great offer for my listeners.
For any first time purchasers,
when you order me undies, you get 15% off
and free shipping. This is a no brainer.
Get 15% off the most comfortable
underwears you will ever
put on to get your 15%
off your first pair. Free Shipping
and 100% satisfaction guaranteed.
Goto me undies.com/burr.
That's me.
undies.com/ [inaudible]
m U. N. D. I. E. S.
It's like the me too thing,
except it says undies.
Yeah.
Hashtag me undies. All right. Butcher
box everybody. Ah, here we go.
Butcher box delivers
healthy 100% grass fed,
grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and heritage breed pork.
Did you guys see a Naipaul
gutsy special yet? Uh,
the Tennessee kid. Fuck
guys. Absolutely brilliant.
He has a great bit on free range
chickens versus the ones that they, uh,
that were not free to range. Uh, it's
on Netflix streaming. Now look at that.
It's an ad within an ad. The incredible
quality of butcher box meets.
Start with the commitment to raising
animals humanely and free of antibiotics
and hormones. Cook with the peace of
mind knowing you are eating healthy,
high quality meat. Each box comes with
at least eight to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individual size meals. If you're
a city slicker, but a few,
some big fast boat province,
you can choose some five different boxes.
All beef ladies,
beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed box for you.
Progressive People.
Custom box lets you choose your own cuts.
That's for the conservative.
You know,
that's for the people who want to keep
their meat separate once via will only
take ds.
They are the ideas that he meets.
My favorite cut of meat is the
heritage breeds pork. Oh Man.
And I can have a fucking recipe. I
was at the airport there. Oh, grant,
grandfather burner here and
Grandpa [inaudible] and I was uh,
it was,
it was basically showing how you can
make all these meals and just one pot.
You know what I mean?
You know those great fucking things that
comfort food that's going to make you
fucking blow up.
I got a good one for pork chops.
Then I'm going to try this
weekend. Oh, I can't wait.
I really am like a grandfather.
I'm excited about cooking
pork chops. All right.
This month, butcher box is offering the
unlimited breakfast breakfast bundle.
What is this?
This includes two packages,
a bacon and two pounds of
breakfast sausages all for free,
and your first box. Our Bacon is
the best bacon you've ever had.
It's whole 30 approved.
I don't even know what that means.
What the 30 people running the bacon
world unsecured nitrate and sugar free.
This sausage is a healthy,
authentic version of a
classic style pork sausage.
My mouth is watering,
like literally reading this simply
seasoned with salt and pepper and sage.
Oh my God. What a way to
start the day. I need that.
I would start crying looking across
the table and life would be at work.
Matter of honey. It's just so
good right now. New members,
we'll get two packages of bacon
and two pounds of breakfast.
Sausage added to your first box for free.
Plus you'll get $20 off your first box.
Go.
Now while supplies last as
this is a limited time offer,
these people know how to do it.
All right?
You want Americans to buy your beef.
You Dangle Free Bacon and sausage
in their fucking face and you set a
Jesus Christ the amount of fucking,
you know what's so?
You know the amount of fucking people
in overalls right now that are like half
hard listening to this overalls.
I like the onesies for rednecks.
You know, that's when they know that they
grew up. I ain't got no sleeves on my,
hey buddy,
you don't know who you fucking with.
Ain't got no sleeves or
or or or fade on my one Z.
I walk out sad, my one
z. That's how I'd do it.
Um, all right, that's the podcast.
Everybody please enjoy the, the,
the musical interlude.
And then there's going to be a hit
another half hour bonus here of a Thursday
afternoon just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. A greatest hit.
I'm an episode from earlier. Oh,
I need to mention last night.
So I went out and I did two sets.
That's right.
Cause I didn't like feeling rusty and I,
uh,
I got this whole new chunk and it
came last night and had a great set.
And then Brian Callen probably said some
of the nicest shit anybody said to me
as a comedian. I think he's
absolutely fucking brilliant. So, uh,
I'm actually going to call him today
and thank him for the compliment.
It put me on a stand up high,
you know,
which being the age that I
am, you know, I, you know,
I got called the grandfather
and I and I haven't, yeah,
Aka our P card and I've still
never fucking used it. Okay.
And if you're young and you don't know
what it is, that's, that's awesome.
Enjoy the party your life where
you don't know what an AAR,
not qualified yet for one of those fucking
things. All right. That's the podcast.
Enjoy the music.
Have a great weekend.
Your comments and I
will see you on Monday,
Huh? Huh. Huh. Huh,
Huh, Huh, Huh, Huh. Huh.
Huh?
All
right.
Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burns
the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
April 4th,
2011 or 2011 as I saw it so
succinctly put this weekend by a,
the great comedian Patton Oswald.
That's how he said it. He was on stage.
I was doing a show with him, the Kevin
and been April foolish in a show. And uh,
I noticed at some point at the
Gibson MP theater, by the way,
formerly known as the Universal
Lampi Theater for blues brother fans.
You might recognize that
name, right? Remember that?
Good Evening Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the universal theater.
Here it is something, something going
on. 1985. So much in music here.
Today's preprogrammed electronic disco.
That's where the fuck they did that.
They were opening for Steve Martin at
the height of Steve Martin's career when
he had the white suit with a
bow and Arrow going through it.
So that's the second year in a row.
I've got to do that wonderful program,
show performance, whatever
the fuck you call it. And, uh,
it was an awesome night of comedy,
but there was something learned and all
the filth and funders that I saw that
night was pat and said 2011.
So that's how I'm saying it
for the rest of the year,
cause I can't say 2011 I
have to slow down. 2011,
2011 see it runs together.
2011,
all of a sudden everybody in the room
relaxes. Hey, we're with the friend.
We thought that that red headed guy
was, was, you know, who's left handed.
Some of the times was just
spawn of the devil. You know,
that's what they used to think about
redheads and people who wrote with their
left hand.
So basically I would,
if it was still the 18 hundreds that would
be getting the shit slapped out of me
and one of those fucking schools,
you know,
that they used to have on
little house in the prairie.
We had grades two through eight.
We're all sitting in the same room.
Um, tell me there was an inappropriate
behavior going on there. You know,
you're a senior in high school, right? All
of a sudden the freshmen girls come in,
there's always one pervert.
Your grade would descend on to someone
who was basically a fucking child at that
point.
You can't tell me back in the day in the
18 hundreds when people got married at
14 so they could pull together,
there's showing so they could go buy
a fucking plot of land in some oxygen.
Ah, you're telling me some eighth grade,
it wasn't rolling up on a fourth grader.
You know,
like some Catholic fucking Prius.
I'm going to start that
God damn debate again. Um,
speaking of which, hey, you know what,
for some reason the theme to Laverne
and Shirley is in my head today.
We're going to do it. I would think
of that's been in my head before,
every once in a while TV that I watched
way too much back in the day, uh,
pops into my head. But anyways,
getting back to the, uh,
the Catholic Church thinks somebody
sent me a little bible thing,
said the dinosaurs are called behemoths
in the Bible and about outer space.
Alien ships,
a space ships abductions.
His talks talked about in a Ezekiel one,
and these are from in
the King James Bible.
Now, after all these years
of trash in the Bible,
I'd have I ever mentioned to you guys that
I haven't even read the fucking thing.
Oh, I've tried. I've
tried to read the thing,
but it's all he said it under
you with and then the fucking,
uh, Polynesians said to
the Persians, I mean, I,
I can't, I can't get through it. It's
like trying to reach straight Shakespeare.
But as far as I remember going
to church, they said, dad, uh,
you know, earth was created in
six days. On the seventh day,
God rested and I created Adam
and eve and they were in a,
they were in Eden hanging out. Right?
Then all of a sudden, you know,
he lays down some rules. He says,
Hey, listen, you guys are in paradise.
I just don't want you to go over there
and eat an apple off of that fucking tree.
You know? Is that so god damn
hard to not eat a piece of fruit?
Who gives a shit? It's fruit.
No one wants to eat fruit.
The only people eat fruit or kids whose
parents are making a meet him. Okay.
Vegetarians and some 50 year old Wall
Street guy just suffered his third heart
attack. Then maybe you'll have a
fucking apple so he doesn't die.
But other than that, how easy is it
not to eat an apple? Right? But Eve,
this stupid fucking whore that she is,
you know,
you're not going to tell me you can't.
I can't do something.
And because she's abroad and
you can't punch her in the face,
what does she have to
worry about? Ah, who,
who the fuck is this God guide to
tell me I can't go and have an apple?
So what does she do?
She marches right over there with their
pubic hair blown in the fucking wind.
Cause there's no shame at this
point because there's been no sin.
Everything's great.
You can walk around and go pet a cheetah.
It doesn't immediately or a leopard.
It doesn't immediately
grab you by the throat,
fucking snap your neck and then drag you
up in a tree so the lions can't get to
it. Or somebody else may be
a fucking baboons, you know,
with it's psycho goddamn teeth.
Do you know let's one of the,
one of the fucking major,
uh,
adversaries for a leper as a fucking
baboons. I never knew that shit.
They got those giant teeth
who would announce, you know,
very agile,
left to right sort of movement,
like a water bug, these
insane things. But Hey,
let's get back to the Bible as far as I
remember it right. So they go z, you know,
walking up to the fucking apple tree,
like some one of those fic Toria secret
horse walking down the first fucking
runway.
Although she's not wearing heels,
she just walk in and she
never steps on a Brock.
Doesn't step on some glass from a
broken Miller lite bottle cause she's in
paradise.
She walks right over there and some
snakes starts yet. That's what happened.
Some snakes starts yapping in arrear,
right?
Like some Douche on Facebook who finds
your wife and her semi hot pictures
starts emailing her, right? Wormed
his way into the relationship, right?
So this whore goes up
and what does she do?
She reaches up and she
takes a bite of fruit.
She eats an apple as far as I've been
told, part of this nutritious breakfast,
part of a balanced diet sheets. A fucking
apple. Maybe she wanted to be regular,
right?
So she'd see apple and then
God goes, what the fuck, bitch,
what the fuck did I t the one thing I
say not to do and you got to go do it.
Go Fuck Yourself. That's the end of
paradise. And next thing you know,
she's putting a leaf over a fucking clam.
All right?
Adam's over there.
He didn't do ship.
And evidently he gets punished
too because it's religion,
you know the punishment
never has to make sense.
It just has to be really fucking scary.
So now they're both fucked.
Now all of a sudden the leopards want
to fucking take a bite out of their ass,
so they got to get sharpened
sticks and all this type of shit.
Right now,
according to the Bible,
all of this that happened like fucking
a couple hundred thousand years ago,
and then one day some nerd who's not
getting pussy, he so fucking hard up.
He just starts digging in the ground.
You know,
he's got all that sexual frustration.
He just keeps digging in the ground and
one day finds these dinosaur bones that
are way fucking older than
the Adam and Eve story.
So it kind of kills the
whole God damn thing.
Now that is far as I know
is the story in the Bible,
how the Bible goes down and that's why
people on the science side question the
Bible. Like I said, I haven't read it.
All right, so people who've read it,
can you give me the cheat notes or
are you Bible thumpers out there?
We think the Bible is the best book
ever fucking written aside from the fact
that when it was written, they still
thought the fucking world was flat.
They thought if you were gay,
you get you go to hell and all that
other intolerant horse shit in there.
But you know, I never read the fucking
thing. So you know, let me know.
Cause this guy's trying to acclaim,
trying to claim,
trying to claim that they
address dinosaurs in the Bible,
calling them behemoths,
which is amazing considering we never
discovered the fucking boats until after
the book was written. So
how does that work? Huh?
Was that when God was a burning Bush
and all the fish was coming out of the
basket and he just sorta muttered
something about behemoths and nobody
understood it, but it was God. So
they just wrote it down anyways.
Is that what you're going
to claim? Oh, Jesus.
Oh, GPA. Um,
who can turn their world on with her tits.
Um, what did I want to talk about
this week? How about the Bruins,
Bruins making the fucking playoffs?
I'm predicting that the Bruins will once
again make it to the eastern conference
finals and then, uh, then
what's going to happen?
I'll tell you what's going to happen is
that they're not going to go any further.
I Dunno. I'm just going to say that
cause hopefully they'll prove me wrong.
Who knows?
We've got a great goalie.
You know what's scaring me is fucking
Carey price up in Montreal has been
playing fantastic.
All right.
And for some reason when the Bruins have
a great goalie, it only gets us so far.
But those sons of bitches
up there with Ken Dryden,
Patrick Ouab back and fucking 93 when
they went on that implausible run one like
19 overtime games,
one of the great runs at winning
the Stanley Cup of all fucking time.
Um, who knows? I don't know. I
think the flyers will beat him.
The flyers never seem to have
problem with the Canadians. Uh,
they don't give a fuck. Right? They
just get a punch you in the face.
Uh, anyways. Hey, listen to
this shit. You know something,
what happened to me twice
this week is people just,
they don't hear what the fuck I'm saying.
This is the classic thing.
When you're doing standup comedy,
you stand on stage and you tell a
bunch of jokes and everybody laughs,
everybody's having just a great time.
And then all of a sudden you come around
to his subject that touches a little
close to somebody's life and all of a
sudden you're not telling jokes anymore.
Now you're making statements. Well, Lo
and behold, once again, this happens.
I don't know if you
guys are aware of this,
but my let it go special is now up
on Netflix, the unedited version,
the version that I
wanted the world to see.
But that dream was crushed
because on comedy central,
they have advertisers and that's how
they make their money, which I respect.
So then, you know, they
got to cut out some jokes.
They got to start doing the Morse code
because they say fuck every other word
and then Yada, Yada, Yada. But now
it's on Netflix. Now it's on Netflix.
And you can watch that son of a bitch,
a completely unedited.
So please tell your friends, please tell
your family, tell some your enemies. Um,
so anyways, so some, uh, some woman
evidently watch this. Watch my special,
my standup comedy special,
the one where I go on and act like an ass
and I'm telling jokes just to make you
laugh,
just to fucking appease my ego.
That's all on doing.
So anyways,
this lady starts off and uh,
she says offended by your stay
at home mom bit. She starts off.
Hi.
Obviously I'm a stay at home mom.
Why is that obvious?
Because you said you were offended
by my stay at home mom bit.
Why couldn't you be just a
supporter of stay at home moms? Oh,
I'm being a cunt right out of the gate.
Let's read this. She starts off high.
Obviously I'm a stay at home
mom and I love watching standup,
but I couldn't continue watching you
based on your bit about stay at home moms.
You know what I love about it?
It's an hour long special and I think
I opened with that joke or it was
literally within the first five
minutes and she had to shut it off.
She says, I'm really sorry you feel
that way about stay at home moms.
That's one of my pet peeves is when
someone's about ready to take the piss out
of me. I hate when they
apologize. Okay. You're not sorry.
You're not sorry that I feel that way.
You fucking hate me because I feel
that way. All right. Stop apologizing.
Oh God. My voice is cracking.
Stop apologizing. All right.
Um, anyway, she goes and the
uh, blah blah blah blah blah.
If it weren't for us,
there would be no one to drill holes and
to do all the other important jobs that
you mentioned. All right?
If it weren't for you,
what are you just fucking
meditate and you'll make a person
you self centered fucking whore.
Can you believe she just took
credit for the creation of babies?
100% credit. What about the guy
who fucking sticks it in? Yeah.
Huh. Oh, I am getting close.
What about that part of it?
There wasn't some hairy,
sweaty man
pounding away at your fucking
womanhood to completion.
I might add a number of times during
the course of a month, two months,
possibly three months if you got,
you know,
if you've got some sort of issue down
there for some reason you're, you're,
I dunno what the fuck. I never
tried to do it, but I know, yeah,
we're having a difficult time.
We're trying to get pregnant,
but we're having a difficult time.
It's not the fucking part.
It's the impregnation part. She's
just totally taking away all of that,
that evidently she just sits there
and all of a sudden she's pregnant.
Kind of like dead chicken.
The Bible hanging out with
that fucking hippie bum Joseph.
Right? He sitting over in the
corner with his vaporizer.
Hey Man, I noticed she looks
like you putting on weight, man.
You got to lay off the
Dorito. It's man. Right?
And all of a sudden she's fucking
pregnant. So have a deli this broad.
She's taking full credit,
full credit for getting pregnant.
Completely ignoring the man's part of it.
He loved getting close.
That's, that's the noise I make
when I climb x. By the way,
I make it, I, I announced it, the
female in a really high pitched voice,
sorta of whiny voice and getting close.
And then I put my mouth right
next to her ear and I go, oh,
that's how it goes down in my world.
Um,
some of the most sophomore
humor humor I've ever done.
And right now there's a bunch of guys
laughing and there's a bunch of females
with the nose all wrinkled up.
This, this is what you listen to.
This is what you think is funny. Yes,
bitch, this is what I think is funny.
Why don't you go back out in the
kitchen and finish, make a potato salad.
All right. The fourth
of July's coming up. Um,
I made no sense. Okay. Um,
and if it weren't for us,
there would be no one drilling holes
and do all the other important jobs that
you mentioned.
I didn't say they weren't important.
I didn't say those jobs were important.
You didn't even listen to the bit.
Let me continue reading here.
I said,
Oprah said that being a mother is
the most difficult job in the planet.
If she said it's the most important
job, I would have gone with her.
But she said it was
the most difficult job.
That's that right there was the
seat of the bit that I created.
Okay.
Just like you creating the fucking kid.
But I don't feel like I
created the joke on my own.
It took Oprah to say to,
to,
to plant the seed by saying,
by saying that it was the most
difficult job on the planet.
All right. That was her
climaxing into my joke. Pussy.
Oh, that's disgusting. Anyways,
so now I think everybody's
wrinkling their nose. So here we go.
So she continues after not even
hearing what I'm saying and she said,
and the reason you stay in your pajamas
all day, that was the line I said,
talking about women is because you
don't have one minute to change.
Try taking a shower and putting on on
clothes and clothes on with children's
screaming and crying at the
shower door. It's 24, seven.
It never stops. Uh, you
don't click a time card.
You never get off work. It's 24, seven.
You have absolutely no
idea until you're in it.
I made a lot of money in my career
before motherhood, Motherhood,
I earned my MBA and other degrees.
I've lived and worked abroad.
Motherhood is the hardest job
I've ever done. I've never said,
I've never said it's not the hardest
job that you've ever done. Okay?
All right.
But I'm willing to bet that you've never
done a job harder than working on a
fucking oil rig in the middle
of the ocean. All right,
sweetheart,
being a mom is not more difficult than
working on an oil rig in the middle of
the fucking ocean.
How about that guy out there worked
on one and it fucking blew up.
He's got second degree burns on his back.
It they're going to turn into third degree
burns and then he's eventually going
to explode into flames.
So his only option is to jump basically
the equivalent of a three story
building.
He jumps off it,
okay
with his rob burned up back into
the salt water of the ocean.
Also now covered in oil.
He's covered in oil with second
degree burns in salt water.
Okay?
He can barely fucking breathe.
The fucking ocean is catching on fire
because of the oil that's on the surface
of the water.
He has to swim out of that,
get out into the ocean but not get too
far away cause he wants to get rescued.
Now he's got to sit there treading water
hoping he doesn't get eaten alive by
sharks or drown
or diet.
I Dunno what else.
While he waits for the Coast
Guard to come and pick them up,
now you tell me all the mothers out there.
I want you to explain to me a
day that was more difficult than,
and not only that all this woman is doing
is talking about the negative aspects
of being a mother. She's not
talking about how rewarding it is.
You don't get unconditional
love from a fucking oil rig.
It's not going to be sitting
there at your deathbed,
holding your fucking hand telling you
that you know the oil rig is everything it
is today because of you as a person.
Give me a fucking break.
All right?
And also you made the choice to become
a mother by letting that guy get on top
of you. Oh, getting close, right?
Typical fucking broad.
Do Your fucking idea.
She goes anywhere she can tell you use
your joke is so offensive and so totally
wrong. It's disgusting.
Another thing, this is precious
time to me in the evening.
Well,
I didn't fucking ask you to email me.
Good Lord. What a fuck she,
this is a mother. Look at
her working with the guilt.
This is precious time to me.
In the evening you are watching a stand
up special that was going to take a
whole fucking hour.
You shut it off.
Seven minutes into it.
That gives you a next of 53
minutes to write two paragraphs.
They're so full of shit.
So anyways,
she's trying to make me feel guilty like
I'm taking away from her fucking day.
I know the thing.
This is precious time to me in the
evening when I can be taking a shower,
read or watch a show and
recharge for the next day.
Wait a minute.
You just told me that being
a mom was a 24 seven job,
it never stops. It never ends.
Here you are chilling out,
wanted to take a shower,
read or watch a show and
recharge for the next day.
Jesus Christ. She's goes, oh, maybe later
tonight when one of my children get up,
I'm not on Facebook.
I don't waste any time on the computer
and I don't complain about things,
but this was so offensive that I make
time for this email. I'll thank you.
Thank you for taking time out of your day.
You're unbelievably 24 seven day
and you just had to say something.
Then this is, this is awesome sheet.
This is how she answered email. She says,
very disappointed, Jamie. Oh,
actually I never named names. Okay,
so this is what I love about this.
This woman is obviously going to be a
great mom, okay? She's dedicated to what?
She's walked away from her Mba career and
all that type of shit so she can focus
on a career.
Okay.
But what you could see here is the
resentment that's already building because
she's already throwing
out guilt on to everybody.
That's what I love about mothers. All
right. No one told you to become a mother.
You made that fucking choice and now you
actually have like resentment for your
fucking job and you just
starting to put it on your kids.
I can tell you're already putting it on
your kids because you're trying to it on
me.
He tried to make me feel guilty that
you took the time to send me a fucking
email.
I didn't ask you to send me your fucking
email and then you end it with very
disappointed like I'm
looking for your approval.
See you're already getting
your God complex cause your
fucking kids are looking
at you like you know every God damn
answer on the planet, which you don't.
Jesus Christ. So there,
there, there you go.
There you go. People,
there it is. In a nutshell.
That's what it's like to be a stand up
comedian. You make one fucking joke.
Okay.
About an overstatement.
That so much said that being a mother
is the most difficult job on the planet.
So what does that, that makes me
think about all these other jobs,
digging for coal,
yet out being president of the United
States and having to have a decide that
we're going to go to war and
then you got to lay to bed,
go lay in bed knowing that a bunch of
people are now going to die. Babies,
women,
you know,
18 to 21 year old fucking people who
signed up right out, out, out, out, out,
out a God damn high school to be in
the army, marines, Navy. You got it.
You got to make that.
You've got to lay in bed,
try and get fucking eight hours sleep
with that shit weighing on your head.
You know
that that was a joke.
It's not the most difficult
job in the planet.
If you said it's the most important, I
would have gone with that. All right.
I said I was arguing that it
wasn't the most difficult. Okay.
And this is what happens.
People.
They don't hear what you're saying and
then they go off on another 10 tangent.
Like this other fucking cunt.
This is a guy. All right.
This guy, what the fuck did he
talk? Where the hell is it? Ah,
Jesus. Bill. Oh Jesus. Look what you did.
You just slowed the whole
fucking thing down. Um, oh,
I disagree.
He said bill loved the podcast,
but I disagree with you on the
whole music downloading thing.
Most of my music that I've,
that I have is not bought for good reason.
First of all,
the last two CD's I bought brand new from.
The store's skipped in multiple
CD players right out of the box.
Secondly,
artists only get about five to 10%,
five to 10 cents per CD,
which in the grand scheme
of things doesn't add up to
much compared to the money
they get from tee shirts and
gigs. Now, don't get me wrong,
the people that just download thousands
of CD's worth of stuff and never go to
shows there.
The douche bags,
I tried to go to at least
five shows a year. Wow.
And I go to Lollapalooza in
Chicago once every three years.
So am I a loser to your
bill? No, you're not a loser.
You're just stealing music.
You stealing fucking music and you're
trying to shine it all up like, hey man,
the artist's doesn't
make any fucking money.
You bought two cds from the store and
they skipped in multiple places. Dude,
you can go to iTunes and you can
download music in a digital form and that
doesn't skip.
All right?
You're trying to justify the fact that
you still thousands and thousands of
dollars worth the fucking music.
And then you spent, you know,
a couple hundred bucks
on concert tickets and tee shirts
and shit. And then, and there you go.
I didn't steal a hundred percent for you.
I completely disagree with you.
I don't want to say, and you're a
loser. I'm saying you're a thief,
you're stealing and you know
you're stealing. All right.
I'm not a musician, dude. I've
bought cds. I bought those things.
I know they start to skip, but if I
buy my fucking upload them onto my,
my computer, but I, I do all of my
shit through Itunes, but uh, I don't,
I don't steal music.
And what I did steal it,
I addressed the fact that
I was stealing music.
I wasn't saying that I wasn't part of
the fucking problem back in the day when
it first came out,
my eyes fucking dropped out of my head
to free music and I went to limewire and
I downloaded a couple of
hundred fucking socks.
But in the end when people presented
the argument, dude, just stealing,
I couldn't get around it. I was like,
yeah, you're right. I am. So I stopped.
So I'm not saying I'm better than you and
I'm not saying you're a fucking loser.
What I'm saying is you
steal it fucking music,
however you frame it and go and do a
couple of concerts doesn't make up for the
fact that you stole the music.
You know,
it's like concert tickets costs money.
It's like a concert ticket was
free and you made a donation.
You still got something out of your money,
you got a t shirt,
you got a fucking concert ticket.
So you're acting like those monies make
up for the fact that you stole music.
Like you didn't get anything out of the,
out of,
out of the concert ticket and
putting down money for a t shirt.
You got to fucking rock
show or hip hop show,
whatever the fuck you went to and you got
a t shirt that doesn't make up for the
fact that you stole the fucking music.
It doesn't. All right. So like I said,
I'm not saying you're a loser.
You're a fucking thief. Oh,
I'm on my God damn high horse here.
Um,
let's get to underrated
overrated here. People, uh,
a topic that I thought was dying that
I'm actually pleased to say is a,
is making a comeback. Oh, before I do
that, I mentioned a few weeks ago that,
um,
the short film cheat that me,
Joe de Rosa and Robert Kelly wrote and
acted in and Joe de Rosa did a phenomenal
job directing this movie,
the short film.
We got it into the Tribeca film festival,
which is one of the biggest
film festivals out there.
It's right up there with Sundance
and all that type of stuff. Um,
and I wanted to give you
guys a screening times.
If you're actually in the,
uh,
New York area and you want to
come down and support our film,
we would love to see you down there.
We're going to try to hang out as,
as many screenings as we possibly can.
There's a couple of them that we're not
allowed to go to just because there's
going to be industry there and they
want to review the film and you know,
we can't be breathing down their necks,
making them uncomfortable.
So here are the screening
times, uh, Saturday,
April 23rd at 7:00 PM
is the first screening.
Of course, I don't have where the
screening, I'm such a fucking idiot.
I'll give you this information.
I'll just tell you when or they are this
Saturday at 7:00 PM Wednesday at 5:30
PM.
That's April 27th and Saturday,
April 30th at 4:00 PM and
Sunday May 1st at 7:30 PM.
Um, I believe I'm calling in the
opiod Anthony show this week.
I believe Thursday this week,
uh,
to Rosa and Bobby Kelly are going to be
on there and we're going to have all the
rest of the information. So
I'm, I what an idiot I am.
Why am I such a fucking moron? You know
it go to the [inaudible] podcast.com.
We'll it, we'll have the actual, that's
the official fan page, by the way.
And he gets all the shit right?
I'm such a fucking more,
I was so excited to tell you guys all
that type of shit. And what did I do?
What did I do?
I fucked the whole thing up.
All right.
You feel that?
Do you hear that silence?
The podcast is just screeched to a
grinding halt and it's 100% my fault.
All right. Underrated. Overrated for
this week. All right. Underrated.
This guy says ice cream sandwiches.
Uh,
they are made from the cheapest ice
cream and the crappiest cookies,
but they are fucking delicious.
And I can eat like five. Um,
I actually had a debate
with Nia on this one.
MMM.
I thought he was literally talking
about ice cream sandwiches,
but she's saying because he said cookies.
He means those ones that have like the
chocolate chip cookies. And with that,
just that generic ice cream in the
middle. It's basically, you know,
the filling that they put in hot dogs.
It's the ice cream version of that.
And he said he can eat like five and uh,
I am right there with you.
I'm right there with you. I think I
could eat, I think I could eat six,
but I would get sick, but I could eat five
just like you and I would not be sick.
And my body at no point would be acting
like what I was doing was incorrect
until about Oh 15 minutes later when
I suddenly would have to take a nap.
Never eat really bad food and
you have to take a nap. Um,
you get all sleepy or as black people
call it the Itis, you get the itis.
I told you that story a long time
ago. Deny. I'll tell it to you again.
The fuck I got an hour to kill here.
I know I got some new listeners, um,
back in the day when I was on the, uh,
the Chappelle show tour and it was me,
Charlie Murphy and uh,
Don l Rawlings who played ashy Larry.
We went out in 2004,
mid 2004 and toward I s I taught,
I stayed on the tour till about a,
the end of February, 2005. And, uh,
these guys used to break
my balls about my shirts,
all my clothes and all that type of shit.
That actually turned into a bit when I
did my half hour special, that whole bit,
that Ma,
this motherfucker only has five shirts
that came from hanging out with those
guys doing talent shows back in the day.
Drew Frazier and all those
guys, Rob Stapleton, uh,
well who are the room did I
used to do Capone's roams,
all those things when I used to jump
back and forth between the black rooms,
white rooms for mainstream rooms,
the uptown rooms as they used to call him.
But anyways, so these guys
used to, you know, thanks,
you just give me shit
and that type of stuff.
So we had gone out drinking
or I had gone out drinking,
I was brutally fucking hung over and I
just didn't want to listen to that shit.
And we were driving from Chicago up to
Vernon hills to do a the xannies up there
and it was a good hour, hour and
a half drive. I don't know what,
but it was gonna seem like five hours and
I could tell that they were just going
to be fucking on my shit
because I was really hung over.
So what I did was I asked the,
I don't know,
somehow I walked out to try and get some
fresh air and I saw that there was a
Popeye's chicken,
like fucking two blocks up.
So I ran up there and got like a fucking,
I don't know,
a 17 piece of that shit with
biscuits and all of that ship.
We will leave and right around 11 and we
go and we get in the fucking limo to go
up there and I'd bring,
hey guys,
they got us some food and I ate one piece
and watched them devour like another
five, six pieces, a couple
of biscuits. Right? And they
were already giving me shit.
And within fucking 15 minutes
they were fucking sound asleep.
And I just sat there with a smile on
my face with some of that greasy food,
my stomach, but not enough to make me fall
asleep. Just enough to feel comforted,
comforted. Right. And I had my
sunglasses on and I cruised,
although we cruise all the way up there
and they slept the whole fucking way.
It's one of the brilliant moves
and my standup career. Um,
so anyways,
I'll speak and that shit,
I'm actually getting myself
into great shape here.
You want to know how I've been
doing it? Well, I don't give a fuck.
I'm going to tell you anyway.
I, uh, I mentioned a back
in the day, I got a juicer.
And, uh, like most things, you
know, when you get something
new, you're all about it.
You're all about it for like, I don't
know what, right, a week, two weeks,
maybe a month.
And then one day you just blow it off.
You just fucking blow it off.
And then it starts gathering dust.
And then every once in a while you just
look at whatever you bought your Ipad,
you fucking, I don't know what
you, whatever gadget you had,
and it's just over there collecting dust.
And he just had that feeling like, God,
I used to be so fucking into that thing.
You know,
it's kind of like a relationship.
You know, you meet some hot girl,
you're telling your friends,
dude,
this one of the hottest fucking
cigs I've ever been with you,
she's got like the perfect tits.
You have to do that.
He starts describing a body to all
your fucking animal guy friends.
And then all of a sudden it turns
into her relationship, you know?
And now it's your girlfriend.
And now, you know,
I described the tits to my friends
or the fucking crazy thing,
she didn't bed, you know, and then
what happened? She's totally into it.
You're and your bag and you're banging.
And then just one day
you don't even notice,
you're just not into it anymore.
Yeah.
And then one day you're walking by and
you look down at it as your pussy just
gathering dust,
like you fucking laser disc player and
you're wondering what the fuck happened.
You know?
And that's the moment where you realize
if you're with the right person or not,
because if you decide that you're going
to work at the relationship and get the
sparks going again,
you're with the right person.
But if you just looking at it like
a fucking old VCR, yeah, no, it's a,
it's time to move on. That's
what I think. So anyways,
let's get back to the juice or everybody.
So the juicer
evidently is a,
my fucking gadgets soul mate,
because I looked at it and I was
getting sad going, you know what?
I got a fucking, uh, I got to
get this thing back in my life.
I've got to find where, where,
where did we lose the magic?
So I went to the health food store and
I went in there like a little fucking,
you know Vegan. I fucking go in there.
Right.
Oh you know what's funny,
this disc displace right around
the corner from where I live,
cells that coconut water that I absolutely
love that I drank on Joe Rogan's show
and that they told me they
got on amazon.com and I
ordered it on amazon.com and
you know me, I'm totally fucking,
I got the OCD like or whatever. I,
when I get into shit I get into shit and
it was like 20 something bucks to get
like, like 12 of these things.
So it was already expensive.
And then you know, if, if you know,
you just do five to six business days,
who gives a fuck? They charge you
like three bucks. But I was like, no,
I want that shit in two days.
So my shipping cost was as much as
the God damn price of the coconut oil.
I paid like 40 bucks for 12 of
them and then I go down the street.
What about when I reintroduced myself
to my juicer going, hey baby, let's,
you know what happened to us, man.
Let's watch a movie tonight, right?
I go over to the fucking
a vegetable place.
You know what that creepy little
analogy just reminded me of,
I guess there's some fucking show out
there where people are in love with
inanimate objects like they actually like
fuck a fence or a bridge or they want
to like marry the Eiffel Tower. Can
somebody please tell me what that show is?
I really want to watch that because
I saw that one that was fatal,
fatal attractions where people have wild
animals that they try to turn to to try
to turn into a,
they tried to turn it the pets and those
people were just so fucking stupid of
me that I couldn't watch the show.
But I ended up hearing that that
show was good cause they get,
they get into the psychology of
of why somebody gets into that.
All I saw when I saw that guy with the
buffalo walking around his house and
every time he walked by them that buffalo
would slam into the wall and he looked
like Wayne Gretzky getting fucking checked
by sort of fucking normal size hockey
player. And he'd just be like, oh,
is he would walk by now she just
play and she just playing this shit.
It was so fucking stupid. I
couldn't watch it. So, um,
if anybody can tell me what
the name of that show is,
where people are like in love
with like a door, you know, dude,
how much alone time are you spending?
I mean, I haven't heard that in jail.
Well he didn't. Solitary confinement.
Do you get love with the walls?
I bet you do. At some
point. Some point you just,
you just from just lack of human contact,
you know that man brain kicks in
where you get visually stimulated,
you gotta get visually stimulated by
something and they would just be like,
I bet it's like at some point during
the day when the sun starts going down,
right in the shadow of just hits
the wall a certain way and you just,
there you are. There you are.
You sweet little naughty,
naughty piece of plaster.
Ah,
well you've been for the last 23 hours.
Shit, I don't want to hear it. You know,
so fucking creepy.
Actually.
Somebody who's probably in jail or has
been a jail is going to be, oh Mary,
actually, when you're assault
Jerry confinement, there's
no sunlight. Ah, right.
Whatever. Whatever the fuck
it is. You fuck the floor,
you know, there you go. Is
that in any prison book?
I think I hit my low point when I
was consistently fucking the floor.
Um, all right, let's
continue on here. So anyway,
so I got my juicer back in my life. That's
what the fuck I'm trying to tell you.
So I go to the Goddamn health
food store, right. And, uh,
you know great about going
to the health food stores,
even though the isles are really skinny,
much skinnier than one of the, uh,
grocery stores. Those fucking, you know,
people who actually eat healthy or
are there just waif human beings.
They do yoga, a little wispy Lilach
Lily Nolan's dog's little snippets.
They just like them,
you know,
walking up and down the aisles with their
fucking tail between their legs trying
to pick out Zucchini.
So I'm going in there right
suddenly feeling like I'm
on roids because I look so
much bigger app full of Shit. There was
a couple of decent size people in that,
but whatever. So I go in there,
I pick out all this fucking, uh,
fruits and vegetables to juice. So
that's, I've been starting my day.
People start my day,
I fucking juice.
Then I go get my fucking pit bull.
We go for a walk,
we go for a hike for like an hour.
I come back and then I have
a bowl of oatmeal with some,
a handful of raisins thrown in there.
That's how I start my day and
it's been fucking great for me.
I'm not trying to preach to you people,
I'm not trying to be a fucking
breakfast Nazi here, but I,
this is what I realized with me,
this is how I get out of whack is
if I start my day either with, um,
I can't even just say toast and eggs,
but if I, if I throw the Bacon in there,
then it's really extra salty. Then I
got to throw a little jam on my toast,
you know, to try to level myself
off. Just like a fucking coke.
It drinking alcohol to bring me down a
little bit. You know, I got the salt,
the salt making me sleepy,
so I put the jelly on the toast
to bring me back up right there.
I'm out of fucking whack. Or if I have
French toast or anything you put Syrup on,
then my sugar goes through the roof.
Next thing you know,
I'm grabbing a handful of
fucking potato chips, you know,
like an hour later. And then like for
the rest of the day, my blood sugar,
I don't know what it is. It probably looks
like a, uh, what do you got? One of the,
one of those things with it,
the heart thing, Sonogram,
whatever the fuck you call it.
Not a telegraph.
What do you call that fucking
thing? You know when, when when you,
when you're laying there in the hospital
and now they're looking at
your heart rate. That's what,
that's what it looks like.
Salt, sugar, salt, sugar.
That's what I do for the rest of the
fucking day. Then at the end of the day,
I take a big piece of cake and I shove
it right down my fucking pie hole and
that's my day.
And then gradually my white doughy stomach
starts to hang over my belt and then
I hate myself and then I start lashing
out at people in the crowd. So,
okay,
there you go. That's what's
been working for me. Um,
so why don't, why don't you guys give
a shot if you want to, if you don't,
I don't give a fuck. Oh by the
way, 170 days without booze.
And I actually fucked it up yesterday.
I was at a party or a barbecue yesterday
and I accidentally twice had two sips
of beer.
Yeah,
okay.
So technically in my world,
my streak is still going because
it was an accident. But I, I've,
I've had booze within the last 24 hours
and this is, this is what I've noticed.
What is really fascinating
about the human brain,
and I didn't realize this
till I went to Stockholm,
Sweden when I did that Gig over there,
my,
but I told you that story and it went
over there and everybody, you know,
and I forgot that,
you know,
I didn't speak a word of Swedish and
everyone's gone highs and tries and cars
and revising. And I was,
you know, the fucking,
the comedian in front of me who was
speaking English backstage went out there
and did his whole act and
Swedish and was killing. Oh,
I just tried to read recharging our
Johari j Tajin and the crowds like,
and I'm freaking out going and they
even got to fucking understand me.
This is what I learned when I was in
Sweden was I took for granted how much I
don't read when I'm in the
states because I you just like,
I think when you look at a stop
sign you don't read stop, you just,
you just visually looking at it and I
didn't realize that shit until I went over
to Sweden and the amount of extra
thinking that I had to do where I would be
looking at like a car and just be like,
okay,
is that a taxi or is that a police car?
You know?
Or I'd have to look at a
storefront and just sort of try to,
because I can't read the word.
It's in Swedish and it's
like 97 fucking letters.
I'd have to just really sit there
looking. Is that close? Is there,
is there food in there? Is that, what the
fuck is that? That's what happened to me
at the party.
I open the refrigerator door and I saw
this green can and I immediately equated
it with soda and I,
and in my brain told me it was a sprite.
Turned out it was seven up and right
next to it was a red and white can.
So I think, I actually think it was
just red. So in my world that was coke.
So I reached for the coke,
opened it up,
took a sip of it thinking I was drinking
coca cola and it was a Mexican beer and
I drank and I didn't even record. I
don't know, it was a weird tasting beer.
I thought it was like ice tea and I
looked down at it and I'm reading it,
you know,
and I actually,
I'm just looking for coke and I'm looking
all over the words and finally I see
beer. I'm like, is this, did I just
drink a beer? I was like, fuck,
there goes my God damn streak.
So of course knee is laughing at me.
So then I go over and grab what I thought
was a sprite was actually seven up.
I started drinking that and then
later on in the peanut at the party,
he grabbed the wrong thing. Once
again, I thought I was drinking coke
and I reached over and I grabbed it.
Nothing other thing.
Now the fucking Swig of beer, so I want
you guys to know is my streak over,
you know all you addicts out there? What
does that mean? If you, if you do that,
if you're an AA,
do you have to turn in your chip and
start all over again and go up there and
cry at the podium because you
actually had a sip of beer?
Do I get any credit with the fact that I,
that I opened the beer,
took the sip of the beer and just
said, oh fuck, this is, you know,
I thought this was coke.
It's a beer and I just set it down.
I didn't have any more anybody.
Can you help me out here?
This is what I wish I took callers.
I'm glad I don't take college because
I think color is really slow down the
fucking show.
You know?
Half of them are fucking prank phone calls
and then half the people it just take
some too. God Damn Long. Plus
I like talking. All right.
You haven't noticed the fact that I rarely
have a guest on this show and I could
somehow keep it going for a fucking hour.
You know,
that's not an amazing ability. That's,
that is an incredible personality. Fluff.
All right. Um, more, um,
underrated. Overrated. Uh,
unpaid internships.
Overrated.
I graduated from college less than a year
ago and had been looking for a job in
my area of studies for more than
a year with no success. Dude, I,
my heart goes out to these fucking kids
just getting out to out of college right
now and the worst of the worst economies
ever. It's just fucking ridiculous.
They already overcharged your for your
fucking education and these goddamn
bankers screwed the whole fucking economy
up. Anyways, plowing ahead. He says,
while looking for a job, I encountered
numerous agencies that offer internships,
but no, but none for PE it
seems. How is that legal,
by the way?
You don't pay him anything.
It seems like many places take advantages
of the bad economy and the desperate
job seekers to lure them into doing work
for free. Unfortunately, I'm one of them.
Dude.
What kind of a fucking,
this is what I want to go undercover
into corporate America and I want to,
I want to see how that
goes down. How that, how,
like is it just like the mob boy
you like age, not focus personal,
it's business.
Oh,
you know,
well, if you're, if you check
out the market, what the
market will bear now is, uh,
it's advantageous if you're
the employer to a nut, uh,
to take advantage of the human
resources and offer them a,
a negative cashflow
contract, however they fucking deal. But
they never just come out and said, hey,
let's take advantage of the future
and pay them absolutely nothing.
So we can, we can drive, we can put rims
on our, our, our flashy fucking cars.
Um, anyways, he says, uh,
what do these agencies offer
an exchange experience,
building your resume,
making connections with other employees,
promises of hiring after a short
period and other bullshit like that.
He says, fuck that in capital letters.
You mentioned in Joe Rogan's podcast,
how comedians should not
offer their material for free
in exchange for exposure.
And I completely agree.
These unpaid internships that are so
popular right now need to stop a more
efficient than some of my fulltime
coworkers at my internships,
which are not a surprise.
Oh wait,
which are not a surprise,
are part of a worker's Union.
And I work, uh, here comes
my bed reading skills.
I got totally confused
with his parentheses.
MMM.
He says, and I worked there
only two days out of the week.
It wasn't funny. It would be sad. So
he's basically saying in those two days,
he does more work than the people who
are members of the union. You know,
that's something that unions have to
address here is I'm all about unions.
But you know,
just because you now have the power to
lean on a shovel doesn't mean you should.
And that's what's really fucked over.
Unions.
Unions were a great idea and people died,
had their heads kicked in,
got shot at by our own fucking army.
When guys like Andrew Carnegie had the
connections to bring them in like he did
there and the fucking banks
of the Allegheny out there
in Pittsburgh or wherever
the fuck was that.
That's now a mall.
All right?
They needed those unions so
we could avoid sweatshop,
the sweatshop labor conditions
that existed in this country.
And then what happened aside from the map,
the mob taken over those things.
What happened is his guys used the unions,
the power of unions as a way to get over
fucking paid and not to bust their ass
at work anymore.
So then they became the exact fucking
thing that they were rebelling against.
So I understand why corporations
move. They're fucking, um,
yeah.
Companies out of this country.
I also understand why that there had
to be union said, you know, this,
this is what it always comes down
to is people are people rich.
People aren't the only greedy fucking
assholes out there. It, you know,
middle class and poor people,
if you put them in a position
where they can be greedy.
The sad thing is most people will
take advantage of this situation.
This is not these, and these
are not unique theories.
This is the overall theory,
harsh theory that most
people learn when they get,
when they get out of their house
and they get into the real world.
You realize that most people are cons.
There's very few good people out there,
poor middle class or fucking rich,
this very few people that will
actually do the right thing. So, uh,
I 100% agree with that. It would
be, you know, speaking of unions,
it would be great if you could
somehow start one. You know,
that's what she needs to do is you need
to get everybody on the same page and
say, listen, we're not saying
you got to give us all of us,
but this fucking working
for free is ridiculous. Um,
yeah, they're totally
taken advantage of you, um,
because of the market.
But I guess if it's a good market,
you guys can take advantage of
them. I Dunno, man. It's just so,
I don't know who the fuck knows,
but I definitely that there's just
something wrong with having kids work for
fucking free.
All right.
And I will say to people
who were in unions,
which I am 100 supported in support of,
you motherfuckers need to work
harder and you'll have a better,
um, you'll have a better public image.
Now I'm not saying everybody in unions,
don't you know they all
have them lean on shovels,
but you know why you got that
reputation. Okay, I'm Irish.
I know we got why we got the reputation
for being a bunch of drunk motherfuckers
because so many of us are,
or at least enough of us got so fucking
drunk that we completely wiped out any
sort of good Irishman out there. All
right, so there you go. Ah, another one.
Documentaries underrated.
In the last few months I've
become a big fan of documentaries,
especially about co are corrupted economy
are fucked up culture and our diet,
a dying planet and environment.
I have to say these films put a really
great picture as far as our civilization
goes. Yeah, I know. That's why
I kind of stopped watching them.
I just try to do the right
thing in my own life. If I,
if I watch too many of those, they
really depressed the shit out of me. MMM.
The president has already looked bad
and I did not see a way we can dig
ourselves out of this
hole that we've created.
I just don't understand why people
dismiss these types of films.
Are they trying to avoid the painful
truth? Absolutely. I just said I was,
are they in denial? Absolutely. There
are ways and solutions to fix it,
but as long as we have, uh,
democrats versus Republicans,
white versus blacks
versus versus Hispanics,
coal and oil energy first,
uh,
clean energy and most importantly
fucking paper money and stock markets,
nothing's going to change.
Yeah. This guy, this is,
this is the exact conclusion that I came.
Um,
although I don't agree that a lot of the
clean energy they say is clean energy.
Like as much as I drive a hybrid,
which is really a scam,
it's only an electric car when it's
going five miles an hour under.
Other than that,
it's just an underpowered gas car,
but it does burn clean and it
does get great gas mileage.
But you know, electric cars,
I mean those batteries,
eventually you have to dispose of those.
And those things. Recap. Basically,
human beings in general wreak
havoc on the environment.
So I think the solution is you have to
have some sort of population control and
they should do it sooner rather than
later because if they did it sooner,
we could avoid some sort of Stalin s
slash Hitler solution because that's what
the fuck they're going to do.
Um,
I think the problem with human beings is
we treat global problems the same way,
which a college kid treats doing a
term paper. We do it the night before.
You know,
remember y two K we knew that shit was
coming and ended up not being a fucking
problem, but everybody panicked.
And the final two months,
they were talking about it for 10 years
that we were going to have this possibly
have this fucking problem. And we
waited until the last fucking second.
And I think that the population
problem is going to be the same thing.
The prop this too many fucking people.
This note,
there's nothing wrong
with chopping down trees.
There's nothing wrong with using coal.
There's nothing wrong
with driving a big car.
There's nothing wrong with any of that.
The problem is,
is that the 7 billion people on the
fucking planet, that that's a problem.
All right? We need to get that number
way the fuck down, whey the fuck down.
I would say under a billion under a
billion people, you need to do that.
So I think that you should just implement
laws, the amount of people that, uh,
kids that you can have. And
I also think that, you know,
you should offer people money if they,
to not have kids,
uh,
adopt kids recycle.
I think that they should do all of that
type of stuff while they tried to have
cleaner burning cars and that type of
shit and just gradually let people kind of
die off.
You know,
I, I, that's, that's what I feel.
You know, cause if you don't do that,
then eventually, um, I think that
we're going to run out of food,
run out of clean water and you're
going to have the rich in their gated
communities and they're going to be
guarded by the black water people and that
is going to be shooting out the rest of
us in their fucking heads, in our heads.
That's what I think's going to
happen personally, you know,
if mother nature doesn't get us first.
All right. That was uplifting. All right,
let's get to, uh, let's get to
advice for the week. Um, Bill,
year and a half ago, um, where the
hell am I? A year and a half ago,
me and this girl that I used to work
with were hanging out a lot and fooling
around all summer. Very nice. It
was pretty casual. There you go.
That's how you set it up. It's pretty
casual. Wonderful. Now I think it just,
the artists trying to keep it there and
as I've told you before, what that is,
it's the,
it's the time between you hooking up okay.
When you keep it a casual
and that type of shit.
If you want to hang out and have drinks,
that's fine.
But when you get back to your place,
you do the deed and that's it.
She's got to go.
You can't hang out and watch a movie.
That's when they start getting feelings.
It's not fair to the female, you know,
that's what you gotta do.
Don't call him all the fucking time.
You gotta keep it fucking
casual. All right. Continuing,
which is kind of hard to do when you
work with them. Um, but anyways, he goes,
it was pretty casual,
but that was only because we both
knew I had to leave in August,
so we made a point to not get
too sir. Serious. Beautiful. Um,
once the summer ended,
I had to go back to school in Miami.
So our situation kind of ended, but
we stayed in touch. Then recently,
this last spring break,
I went home for 10 days when I let
her know I was going to be in town.
She said that, uh, that
we had to hang out,
but only his friends because she had
a boyfriend, which I was fine with.
All right, dude. Now I haven't read this
one yet, but I got to tell you right here,
uh, don't hang out with, they're
more than once. All right?
This is what you should do
in that situation. She's
got a boyfriend. It's over.
All right. So if she wants to hang
out, hang out in a public place,
and at the end of the night you say
you gotta go, don't bring up sex.
Don't fucking do anything like what
you used to do. She's got a boyfriend.
He got to walk away from that situation.
Not to mention if you,
the two of you are just
hanging out in any moment.
Her boyfriend could walk in and you could
get the old fucking clattering to the
side of the fucking head. Uh, anyways,
so the first day I was there, she came
over to my house to hang out. Okay,
that's a, that's a red flag right there.
She's got a boyfriend. You come to town,
she immediately drops her boyfriend. It
comes to hang out with you. All right.
After a half hour of that
awkward catching up conversation,
we went up to my room to watch a movie.
Oh Jeez.
Once the movie started,
she made sure to drive home.
Uh,
the fact that I should make a move on
her because she's with someone else. Yes.
See right here, dude. She's playing
with your Dick. She slapping it around,
making it go up, and then
she's going, hey, hey, hey,
hey. We got to take it easy.
And then it goes back down again. She's
fucking with you. She's fucking with you.
She's playing the up and down game from
the Opie and Anthony Show with your Dick.
If you guys haven't seen that yet, I'm
telling you, look that up on Youtube,
the OPIOD,
Anthony up and down game.
It's one of the most genius bits of ever
seen. Fucking hilarious. Um, anyways,
I completely disregarded this. Oh, so she
tells you. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let me get,
let me go back here.
I really have to drop my commentary here.
Why don't we just read the rest here.
Um,
so the movie starts and she drives home
the point that they shouldn't. Yeah,
he shouldn't make a move on her because
she's, she is with somebody else.
So he says, I completely disregard this
and I put my arm around her anyways,
10 minutes into the movie,
you know what I respect that move. By
the way, 10 minutes into the movie,
we're in a full on cuddle and she's
doing that shit where she's running her
finger up and down my arm.
Then out of nowhere she flips around
and climbs on top of me with that.
Fuck me looking arise. Dude,
this is a great story. She even,
she's even doing that preset, slightly
heavy breathing dude, I'm not,
I haven't read this. I'm telling you
she's going to pull the emergency chute.
This is the Richard Pryor bit where they
went to your dick is hard enough to cut
diamonds, I believe is how
Richard put it. Or Mr Pryor.
Let me have some fucking respect here.
Saying Richard, like I know the guy. Um,
she drops in to start kissing me but stops
an inch from my mouth and stays there
for a second or two. Then she climbs
off and goes back to cuddling.
Uh, you know what dude, you're
young. You didn't know any better,
but if you are older, you,
you set yourself up for this.
After recollecting myself,
I started to say something,
but the second I started talking,
she flipped over and did it again.
But for a bit longer this time,
this time I asked her what the fuck
she was doing and she giggled. Cunt.
Yeah. Dude, right there,
man. This is the thing.
You got to take charge of the situation.
You got to tell you a dick to
stand down and be like, look,
either we're going to do this or
we're not going to do this. This is,
I actually think at that point you should
have just bounced around in there and
rubbed one out. That's the
power move right there, man.
That's the move that's going to make
you feel better than if even fucked her
because she's still going to get something
out of it. She got to get laid right.
So fuck that. You should have kicked
her out right there and just been like,
you know what? This was a bad idea.
Shut this off. You have to go.
You shouldn't be doing this. You have
a boyfriend. See, you flip it around.
You put the guilt on her. She leaves
you fucking rub one out. Right?
Then you don't give a shit that you didn't
bang her and then you fucking go out
to the local watering hole. You know,
you've got to run into some chick.
He went to fucking high school with
your little older, a little more manly.
You get the scruff going and you
fucking tag her and fuck this girl.
She is a con. She has a boyfriend. She
shouldn't be doing this shit. All right,
let's continue. Um, where the
hell was I? Uh, this time though,
she stayed, she did it for about
four full 30 seconds. Okay. So,
so we went back to cuddling for the
next five minutes until she did it for a
third time.
This time though,
she stayed there for about
30 seconds and she wouldn't,
and she would pull back
every time I actually
kissed her so that she
kept the inch between us.
Once she got off,
she started that giggling again,
which by then had gone from cute annoying
as hell and then slipped her shoes on
and said she had to go see,
don't,
if you took charge and one of those
you could have bounced her out.
We didn't hang out again after that.
And now I'm back in Miami.
I guess my question is what should I
have done? I guess I already answered it.
And what the fuck was she doing?
Any answer would be great.
Or even a rant about those annoying teas
and cons. Thanks. Well, you know what,
dude, I hadn't read this one. I
was a busy this week in my, uh,
the guy who helps me with my podcast,
we will remain nameless
because that's how I do it.
Sent me this thing and
I'm a little late today.
So what's the first time I read it? Um,
yeah, that's what she was doing. She just,
I don't know,
you'd almost have to ask a female to get
into the psychology of it, but I could,
I guess like I think
that, I don't know. Does,
does she want to just see that you
still want to fuck her and that, like,
I can tell you this right now that her
relationship with this other guy isn't
going to work and she has major
fucking not major. She's gay.
She's either really immature or eventually
she has major issues and she'll fuck
up every relationship
by doing shit like this.
And eventually she's going to be that
old hottie hanging out at the wine bar,
you know, with the crow's feet
around our eyes, you know,
you know that Szyk she'll just send me,
ended up being that girl and then we'll
look back in regret at all the good guys
that she fucking, Dick teased as she
was playing the fucking field. But um,
this is what you do in the future.
The second a girl is
doing some shit like that.
The second she said,
listen, just so you know,
I have a boyfriend, we can't be doing
this. You should have said, you know what?
You're right.
Let's not watch a movie
and right then you kick her out
so you have some sort of power.
All right?
And if you want to fuck a girl like that,
you should have been the one saying no.
You should have been the one
pushing her off. All right?
Because it sounds like she
has that fucking thing where
you know she gets off on
the fact that you want our
but can't have her. All right?
So if you're acting like you don't want
her, that fucks with her head like,
wait a minute,
what am I losing my pussy power?
And you just literally back
your way into the fucking boat.
Then you clubber over their
head and then there you go.
You got your fish in the boat.
All right? That's how you do that.
But I got to tell you in the future,
do chicks like data?
Just a complete fucking waste of time.
You're already banged her so you're
already dotted all the i's crossed all the
t's. What the fuck are you still
doing your there because it's an easy,
you thought it was an easy
fucking lay when you got back,
which is understandable.
Okay.
But the problem is is you don't
have your Dick and check you.
Dick is running your fucking life. You
got to make the decisions. All right?
And when you fucking do that, you
start winning those a lot more. See,
women have their pussies in check.
That's why they always win those
battles 90% of the fucking time.
So there you go.
That's the little information that
I can help you with what I see.
But like I said,
don't ever,
don't ever be afraid to fucking ask a
female for advice on stuff like that.
Not only will they give you advice,
they actually enjoy doing it and
they'll have way better advice than I do
because uh, you know, cause they were
fucking woman. You know what I mean?
It's like you calling me, you're asking
a plumber about fucking carpentry.
Go to a carpenter. All right. That is the
podcast for this week. I hope you guys,
uh, hope you guys enjoyed it.
Seemed like a fairly smooth
one. Right? Um, let, let me,
can I whore out some dates here? People,
can you hang with me this long enough?
Huh? Well maybe you're going to hang with
me cause you're on final approach. Oh,
you know what? I can't stand. This
is what happened me the other day.
I went out to go buy a my fucking water
cooler that I want to have just in case
of tsunami hits out here.
Cause I live on a fault line and I
always want to have at least five to 10
gallons of water.
You know,
I'm already inland enough with
the tsunamis not going to hit.
If a tsunami hits me here, I'm telling
you, Utah's in trouble. All right,
so I go to Lowe's hardware,
I go there online,
I look up to see if they have the
one that I want and that, you know,
and Lowe's has it.
So rather than just saying
they only have it online,
I'm assuming it's at the fucking store.
So I jumped in my car and I
drive over there and they,
they don't fucking have it. They don't
fucking have it. And it's just, you know,
just fucking drove me nuts.
So then I stop off at sporting good
store to buy a pump because my football
doesn't have any air in it.
And this is what you do at 42 when you
don't have any fucking kids, you know,
you actually, you, you're still acting
like you fucking 14. So I dunno,
I just had that moment when I went into
the sporting goods store. You know,
I hate when they can't fucking help me.
I'm asking a simple question and then
I start to flip out and then they just
call me sir a million
fucking times. You know, sir,
I'm sorry sir, but it
sure. Could you sure.
Could you please nudge sharing this
year please sir. Thank you sir.
That fucking shit. That's what
reminds me of, of flying on the plane.
If you do anything,
if you have your seat backs here,
could you please put your seat back
ups here. Thank you, sir. Sure.
In order to expedite this series
here. Could you please, sir,
I fucking hate that.
And I that,
that you know what I do then I
through gritted teeth, just say ma'am.
Back a hundred times. I'm sorry ma'am.
Yes ma'am. Thank you ma'am. Ma'Am,
could you stop Mami? Me
Man. You fucking cunt ma'am.
I'm sorry.
That's a little bit of fucking half an
ounce of rage I had to get out there.
Let me get back to hype and my dates
here. So anyways, this week, oh,
what a week I have, I'm going to be
at the record theater for two shows.
I believe the second show is already sold
out. So, uh, if you want to get tickets,
you better fucking hustle there.
Ah,
you fucking conscious the Goddamn
Internet work, not working in this room.
You know, I really need to
step my life up. I'm, I'm at
the record theater at this,
uh, this Friday, April 8th for two shows.
I believe they're like eight
and 10 are eight and 10 30.
I don't know what the fuck they are. Am
My God damn website won't come up. Um,
that's in, uh, Baltimore outside of
Baltimore, Maryland. And on Friday night,
I'm at the Tower Tower Theater
in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Later on this month, uh, I got two more
shows. One is in Milwaukee, Wisconsin,
April 22nd at the Pabst theater.
Um,
unbelievable response by the way.
I want to thank everybody
beforehand in Milwaukee.
Maybe that's why I had the Laverne
and Shirley Song in my head.
Isn't that where that show was based at?
Um,
and they also worked at a beer factory.
It's all coming full circle.
And on the 23rd, I'll be at the, uh,
Royal Oak Theater in
Detroit, Michigan. Um,
both of those dates are
selling unbelievably well.
Both of them are going to sell out,
so get your tickets as soon as you can.
And uh, I want to thank everybody
there for it. Like I've, I have not,
I've never played Milwaukee and I
have not played Detroit since I did.
Uh, the rich bitch tour, the
Chappelle show tour back in.
I think I did that.
And an o four I all I've done is I've
done like kickers and that type of stuff
outside of Detroit, Detroit, but
I haven't been in Detroit so, um,
I guess it's Royal Oak.
I have no idea.
And then the last one
is actually sold out.
It's a one of those antisocial comedy,
um,
comedy tour dates and that one is uh,
Jim Norton puts a tour together.
Jim Norton from a little Jimmy from the
opie and Anthony show best radio show
out there for my money.
Uh, Jim Norton, Jim Breuer,
David tell on myself are all doing a
comedy tour. We just added some dates.
We have a date in
Washington DC on May 13th.
We have one in June,
I believe it's at the Chicago theater.
These are all@antisocialcomedy.com.
Uh,
I believe that one is June
15th, I think. I don't know.
All of that is on antisocial comedy.com.
Just click on tour dates.
Those dates are all on sale. Um, you know,
please come down. Do you get you
get for comics for the price of one,
we're playing some of the most
beautiful venues in the country.
More dates are going to follow because
the turnout has been unbelievable.
Ticket sales have been fantastic.
So that's a podcast for this week.
Uh Oh real quick.
Jay Miller,
one of my favorite enforcers
of the Boston Bruins is in, uh,
is in the hospital
recovering from pneumonia.
Just want to send him a
get well soon wishes. Uh,
one of my favorites and a, we're
going to send a link, a youtube video.
We got some great youtube videos this
week. I almost forgot about those. Uh,
we're going to have one of Jay Miller
holding his own against the greatest of
all time for my money.
Bob Probert and a,
what are the youtube videos for this
week? Oh, we got some good ones.
I got one from that show. Cheaters. You
don't, let's show cheaters where they got,
you know, they basically, uh, somebody
thinks that somebody is cheating on him.
Then what do they do?
They get,
they hired this company and they start
spying on the boyfriend and girlfriend.
And when they confirmed that
they are in fact cheating,
they show up and confront them.
And this is one of the greatest ones I've
ever seen. They confront this kid at a,
at an ice rink after he just
played a hockey game. And you know,
usually the person who's cheating,
you know the dude is absolutely stunned.
This guy handles it absolutely perfectly.
He fucking breaks up with her. She
shows up. She's like, you know,
cause the chickies cheating with, is
that the ice rink? She says, yeah,
who the fuck is that? You know,
what the fuck are you doing here?
And he just goes, he just breaks
up with her right on the spot.
He's leaning on his stick, white
wipe, wiping the snow. I mean the,
the sweat off of his fucking nose.
He looks like a hockey player in
between periods going like, yeah,
we got to work on our for checking and
I hope we can get that goal back in the
second period he wasn't even sweating and
he just breaks up with her. She's like,
yeah, who the fuck is that?
What the fuck are you doing?
He just goes, he goes, yeah,
we're done.
What do you mean with done?
Just like dad. He goes, yeah,
it's over. She goes, that girl,
because the other girl was uglier.
She goes,
you're going to dump me for that girl.
And he goes, what can I say? She,
she does it right. I mean, he
didn't, he didn't give a fuck.
He was barely looking at her. He was
just sitting there leaning on his stick.
He wasn't nervous that there was cameras
there and he just fucking breaks up
with her and then his girlfriend
doesn't know what to do. She's so,
she ends up getting into a fistfight
with the chickies cheating on and he just
sort of walks away into the locker room.
It's fucking phenomenal.
Um, what else do we got?
We have some hippie chick trying to give
a presentation to a bunch of corporate
people. Uh, what the hell
are these youtube videos?
We got Paul Orndorff hyping the
Hulk Hulkamania workout thing.
That's one of my favorites.
And A, we got a couple others.
They're all going to be
up@thempodcast.com. And,
uh, like I stated earlier,
if you want to send
emails to this podcast,
uh, the new email address
is bill@themmpodcast.com.
Please keep them coming. You guys emails,
they get better each week. Uh, that's it.
You guys all have a great weekend.
Great weekend. A great week. All right.
I go fuck yourself.
I'll talk to you next week,
Huh?
Huh,
Yeah.
Huh?
Yeah,
no.