Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
just checking in on you.
How's it going?
As you can hopefully immediately tell,
especially after I just pushed
that button. I um, I forgot,
I didn't forget my recording equipment.
I'm having a problem
with one of the cords.
I can't tell if the cord got stepped
on and it's fucked up or the Jack to my
computer's messed up.
But I've learned in life to not force
things because you just make a bad
situation a little worse.
So I'm just kind of to record this
one like this and maybe Monday,
cause I'm on the road right now. I'm out
here in Nashville, Tennessee, Nashville,
Tennessee,
home with the Grand Ole Opry and that
fucking [inaudible] river that overflows
in the evil looking building downtown.
Other than that, wonderful people,
great food and all that type of shit.
Um,
I'm out here for one
day and one day on week.
I know you guys probably think,
well what the fuck bill,
you didn't advertise it on your goddamn
website. Are you doing a stand up show?
I am not,
what I am doing is a,
I'm doing a panel thing for
f is for family with uh,
the Great Mike Price.
Cocreator co creator of the show from
other Simpsons were doing like a live
thing where they show an episode and
then we answer some questions, um,
hosted by Russell Peters and
it's going to be on Xm Sirius.
I don't know what channel of course,
cause I'm a moron,
but that's basically what I'm doing here.
And then I go off to Calgary
tomorrow morning, Calgary,
Edmonton and then Seattle. So, oh,
I got some stories for you. I hope these
levels are okay. I did my best with them.
Um,
this was my plane ride out to Nashville,
so we wrote all day and then,
uh,
I took the red eye out and um,
okay.
The dude who sat next to me on
the fucking plane, God bless him,
but he's one of these guys, man,
if he doesn't turn it around,
he's not going to see 50 because
okay.
He was one of those guys who was
abusing his body so bad. Like, I can't,
like when I go go to guesses age,
it's going to, he was either like
26 to 28.
Yeah.
Or like 37.
I couldn't tell,
but he looked as old as me.
Uh,
he looked like he was, if he
was my age, you're like, dude,
you got like another two years because
if you fucking did that to yourself for
close to 48 years, you would be done
this fucking guy, man. Holy Shit.
He put on a display.
All right.
So you know it's late at
night and take them right.
I like I said 11:00 PM and I got
the aisle, he's got the window.
Right. And fortunately my
Sciatica is, is almost yeah,
but gone away.
And um,
I just been taking it easy and a,
it's just sort of naturally working
itself out while doing all the,
all the stretches and all that shit.
So anyways,
he's got the fucking window seat and
I'm thinking I'm being smarter than the
aisle thing because all right,
if I need to stretch I can just step out
into the island and won't have to step
over anybody. Um, cause I fucked
up. Last time I went to Saint Louis,
I flew southwest and I wasn't thinking,
I just went to the window seat
and then I was trapped, you know,
on the other side of two other people.
So this time I'm thinking I'm being smart,
but it turns out my back feels great and
now all I want to do was go to sleep in
this fucking guy. Man. Holy Shit.
This guy was like crushing
the fucking airport bar.
I don't know how many fucking
Jack and cokes this guy drank.
But he just kept going like the guy would,
he would just go,
can I get another one? And then the guy
would bring it over and he'd be like,
my dude, thank you freight.
Some reason he said my dude.
And then he would just be
sucking these sinks down.
And he was one of these fucking
guys that was so out of shape.
Like he snored while he was awake.
You know what I mean?
He did the noises this guide makes right.
So after about, I dunno, like fucking
five of these things. We're in the flight,
I'm starting to nod off.
He fucking goes to step over me.
Mountain of a man goes to step over me,
you know,
which course sort of wakes me up and
he goes into the bathroom and I noticed
he's wearing his socks.
Fucking animal.
This guy is like trying to kill himself
from all sides. You know what I made?
Death comes from the mouth, but he's
also trying to fucking speed it up.
Try to go into the express lane by
bringing a little in through the fucking
pores of the bottom of his feet.
People.
It's not your fault that
you weren't raised right,
but you got to look around in life.
Okay? You got to do the fucking math.
I almost think. What do you
think it's his grocer to?
To be in your bare feet or in your socks.
I know initially the bare
feet has worked worse,
but does something about the socks
just absorbing it and like, you know,
the next day if you put them on
again after you took a shower,
you still got the fucking shit and cause
it's going India feet no matter what.
One of the grossest things,
so the entire fucking flight,
this guy has just pounding Jack and cokes.
I mean he had,
he must've had like nine
of them on like a a,
I don't know how long that flight is
like four fucking hours and I'm trying to
sleep and I can't get to sleep because,
you know, he's a big guy. He's a cool guy.
He was trying to step over,
you know,
one point I did that Vietnamese
gamblers squat and he's like,
he goes, what are you doing? You praying
over there? You all right? And I said, no,
I got it. I got a Sattik nervous
unit. He goes, Oh man, that sucks.
So I couldn't get mad at him
cause he was friendly spot.
Every time he went to step over me,
he'd fucking wake me up and then I'd
look and he'd be going into the bathroom
just wearing his socks and it
just was driving me fucking nuts.
So finally, all I'm
thinking is going, my God,
when this fucking mountain
of a man goes down,
like he is going to snore like a,
I mean,
I've never had the displeasure of
sleeping next to Terry Saragossa,
whatever's Tony Serra Bussa but I imagined
he was going to sound like whatever
that guy sounds like at like two
o'clock in the fucking morning. Right.
But it was the weirdest
thing. He was snoring while
he was awake, but when he was,
when he went to sleep, he didn't
make a fucking sound. And uh, oh,
he kept dropping his fucking iPhone.
He had his shoes off and just the noises
he was trying to make to try to pick it
up. It's like, why the fuck would
you do to that? Do that to yourself,
these fucking people that treat
their own bodies like a rental car,
I just don't understand it. It's like
you can't return this fucking thing.
At the end of the weekend,
you got to keep,
this is the vessel that's going to
bring you around for your fucking life.
You know, I mean, I should talk the
way I fucking booze, but you know,
I still do my jumping jacks and I do a
couple of cartwheels to keep the stomach
down, you know. So anyways,
the flight fucking ends,
my travel is all fucked up
for whatever reason. And um,
I'm basically,
by the time they booked my hotel,
everything was sold out.
So I had a hotel for the night,
but I couldn't check in until three
in the afternoon. So I go, you know,
so they booked me at another
hotel and the person, you know,
the travel person goes, so you've got
to check in at this hotel, you know,
at five 30 in the morning and then check
out at 12 and then check in for the
other places. It is like at
3:00 PM it's like, is that cool?
And I'm like, no, it's not
cool. Like, do you ever travel?
Is that the way you set up your travel?
Do you want to switch hotels?
You know,
in the same fucking city you staying.
But I mean I don't have any choice,
so it's going to have to be cool.
So I fucking take a cab over there.
I get to the place that like fucking
five 30 in the morning. It's like planes,
trains and automobiles, right. I get there
and they're like, yeah, what's it under?
And I'm like, oh no. I'm like
bill burr. They're like, yeah,
see I'm like William, Eh rumple fucking
still scan. I may not get it right.
And the guy keeps going, I'm
sorry, I'm sorry. I'm like,
well I know it's not your fault.
So now it's like fucking five
and the God damn morning,
I got no place to stay.
And he goes,
well the bellhop can take you over
to the fucking waffle house. Right.
Sorry if I make Mike Noise here,
I to move this laptop around cause I
want you to fucking hear this thing.
So good. Yeah. I'm sorry if
a, you know, sorry about that.
So the fucking, so now it like
fucking five 20 in the morning.
I got no place to stay til three in
the afternoon. I'm fucking dead tired.
I couldn't sleep because all fatty cakes
over there was drinking the fucking, uh,
Jack and cokes all night,
stepping over on me with his fucking piss
and shit and fested soak socks and now
they don't have a room for me. And
now I'm to a waffle house. Right.
So I get to the fucking waffle house,
you know,
it fucking quarter to six in the morning,
half expecting to see Jay z finishing
the end of that song. You know,
it'll fucking thing go to the waffle house
and we're going to do it again or how
the fuck,
I guess he'd be walking out with them
right to banger and then kicked around at
seven. Well, Beyonce sings
lemonade in the background.
I don't know what the fuck it is,
those two do. I don't pretend to know.
I'm an old man anyways,
so I walk in there,
okay.
Bunch of fucking characters
and uh, um, bleary died.
I'm not even fucking hungry,
but I know I can't just sit in there like
some sort of vagrant soil, some eggs,
and a fucking waffle.
And I'm sitting there and this black
guy in there wearing a suit and he's,
he's like an anomaly. I don't
know. He sees a black guy,
but he isn't funny.
It's very rare.
It's like an obese Asian.
It's very rare that you see like obesity,
you know,
I don't know what food they eat over in
Asia, but I mean, whatever they're doing,
they're doing it right with all the
vegetables and the third fried, those,
those people are phenomenal.
Okay. And it was getting old,
right? Have you, once you,
it's very rare you meet a black guy wasn't
funny. This fucking guy is not funny.
Any,
won't shut the fuck up.
He keeps telling jokes and he's laughing
at his own fucking jokes and I just
want to, I want to stab myself
with my fucking waffle house.
Fucking fork.
So at one point he just won't shut up.
And then finally one of the
waitresses makes a joke. Well,
and the other way to see all
the way to goes, you know,
don't be walking up behind me. You
know, you don't want to, you know,
you don't want to basically fuck with
me. And then the lady goes, no, she goes,
I don't slight pregnant women
and she wasn't pregnant. Okay.
But admittedly it was a decent joke.
The unfunny black dude in the suit,
you know, high pitch left, stands
up, runs out of the waffle house,
goes up to the front and does like a
fucking three 60 turn and immediately the
fucking, you know, the road
weary comedian in me going like,
all right dude. It was funny. It
wasn't that fucking funny. And uh,
yeah,
he comes back in and then I didn't
know what the fuck they do. I'm like,
what the fuck am I going to do
with myself? I can't go to sleep.
Yeah.
My phone's running out of batteries.
I'm charging it there.
It was just a fucking nightmare. So,
uh, I just started calling hotels.
They're all fucking booked up. I don't
know what's going on here in Nashville.
If there's some sort of fucking Banjo
festival, I have no fucking idea.
But there's no way,
some Jesus Shit.
Okay.
You know, or some, you know,
democratic or Republican convention,
I have no fucking idea, but I cannot
get a room. So, you know, I'm like,
what do I do?
So I called in EOP and Jimmy show.
Yeah,
I talked to them for a minute and
then I was just like, what am I doing?
So I finally,
the cat and I just went over to the hotel
that I was supposed to be at and they
were like, and they were like, oh yeah,
you know, somebody called said, you know,
fucking last night if we could get you in,
unfortunately we can not blah blah blah,
blah blah.
So I at least check my bags,
you know,
I felt like a fucking homeless person
when I was in the waffle house with the
unfunny black dude.
And I had my fucking bags on the
inside of myself as I sat in the booth,
made the two fucking people, but
of sitting there by myself. Right.
So I get to the hotel,
at least checked in my bags and they had
a fucking like a couch in the lobby of
this place.
They go,
we're already cleaning a room and at
this point it's six 30 in the morning.
And I'm like, great. Whenever you
can get me in, if I got to pay extra,
I just don't give a shit. Right.
So they say fine. So I go over,
then I just lay down on the couch,
put my hat over my eyes,
and I just pass out.
I'm talking like I wasn't
even trying to be a gentleman.
I had both feet up on the fucking couch.
I was like,
this is my bed and I'm just sleeping
there and I just keep hearing people's,
they're getting waking up,
getting on with their day.
You want to get some smoke.
I heard they have such great
eggs and all this shit.
And then at one point this guy walked by,
you know,
it was fucking assholes who whistle a
fucking, you know, I think I tweeted,
nobody likes a whistler at some point.
This is fucking guy just came
by whistling, you know, just,
it's just some random song. It's not
even, it's not even a fucking song.
He's just whistling cause that's
what the fuck he does. Um,
and, uh, then I just completely,
I was just zonked out and then all of a
sudden I just feel somebody pushing me
once twice and I fucking wake up and then
they go, hey Mr up, your room's ready.
I'm like thinking, oh, thank God.
And I thought it was like seven 30 in
the morning. I looked, it was like 10,
15 if it's sleeping at like
a bum for like four hours.
So
I finally ended up getting
my fucking room and uh,
fortunately it was one of these
rooms that has the great curtains.
I was able to close them and it felt
like midnight and I'm then I just fucking
crashed,
woke up,
met some friends that I've met
along the way on the road and uh,
took a drum lesson.
Um,
I hate dropping names on this,
but like,
they're one of my favorite
bands out there right now.
Mute math is based out of here. And, uh,
I got some lunch and down king
actually gave me a little drum lesson.
I still stink,
but it was fucking like,
I was beyond geeking out
that I got to do it. So, um,
it was a bad day and I actually,
uh,
ended up turning it around and,
I'll tell you what's funny is if you
notice in the story, I never flipped up.
Bear with me. Watch your ears. I've
got to click and drag this thing over.
Just hang on a second. I
apologize. Here we go. Here we go.
It's almost over and it's over.
And I just realized I have no idea
how much time I'm doing here. The fuck
does this mean here for 47,
448,
448 one millimeters is just the
metric system where the Fox,
the timer.
How do I tell him much time I'm doing
all right. You just going
to have to fucking deal with
this. I apologize. Anyways,
um, I got this weird thing when like
major shit happens. Like I don't,
um, I don't flip out like
bigger shit like this.
I don't flip out little shit bugs me.
Like 20 minutes ago,
I'm going down in the elevator and we
just hit every fucking floor and every
fucking floor is another person coming
on a fucking full grown adult wearing
their name,
a name tag around their neck,
like it's their first day of preschool
and everybody knows everybody. Hey Carl,
like the shorts,
you're wearing those to the meeting.
It crazy right down one more floor.
Every fucking floor.
It's getting more and more packed.
And then I have
to sit there and listen to office
humor, right? I'll tell you right now,
if you think every once in a while,
a random black dude in a suit
in a waffle house isn't funny.
Wait till you're in a crowded elevator
with a bunch of people that sit in
cubicles all day.
They had their fucking name tags around
the neck listening to their jokes for
eight fucking floors that I like. I was,
by the time I got to the third floor,
I was fucking livid.
I was so fucking angry that the
people around me could sense it,
that when I went to get off the elevator,
even women got out of the way.
So I'm not proud of that.
Which you would think I would
have flipped out at at the big,
don't stepping over me or I
would've thought this anyways,
or I would have flipped out when my room
wasn't ready. I would have flipped out.
You know, even when I sent the
text message to my travel person,
I didn't curse. I didn't say
that they fucked it up. I
know somebody fucked it up.
But I've learned in the past to not just
slice the head off of the first person.
I just went very like, you know,
I don't know what happened,
but this is not acceptable. People
knew I was coming here for two months.
I don't understand. I've never had this
problem before. This can happen again.
I am now on my way to a waffle house at
five 21 in the morning with all of my
bags and I just, you know what, what else
do you need the fucking second? Right. So
anyways, it all ended up working out. And,
uh, I got some great food out here and,
uh, I ended up running into one
of the cast members of Nashville,
which is my wife's favorite fucking show,
unfortunately.
Just got canceled and I ran into the guy,
Charles Ashton,
and he was the coolest fucking guy am I
was like, oh my God, my wife loves you.
Show is there any way I could get a
picture? And he goes, no, put it on video.
He goes, watch this. He
goes, you do the intro.
He was so fucking cool. So I just was
like, Hey, yeah. Well, I'm in Nashville.
I ran into one of the
locals and then it turns in,
it's his face and he just goes, Hey
Dan, thanks for watching the show.
She freaked out and I got some good
points, so thank you to Charles.
Make it my fucking, uh, making my
married life a little easier. So a,
so they go, I don't know how much time
that took up. According to a garage band,
I'm at 540 something.
Yeah,
540 fucking of these.
Okay.
Oh, they count in the little
things was at 540 seconds.
Okay.
My really supposed to do that math
had I have I not done 10 minutes yet.
600 seconds is 10 minutes.
Oh Jesus.
I don't even know what I'm
talking about. This point. Sorry.
I got to click on this thing here,
which is not, let me do it. All right,
here we go. A little, a little advertising
here. Alright, ZipRecruiter, everybody.
Okay.
Are you hiring? Do you know where to post
your job to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your job on all
the top job sites and now you can.
Next, please mention the talking points
below. Well, why would not you wrote them?
I'm going to read them.
Yeah.
With ziprecruiter.com you can post
your job to 100 plus job sites,
including social media network
networks like Facebook and Twitter,
all with a single click. Find candidates
in any city or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your qualified
candidates roll into ZipRecruiter's.
Easy to use interface,
no juggling emails or calls to your
office quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
Find out today why ZipRecruiter has
been used by over 800,000 businesses and
right now my listeners can try
ZipRecruiter for free by going to
ziprecruiter.com/burr that's
ziprecruiter.com/burr hey
ziprecruiter.com/birth
all right track or a smart cash.
My phone's smart homes technology has
made everything like wicked smack do.
But losing your stuff still makes
smart people feel really stupid.
These wicked stupid tracker
makes losing things.
A thing of the past tracker is a coin
size device device that locates misplaced
keys, wallets, bags,
computers, anything in seconds,
just paired tracker to use my phone,
attach it to anything and find its precise
location. With the tap of a button.
It's that easy.
Lose your phone,
press the button on track and your
phone rings when it's on silence.
Silence Lit.
Sorry.
With a 1.5 million devices tracker has
the largest crowd gps network in the
world. So your last item shows up
on a map. Even if it's miles away,
never lose anything.
Again with tracker listeners to this show,
get a special discount of
30% off your entire order.
Go to the spelled t,
h e t r a C K e r.com the
tracker.com enter the Promo code bar.
The hardest thing you'll ever have to
find is their website. Go to tracker,
the tracker.com right now and
enter your Promo code birth for
for 30% off your entire order.
Again, hey, that's the tracker,
the tracker.com Promo Code Bar and lastly,
but hopefully not allocate.
Lastly, but not least. All right,
boil and branch. Oh, sorry.
Ball branch.
Okay.
I don't know what the feel.
L L N branch. All right.
As you set out to improve yourself,
there is one simple thing you can do every
day to help you be in your best to be
your best in every situation.
That's getting a good night's sleep,
but Jesus Christ,
Lord knows I never do that.
Ball in branch delivers the rest you need
wrapped up in their super comfortable
luxury linens and they do it right.
The first bedding company
to be fair trade certified,
which means that your sheets come
from the work of happy hands,
not crying children in sweatshops in
beautiful packaging made entirely from
recycled and sustainable materials. You
can only get their sheets in one place.
That's Boll and brand.com where you
know you're paying for quality and not
department store overhead.
You're getting thousand dollars sheets
for just a couple of hundred bucks.
Go to ball,
that's B o l l and branch.com and
they'll let you let you try them.
Risk free for 30 days. If you don't
love him, you can send them back.
You have nothing to lose
and it gets even better.
Go to ball and branch stock comp today
for 20% off your entire order sheets,
towels,
blankets,
do VA covers everything plus free
shipping and all their products come
beautifully packaged in
their signature boxes.
Go to ball and branch.com today for
20% off your entire order and use Promo
code, Burr ball and branch.com
Promo Code Burn. And mercifully,
that's the end.
Hey,
I've got to ask you guys a question here
and I apologize for all the extraneous
fucking noise,
if that's the right word here.
MMM.
I went into the, uh, the drug
store out here because I forgot my,
a leaf to kelp to help
my inflame Sciatica here.
And um,
okay.
Sciatic nerve I should say.
And um,
okay,
I went in there and this,
this campaign,
that red nose fucking fun thing,
whatever. And it's all these,
okay.
It's some sort of charity and
it's all these fucking people.
Famous people wearing the red nose.
So I'm going, what the, what is this?
I keep seeing this.
So I start reading the box and it says
Walgreens will donate 100% of everything
that they gain,
collect or whatever to this red nose camp,
red nose fund.
100% is going to this red nose fund.
So I'm like, all right, what
is it? What is the fund?
Nowhere on the box.
Will it say what the fuck it is?
It doesn't say what it's raising
money for. Nowhere on the box.
So I asked the lady behind the counter
and it goes, so what is this for?
If I buy one of these red noses,
what is this for? She goes, Oh,
you get one of these?
And it was like a little fucking gift
certificate off of fucking chapstick or
something. I go, no, no, no,
no. I, I don't like what I
get. If I buy a red nose,
like, where does the money go? Who am I
helping out? She goes, oh, I don't know.
It's like my first day. And I
just laughed. I was like, well,
I'm going to just start the fucking green
hat fun and everything's going to go
to me. She sorta like,
I guess half ass left.
I should have told it to the black guy
in the suit and the fucking waffle house
he would have ran out of the place then
15 cart wheels and come back in. Don't,
it's not that funny. Um, I'm
telling you, man, that's the new,
I'm not saying the red nose thing is a
scam, but it's pretty fucking shifty,
pretty shady than I'm sitting there
looking at all these celebrities and it's
just the red nose fund and there's
nothing on there. Same way the money goes,
you know,
is it,
shouldn't that red nose thing bring
up a couple of red flags there? Um,
I think that that's the new,
there's two new things going on in this
country that are actually generating
income for people.
The legal selling of weed
at the state level and um,
nonprofits.
Okay.
Nonprofit is like the new hardware store.
Like back in the day you had to
open a store and actually sell shit.
And nowadays you can just start
fucking come up with a mirror,
a mirror,
not a ribbon of fucking wristband,
a red fucking nose have people dump
ice water over their fucking head,
whatever it is. You know,
some of them are legit.
I got this fail and most of them aren't.
And I kind of feel like,
okay,
if you're old like me,
and you remember the late eighties when
all those televangelists were on TV and
they went to like this national fucking
level and they just made hundreds of
millions of dollars before it all just
came out that it was just this giant
fucking cash grab.
I feel like all those fucking nonprofits,
it has to be going in that direction
and how all these sports, uh,
sports leagues get in bed with
all of these fucking people. Um,
okay.
I Dunno,
maybe they have enough money.
Maybe you have enough money to keep it
silent. But, uh, I dunno. I'm Kinda done.
I give money to saint Jude's hospital.
That's it. Everything else. I just, I,
I don't have the fucking time to figure
out whether or not you're a fucking scam
or not because I gave to that
wounded warrior shit. I gave so many,
I gave so much fucking money.
I used to donate like 10% of the Shit I
made in the advertising to those fucking
people.
And then people started sending me these,
these articles and the
next thing you know,
they get investigated and all that type
of shit. And I don't even know. I didn't,
I just stopped following the story and
I just stopped giving him money because,
okay.
I don't, I don't know. I don't
know if it's true or not.
I don't even fucking want to know.
But like,
I just feel like the future of helping
people out is literally walking up to a
wounded warrior, like finding out
where the fuck they live and be like,
what do you need?
Go out and get it.
Or you raise the money and then you
give it to them. But then if I raise it,
then do I become one of
those people and be like, oh,
we have a little bit of overhead and all
of a sudden I have some sick ass drum
room and I just bring a fucking box
of bandaids to a fucking veteran.
I mean, that's what seems what
all these, I don't know. I'm,
I'm a cynical son of a bitch, but
my new shit is I want to just, um,
I, I still love doing charities.
I love doing benefits.
I did one the other night for like a
fucking, it was for like a private school.
It's like, it's a fucking private
school. Like you guys don't need money.
It's like, oh, it's for the people
who can't afford it. It's like, is it,
who knows what it is?
You just saying what it is and then what?
Then all of a sudden they, yeah. Who
gets the money? Where does it go?
Where does that person go? Or they in
Tahiti. Are they helping somebody out?
Nobody fucking knows. It's
brilliant. It's fucking brilliant.
I hope that red nose things
is on the label is on the
labels on the level. Sorry,
I didn't get a good night's sleep.
You know those hotel couches are,
and what they fucking used to be there.
MMM.
I honestly have no,
no idea how much time I've done here.
I'm up til like 838 of these seconds here.
I'm just going to say this seconds.
Right.
Well, let's see if there's
600 seconds in 10 minutes.
Yeah.
So that means that'd be 1800 seconds
and a half. That has no fucking way.
That's only a second.
What if it's two seconds?
I gotta be coming up. I'm
going to say it's two seconds.
Fuck it. It's two seconds.
So all you gotta do is just make it up
to 900 and I got another 49 to go. Oh,
it's fucking easy. Let's talk a
little playoff hockey. Everybody.
Anybody watched ya? I keep missing just
to how busy I am. I keep missing, um,
that uh, that Tampa Bay Pittsburgh
series, I caught the end of a,
a game three with the penguins were up
and then the game a couple of right,
their threads
to put it out of reach.
And I fucking sense a buddy
of mine in Pittsburgh,
a text congratulating them because as
much as I don't like what the penguins
cheap shot artists have done
to the Bruins, uh, you know,
I don't take it to the level that I
don't want my friends teams to win.
So I said congratulations.
And the second I sent that Tampa Bay
scored one and I felt like I jinxed them
for half a second. But, um,
I've been watching the blues
and in San Jose Shacks and uh,
this is fucking huge tonight
for the blues because San Jose obviously
adjust it to whatever the fuck the
blues we're doing and gain one.
And uh,
so now blues have to adjust to whatever
San Jose was doing it because San Jose
Pretty,
uh,
dominated pretty much wire
to wire the last game.
And uh,
I dunno if it's making me nervous as a,
as a total bandwagon blues fan.
They obviously got a witness.
Well that's such a stupid thing to say.
It was a busy, it's just one, a big one.
Bill. Should they not go down three
games to one? You fucking dope. Um,
big shout out to all the soccer fans
over there in Europe that got so fucking
annoyed at everything that I
said that I shouldn't talk about
about uh, um, sports over in Europe.
You guys all make a great point because
I don't watch them and I don't know
anything about them.
But uh,
what you fail to understand is how
much I enjoy irritating the shit out of
people that I'd never met before.
So I stand by. What the fuck?
I said you guys should have some
sort of in the premier league,
you should have a fucking play off play
off the fact that somebody can win a
fucking championship because another team
came to like a tie and like that's it.
Just imagine
every fucking movie about soccer is
always, there's the big fucking game,
right? And then somebody
comes down and scores a goal.
It's not like the stars of the movie
standing around waiting for somebody to
fucking, you know, have a
one, one ty was somebody.
Is this sitting there and fucking street
clothes or sitting in an apartment
doing jello shots with each other.
Okay.
I don't know. I'm just
fucking with you. I know.
Remember that's the best of
Solo movie victory ended them
okay
with them walking away from the game.
Oh No, no. They were going to do it.
They wanted to escape and then they came
back because they wanted to beat the
guys.
Okay.
And if that was actually
based on anything real, um,
the game would have ended
and then they would have won.
They would have been brought back to
the prison camp and they would of been
beaten to death.
But instead what ended up happening was
they came back and they beat the Nazis,
these prisoners allied prisoners of
or,
and then they fucking,
uh,
they just walked out with the crowd
that's stored under the field and gave him
extra clothes and shit.
MMM.
I Dunno. I'm sure it was based
on a true story, but, uh,
I've seen enough of the Germans and their
respect for life outside of their own
country.
Um,
for people
who are non German, I think that they
would have just opened up on the crowd.
So I'm calling bullshit. That movie was
called victory, by the way, by the way.
It wasn't
great. It was, I actually
really enjoyed that movie,
but it was when I first got
cable. So who knows. Um,
anyways, is that, is that a half hour?
I'm up to 962 seconds or a 1800.
I have no fucking idea.
You know what I'm going to find out
here because I'm going to have to do the
Monday morning podcasts
like this one also. And uh,
my timing will be a little bit better
on the next one cause I'll know exactly
how much time I'm doing. I just don't
understand why this would fucking thing.
Wouldn't tell me how much time, but I'm
not gonna start hitting buttons going,
it's going to be irritating to you
if you listen to it on a fucking with
headphones.
So anyways, that's it for the
Thursday afternoon podcast.
Just checking in on you.
Hope you can't have a great and
a his little bit of music and uh,
enjoy the a clips from a
podcasts from years gone ball.
Yeah.
And of course like,
Hey, where there it is.
Hey, what's going on? It's built bar.
It's the Monday morning podcast and uh,
eight gloomy,
rainy,
depressing Monday morning
here in Los Angeles.
Um, probably days or extra
depressing out here because,
uh,
it's usually sunny and it's
what you expect out here. See,
look, I'm going to go into
a Karen Carpenter songs,
rainy days and monitored. Oh,
Kathy down.
Really?
Is that a reason to stop eating?
I don't think it is. Wow.
Wow. I just started off real means did I
well, well shit. Well, who gives a fuck?
It's a gloomy Monday and uh, I attack
a dead anorexic. How do you like that?
That's how I started the Monday
morning podcast. So there you go.
If you're new to my page, um, I do one
of these, um, every Monday morning,
can I say Monday? Oh, did I say run day?
Every Monday morning I do a podcast and a,
evidently I attack some,
uh,
defenseless dead person. That's how
I started off. Only if it's overcast.
If it was sunny, it would have, I
would have a completely different vibe.
But basically I do of these every Monday
and I answer questions that some of my
14 listeners send in. Um, lately
I've been giving out advice.
People have been asking me advice
and sometimes I ask questions and,
uh, hopefully in the end of
it, nobody learns anything.
And you know you've wasted 15 minutes of
your life. That's what I'm trying to do.
And speaking of wasting
15 minutes of your life,
I am actually sitting in my apartment,
my little villa,
and really made me sound like
they had a pool. Boy, it didn't.
My little villa here and I'm
waiting for a plumber and you know,
I don't want to judge the
guy cause I never met him.
But this motherfucker guy was supposed
to be here at nine o'clock in the goddamn
morning.
All right?
It's two minutes past the
hour of 10 o'clock now I
don't know what time zone you
live in, what world you're in, but
in my little neck of the woods,
10 oh two. Now it's 10 oh three.
It just turned on my cable box.
It's fucking 10 oh three 10 or three
is not nine o'clock and God damn it,
I want some answers.
Unburied a ball my hand up into a fist
and fucking pounded on my coffee table
like, uh, like some like that
guy in the Spiderman comic books.
Who's, who's the guy at the
daily planet? Jamieson. Huh?
With his fucking, it's such a
weird way of going gray. Didn't he?
Just the side of his head turned white
all the way around and then on top it was
jet black and he'd always be chomping
on a fucking cigar. You know, just,
I don't want to tack Stan Lee, but you
know, it's really, you know, I got it.
He's the boss. All right. What am I
doing? Okay. All right, let, let's,
let's fucking get back to this. Let's
get down to brass tacks here. Okay.
Why am I waiting for a plumber?
I'll tell you why I'm late for a
plumber because for some reason my sink,
when the water comes out lately,
it's smells like swamp ass.
Um,
I don't know what it is.
There's definitely a funk coming onto
my sink and it's not coming out of the
kitchen sink. So I've ruled out
some sort of outside sources,
obviously, you know, cause it was coming
from the street, the main water line,
I think every,
it'd be fucking everything.
It'd be coming out of
everything right now.
Do I have any plumber listeners out
there? You know, can you help me out?
Because evidently this
fuck is not showing up.
It's 10 oh four and he's still not here.
See,
this is why the United States of America
is starting to lag behind China and all
of them I've had in China,
when you call a plumber,
48 of them show up at fucking eight 58
begging. You don't need to have a wrench.
You know what I mean?
Somebody just fucking bites down the
pipe and three other guys just start
spinning the guy around, you
know, but not in America.
I got away for this
motherfucker to show up.
I'll tell you what sucks too is I don't
know if they act stupid, but it just,
that, that, that makes it hurt even more
is when they can't figure
out how to fix a sink.
And then some guy comes up more
mobile boom pole, you know,
with his fucking ass hanging out,
he knows how to fix it.
That's why I've started to become handy.
Okay.
Because I actually sat down and I
analyzed it the other day and you know,
fixing a sink is not a gift.
You know what I'm saying?
It's a skill. It's something you
learned. Does inventing this sink.
Okay. Or the toilet
like that. That guy, uh,
Eddie crapper but whatever
his fucking name was,
I know is his last name was
crapper. Okay. Because of him,
we don't have to shit outside.
And what's what banks does he get his
last name becomes slang for taking a dump.
Tell me he didn't die. A bitter
rich man. Jesus Christ. You know,
some people man, it's just
these, you know, they, they,
they do such good and what
do they get out of it? Huh?
Jesus Christ.
I mean,
I bet you and your last name was crapper
to every female in that family could
not wait to get married and just get
away from that Goddamn last name. I mean,
they probably took the first
thing that came down the pike.
That'd be a great thing to Google and go
check out the amount of women with the
last name crapper that married the first
trucker that fucking fingered him on a
fucking Tuesday night.
Jesus Christ.
Just cause they were shameful of them.
Their maiden name,
which probably led to some sort
of child abuse and alcoholism.
And that's probably another reason why
it's 10 oh six in the fucking plumber
still isn't here. I really hope he
shows up halfway through this. Okay.
Cause you guys have watched me give
this guy a piece in my fucking mind.
Then I won't curse either. So we can't
leave. What is he doing? What's he doing?
Huh? He drive and you know he's
got a van. Drew. You know if,
if you're a carpenter you got to pick
up. If you're, if you're a plumber,
you got a van,
you know,
because in case it rains you can't have
it go on the pipes and they get all
rusted. I don't know why. What,
what is he doing as he is the army
navy store buying some more Dickies,
you know, what do they trade their
underwear for? Their Dickies.
So they're fucking crack of their
ass hanging out. 10 Oh seven okay.
Anyways, yeah. So that's the
deal I started, I started
to learn how to fix shit.
Okay. I fix the leaky faucet the
other day, which is unbelievably easy.
But it makes no goddamn sense.
You fucking take the handle
off and there's this,
this little rubber stopper with this
spring in there and that's all it is.
You take it out and you
stick the mother fucker back,
pick a new one in there and magically
it stops leaking. I don't get,
it's not like it's in the pipe.
I have no idea why it works,
but it works.
And I went on the Internet within three
seconds I learned how to do it. Okay.
My ass wasn't hanging out in the back
of my pants and I didn't charge somebody
fucking $200 and I was on time.
Damn motherfucker. Okay. So anyways,
I do one of these things every single
week and people ask me questions and I
hype upcoming gigs,
like the fact that I'm doing a,
B and a this week I'm going
to be at out of the same,
he's in Chicago and uh,
it's actually downtown Chicago on the
14th and 15th on the 16th I'll be in,
in Saint Charles and on the 17th
I'll be in Vernon hills, Illinois.
And I got to tell you something I really,
really enjoyed doing
this Gig at, especially the
downtown Chicago, this nice small,
and I mean it looks like a walk in closet.
The place is so small and uh,
I dunno man.
It's like an old school comedy club
and all these old comedy photos,
they just left them up for like two.
I'll take a fucking museum.
I loved the place and I always
have great shows there. So,
and I'm going to the cubs game on the
15th Beignet be like my third or fourth
time going to Wrigley field,
you know.
And here I am pitching about a plumber.
I really ought to count my blessings here.
Going to a fucking cubs game this week.
Okay. And continuing on, on the 29th,
May 29th through June 1st I'm making
my triumphant return to New York City,
Caroline's comedy club. Uh,
I got a whole brand new,
our last time I was out
there. I take my, uh,
my one hour comedy special,
which I have information about that
I will be giving out later on in this
podcast. Uh, look at me. Look
at me. Teasing it a little bit.
Making you stick around. Huh? Don't roll
your eyes at me. I know what I'm doing.
I'm playing the fucking game.
Uh,
let's see what else we got here and then
you go into June and I actually forgot
about this date. I thought I had a couple,
a couple of weeks off after Caroline's,
but evidently not. I'm going right
back out to Raleigh, North Carolina.
Good night's comedy club. How to
fuck did I have a date there, man?
I'm turning 40 on the 10th.
I planned on coming home on the second,
getting into the fetal position,
doing some crunches
and not eating any carbs until June
10th when I turned 40 goddamn years old.
But now I have to fly across this country
and go to Raleigh, North Carolina.
The desolate, the frightening
Raleigh, North Carolina.
The what the fuck happened to
the downtown area that, you know,
it's a beautiful part of the, this,
the of the state during the day.
Raleigh, North Carolina downtown. I'm
not talking about NC state, NC state,
that that place is nice.
I actually went there for two semesters
in 87 88 and if you want to know why,
I only went there for two semesters,
go online and Google Bill Burrs,
fucking NC state,
uh,
fucking transcript and you'll
figure out why I left after that.
But the downtown area, that's one
of those downtowns where, you know,
he would tell at some point in the past,
the history. It was, it was a place,
it was hopping, it was jumping. They'll
make a narrow moonshine down there. Right.
And then you know what happened? You know
what? I bet the Wa the dreaded Walmart.
That's what happened. They built a
Walmart. Then they, then they made a mall,
the Crabtree mall. Is that what you
guys go and the whole downtown area?
Just,
it's a fucking ghost town.
Past six oh one in the evening and
I'm just left down there by myself,
downtown in the fucking hotel. I
hate it. I need people around me.
I'm a city person.
Goddamn people all fucking leave.
And then I'm down there and I got to go
out and hail a cab and all that stuff is
just homeless people. It's like that
fucking, what did that movie, 28 days.
That's what I feel like I'm in.
I'm feeling I'm in a Zombie movie.
If you work in downtown Raleigh and
you're going to go to one of my shows,
why don't you hang out at work?
Just work and go straight to the clubs.
So when I walk out to get a cab,
I can actually see another fucking human
being that looks like they don't have
hepatitis. All right. And uh,
the next Gig I have coming up is June
19th through the 21st I'm going to be at
the punchline in Atlanta.
Uh,
that's another one of my favorite
comedy clubs that Xannies Caroline,
good nights punchline in Atlanta.
I like all of those clubs.
I like all of them. They're just
good clubs, good, clean fun.
And I'm going to come in there with my
potty mouth June 19th through the 21st
and uh, I dunno, I've been
to Atlanta a lot lately,
so I'm hoping I'm going to start
to build a following out there.
I always seem to get a good turnout and
I got a whole nother new hour for you.
You sons of bitches.
And
then after that you guys, you're
on your own. Just go to my website.
You can click on it right there. If you're
looking at my myspace page, I manage.
I imagine most of you are
secretly listening to this
and your cubicle and you've
probably reduced the window.
Is that what you did?
And now you sitting there looking at
what do you look at it in a cubicle? Huh?
What are you looking at? A spreadsheet,
some sort of counting thing with,
with assets and liabilities and you're
rubbing your chin as if you're not
listening to me. Well
that's good. You know what?
I think that's a good thing you know you
should do today is take a magnet runner
right down in the back of your
bosses hardware, not as hardware,
his fucking hard drive.
That's what you do.
And if he walks into the office right
in the middle of you doing that,
what you do is you smile.
They've open smile,
which causes his defense is to go down.
And then you fling that magnet at him
like a fucking Chinese star and you hit
him right in the forehead. Now the great
thing about knocking somebody out is, um,
as far as I know, as far as my
experience with getting knocked out,
is you forget the previous three minutes.
So as long as you fire that puck and
magnet at him before the three minutes are
up, he won't even remember
what happened. But the key is,
is to do it in a manner before
he can be like, you know,
yell your name and say, what are
you doing in this office? You know,
Jennifer fucking, whatever.
I'm so bad at coming up with
God. Dammit, Jennifer,
we'll go with Sullivan
[inaudible] fucking basic name.
That's why I can't write scripts.
These stories are always good.
But my fucking name, you know
the hero's name, Joe Smith.
William the worst. Um, it's,
I can have a commit crime.
Never could come up with a good
alias. What's your name? Bob.
Bob Was Avenue.
All right.
Robert, why did she get in the back of the
fucking car? Man, I didn't do anything.
All right, let's get on to the,
uh, have I ever been arrested? Yes.
Yes I have. Yes, I have. I innocent
arrested, drinking and driving,
uh,
back in December of 1989 and if
you'd like to hear more of the story,
tune in next week, um, I'll wait a
minute. What did I say? Oh, I know.
That's right. I'm going to tell you
guys when my DVD is coming out. Uh,
but first we're going
to answer some of the,
some of the questions that
people have asked me. Um,
here's a question I might've
answered it before. Okay.
Podcast question number
one. A. This is how many,
I have actually went into some old emails
and I found a bunch of other ones so
that I didn't get to. So who knows.
Here we go. Question one eight bill,
have you ever thought about going
to Iraq to entertain the military?
I served in the Gulf War and we liked
having entertainers. Come see us.
If you have a few have already gone.
What was it like for you?
You would fucking kill? Um, no I have not.
I have not gone over there for the simple
and the only way I would go over there
is if I went through six weeks
of boot camp first like you did.
And you know, they gave, they taught
me how to fucking kill somebody.
You know what I'm saying?
That's like not knowing how to swim
and then doing a fucking, you know,
entertain some people on a tugboat during,
during choppy water.
You know what I mean? That to be honest
with you, I would love to go to Iraq,
but I'd love to go over there.
And when it was fucking peaceful and
experienced the culture over there when
there are no insurgence and yeah,
that's thing, you know what I mean?
I know they fly into the fucking base
and I'm surrounded by a bunch of marines
and that type of shit.
But you know,
I just watched too many will Smith
movies where he's the only guy left and I
don't know how to fire
a gun. So, uh, you know,
I don't have that kind of boss
like Bob Hope would go, you know,
he went all over Vietnam with like
a fucking golf bag and umbrella.
I guess he never died. Right.
Maybe that should be, uh,
you know, but you know what?
Chaos theory, I don't think he'd get
killed on the base, but you know,
I'd be one of those guys.
Yeah. Fucking, you know,
the plane I was in would get shot and
some of everyone in the plane would
survive, but I fall out the
bottom through the damn book.
I'll entertain the troops. Okay.
I've done it a bunch of times,
but I've done it over here. I don't,
I don't do away games. I'm like,
Roger Clemens when he played for
the Astros. Okay, I'm on steroids.
I'm cheating on my wife and I
don't fucking pitch in Iraq.
I'll be honest with you, I'm terrified
to go over there. There you go. Okay.
That's why you were fucking marine and
I'm a civilian and I respect you and uh,
you know, I'll fucking, uh, you could
listen to these podcasts and Iraq,
you know what I mean? What am I,
what am I fucking, Chuck Norris
doesn't mean getting all defensive
because I don't have the balls to go,
but yeah, that's basically it. Yeah.
I don't want to go over there and then
somehow get kidnapped and end up being,
you know, rocking back and forth gently
in an orange jumpsuit is there, you know,
is there reading shit about our lot and
then they saw my fucking head off and
I'm really sitting there going like, you
know what, why, why did I come over here?
Um, okay, moving on. Question number one.
That was one a. Okay. Uh,
did you do a voice on grand theft
auto four. There was a biker dude,
that sounds just like you. If it
wasn't you, you got to check it out.
Actually yes I did.
I did do a voiceover on that and it was
a big thrill to do that and I got to
give a big thanks to uh,
to Laszlo for hooking me up and uh,
Jimmy Norton for hooking me
up with the OPN Anthony show.
Cause that's how I met Laszlo. And then
I got in there to do the boys over.
Um, see how that works.
Uh, question number two,
I noticed you have Strikeforce
MMA in your top friends.
I was wondering who are a couple
of your favorite MMA fighters? Um,
that's just a friend I accepted and then
I guess they switched their picture.
Mixed martial arts. Um, I dunno,
I do watch the, I I watch,
uh, what do I watch? I
watch the UFC fights.
I watch,
I watched their reality show,
which of course I can't remember the
name of the ultimate fighter this,
this season where they have to fight
their way just to get into the house.
And uh,
what the fuck's his name there?
The junk yard dog. I'm getting them
fucking confused with old time wrestlers.
Who's the guy who knocked out chuck light?
Dell,
the fucking guy who goes out and
then kicks the shit out of you.
Where's the chain and Shit,
you know, beats the fuck out
of people. Randy Jackson.
Yeah. And then the other guy with the
fucking, you don't want to fuck with me.
Cauliflower ears.
You know,
actually have a theory that if you just
say you don't even need to get the black
belt.
If you just have some somebody's box
your ears and you get those cauliflower
ears,
no one's going to fuck with you in a bar
because they just look at those fucked
up ears, those exploded vegetable
ears and they're just like,
that guy could fucking snap my neck.
Choke me out and give me the superman
punch with a flying knee all at the same
fucking time. I even answer the question.
Who are some of my favorite ones?
Uh, I liked Matt Serra. I
love the shit he talked about.
Uh,
and what's his face was Saint Pierre.
That's the kind of shape
I would like to be in
for my 40th birthday that evidently I'll
be contemplating in downtown Raleigh,
North Carolina. All right. You know what,
this podcast is starting to seem long,
so when we let me blow through these
next fucking questions. All right.
Number three,
Bill,
did you hook up with any
of the stewardesses at the
airport from last week's
podcast? Oh yeah. I hooked up
with all three of them and they,
we had a fucking foursome right
out in the open, you know,
and that didn't violate any new
fucking Patriot Act. Now I didn't.
And um, thanks for bringing
that up. Okay. I don't know.
I was going to go off
and say what's up to him,
but there was something about
their blue panty hose that just,
I really found it intimidating.
Question number four. I was wondering,
since you're such a big, such a, a
bug sports fan, a big sports fan,
what is your best sports
memory from your childhood?
Um, well fuck that. Let's go
with something funnier then. Uh,
how about, uh, he, his
my best, my best? Fuck,
he's a good sports memory. When the, uh,
when the New England Patriots beat the,
the Los Angeles Raiders,
um,
what was it, 1985 the year we get,
we get destroyed in the Superbowl.
We were a wildcard. And, uh,
that's what we beat the jets.
And then the next week we'd beat, look
at me with a memory, beat the jets,
and then we'd beat the Raiders.
And I went down to the,
the airport in Providence,
Rhode Island and a,
it was like me and like
only 70 other people at this
point, you know, and we met,
have all the players as they got off
the plane, all the old school guys,
Julius Adams,
I remember somebody reaching over and
slamming him really hard on his shoulder,
like hitting them way too hard.
And he fucking looked at me like I did it.
And I was like, oh, I went to the mayor.
It was the guy behind me. But, uh,
that was the first time I saw a
bunch of athletes up close. Uh,
Tony Easten completely expressionless.
I remember he was wearing a butterscotch
members only jacket. I swear to God.
Um,
and he looked like he was on his way to
home depot and right down I should have
known that he was going to get crushed in
the Superbowl. But, um, I would say that,
you know what, Bruins Games,
the first Bruins games and
went to the Boston Garden.
I used to always go to Bruins.
Canadians actually went to that bench
clearing brawl. If you go on a youtube,
it's the one where Chris and island,
uh,
was that the game where he hit Rick
Middleton and the teeth with this thick.
And then as he was walking off,
that's right.
He walked off the ice and then he pushed
dot 10 landsman who chased them down.
And next thing you know,
there was a bench clearing brawl.
And Terry O'reilly in his
suit was grabbing onto
somebody and never more quad.
I was good. All right, I'm just babbling
here. I'll just wait for my plumber.
10 23 motherfuckers still
down here. Okay. Uh,
wow. I'm getting bored with
myself here in number five. Uh,
what do you think of the comedy genre?
Anti humor,
like the type by Neil Hamburger and ted.
I don't know those guys.
I watched him and uh, they seem
funny to me, you know, I dunno.
It's not anti humor is it? I Dunno
who gives a fuck. All right. Uh,
so I was watching one of these in tool.
Who's throwing food at you?
I already answered that. That's
a donut. It's a donut hole.
If you see the video on my
page was a group of people,
they were a advertisers.
They all worked at the same place.
I started trashing him and they
threw a doughnut hole. Let me,
and evidently I didn't give
a fuck. Um, number seven,
when you have these horrible
thoughts about people,
are you able to keep your face stoic,
mine,
wrinkles up and I don't notice
until the person looks at me. If so,
how do you play it off? Um, no,
I'm usually cursing like what
I think is under my breath,
but out loud and then
they look right at me.
I literally walked through like an
airport, go and look at this fucking guy.
Fuck kind of shirt.
Is that,
and I think I'm kind of doing
it in my head or whispering,
but I'm saying it loud enough that they
look right at me and then I look away,
which is pretty pathetic. Okay. Which is,
you know what this podcast is
getting pathetic is way too long.
Let's get the thing.
Okay. My DVD, the dog,
the big announcement is going to be
coming out in September of 2008 and the my
DVD,
my a one hour special will also be shown
on comedy central in September of 2008.
So I have all summer to write
some, uh, to write some new jokes,
which I already have already got a whole
new hour. So, uh, all right. This podcast,
I mean minutes is this.
Yeah,
this podcast is really fucking long and
I didn't even get to half the shit I
want to talk about. I want to tell you
guys how I was back to drinking Budweiser.
I've come full circle. I actually,
I started off with Michelob light,
then it quickly went to Budweiser and
then throughout the years I switched to
vodka.
Then I ended up with fucking Johnny
Walker Black and now I'm right back to
Budweiser again.
And uh,
I guess that was the moment at the Johnnie
Walker black where I was supposed to
admit that I had a problem
and stop cold Turkey.
But evidently I'm going to run the cycle
all over again and go back and start
dating some of the same psychos
that I, I dated, you know what?
Next week,
I'll tell you the story about me getting
arrested for drinking and driving back
and fucking June,
no,
December of 1989 I was on my way back
from Boston college to go watch the
Patriots play fucking the Los Angeles
Rams Cause I get season tickets.
Who knew they were going to be five
and 11? Um, anyways, so that's the pot,
you know, it started off
fucking, it started off strong.
I was trashing the art of plumbing and
a dead Karen Carpenter and then it just
sort of tapered off. I, you know, and
I don't want to happen, I shut up,
fucking quit while I was ahead.
But anyways,
thanks to everyone who listened to these
podcasts, I really appreciate it. And, uh,
he would actually, you know,
something, if you enjoy my podcast,
could you please let people know
about them? Because, uh, you know,
I burn up a lot of minutes every
week on my fucking cell phone.
I'm getting brain cancer and I'm
talking to like 15 people. And um,
I'd like to break 20.
If I could get it up to 20 people
before June 10th when I turned 40,
that would make me feel a whole
lot better. All right. So, uh,
thanks to everybody who,
uh,
who has been listening and uh,
sorry to all the Karen Carpenter fans,
I'm sorry to people who are
plumbers. Actually, you know
what? I'm not sorry. Okay.
I'm not fucking sorry, because
one of your, I'll, I'll be sorry.
When some you guys from the plumber's
union have a little talking to,
it's 10 20 fucking seven.
I started this podcast at 10 oh three.
So there's a 24 minute podcast.
I was hoping that the guy was going
to walk in during the middle of it,
and we could have a little
reality show moment what he did.
And you don't probably have
when you first walked up,
halfway through the stairs and hurt me
bitching about fucking plumbers on my
podcast. He didn't hear me talking to
anybody, so he thought it was crazy,
or I was berating my wife,
my nonexistent wife.
Oh God. Look at it. Boom. Look at the
fucking gloom out the window. All right,
that's it. So please come out and
see me. Uh, Chicago would Zane,
he's this week or Caroline's in New York
City at the end of the month or at a
good nights and Raleigh, North
Carolina or the punchline in Atlanta,
Georgia next month. All
right. Your mother fuckers.
I have a CD up on, uh, iTunes
called emotionally unavailable,
the expanded edition. Why don't
you, uh, go there, buy it,
buy for friend five for
plumber. Fucking, uh,
break the CD and half stab him and
his juggler. He's late and that's it.
That's the Monday morning podcast
the next week.
Ooh,
okay.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].