Hey, what's going on? Just checking
what's up. It's bill burn.
It's the Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast just
before Friday special edition.
And I'm here this week with a very
special guest may and I'm here to talk to
you. What's going on? How's your
week been? How you fucking baby?
You made it through Tuesday and Wednesday.
All right. Quit your whining. Okay.
You got your shillings for the
week. Didn't shift. You know,
it's funny I told you guys when uh,
this,
this recorder that I use this
fucking recorder that I use it for,
I have to talk for 30
seconds for it to get the um,
the proper levels levels that are
made in nor they'll have a good audio
experience. Um, so you
know, what am I doing?
I run out of shit to do so I just sing
the national anthem and I just fucked it
up.
Why is that such a hard song to sing by
yourself and everybody else is singing
it.
You know it.
Okay.
You always end up going,
I throwed up pear raw Luz Phi.
What so proudly we hailed at
the twilight's last gleaming,
whose broad stripes and
bright stars don't apparel.
You always go back to that flow.
They'll pile you did the stuck in this
fucking groundhog day of patriotism.
So you know what?
All you guys we've ever made fun of.
Anybody tried to sing the national anthem?
I challenge you right now.
Start singing it to yourself at your
desk. Just whisper. Hey, can you
see how far you get?
See how far you get and we'll see
how much you support the troops.
We'll see how much you love America.
Yeah,
we'll see whether or not you live or die
in a work camp coming up.
You know what?
The other day I was talking to I was
talking to somebody about finance and he
had heard that, you know, I don't let
anybody fucking handle my money. You know,
cause I watched behind the music
and that's the first thing.
The first thing you'd do if you want
people to fucking steal from you is let
them handle your money.
The second thing you do is you
give them power of attorney,
which means they can sign your name,
which means they're essentially you.
They can legally sign your name.
Hi, my name is Frank Gifford.
I'm also Frank Gifford. I don't remember
you being on the giants. Well fuck you.
I got a piece of paper says I
did. Well, at least on the check.
Why did I pick Frank Gifford?
I Dunno. Um, so whatever.
I was talking to this guy about all
my theories. You ever like be talking?
He talks to somebody and you just see
them sort of half smiling and you just
like ask, I think I'm a fucking
moron. I should have just stopped.
I should have just been like,
dude, you're giving me the,
this guy's a fucking moron.
Smile. Which I might be, but, uh,
I don't think I am. You know, I
still remember the Billy Joel One.
Shit. I got friends I know got
fucked over, fucked over already.
And what's the number one
thing that happens? They,
these people could go and
they could infiltrate. How
the fuck do you spell Miami?
Sorry, add kicking in here. Um, they
could go into your fucking account.
Okay.
You're, you're out of your fucking
mind. No, dude. You said you quit.
I've been working with him forever.
Oh, have you? People Change, you know,
people go through a divorce. You know,
a lot of that mental shit if you're,
if you're,
if you've got mental problems.
Yeah.
You know what I mean? When was the
last time we met a schizophrenia?
Eight year old. It never happens. Okay.
Somewhere around 30, all of a sudden,
you know, the person is over in
the corner talking to other people.
It happens later in life. Okay. And you,
and you can take that to the bank because,
uh, I am not in the medical field.
I'm just repeating shit that I heard.
You don't know what's going to happen.
They go to a door,
so they start smoking crack. They go to a
fucking rave. You know, they do ecstasy.
They banked some chick way out of their
fucking league. Next thing you know,
they're doing that,
right.
Okay.
This is fucked up. I don't trust
anybody who drives a white car,
not like a fucking Camry.
Anybody who drives a white
Mercedes Benz or white BMW.
It's a nice car.
And the car is white scumbag,
straight across the fucking
board. Scumbag. All right.
When was the last time you saw a class
act getting out of a white Mercedes?
A White Ferrari? You
know what I mean? Well,
for Aria gets you a little fuck what
have, I mean, you know what I'm saying?
Okay.
Fucking tacky. All right. People have,
oh, anybody has a white leather couch?
You know, just fucking,
just bill, you know,
I forgot something in my car and
just leave scumbag. All right?
Okay.
Um, you know, I'm actually
creating new stereotypes on
this one. I kind of like it.
Um, well built in. What
color car do you trust? Uh,
somebody as a brown car.
They never gonna steal from you,
but they're not going to make
you any money either. You know,
that's a lunch pail Louie,
right? It's got an a brown sack,
fucking Greece armpit stain of the
fucking greasy sandwich coming through the
side of it.
That guy's just accepted his lot in life.
He's gonna put his head down on, one
day's going to look up and he's 60. Right.
It's got to hit them with the fuck did
I do with my life and right there you
drop dead usually with hedge
clippers or something, you know,
cause he didn't make enough
money to fucking, you know,
by the electric pair or maybe even
get a gardener. Right. All right.
So what has happened over the last couple
of days since I last talked to you?
Well,
I lost,
I lost money by betting on Wisconsin.
Okay.
I bet.
I bet a steak dinner with Keith Robinson.
But either way I get to have dinner
with Keith Robinson. So it was really,
it was really a win win, you know what
I mean? He's such a sharp dresser,
you know,
man of the world renaissance man.
He could discuss everything from Earth,
wind and fire to the gap band.
Now we would talk shit the
entire, and uh, I dunno,
I don't know shit about basketball,
but I'm going to tell you,
I'm going to tell you why I would
not draft oca for in the first round.
I think that guy is a classic
waste of a first round draft pick.
I think he's a freshman.
He's probably a sophomore,
but I'm telling you he should have been
destroy a net fucking jam band guy on
fucking Wisconsin number 44,
you know with his Kevin
Mchale 2.0 fucking moves.
I don't know why everybody just,
if you're a big man.
Yeah.
All right.
If you're a man who's big and you play
the game of basketball's Michael Jordan
used to say, he never used
to say basketball was always
the game of basketball.
Kind of like that. Mike and Mike, I
always goes a year, he'll flip wall leak
a day. Right now you're going to have
a lot of problems covering. She'll be
um, the fuck was I saying? Yeah.
I don't know why every big
man just doesn't go out.
Like if Dwight Howard just went out
and stole five fucking moves from Kevin
Mchale and five fucking
moves from, uh, uh, uh,
Keem Olajuwon fucking guy,
it'd be unstoppable.
He just did that right?
And he stole a heart and
stuck it in his chest.
I think that guy,
that guy could be dominant.
Fucking guy's a superhero. The guy's
got damn bicep is bigger than his head.
It's fucking unbelievable. You couldn't
draw a guy in better shape than him. Um,
what is he doing?
He goes on Ellen and he dances around
right then as a Celtics fan. I'm like,
the lake is not winning a championship.
Kobe's is not going to
pass the ball to this guy.
Yeah.
Um, you would have had to come on
screaming, like fucking powder salt,
punching his chest, freaking out. Ellen.
Um, I didn't know what I'm talking about.
Yeah. Oh, cool. For, I'll tell you
why I wouldn't draft if I were,
if I had to go back and if I was working
for like the w the bobcat's or wherever
the, whoever the fuck is going
to draft them, cause you know,
he's going to go early. All
right. This is what I would say.
I would just say, yeah, listen,
uh, I, I don't think, uh,
I don't think we should draft
this guy in the first round.
I think it's a waste of money.
And they would say,
why you uncoordinated unathletic
balding fuck. And I'd be like, you know,
that's a little harsh. Okay. You know,
you fucking ask me to do the Goddamn job.
Excuse my French. Okay. And, and I'm doing
the job. And you come in and you, what,
what's, what's the deal? If I don't
agree with you, you're gonna insult me.
I'd never say that because I'd be fucking,
I'd be, I'd be working for this guy.
So it'd be like, yeah, you know, I am,
I am a balding fucking loser. Right?
Take the paycheck, get in
my car and scream at the
windshield the whole way home,
saint, all the shit I really
wished I had the balls to say.
Then I'd walk in the door and my wife
would see that beaten man, you know,
next thing you know,
she's looking at the fucking neighbors
getting bent over a hedge there.
Um,
this is what I would say, I would say
don't draft. And they would say, why?
Look at his, look what he
did. Look at all this stuff,
all the spreadsheets across the table.
Why wouldn't you draft this guy in
the first round? I'd say it's simple.
The man breathes through his mouth
over.
Guy Breathes through his mouth.
I don't give a fuck what he does
on the court. All right. It'll jam.
Band Dad was fucking going
up and under all the time.
Even before he got into foul trouble.
He sat on the Goddamn bench breathing
through his mouth by two freshmen.
One Who looked like he
was in Lord of the rings.
Okay.
Little Elfin looking dude, Eddy
Munster looking guy. Right?
Just fucking drain and them. Then that
number three, whatever he was, that guy,
I swear to God,
he hits like a fucking 3.0 and I think
he screamed for like a minute gov down.
It's a 3.0
ah.
What is wrong with you?
You would've thought he wanted a
Kia or something with that shot.
I don't fucking get it. Did
he bet the game? I mean,
I know it was for a championship,
but even that reaction,
it's like the middle of the fucking game.
He's screaming like he just
wanted a that said new shit.
That's the shit that makes me feel old.
I literally watched the game going like,
what are these guys screaming above?
You just hit a bucket to go up 58,
stop yelling and get back on d or when
they dunked the ball and then they stare
at the crown like, oh my God, can
you believe what I just did? Yes,
you did it another games.
That's why I bought a fucking ticket.
I came in and watch you do that.
By the way,
you see that guy will get just scored.
That was your fucking guy.
Okay.
Just negating what the fuck
you did because no matter
how hard you throw it down
and you still just getting two points to
get the fuck Vercon do friendship can't,
uh, who's tough on his podcast. I
am tough. I'm tough on my podcast.
Bill birth tough on the podcast.
Okay.
Fucking sweetheart and public.
How are you everybody? Um,
give them a microphone.
Instant cunt.
Okay.
I was singing,
I'm singing Beatles songs today
with domestic violence lyrics and a,
that'll put you in a great mood.
You know I punched you in the face,
bitch, and you know, withdrew.
Just makes you laugh as
you drive down the street.
Does that mean you advocate that behavior?
What do we return controversially
on the Thursday afternoon podcast.
My name is Tripp tripper.
And you're watching the Thursday edition.
I'm sorry. The fuck am
I talking about? Yeah.
So congratulations to the Duke
Blue Devils. First of all,
congratulations with being in the south
and being able to keep the name blue
devil.
I'm surprised considering the devil
rays had to change that. I mean,
how many pussies live in Tampa
or how strong are the fucking
pussies that live in fucking tamp,
I should say?
How big is that group?
How many people do you need a group
to really affect change like that?
How many fucking whining constant you
need to change the name of a baseball
team. You know what I mean? Or how bad
actually we know what the reality is.
How bad is your attendance that
you're trying to get those 40 cops
that you know, I dunno, what, what
are they doing? You know what I mean?
Okay.
I think if,
if you can't handle devil in a name,
I don't think you're going to go to a
baseball game because you're not going to
want to sit there amongst
all those sinners, right?
Abusing the Dayville alcohol.
Okay.
Using the Lord's name in vain,
cussing and swearing and other words
that mean the same thing, right?
You're not going to the game.
I don't fucking understand it.
So congratulations to them.
Duke on tobacco. Rude.
But game of basketball. We take it
seriously down there. We take it serious.
We take basketball seriously down here,
North Carolina,
north cack a lackey.
We take it so seriously.
We didn't even know we won a Stanley Cup.
What is that thing?
Why would you have a
spittoon so fucking high?
Am I supposed to stand on the table
and spitting that fucking thing?
Get it out of here.
I'm speaking of the south.
I got my southern tour coming up,
southern tor coming up
the Billy Bible belt tour.
Coming to a city near you.
And um,
ticket sales have been good as the first
time I've been to a lot of these places.
So a couple of them been a little rough,
you know,
so I'm trying to been hyping
the shit out of it, you know,
hoping that it's going to fill up.
But I've been told in Savannah
there's a lot of walk up traffic.
That's what they always say is to
the performer doesn't kill himself.
But actually we've been doing good there.
Um, if anybody can get the word out,
anybody remotely in New Orleans,
if you can try to fucking rally
some troops to come see me in uh,
the fuck am I going to be dumb?
Am I,
once I say Savannah was going to
say Savannah fucking New Orleans.
I know it's not that. Well, gee bill,
maybe that's why they're not coming out,
cause you don't know where the
fuck are you going to be. Hey, hey,
it's fucking side. Are you on here? You
know the hell am I going to be here?
Well, this weekend I'm going to be in
Miami at the Fillmore, Jackie Gleason,
and then I'm going to be up in Tampa.
If I just called 40 field
people up their pussies.
I'm at the Ruth Eckerd Hall.
Devil Hall in Tampa.
You speed the devil halts. Not
Savannah, Knoxville, Chattanooga,
Memphis is Shreveport, Shreveport,
Louisiana. I need some help there.
All right.
If anybody,
anybody at all knows anybody who knows
anybody at all that can come out to that
show,
I'd really appreciate it.
I'm playing this legendary theater
that's a big fucking theater,
but it's the only game town. Um,
and it's this theater that like,
uh, an unknown. Elvis
performed at an unknown.
Jerry Lee Lewis has fucking coolest
shit they got there. And you know,
I'm of course a bunch of black performers
that fucking, and they stole from.
So whose statue is out in front of the
thing? Elvis, Jerry Lee Lewis. Of course,
white people. Um, the other
ones are going pretty good.
I cannot fucking wait to
get on that bus and, uh,
go to all these towns that I haven't
been to. Man, it's going to be sick.
And I am so upset that it's not football
season because we're going to a bunch
of sec, you know, we're going to
miss chipper going to Knoxville,
Tennessee. I mean, we just go and
buy all these fucking schools.
It's going to be killing me,
but I'm hoping I sell tickets here so the
next time I come back I do even better.
And then the next time I do the tour,
I can do it during football season.
Really Bill is at your plan?
Yes it is. Um, all right.
What else do I need to talk about?
All right.
I talked a bunch of shit
a couple of days ago.
I shit on the Ottawa
senator fans the fucking,
and I was saying, you're not making
the fucking playoffs. All right.
Cause I'm like, dude,
we want six in a row.
And it wasn't even looking at the
stats. I had no idea. I thought,
I thought Ottawa was fading.
So I said all this horrible shit
about them, you know? And uh,
now here it is, four days later
we lose to the capitals, you know,
which isn't good. It's not good
when you can't even, you know,
score a fucking goal. You know what I
mean? And it's driving me nuts. Anyways,
so a lot of you probably think it's
so, Bill, you're gonna apologize.
Are you going to back down
from what you say? No.
All right.
What's my name? Fuck. Yo.
Yeah, I'm staying with it.
I'm going Alec Baldwin in Glengarry Glen
Ross. Fuck you. All right. Fuck you.
The Bruins are making the
playoffs and like I said,
we're going to play the Montreal Canadians
and not only are we going to set them
in the first round, we're going to
sweep up. Okay. Which will be fine.
Montreal Canadien fans will be able to,
there'll be able to survive because they
have that little pocket square right in
the front pocket of that Blue Blazer,
which is great for wiping
away tears and snot
when you fucking lose.
Um, now who's kidding who?
I'm just hoping we're
going to make the uh,
okay.
I hope to make the playoffs. I mean,
shit, that's our fucking Stanley Cup.
It seems to shift.
But you know what's funny?
I watched like the first period of
half before I had to go to work, um,
if you want to call it telling
jokes work, which it isn't. Um,
and I thought we would, we were playing
great. You know what I mean? We will,
we will, it looked like we
were competing with them.
We just couldn't score a fucking goal.
I don't know what we need to do.
Who the hell knows? I mean, what do they,
they don't, I saw the first two goals.
The first one was, was a great goal.
The second one, I mean, no deflection,
what are you going to do? But, um,
I've actually become sort
of a capitals fan because,
you know,
just Ovechkin scoring
all of those goals. It takes
me back to the 80s, man.
Like that shit used to happen
all the time. You know,
like goaltenders were like my size
in the 80s and they wore pads,
you know, that weren't like
gigantic. Did you see, you know,
I saw a thing the other day that
saying how the fucking, the, uh,
the goalie's glove now doesn't even close,
which is weird to me, I think closes a
little bit, but they figured out that,
you know, what, why have it
closed? Because the goaltender,
we'll just have a closed and if he can't
open an in time, it might just slip by.
So just have this giant fucking
fishnet thing, you know,
like you're scooping up large mouth bass
out of the fucking a lake or something
and just have it open like that.
It's like really,
do we need to take away more than that?
You know?
I Dunno, but I actually learned
some shit about hockey. You know,
they always say five hole is between the
legs. And then there's one, two, three,
four, which is the fucking corner
starting down in the lower left,
I believe it goes like this lower left
corner is one lower right corner is two
and then you go straight up.
That's three.
And then back over to the left is four
I believe I might might have fucked that
up. And then five hole was between
the legs. That's all there was.
So the other day somebody goes,
he went seven hall and then I heard
there's a six hole. I had no idea.
And that's six holds seven hole,
his fucking his glove side between the
arm and the body and then blocker's side
between the arm and the body.
One six one seven I don't even know.
I never even fucking heard of that shit.
And it just struck me as
funny that they're now talking
about two more holes in
the goaltender when they're
fucking gigantic people, you know,
they look like refrigerators.
Like the padding that they have is unreal.
I saw to grasp on time,
I did comics come home and some of the
Bruins were down there actually a bunch
of them down. It's fucking
awesome. But um, you know,
I thought that guy was like,
I don't know why I thought he weighed
like two 40 or something like that.
And he's very like, he's
tall, but he's like lanky.
But you look them with the pads on guy
looks like a monster. So there you go.
If you get mugged in the subway, just
get yourself some goalie pads, right?
If you get mugged every day, you know,
go to big and tall, get yourself a suit,
you put it over there. Obviously adult
wear the mask or the gloves. All right.
Then you do that weird little run that
you do when you're wearing goalie pads.
You sit down with the train.
Nobody fucks with you. If they do,
you got on all the paddock,
they'll just think you're fat.
You know he's a hitting you and that's
a stupid plan. What do you want from me?
Go Fuck Yourself. Okay. I'm trying
to help you out, you know. All right.
This is another being married story.
All right?
Just the shit that will fucking,
that will really drive
you up the fucking wall.
Unless you could figure out a cute
way to bring it up. All right.
I'm coming home from the gym. All right.
We don't have any food in the house.
I don't know why.
Probably because we ate it all
and didn't go to the supermarket.
That's how you run out of food.
But who knows? You know, might
have a fucking mouse. I Dunno.
No Jesus fucking plot.
Guess it's going off the rails here.
Let's get to the thing here.
So I fucking,
I'm going to come home and
make some toast, right? We
don't even need lunch meat.
We got nothing. So I'm like,
all right, fuck this shit.
I'm just going to make a
fucking piece of toast, right?
Peanut butter and Jelly on top of it.
That'll fill me up. Bowl of cereal.
Who gives a fuck? Okay,
great. After work out great.
After a workout fucking meal.
So I show up,
I put the piece of bread to crust
all the way down to the end.
It sounds like a fucking like
one of those fairy tales.
Like I should be scrubbing the
floor with a toothbrush to the, the,
the level of lack of food here.
So it's the cross. The last piece,
they put it in the toaster.
I get the peanut butter,
the peanut and I get the Jelly and now
I'm looking for the fucking table butter.
Where is it? Where the fuck is it? And
I immediately start muttering to myself,
did she put it in the fucking bridge?
Why didn't she always put
it in the fucking fridge?
You know this fucking hard butter
in the fridge. You know you get,
I don't know about you guys, but I like
soft spreadable butter for my toast.
I don't want to fucking hard as a rock.
And then I'm going through the bread.
Some, the old me, the old me
would have flipped out. Like,
why the Fuck d? Like, you know? Yeah,
why the fuck do you keep putting
the fucking man? You know,
it would've been an idiot about it, but
I didn't. I wrote her a note instead,
I wrote Nia, I think it's time. We
talked about soft spreadable butter.
I like soft spreadable butter.
It's great for toast waffles.
And I imagined pancakes too.
There's already hard butter in the fridge,
so there's no reason to add to it and
eliminate all options for soft spreadable
butter. It's not. The summer
said, don't be a parlor. Say Yes.
This soft spreadable butter bill
came in laughing her ass off.
She still didn't understand my point.
I explained it to her.
She laughed and she said okay.
And she left. So they had golf.
And that's one to grow on.
Always use sense of humor when you can.
If you get the fucking broads laugh and
once they titty started jiggling and
your fucking homefree,
how would it do she know?
There was such a cute little story there
and I had to ruin it with my fucking,
my, my, my piggish behavior.
Um, look, and by the way,
for all you butter cones out there,
I realized in the summertime,
if it gets really hot, it
can totally melt. Okay?
That's why I threw in the summer
thing cause I was trying to think,
well how is she gonna fucking argue this?
So I think she understands it now.
All right. I am a waffle
making motherfucker. I don't
know if you guys know that,
man. I fucking got that shit down. I
make them all the time. I enjoy them.
Um, all right, Dave Grohl gets spooked
when he looks at Francis being Cobain.
I'm looking at news today. What's
in the news? Oh, by the way,
I've got a couple of retail. What do
we got here? A couple of quick reads.
One with a bunch of instructions,
getting a bad reputation for cunt
and stuff during copy, you know,
whatever. Um, okay, here we
go. Zip recruiter, everybody.
Ziprecruiter, are you hiring? But not
sure where to find the best candidates.
Um, well, zip recruiter, zip recruiter.
If I can say that can tell you that your
company is only as good as the people
you hire.
A,
they can also tell you that posting your
job in one place isn't enough to find
quality quality candidates,
but when you're short staffed,
there's no time to deal with the dozens
of different jobs sites. Until now,
thanks to zip recruiter.com you can post
to a hundred plus job sites with one
single click and have the highest
possible chance of finding the perfect
candidate just post once within 24 hours
and once your candidates roll in a roll
into ZipRecruiter's,
easy to use interface.
Ziprecruiter has been used by over
300,000 businesses and you can try.
You can try it right now for free.
Getting the right people for
your company is so important.
Try ZipRecruiter and get your perfect
candidate before they go to somebody else
today you can try zip recruiter for free.
Go to ziprecruiter.com/burr B,
u r. R. That's zip recruiter.com/. Burpee.
You are R and for
everybody's who's dumb as me.
I'll spell that zip recruiter, R, e c r u,
I t e r.com. Just for people
that don't have spell check.
And then the last thing Bombas socks.
Chances are if you still have feet,
you wear socks in. Face it. Socks
haven't changed since they were invented.
They fall down.
They were up there and they always,
there's always that toe scene that never
seems to be in the right place. Oh,
he could reach down and adjusted. Right.
Our new sponsor Bombus has changed.
All of that bomb is dedicated two years
to engineering socks that stay up last
forever and feel amazing on
your feet. Yeah, that's true.
When they kidnapped subjects that made
him walk around in them for two years,
can we go? Yeah, no, I have
a pair of Bombus. No I don't.
Oh yes I do. Yes I do. Now I have
them and I tried them on. Oh Shit.
They feel great. They do. I
got to tell you all this shit,
all this stuff that people
send me, they're really
smart. You know what I mean?
They know the two areas that you really
want to have comfort in is your balls
and your feet.
Get balls and feet feel good.
Are you a fucking hoo ha and
your twinkle toes? You know,
you can put that day in the
win column. Um, anyways,
the pre the prima cotton they
used is so soft. It's amazing, uh,
to know what I'm talking about. You
really need to try a pair of for yourself.
But listen, Obama's doesn't stop with
your comfort with every pair of socks.
Bomba sells. A pair is donated to
someone in need because socks is,
it turns out are the number one requested
item at homeless shelters right now.
And for a limited time bomb is,
is offering my listeners 20% off
their first order and free shipping.
Just go to bombas.com/ [inaudible] B o
m B a s all lowercase a.com/bird do it
now for 20% off. Most of the most
comfortable socks in the planet.
And a pair for someone in need,
go to [inaudible] dot com that's
[inaudible] dot com B o m B a s.com/
[inaudible] all right. All right.
The reading is mercifully Oh,
um,
all right.
Okay.
Oh fuck.
Was I reading there something about
Francis Being Colbian today.
Rolling Stone published excerpts from
his forthcoming interview with Francis
Being Cobain,
uh,
the daughter of Kurt and executive proof
producer on the new documentary of his
life,
a montage of heck.
And unlike some sections of
the Nirvana diehard fanbase,
Frances isn't so quick to lionize her
father speaking about the potential
awkwardness of preferring
oasis to Nirvana. Francis said,
I would've felt more
awkward if I'd been a fan.
I was around 15 when I
realized he was in escapable.
Even if I was in a car and had
the radio one, there's my dad.
He's larger than life and our culture
is obsessed with dead musicians.
Yeah, that's true. We love
to put them on pedestals.
If Kurt had just been another guy who
abandoned his family in the most awful way
possible.
Hm.
What buddy wasn't,
he inspired people to put them on
a pedestal to become st cart. Yeah.
Well you know,
you fucking kill yourself.
Your kids are going to be
mad that I over simplify it.
Uh, Dave Grohl and this
is some fucking, you know,
had is like gossip. I didn't know was
going to be like this. Jesus Christ.
I can fucking read this shit. I love
Dave Grohl. Um, so anyways, there you go.
It's coming out in rolling
stone so you know it's true.
Oops.
Yeah,
these people raped her.
I know they did. Sorry,
we only talked to one person.
That's how you do journalism.
All right.
Are we done here for the week?
This is just me fucking
checking in on you.
So I'm only required to do a
half hour and we're at 28 45,
which means I only got a minute 15 left.
But if I was playing basketball
at a professional level,
this podcast would go on for like
another nine hours. All right. Did He,
is making Sean John Close for tween girls.
Now,
this is like when I looked up Google news,
this is what they suggested for me.
All right.
They got that awful story of that
police officers shooting the dude,
South Carolina. Man, it's just fucking
Jesus Christ fucking guys running away.
You know what I mean?
I know they're trained to shoot
center mass, but how about you now?
Fucking shooting the leg. Do one
shots. They'll give me a fuck dude.
If somebody had a sling shot shot in the
ass with it, I I, I'd go down. All right.
All right.
Obama set the test engagement
doctrine with Cuba in Panama.
This is annoying that like cube was
just going to be open to everybody.
I always want to just fucking there,
right?
Cause you're not supposed to now
going to be able to go there.
Yeah,
I'm calling this right now.
All right.
Within 15 years you're going to
see why Cuba did kicked us out.
You're going to see it. You Watch, you
watch what happens to that fucking place.
How soon before Citibank and
chase have skyscrapers there,
you know, and once they're there,
they need some place to eat, right?
It comes Papa John's and
fucking cheesecake factory
and next thing you know,
right.
You got your fucking biggest losers on TV,
the Cuba edition. Oh, Jesus Christ.
They can be sitting there eating
cheesecake, smoking cigars. I mean,
we're going to there. That's what
we, we, you know what I mean?
People were going to cause the die
down there, but just with our diet,
okay.
Coming down there with
Fritos and Coca Cola, um,
this is what I'm predicting.
Yeah.
We're going to ruin that place and
the kids are going to be eaten,
are poisonous food.
They're going to stop playing baseball
and there's going to be no more.
Sammy Celsus all eight ways. Was He
Dominican Republic? I can't remember.
Gloom and doom and the cigars aren't
going to taste as good because every
fucking jerk off now.
We'll just do it to do it.
Is there anything good about it, bill?
Uh, they'll get a roller coaster.
There you go. Why? I'm not buying
an apple watch. This person says,
Oh man, you're an idiot. If
I should say your an why,
why would you buy an apple
watch? Why would you do that?
Okay. You got to fucking,
you got a clock right on your phone.
Your phone can do all the shit the
fucking watch can do. What are you doing?
What does a tween,
well,
I want to know that the last thing
you want to do is search tween girls.
Fucking FBI guy will come through
your screen. I swear to God.
I was doing research. I was doing a
podcast. All right. Guns and roses,
new album underway. Steven Adler
questions. Axl Rose for not,
ah, here we go. Now I know them.
Okay, we'll end on this gossip here.
Do you guys listen to his podcasts a
lot? You know, I'm a big fan of us,
Steven Adler and a,
what am I working on with drums right
now I'm working on a little molar
technique coming together. So when I, uh,
play awfully, I can do it without
getting carpal tunnel, a guns and Ra.
Oh, good. A pop up ad.
I think I'll click on it and
buy whatever they're selling me.
Has Anybody ever done that? Maybe an 80
year old woman. I just, I don't know.
I just fucking close it, right. Anyways,
guns and roses, new album underway.
Steven Adler.
Questions axl rose for not
trying to set up a reunion tour.
Yeah, I don't understand why he's
still doing that. You know why?
Because people keep going to see him
with his band. Like if you're a true fan.
Well, I don't. I don't wanna fuck
with somebody tickets. But you know,
that's the deal.
A guns and roses have been making
some noise this year as a new album is
confirmed in a tour as well on its way.
The vocalist axl rose is being urged
by bandmates to do a reunion tour,
but he won't do it for money's sake.
Drummer. Steven Adler, however,
contradicts axle statement,
a guns and roses guitars.
Richard Fortis answered questions about
axl rose willingness to do a reunion
tour.
Here's what he said.
I've never met anybody that has so much
genuine musical integrity, integrity.
He won't horror himself out. He won't
do anything for business or money.
It's just about the music.
Well, this is a company, man.
What else is he going to say?
He won't horror himself out.
He's got a band that isn't guns and roses.
He's calling guns and roses.
We're going to file this under rule is
always a fellow red head. I got it back.
I'm here, right? Here
we go. Let's keep going.
You guys think I should have
done that when I went bald.
Should I fucking got cornrows instead?
Sewed it into whatever was still left.
Okay.
Could somebody please Photoshop axles,
corn rows on my head so I can retweet it.
All right,
and he went and he won't defend himself
in the press because he doesn't think it
matters. It's just about the
music. That's all he cares about.
I've worked with a lot of people in this
business that I've never seen or met
anybody that has mo is motivated.
I was motivated purely by the desire
to make art. Well, you know what?
I don't fucking know the guy.
The only reason why I trash them 40
is doing this because I want to see,
because I'm being selfish.
Okay?
No, fuck. It's his career.
We can do whatever he wants.
Right. They get, go see that.
That is an enlightened man.
Um,
and his fucking late forties. Oh God.
I'm gonna be 47 this year doing it.
It's fucking over.
I got to pass the torch.
I got to find somebody
to pass the torch to it.
Okay.
Let's see who the fuck.
Who the fuck is on their way up?
I don't fucking know what torch do I
have a, that's the fucking bic lighter.
All right, well there you
go. Well, now with the, uh,
for those of you who are new to the,
uh,
just checking in on
your Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast just
before Friday podcast. Um, um,
we always, I always do like a half hour
or whatever, maybe interview a guest, but,
um,
we try to put in some classic clips
from back in the day back in the dam and
doing this podcast since 2007.
So a,
I don't even know what we're
going to have this week. Uh,
I dunno what they pulled up, but uh, enjoy
the last, uh, I guess, I don't know, 25,
30 minutes of some classic clips here.
Thank you guys for listening and uh,
Shreveport new or a New Orleans,
Shreveport, Louisiana. Jesus Christ.
Trying to get the word out.
Um, you know what I mean?
I, you know, it's such
a legendary theater.
If I go there and there's nobody there,
I'm still going to give a fucking,
obviously I'm still going to give a
great show, but I just, I don't, I don't,
I just don't want to fucking,
I don't want to disrespect that
legendary place by standing there
in front of five fucking people. All
right. That's it. Okay. Fuck you.
Auto was senators the Bruins and making
the play offs. I'm calling it right now.
All right. All right. Right.
I'll talk to you on Monday.
Like I fucking hate judge, Judge
Carol. I hate all those mother fuckers.
Okay. This one is some lady screaming
at this guy going, you know,
you don't come in here and
disrespect is quite like that.
Disrespect what court?
It's a fucking TV show you dumped cunt.
You're not a fucking judge.
We're so sick of these fucking people
who get TV shows about a job and they
think that that that's your fucking job
now is still the job that the show and
know you're a TV star.
It's not a fucking court of law.
Even though it has the
authority of a court of law.
How many courts do you know out there?
Okay,
that ceased to exist if
they get bad ratings,
you know what I mean?
Actually left that comment on one of
those fucking youtube video things, man.
He's fucking girl show boat.
They always show boat and slam it down
the hammer screaming and yelling and then
you know,
they go to the commercial and then the
producer comes up and whispers in their
ear like, yeah, that was great
television. That was great. Tells me, Hey,
do more yelling, yell more. ESPN is
making a killing with the yelling.
I fuck ain't oh maybe it's my hatred
of women. I don't know what it is.
But those fucking women judges, that's
my nightmare of what being married is.
You know, cause you're legally bound to
them and they can take half your shit.
So now they can fucking
yell at you like that.
Banging a hammer hammer on
some fucking coffee table.
Oh, I'll tell you right now.
You can take half my shit.
I'll fucking walk just to get away
from you and your fucking goddamn
menopause. Chicken neck fucking screaming
at me. Go fuck yourself, Judge Judy.
There's no fucking way I
would stand there. Okay.
And get yelled at like that because a
third of my swing set is on my neighbor's
property.
You're gonna fucking yell at me like that.
Yeah.
Cause cause why? Why are you yelling at
me like that? You don't even feel it.
Judge Judy, all you, all you
want to do is get good ratings.
Fucking grand standing.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Please tell me not naked under that rope.
You emaciated older fork.
Oh.
Oh
I got,
I got an overrated overrated.
Picking up a fucking magazine that lists
10 great places to go to breakfast and
then believing that no one else read
the magazine and there's not going to be
aligned three miles long the next fucking
morning when you show up to get your
pancakes.
That's exactly what happened.
We pull up and I see this fucking looks
like a God damn breadline during the
depression and then with Nia and a
mom and I immediately just go, hey,
you guys want to go somewhere else? And
then somebody in the car goes, well,
there's probably going to
be a line everywhere, right?
So we fucking stand in line for
40 minutes. Got to the point.
I'm crouching down like, uh, my back is
killing my lower back. Like I'm so old,
I can't stand for longer than like 20
minutes without my lower back killing me
some standing there, 40 minutes
in, I'm crouching down like a,
you ever see Asians when they
have a conversation in China,
how they just fucking nigger.
They can crouch down like that
and are people in India, you know,
they crouched down like that.
They'd been doing it their whole lives.
So their hamstrings are all stretched out.
I was down like that.
My big head turn it all red.
I'm trying to stand in a
little bit of the shade and uh,
I don't know. Finally I was like, let's,
let's get the fuck outta here. Right?
So everybody agreed, we leave
and we ended up going, I mean,
we stood in line for breakfast so long,
it's not time to get lunch.
So we ended up going down.
We were on Santa Monica and we go down
into West Hollywood and there's a place
down there, hamburger Harry's.
They have great fucking, uh,
they've got great burgers and it's one,
but it's also one of the gayest places
you'll have a goatee in your life.
I didn't realize how gay it was.
And I went there and the waiter
was like really gay or whatever,
but I didn't really think about it.
Right?
So I drop off the ladies and I
go over and I parked the car,
I get out of the car and I come
walking in and I'm starving.
And as I'm walking in, all of a
sudden this guy pushes me in the back,
like gave me a nice little shove and I
turned around and he goes to need a table.
Fuck it. It's fucking gay.
Dude pushed me in the bed.
He pushed me like fuck. Then like
not hard enough to make me stumble,
but hard enough to fuck up the
gate of my walk. And immediately,
you know, felt the feelings you feel
when somebody fucking pushes you.
When I turn around like,
what the fuck?
And the guys just standing there
[inaudible] the table and I went, no,
I'm just meeting them over there.
And then he kinda had a weird look on his
face and he walked away and I sit down
and he's like, hey, how's it
going? I'm like, wait, but
how's it going? I go there.
Fucking gay guy. Just push me. So
I tell her the story and I'm off.
I've got with like, what the
fuck is it? Some gay thing.
You just fucking go around
pushing people and then Nia goes,
he was probably hitting on you, right?
So now my ego kicks in. I'm like,
fuck,
I still am in shape sell for any of my
fucking twinkle toed listeners out there.
Is that how you guys hit on each
other? Was that just like, Hey Kelly,
do you want to table? Is that what
he was doing? Fucking annoying.
Whatever it was. And I felt
embarrassed and I felt bad, like,
like a that look on his face when I went,
now I'm sitting over here like,
then he thought that I,
I don't know what
okay.
That I was saying, get out of
here. You're queer. You know,
cause that's a whole big fucking thing
now you gotta be nice to those guys.
What the fuck I'm saying? So
anyways, so we sit down, all right.
And immediately the dude comes over,
how I'm, can I take your order?
We fucking order and we're getting our
food immediately the way you should when
you go out to eat. So now,
despite the fact that fucking the,
the waiter pushed me like
that dude who push Zidane Oh,
Chara after he scored the goal,
that's basically how he pushed me.
And then I turned around and looked at it.
I'm like,
I was going to run him into
the boards basically, right?
So they fucking bring the food over.
It's delicious, everything's going great.
And then all of a sudden this fucking
dude gets on the Mike and he can't see
him. He's like, okay,
everybody shows 10 minutes,
right?
And I'd say, Nigga, what's
going on? She goes, evidently,
they're going to have a show.
It's fucking broad daylight out.
I guess they're going to come out and
drag and they're going to do a show like
this.
This is how gave this place is that
they're going to have a brunch slash
transvestite Lipsync fucking show.
And I got to tell you,
it was absolutely fucking hilarious.
We was sitting there
and the guy on the mic,
it's like 1130 in the morning and he said,
cunt on the mic.
He goes, come on, bitches,
drink up. We're having a show.
Don't be a bunch of something.
And he goes, sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm just feeling a little cunty
there with Nias mom.
And this guy starts saying cunt,
like every other fucking word in
broad daylight. And as a comedian,
I had to respect the guy.
All right.
I've never said cunt on stage when the
sun's out, I'm not going to lie to you.
I barely say it on stage. I say at a
ton of times here cause it's ridiculous.
But I really don't say it that
much on a comedy club stage.
And this dude slash half a lane is
say it con every other word at Brunch.
And uh,
so anyways,
so they come down like three of them.
The host sucked,
right? He had this giant head
with this huge fucking, uh,
I dunno what blonde wig on
and he,
he was like doing jokes that should have
been funny but weren't at some point he
said something about a bloody pussy and
we're sitting here eating brunch and he
makes a bloody pussy joke.
So as a comedian, this, this
should have been hilarious,
was timing was awful.
He'd say the setup and then he mumbled
a punchline and he was annoying me.
The next one came out was, all right,
the dude looked like Nancy grace.
So that was cracking me up. And then, uh,
the next one looked like a soccer mom.
Yeah.
If, if she was in Battlestar
Galactica, you know, you know,
when they have those, uh,
you know, they get that Woodstock, Ellen
degenerate haircut kind of had that,
but spiked up and that was hilarious.
And then the last one freaked me out.
There's always one that's going to freak
you out because it's going to almost
look like a fucking chick.
So it had like acid plants and it's like,
I'm trying to eat and I got, I
gotta get Outta here. So I go up,
I walk out of the restaurant because,
you know, it's one of those deals.
It's like when in Rome you went into
their place, so you got to tolerate,
then becomes, does that point we
just like, all right, this is,
this is too fucking creepy. I
gotta get Outta here. You know.
So I walk out and I'm standing on the
corner out in front of this place that
turned into the gayest place I've
ever been in. And I got to tell you,
I walked down the street
all the time in la.
Nobody ever tells me that they saw
me, nobody's ever seen me, nothing.
I come walking out of this place right.
And this behind me is this something the
transvestite that almost looks like it,
chick with acid plants and his
dancing to salt and pepper push it.
I swear to God.
So I'm standing out in front of that
place and it's that part of the song was
going Bullshit Dona Ana and this guy
pulls up from the comedy store stopping at
the Red Light. He's like, hey bill,
how you doing? And I'm just like, hey,
how's it gone?
Done
and the fucking background and my face
literally turned red with embarrassment.
But fortunately,
fortunately the guy owned a
restaurant across the way.
So then he ended up coming out,
coming over to me coming out.
How fucking funny is that? He comes
over to me and he goes, uh, you know,
to shoot the shit.
Cause I've been telling him I was going
to go to his restaurant and that just,
then fortunately Nia and her mom walked
out and I've never been so relieved to
be like, this is my girlfriend.
And this is your mom.
I didn't know that there was gonna be a
fucking, it was like, uh, when I got a,
I had a mid eighties,
I don't know what a mid eighties,
a sitcom, you know, with this,
this situation
[inaudible]
[inaudible].