Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast data.
Just checking in on you. I can't yell at,
I am in New York City right now and I'm,
it's late. I forgot, you know, today
was Thursday and I had to do the Po,
the podcast. So I apologize for
being late. I, um, I dunno. I,
I, uh, I don't know. I wasn't
thinking the fuck do you want from me?
And all of a sudden I landed and I got
a bunch of tweets from people going into
it. I thought you were going to
check in on me. I was like, God,
I'm letting people down. I'm letting you
down. So here I am. I'm checking into,
so now you're gonna hear it on Friday,
but she some lonely bastard
on the west coast, you know,
still up or some lonely lady.
Um,
anyways,
so I just got here to New York because
I'm doing Foxwoods this weekend.
And, um, since I left New York,
my neighborhood has become extremely gay.
And I don't mean it in a way that
all the gay people don't like.
When you say that neighborhood's gay,
like it stinks. I mean like literally gay.
I mean men are attracted to men,
you know there's Gig eyes up and down,
this tripping over each other.
And let me tell you something.
Nobody's complaining honey,
right? So here's the deal.
When gays move into your neighborhood,
this three stereotypes that
everybody says, you know what?
Gay people moving into neighborhoods,
this is,
these are the three things everybody says,
right? They say number one, all right,
what do they say? They say the
neighborhood's going to become safer.
Yeah,
right?
Number two,
they say property values are
going to go up. And number three,
they say there's going to be all these
great new fucking restaurants and Holy
Shit, the cuisines going
to be fucking unbelievable.
Thank God that gay showed up.
Now this neighborhood can fuck in,
you know,
live up to its potential.
Well, they showed up.
Definitely got safer. Definitely
less shady. All right,
so check on the first one.
Stereotype number two.
Uh, the fuck did I say it was still
property value would go up? Yeah it did.
But I miss New York. It
goes up everywhere. But you
know what? You know what?
It's an election year. I don't want
to derail the podcast campaign.
I'll give you credit on that one.
Gay People,
it got safer and the property
values went up. And then lastly,
all this great cuisine was going
to come here. And you know what?
It's still hasn't shown up.
The food in my neighborhood
absolutely fucking sucks.
And I am so sick of it.
Okay. The God damn it.
I was told when these gay showed up at
the fucking food was going to get better.
And I think it not only
has it not gotten better,
it's actually taken a nose dive.
I just went out and got a Burrito.
Right.
What kind of asshole leaves Angeles and
then tries to get a Burrito in New York.
You're listening to them, this
asshole. All right. The Brita was fine.
Okay.
You know, chicken Burrito, whatever. It's
funny, you know, I looked at the menu,
it was all this fucking shit. I
just looked at the, the waiter,
I felt like I disappointed them.
I was like,
can I just get some chips
with guacamole salsa?
And like it just like a chicken burrito
and I just saw it in his eyes like, oh,
you want white people Mexican
food? And I was like, exactly.
I am as white as it gets and I will
have my Mexican food as white as I am,
please. Right. Um, and
before, you know, Mexico,
people write in and tell me that's not
real Mexican food. I understand. I get it.
Alright, whatever it, this is what the
fuck I want it. Here's my question.
How do you have all these gay people
walking up down the street and you can't
even make decent guacamole?
How the fuck does that happen?
Okay.
You know, who do I blame in
this gay people slipping?
Is it because these are the millennial
gays and they're just Emoji and each
other? You know, I don't
know what's going on.
Um, I'm blaming the gates. I'm blaming
you guys on this one. All right.
Whatever pressure used to put
on a fucking neighborhood.
You're not doing it anymore. Oh, what? You
decided not to do it in my neighborhood?
I was so fucking,
you know the anticipation.
Oh, once you guys to send it on this
one straight shady fucking neighborhood,
you know, and the rainbow flags
came out and all this shit.
When the fuck is the food truck get
in here. That's what I want to know.
Fucking pizza sucks.
The fucking guacamole sucks.
Okay.
The Middle Eastern food sucks. The
whole fucking, they just sucks.
Everything is just like, it's you.
How much I drink when
I'm in my neighborhood.
It's just still the fucking food or tea.
It's all like,
just get shit faced and didn't make
it fill up that hole in your stomach.
Maybe that's why I'll buy all these gay
guys are in such great shape around here.
They're cooking it all. Ah, fuck Nah,
that pisses me off.
I just had a fucking God damn chicken
Burrito and Guacamole this late at night.
So at my age, I, you know,
I'll probably have a heart attack around
eight 30 in the morning, you know,
at least it could have tasted good,
right?
Why is it fucking button on
it now? It's off. I want,
if you guys can hear this shit,
whatever the fuck you going to do.
I don't know why the fuck I bring my
mixer and all this stuff. God Damn.
And I'm in a grumpy mood and
I was in such a great mood.
It's nothing worse than when you're
starving and you go out and you'll order a
fucking meal,
right
in a neighborhood that's now a gay
neighborhood and it sucks. I mean,
I'm talking literally like the two dudes
next to me at the end of their fucking
meal, right? They fucking like
kissed each other tenderly.
Can I at least get some
fucking decent guacamole?
How much greater is it going to be
around here? So to get a decent burrito?
So I learned that stereotype is not true.
Just can say show up.
Doesn't mean the chefs are going
to start fucking throwing down.
They're dropping the fucking ball.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
When the two went to kiss. Okay. Is as
open minded as I am. I have to admit,
I was wearing a baseball cap and I
tilted it down so I didn't see their lips
meet. You know, does that make me
a bad person? If you're judging me,
can I just tell you that
one of them look like that,
that fucking scrawny little
dude that j Lo married.
Just imagine that Guy
Kissing Lenny Kravitz.
You know, forgive me, I didn't
want to see it. You know,
we made that makes me a bad person,
but whatever.
I am a work in progress just like
everybody else and I will have a decent
bullet. Fucking guacamole. You sons of
bitches. All right, let's plow ahead here.
So,
um,
I flew out this morning and I actually
have this app on my phone where I can
listen to the control tower and I'm
just totally nerding out, you know,
every time he had the tower talking
about our plane, I'm sitting,
he's talking about us.
He just told us to go onto this little
fucking taxi way or whatever, you know.
And, um, so I'm flying up front,
right? Cause at this point I,
I spent 20 years in the back of the
plane. I'm not flying. I'm not fucking,
I'm not doing that anymore.
I'm done.
I don't give a shit if I lose money
on the gigs, I am flying up front.
And for all you guys,
for 20 years,
I sat in the back of the plane looking
what goes on on the other side of that
curtain. What happens up there? What is
that like? You know what happens up there?
People, spoiler alert,
you know what happens?
They treat you like a human
being. I sweat. They do,
they treat you the way they treat
everybody in the commercials about their
airline. Right? Everybody's smiling,
having a good fucking time. You know,
he got a seat that's actually comfortable.
There's nobody leaning on yet.
Nobody breathing on you. You're hungry,
they bring your food, you're thirsty,
they bring you a drink,
they treat you like a fucking
person posted in the back. Right?
Just jamming in there,
stuffing in there. Right?
So anyways,
so I poured first because you know
I'm a fancy fucking guy, right?
So I fucking I board, right? I can't say
fancy guy. Jim Norton says that fancy man,
I'm a, I don't know what I am but
fucking jerk off, right? So I cannot,
I can't underplay right.
And um,
this fucking lady behind me.
All right,
the second she gets to a chair
and she just starts yelling
going, sir, sir, stare,
stare.
You know,
just yelling at this foot that the fucking
male stewardess. And he turns around,
he's like, Hey, what's the
problem? She goes, there's
something wrong with my chair.
Is this broken? Is it broken?
Like freaking the fuck out.
And the guy's like, no.
The other person just,
you know,
whoever was sat in this on the last
flight didn't bring it all the way to the
upright position. Oh. Because I
thought it was broken, you know,
and write down immediately. Just fucking
hated this woman fucking be dementia.
This,
the sniffles just kept sniffing and shit.
Didn't give a fuck about anybody and just,
I swear to God the shit that I thought
about her because she sat up in the front
of the plane,
I immediately judged to that she was
some rich caught me while I'm sitting up
there. Right. I know what
she was thinking about me.
It was Baldwin. Redheaded fucking,
oh he used as miles to get up here.
Um, anyways. Oh Jesus. I can,
I apologize early for the fucking
horrible fucking mood I'm in right now.
I was in such a great fucking mood. You
don't, and I was actually, you know,
walking down the street here in Manhattan.
It just laughing,
looking at these people,
so excited that I left this fucking place.
People in their twenties look.
Okay, all right. In Manhattan,
they just got here. It's still
exciting. Okay. But see this, this,
this city beat stuff. Fuck out of you.
All right. I've always said, you know,
if you can do it, if you have a desire
to do it, at some point you left.
You got to come here and
live here just to do it.
Cause it really is one of the most amazing
cities you're ever going to live in.
But you don't. What else is amazing about
after you let you owe it to yourself,
to Olivia, and you also owe it to
yourself at some point to fucking leave.
I swear to God,
Dude,
the amount of people that you see walking
down the street that looked like shut
ins, that finally just fucking came out
of the Cave of a God damn apartment.
Jesus Christ. I fucking walk into my
building and this lady standing there,
she looks like one of the
patients on shutter island.
Fucking dark circles under her eyes,
her hat,
Yag down like one of those people
that's like ageless. It's like,
are you 70 or 26 I don't even
know what you just, just,
your skin is gray,
right?
And she's with this older dude kind of
look like make it, to be honest with you,
a little chunk here, you know,
probably a lot more jollier.
He's probably not bitching
about the guacamole. Right?
And I'm fucking like, hey,
excuse me. As I go, hey, how are you?
And excuse me as I got to walk by and
she does like this weird like, Eh,
to get out of the fucking way.
Like, oh my God, another human big.
And then as I go to walk away,
she starts singing in this
beautiful voice is she walked out,
she had an amazing,
beautiful fucking voice.
Okay.
Assist. Why? What happened?
Jesus fucking Christ.
What's like the way she looked and then
the sound that came out of it was like
haunting. Then I felt like I was
in one of those horror movies.
You know that now I'm in and now I
can't get out. You know what I mean?
She's actually a vampire is going
to come by later to feed, you know?
Then I become her boyfriend forever
cause we're both vampires until she gets
sick of me and find a fucking, I
dunno, a younger version of me.
That doesn't happen. Right. The fucking
redheaded mail is never a love interest.
That doesn't happen in movies, you
know? Do you hear us bitching about it?
Ah, we boycott in anything. I
don't think so. We just trudge on
trying to stay out of the sun.
That's what it feels like when it
comes to New York. Everybody here,
did she just go, can you get some
sun in your fucking face? Something?
What's that vitamin you get when the,
when the sun shines on you?
It's what I was fucking things. And
everybody just says in a bar, Oh Yay Vita,
me son's good for you via
many, you know, not too much,
but you know it's good for you. You know
what they say? You know what they say?
It raises your levels of, oh is that
what they say? So what they say,
they're a guy with his fucking name on
his shirt. And what do you do? Well,
what do you for you fucking unclog
during the course of the day?
What are you talking medical here for me?
For me or to me? Why are you doing that?
All right,
fucking plumber.
I'd say they would. Extreme
prejudice. You know,
that's the one train I don't
respect to plumbing. You know,
cause I go to home depot and I swear
to God I can almost figure it out.
Electrical. That's like wizardry.
You're a fucking wizard. I pluck him.
He teases me. Me. He
just opened the doors.
It's everything's right there in the
sink. You know, once it goes in the wall,
then I give it to you. You know
what I mean? Then you're a closer.
All right? But if you just find
that we to hit it with a wrench,
he antique shut off the main fucking water
and you're,
you're, you're fucking, he, I don't
know what you're doing. You're your gun.
Screw it. Right. If you can,
you can fucking open and cold.
Or if you could take the lid off the jar.
Do you remember what the thing
is that's on top of a jar? Right.
You're smart enough to
be a fucking plumber.
I just don't respect that
trait. You know? Look, the the,
they really are, they're like welders
are the shit. Electricians have the shit.
People can fabricate stuff.
People will build hot rods. Those,
that's the upper echelon.
Those are the one they have like the,
I work with my hand awards, my hands,
I should say. They're not jerking off.
I work with my hands when
they have those awards. Right.
They got to have those at some point.
The, well these right, there's some shit.
Whatever the fuck it is.
You know,
those are the people that bring
home the fucking hardware.
Nobody gives it to a plumber. Plumber.
Yeah. Once you go on [inaudible]
what trade did you really
want to be good at? You know,
it's funny right now
there's a plumber out there.
It's actually getting upset by this
and someone will present it on another
website is if I was fucking serious.
Hang on, I'm trying to get to my
fucking password here. Plumber.
Jesus Christ. I mean, the whole fucking
state doesn't even sound respectable,
does it? Um, oh my God. To
the other night I fucking met.
Lie ahead for a drink. Okay. I was just
like, dude, I've been trying not to booze,
but I, I gotta I gotta have a couple, two
or three, right? So he goes, all right.
He goes, you know, I'm doing a spot.
I'll meet you over at this bar.
So we go to the bar and sitting there
with shooting the shit would have a great
time. And uh, this is plumber
thing, this is what reminded me.
So this big guy comes in and
by big I mean fat, all right,
big mother and hips to puts
it on like Oprah Fi's and ass.
And then he also puts it on like a dude
and he puts it on like a chick and a
dude. This was just a fat man
and you know, he, he was obese,
but he wasn't even biggest loser
fat. He just was, he was just tall.
He was a mountain of a fucking man.
So he sits down at the bar stool
just off to off of the,
you know, La heads,
right shoulder and it's a
really not a well lit bar.
And I'm just sitting there and I'm looking
and he's got this weird design
on his pants and I'm just like,
what the fuck is that? That's weird.
Is that a new style at genium,
those bedazzled jeans and everybody
was wearing like 10 15 years ago.
It looked like he had a horse shoe
on, on your pockets. You know,
the big thing was to
have the stitching it,
the blue jeans were blue and then
you had the, there was all white.
I never bought those.
I'm so fucking glad I never bought those.
There's not one picture of me and those,
it's already pictures of me and Z.
Cavariccis okay. I don't need,
I don't need to, you know,
jump on that trend either,
you know. So, um,
I'm sitting there going,
what is that design?
It looked like a like almost like he
ordered custom pants and they just,
they put this design right
and I looked a little closer,
my eyes adjusted and I realized
it was his Harry. Yeah, ass crack.
I couldn't fucking believe
it. Okay. This guy sat down,
he was so big, dude, I am telling you
there was the top of his ass crack.
He was so fat. It was like twice
the size of my whole ass crack.
That's why I didn't take her was that,
and it was fucking Harry,
I apologize for putting this image in you,
but it was Harry.
So it looked like it was a design and it,
I just can't fucking,
and head was caught my eyes when I
realize what I was looking at and he was
like, dude, what the fuck? And when
I told him what had just happened,
I don't think I've ever made
lie had laugh like that.
He was fucking howling
in this bar to the point.
I think even the guy looked over at us.
Oh my God,
I kept saying that. I said that you
could measure I was going to do it.
How can that be? How can
that be more ass? Correct?
Like this is weird. Like
when you lose weight, do,
like if you become a fat fuck
you have a giant s so yeah. This,
I never thought about this.
You have this giant fucking ass crack.
So when you lose the weight,
like the crack goes away too.
Right?
That doesn't seem like it doesn't make
sense to me cause it seems like it's a
hole in your body Kinda.
You know, I don't,
I don't know what I was trying
to figure it out. I was,
I was riffing about this
dog discussing this was a,
what the fuck did I say?
I would say,
and you remember that home run Mark
McGuire hitting the king dome off to Randy
Johnson.
I was saying you could measure that home
run with the amount of ass crack this
guy had coming out of the top of
his pants. And that was just his,
that was just as plumber crack.
Oh Jesus Christ.
What a fucking image they'd gone already
ate before I did this. Huh? Um, all right,
let's uh, I, Oh God,
I wish I had video of my,
you know,
they always do those reaction
videos that just fucking seat.
Like you must have done that before. I,
you know, when you're looking at, so, oh,
what is that? And then you
realize, you know, I don't know,
pretty mo gross things in your head.
Oh God, I got another disgusting story.
I should I do it at this point.
If he get grossed out easily.
Um, you know, you should have tapped
out by now. You want another gross one.
You know, I got to read the
advertising, I promise. I'll tell you I,
this one is really,
really fucking gross. Um,
all right, here we go. You're not
five minutes to tell you that the,
I'm going to tell you that one and
I'll tell you another one of like the,
basically the two grossest things
that ever happened to me on.
There's another one, Jason. He was funny.
They're all like fucking 15 years apart.
Like every 15 years. Like just something
fucking gross happens. Twosie Amy,
if you get lucky as a human
being. All right, here we go.
Let's get the reeds going here. All
right. Oh Shit. Here we go. Club Debbie,
clump Gabby for Jim Club. Debbie. Um,
if you're anything like me,
then you know exactly what you
like and how you like it. Well,
don't fucking talk shit for me.
If you're anything like me,
you question everything you do. And then
the next day, like, why did I say that?
All right. If you're anything like
the people that they think that I am,
you know what you like and how you like
it, except when you're in the wine aisle,
tannins in Ontario,
our hours mean nothing to you.
I got to know what the fuck those and
those, the types of wine, I guess,
unless you happen to be a fancy pants,
professional sommelier,
you know, there's no reason to shit on
people in wine just because you know,
they know something that you don't,
right.
It's not wizardry than making booze
that just into it. You know what I mean?
It's like listening to
somebody who's into star wars.
Really talk about star wars.
That's like, yeah, I saw it once.
What are you talking about? I don't
understand what you're in. They can like,
you know, they know the rock
that the fucking little,
what are those little chihuahuas?
I still remember that.
My brother collected the action
figure. Such a jealous, right?
Those little fucking secret
society looking fuckers. Right.
And then we're going to sacrifice a
virgin. Um, what was under that robe?
All right. Club W uh, please
include all of falling shit.
You read very well with
club Debbie full for champ.
Comops can't be Trump. Uh, the
guessing game is over club Daddy,
but daddy still loves me. Is the
world's most personalized wine club.
And your wines sent directly to your door.
Not only does club w he'd
come to my ranch, I'll make
you some burgers, sent what?
Send you wine. They send you wine
that you'll love drinking. Uh,
that's because club Dabi Club Gavagan
nothing happened on my watch except when
it did. Uh, easy six questions.
Quiz figures out your palate.
So I got to stop doing the club w
shit cause I can't read the fucking,
that's because club W's easy.
Six question quiz figures out your palate
so that every bottle you receive is
perfectly tailored to your
tastes. Collab. Debbie
is leading the grape to
glass wine revolution.
Okay.
Uh, they work directly with the
vineyard to cut out the middleman,
which saves you money. Club. Debbie
and Medan was at world war two.
Pilot ask if the war,
even others even offers a no risk
guarantee that you're going to love.
They'll send you or the love
what you send yours. Oh,
you get your money back to you.
And why don't we just fucking improvisers
thing cause I can't read right now. Uh,
and right now clubs,
Gavi,
is offering my listeners 50% off your
first order when you go to club Debbie
at.com/burr wind should be fun.
Not Pretentious. Start learning.
Well,
why don't you fucking escalate yourself?
Why do you got to bring
the wine world down?
You know,
listen this smarter than we are.
You know the fuck he want.
Start learning as you drink it.
Club Debbie at.com/burr I used to drink.
I don't drink anymore. I
speak Spanish. You'll leave.
We'll get 50% off your first order. That's
clubbed. Debbie a DOTCOM. Slash. Burger.
Has Anybody Seen Dick
Cheney? Alright. Legal Zoom.
To run a successful business,
you need to make the most of your
time and your money. Good News.
Legal Zoom can help you save both
during national small business month.
Legal Zoom is the smart way to start
your business. For some reason,
when I read like this,
I don't fuck it up right now.
When you incorporate or form an LLC,
you can also save money on some
of the basic shit I fucked up.
You can also save money on some of the
basics to get up and running like a three
month trial of quickbooks
online accounting software
and a domain name for a
year through web.com both at no
charge after your business is set up,
legal zoom can help you with a lot more
reviewing contracts and dealing with
the day to day legal hurdles takes time
away from growing your business.
That's why that's what legal
zoom business legal plan is for.
You get legal advice for your
business from independent attorneys,
licensed and for 48 states. Legally, I
just want to throw in an illegal in there,
somebody fucking legal. Uh, you also get
access to Ndas, lease agreements and more.
The best part is you won't
get charged by the hour.
Since legalzoom isn't a law firm.
Instead you pay a low monthly fee,
save time and money.
Start starting and running your
business during national small business
month@legalzoom.com today.
Don't forget to enter Burr and
the referral box at checkout.
That's legalzoom.com and also if you'd
like to contribute to this podcast,
but you don't want to give me any money,
next time you go to Amazon,
swing by bill bird dog cub,
click on the podcast page and all
you do is click the link to Amazon.
It takes you right to Amazon, doesn't
cost you an extra dime. And they just,
I get credit for driving traffic to this
site. You would go in there anyways,
but don't tell them all right then I'll
then I dedicate, you know, dedicated.
I donate, you know, a percentage
of what you give me 10%, you know,
to uh, to the fucking, uh, oh
Jesus. What the fuck's it called?
I'll go.
I always tell you the charities to cause.
So then you guys can tell me that
they're scams later. Saint Jude.
Nobody's gotten any dirt on these
fucking guys. Alright. Alright.
I'm not gonna tell you all the growth
stories. I'll tell. I'll tell Ya.
I'll tell you one quick one.
All right.
Okay.
Um, I was living, I have roommates,
I was living in this place.
And,
uh,
I got up early and I went
into the bathroom to take
a shower and I looked down
and what looked to be a brown wash cloth,
you know, that was all twisted up. Uh,
the bottom of the shower, I
think, you know, what's his going,
I reached down to pick it
up and if somebody had,
one of my roommates
had shit in the shower,
I never got over that.
I walk them all up,
they will all awoken by who?
Shit in the shower.
And they were laughing because I have
think laughing because it was hilarious.
And then also I started laughing
because it'd be literation later. I did,
but like,
I literally could not eat with that hand
for like fucking a month and thinking
now I actually, I don't remember which
hand it was, just fucking disgusting.
It's the, it's the closest thing. That's
the study. It funny. Is it the United,
if you laugh at that right now, you're
a sick fuck. Um, and who am I if I,
I told you about it, right? So
anyways, I was on the plane and um,
I started watching this
space movie and um, you know,
it's just another one of those space
movies where it's just like, you know,
everybody dies or people leave.
There's always just like the
one person left out in space.
How are they going to survive?
And I started to watch it.
It's like I already saw this
fucking movie two years ago.
Sandra Bullock did this
movie, right? She could go,
I left alone when Richard Gere fucking
floated off into sweat out his fucking
guys name is the guy with the
motorcycles, right? Married the lady,
finally guy from Ocean's 11, one of
those guys. He has so much charisma.
All he has to do is just say
the fucking line, you know,
is that the throw is and it's dirty
mustard on it. That Guy George Clooney,
George Clooney, he just says the
fucking line and yet believe them.
Right? Fucking guys fearless. You'd see
him in that movie. You didn't give a fuck.
Yeah, I'm just going to float off into
space. He's still cracking jokes and shit.
She going to go over here and
suffocate. Take it easy, Sandy. Right?
That's it, man. That's all man goes out.
I bet once she floated out of her
fucking ear shot, he started crying
as you sit there and
fucking floating around, um,
you gotta love Scifi. You know
I gotta Love Psi. You know,
I said I hate watching real shit about
space because all they do is just tell
you how infinite it is and
how insignificant we are.
It's like I get it. I got it.
Do you have anything else?
Have you filed one fucking living
thing out there? You have it.
So there's really nothing to report
other than it's so fucking immense.
And where we still don't have
the technology to meet anybody.
That's why if you really want
to see something about space,
she got to watch a Scifi movie,
you know,
say what you want a bottom
at least a fine shit.
You know there's car chases and
people, you know, a hot chick aliens,
right?
Space bars and stuff like that.
You fucking put on one
of those bravo shows.
Would that black guy there who fucking
knows everything. What's his name?
He's like that. He's like the guy
from the matrix, Laurence Fishburne,
except it's just fish board Fishburn
whatever. He's like that guy,
except he's real. It's a Lawrence is
real. I'm talking about his character.
I fucking watch that guy. I've watched
that guy like three times and I just was,
he had me believe in that.
We came from the trees. I'm
like, this guy is. Yeah, we,
and I was like, I thought we
came from the ocean, a mud.
I was going with that and this guy
was like, no, we're from the trees.
We've got the same fucking, I don't
know what he said, but I mean,
there was nothing between my ears.
I could argue with anything that he said.
You just have to fucking listen to it.
I'm not,
but just sitting there watching
the guy just going like,
this has gotta be what it's
like when you joined a cult.
Like how dumb I feel right now.
This is what you have to do.
Like I was reading this,
this fucking thing,
who's getting who I was browsing and
I don't really read anything. Um,
I saw this picture and I just
put words to it, my brain,
and now I'm telling it to you.
There's some fucking guy I know.
He had like 80 wives, one of those
fucking Weirdos out in fucking Utah.
You know what I mean? Did I? Oh,
either that or he's just like,
how come rappers don't
talk about those guys?
They're always talking about fucking
pimps. How could a guy, that's key.
The guy's got 80 fucking women.
They all know about each other and they're
all smiling in the fucking picture.
Huh?
I want to see somebody else pull that
off and not live in the middle of fucking
Utah. I don't know what
the fuck it is about Utah,
but you could talk a woman
into anything out there.
You're the a one for me. Hi. Yeah,
you and they'll 79 other bitches.
Okay.
But God, man, bitch. MMM.
This guy is in prison and he's
still running. That's this Harem.
They don't know any better.
You know when you're walking around with
a little house in the prairie close,
I mean, he could fucking tell
people anything. That's the key.
You know what I mean?
It's like if you want to start a cult,
it's very difficult to start
it with people that have
gone to a department store
and bought their clothes,
you know? But if you,
if there is a group of people that are
standing there and close that they made
themselves you, that that's where
you start. You know what I mean?
It's like when you got a shit team, all
right, and you got the number one draft,
pick the, the t, the guy,
the person you're going
to build your fucking team
around. That franchise player.
When it comes to cult,
those still to franchise tag is on all
those people with those little house in
the prairie close, those
Quaker close, right. The QC,
you know, you ever think about start? I'd
start at cult. I would do it, you know,
I would definitely start a fucking cult,
but then I,
after a while I wouldn't want to do
the work and I would just sort of,
I'd start like a,
what do they call that?
When you fucking don't want to do
your job and you have other people do
delegating. I'd start delegating all the
fucking things and granted one point.
So people are going to be like,
whoa, hey shit was Jason's,
how come he's not doing anything?
I don't remember reading anything
about change being be lazy.
Yeah,
let,
he just sits around and fucks everybody.
I'm going to check it is no
shit.
Maybe I'm Jesus.
Right?
And then he takes over and then all
of a sudden they all show up one day.
You know,
is there anything scarier than angry,
stupid people standing in clothes
that they made themselves?
Just picture what that would look like.
You know the amount of Mano Browse
staring back at you and you just have to
relinquish your power
and just at some point,
easy way out the back door and let them
know that you're not the son of God.
There's a fucking afternoon
for you. Huh? Jesus Christ.
Tommy deadbolts would you
have on your bedroom door? Um,
speaking of which,
by the way,
I got all the fucking interior
door locks fixed on my house.
They all have fucking skeleton keys.
And then I found this fucking
person on the Internet,
on the interweb is Richard Rollins
says from fast and loud. Uh,
another great shell.
Um,
okay.
I got some of that's going to line
it up with the door jam. You know,
the little fucking latch thing there.
And then I'm going to be good to go.
It's going to be, fuck. I can't
wait. Very excited about that.
And speaking of great shows, I'm
finally caught up with better call Saul.
I feel like such a, not only a
bad fan considering, you know,
Vince hooked me up to be in.
I'll have a small part in breaking bad.
I should have been watching right along.
But what happened was those of you
who listened to the podcast last year,
I fucking was taping the thing.
If for some reason I didn't get episode
three and then I suck computers and the
Internet, I couldn't figure out
where else I could watch it.
So I've been stuck on episode two.
So finally they came on Netflix
right before season two started.
And I just binge watched the entire
first season and it was fucking
unbelievable.
Yeah.
Who's fucking amazing
starts. It just, it's,
I don't want to ruin anything for you,
but I gotta tell you something like a,
the level of acting that,
that, uh, everybody's doing,
but like Bob owned Kirk, man,
you don't, it's very rare that someone
does, is as great a comic as he is,
is equally as great a fucking actor.
He was,
I want you guys to watch it
just because you got to see,
he has just blowout fight. I can't
ruin this for you. What's the relative?
Any now you just say
mean shit to each other.
Yeah.
Haze brothers says something to him.
I've been thinking about that line
for like the last five fucking days.
It was just, I don't know.
It's one of those lines.
Yeah.
That in real life usually get set around
the holidays after you've been sitting
on something for 20 fucking
years and when it comes out,
it's needle off the fucking record and
the relationship is over. It's just like,
yeah, dude, I'll see you when you're
on your deathbed or I'm on my deathbed,
or maybe never again. I mean, it's,
it's a fucking rap. It's over.
Um,
okay.
Oh Man. Though the writing was just,
it was just fucking outstanding.
And I'm the can't say enough good things
about it and I am totally caught up and,
uh, I can't wait for next week's
fucking episode. There you go.
There's my little plug there for
better call Saul. Um, and with debt,
that's it for this, uh, checking in on
your podcast. Once again, I apologize for,
you know, for not doing the
podcast on a timely fashion,
a timely fashion.
I where the fuck you said and I
realized that I brought up that APP.
Sorry about the shit in the shower story.
The ass crack one was funny.
I don't give a fuck
who you are by the way.
That APP is three 99 that I, when you,
if you want to listen to the towers,
anywhere where you're at, it's a
called live a t c. Dot. Net App.
Just do that ATC air traffic control.
Um,
and it's really cool.
Like I just thought you could
listen to the towers and near you,
but you can actually, um,
I was at lax today, Dan.
I was listening to,
uh,
Logan Airport in Boston and it's really
cool cause you, you're basically like,
I'll click on California, they got
Burbank, camera, real Concorde,
any place in El Monte,
any place you want to go to.
And when you click on it
as I'm doing right now,
okay, this one has ground and
tower and then you click on that.
Um,
and then there's what's really cool is
they have like a diagram of the airport.
So like you can actually, you know,
I like to listen to what, whatever,
whatever airport I'm at as
we're taxing to the, um,
to whatever the fucking runway,
Jesus Christ bells, you know,
you'd think you'd know that.
Um, go out to the runway.
I just like listening to it and it's
fucking cool as shit. And um, you know,
watching the,
um,
Jason Spill all the taxi ways going by,
sorry, I'm trying to multitask here.
Answering a text message. I apologize.
Let me just put the fucking phone down.
See that, see that, pick it up.
And all of a sudden I thought,
I'm just starts clicking on other stuff
and we'll start fucking looking at
Twitter when I'm trying to
do a podcast here. Anyway,
she got the whole layout of the airport
and as you're going down he can tell
what taxi way you're on. And then, uh,
right
there you go see that.
You just listened to that shit.
So that guy just obviously was cleared
to land and that was the runway and he
said his tail number.
That's it.
So I just listened to that shit because
that's one of the hard things when you
first get a pilot's license, when you
get up there and I'll just sounds like,
yeah, join it down. We're,
I'm gonna Plant Plant, plant. They
don't even have southern accents,
but that's what the fuck
it sounds like to me. Um,
you know what's funny is when
this shit happens, when I, uh,
when I'm just like walking around, like
I'll accidentally set up pocket dialing,
I'll hit this fucking APP.
And, uh, if you're in the mob,
do not get this fucking app because
they'll think it's a bunch of fucking feds
in a,
in a van down the street.
You know,
if you fucking sitting there in a mob
meeting and all of a sudden you got this
fucking thing going and you're talking
about some bullshit and out of nowhere
this thing comes on. Come on. Just do it
one time. One more time for me. Come on.
This is Lex. Oh, it's a
quiet night out there.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
All of a sudden you just hear some fucking
guys voice in there talking to some
official,
hey,
who the fuck up their fucking,
next thing you know the Yan can get
tongue through your throat. Um, all right,
so that was a long way to go. Why would
it go? Who uses a prop and a podcast?
All freckles does. Hey, go
fuck yourself. She can't.
So I hope you have a great weekend.
And I a little music from Andrew Samela
sat a little throwback podcast from a
Monday or Thursday gone by,
you know, a few weeks ago somebody
was asking me, Ah, you know,
they wanted to break up with somebody and
I was saying, listen, you gotta listen,
you know,
the person who has it down how to do
the breakup was minivan men podcast,
own celebrity star Al Madrigal.
But if you don't have
time to email Al Madrigal
just listened to ll cool j a big old,
but
I don't know why. I never really listened
to him when I was growing up. You know,
Mama said knock you out. Oh, did
shake, is that what she said?
Ll Cool J I don't care. You
know, I just wasn't into it.
And his deodorant and his armpits when
he was jamming with those white guys.
I just,
I never got into it.
But lately like I dunno, I
dunno what happened. I, Geez,
just come onto my youtube
shit. I don't know what it is,
but I was listening to some of his
stuff. Oh, I know why. Yesterday.
I was trying to remember like what was
that song he used to have that I'm the
type of guy and you're the type of guy
get put back, but what the fuck was that?
And then I listened to it and I kind
of liked it, but I hated that. Oh,
we owe part of it really
annoyed me. I'm like, oh,
that's why I never downloaded this shit.
But then on the side they
had a ll cool j big old,
but you know I played drums at Michael.
Let me hear what this tracks track
sounds like. Can I put it on?
And he basically teaches you how to
break up with a girl and that song,
but that rap or that, uh, that rhyme,
whatever, however you supposed to say it,
he breaks it down and just
in like fucking 11 seconds,
he sits his girls down.
He's basically hanging out and like some
sunglass hut or some shit and some girl
comes in with an insane ass and
he does what every guy does.
He stares at it. He thinks I want to fuck
that, but oh shit, I have a girlfriend.
So what does he do? Does
he sneak around on her? No,
he goes home and he sits her
down and he says, listen,
I met this girl named Tina.
Okay, Tina's got a big old,
but I know that I said I'd
be true really whiteness up,
but Tina got a big old butt
so I'm leaving you. It's,
I mean that's just fucking airtight.
You can't fuck with that.
He was 100% I don't even
know if she could get mad.
I think that I think women's show expect
guys to be lion weasely pieces of shit
that if you actually hit him
with that level of honesty,
I think they would just be stunned.
Just like the chicken, the video,
like I didn't think that
that was bad acting.
I think that they would absolutely be
stunned if you just came home and said,
listen, I met this girl. I know that.
I said it'd be faithful to you,
but she's better looking than you,
so I'm breaking up with you.
What is the combat?
There's nothing that'd be like if
your girl came home and said, listen,
I know we're together,
but this guy, you know,
I met him at the mall is Dick is twice
the size of yours and he's got a better
car. So, uh, it's kind
of a no brainer. Amati
what are you going to do?
What are you gonna do with your little
dick in your fucking Domino's pizza?
It's over. You just got to fucking be
like, you know, you only go around once.
So, uh, yeah, I, I, I get it.
So anyway, so if you don't have
time to a email Al Madrigal,
which you should,
which you should just listen
to a ll cool j big old bud.
You got to see his face. He
goes, so I'm leaving you. It's,
it's, I don't, can't explain it.
It's way meaner than it has to be.
That's what it makes it funny
cause there's a way to read that where
you kind of letting them down easily,
you know, but he didn't,
he just did it like, yeah,
this is how it works. So there
you go. Look at that on a holiday.
Um, anyway, so this is the Monday morning
podcast. It is the end of May. Everybody.
All right, how many days are
in May? 30 days has September.
His throat is April and November.
All the rest have a bunch of other
dates except for stabby wary Yag.
Go Fuck yourself with your song.
Um,
she got 30 31 fuck, what is it?
April has 30. June has 30 maze.
31 I got the little thing.
I can click right here. Oh, I have a
computer. I don't need to think right.
It has.
Why is it in September?
Oh for Christ sake, do I have to
click another button? It has 31 days.
All right,
so you had till have,
do you guys have until Thursday
midnight to make something of May,
2012. All right. Are you in a fucking
relationship? You don't want to be in?
Do you want to be in this relationship?
You don't want to be in, in June?
Why don't you celebrate the end of
May by getting out of your fucking
relationship and sitting down
and basically just go
with the ll cool j vibe.
Hold her hand and just go straight up
honesty and then w w what's she gonna do?
What's he going to do if they're
going to flip the fuck out,
but the the die has been
cast to ship is set sail.
The ball is already rolling. The
Sun is setting, the rain has fallen.
Wherever the fuck you want to call it.
It's out there. Just put it out there,
let him scream and yell and
then you had as much as he suck,
you're going to be like,
okay, I did it. I did it.
Now I just got to sit here
and get yelled at. And uh,
how long could somebody really yell
before they lose their voice and hour,
90 minutes and an hour and a half.
I'm going to be in the car listening to
ll cool j driving away from that thing I
didn't want to be in. All right then.
I know I talk about this shit a lot,
but I think a lot of people
are in situations like this
and they don't know how
to sit somebody down. It
just say, so I'm leaving you.
You know, if I was ll cool
J and I stop, you know,
selling tickets and all that type of shit,
that would be a side business
that I would have. I would take,
okay,
that little fucking rhyme that he had
and I would custom do it for everybody in
their life and just, and then
people who just write you all right,
I need to charge it. You charge them 100
bucks and he would write you a, you know,
four bars. It all rhymes and
you just get out. Exactly.
Okay.
What you say it,
you know?
Okay.
Just be like you eat with your mouth open.
I know I said that I'd be true.
Yeah,
but you eat with your mouth open
so I'm leaving. You just get right.
Get right down to it.
Your mom is a fucking con.
I know I said that I'd be true,
but she's fucking always
coming over here and,
and something that rhymes with
[inaudible] you I, you got the,
you got the idea right? Jesus
Christ. What do I have to be yellow?
Okay,
let's get back into this. Mark from a
dozen a fury. Yeah, I guess so. All right.
Hi. What's up? [inaudible] standing
here with the guys from a theories,
I think. How do you guys
think you sound one today? No,
I think it went really well man.
I mean it's probably that then the
hottest day so far and the whole tour.
But you know, we're Texas boys. Where
do you see the hate? So I get up there.
Let's do our thing man.
So you guys are like brand new.
You guys have won a contest or something
to get on this? Um, yeah, I mean we,
we won a contest to be on the show.
I mean to, you know, be on the tour.
But you know,
we've been a band for about two years now.
I've been torn on her own and
doing her own thing and you know,
this was pretty much just a blessing
and a big step forward for us.
Definitely a blessing. How, well
this is what I'm trying to get these guys
to say some fucked up like what you do
on tour and these guys,
we still have to cover it in tattoos.
They all look like Mick Mars.
Yeah, Motley Crue and they just,
I'd like the nicest guy.
Like everything's a blessing.
Everything blessing to be here. I know
what I said at the last days. God willing,
we'll go on for the next tour.
I'll try to angle it towards some sort
of smart and they just keep going back to
the church. Remember that when we
did the Oz fest thing and they're,
they're eating vegetarian meals backstage
tofu and drinking a little green tea.
It's like, what's your old,
you're going to help set it up.
They and watch behind the
music they saw not happens.
Meanwhile you listen to behind them to
say a contract soundtrack to hell is
playing.
Right.
I know there's something going on in the
background that just listen to music.
How well, how well do people know
you're here? Um, so far it's been great.
I think we've done two signings and
they've been tagged it tons. A kid.
What's the, what's the biggest asshole
crowd you guys have been in front of him?
Just been like, fuck you. You're
the open advance. None yet man.
They've all been really cool.
I think like not expecting us to
do what we actually do. You know,
everybody thought we were still be
some MTV show man and stuff like that,
but it turns out, you know,
everybody's like, man,
you guys blew us away
and it's really cool.
Like there's lots of boards from the fans
and shit. So I mean that's cool. Hey,
you have the other drama,
right?
Have you ever like went to throw the drum
sticks in the crowd and some dude was
pissing you off so you can
kind of rather than tossed it,
just fucking throw it at him?
Not really that. It's just not,
could put an eye out.
We wouldn't do things like that.
That makes sure a rubber tips and I guess
we have special styrofoam drum sticks
that we throw out. So it was not to injure
any of our loving fans. Wow. They'd,
we're not biting. Even these hardcore
fans have become PC. It gets even better.
I sat out,
it starts like
see again. So many people talk
really called so long person
who gets the most puzzling. None
of us. We're all, we're all,
we're all taking man.
Ah, we're in loving
relationships with lovely women.
It's just, it's just the
most anti rock and roll. Wow.
Can Roll band.
Yeah, we're rolling. You
guys are the tattoos.
I'm thinking is this going to be maniac
going back there? You guys all committed.
Oh, rock mineral. Everybody got a baby
on the way. You went to one house.
Got a daughter already. The rest
of, what's her name? Madison.
Madison pass and that's it.
Oh,
and then the names of their kids.
Safe Madison destined for a polo.
I couldn't Madison,
you know exact names. His son, right?
Hendrix handed her Jimi
Hendrix got a fucking animal.
It's still the real deal is an animal.
But these newer bands, you know Billy,
just try beautiful Ryan. I got, I got
them to do a PSA though in the end.
What's her name? Um, Madison Madison
Pass. That's a beautiful name and went.
No one is skin cancer awareness thing
here right now. Opie and Anthony.
So if you guys could just say
something to make, you know,
the kids are wearing about skin cancer.
Just swing at anything.
Throw a couple of bucks in there. So
the kids will listen to it. You know,
we are out in the sun all day long,
every day,
and we put on probably like five times
throughout the day, man. You know,
you gotta take care of yourself,
got take care of you start over again.
Just throw a couple of flux
in there. Seriously? Yeah,
yeah. Over there. All right.
Just say, you know, skin
cancer awareness. I man,
we're fucking caught facts and
we put on a lot of sunblock.
Fuck yeah, we're out of the
fucking sun all day long, man.
It's just fucking beat down
on you. And you know, dude,
you got to fucking take care of him dude.
You gotta wear sunblock and
away and over and over again.
Especially you want to keep in touch with
fresh shoes. You need to tighten it up.
Just just tightened it up real quick.
Where are your fucking sunblock?
Right?
Listen,
you can do
each with each band.
Cause I had no idea what they were.
So with each band I just made
whatever the PSA was more ridiculous,
just always had them like throw it. Just
throw a couple of fucks in there. Yeah,
the kid,
you know the crazy something with a
little rock and roll attitude going into
that. I was like, ah, audio from a band
called it doesn't furious. Who Cares?
That was really interesting on
a lot of levels. Oh, they just,
the job bill burr boarded me. You
ever have an orgy? Ah. You know,
I'm more just like one on one connection
with somebody, you know, feelings,
very monogamous and our relationships,
they're just not living that rock and
roll lifestyle. But at the last name,
whole arms. No, I understand.
I understand. They got
all the luck in the park.
You've got the piercings and tattoos.
Mixed messages, yes. All right.
What about this band? Shadows
fall? Yeah, same shit.
I just would ask them questions and we'd
go nowhere and then I just had them do
a PSA. I did. Well we got to
listen to until we get to the PSA.
It's Brian from shadows fall.
No, it's up still bar
opening. Anthony show.
I'm talking to Brian Pfaff and
satisfying. Great. That man.
How'd you feel about it? Oh, it's
what else? Man? The whole hospice.
This is incredible, man. You know,
sharing a stage with me and Sabbath
does doesn't get better than that.
How to help me sing like that for so long.
And I yelled at my dad like that about
20 minutes. I'm used to it for you.
Hold on my girlfriend, how much,
you know, you know, builds it up.
You've got to build the strength,
you know, like, you know what,
I'm going to do that drop
right now. You know, it's good.
I'm glad you brought that up.
We had a open,
Anthony's doing like a thing for like
domestic violence awareness. Yes.
Somebody kicked the shit out of their
girlfriend and like Newark or something.
So yeah. So just, just ad Lib,
some sort of dropped and not to domestic
violence to your girlfriend or whatever.
Not, and you know, it's kind of weird,
but toss a couple f bombs and
that I listened to as a retarded,
but just try to keep the good message.
So just describe shells fall.
Oh,
it's such a great gag.
Rockville.
You're gonna have to come back and
Redo this, uh, this new Gig, right?
This is your thing,
girlfriend, you know, fucking don't beat.
If you grow this bribe
and shadows fall man,
you gotta stop punching
your girlfriend out there.
Save that shit for the bedroom. You
know that's where it's at. But you know,
don't take it to the streets.
Okay.
Do it again is just throw like
one fucking got their idiots.
What's those five shadows fall? Just say
stop hitting your fucking girlfriend.
You Idiots. All right. Saved to
violence for the bedroom. Cool. So uh,
what do you guys call from him? Uh, after
this? Uh, where the hell are we doing?
Well we're two days here and then we
got yo, I don't even know where we go.
Dust and they bring me where I got
to be. That's hilarious. What do you,
what did you think about playing out
here in the eye? The parking lot.
Do you think it was, give me one like
a seated area cause I know I did.
I was thinking like we're actually,
we're all on the main stage
so you know that's it.
I like the parking lot by it actually
better cause there's no seats in a way.
Cause he can go crazy.
Let's stay,
you know we're going to be
played with where their seats.
So it's a little different,
but you know it works out.
How long you guys been a band full? Oh,
almost 10 years. X amount. Well good deal.
You got to, you've got a new album
or anything coming out the war.
What with it's been
out for a little while.
We're going to be doing one more tour
after all semester and then working on new
records. So keep an eye out for
that. Well that's awesome. Well,
always keep us post event. Thanks. Thanks
for that. Domestic violence, right?
Already. Not should have that funny. Don't
beat up your fucking girlfriend. Bombs.
They're idiots. Sacred for the
bedroom. Save it for the bedroom.
Once it punch her in the bedroom.
Oh God damn. Is that funny?
That's really good. We got one
more here from Peter from inflames.
Hey, what's up? Hoping Anthony Shell.
You know that you listen to this shit.
I'm with the bass player from
installation speed. I was, hey,
how was your set today man? Uh,
it's going to be fine. All right,
we need to start that again.
So I don't look
like a retarded
assessing.
Do you said going to go tonight
looking forward? You on the main stage?
I think it's going to go great.
We always put in 150% know
sitting down crowd,
but so far the oldest shows has been
nice and so I'm pretty sure today will be
as well. So you guys don't like Yo
vibe, you come home mellow, melodic.
Does that like how you guys are? I
think we're metal. It's, you know,
it's hard to categorize us.
It's basically all right.
So you're not like, I had made me watch
movies and stuff. You're like, I made me.
I guess we could say that,
but it wouldn't be unfair probably
to just categorize it into, you know,
we're metal bat. That's cool man. That's
cool. How long have you guys been playing?
A long time.
I think it's like 12 years.
Something like five years. Everybody in
the band. If you had to kill someone,
who would you kill myself?
The road sign and gets you?
No, no, but I mean it wouldn't be fair.
God, there's just no one would go
with it. No one wants to come next.
Fair to the others.
Wouldn't be fair.
Otherwise. I like this guy.
This guy can tell you like the
peacekeeper in the band, right?
You're like the mellow one. Unless
the man, what else is doing now,
this is kind of a side name,
but kind of doing this so there's benefit.
Somebody beat up a special
needs kid and like, no. And uh,
so we just want you to just say,
you know,
just give a shout out to the kids so they
know not to beat up somebody with like,
you know, special needs, you know,
so just, you know, say like a,
you know, hey guys, you know,
it's not cool to beat up on somebody just
because they're different or whatever.
You know, just, you know, just
like a quick kind of like, uh,
like a soundbite and it's kind of weird,
but throw a couple of puffs in there
just cause I find the kind of retarded,
you know what I mean? So
you didn't like, you know,
just winging it goes,
it was the spirit of room place.
She shouldn't treat
everybody equally and uh,
don't beat anybody up or
do something bad to them.
Just feel so different and
everybody is the same way. Okay.
That's totally the perfect vibe.
Just throw in special needs and
throw in like one or two fucks.
They have the awkward, it's kind
of like I said, they're retarded.
Same thing again or sorry,
the spit of blue flame.
Treat everybody the same way. It'll be
people still special needs to reflect us.
Go and fucking go on to and do any which
would cause a different Truett ever go
to the same. That's beautiful.
And the kid's name is Russell.
Just give him a shout out to Sam Fox and
a big metal fan. So it means a lot to,
unless the kid has got beat up, Russell
from newer Russell, the fuck you doing
six hours of do. That's beautiful. Matt,
thanks so much and good luck tonight.
Holy Shit. You are insane. I
love it. All in the same breath.
I wish you could see the
looks on their faces.
They're trying to wrap them fucking head
around the concept. I don't doubt it.
I love how the same breath you saying
this poor special needs kid. Yeah,
I'll listen as a fucking retarded.
They use this archaic term like retarded.
Oh, oh wow. Bill. That's
great. That was great.
Just to add special needs and throw a
fucking there and they just do it to say
how to Russell obnoxious drown
the clown guy. What's this? Oh,
this guy was one of the funniest
acts that I've ever seen. He was a,
what's it called?
Drown the clown.
He basically get all the
Dunkin stool at dunking.
So some guy is sitting there on this
clown masks and he's just trashing these
people. Half of them are fucking like
totally old jokes, but he says, Hey,
look at the white trash
people add you fucking loser.
And then he just had this
maniacal laugh like the clown Lou,
and then he'd just go, at the end
of it, it was so fucking of Nazis.
He got some skinny kid.
He kept calling him a crackhead and this
dude is literally walking behind what
you throw the balls that go,
come on down, come on down.
He wanted to kick is a kick his ass.
He would get these people so mad in,
there'll be like 20 of them
and he'd get him so mad,
but by the time that they
actually like dumped him,
they would all start giving the
finger go, fuck you. Fuck you.
You might need video on this one. I
don't know. I was taking a lesson.
It's obnoxious.
Drown the clown guy.
You want to know?
Quick to say on
what do you want to be when you get older.
All right,
and then he's taunting him.
All pissed.
Here's a noxious drown the clown guy.
I guess a chick with no boobs
was in the area. Huh? Hey Mommy.
I know you love me. You just
don't know. We get babies.
You visit CBGBS before.
Yeah.
You know why I can read your shirt if
you're a clock of the dream for this group
back then a pound
time.
Kibbles offense. I was going to
get me some tables. Let's face
I,
I've got one more drug for
you. Hey Gee, I can look at me.
You got to have,
yeah,
it was just all jokes.
Just fucking the most horrendous jokes.
And you said,
ah,
and it sounds like Keith Robinson,
I love this guy,
knocks his ass asshole.
You could have seen these fucking
people standing around how they are all,
there was one dude,
he had like a,
he was like completely bald on top and
he had a hat on and he took, he just,
I don't get lost. This happened. His face
was like, like Puerto Rican Brown. Right.
And then his fucking head
was totally waiting. Lose up.
Well your fucking head.
Yes.
Screaming at Adam and this fucking guy,
he's just losing. Yeah. I look at my head
and then they would try to throw the
balls even fucking harder and they're like
missing by like 20:00 PM and every ball.
Oh, what an asshole. It was actually,
it was literally like a better
job than stand up in a way. Yeah.
He didn't have to just fucking sit
there like God damn parking lot.
You're able to do an act. You just
fucking irritated people's time. People.
And it doesn't matter how bad
they try to heckle you back.
We've got more from the
obnoxious drown the clown guy.
What are you talking about?
Hey,
I know you ain't got a green card.
It was like Mexican.
Do we isolate that? He the
worst. Get that on my machine.
All right. Another loser that he was
making fun of him. Ron, Ron, Ron,
what are you going to do lose out?
We were standing up there for like six
hours and you heard that last like every
three seconds. People like,
I'm going to fucking kill it.
I put my head on the pillow and that's
all I hear. Is that guy laughing.
What are you doing?
I
mean the second part of it done.
Oh, he wouldn't do the light. He could
only do the laugh when he was there.
He probably doesn't even know what
you're talking about. The APP part.
You look like what?
That red shirt on.
Oh my gosh, I gotta do that all day.
That lasts. Just knocks down the street.
We've got to get that guy on the show.
How we get a hold of that guy has,
we need him on the show. I'm the clown.
We need him. At the next road show, man,
starting to put together
our first anniversary show.
Someone says it's Nice a lot,
Colin Quinn getting worse.
You wouldn't have understood the tonsil.
Something ironic
on many years ago.
It's probably three years in the business
and some guy was heckling me and he
just
talked to him after the show and he's
really a cool guy and it was one of those
guys. He's one of those fucking
balls to really have. Yeah,
some of them like that guy.
Pretty good at.
It doesn't matter how old the
jokes are. Not. Doesn't matter.
You got to see you say with the right
attitude, it's going to work. You know,
piss people off. It's fence. See,
just like if you're completely uninhibited
and you're not going to shut up,
you'll win every time. Yeah.
Very funny stuff. Build.
You've got to leave or I can hang
out a little bit after 10 all right,
cool.
We'll take a little wacky.
[inaudible]
yeah.
What am I talking about here?
Can they show that fucking John Malcovich
talking to his phone and just having
the time of his life commercial.
One more fucking time.
What's more annoying that one or
where that weird family does the, uh,
the acapella version of
Ozzy Osborne's crazy trade.
Would that random black kid in the back?
Like where did they get that kid? Like,
you know,
it was he an exchange student.
Okay.
And he just seems like he's over all of
it and not enjoying hanging out with the
other white people as he fucking shakes
the ice in his, in his great drink,
you know,
and then they gotta end that great song
with the parents singing like they're on
Broadway.
Right.
You know,
anybody else with me on that? John fucking
Malcovich sitting there or you know,
if that,
if that commercial was 30 seconds longer,
he'd have the phone like blowing him.
Tell me the joke.
Do I have anything coming up tonight now?
Oh,
lobster souffle or whenever.
Pretentious fucking foodie orders.
Was it pretentious, Bill, or
are you just not cultured in,
in his order made you feel dumb.
All right, you got me on that one.
You got me on that one.
Um,
I'm the only one who's creeped out that
there's a fucking robot in my phone.
Okay.
Oh, whatever it is, it's that
they try to make it human.
Why did they do that? Just
make it sound like a robot. No.
Can I have him massage Parlor Tyra?
Just do it like that. So I,
it still keeps that like,
yeah,
we keep that distance.
I don't need intimacy with this
thing that isn't fucking alive.
I don't need that 2001
space odyssey experience.
That's all I'm trying to say here. People,
oh, he's bill burr. He's mad at phones.
Get outta his way. Everybody.
This guy's got shoved to say,
what's the deal?
Oh,
[inaudible].