Hey, what's going on is Bill
Barr and, uh, just checking.
Just checking in on you on Thursday. Cleo,
get over there and lay the fuck down.
You're driving me nuts today.
You're a maniac. I still love you.
That's only because you're cute, if you
will. Not ugly dog like a poop. Nope.
Get over there and lay down, down, down.
Lay the fuck down. The mastery spoken.
Um, what's going on? How
are you? Oh, why? Yeah.
Welcome to another Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday afternoon.
Fucking morning podcast,
whatever I call it that just checking
in on your podcast for short, you know,
uh Oh, what a couple
of days it's been, oh,
what a couple of nights bubble.
Jesus Christ.
Unfucking believable.
All right.
I've already had myself all a
hell of a Goddamn Day, right?
I finally got my God damn truck,
Beck, right? Brand new engine.
Everything was going great. And then, uh,
you know, I look cool for about six hours,
six fucking hours. And then, uh, there
was something going on with the clutch.
I don't know what was going on.
He's guys that take a to do
fucking phenomenal work they do.
So some of the sickest fucking hot
rod trucks I've ever seen in my life.
And I think what fucked me over
is one of the parts, you know,
they make them in China now.
You know,
cause they don't want to play Americans
cause they don't want to fuck with the
unions and then it's not
enough that they're going to
underpay some poor Chinese
guy over there. Cause people
always go, all the Chinese,
they don't fucking make them right.
They'd make them right if he gave
him the right fuck of materials.
What's that Chinese guy supposed to do?
Fucking uh, you know, fucking, I dunno,
pull up God goddamn clutch out of his,
out of his stomach like a
chicken heaven aserion section.
Um, whatever the fuck
materials they give them,
that's what they're going to put
together. So anyways, he's trying to say,
maybe it's, maybe it's that thing. So I'm
back to drive in some fucking car shape.
Look at God Damn Dinner Roll.
So why that guy got that going on right.
Um, I went down, took a helicopter,
you know, fucking thing here.
I'm getting ready to do my check. Ride
flew great. Everything was going good.
My auto's what great nose was dipping
down a little bit, but you know,
I recovered and then a, all of a sudden
my clutch was acting up. So I'm like,
Oh fuck right. It's all
freckles. Needs a hair cut.
Who's getting to all you
do is just buzzing. My head
takes two fucking seconds.
So driving up, I usually have this lady
do it, but she's off today. So I said,
you know, I need it. I'm taking
my wife out. Fuck it man.
I'm just going to get my head buzzed.
Right? So I go by, there's a barber shop,
little candy stripe fucking sign thing
going. So I pull over, I walk in,
there's one dude sit in there,
there's no barbers. Right?
And I'm looking around and they got,
they got fucking a this selling combs,
right?
They got all these fucking vintage hot
rod magazines that playing music from the
1950s all of this should have been a
warning, but it wasn't. I was just like,
oh, all right, that's of cool, whatever,
and then this fucking guy comes
walking out wearing this smock,
indicate that he was a barber
and I'm immediately thinking, I,
this guy next to me, he's
first, right? The guy goes,
he walks out, he sees me. He
goes, oh, hey, how are you?
Sorry. I say, I'm doing good.
How are you doing? He goes, great.
He goes, are you have an appointment?
I'm like, do I have an appointment?
What do you mean appointment? He goes,
you've got to make an appointment here.
I'm like, dude, is a barbershop. I think.
I said, what is this, a hair salon, and
he's going over to the book looking at it.
He goes, Oh, you know, I can get you. I
got you. I just want to get my head bust.
Take like five minutes.
There's nobody fucking ear you can be.
Damn this thing halfway done.
You're chark off right inside.
I was thinking that right now.
Then he's fucking look at his log book.
I just said, forget it.
Forget it. I'm out of here.
Fucking assholes done
with that place for life.
God Damn fucking hipsters, man.
They've ruined everything. You know?
I didn't realize that wasn't a barbershop.
That was an ironic barbershop.
That's why they had the old magazines.
That's why they had Frankie Valli
and the four seasons playing.
Okay?
Rather than some old guy
come walking out this,
this fucking 30 year old guy walks out,
he can't cut my fucking hair.
This is what's funny.
I fucking drive away my truck with
the fucked up clutch now. Now,
now I'm really losing my shit because I
get in. Don't try to push the clutch in.
It won't go all the way to the floor.
So I've got to push it a little
harder to get some ungodly sound in my
transmission. So me,
and I'm like, all right,
I'm not going to take this back to
the place because when I'm driving it,
it's fine.
But when I would stop for whatever reason,
wouldn't go all the way to the floor.
So by all means,
all you fucking weekend warrior gear
heads. Please tell me what it is. Oh,
I know what it is. I know. Jackie,
why do you fly wheel dog kicked
over to quick chefs. Shut up.
Sorry.
So anyways,
so I go to fucking drive away and uh,
who's standing out in front of the
fucking barbershop on his iPhone? Oh,
fucking the barber shop guy
checking his tweets or some shit.
Okay.
And I'll make it, I just
fucking drove away. Just like
beside myself. Just go like,
what the fucking God damn hipsters.
They fucking ruined.
They haven't ruined anything. It's
just a so fucking, and this is,
why can't you just be yourself?
You know,
why does everything
have to be like mocking?
So why did get my kid you just
like I sweat. You know what it is?
Cause he could took off their facial hair,
wear their glasses,
and they'll Robert Fulton fucking
God damn outfit. Yeah. You know,
what would you be left with? They'd
have to be themselves and you know what?
They're not fucking interesting.
Yeah.
Jesus fucking Christ. Really
build. Do you have to go this big?
Yes I do. It's a barbershop. Okay.
You fucking walk into a barbershop.
You sit down,
there's a bunch of old guys there with
their balls going down to the floor
wherein smelly fucking old awful slacks
with horrific shows and all you start
thinking is,
wow,
I guess that social security really
isn't going to be there for me.
That's what you'd think when you go
into a barbershop fucking dickheads.
They should have to take that fucking
signed out or at least put it in quotes,
barbershop. Right? Is this a dumb
thing to be mad at? Well, fuck you.
I don't care. This is this. You know,
I didn't want to be this man
coming on the fucking podcast.
I'm getting over a goddamn summer cold.
What's the world coming to,
man, you can't walk into a barbershop
to get your fucking head bust.
There's nobody there.
And there's one guy standing there
and he asked you if you have a fucking
appointment. It's a, is this
a Maserati dealership? What?
What the fuck are we doing here?
Right? Just have me sit down,
put the fucking apron around my neck
and just add,
what do you usually do? I usually go
down to the skin. Then the half of them,
one and a half on top of one day, he'd go
big bang, boom. The Allie, Allie, Allie,
I'm done. Here's your 20
bucks. God bless Ya. Right?
Well, I have an appointment and he walks
over. He looks at the fucking book, Jesus,
because it should have been somebody
get their nails done over in the corner.
Can you call yourself a barbershop?
When you take appointments,
you never have appointments.
You just show up, right?
I went to a barbershop when I
went, I was fucking back in, uh,
back in Massachusetts. I
wouldn't a house, right?
Just fucking walked in,
sat down.
So fucking old guy or
door fucking shut down,
gave me the same hair cut.
He gives a fucking stay true in and out.
I did it on the way to the gym.
What are the great things?
One of the few great things about having
a shaved head as far as you'll never
get lice again is it takes
you two seconds, right?
You just go in these zoom, zoom,
zoom, you don't give a fuck.
Who does it done over and
then you fucking leave.
Now the great thing is whenever
you're going out, you know,
you can just throw a shirt on.
No one knows he didn't take a shower
because you'll never have bedhead again.
So I guess there's two positive six,
but you know what,
what are those positive things
was taking away from me today?
And I'm really sad about you guys.
I'm not Jesus Christ. So people have
told me a bunch of shit to go off on. Uh,
I got, one thing I want to go off on was
fucking Robert Kraft for some reason.
Just rolling over and tapping out,
okay,
what happened to the other owners?
Get together and just say, listen,
we know Jim or say is a pain in the ass,
but you know,
this is just going to
bring negative publicity.
The NFL and over the last 24
fucking months, fucking understand.
Now was a fan.
I have to sit back.
It take the fact that a league that
didn't pay taxes since 1942 this is the
first fucking year they're paying
taxes. Right? How funny is it?
I want to go on a rant.
I have a fucking stuffed up nose.
Hang on one second cause I have a summer
cold cause I'm a drunk who can't go
home at night. Hang on a second. I'm back.
The NFL did not pay taxes
from 19 two until last year.
2014 this is the first year
they're paying taxes. You know,
meanwhile, whenever the military goes
out on the field, does a display,
they have to pay the NFL and the NFL
sits back and acts like they support the
troops. They don't support the troops.
They charged the tropes. Right.
And then on top of that, according to
the Internet, so you know it's true.
You know it's from that
whole pink campaign.
The NFL keeps 97 or some 95 97% of
all the money from the pink hats,
the pink mugs to Pink Jersey.
Then they give it to the pink fucking
Aa and she keeps like 90% of that,
so they raised like a billion dollars.
The NFL keeps like 970 million,
gives 30 million to the pink lady,
right?
She keeps 90% of that and then she peels
off $2 million for breast cancer and
all these fucking scumbags is
sailing around a giant picky on.
These are the fucking people that
are going to judge my Tom Brady.
They're going to call him a cheetah
because of fucking air pressure.
You know what I mean?
I have to sit back as I got to
sit back and take it as a fan.
Tom Brady's a cheater because he went
up against the colts and Andrew luck the
how did the colts get Andrew Luck,
by the way. Oh No, no big deal.
They just tanked an entire season.
Bilking every fucking NFL fan completely
against the rules. Lost on purpose.
They did it every fucking week for
16 games. Was there an investigation?
Whether it's suspensions was, they're
fine. Now they're from Indiana.
Those are good down home folks out there,
man.
They put their pants on one leg at a time.
They sit down with a ring.
The dinner bell like got
one of the highest clan
memberships north of the Mason
Dixon line. This is Indiana. They
couldn't do anything wrong up there.
We shouldn't even been facing Andrew Luck.
Do you know ESPN?
They did that study and they showed
that the deflated ball was actually a
disadvantage.
Espn took it down within 30 minutes
because it was going to end the story
because it was in their best
interest to have it be an advantage.
They took that fucking thing down,
so I got to sit here and sit back
with a guy who sits on a fucking rules
committee and changes rules for the colts
so they can finally beat the Patriots.
Win a Superbowl, no suspension, no
fine, no investigation. Right? Hey,
here's the funniest thing. First game,
Brady comes back. Who? Who they playing?
The Indianapolis Colts.
This is like this.
This is like promoting a
summertime blockbuster.
It's complete fucking horseshit from
top to bottom, but you know what?
Craft tapped out. So that's
it for me. I tap up, you know,
unless at some point I go on,
I am Rapaport and I school
that sad ass Knicks fan.
Yeah.
You listening to me Rappaport, you've
been ducking me on this podcast. Oh,
I'm talking to you Michael.
Huh?
Not talking to you I and DB page.
I respect the shit out of that.
But as far as you as a sports fan telling
you right now, you owe me an apology.
Alright. And I will go on. I am
Rapaport and I will get my apology. Huh?
I'm just doing the shit.
Cause at some point I know I'm
going to go on his podcast.
That guy gets amped up. He gets, he
guys ever listen to I am Rapaport.
If you want to listen to the only sports
fan I know that's more uninformed than
me and talks more from his heart
than I do. He did a fucking,
he did this unbelievable
documentary on the early seventies,
Nixon when the garden was eating
four stars, four out of four. Right.
The Fun.
My favorite part of it other than watching
what's his face beat up the entire
Los Angeles Lakers, um, was uh,
when Rapaport was trying to get one of
the Knicks to say that Celtic fans were
animals, he goes animals. Right?
And the guys going Naba and no,
no. And you hear Rappaport off Cam and
go, come on man. Come on. Their aunts,
their animals up there.
Right. It was fucking great.
So anyways, um, so there you go. So
that's it. I know you guys was sick of it,
but I don't give a shit. I don't give
a shit. So you know what I dunno.
Fuck the NFL for the first
four games ain't gonna Watch.
I'll watch college football
instead where I know it's crooked.
Gimme a God damn break.
How long do you think the Patriots could
have a stadium like Seattle Seahawks
before the entire league demanded? We
took it down. You know what I mean?
Quite somebody clears their
throat in that stadium.
The opposing team has to go
into fucking silent count.
It's such a fucking ridiculous.
That whole franchise is felty.
Their owner was fucking their own fan
base over with the small beers and the
large payers.
Do you have a watch that youtube video?
They had a tall glass for the fucking
large one in little short fat one and
somebody finally,
they had ordered both suck down the
short one poured the tall went in.
There was the same amount of beer.
Oh there Phil.
That's like some dukes of Hazzard.
Shit.
You might as well be putting fake fire
hydrant next to people's cars. Right.
Then they got dirty, filthy, sneaky
fucking Pete Carroll is a God damn coach,
right?
Jesus Christ.
I loved how he rebuilt that
fucking program down there and USC.
That program was so fucking filthy.
They got stripped of a championship in a,
in a,
in a Heisman trophy and he snuck out the
back door when the wolves were at the
front, but now that he's at
the pro level, I'm sure he's,
I'm sure he's on the up and up.
By all means.
Let's just keep focusing on the patriots.
They're the only guys.
Lana Falcons got caught fucking pumping
sound noise and nobody's calling them
fucking cheaters. Ah, still just
the glitch. That's just blow, right?
That's it. Total fucking, this is a weird,
the fucking world is somebody just
wrote, Hey, somebody wrote me.
Please put today's barbershop
walkout in your next bit.
It's the fucking only other
guy that was in the barbershop.
The fucking customer. You know something?
Show me something. My phone today,
it was tracking. I had been, I
didn't even know it was on there.
It's called this locator thing.
If you want to shut it off,
I'll see if I remember how to do it.
As you go on your phone,
you go to the settings,
click on settings.
Then you go to notifications center and
then you scroll down to something that I
don't remember what it is. I don't
remember what I can get you to there.
Today's summary. Ah, you fucking
content notifications, views.
That ain't it sort by time. Oh,
fuck you, man. This is unbelievable.
This is why I always sucked at that game.
Simon,
who that Parker brothers came from? Was
it Parker brothers? I don't fucking know.
Government alerts, amber alerts.
What the fuck is this thing?
Emergency alert.
What a government alerts.
Cause somebody let me know why I need
to alert the government as a fucking 46
year old man. Um, oh Jesus Christ.
I had been fucking rag and today. Oh, let
me tell you, this guy's been pitching,
you know. Um, all right.
So here's some of the things that people
wanted me to go off on this week. Um,
they wanted me to talk about,
oh, I forgot to mention, hey,
I'm going to be doing an all things
comedy live. We'll do it live. Fuck it.
We'll do it live. We're doing it down
at the comedy store next Wednesday,
May 27th. All right. I'm coming off 19
shows and I'm bringing my fucking a game.
All right, Mr. Um, no,
I got, I got some, uh,
I get sort of new bits that have
funny shit to do. Um, and a whatever.
We're going to go down there.
We're going to,
we're going to sell the fucking place out.
It's in the main room at the comedy store,
Louis C k just to the special there.
So,
uh,
the already famous room has now become
even more famous with the release of his
special. So, uh, we're riding
on his coattails down there. Um,
so come on down May 27th,
the all things comedy live show,
it's a sponsored by some fucking
beer. I can't remember who, whatever.
I'm the worst when it comes to this shit.
But anyways, I'll be down there. Um,
I'll be there. So people
wanted me to talk about, um,
some of these cleo get over there
and lay down. You fucking maniac.
Don't ever let your dog sleep in
the bed with you at that point.
They think they're a person and they just
look at you like they look at you like
that paying rent now, you
know, it's fucking ridiculous.
So anyways, um, speaking of that whole
fucking thing about like the pink lady,
the pink ladies, um, people
wanted me to talk about this, um,
to go off on this shit, but I mean,
didn't you already know that this was,
I don't even know if this is a legal
government says for cancer charities are
Shams.
MMM.
All right. Well in Washington are
rare. Joint Action with attorneys,
attorney generals from
each of the 50 states.
The Federal Trade Commission says
for cancer charities a shut up.
Oh my God. What did I do?
Why is it talking to me?
How do you hit mute on this
fucking thing? Oh God. I know.
This is just going to come
back and haunt me. Um, oh,
here it is. It's one of these fucking
commercials. You can't shut off right.
There you go. Well, I can't, I shut
you off. Why can't I shut you off?
Don't I have a say? I turned
it down right? I do mute.
I have the power and then I scroll
you down so I don't watch your fucking
message. Um, anyways, in a rare joint
action with attorney, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
I just said for cancer charities run by
extended members of the same family con
donors out of $187 million from 2008 to
2012 these guys were making like Derek
Jeter salary between the four of them
and spent almost nothing to help actual
cancer patients.
Each of the charities charged with
the subject of extensive reporting.
What we charged a word,
the subject of extensive reporting
by CNN in 2013 and in an instant,
CNN pat themselves on
the back and an instant,
none of the four charities
in each instance,
none of the four charities would comment.
We were ordered out of the building at
the cancer fund of America in Knoxville,
Tennessee.
I love Knoxville and where the object
of an obscene gesture by the CEO of the
breast cancer society in Mesa,
Arizona. How funny is that?
You fucking running a charity to
raise money for breast cancer.
You taken most of the money and then you
have no comment to the press and when
they show up, you flip him.
The bird. Good Lord. Ah,
it's always good to see somebody that
you know is going to be a little further
down and held in. You are, you know what
I mean? It gives you a little bit of hope.
Like I'm not that bad.
God can only be so mad at me when this
guy's coming down the pike. Right.
Then he luck. He'll die right
before me. I might sneak by. Um,
you know what's funny is that the level
of stealing that these guys had to do
before they got caught,
the fact that they were taking like 97%,
because I feel like the NFL is so fucking
big and so fucking powerful that they
can continue to do this pink shit if it's
true. This is all alleged, by the way,
you know,
if they're taking the level that people
are saying in the 90 percentile on all
their pink horse shit, um,
you know what I mean? I mean,
I don't know that they,
they NFLs right.
Just below a bank as far
as they're not going to,
they're not going to take these guys down.
That's the bread and circus.
That's what keeps everybody fucking
occupied while these banker comes,
do whatever they want. Right. Um, anyway,
so I dunno.
I know saint Jude is a good one.
I know the Jimmy Fund is a good one.
I know Cam Neely Denis Leary,
that cancer house is a great one.
Um, I'm just sticking with those.
I'm just sticking with another that,
you
know what I mean?
If I want to fucking,
okay.
You know, give money to veterans,
have a walk up to a veteran.
I think that's the best way to make sure
they actually get the fucking money.
How about that everybody?
How about we do it that way?
How about rather than the fucking NFL,
charging these people to come out on the
field and fucking Yammer on about that
bullshit and then knowing that they're
going to take this skim out. Right.
They like casino, right? They get
in their taste. Charlie fucking him.
You may be popped your fucking
eye out for Charlie fucking up.
That's what they're doing, right? Skimming
off the top. Just fucking walk right up.
I don't know how to do this.
Gotta be a way to do it.
Can you just walk into
a veteran's hospital?
Okay.
She can walk in with a
bad catch. All right. Oh,
Nate said or cut out the middle man.
Fucking go directly to them.
Okay.
They wouldn't want that.
Wouldn't want it that way.
Then they can't track the fucking
money in tax the shit out of it.
Oh goodness. You know, it's been awhile
since I've been this negative, you know,
probably since the last Thursday
afternoon, just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast possibly.
Um,
that's gotta be fucking,
I mean, Jesus Christ,
I wonder if those people are like such
psychos that they can actually sleep at
night. You know what I mean? I've done
a lot of fucked up shit in my life,
but it keeps me up at night. That's
my one saving grace. I will sit down,
I'll talk in my sleep, I'll grind my
teeth if I fuck up. You know what I mean?
You know, it bugs me. These
people like they, I mean,
I can't imagine just sitting
there because if you told a few,
if you're raising the kind of
money that they will raise it.
You know what I mean? You know? And
one of them was like a father son,
combination two different fucking charity.
So he taught his son the ropes, right?
Like Marlon Brando down
to fucking, uh, help, uh,
Chino Godfather one, godfather
two. Right. You know,
they gotta be just sitting there going
like Jesus Christ at night after the
accepted yet another award or
at one of those Tom Cruise,
buck Rogers things put around
their fucking neck, you know,
tirelessly working against
the fight against cancer.
Then at some point, you know,
you got to stand up there
giving a speech to people
going, you know, each year,
hundreds of thousands of people.
I don't know how much it is.
I don't really research it
cause I'm keeping all the bike,
get diagnosed with some form of
cancer that I'm not familiar with.
Yeah.
Each year you guys give me body.
Okay.
And I go out and get a cigar boat,
but most of the money that's left after
I buy that bulb goes towards fighting,
uh,
in step cancer,
a very rare form of cancer that affects
a couple of feet every year in Laos that
we want to stop it. Thank you for
helping us at, uh, believe me.
I appreciate this for ward.
Thank you.
It God bless America.
Um, what the fuck I'm
talking about here?
Uh,
how far into this fucking thing am
I? This. This was just a dumb idea.
I should have gotten a better
mood before I did this.
It's probably what I should've done,
right. You know, and I was getting dope.
All right, so I'm back in fucking
la. I've got to tell you something.
You know what needs to stop?
Does Anybody Flown Virgin lately?
And Dude, they made like a
fucking 22 minute music video
about
putting your seatbelt on.
There's a part where they start,
there's singing,
and then there's wrapping,
and then there's a robot
part and then the robot goes,
this robot wrap is over and you're
thinking, Oh God, thank God it's over.
And then they just go and ready to go.
Put your fucking seat belt.
All right.
And there's all that Christina
Aguilera over singing,
doing all of that fucking
shit, pointing it notes. It's,
it's so fucking loud. You know,
he goes, those fucking doses.
We have those Bose headphones.
I just never could fucking
buy one of those things.
That's the first time it was like,
I really need to get a pair of those.
I need a pair of earplugs
and will I actually sit?
I fucking put my elbows on my knees and
I jammed my fingers into my ears and I
hum for five minutes
waiting for it to stop.
Um, yeah, I don't know.
You'll kills me as I was sitting
next to my wife and she loved it.
She thought it was great.
Okay.
And I was like, there you go.
Right there. There's the balance,
the balance of this relationship.
I fucking hate everything.
You know, like knee.
If she went down there,
she'd be like, oh, it's cool.
It's like a barbershop 2.0
I will make an appointment.
What is your name? Well,
it's very nice to meet you.
What do I do? I fucking store Mako.
Was this a fucking hair salon?
And I storm out. All right. And
in the end I still need a haircut.
So who won bill? Who Want to
get lost? Your temper again.
Who won and who lost? You think that
fuck. Oh, down the street gives a shit.
Sky's making these,
taking reservations down there like he's
got a fucking a pork chop to die for.
Right like you some fucking
unbelievable restaurant.
MMM.
All right. Whenever the fuck
you, what are you going?
What are you gonna fucking do, you
know? Oh, by the way, you know what I,
why don't I have anything here?
Hey Nia.
Yeah.
Can you grab my wallet?
I'm going to take a video of
this goalie mask and he just,
I that this kid made Jesse custom. I
know. I keep talking about them, but uh,
I got this right in my office
now I got to take the video of,
it's fucking unbelievable. I, one
of my wallet, if he didn't mind.
It's where we keep all the wallet
keys and stuff like that. Clear.
I'll get over here. Get over here. Clean
up. All right. Get over here and lay down.
Yo, you know your neck, Clara. Hi.
What the fuck is wrong with this
fucking dog? Cleo? Get in there. Oh,
this is embarrassing. What
are the podcasts? You just
fucking walked away? Pillows.
Cleo. So every time
we're around, she thinks
she wants you to last night.
Oh,
you just stupid excuses.
Four.
All right. See that? She just goes
off. She just wants to go outside.
I'm sitting there flipping out.
I don't buy it.
That's why she jumps up and down all over
company cause she has to take a piss.
Um, anyways. Oh, here's a
cadets. I mentioned this
restaurant here on broad street,
right? Speaking of a pork chop to
die for in Boston, Massachusetts,
one 31 broad street,
Boston, Massachusetts,
head chef and row. Go
in there, check it out.
Tell him I said tell him the Thursday
afternoon, just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast. That's just
jacket in on yet set. Yeah. All right.
Um, so anyways, well we're
winding down here. Uh,
have you guys been watching
any of the hockey playoffs?
I finally got back into them now that my,
uh, my run there in Boston finally, uh,
came to an end. Um, what
did I watch last night?
I watched Tampa versus the
rages and I turned it on in the,
uh, the, uh, halfway
through the third period,
and I saw Tampa score to go up five
to four, and I thought they had him.
And then the rangers came back with his
fucking goal was like a minute left.
Playoffs. I've been sick.
Right. And then, uh,
over time I fucking flipped out
when Santa scored, you know,
I don't know why I got to
root for somebody and I've
got to go for the underdog.
But I also like the rangers. I
would, might see the ranges when it,
although that might make Rappaport happy.
So I dunno, he doesn't watch hockey.
Look at rapid portraits, that
guy, you know what I mean?
Does that guy look like he even
remotely gives a fuck about hockey?
Um, he would talk shit about
though. I can imagine. Um, anyways,
what else? Uh, and then I've been
watching, uh, Chicago and Anaheim Dude,
if Anaheim,
Anaheim one game two,
I say they win the Stanley Cup. That's
how big that game was. What did they hit?
Four or five posts and those,
those uh,
three overtimes um,
hey, you know something.
Did you guys see when shy
headbutted the puck in?
That's one of the few times I was
right on a controversial thing.
I was able to figure it out was like,
well wait a minute.
If he can't kick it in is the
way can use your fucking head.
Um, but then I'd never seen anybody use
their head other than Dominic Kaushik.
Um, so anyways, so I'm still
sticking with it. I think, uh,
I think the ducks are going to beat
Chicago only because Chicago has it been
scoring a bunch of goals on him.
Um,
the fact that they've
been hanging with them,
they've been close games and that type
of shit. I just, I don't know why.
I just feel like Chicago might be getting
a little old. Who the fuck's can do?
I was so busy. I barely watched any
hockey. I'm just going with my guts.
I still say the ducks and then the Cavs,
the Cavaliers are going to fucking win.
Cavaliers are going to win and Jason Law
head is going to cry like a baby and he
will have every field have
Cavaliers championship pajamas.
You know those Cleveland guys,
they'd been waiting their whole
fucking lives run for your lives.
All right, this is the Thursday
afternoon, Monday morning podcast,
whatever the fuck you call,
just checking on you on yet. Uh,
we're now going to play
a couple of classics,
couple of classics from a podcasting
days gone by. I want to thank you all,
you guys for listening once again,
thanks to everybody and then
amazing run up there in Boston.
Thank you to bill bloomin' Reich,
his daughter, Taylor, and uh,
everybody down there at the, uh,
at the Wilbur theater. Everybody,
I just had it. I had such a
fucking great time. Uh, Raul,
Johnny Ali, you guys down there. Thank
you guys for just a wonderful week.
And uh, I know I said I'd never do that
run again, but uh, I'm already thinking,
Hey, you know, maybe every couple of years
make it a little tradition. Who knows?
I would schedule a day off or two
the next time. I do it, but uh,
but it was still fun. All right, so I'm
sticking with it. Sticking with the ducks.
I'm sticking with the Cavaliers
and uh, yeah, fuck it.
You want to have a hipster barbershop?
We got to make appointments.
Wasn't I really just mad? Because they
wouldn't do what I want them to do.
I still do this. You should have a
different colored barbershop sign them.
But that little fucking red,
white and blue stripe thing going up.
It should be something diff. Something
hipstery little mustaches in there.
You can't. All right, you guys have a
great fucking weekend. All right. See Ya.
Hey, wait a second. I forgot to read a
couple of fucking advertisements here.
I didn't realize I had a couple of
ads I got to read here. You know,
it was fucking funny.
I'm just sitting there going like,
why is my day going so fucking
started off school? Good.
And that's just cause I'm
allowing everything to affect me,
so I need to fucking relax. So I was
sitting there, it's like, all right dude,
just relax. Take a deep breath and
then you know what? This fucking,
that's stupid fucking song. I
Dunno if it's Peter, Paul and Mary.
I don't know if it's fucking, uh,
Paul Simon and the guy with the hair.
All right. The bridge over 12
water guy. What's his fucking name?
Their fucking Robbie Krieger's cousin.
They had the same fucking hair was
like pubic hair bows on their heads.
Okay.
What's his name there?
Simon and Garfunkel?
No.
Yeah. Second Garfunkel and Oates.
That was fucking me up. Anyway,
so I'm sitting there
trying to relax and all,
I just start here in this stupid fucking
song in my head, you know, slow down.
You go into fast. He got
the, make that bone in line.
Wait.
See any reason why so many focus got
the fucking guitar smashed the head.
Maybe it just happened in animal house,
but you'd like to think that it happened
a lot. Why should it happen? Belt? Why?
Because your angry.
They can't be fucking baby there.
They're more advanced beings.
And you are.
Yeah,
I dunno.
Maybe they just ate some fucking weed.
Video Doorbell. Everybody. I know.
This sounds creepy. This is a new one.
It.
W we'll insert dinging sound.
This is the sound of a package. Oh, what?
Someone else is going to insert that
Ding Dong sound or Zeiss Ding Dong Song.
Is that what the sound I was supposed
to fucking do that video doorbell being
ball.
This is the sound of a package
being delivered or friends
coming over for dinner.
But also it's the sound of
someone planning to rob you blind.
Well, what kind of a cat burglar
rings the doorbell and I don't,
she didn't want people to not know.
These people aren't going to
last long in this fucking thing.
Over 95% of home breakins happen during
the day after someone rings the doorbell
at Burglars. Almost always start by
ringing your doorbell. Oh really?
Isn't that convenient?
People selling doorbells to see
if anyone of someone's home.
Okay.
Oh, okay. I'm sorry. You know what?
Maybe I'm Lee is already laughing at me.
They had come in here and help me
save this. This is just, I'm sorry.
Doorbell people. Video
Doorbell guys, I should relate.
I should hear you out before I judge you.
Right?
Having the worst day.
Hang on. Hang on. This is classic.
You had burglars reading or in the
beginning you don't read it first,
so you get a handle on it.
You just start reading it and you know
you're not good at just reading cold
first of all.
Second of all,
yeah,
you have no patience.
So you can't even just be bothered to
know what your range to come in and help
me out,
not read me the riot act
and burglars. I didn't know if
he knew this read line by line.
I didn't know this at burglars.
Almost always start by ringing the
doorbell to see if someone's hope before
pillaging your possession. Just cause
you'd be come to the door. They, oh,
I'm sorry. I thought you were at
all cause I was going to rob you.
Lucky for you sucks for your neighbor.
Um,
when the ring video doorbell,
uh, with the ring video doorbell,
you can see and talk to anyone at your
door from anywhere in the world using
your smartphone.
Oh,
so I guess you can pretend you o
rings advanced motion detection.
Shut up a large shoe.
Even if someone doesn't ring the doorbell,
it's like caller id for your home.
Please share a personal story or how
this could help someone you love.
Well
yeah,
I a one time my uncle,
uh,
he was living in a shack and he
didn't have fucking dollar. Whatever.
Installing ring takes minutes and it
works with either your current wiring or
built in rechargeable
battery,
puts your mind at ease and protects
your home with the video doorbell Time
magazine named one of the
top 10 gadgets of 2014.
So you look at that Time magazine.
Yeah.
Is it why?
Because what you can, you can access it
from your smart phone or what have you.
So you can just sort of, yeah, if
someone rings the doorbell, wait, when
you ring the doorbell.
Oh well,
well well yeah.
A cat cause kettle cow calls Kit Kat Cole,
whatever pot podcalls kettle black.
Uh,
right now my listeners get
the ring video doorbell Foley,
174 bucks is $25 off the normal price.
Go to ring.com/bar right now. Protect your
home and have peace of mind with ring.
Go to ring.com/burr for $25 off.
That's [inaudible] dot com slash
[inaudible] how do you have peace of mind?
So somebody rings the doorbell and you
put it on video and he has an ax and he
just go,
I could see,
I see what you look like and
I'm in here calling the cops.
He hangs his head. It drags the
ax down the fucking walk. No,
I used to be. Now that makes sense
that they would reign to make sure.
And if nobody's home, they
like our grand. I can,
you know, break in. So
if you go, thanks. Okay.
Near the hill, everybody.
Uber. Hey, you like
making money? Great money,
right?
Well here's a really cool opportunity I
had to share with you driving with Uber.
Uber's that popular smart phone app
that connects riders with drivers.
I take Uber a bunch.
I love them by the way.
And in chatting with
the different drivers,
ed chatting with the diff and in
chatting with the different drivers,
swear he goes,
says that some of them have really
interesting stories as to why they,
they drive you Uber soda cab drivers.
Most of them fucking came from like war
towards places that our youth to be a
doctor. Um, they love being their
own boss. They are in great money.
It was the worst accident ever.
It's easy to stat.
You just need a cat and a license.
Oh my God. Catholic driving.
Uber driving with Uber is great for
anyone that needs flexibility. Parents,
this is really easy way to work
around your family schedule.
This is the shit right here.
Back in the day we know what this job was.
You delivered afternoon papers,
picked up a couple of hundred bucks.
This is the best way, right? You get to
meet people and out your resume students,
you can make some extra
money between classes.
Now's the prime time to cash in
with drive Uber. You can fan.
You'll thank me for telling you how to,
how to get paid every week.
You will thank me for reading this stuff.
I could be getting into your car.
When you drive with Uber,
that's a selling point.
Call to action. You got to get, you have
to, you gotta get a car and a license.
You Lazy,
put a ball to work.
You would start hurting series.
Do they really need to say that?
You want to be a butcher? 81 of them
knife things and some dead meat, right?
A life changing money today.
Sign up with Uber.
Visit drive with uber.com
that's drive with Uber,
U B E r.com. Drive with uber.com.
All right, give it a shot.
Give it a shot. They go.
All right. How was that? Uh,
yeah, that was, that was good.
That was all right.
Hey,
doorbell. One might might need to
do that one a couple more times,
but it was really good.
These kids today, they don't like
excitement. Back in the day you were like,
you're like, who is it?
I hear you breathing.
Who is it?
Are you trying to rob me?
You know what I've found, like sometimes
we get food, we get to the mic when they,
when we get food delivered, they'll,
they'll call from my cell phone,
we'll get food. What's
the limit we'll get, uh,
they'll call my cell phone and
be like, hi, I'm here. And I say,
did you rang the doorbell? And they're
like, no. And I'm like, what? Oh,
these kids today? Yeah. Just
ring the doorbell. Like that's
how you, that's how you,
uh, oh, that was sweet.
I just find it weird that they would
call and not just ring the doorbell when
they're here.
Oh yes. So much to think about it. That's
weird though, right? Yeah, it is. Well,
whatever I'll just do it
is making me sound old.
Do you want to sound old with me?
Oh yeah. Well that's true. Do you?
I went to a barbershop when
I couldn't really feel it.
It will be screaming
about it to get my head,
but I definitely heard you screaming.
And the guy said,
I didn't have a fucking appointment. And
he, he goes, you have an appointment.
It's a barber shop.
You don't need a fucking appointment,
but you know somebody is high
Falutin places they get, you know,
they work on appointment.
It's not like, you know
barbershop. You're a, you're a
hair salon, right? Yeah. I know.
We're a salon that does my hair.
Yeah.
Did you go into an actual barbershop
though? Was it just one of these?
It was a fucking barbershop that gay,
the little swirly sign
and it said barbershop.
Oh yeah. So she, you should be
able to walk in there and be like,
let me get a haircut. And they'd be
like, yeah, have a seat, grab a paper.
Nice. Justified on one. Number two
should have Tom Brady had been suspended.
I have no idea as it's about deflate gate.
How do you know about,
you only watch sports? Well I had deflate
gate has been all over the Internet.
What happened?
Something about football being deflated
and that mess other people up and the
Patriots are being accused
of being behind it.
Bill Bellacheck that's good.
Yeah.
Oh yeah, that was great. You pretty much
had it. Why was he suspended though?
You Tom Brady? Yeah, cause
he's flooded. You know,
because he looks like a war hero and
astronaut and a quarterback and a movie
star all in one. That's why are
you blaming this on haters? Yeah.
Well I don't understand how fucking,
uh,
an organization that never fucking
paid taxes for the first fucking 60,
80 years of their existence.
All of a sudden it's gonna
start wagging their fingers.
Are People keeping all the pink cancer
money for that Goddamn yachts hire
the same at Tom. Brady
is suspended. You still
didn't answer that because Jim or stays
a fucking baby and he weighed the balls.
Do you have a play a
board game with somebody?
You have to play a board
game with somebody and then
you win and in the end they
got to fucking find out some reason why
that they lost and it has something to
do with you cheated and they'll
say like, oh, Tom Brady,
like secretly deflated the ball
beforehand. They don't know he did.
They just have circumstances that
maybe possibly could have known.
It was basically like, like in baseball,
some guys shaved the handle down,
some people put Pine Tar. It was
literally that level of Shit, man,
they lost by 38 fucking
points. Reminds me of uh, uh,
what's that Jim Carey movie where he
was like the liar liar? No, no. The,
the one ace Ventura.
Wasn't that the one where there's a no,
somebody kidnapped Dan Marino.
Right. And then like Sean Young,
the actress or places out lays this out.
That's what that reminds me of. Yeah.
That was like a fundamentally she was
claiming that it was sabotaged because
it's supposed to have the license you,
it's a fucking pony and don't
show and it's over. And the show,
is that what it's pony pony
and dog show dog and pony show.
Okay.
The ponies. The headliner. It's,
but the saying his dog
and pony not pony in dog,
dog and pony. Look that up.
I don't have to look it up.
I'm telling you it's correct. Oh,
fucking believe that. Pony and dogs.
Thank you. Thank you
for stopping by, by, by.
All right.
You guys have a great weekend.
[inaudible]
of self.
For the last five years,
I've been teaching guitar lessons full
time at a very large music school in
Chicago.
Um,
there are over 100 music teachers at
the school with about 5,000 students.
Every session,
half of those students are under 18.
The school has been around for over
50 years and is globally recognized.
We'll see if I could figure that out.
Was Chicago.
I don't know that one was
going to guess Berkeley.
Now I get an email from the new director
of the school is saying all of the
staff are required to get their thumbs
scanned by some company called bio
metric.
What
biometric scans your thumbs
into their watch system.
We all already had
background checks done when we were hired,
but now they argue we
need to have this done.
Apparently all of the public school
teachers in their entire city are being
forced to do this as well.
Basically anyone who is around any
younger who was around any younger,
please people please proofread your shit.
You make me sound dumb.
I'm already dumb enough.
Basically anyone who was around any
younger people for a profession is now
mandated by their employee to get
in this creepy biometric system.
You see this shit. You guys notice this,
all this fucking screaming and yelling.
We do during every single election that
comes around to pick the Democrat or the
other Republican.
It doesn't make a difference because when
the real shit goes down like approving,
giving biometrics the right to do this,
we don't get to vote on this.
They don't even tell us about it, so
just go with the law. It's mandatory.
You have to do this.
Okay.
Anyways, he says, I don't
want anything to high,
but the mental picture of all of us,
harmless musicians lining
up like fucking cattle.
Having some storm trooper assholes
scanning my thumbprint into some super
computer where it will stay
forever is really depressing.
Obviously this is all done in the name
of air quote, protecting the children,
but at what cost?
Here's my question for you.
I feel like this is my
moment to take a stand.
Should I make a deal big deal about this
and try to rally all the other teachers
to fight this or will I just look like I
have something to hide? Uh, it is really,
really hard to get a job at this school,
so I'm scared to make waves.
Do you feel like this
protects kids from creeps?
I should mention then the schools, 50
year history, no incident of a teacher.
A student misconduct has been recorded.
Everyone knows that pedophiles
can't play an instrument. Lol. Uh,
and do you think um,
they are making priests get thumb scans?
I fucking bet. Not all joking aside,
I'm really bothered by this situation.
What should I do, Bill? I don't know why.
The first thing I would do is
I would talk to other teachers.
Okay.
And see how they feel about it.
I think that's complete horseshit dude.
Okay.
They,
they have been basically working their
way towards this since they first came up
with photo id and social security
numbers and all of that shit.
It's all done under the whole guise of
organization in your own fucking safety
and it's complete horse shit.
It has to do with them eventually trying
to have a very few people be able to
make the decisions for all of us.
Yeah.
That's basically what's going on.
Okay.
And the more information
they have about you,
the easier it is to be able to find
you. I mean, think about that shit.
They're going to have your thumbprint.
They know what you're fucking
fingerprint looks like. All right.
They're going to have an a visibility
to freeze your fucking bank account and
your cell phone as a God damn microchip
in it. Okay? So the second day,
I mean this is like of day shit and they
got these fucking robots that they'd
been working on that can outperform
human beings. I'm telling you,
our days are fucking number.
They are in jeopardy.
The other day they had two human beings
playing against a fucking computer.
Those two people, they're helping
human beings get phased out.
You should see I'm not competing,
gets a fucking computer so you can figure
out how it does against me and you can
figure the computer's
weaknesses and strong points
so it can come back with even
more game. And you can pump it
back with more fucking information.
So eventually I become fucking useless
unless of course I know how to build a
robot or know how to grease it's fucking
joints. Yeah, Dude. I think, yeah,
I think it would be a very uh,
noble thing if you complained about that.
I think people need to complain more.
I'm guilty of it.
I fucking rant here on this podcast,
but I've never been to a protest,
but I don't think that it's right
that they, that they pass a lot.
Like whether you agree with that or not,
that's not something that they should
be able to pass without the voice of the
people. We should be able to
vote on something like that.
It's fucking ridiculous.
I just found out from my account the
other day after years of saying I'm not
doing my shit online cause I don't want
to put all that information online.
I now have no option.
I have to do it online.
You know, I don't want to put all
my fucking information online,
my tax ID numbers, my social
security numbers. You're
right at your fucking mind.
You're letting people in to
your entire financial history,
you'll let me Gigi or whole fucking God
knows what they can do with that and
they can ruin you. All right. I'll, I'm
doing is bitching here, but I don't know,
that shit really stretched
fucking creepy as hell. Um,
I would talk to other people would
be like, dude, hey, you know what,
what do you think about this? You
know, sort of get it going. You know,
just like how they started the
revolution in this country. Hey,
what do you think about those red coats?
Yeah. Like they're kind of a yeah.
Ditch right. To kind of dicks. Yeah.
Sent me this email here
that was a inspired by the fact that I
was talking about this shit. And, uh,
here we go. Ask Bill Bill.
I am currently engaged,
but I'm kind of over it. Oh, Jesus.
Wow. I am glad. Let me
read that again. Let's,
let's all just take a deep breath and
let's take that a tank when it's time to
Jay age. Uh, let's take that
one. And again, uh, I am bill,
I am currently engaged
but I'm kind of over it.
Um, you know what, I might need
the help of a female on this one.
Hey Nia,
they know you want to help me on this one.
I've got a relationship question.
If it gets a feel and your girlfriend's
mad at you and you haven't even done
anything.
I think I just heard an exhale.
What's that? You can't talk cause
you voiced you making lunch. Oh okay.
Okay.
Are you
yeah, I'm recording right now. Yeah. And
you hit me with this attitude. I'm sorry.
She what I want. I I just had
Jesus. This is getting really
awkward. Yeah. All right.
My is under the weather
and I actually forgot,
she told me she was under the weather
like 20 minutes ago and that's how self
absorbed I am. Cleo, get down. All
right. Just listen to this. Okay.
Cause I think I also need
like female help on this one.
Could you take your hands off your
hips and stop staring at me like that?
Come on. Do you not want to do
this if you don't want to do it?
Okay. Okay. Bill, I am currently engaged,
but I'm kind of over it.
She just laughed.
Huh? This is a female. This
is why I have you in here.
He just talked to the people with
your voice here. Hi. How are you?
Sound like Demi Moore.
I liked that.
You know what I already
talked about Andrew Mccartney,
right? Brought up rob Lowe.
I got the whole brat pack here. I,
why don't you, you don't trust me.
You got to look on your face.
Like you're not trusting me.
Like I'm gonna make you
look stupid and I'm not.
I generally want your help on this.
It's a low budget podcast.
We only have one microphone. All
right? I'm currently engaged,
but I'm kinda over it. Um, I love him, but
our relationship isn't working anymore.
I keep making excuses.
Like my schedule has changed.
I'm working and going to school, so I'm
just stressed, et Cetera, et cetera.
But, uh, honestly the excuses
aren't working anymore.
I want us to get back to when we were
having fun and sex and not arguing.
He gets frustrated.
He gets frustrated with me when I don't
want to cuddle with him at night or fuck
them at 4:00 AM
when I,
when I have to get up at seven
in the morning to go to work, uh,
then come home at five and cook
him dinner and get to sleep by 11.
And then she writes, okay,
pause in the email. Um,
why does he want to fuck or cuddle
at 4:00 AM when I'm sleeping?
Is this like a guy thing?
I don't understand what he's thinking.
This is my argument. It's four in the
morning. Number two, he's half asleep,
which means I'll have to wake up
and get on top and do all the work.
What the fuck? Number three, if I don't
sleep, I'll be cranky in the morning.
Then I'll be mad at me because I'm being
a total bitch. And for, um, being, uh,
I like being alone.
I love sleeping by myself.
Granted in the beginning it
was fun to sleep next to him,
but now I want my own bed back.
I don't understand what it,
that he's thinking. Okay. Continuing.
I guess she was digressing here.
I'm almost done here. All right.
Are you enjoying this here? Okay.
Cause she's shaking it in.
She's got a very serious look on her face.
This is why I brought her in an expert.
This is like Oprah,
our relationship expert. Okay, here we go.
Uh, we are planning to move in together,
but it's not a good idea because I'm
not really in the relationship anymore.
I'd rather be alone. In addition,
is there an ax murderer or outside?
In addition,
I just really realized that that was,
yeah. All right. In addition, um, come
close to them. Like, Sweetie, here we go.
Sit down and take a load off. You're
not feeling well. Uh, in addition,
he's the first man I've ever had sex with.
Don't read this cause you read way
faster than me. Just listen to my,
the soothing tones of my awful voice.
You just snort it when you laugh.
That's adorable.
He's the only person she's ever had.
Yeah. Now don't, don't comment yet. Okay.
We're building it up. We got the
listener's riveted at this point. Okay.
Someone's being hacked to
death outside. Um, in addition,
he's the first man I've ever had
sex with. Uh, I am faithful to him,
but when we have days like these,
I think is this really as good as it gets?
I'm sure he's thinking the same
thing when I'm being an asshole.
That's the femur right there.
That's the really got to give the chain,
saw a full fucking force there. Um, oh.
Well they did taken out that tree
over there. Okay. Yeah. The sick tree.
We had a sick tree tree had aids and r
block and just keeled over. It's very sad.
We stood out there with candles
and had tree aids. It had treated,
it was HIV positive.
I'm not making light of AIDS making Jesus.
Jesus. I don't know who to get more
offended that you're trashing Jim Norton.
Are you saying that I'm ripping them off?
You do not.
Why is my voice cracking? You do that.
All right, let's get back this. I Dunno,
I could totally be seeing this
from a fucked up spot. Actually.
I think I am because he's great now.
She's going back this way.
She must have her period this week.
She's all over the map out.
Did you really have to punch me
right fucking there? All right.
He gives me whatever I want.
And as far as material things go,
typical broad, he buys
me stuff. He's gray.
I don't want to fuck him anymore,
but look at all this stuff. Uh,
um, he listens to me. Sarah says,
I'm taking this one seriously because
I'm think girls in a serious situation
here. That's why I keep saying serious
as many times as they can in a sentence.
Seriously.
Um,
he listens to me whenever I wine and he
has conversations with me that show me
life from a different perspective and
he's willing to work at our relationship
and is committed to me. Those are
the things that I love about him.
Duh, Duh, Duh, Duh,
Duh, Duh. Right. To me,
those are the things that I love
about him. Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah. Right. I am getting
through it. I got to do fifth.
She just gave me the same,
wrap it up. All right, fine.
You're speaking for the
listeners. I'm going, uh,
but I can't live like this anymore.
This girl is all over the map.
I told him once that I wanted some space,
like I wanted to wake up alone some
days and he blew it out of proportion.
It says, okay, I'll give you plenty of
space. Let's break up. He did that shit.
Um,
and then she said,
I asked if that's what he
wanted because that wasn't yeah,
because that wasn't looking like the
worst option in the world. Oh Jesus.
But his voice cracked and he
said, no, that's not what I want.
So long story short,
I'm still waking up to him.
He still asked why we can't fuck
at 4:00 AM and we're still engaged.
I'm willing to say if we can make a
few adjustments in our relationship,
I'm willing to stay. If we could, uh,
if we can make a few adjustments
in our relationship. Otherwise,
how do I get out and hurt him the least.
All right,
here we go. I brought in a
female for this one cause I know,
I know what you want me to tell you
what I'm thinking first. No. Okay.
No I don't. Um, she needs
to break up with him. Okay.
And why? Because she doesn't love him
anymore. She's not in love with them.
She recognizes all his
good traits and stuff.
But that's not a reason to
stay with someone if she
can't give him what he needs
because at no point did she say well no,
she talks about him wanting to cuddle
and us know rather I think the 4:00 AM
doesn't mean anything.
I think he just wants to be close to her
and that's the one time that maybe she
slows down and is in bed and that's where
he can wrap his arms around her and do
all that sort of thing. Cause it sounds
like she's super busy all the time.
So he wants to spend that time with her.
So let's stay on track here. So what,
why do you feel like she
should break up with him? She,
she's not in love with him
anymore. Clearly. She's not
in love with him anymore.
She loves him. He's a great guy. Um, but
she's not in love with him. Yeah. No,
she is not off.
Yeah.
I think that she bringing up the good
traits as she's trying to convince herself
to stay in the relationship because
she doesn't want to hurt him. Yes.
She wants to be alone. She's not
ready to get married and that's fine.
He's going to be heartbroken no matter
what because obviously he is in love with
her. He wants to work
it out. But it's Cliche,
but it's like if she really loves him
then she will let him go so that he can
find somebody that wants to do all that
kind of stuff that she's not because
she's a bad person. Wait a minute. Wait,
before we get going, before we get going,
let's, what's the, what's the, uh, what,
this is a great topic for the podcast.
Breaking up with somebody
sucks cause you get, you know,
they're going to start whimpering,
you know,
when you're going to drive their tiers
with the dirty pages of a TV guide. And,
uh, I don't know. I was thinking about a
coffee table. What would be on the car?
I always break up girls near a
coffee table. Yeah. Well yeah.
You're not gonna be sitting on the bed.
You on the bed. You don't want to fuck no,
I'm sorry. I just, sometimes he'd
dump shit on this. Um, what did,
what is the best way,
what is the best way to break up
with someone to hurt in the least?
Do you have a technique?
No, there's no way. Well,
could you try to be funny on this
thing and just try to come up,
come up with the technique.
I got one for you.
Send an email, send it, send them a card.
Yeah,
that is actually for like a good occasion.
So it'll have like balloons and
like silly animals on it. Yeah,
yeah, exactly. You just see you
cross out all the good stuff you are.
You add words. You aren't the love of my
life, but there's going to be all this,
there's these cool pictures.
You have a new live congratulations.
She could find um, a girl.
Oh, she can be like, oh,
let's have a threesome. And find
like a really hot, sexy, funny,
amazing girl. And they all
have like dinner and drinks
and all have a good time.
Go back to the bedroom and they all start
doing it and she could slowly slip out
and she's got her bags packed. Dot.
Right. Yeah. You know what that's like.
Two of them are having
leg probably amazing.
That's fucking awesome.
Yeah. You know it's funny. You know
it's funny is he would get no sympathy.
Went to the bars. Like, look, girlfriend
broke up with me. Oh God, Dude.
How's she did it? How did
she do it? Well, she fucking,
we had a threesome and I start this
unbelievably hot girl. I start banging.
She just slipped out of the
window and be like, wait a minute.
That's like, you know what that's
like? That's like as a comedian,
if you have to cancel a Gig,
but you,
you do the effort to give them a
replacement comedians. So there's,
there's no pain. That's what she
should do. Ladies and gentlemen,
how about a round of applause?
I knew there was a reason I brought
you and that was fucking awesome.
Okay.
Fucking Neah Bay. You Go.
Good for you. Good for you.
All right. Thank you. Thank you for being
on the podcast. This is, you know what?
This is this weird thing like when you
do panel on a talk show and no matter
what, when the person wraps it up,
you feel you still feel slighted.
Like I was just killing them. We're going
to commercial. Well listen, thanks a lot.
Good luck on your movie.
We're going to be right back
with the Monday morning podcast.
That was fucking awesome. High Five.
There you go. Go make me a sandwich.
Oh right. Huh? I'll fucking
coolest chic. Jesus Christ.
There's no reason to even to
even try and top that one. I was,
I thought that was going to be a new,
uh, a new segment on the podcast.
Wow.
If she ever breaks up with me,
she better fucking do it that way.
Cause that would,
uh,
I wonder how long until the three,
before you actually fucking discovered it,
you know? And is that technically
a threesome? You know?
Because if he didn't bang the other
person, you know what that's like?
That's like you get a base hit, but you
fall down in the way, the first base,
and then the right field of throws you
out. Is it bill? Is that what it's like?
I don't think it is.
All right.
[inaudible].