All right.
Hey,
what's going on is bill burn his time
for the Thursday afternoon just before
Friday, Monday morning podcast,
and I am just checking in on you.
I didn't yell this time.
I did yell at this time because I'm
sitting across from a man who is currently
setting the Guinness Book of World
Records for podcasting in a day,
promoting his new show on Netflix.
Stand up in a way for episodes
debuting Christmas Eve.
Ladies and gentlemen,
all of the greatest theater of
comedians have ever seen in my life.
Please welcome Mister Brian Regan.
Bill, how are you man? I'm excellent.
How are you doing? You look like
you're about ready to glaze over here.
You're on the whole media
tour, right? Did they get you?
Did you do some morning TV?
Did you do any of that crap on morning TV?
I,
I'm not comfortable with
those morning shows.
I tend to love doing these with other
comedians. Oh, okay, good, good.
You know when it's, when it's
not another comedian, it's, I'm,
I am so horrible at them. And
you're funny, Brian. Oh boy.
What can people expect from your show?
That's the Mo,
like if I'm doing a phone interview,
like a radio and phone radio interviewer,
well as soon as they say,
what can people expect people for
people who aren't familiar with you,
what can they expect from your show?
I know right away they're not familiar
with the person asks me the question and
I just want to hang up.
Like I just want to get a few to be over
at that moment.
Is your show going to be the exact same
thing I just watched on television?
Yeah. That's another one. Did
you write any new material?
It's good to be exact same shit.
See, after I finally got his special,
I didn't want it to ruin it by boring
people by doing the exact same stuff. Uh,
Brian in this company asked you all
hacky questions in this current comedy
climate,
how do you find the altitude until fly
at with your current presentation of,
of satire in a fucking
crazy. It's a, it's a,
it's an insane world. It's in the
same world right now. But uh, anyways,
tell me about your show.
It's a hybrid half standup,
half sketch.
A lot of the older bits that I used to
do years ago when I do my shows around
the country,
people at the end of my show sometimes
like to hear some of the older stuff and
I'm like, well, what can I do? Maybe I
could do something with this. So, um,
you got,
you get you like that good that you have
like classic jokes that's harder than a
classic song. And I'm not going to
use that word on myself, but, uh,
it's nice of you to say
that, but, uh, you know,
so I'm like Johnny Cash. Yeah. Well,
it feels good that people still like to,
you know,
here some of these routines and I thought,
well,
maybe I can do something with them,
but I don't want to just do the standup.
I mean, people want to know that. So I
thought maybe if I do like a standup bid.
And then that segues into some
sketch or something like that.
And a Jerry Seinfeld got
involved. Oh, hey, go. Um,
he was the one who reached out and he's
always been cool with me and said that
he wanted to help spearhead
me having a show. I mean,
what better phone call is that? It's in
a life that's a big phone call. You know,
like, like you're, you're on the
phone going look at, he's goosebumps.
I got goosebumps. Yeah. You know,
it's funny when you said this when you
were describing your show is I, that's,
he's the first person I thought I was
like, Jerry would like to show. He was so,
you know, was cool. He said that he had
this idea or he didn't have the idea.
He said he wanted me to have a show.
He said,
let's get together sometime and see if we
can talk about this. And I was like, Oh,
you know, of course, you know, and um, he
was performing in Las Vegas where I live,
so I went to go meet him at his sweet.
They have sweets and hotels that are like,
that I didn't know were possible
like piano and a segues to
secretary after that from what
I have to go to that kind of room is this,
you know,
so I go, we go meet and we chat.
And uh, he said, yeah, you know,
he thought that I was one of the
comedians that have, should have a show,
which was just a huge, huge honor even
hearing that. And he said, well, you know,
maybe we'll get together and talk about
it sometime soon. And I said, well,
I have an idea. And he goes, okay. And I,
I know he likes coffee, right? So I said,
do you mind if we order some coffee?
And we chat about it.
So called room service.
They brought up a pot of coffee. I
pitched it to him in about three minutes,
you know, and he goes, I
like it, let's do it. And um,
I got emotional. I swear
to God, I started like,
I got a tear in my eye because it's
show business doesn't work like that.
I say we had his shell.
Business does. Yes, exactly.
I knew when he says,
yeah, yeah, let's do it. And they
didn't do it. And now we made,
I knew it was happening. I mean, I'm on
belittling all the work he does, but like,
he has like the, uh,
whatever that is. Like,
he knows when an idea is good and
then he goes, let's just do it.
And then he does it. He does it where
he wants to do it. Everybody responds.
And then,
uh,
and I knew back the bank truck
up exactly the money part as a,
as an even that important to me, you know,
I mean right now, but just his cloud,
your agent just slapped his forehead.
It goes renegotiations weigh in
or they're going to play this
wait is still be down to earth.
Brian,
at some point would you
be a little bit of a diva?
But I knew when he said he wanted to
do it, that it was going to happen.
Who's going to say no to him?
You know?
And I knew that he's the one shepherding
this. So anyway, it was like really that,
uh, that uh, he's supporting this. Yeah,
I would say I would say that would be a,
if you're going to go in with anybody,
that would probably be uh,
let me see. He did for them.
How long does it take
you to shoot an episode?
I'm fascinated with this aspect of it.
Of the Wendy you get to go
home aspect of show business.
Well there was a lot of a
writer's meetings, you know,
a a bunch of weeks of that, you know,
just coming up with the sketches.
A lot of the sketch ideas I
had, I had already had. Um,
and then we shot the sketches also.
Not every one of them is based
on one of your older bits.
It's just some of them are and
some of them are newer ideas.
None of the sketches are standup done
as a sketch. I didn't want to do that.
Stand up. I love stand up and
stand up. Should be stand up.
So they do the one where you want to
do the cattle prod and the person who's
just standing where they're supposed to
be walking in the airport was one of my
favorites. I'd like to see somebody, maybe
that one, maybe that one, I'll do it,
but I wanted to stand up to be
stand up and then I wanted, uh,
some type of transition into a sketch.
Sometimes it's a natural lead in,
sometimes you have to kind
of like horseshoe it, you
know what I mean? And, um,
but that was part of the fun too,
is like manufacturing
these segues into sketches.
So we shot all the sketches and then we
shot a all four episodes in two nights
in front of a live audience
where we would throw,
I do stand up and then throw to the
sketch or effect. Yeah. So in theory,
if you get 10 episodes, you could
be done by Wednesday for foreign to,
you can do a half day on Wednesday.
Like they have the PTA meeting and
then you'd done, yeah, it was cool.
It was cool. And then, you know, the
final night, you know, it was, uh,
happened to be my birthday and had a
big birthday celebration after that.
So it was cause, uh, nice. Uh, it was a
cool experience. That's awesome. Well,
my next, next time I do a TV show, I don't
think I'm going to do animation again.
I tried that. I was being so smart. I
love my show. I love doing the show,
but it's just like there's always,
you know, all, you know, every, yeah,
I shot the episode in
three days. I'm like, Jesus
takes us a fucking year.
You get this thing done. Um,
so [inaudible] uh, who is some of
the cast members? Anybody? I know.
I didn't want to a normal cast.
I cast pur sketch, you know,
so it isn't like there's this from Isis
how against the grain digit digit digit
cast here.
I want it like if it was a particular
sketch where you had three characters,
we would cast for that particular episode
or that particular sketch. You know,
I didn't want like a,
like a mad TV or uh, oh,
you don't want to know kind of thing.
People know whoever services the thing,
you know. Okay. And uh, so
there's some obscure people,
but uh, they were all great.
Soon did not be obscure when this
thing debuts, like I said earlier,
four episodes on Netflix,
Christmas Eve. Uh,
so you're a Florida Guy, right? Um,
what can people expect from a Florida
guy with a sketch show? Sorry,
I just love those questions.
Oh,
what do you think about our
current president? Is that crazy?
Let him material that event. So
He'd in a, uh, a social situation.
When you meet somebody who just finds
out you're a comedian and like every
single thing that said they
have to throw in I bed.
This is going to end up in your routine.
You should talk about this.
You know, somebody has a chip
and they put some, you know,
some guacamole on it and
it falls on the table.
I bet that's going to
end up in your attic.
They're in front of you in the buffet
line. Don't put this in your APP. Yeah,
usually try to avoid bombing.
My job is to entertain,
I mean, I might put this in the act,
the right this because now we are,
we're actually, they're actually
a, we're putting it in the act.
You described the Guac, fallen off the
chair. You know what I want more of?
I want celebrities,
celebrities,
if I can say the word telling me
about their political opinions,
I can't get enough of it.
You know,
cause I'm very unsure on
what I think about the world,
in which way I'm going to vote.
And then all of a sudden the f
six lead on a sitcom, you know,
informs me about finning or something.
And I'm like, oh, okay. That's,
that's how, that's how I need to think
about that. I want to see the flip.
I want to see in an inauguration
ceremony for a congressman and during his
swearing in, he says, who should
have one for wardrobe design
in a movie? You know, criticized,
criticized the wardrobe
winners, you know, um,
which of course is absurd, but I
know it's a weird, it's a weird time,
man. You know, I, I've never felt,
uh, I don't feel old, you know,
I just feel, I just feel like,
uh, it started with the music.
I didn't know what
people were listening to.
I didn't know what the popular bands was.
And then I started to not know who the
players were playing sports and now it's
like a, yeah, I don't know
the words, you know, I don't,
I don't know. In other words,
I'm not that bad. I just, I just,
I, I, uh, I don't agree with it.
When, uh, the academy
awards come out, the,
it used to be, I had seen all of the
movies that are up for best picture.
Then it was like, oh, I didn't see
that one. Then it was like, well,
I saw a couple of them.
Right. And then it got,
now it's gone to the point where
I've never even heard of any of them.
Yeah. I've never even heard of them.
Yeah. I haven't even heard of him. Well,
now there's so much stuff to watch.
You heard they just got rid
of another Oscar host. Yeah.
Evidently he trips somebody in like
outdoor recess it like in 1983. Oh,
that was it. And there was some
sort of getting me in kindergarten.
Kindergarten thing. Yeah. And so,
yeah, I don't know. I don't blame him.
I don't blame him because
that was a mistake.
That was a mistake that
he made in his past. Yeah.
And tripping is never should be how
many times you apologize for it.
It's never cool. No, I think all,
I think all mistakes in life should
disqualify everyone from any future
endeavors. If you're human. Yes, yes.
No mistake should be allowed for in,
in the human condition.
Perfect people. Perfect. People should
host award shows. Perfect. People should,
when Heisman trophies, they should, uh,
host award shows 70 people like
us. Perfect. People like us.
So I want to add for younger kids now
because so much of this shit is like on
video and just summit. You get
there, you're going to be fun. Nick,
the amount of the population that won't
be able to run for any sort of office.
I just wonder,
you know,
there's always pendulums and everything
and right now the pendulum is over.
Two people want to, is it Penn
dilemma? Pendulum. You might be right.
I don't know anybody.
She's Arron pendulum pendulum.
Oh, I'm getting a nod that I'm
right. Look at it once, look at that.
But once penned alum,
well it's a pendulum.
You went to Florida schools pendulum.
Well there,
did you go to Ponce de Leon in high
school? I went to Pendleton high school.
I went to the High Fountain
of Youth Junior high.
I went to Christopher Columbus high
school. Of course you did talk about,
you know, politically incorrect in
today's world. You know another guy who,
where like where all of that new evidence
came. If he did all of that shit.
What did he write it all down? He
tweeted it. A toy. Oh, they went back to,
is this tweet to do you got to do a sketch
about that? Cause he's on the lumber,
say go back and hey, you know, it
was on the Santa Maria, you know,
and it's a lot of time going from Spain
or wherever they left from over to the
new world. So we would just
sit back in his cabin and tweet
uncredible Wifi when went across the US.
Um, so anyway, I, yeah, I do.
I went to a Columbus high school.
I forget the point of,
I forget the question and what my answer
is. I don't know, but I'm enjoying it.
All right,
good talk anytime you can.
You talk about Columbus tweeting when
he should be captain in the Santa Maria.
Uh,
it's actually a great premise.
Like how quickly would Hitler get kicked
off at Twitter? The second he got on
Hitler,
you said Queer.
You can't say that. That's a
great sketch. All these people.
And then you got to have like, you
know, Mother Teresa when she was young,
something she did. I don't know.
Who knows? Uh, anyways, what's your,
are you still see you a college football
guy? What was your deal? I played,
I played college. That's what it was.
Um, a small school division three.
So, um, it was sorta like a school,
Heidelberg College and Tiffin, Ohio.
Loved my years there and just,
you know, Midwestern school,
just like if you were to film a
movie and a mid Western campus,
this is the perfect place. You
know, just a thousand students.
Everybody knew each other and a future
supreme court justices either say,
yeah, right, right. It wasn't perfect tab,
but wasn't underneath what was happening.
So I played football there.
Love that. I actually tried out
for a semipro football team.
When did it happen in
those leaks by the way?
The a f a I'm sure you've heard of that.
No,
nobody has the American
Football Association. Okay.
And uh, they had a, they
were forming this new league,
so there was a team going to form in
Orlando called the Orlando Americans.
They're going to play in the
Tangerine Bowl. Nice. Hi.
Buddy of mine went up and try it
out and they invited him to camp.
He's a quarterback. He played at
Notre Dame and he said, Reagan,
you should go up there
and try out as a receiver.
I played receiver in college and I'm like,
I am that guy that was out of shape,
you know, it was like a year and a
half after college because no, the,
the talent up there is the
kind that you could fit in.
So I went up and try it out of this
big mass tryout and invited me to camp.
Wow.
They invited me to camp.
They brought a nine receivers into camp.
But when,
then we had to try out from there.
They were only going to keep three
receivers. They had like a skeletal squat,
like two starters and one backup,
you know, and they cut down to five.
I was one of the five, I was one of the
five left. Nice. And then they, uh, I had,
I did a post corner pattern
and through my hip out and um,
I don't think I would've made it
anyway, but they cut me, cut me.
I'm just picturing you running in your,
your standup crouch.
Like that's why you threw your HIPAA.
What year was that?
I will always say how old?
How old are you?
Uh, well that was like 20. No. Yeah,
it was probably 20 to 22. I
already too out of shape. Yeah.
That's how it is.
No, no, I was, I meant that as
like a compliment to athletes I up,
I think I had a cousin, uh, played
a little semipro football. Um,
does the least still exist?
Is that an actually an actual way into,
I feel like it's the CFL or you
walk on and you know, or that's it.
Like as far as getting into the after
college to try and get into the NFL,
I figured either going to stand out at
the CFL and even then that's a long shot
or he just try to get a
walk on right after college.
Well,
I,
I had no aspirations of
making it in the NFL zero,
you know,
but the fact that my buddy
thought this one team, I thought,
well this could be a good experience
for a year or two if I could get on the
team. And uh, you know,
that that particular league
doesn't exist anymore. So
what exactly did you do? Your hip?
I did a post corner pattern. Yup.
45 degree angle and then cut back out.
I had these hip pads that were too
tight and I just remember feeling like a
sprawling, oh no. And I have no idea.
Like I didn't have money to go
to a doctor and I was like that.
I just couldn't walk. Kind of hard
to make a team when you can't walk.
So wait for that feeling to go away and
then you just sold it still hasn't gone
away. I continued on with your life.
It still hurts. It still hurts.
My knee hurts from football, you
know, uh, when I was in college,
I had a knee thing and they would shoot
me up with cortisone for the games
because we had to keep this oh
and eight streak going. Oh yeah.
You know what I mean? And they would
shoot me up with cortisone. It was, uh,
it was amazing because,
uh,
the pain was so intense when
they didn't shoot me up.
Like I could barely walk and then they
would shoot me up before the games and
I'm going to field running
around like a deer, you know,
like I felt like Bambi like,
but while I'm running,
I'm practically hearing crunch,
crunch, crunch, crunch, crunch, crunch.
It's just twisted my knee up,
you know, and I finally quit.
I quit college because of the knee.
I was worried that it was going to do
permanent damage to it. Did you, I mean,
it still hurts it dad a little bit
here and there, but uh, yeah. Yeah. He,
one of those weather guys, nice
starts acting up. You're like,
this is going to be a twister.
That's my hip. It's going
to be a cold front. Um,
I can tell asteroids when an asteroid is
coming. Oh really? That's interesting.
Yeah.
Is that your hip or your knee?
My hip is like if there's an
incoming asteroid and mine,
my knee lets me know if there's an
earthquake coming. How's was been wired?
Bizarre. You know what I think
here at all things comedy,
we could cut a side deal with
the weather channel. You know,
let's just cut over to Regan anything
hurting the Regan report and then we go,
oh,
oh I feel a magnitude six coming on.
You know,
I really resent to channels that I
used to actually enjoy was the weather
channel.
I actually used to like watching it and
for some stupid reason ended discovery
channel and both of them, you know,
I dunno, I dunno what they did.
I don't like how the, you know,
the discovery channel further,
like make sharks look out.
Like they're just inherently mean things,
you know, with all this shit going on
now we sit that and whenever you watch,
you know something on sharks,
they're always telling you now
people is a misconception about it.
But then the whole way they sh they sell
shark week is that jaws vibe, right.
You know,
they put a ski mask on him and stuff.
They always said they'd been typecast
and I would think with all this
progressive talk out there that someone
would speak up in them and then the
weather channel,
they went the way,
the food network where they used to
just tell you what the weather was and
they'd have some Weirdo and now it's like
all personality driven and they got to
make it sound like Jesus is going to show
up every time it fucking rains as a my
issues. Those are the things that keep me
up at night. I feel that about, um, CNN,
headline news, not regular CNN, CNN,
headline news used to be 30 minutes of
just news with the most middle of the
road news anchor. And I'm like,
this is the way it's supposed to be.
Just a guy just telling you nice
and straight what's going on.
And now it's personality driven.
They have just like you're talking
about these other gyms, angry people,
hot chicks, this person, that person.
Yeah. I saw one the other night,
the local La News here and uh,
they teased this for half an hour.
A guy got cut off on a motorcycle,
went over his handlebars in the highway,
got a couple of bumps and bruises
but was fine, but he filmed it.
He had a little camera on top of his head,
so they just kept filming the
footage on the five south.
May Am happens, it's this guy splitting
lanes. I mean his legal out here,
but that's what he's still are.
The guy just went, you know,
the guy went to change lanes.
I didn't see him.
He hit went up and over and they
were like, yeah, after 80 teeth,
the whole fucking like this,
this is an actual news, right.
Then if you ride a motorcycle in La,
you could probably going to go down at
some point and he didn't even get fucking
hurt. If he died, I'd be like, wow. All
right. But it wasn't, it was like a,
it was like the first draft
of a script where it's like,
you got to raise the stakes.
Can he go?
Can he go over the handlebars into
the oncoming traffic? Can we get,
can we get some of that? But the whole
thing, and he just led for 20 minutes.
They teased it and then I finally see
the footage that I already been watching.
They didn't have any more footage.
And then they interviewed him and they're
like, how do you feel? He's like, yeah,
you know I'm all right.
Yeah,
I guess it was news because the guy
who hit him walked up to him said,
are you okay? And he said yes. And
then he got in the car and peeled away.
So they had his face looking at them,
you know, so I guess that, I
guess that was the news aspect,
whether it was a hit and run like hell.
The guy that he didn't care enough.
The guy who hit him while he took
off. Yeah, I think he did plenty.
[inaudible] House. He got
out. He said, you are.
The mistake he made is he peeled away.
That indicates guilt.
What he should have done was just signaled
and got back on the highway and just
be like guy. I thought it was
fine. I got out. I asked him,
I knew he had the Gopro on. I knew I was
on camera so I didn't do anything wrong.
He had a helmet on. Defense attorney.
I didn't have a helmet. I was fine.
I figure he'd be fine to
look at the side of my car.
I was out here in la one time
watching the local news. They said,
we have breaking news right?
And they had a helicopter footage of
a home who's the garage was on fire.
And I'm like the only person that would
possibly give a damn about this grudge
being on fire is the guy who lives in
that house. Yeah. Think about our target.
Nobody else would care about their garage.
Been on file yet.
It was breaking news.
Well it used to be when I lived out here
in the 90s I remember I was just like,
this news out here is a fucking joke.
And then somewhere along the line,
national news caught up to what they
were doing out here in la. Cause when I,
I kind of stopped, I don't know
if this is probably a bad thing,
but I kind of stopped watching the
shit like at least seven years ago.
Um,
like right now I'm trying to remember
the name of the vice president and the
first one that I thought was Joe Biden,
but that was the last one. Mike Pence.
Mike Pence. Yeah. Okay. See that?
I mean that's literally the backup
quarterback to the United States.
I don't know his fucking
name. I can understand. Not
No one. The uh, what was it?
The Secretary of defense?
The treasurer. The uh,
no, if I know those, the coordinator of a,
cause they keep changing in the current
administration. So it is hard to keep up.
But usually when they, when they ride
for years, I can remember them all.
Oh, is that what it is? I
don't, I don't, I don't pretend
to know. All right, so what,
what else can we talk about
here? Anything, anything
else you want to promote?
You got some standup dates?
I'm in a,
I get to where the actors hat
and a show called Loudermilk,
the farrier milk.
Fairly brothers Peter Fairly.
They did dumb and dumber and all
that. They've done some things. Yeah.
Well there's huge and they're like, well,
the funniest fucking people ever. Well,
Peter Fairly and a guy named Bobby
Mort created a show called Loudermilk.
It's about substance abuse, dark comedy.
It's on a direct TV's audience network.
We just got picked up
for our third season.
I play a guy recovering from
substance abuse and uh, I,
I love it. I never did. Never had an
opportunity to do a lot of acting.
And uh, sounds great. I,
it's just so much fun.
What is your character addicted to? Uh,
alcohol, clay, Lubes, the whole thing.
Had a big family and had a falling out
with his family and the whole thing.
And uh, but it's funny but serious,
serious and funny. Mostly funny.
And Ron Livingston please. The,
the main dude. Um, and it's,
yeah, and it's like a group discussion
thing, you know, like an AA meeting,
but it's about people. I have
direct TV. How can I see this?
It's on the audience network. Every
Tuesday night. Audience Network.
So is that somewhere in my thing?
If you have direct TV,
you should have the audience network. It's
just a channel on there. What channel?
I think two 39 to 39.
What is it?
500 500 Jesus Christ.
You weren't even close.
Three [inaudible] this fucking thing.
You know, you know what Shannon,
I know it's on two 39 where I live,
it's it on 500 as well.
Oh, I don't know. But uh, on
the bus it's 500. All right.
So if you're in a house,
it's two 39 if you cause the channels
at the same but directv because that's
what I like cause I haven't direct TV.
You go on the road and I like
going to the hotel. I already,
I know ESPN is going to
be 206207208 you know, uh,
the redhead channel is a 798
I get the ginger report and see if
it's okay to go outside that day.
Jesus Christ,
look playing everything close to the vest.
What else do you got going on?
He had talked to you a fuck fucking
half hour before I find out you were in
third season of a show. That's all right.
A lot of people don't know about it.
You know it, it's an obscure, it's hard.
A lot of people haven't seen it yet,
but it's getting a lot of good buzz
and starting to get some traction.
Don't you feel like you almost have to
do three seasons of a show now just for
the general population to know that
it exists. It's amazing to me. I mean,
when I started in this business,
if I would've thought that I would be
on a TV show that my friends don't even
know about and I'm not exaggerating,
I have friends who go, Oh really?
You're on a show?
And it's like,
my parents have never seen the show that
I'm on just for the simple fact that I
can't figure out Netflix. Like they
came from an age, you just walked up.
He just pulled the Knob, turned
on the TV, four or five or seven.
What do you want to watch?
So they're not going to sit back.
I did a wide and then
they got that they can,
then they got to type in and search
like they just can be, I'm not, I'm not,
you know, I'm not fucking
doing that. They, they are,
uh, they are old school. So,
yeah. Um, I actually talked to
somebody have told this story before.
I talked one night I was talking to
another comedian and I was telling her how
much she liked how much I liked her
show she was taking. Oh, that's great.
[inaudible] we talked for 10 minutes
before she realized the show I was talking
about had already been canceled and she
thought I was talking about a different
TV show that she was on that I
had never heard of. That's crazy.
Then I told her that I had a TV show and
she had never heard of that and I was
like,
do you understand how fucked I could see
if we both worked at a lumber yard or
one of us did, but we're both
in this business. You're like,
you're like shooting, you know, you
don't even know what you're aiming at.
And we're both on beyond the first season.
So there is some sort of success to both
that shows that we're on and we still
have, we still haven't heard about them.
Wow. Um, anyways, where are you? Gonna I,
I saw, um, I had an
embarrassing moment with the,
Colin Quinn has showed tough,
tough crowd and uh,
you know, I saw him at a charity event
or something like that and said, hey man,
it's what you to know.
I'm loving you on tough crowd.
And he said it's off the air for
like four years, you know. Oh God,
you just feel so stupid. You know, like
that's, that's always the conversation.
First conversation, I would
have a colon coin. I, he,
there was a movie out that he
was getting credit for writing.
Uh Oh my God, what the
fuck was it called? It was,
it was the one with Daymond Waynes
in the Celtic Celtic pride. Okay.
I met him at my first
comics come home and,
and we're literally out
in front of the crowd.
I can't believe I worked with Colin Quinn,
Denis leary and all of these guys.
The crowd's doing a standing ovation.
Fucking Cam Neely standing there.
I'm like three years into the business,
right. I can't believe I'm a part of this.
And I see Collin and I'm like,
oh my God,
that's Colin Quinn from our
remote control SNL. And I'm like,
what do I say to this
guy? So I, and I was just,
oh cause I auditioned for the
movie. So, um, I lied and said,
saw it cause I didn't see it. I said,
hey man, I really enjoyed Celtic pride.
And he goes, I didn't write that piece of
shit. They took that away from us. Well,
I was like, oh my God. I
said the exact wrong thing.
That's what I get for trying to kiss ass.
But I made a mental note to never tell
somebody that I saw a movie that he
didn't see again. And I've broken
that. You have to, in this business,
you have to do it. Uh, speaking,
uh, golf. Golfing. Did you
say you were golfing with?
Right. Let's put Colin, is that we, we
met any minimum on the golf channel thing?
No, no, no. At a charity
show is where I saw Jesus.
I'm so [inaudible] list to my
goddamn guests. Well, you, you,
you do you have golf or I gotta go,
I gotta go on this thing.
When is this thing going to be here,
Brian and comes out to me or, dude,
you got to go on this, this three day.
It's like, it's like a spa, right? Yeah.
Give you sober up.
You can chill out and eat.
Nothing but a lot of fruits and
vegetables and we golf probiotics.
We do hot yoga. We go back,
we have a, we do hot yoga,
getting hip aligned again
and a lot of meditating,
a lot of meditating and it's just so,
it's so good for all,
all the fellows to get together.
Yeah.
So when did you got to be involved?
When is the next one? Uh, probably May,
but uh, yeah, I'd love to
have you involved, man.
I always feel like whenever I run into
the, the few times that I go on the wagon,
I then that's when I run into,
I sat my boots with you is,
was in New York and that was
that time. It was, it was,
it wasn't just the guys
that was men and women.
So they picked like this fancy fucking
place and that waiter came over and you,
you ordered like a Budweiser or
something like that guy. Sorry Missoula.
He did not have it.
Oh,
we haven't said these even the day and
you're just staring at him waiting for
him to finish. You're
like, is that a bear?
And you're like, okay,
I'll have one of those
when I love you weren't even trying to be
funny. You're looking at this guy like,
is it going gonna be a fucking
test at the end of this? Um,
and then I saw you more recently at a,
at a bar in New York and you weren't,
you weren't having cocktails at the time.
And then I felt guilty. I'm like,
I'm like six in here. No, I,
every once in a while I just, I, I, you
know, I shut it down for a little while.
Uh, I'm going to hopefully shoot another
special coming up soon and I just don't
want to go through the whole
fuck. I got to drop, you know,
20 pounds of pizza and beer.
I don't,
I don't feel like doing
that this time around.
So I'm also doing it during the
holiday. So my game plan is, uh,
I'll be three weeks in on Saturday.
I'm taking one night off,
which is dangerous for me because I'm a
big binge drinker. You know what I mean?
I'm, I'm goal oriented,
you know, I see a bottom,
I want to finish it right
now. One of these, these,
these path ass people that leave
sync in the dish dishes in the sink.
So I can't even speak now.
So I'm going to make a dinner for
my wife and then I'm going to,
we're going to drink a split,
a bottle of wine. There you go.
In the game plan is to
immediately go back on the wagon.
However, one of my buddies from New
York is also in town and he said, hey,
let's hang out Monday something.
Well maybe Sunday and Monday
and this is what happens.
Then it becomes Sunday, Monday, Tuesday,
right? And next thing you know, you know,
I uh, I love, I think we chatted
about this in the past. I,
I, I get my work done. You know,
I work hard and what I do and I
put my nose to the grindstone,
you know what I mean? But you're giving
me the classic, I work hard, play hard.
But when you guys, you can see that
the, when I did more hand movement,
Trump's got to get this much about it.
Like it's like the thumb and index finger.
Everything else is lined up.
And then the pinkies up like you're
a little tea cup, but when I,
well I'm going to go out, you know,
like, and I'm safe about it. Car Service,
the whole thing guys together,
you know, getting ballistic.
I liked those moments or
those evenings and it's good.
No, no, I love those months. You know,
when you get lit up half the year.
I hate the winter.
I don't want to remember it.
That's right. I want to be warm.
That's what hibernation
is all about. Yeah. Um,
so it's probably not a good
message for people out there, but a
problem with it. It's like Jesus Christ
my advice. That's my advice. Yeah.
That is mine too. So I, I, you know,
I shut it down for a couple of months
and then I slowly start back up again.
And then when I just, I just feel like
it's getting out of control of like,
I'm just, you know, I'm just
living too much of a, a, you know,
I dunno.
Just too much of a slothful the whole
state because what happens is everything
goes off the rails. It's not just,
okay, I'm having too many cocktails.
It's like I'm also eating a steak and
cheese. You want to fry side salad,
I'll take the fries. Well done. I start
doing that shit. So, um, you know,
every once in a while I just,
I sort of dial it back and uh,
and I dial it back and I get eight
hours sleep and I, I'm just sort of a,
I like it in the morning,
but the rest of the day I'm sad.
So you like waking up like having not
drank the night before and go ahead.
It's fine. I'm glad you know, eight
hours sleep, nobody go apologize to,
but then, you know, once after breakfast,
man, it's just really like the gloom.
All right man. The next weekend you're
in. Yeah, I'm definitely in for that. Uh,
is it while you're in Vegas,
right? He's going to be out there.
I don't know if I could do, I don't
think, I think I know it's a good idea.
This next one's in Florida. We do it
in a different place. Every, every, AH,
Jesus Christ.
I had to pick the year.
It's all going the other side of the
fucking country. I'm going to, I'm,
we'll spring for a private
jet for you can, you know,
can you just book me at a
Magellan's fucking comedy club?
Every comedy club down there always seems
to be like, you know, the Captain Hook,
the barge, the, the uh,
whatever the fuck is the top.
The tugboat.
Tommy's Tommy's didn't
get down in Boca Raton.
It's funny. It's a guy from
the Florida keys. He books, uh,
he books almost to Cuba. Comedy
Club, whatever. All right, sorry.
I'm sitting here reading, trying
to make dumb jokes. Um, all right,
so stand up in a way for episodes.
Netflix, Christmas Eve. Uh,
are you a, you're going to be celebrating
holidays or anything like that?
A New Year's Eve.
I'm performing finally.
I get you to fucking plug a date.
What does it take me 20 minutes?
He just told me, cause I didn't plug them
on any other thing. He said, you know,
if there's an opportunity, this is Dave,
my tour guy. Smart Guy. Yeah. He said,
you know, part of this is plugging things.
He didn't say it that way. He goes,
if you can plug your New Year's eve date.
So here I am going to be here.
I am smoothly plugging my New Year's eve
date, Chicago, the Chicago theater. Ah,
New Year's Eve.
That's tremendous.
But that I'm not bringing in the new year.
I'm not on stage doing the countdown.
I always, what time's your show?
Eight o'clock. It'll be over,
you know, like nine 30, nine 45.
But I want people in Chicago knowing that
like you come to the show and then you
go to a party and have fun. I'm not
going to, you know it all night.
Chael let down.
I've done those and then you got to come
out and it's like a DJ still spinning
around. Why they want to hear,
keep doing your fucking job.
No, I can't. I can't, I
can't be. I'm an MC to uh,
the countdown and they've
already shut off the bar.
It's everybody's just standing
there sort of starting to sober up.
Good. I got mad at everybody
and then it's just over now.
Guy. Get the fuck Outta here.
Yeah, I would even rules
worked this many years at this job so
I can count from 10 to zero backwards.
And I've done that so many fucking, oh
my God, all those years of doing that,
I don't even work new years anymore.
I work a couple extra in November
and December and then I just,
I take that night off so I'm going to
take my wife out is what I'm going to do.
There you go. She doesn't know that yet
cause I usually a surprise. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. So that's what I'm
going to do. All right,
so that's it everybody. Brian,
Regan, everybody. By the way, dude,
you always such a huge influence on me.
You were one of the greatest comics I've
ever seen and just decade after decade,
just still in, you
know, the upper echelon,
everybody always brings you up when they
go the best guys ever the best fucking
albums and all of that stuff. So if you're
in the Chicago area, New Year's Eve,
it's an eight o'clock show.
He's not doing the countdown.
So get some friends to hang,
you know,
go to the show and then afterwards
pick a bar and a last time, uh,
stand up and away for episodes.
Netflix, Christmas Eve before you wrap
up, I, I have to say, I
think you're a genius.
I think you're wonderful at what you do
when you throw me a compliment that way
it means the world to me.
I love watching your craft
and how much you put into it.
You have a wonderful comedic mind.
So that compliment coming from you
means the world to me. Thank you.
And you said that perfectly.
Just the way I wrote
it out. I love you brother. All right man.
Happy New Year and Merry Christmas
and we will golf and make a right.
All right, let's do the little bit
of advertising here. A tipsy elves.
Everyone.
Everyone needs an ugly Christmas
sweater this time a year.
Do you want the bragging
rights for the most?
Talked about sweater at the
holiday parties. Then wait
til you see tipsy elves.
Hilarious. Re-Imagine in a reverent new
designs. You barely get these soon, man.
It's almost Christmas here.
Stylish Christmas suits for the classiest
of holiday gentlemen interactive
sweaters. Oh Gee, got the AH, in this
climate. I don't know about that.
Uh, beer pong, corn hole,
drinking game darts.
So uncle Bob can relive his college
glory days at the family dinner.
How is that interactive?
Do I not know the definition?
That must be the third
definition in the dictionary. Uh,
interactive to participate with another
person. Definition number three,
you get down to three. It's like
a ugly Christmas sweater. Um,
anyways,
and even hilarious theme teas and awesome,
cozy onesies for,
for women holiday dresses.
So you can get down with your bad elf.
Oh Jesus,
that's such a mom SUV joke. I
love it. I catching leggings.
If you're not happy in your marriage
so you can strike a festive yoga post
thirsty or lounge around with a cup of
spiked eggnog and tease that sleigh and
cute, comfy ones. Ease.
They even sell bright and crazy ski
suits for when you're shredding some Nar
this holiday season going
west coast on that one.
You won't find some hilly,
you won't find more hilariously
awesome designs anywhere else.
So be sure to order from tipsy elves
in time for your ugly Christmas sweater
party.
And Right now my listeners get 20%
off@tipsyelves.com when you use my code B
Bravo, Bravo at checkout. That's 20%
off anything you order on the site.
Go to tipsy elves.com and enter my
code BB at checkout to get your 20% off
sitewide discount,
dollar shave club,
Joe Dollar Shave club hubs,
everything you need to look,
feel and smell your best.
And you never have to go to the store.
That's because they deliver everything
you need right to your fucking Doula and
they keep you fully stocked and
what you use so you don't run out.
Here's how it works.
Dollar Shave Club has everything you need
to get ready and they just said this,
no matter what you're getting ready
for, they have you covered. Head to toe,
your hair, your skin, your face. You
know, he just said here I was working,
going back into more fucking copy.
They have a new program
where you keep your odds,
you automatically stocked up
with the products you use.
You determine what you want and
when you want and how to fuck.
Do you do it for once a month to
once every six months? Oh yeah.
I guess you do it on website.
She says,
I was like somebody telling a bad fucking
story like where you get to the point
plus what they're handsome discount.
The more you buy, the more you save,
and right now I'm not good at math,
but that doesn't make sense. Right now.
Dollar Shave Club has
a bunch of status sets.
You can try for just five
bucks like their oral care kit.
After that, the restock
box ships, regulars size
products@regularpricegetsyoustartedexceptforjustfivedollarsrightnowatdollarshaveclub.com
slash burr.
That's dollar shave club.com/burr
for just $5 all right,
last one.
Everybody hymns,
40% of men by age 40 struggle from
not being able to get and maintain an
erection because they're
thinking too much. Even if the,
even if the world's greatest actor,
even the greatest world's
greatest actor can't fate one.
Why do you guys turn to weird
solutions or do nothing?
I Dunno cause you get shamed for it.
You know
what am I going to go on Oprah and talk
about that? Well I might pee pee, whoa.
Work.
Uh,
when they can turn to instead to medicine
and science for Hims Dotcom a one stop
shop for hair loss, skincare,
sexual sexual wellness for men.
Answer a few quick questions and chat
with the doctor for confidential re
review. How does your, I mean, I
know blood goes into your addict.
It's gotta be like a garage door in
there. You know, like a valve, you know,
it's like a reverse varicose vein.
It's like this is the one you want.
Products are shipped
directly to your door, right?
Answer a few quick questions and chat
with a doctor for confidential review
products. Products are
shipped directly to your door.
Severe Ed isn't just an issue for rich
old guys in bathtubs that affects men in
their thirties and forties.
Oh God bless you.
You got to get these guys
up and running again. Uh,
this is like gas monkey for your Dick.
You know, it's like a garage. Fine.
Uh, being your best means
performing your best.
It's a rectal without the dysfunction.
Hard made easy sale.
Odie say a lot to your little fat.
Try Hymns for a month for just five bucks.
Will get you started for just for
just five bucks while supplies last.
See website for full details.
This would cost hundreds if you
went to the doctor or a pharmacy,
go to [inaudible] dot
com slash Burr ed for a,
that's for hims.com f
o r a h I m s.com/burr.
Um, ed capital Ed. All right,
no space between Bernie
de for hims.com/burr ed.
All right,
now listen to a little bit of music and
we got another half hour grace hits from,
from some Thursday afternoon
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcasts from
early this year, five years ago.
Wow.
No Sir.
Yeah,
it's the holiday season.
Doobie Doobie.
Do who sings that song?
What's up? It's bill births.
The Monday morning podcast for Monday,
December 13th, 2010. How the hell are you?
I've had that fucking song in my head.
I heard it on the radio
and like the grocery store,
you know I was going in
there to go buy a ham,
some glaze Jenelle gelatinous shit.
Right.
And I was in there and there
was this song, yeah, on the uh,
on the speakers there,
the sealant of the grocery store
that I just mentioned I was at,
if you forgot already, you
know, and I'm driving around,
I got this big fucking ham sitting in
my grocery cart and they'll through the
speakers, it's just this guy. It sounded
like it was from maybe the fifties,
you know, it's the holiday
season. Doobie Doobie do,
I can't remember if you went Dolby,
Dolby doe or that's just
how I remember hearing it.
I'm trying to give you more lyrics cause
I got to know the name of this song
cause I want to download it.
I want to drive around La in 80
degree weather on Christmas, you know,
with a stupid look on my face listening
to that song. How the rest of it go.
It's the holiday season,
Doobie Doobie. Do Hey,
just take a kid Katie and you cut
something like that. I can't remember.
You know all that is, you know
when that, you know the, the uh,
what is it when they do
that thing where uh, no,
that that elevator music from the 1950s
where they actually took like sorta like
Blues Progression and I
dunno what they did to it.
So it's almost like still has
like the bed, but the habit there,
but that data, maybe
that's more swing, Eh,
you fucking stick it in your cut,
something like that.
But obviously it's a lot more,
uh,
has a lot more family values two or
whatever. It's the holiday season.
So please for the love of God. So I'll
stop singing this fucking song. Somebody,
somebody let me know what the name of
that song is. Okay. And before I forget,
which, I don't know how
I would, all right. Um,
you know,
we do underrated overrated every week.
Do you guys remember that from the last
three fucking years and be doing it just
about every Monday. I got
one for you. Underrated.
The black Crowes underrated.
Despite the fact that the selling out
these huge venues, this still underrated.
I went to go see him a Saturday
night or say as they say in Boston,
it's amazing.
They actually take that word that has so
many consonants and they remove all of
them like a cancer when you're going
to come on and come over with say a
Saturday night at the palladium,
the same place where Richard Pryor
tapes live on the sunset strip.
I went down and I saw the black Crowes
play truth and salvage company opening up
and the black Crowes played
three hours people three hours,
hour and a half acoustic set,
and then they take a break like fucking
barely 12 minutes and they come back out
again. Basically after kicking the shit
out of the crowd for an hour and a half,
they take a 12 minute break,
right? Just to go back, you know,
have a cigarette and a little shot of
Gatorade and they go right back out again
and kick the shit out of the crowd
for another hour and a half. Uh,
it's easily the best show
I've seen in like 10,
12 years. And um, I
don't, I just go see them.
They're up in San Francisco. If you're
in the area that playing the Fillmore,
all this, uh, all this week. And
uh, they, they were unbelievable.
And the greatest thing that I liked
about it was everything that you were
hearing was being produced by human
beings that the humans that were on the
stage as opposed to all this other
shit that you go to see. Now,
I'm not saying these people
aren't talented, but you know,
I've been flipping through the
channels like an old man, you know,
four fingers inside the fucking
waistband and my pajamas,
you know, the guy, you know, the,
the fucking was that married with
children just sitting there, you know,
you got the remote, the
other hand clicking through
and you see like, like, uh,
you know,
these little pop tarts.
Even a guy like usher who
is tremendously talented,
the singing and the
dancing and all that shit.
You're hearing all of these instruments
that are not on the fucking stage.
And then you're also hearing like,
I can't say with him,
I can't remember who exactly it was,
but like you here at least it's like
the person is singing with themselves.
They have the track going
and it's like, so I dunno,
musically, socially acceptable
now, like back in the day,
if you've got busted doing that, that
was like the end of your fucking career.
Everybody's just like, he's the
fucking sell out man. And that was it.
It didn't shit. So the fuck am
I trying to say? It was awesome.
It was unbelievable show. And
uh, recently I finally started,
uh,
downloading us actually some little feet.
It's a band like 20 years ago,
guys I worked with in this warehouse
with telling me I should get into.
And when I finally got around to doing
it and downloaded their greatest hits and
that live album, uh, uh,
Christ, what's it called?
Waiting for Columbus, I believe. And uh,
they have a song on there called Whelan.
And I had listened to it, if
someone was saying, Oh yeah,
the guy wrote it and that's why he got
kicked out of fucking Frank Zappa's band.
And then he made fucking,
and he got with little flunk story short,
the Black Crowes ended up,
uh,
they closed out their set
singing that song and it was,
it was, I was just a shit.
It was even the way they ended this set.
They didn't do the big fucking, you know,
you know where they are just sitting there
strumming that one note in the guitar
and a fucking drummer sitting there
smashing all assembles. Thanks.
[inaudible] you been quite good.
I didn't even do that.
They played this really cool fucking song
and it ended on this nice just I was,
it was the shit. It was the shit.
So if you get a chance to see him,
please go see him. And uh, the
drummer of that band, Steve Gorman,
uh, has a podcast and a few
baseball fans out there to, uh,
or sports fans in general.
It's a sports podcast and a this week,
Tuesday,
I believe he's going to upload it.
Uh,
he interviewed a useless from the, uh,
the red sox. So please check that out.
And if you're not into sports,
please go see them at the Fillmore.
I'm sure they're already sold out,
but it was, it was fucking awesome.
So there you go. There's my plug.
I am in a generous mood this week.
You know why?
Because it's the holiday season.
Dooby dooby Doo and you stick it up.
Your fucking comment.
Sorry, I just, I got a
jar this loose in my head.
I'm going to figure out what
it is. So anyways, well,
well well a lot has happened since the
last time I did my podcast has an invoice
and girls,
a lot of things have happened.
Does anybody know what I'm talking about?
Just you know,
it isn't that an amazing thing
about life that in six short days,
seven days,
if you're into math,
how many fucking things can happen
and just a little seven day period.
If you go back eight days and you
think of what you thought about certain
aspects of the world and how different
European is a mere eight days later,
what would be a good example of that ass
shit? I don't know. Let's see. Let's,
let's just take your average
fucking Joe from eight days ago.
Like, I dunno. Let's say like a jets fan.
A jets eight fucking
days ago,
Huh?
What you oh my God. I was just
looking at my fucking my recorder.
I thought that whole thing. I thought,
I thought I didn't record it. I died.
I thought, I thought, I thought
he said you wanted one. Um,
I thought the thing had shut off.
Let's continue here. Goddammit.
I just fucked up my momentum.
A jets fan eight days ago.
What the fuck would they thinking?
Huh? I'm walking around now. People
eight days ago,
those motherfuckers thought that they
were going to win the Superbowl. You know,
probably talk to this day.
We're going to go into Foxborough.
Grab fucking Tom Brady with
his bio is updated mullet.
Slap him around a little bit. Put a
couple of more dimples into his chin.
That's what they thought was going
to happen eight fucking days later.
Eight days later.
Right now,
every jet fan in the country eject them,
has their green fucking head between
the knees looking at the fucking green
balls, shriveling up, pulling
up into their fucking abdomen.
All right, now here's the deal.
I'm not going to talk shit.
Talked a little bit of Shit.
I had to because of all the fucking
emails I've been getting and not just from
jet fans.
That fucking Dick from Philly.
You know who you are when you sent
me that email. Go Bill. Give it up.
Give it up already. You sound like
a moron. The jets are a fucking,
when the the the best team in the
AFC and all that shit. All right,
I'm gonna say this.
Say it real quick cause I don't
feel like I need to say anything,
but I'm a cunt so I'm going to
continue talking about this. Okay.
What did it, what the fuck did
I tell you? What did I say?
Everything I fucking said.
I'm not even saying that they can't
still pull it together and maybe win the
Superbowl.
But to refresh your memory
at the beginning of the
season when I was watching
those fucking morons on
that HBO hard knocks thing,
running their mouths, that's what it
has. Why are they talking all this shit?
They're talking as if they already won
one, two, three fucking championships.
And do you remember what I said?
I said the Patriots,
the fucking Ravens,
this Steelers,
the chargers or even the dolphins could
beat this fucking team on any given
Sunday.
And Lo and behold,
within six days to fucking losses,
you know? So that's it.
I had to give you one.
I told you so.
All right.
And here's one for you jets fans.
If you think I'm thinking that the
Patriots are fucking going to win the
Superbowl and that the defense I saw the
last two fucking weeks is their defense.
Now you're sadly mistaken.
This is why you fuckers get disappointed
every year is because you see,
you see half
a ray of sunlight and you
think, dad, that's what it is.
I still don't like our defense.
All right to fucking great weeks in a row
does not make up for the fact that you
shit the bed and let up 24 to 30 points
for the first fucking 11 weeks or
whatever the hell nine weeks,
whatever. I don't know. No,
11 weeks we were nine and two.
That's right. The first 11 weeks. So,
I dunno who do you like for some reason
I'm thinking the ravens sitting there
all quietly nestled in Baltimore.
Right? No one's paying attention to him.
Joe Flacco. I Dunno. I know we beat
them this year but I don't know.
I'm trying to beat those guys
twice in one year so I'm not,
I'm not fucking saying anything.
So there you go. That is it.
And having said that,
how fucking hilarious
I really felt as this something here,
I felt really bad for the strength and
conditioning coach who stuck his knee out
and knock that dolphin guide down.
I,
I felt really fucking bad for that
guy because that was such a classic
spur the moment completely
out of character
move.
It was just the right set of circumstances
had they'd beat the Patriots the week
before.
He wouldn't have done that shit had they
bounce back and they were beaten the
dolphins,
he wouldn't have done that shit.
He's never done anything like that was
just the classic that spur the moment.
Like it was just fuck we
got killed by the Patriots.
Fuck we're losing this game.
He's a competitive psycho.
Cause that's how you get to that
level, right? It was just all line.
I'm telling you
that guy like I don't think he's a
bad guy. I really don't. It was a,
it was a piece of shit thing to do,
but you know,
there's so many fucking people in
jail because of a moment like that.
They had never committed a crime their
entire fucking life and just two major
shifts happened in their fucking life.
And then an opportunity presented
itself to think about it.
How many times you go down this,
you walked down the street,
you see somebody bent over tying
his shoe and your brain just goes,
why don't you just go fucking
boot him in the ass? Right?
But you don't because the other side
of you is going, wait a minute. Yeah,
put this guy in the ass.
What if he knows that fucking UFC
shit comes over and fucking, you know,
blows out my eye and I look like
fucking Josh Koscheck over the fucking
crosscheck, obviously his
fucking name, right. Or what if,
what if I get arrested for assault?
What if I get sued?
Like that voice just beats down
that other voice count. God Damn,
look at those titties. Once you go up and
just grab them, just grab those titties.
They're right there.
Grab them.
But you don't cause you have a job.
She got a family cause you're
working towards something and it's,
it's going relatively well.
Yuron course.
Then what happens, you know,
girlfriend dumped Hsa, you know,
you lose your fucking job.
It starts to unravel and when it starts
to unravel that voice in your head,
you know,
and she just fucking kicked that guy
right in the balls become so fucking loud
that that other voice of reason is now
it's way in the back of your head. Oh,
you don't do that? It hurts.
You can't even hear it anymore.
And that's what the fuck happened to
that guy. It was just, it was too,
I'm telling you last
night. Yeah, last night.
That dude was sitting there. Okay, why
is this fucking thing saying I'm peak?
And that was a too loud.
I'm trying to overcompensate for the
fact that people were saying that my,
my podcast with too quiet. Try
and overcompensate. There we go.
Why is that light sitting there
going peak. Hello? Test one,
two test went.
Oh fuck you.
Okay,
so ever dealt lead.
The reason why it said peak was because
I had reached the memory limit for my ls
10 or right. It deleted some shit. I'm
back. So anyways, the fuck was I taught,
I was talking about that guy.
I guarantee you he's not a bad guy.
Last night he was sitting there talking
to his wife. He couldn't even sleep.
It's wife or his girlfriend,
you know, she's sitting down
in the corner, you know,
holding her knees, sitting in the corner,
go to, why did you do that? And he's like,
I don't know.
I don't know why I did it like
Gus Grissom and the right stuff.
It was, there was a glitch.
The hatch just blue.
I Dunno why it did it.
I was standing there,
we were losing the fucking gay
with a guy came by. It just,
I only stuck it out a little bit,
man. I just stuck it out a little bit.
He's, he's, he just fucking
muttering to himself.
Why did I do that?
Why the fuck? Why did I do
that? That was so fucking stuff.
There's guys in prison right now.
Why did I,
why didn't I listen to that voice?
Why I paid my taxes?
I was a cub scout.
Right?
I fucking made sandwiches for my kids,
send them off to school
and then just sat one day.
My fucking neighbor,
excuse me,
Karl Koller talked to you for a second.
Um,
I know we've discussed this before.
Is there any way you could just not have
your dog relieved himself on my lawn
and that just happens to be a fucking
shovel and you're just looking at his
mouth, you know, and she
pedal what the Shovel Bang. You
fucking do it. Then you're like,
fuck, get up. Please get up, please
get up. Did anybody see that?
Bury the shovel man.
And then you just go down that road and
you've never committed a fucking crime
and then you end up in jail.
It was just because of that one.
The circumstances were there.
I don't think that that guy's a
bad guy. I don't. It was just,
you know,
the problem is they're
being led by a crazy man.
Rex Ryan is out of his fucking mind.
Another thing that I've said
since last fucking year,
okay? That guy, I don't know if he's
bipolar or if he's manic depressive.
All right?
But I am a psycho and I can spot another
psycho from a fucking cross the room.
That guy is out of his mind and what the,
you know,
you got to buy into your
coach's philosophy. All right?
So they bought into his shit.
Talk in fucking John Wayne
Horse Shit when he was having,
they didn't realize he was
having a manic episode. You know,
all the coaches sign in that bus as
he's walking up and the depths of his
insecurity saying that, you know,
you don't even deserve to be here.
He had to so overcompensate for it. He
just, by the time he grabbed that Sharpie,
his manic episode was so
through the fucking roof.
He just starts writing on
the board. Ooh, so long
we're going to win the Superbowl.
He did that and he brought all his
players up to this manic fucking level.
And when you go that high,
you crashed that fucking low and
that's what happened in two weeks.
This motherfucker, the strength and
conditioning coach, no pain, no gain.
You've got to want it.
That guy whose dad was probably
like Emilio Estefan says,
I have a step as whoever
the fuck you say his name,
his dad and the breakfast
club where I hate you.
You son of a bitch.
That was his dad.
So he's got that information up there.
He's got rex Ryan's manic,
all right,
and his fucking head and it comes his
dreadlocks locked jackass running right by
them. Sticky meal, stick
your fucking knee out.
And he just, he went with it. You saw him.
He's trying to fight it is
other needs going. No, no, no.
Stay back here with me and the other
needs like fuck that. I'm going in.
I'm fucking going.
And he stuck it out and that fucking
Jesus. Could you ever think that you could
take down a professional athlete that
easily.
He looked like he fell out of a car.
He got kneed in the side of
the leg on the 40 yard line.
He didn't stop rolling to the
fucking 12 yard line. Okay. Ah,
can you imagine that? The second he
did that shit, that poor bastard.
I bet it felt like a cold.
Like he was standing under a fucking ice
water waterfall. That even makes sense.
And then that would be like hale.
I could've just said hail whatever.
It's fucking cold and he's standing at it
and I bet he could even feel is fun
fucking from is his goddamn heart down.
He probably couldn't feel anything
just going like, oh my God,
what did I just do? Oh my
God, please get up. Please,
please get up. Ah, fuck. Did
anybody see that dip? Did
rexy that. Why did I do that?
Oh my God. Oh my God. What if I
get fired? But if I get fired,
he fucking went through all of that
shit. That poor bastard. You know?
But I got to admit,
as a patriots fan,
I don't ever have to listen to the fucking
jets fans talk about cheating anymore,
do I?
It's the post going to have that caught
cheating with a little asterisk next to
it for the rest of the fucking
season. Ah, your green counts.
Um, so there you go. Whatever. So
that's, that's this week and football.
That is this weekend football.
How about those fucking Minnesota
Vikings with their inflatable roof,
you know, can you imagine if that happened
during a game? Even with helmets on,
I think somebody could die. It's a weird
thing because it's snow. You think like,
it's just going to be like,
you know,
getting a snow storm over with
in like a half a second. But, uh,
that was probably a good couple
hundred pounds of snow and a,
I don't know about you guys.
I don't want a couple hundred pounds of
anything landing on me from the top of a
fucking Dome Stadium. Jesus Christ. Okay.
That was one of the saddest moments I've
ever seen for professional franchise.
You know, getting ready to play the New
York giants, New York football giants.
How you guys want it?
You want it?
They have fucking big
blue fucking bring it.
The 20 minutes you got to
call back. Yeah. Listener,
you know about that football game.
A Kuka.
Is there a way we could do it on Monday?
Monday would probably work a
little bit better cause uh,
stadium collapsed and uh,
we have to,
we have to get a bicycle pump when we
have to repair it. We'll duck tape. Yeah.
But uh,
okay.
I figured Detroit's in between your
city and our cities. Okay. Okay.
You know, sort of equally
distant and uh, okay.
It's just a suggestion. Oh yeah, just
call me back. Okay. All right. Bye. Bye.
Okay.
Oh fuck. So anyways, let's, let's
get into the podcast here this week.
So that's it. I'm done
fucking talking shit. Uh,
and I got to tell you something.
I'm going to pat myself on back.
I could have been a lot
meter, I could have been a
lot meter. And you know what?
I gotta be honest with you. If I
believed in our defense a little more,
I think I would have been,
how are you doing down there in San Diego?
How is your team slapped you around
enough this year? Jesus Christ.
Whatever you do,
do not bet on the fucking charges.
You don't know who the fuck is going
to show up. It's kill or be killed,
rape, or be raped. That's what the
fuck's going on down in San Diego.
They're either going to win 41
nothing or lose 56 to eight.
They got to safety. That's how
they got the eight. All right.
Two field goals in a safety,
right? Is that another works?
Maybe then went for a
two point conversion.
I'm just trying to cover all the basis
for the fucking mathletes out there.
All right, let's move. Let's move on
here. Uh, up, up, up, up, up, up, up,
up a bear. Oh, here's something
that somebody sent me.
They mentioned that they'd
seen Paul Mccartney, uh,
a beetle on. Uh, why don't I just
read the email? What are, let's,
who's getting who? Let's be honest. Why
don't I just attempt to read this email?
Okay. Hey Bill, I just
finished watching last night,
Saturday night live with Paul Mccartney
and I think it's time for Paul to hang
it up for good.
I feel like a bit of an
asshole for thinking it because
we're all supposed to be
in awe of him because he's a beetle.
Uh,
they let them do four songs last night
because everyone is in awe of him and
that's the problem.
No one wants to tell the 68 year old man
with the dyed brown hair and saggy man
boobs that he doesn't have the voice
for a live performance anymore.
I fear getting old and
being irrelevant too,
but I hope that when
it's my time to retire,
I can accept that I'm not what I once
was and move on to something else that
better suits that stage of my life.
Paul should look to someone like Bano.
Not that I'm a big Bono Fan,
but I think he's done it right by
imitating Bob Geldof's example of rock and
roll for philanthropy.
How about a pat on the back for getting
through that sentence without fucking it
up? Uh, you two won't draw a
stadium sized crowds forever.
So Bonno set, set himself up as a jet
setting friend of the world's poor.
Even if he never gave another
concert as sung another note,
he'd still have a meaningful, you'll still
have meaningful work beyond his music.
Uh, it's like you were
saying in previous podcasts,
it's good to have a side business in
case show business doesn't work out best
regards. Um, yeah. Um,
I kind of see what you're
saying a little bit, but uh,
I know a lot of people saw Paul Mccartney
last year on tour and said he was
fucking unbelievable.
And then I also think that the Beatles
right now are a victim of a backlash
because of something that they
didn't create. I think apple,
not apple. Is that, uh, whatever
iTunes. That's right. Itunes.
I got real confused there because they
had apple records and then Macintosh has
a fucking apple and that's all it takes
to really just send me flying down the
fucking sideline. Like that. Dreadlocked
son of a bitch. You got tripped anyways.
Um,
okay.
I think iTunes has been trying
to get the Beatles catalog.
Obviously it's probably the first band
you would want to start with as far as if
you wanted to make money.
They finally got them and they
are from the baby boom generation,
Steve jobs and all those guys. So this
is, you know, this is there Jesus.
So they present the band as their Jesus
and just eventually it's just inevitable
that it's going to a
annoy the generations after.
And not to mention,
because we weren't born when
they were putting out albums,
it's impossible for us to see how far
ahead of their fucking time they were.
You know?
And that's something I also see in comedy
where I've actually gotten emails from
people going, what's the big deal
with Richard Pryor? You know,
35 years of people ripping off his shit.
They've actually made, you
know, some of his stuff.
You know, like after 35 years,
people finally caught up with them,
you know, so, or like an
athletic thing. Somebody,
somebody sent me a fucking email
this week, was talking about that a,
that running back on Cleveland.
Remember that guy was talking
about who has the face mask,
makes them look like the front
of a dodge ram pickup truck.
Someone was saying they thought Jim Brown
of the Cleveland browns was overrated
and that they're so sick of hearing
about this guy that if this fucking white
dude played back in that era with those
skinny people who played football,
he would have run all
over them. Which, uh,
a lot of people say shit like
that and it's complete bullshit
because
is if he played back then
look, if you want to stick
them in a time machine, yeah,
he would run all over those guys.
But that doesn't mean he's better.
You know what I mean? That's like,
okay, I have a big test on Tuesday, um,
the me on Friday,
we'll go back in time after I've taken
the fucking test and then I'll know all
the God damn answers.
That's what it's like.
If you take today's athletes
and you put them back then,
which you have to do is just say,
okay,
if you take that guy and you had him
born the same year Jim Brown was born,
you know, he'd still be what he is
today because of the nutrition, the, uh,
the level of, of uh, just
intelligence about sports.
And what is possible at that moment,
the workout equipment and all of that.
But you know, obviously if you
take a fucking guy you don't have,
the big flaw in that is that kid today
is not the Jim Brown of this era or any
fucking error. You know? And if you
took Jim Brown from back in the day,
you had him born in 1980 instead of 1940
or whenever the fuck this guy was born
and he had access to all this,
all this information about nutrition,
sports science and all that,
he would have been much bigger than he
was. He still what a fucking dominated.
All right? So that's one of
those sports arguments that they,
that that people have,
like they'll talk about
Koby Bryant because they see
Colby doing everything that
Jordan has already done.
They, they equate it,
therefore he's as good as Jordan and
they forget the fact that no one had ever
done that shit until Jordan Jordan
changed the game. All right?
Same thing with the fucking Beatles.
The Beatles was so fucking
far ahead of everybody,
but now it's, it's 40, almost
50 fucking years later. Yeah.
Now you're going to look back on it and
have to, everybody's ripped him off.
It's going to be like, dude, what
the fuck was the big deal? All right.
So there's that.
And then the last thing is I'm sick of
people throwing old people out in the
fucking yard. You know, like
they're your old iPod speakers. Eh,
there's a loose wire. Fuck him. He's out
the God damn door. I think it's bullshit.
All right. I like old people. Even
that fucking asshole downstairs.
I like him. I respect him.
And you, you, what it is,
is you look at them and you see that died
here and you see their saggy man boobs
right here, wrinkled up. Tushies. Right?
So you equate that with their level of
intelligence rather than this fucking guy
has walked this planet for
65, 75, 85 fucking years.
And uh, you know, what's that
expression? As much as things change,
they stay the same. Stitch in time,
saves nine without a fucking hammer.
Remember expressions, whatever. You know,
this guy has seen everything
that you're about ready to see.
He's already seen it. Okay? He didn't
have a fucking iPod. Who gives a fuck?
All right. A cunt is
still a cunt. All right?
Some things don't fucking change.
And this guy has this whole wealth of
knowledge that here's a guy's been playing
live gigs for 50 something fucking years.
All right?
He can still physically play.
Why wouldn't you want to go see him?
You know, with all his fucking
experience, you know? Yeah. I mean,
I could see if he was
jumping off the piano,
trying to do splits and
touches fucking toes.
And then he came down and blew out his
knee and they had to give him fucking a
Geritol rub right on is blown out
knee then. Yeah. You know what I mean?
But like I don't like that whole fucking,
it's like,
it's like a corporate mentality. I,
your skin's wrinkled up. We have no you,
we don't like looking at you beat it.
I Dunno.
I'd still go pay to see the rolling
stones. I would. Why wouldn't you?
Why the fuck when those got red?
Those guys give me hope that I can sit
there and drag my ass out on a fucking
stage. Eight years old, watch
up would medicaid you know,
out on a cruise ship.
But I do understand what you're
saying because definitely want to, uh,
if I'm on stage
in my sixties and seventies,
sixties is fine cause I'm still going
to be fucking annoyed and want to be out
there. But in my seventies,
if I'm still on fucking stage,
I want it to be because uh,
because I had not because I need the
money because I want to be out there.
All right. I remember Keith, Richard's
saying like, someone was like,
when are you guys going to hang it
up? He's like, never, I'm a musician.
This is what I do. I will do this
in front of two people or 200,000.
It's what the fuck I do. You want
me to put down my guitar? You know,
he has a great line in his book where
he talks about how much he loves guitar.
I don't know if I said this last week,
it,
Keith Richards has this book called
life. It's the fucking shit. And um,
he talks about how he loves
guitar so much that to this day,
like he opens a guitar case
and just the smell of a guitar,
he wants to crawl in there
and close the lid. Alright.
So if you ask this guy to
stop going up playing live,
you might as well put a bullet in
his brain. You killing them in. Okay.
So having said that,
let Paul Mccartney do is fucking thing.
Has any been through enough?
I mean that guy truly found the
love of his life. All right,
you fucking dies then.
He, he's in a bad place.
Like the fucking jets strength coach.
He goes out,
he married some gold digging
whore with one leg, you know,
which was the classic
fucking misdirection.
Cause I bet in the back of his
head he kept going, you know,
I think she's a fucking gold digger.
And then that other place like, dude,
she only has one leg man,
stop being so mean. Right.
And then he just gave
into that and then you go,
hey, you think if you tried to
trip her, you stuck your knee out.
Like maybe there was a possibility that
she's athletic enough that her fake leg
would just fall off and she would just
be able to continue hopping down the
sidelines and make a play.
Granted, she get a penalty if she,
if she ran out of bounds on her own.
You know,
that's a question for you this week.
If that fucking gold dig and horror
with the one leg, if she ran down,
she had a fucking dolphins uniform on,
right?
She went to the islands and got her hair
braided by some dude in Jamaica. Right.
And she comes flying down the sideline.
If you stuck your knee out,
hit her fake knee. Right.
Knocked her fucking leg off.
Why am I repeating what you just heard?
Everything I just said.
Do you think that she would
have the ability running
full speed? All right, we'll,
we'll uh, we'll adjust it a little bit.
You tell her you're going to do it.
You can delete the legs going to fucking
pop off now. The fake one. Jesus Christ.
We think I'm an asshole, but just
shut up. You're dumb whore. All right,
I'm going to fucking knocked.
Shut up.
I'm going to knock your fake
fucking leg off sweetheart.
When you're running full speed, if
you can keep your balance. All right,
we'll give you some shiny shit.
You're gold digging whores.
Do you think she could do it?
Okay. That is my question for you.
During the holiday season,
Doobie Doobie, do air,
we knock off your fake leg. You can't.
Um, all right, what else do we got here?
You guys want some youtube
videos for the week? MMM. Okay.
Once again is great as the
black Crowes were. Let's,
let's talk about some
fucking music that I respect,
but uh, I, I have to shut
it off every time I hear it.
And that is basically the melancholies
singer songwriter put a gun in your mouth
early to mid 70 shit.
You know,
did I talk about this last week?
I can't remember. Like Carol King.
Okay.
Seeing an Aas,
David, it's too, they [inaudible]
south.
It is that has died and fucking kill.
Yes.
Self. You douchebag. How would it
fuck it goes that song. James Taylor,
I seen fire and I've seen rain.
My fucking friend died in a plane crash
and I always thought that I'd see you
once again, Carly Simon.
Okay. That's the way.
That's the way I've always heard it
should be. I'm telling you right now,
don't ever listen to that song on a rainy
fucking day. If you put that song in,
you have a 40% chance of doing
something really harmful to yourself.
Joan Baez, diamonds, and rust,
you know, and I have the song. If you
have, if one of those songs ever comes on,
you're in a car and you don't have
control of the radio and you just feel
yourself getting dragged.
Yeah. Down this bottomless pit.
I have the song that is basically like
that in adrenaline injection to the
heart, like in pulp fiction. Just
put on Huey Lewis hip to be square.
All right?
I can't take 100% credit for that.
Me and a young Joe to Rosa.
All right. The teen idols,
sensation of the opiate.
Anthony Program we're taught was,
it was actually a segment that we'd love
to do on the uninformed shelf that we
do once every nine
years. At this point, uh,
we were talking about how it's impossible
to be depressed if you listen to Huey
Lewis and the news put
on hip to be square.
I challenge you not to fucking
get a smile on your face.
It's like trying to hold off a yawn. You
know, you can't do it. It's impossible.
So, uh, I don't know. I don't even know
why I'm bringing this shit up, but like,
I don't know what it is about that music.
I respect it once again,
getting back to the black Crowes
thing cause it's actually okay.
Human beings producing all the sounds
that you're hearing. All right.
But uh,
you know Jesus Christ already.
Do those people have any happy songs?
Who's another one?
Oh, that that fucking girl sings in
the false set off with a weird eyes.
Joni Mitchell
singing about a paved,
paved the parking lot, pay paradise,
turned it into a parking lot.
You don't know what you got till it's
gone. All right, Joanie. I got it.
Last week was better.
Jesus Christ. You fucking,
you know, I don't know. I
did. I am it. Was there any,
was there a point that was made there?
Other than the fact that I can't sing?
Um, oh, here's a music
question for this week.
As you guys also know other than playing
drums, I a I fuck around and guitar.
Um,
and uh,
I recently bought ACDC flick of
the switch, another underrated,
which I know I did last week.
Underrated ACDC flick of the switch.
I just want to know what
tuning of those people in are.
They tuned down like half a step because
it's like I listened to the album,
I shut it off. Then I go and
I go to figure it out. Like,
let's take the first song for you.
Guitar players out there rising power.
All right. He's doing a pull
off down to a B court. Right?
But are they tuned down like half a step?
Because last night I'm sitting there,
my jam jams and I got my guitar that I
can't even fucking play. And I'm like,
you know what, I'm gonna have a little
geek moment by myself that nobody can see.
I'm going to put on much
this fucking record.
I'm going to play along to this song.
Cause I figured it out the Malcolm part
and it sounded like shit and I tried
tune it down half assed and I just could
not fucking figure it out and beyond
the fact that I suck. Can somebody
help me out? What are they doing there?
I know it's not a drop d
drop d tuning.
Cause I know what that sounds like.
That sounds like Satan is
your bitch and you got,
you got some errands for for it to run.
I know what that sounds like
and I challenged somebody to come
up with a riff and drop d tuning.
That doesn't fucking rocket. It's
just, it's just, it's the shit. Right?
But does that tune down half a step that
I, I can't fucking get. Come on man.
You heard how I sing?
Help me out here.
Help me out or I'm going to fucking sing
for the rest of this podcast. All right.
It's the holiday season. All right,
wait, let's, let's continue on here.
Uh, oh, I got my, uh,
I tell you somebody rear ended my Prius.
You know what I mean?
Which really is like fucking boot and
an eight year old in the ass when you
really think about it.
Um,
and got it just hard enough where I
couldn't walk away and be like, Eh,
don't worry about it. You
know, my hatchback wasn't
quite closing correctly. Um,
you know what I mean?
Wasn't quite,
it didn't quite work on the
hatchback area. Kind of like
a girl with a big booty.
You know what I mean? There's always
a little bit of butt crack coming out.
Who's got a tug? You know,
that's how he can judge.
If you see a girl with a nice ass,
whether or not she's a whore or not,
if she's constantly trying to adjust
her genes and pull them ups or ass crack
isn't coming out of the back of
her pants, uh, that's a good girl.
That's when you can take home to mom,
just makes sure she wears addressed.
But if she's just standing there with
like an inch and a half coming out,
she doesn't give a fuck. I can't
even say that she's a fucking whore,
but either that or she's
just accepted who she is.
And for some reason that they don't make
jeans for girls like that. All right.
That's one of those references that
it just was such a visual to me that I
completely forgot what the
fuck I was talking about.
Let's go back where you talking about,
what was I talking to? Look at tar.
Who gives a fuck? Oh, a song
about my car. So anyways,
I'm getting it fixed this week.
And uh, so I went down to, uh,
the rental car place and it was a usual,
I go down there and I asked for a
fucking, uh, uh, an economy car.
You know, I don't give a shit. I really
have no pride when it comes to cars,
even though I fucking love him.
I don't give a fuck.
I'm just so into not having debt
that I, I'm, I'm, I'm a little miser,
so I get this a con, I go
down there and they go, well,
the economy car isn't quite ready.
We could give you a free upgrade
to this four door fucking pickup.
And then it just became,
my,
you don't even got outweighs my miserly
ways is, uh, I don't like waiting.
I refuse to wait. So I go,
yeah, fuck it. I'll take it.
And then immediately my girl was
just like, why did she get that?
I can't try that. It's so
big. What am I going to do?
I'm like, we only got until
Monday. Fucking relax.
Plus we got to get the Christmas tree
this weekend. Right. Well, you know,
Dasher read their Ed vixen
daughter.
If you wonder how I did that,
that was not some Phil Spector
Shit that's called just,
you just spin it around ThreeSixty
away from your mouth and you just keep
talking,
cause back around you like that.
It's a new recording
process I just invented. Um,
so anyways, uh, and go, yeah, we
got to go get the Christmas tree.
So for the last two years, I have to
admit something to you people. All right.
I have been going down to get these
fucking Christmas trees and I have been
getting the traditional Christmas tree
and we all know what it looks like.
All right. It looks like someone on
the biggest loser about four weeks in.
That's what a Christmas tree
supposed to pop that full, you know?
But there's these other Christmas trees
that I noticed, not the scrawny ones,
but they are minimalist Christmas trees
where you can see the entire trunk and
it's like they still have the branches,
but there it's very like symmetrical.
It looks fucking cool as hell.
Clean look and Christmas tree,
right?
It looks like one of those trees and
like the doctor Seuss books, you know?
So I go, you know what? Fuck this.
I'm going to get something different.
I liked this tree.
It looks fucking cool.
I think the ornaments are going to hang
off it much better as if you know when
you get one of those full
trees, you know this. Yeah,
just it's a fucking pain in the ass. And
then the end of the end of the God damn,
you know,
Christmas season,
if you're not a dick and you just don't
throw it out the side of your car,
like a fucking some,
you know,
some piece of degenerate
gambler that Oj money,
I said have it by Tuesday and then you
just throw it out the fucking car, right?
If you actually do it the right
way and you, you saw it up,
it's a pain in the ass. It makes it
unbelievable mess this thing, you know,
it's like, it's like you ever walk into
like, uh, like when I'm out with, with uh,
with Nia and we go out to one of
her, uh, her clothing stores and
if it's like a corporate place,
the place is just jam packed was shit.
But if it's like a privately owned,
they go out and they buy these individual
pieces still by a couple of sizes of
each things that they like.
And you go in there,
you pray to God that they
have your size and it's,
and you go in and it's very minimalist.
That's the sort of Christmas tree
that I bought. And uh, you know,
knee is a fashion Easter,
so I thought she would like it.
So I bring this Christmas tree in
and the second she looks at it,
cause I think she's going to
be like, you know, like I live,
she just have like techno music on like
I'm so far into the fucking future here.
The second sheet looks at
it all my confidence just
drains out the bottom of my
shoes. And I go, yeah, this is the
Christmas tree. And she goes, Oh yeah.
He goes, where's the rest
of it? And I'm like, no, no.
That's the style. That's the style
it's supposed to look like that. I go,
it doesn't have the cool, I mean it looks
like one of those trees in Dr Seuss.
She goes, yeah, she goes, I
think it looks more like that,
that Christmas tree and
that Charlie Brown cartoon,
it's now I feel like an asshole.
So because I love the verbal abuse that
you guys give me every fucking week.
I'm actually going to be dumb enough
to send a picture of my Christmas tree.
Now granted, it's naked. It's
not all dressed up. It's not
all dolled up. All right?
It's like Charlie's Theron and that
stupid movie monster that rather than
chastising her for being a murderous cont,
they actually made a movie that said
maybe guys Outta to look at themselves and
treat bitches a little bit better before
they go and start killing you after a
blow job.
It wasn't that the message of
the move SMS a gy got so anyways,
it doesn't have any makeup on,
which I think should automatically
give it a golden globe for being that
courageous. It was so brave. It
was such a brave performance.
Um, just take a look at the Christmas
tree. Tell me what you think.
I think it looks fucking bad ass.
I love it.
I fucking love it. And uh,
I stand by it. You know,
I'm breaking a little tradition here.
So, uh, go on the M podcast.com.
Take a look at my Christmas tree.
We'll have a whole section where you can
leave your God damn comments about what
a moron you think I am.
Um, or maybe actually like,
um,
and along with that you can also
look at these youtube videos,
the youtube videos of the week.
People.
I just felt like I should have had a
theme, some theme music right there.
At some point,
at some point,
I'm going to have a make enough
money in this fucking business.
I'm going to make a little studio and
I'm going to have all those little sound
effects, like a real radio show like
Anthi on Opie and Anthony, you know,
he's got all those little buttons he
pushes and ops got all his little buttons
that they push, you know, those
button push and son of a bitches.
I want to be one, two, I have
drains. Um, and when I do,
I'll have a little fucking theme
music here. Uh, but until then,
you'll just sit there and listen
to the awful silence. All right.
Youtube videos of the week that you
can watch on the MM, podcast.com,
the official, uh, Fan Webpage,
whatever the fuck you call it,
of the Monday morning podcast.
All right. Youtube video. Uh,
this is one of my favorite ones.
Uh, if people puking makes you sick,
please don't watch
this. But, uh, you know,
the great thing of watching a video tape
of somebody puking is you don't have to
smell it so you can just
enjoy the hilarity that it is.
You know what I mean? It's like
that shit that people, they, they,
the vaporizer with weed, you know,
where it gets rid of everything,
all the toxins that just keeps the
shit that gets you high. This is,
this is the vaporizer version of
watching somebody puke. Watch this video.
This is, this is such, this video
literally made me cry. Laughing. Uh,
epic beer pong puke. Um, it's just,
it's got it all the,
the, the volume of Puke,
the noise kid's making when
he's puking and then the,
the fucking good natured
attitude that this dude has.
He actually,
he has poise while puking.
I think Mark Sanchez could learn a
little something about this, you know,
little poise under fire by the way.
One of their offensive lineman got hurt.
Now watch a run for his fucking life.
All right.
This game management son of a bitch.
Oh,
so right about those
motherfuckers. All right. Um,
all right, youtube video. Another one.
Uh, this one is just so fucking creepy.
Um, I love this. I want to
go on a date with this woman.
Uh, it's called the best model in the
world and I'm sure a lot of you guys have
already seen this and I'm sure Taj
Point Oh is already put it up. Uh,
but it's the best model in the world hand
model and is this woman talking about
being a hand model? And for a
lot of people it's what she says,
but for me it's the way she
just keeps stroking her hands.
I don't know what she's doing,
but it is so fucking creepy.
I want to go on a date with her.
I want to take her out to dinner,
have her sitting across from me as I
tell her about how many brothers and
sisters I have in my hopes and dreams
in life as she sits there nodding,
just stroking her hands and that it
would just, it would really, yeah, no,
I don't know. Call me a
fucking psycho, but I,
I would really love to just have that
experience. It's on my bucket list. Um,
uh, did I spell this right? The next
one is Cammy secret parody, boob apron.
You know that thing,
that commercial they have out there where
a women with the big titties and then
all their boobs are always
fallen out of their shirt,
but they don't like wearing something
underneath it to alleviate the problem.
So they created this little napkin
that hooks onto your bra straps. Uh,
first of all, let's pause and just say
how fucking brilliant an idea that is. Um,
as far as just making $1 million,
you know,
this checks out there who just
have, you know, efficient boobs.
Just trying to think of a nice
way of saying small boobs, um, um,
comparable, capable titties. Right.
There's still going to buy him just
cause I like having different colors and
sometimes I don't want to wear a shirt.
And then those other girls who lie to
themselves about how big their boobs are
and for some reason they've,
they buy a D Cup Bra. You know,
when they got BEACOPP titties,
I don't know why they do that.
Kind of like the guy who goes in and
buys the magnum condom and then it slips
off and he becomes a fucking father for
the nighttime. Uh, yeah, just watch that.
It's a parody of that. And um, this
next one, all I have is a website,
but my, uh, my web guys definitely
going to have it up. Uh,
if you want to watch a video of somebody
who's about ready to get arrested by
the FBI, watch this video.
This guy took one of those, uh,
um,
you know,
as those nerds who rather than going
out and getting a pilot license,
they go down to an open field
and they just fly like a,
a fake playing around a
model airplane motorized.
There it is motorized playing around.
This guy put a camera on it and he
flew around the New York City skyline.
I, yeah, I'm sure this guy isn't
going to get in trouble at all these,
they had the brains to
blur out their faces,
but the dude is talking on the video.
You can hear his voice that
they're going to get caught.
Some is going to recognize his voice that
he went to high school with. You know,
by the way, people, if
you do something illegal,
if you're going to be dumb
enough to videotape it,
don't put it on fucking youtube and of
all the fucking cities to do it too.
I mean it's definitely,
the footage is fucking cool,
but this guy buzzes the statue of
Liberty with this model fucking airplane.
And considering the military has those
drones that can fly around and just
vaporize people,
it's probably not a good idea to
have one of those flying around.
I'm going to go out on a limb, so
I look for that news. Everybody,
these guys getting arrested in the
next couple of weeks. Um, okay.
We also have the youtube video of the uh,
the jets strength coach
tripping the Dolphin.
If you just want to watch that and shit,
just watch that with my psycho analysis.
Is that all right? My psycho
psycho analysis of that guy? Uh,
is that it? I think that's it. Those
are the youtube videos of the week.
And what are we up to here
at this point? Ah, by Golly,
we look at that 53 fucking minutes.
Um, I know what I need to do.
I need to hype my last stand up Gig,
my last official,
one of the official one of the year.
I am going to be at the Improv
out here in Bray, California.
Beginning this Thursday and I'm going to
conclude on Sunday and it's going to be
a, what is that? December 16th,
17th 18th and 19th.
Um,
and I got to tell you my new hour is,
I'm really happy with where it's at. Uh,
so I figured something out
somewhere during Seattle,
right through the cobs Gig in San
Francisco and I'm really excited,
really excited to go out
there. So, um, you know,
come on out and see me. How
about some Latino people? Ah,
trying to break into this
market out here. I, I don't,
I don't know how to get in touch with
you guys. You know, I started doing that.
Resent his stone shit. I
fucking, I quit it. You know,
I really want to learn how to speak
Spanish and I'm realizing that if it did a
little bit of resent of stone and I
just had somebody who spoke Spanish or
Mexican,
whatever the fuck it is,
you skip call it and not trying to offend
anybody. I want to know how to do it.
I think it's fucking, I don't
know, it's a cool language.
I want to learn how to say it and
then I can talk to some Spanish women.
Who the fuck am I kid?
All right, so that's it.
I'm going to be there this
Thursday, Friday, Saturday,
and Sunday. All right? If he,
if he can't make it there and
you're in the San Francisco area of,
I'm telling you, go see the black
Crowes, go see them because, uh,
I think they're going to take a little
bit of a break after this tour from what
I've heard. Uh, you know,
it just fits into my whole,
don't go to the automated checkouts.
Don't go to see these fucking
autotune jackass is go,
go see the real fucking deal. All
right there. I'm done with that shit.
And with that, is that the podcast for
this week? I'm coming up a little short.
All of a sudden, am I running out of gas?
You know what it is, is I'm, I'm in a,
I'm in my,
my vacation mode already and
I'm in a silly fucking mood.
I got my Christmas tree and I'm going
to be singing out those fucking holiday
songs this weekend on stage
or just society that just
for the podcast listeners,
and I'm not even going to explain why
I'm doing it. I'll be telling Joe again,
this guy can go fuck himself. It's
the holidays. Cs Ed Dolby go bay doe.
Um, all right. Who's kicking?
Tell him I'm going to keep
repeating that fucker joke.
Is that what I'm going to do,
Bill?
Are you pulling the Paul Mccartney
right now and you don't know when to get
offstage according to that one
fucking listener? I think I am.
Did I have any underrated,
overrated, underrated?
A four door pickup truck
like I rented this week,
couldn't believe how convenient was
I went to go see the black crows.
I put me and four other
adults in that thing.
We went to go see him and
then the next day I got a,
I got a fucking a Christmas tree
in the back, standing upright.
You know, it's funny when I put it in
the truck, uh, these three people walk,
we're walking down the street.
One of them was some Mexican
dude and he in Spanish,
he said something and started laughing
and I was convinced he was laughing at my
tree.
You know another reason why I would have
loved to gut through the Rosetta stone
so I could have said in Spanish,
um,
actually it's not the Charlie
Brown tree or right Hector,
it's supposed to look like that.
Thank you. Very classy. It's very much
just a freak them out. You know
what I mean? Cause you know,
nobody thinks a white
dude could speak Spanish.
Like how many times did George Bush catch
somebody's saying something fucked up
is he sat there in his fucking white
elite fucking brown penny loafers with no
socks and is Pete Carroll Coaching Pants,
right?
Jesus Christ of the Seahawks get their
fucking asses kicked this week or what I
went to and to this week,
everybody, I finally went 500.
I got something for first for gamblers
out here that I know you're all going to
agree with. All right. And, uh,
oh before I said, you know, one of the
reasons why I didn't do an extra podcast,
because a lot of people were asking
me how come right after the jets game,
you didn't do a podcast making fun
of the jets. That's because I didn't,
I didn't believe in our defense.
And I thought it,
we had a really good chance
of not, uh, you know,
of losing that game by a couple
of points just because you know,
when you let a 24 to 30
points, that's what, you know,
that's definitely a possibility.
And a,
I just thought it would have
been bullshit if I came. Yay.
You know what the fuck you,
you fucking lost.
That's also why I kind of
took it easy on you this week,
which you probably don't think I did,
but hey,
I did defend your fucking strength
and conditioning coach did and I will.
All right then why don't I just talk
about that and I can't remember what I was
talking to. Oh, here's one
for the gamblers out there.
So I took the eagles last night.
All right.
Given three and a half against
the cowboys had they want,
I would have gone three and one which
I desperately needed instead, you know,
and they drive down,
write down the fucking field,
all write that down by three points and
they can kick a field goal and win the
bet. But because it doesn't matter,
they just want to win the game.
They take a knee and they
run out the fucking clock.
And this is a rule that
I think NFL should do,
you know,
subtly without letting the public know,
because they really can't line
up with gamblers in or anything.
I really think that is in a sign of
solidarity for the regular Joe out there
were actually had the balls to put money.
So believed in your fucking team.
If you put money on your fucking team
and you have a chance to cover the spread
and the final fucking second.
Sheesh. God dammit, you should do it.
Andy Reid kicked a field goal.
You fucking asshole.
Oh, I needed three in one. I needed that
so fucking bad. So now I'm too went to,
I can't pick a game to
save my fucking life.
You know it was funny was
I took Tampa this week,
Tampa and Atlanta had been my
goto teams and I, for some reason,
Carolina has been a little Jekyll
and Hyde, so I, the game scare me.
It's a divisional game.
I just didn't fucking like it.
I stayed away and I went with the ramps
because the saints have been Jekyll and
Hyde and I wasn't buying into
this. Oh, here they come,
shit that they've been doing the last
couple of weeks at Sam Bradford has been
shown that he can play at that level.
You know,
hundred percent wrong on that game.
And I can tell you this right now
to save yourself a fucking all sir.
When the team,
you bet on throws a pick six.
I don't give a fuck if it's in the first
quarter. Shut the game off. It's over.
It's like God damn. 14 point
turnaround. All right, whatever.
I bitched moaned and complained enough.
We're coming right up on an hour.
I think that's a good, that's a good,
that's a good number. Isn't it? That's it.
God bless all. Yeah. I hope you
enjoyed the podcast this week. Uh,
get out there and go do your quads at
Christmas or a Hanukkah. Is it over yet?
I saw a couple of people driving around
with Menorahs on top of the car's not
even bullshitting. Um, I've done only
idiots did that with Christmas trees.
They mocking the idiocy of Christians
or they like, we can be dumb to,
you know, like how women do. Yeah.
How come only you guys get to box and
have brain damage. We want it to it too.
You know,
why are women's so convinced that
everything guys do is so fucking worthy of
getting involved in too?
You know, we're dumb.
Just sit back and think a minute.
I want to join the workforce rather than
sitting around hanging out with cute
little kids. I know it's a job.
What the Fuck's wrong with you?
Wouldn't that be awesome as a guy?
Just think about that right now.
If the roles were reversed,
you know,
and you had the option of just Mary and
some rich broad who just go out there
and just take care of you and all you
gotta do is just keep the house clean and
make a meatloaf a couple times a
week you can just tap out. Okay.
You know,
I'm not saying you have to do that,
but there's a lot of us out there who
would, okay, I do that for a couple.
I think I'll be in the fucking
stay at home dad for a couple of,
and just chill the fuck out.
Right.
Getting an incredible shape. So sick. All
those broads out there talk why? Again,
I understand what they're out of shape
because they had to carry the baby.
But if you're a guy, there's no fucking
reason why you can't be in shape.
He didn't have to carry that kid around.
You know,
you got all day long to work out.
Oh my God, there'll be the shit. I know
what you think it out of these kids.
They never fucking go
to sleep. Yeah, they do.
They take a nap every fucking you can
nap with them. You can figure out a time,
you can go out and go buy all kinds of
healthy food and then just chill out.
I would get the fucking NFL package.
I would just whine to my rich wife in,
just be a, come on guys, I won. Yay.
Would you, you know,
do like the, you know,
they do the little girl thing when
they want something, why did you start?
I just your baby, you'd buy it for
me. I do that with the NFL package.
You know, just make it a little weed here
when the kids are screaming. All right.
And I would fucking
tape every goddamn game.
That would be my mission every week that
I was going to watch all 16 NFL Games
or whatever the fuck they have,
Cup people have by weeks, 14 games,
whatever the fuck it is.
And I would sit there like a fucking
defensive coordinator who was waiting for
the phone to ring, you know, and what's
going to get picked up or some shit.
And I would just, I would watch all
of those games and I would get a gate.
I get up a padded fucking play room where
the kids couldn't hurt themselves and
I just fucking get a gate where they
couldn't get out and I just stick them in
there all day at play amongst yourselves
and that I would just watch all these
games and every once in a while
I would just throw food in there.
Like they will like, you
know, animals at the zoo,
you know,
rather than making three sandwiches,
I'd make one big one and I just throw
it in the middle and then just film it
like the discovery channel, you know,
with the pecking order, like the,
the most dominant male
lion gets to eat first.
Then all the other ones are sitting
there, you know, Growlin and shit.
Waiting to see when the, when the
biggest one is full, when they can go in.
I think I'd like that. Uh, all right,
that's it. That's a podcast for this week.
Please help me out.
I want to know about that one legged
gold digging horror running down the
sideline.
If she could keep going.
I want to know what tuning ACDC is
using on the flick of the switch album,
particularly,
uh,
houses on fire and rising power. And, um,
it'll be funny if it's standard tuning.
My ear is just that bad add.
What's the last thing?
Was there anything else?
I know I fucking asked you something
else. I don't fucking know one. All right.
That's the podcast for this week. Have
a great week. Opiate jointed. Go Fuck.
[inaudible].