Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
Just checking in on
what's going on. Let me do that.
Like I'm falling off a cliff.
I woke up this morning by Dubai,
Dubai,
the dumbest song in my head and I can't
get it out and now I'm going to sing it
to you so it will be stuck in your head.
It's a very vengeful thing for me to
do. It's something that, you know,
pieces of shit guys.
Do you know if I'm going down,
I'm taking you down with me and all
those kinds of pieces of shits. You know,
they do that. Uh, the ladies, the
ladies like to dabble in that. Well,
fuck you. This isn't a relationship. At
least I'm getting some of your t shirts,
right? They're going to get
something from it. Well,
if this song's going
to be stuck in my head,
I'm sorry to say that it's going to
be stuck in yours head too. All right,
and I have given you a good, I've been
talking about this for a good 18 seconds.
That's plenty of time.
Even if you're driving in the car to
hit pause and you're choosing not to,
why do you do this to yourself?
Why don't you just choose the road
that's going to bring you true happiness?
Is that because you grew up and you watch
people being abused and you felt like
you didn't have a choice in life that
this is the way it was? You know what,
that last 10 seconds is probably going to
be worse than the song, but here it is.
Right?
Okay.
Yeah,
and it's something,
I don't know who sings that song.
I don't think I've ever gotten past
those first two lines of that song.
It's always comes on session presents
love songs from the 70s yeah.
This one
dude,
it make my brown eyes blue.
Right? And you say and go look
at this fucking horse shit.
And he start thinking about your childhood
and next thing you know you're on the
phone with the operator. Can I
get the deluxe edition? Yeah.
I still have a CD player in my
car. Well, because I'm frugal.
It's not because I'm failing and I
resent you saying that. Of course.
I still want the CDS.
I'm speaking of my old car,
my car. I've had it since, uh,
October of 2007. It's a 2008.
Oh, it was a brand new. [inaudible]
had fucking stars in its eyes, right.
Just stepped off the bus here in Hollywood
with a piece of Straw between his
teeth,
like axl rose and the guns and roses
video while welcome to welcome to the
jungle. Um, and now look
at it. Oh, this thing,
it looks like somebody attacked it
with the fucking can opener. Right.
It did as until as of the other day.
My uh, my wife was out of town. She was
in New York City for the Great Patrice.
So benefit,
I want to thank everybody who came out
and I want to thank everyone who did the
show. I unfortunately was not able
to get a fucking flight in, in time,
if you can believe that I actually
missed the benefit is fucking brutal.
I had a flight out, uh,
Saturday morning, Saturday,
and I believe that one I was on American
Airlines and they just gave me a call
and they were like, like a, you know,
when a one 800 number and I went hello.
And they were like, hello. Well it says,
oh by American Airlines and flora you
there's like two or was three as by Ganzel
you'll then relocated. No,
you might want to grab a pad.
You'll dow bed rebooked it's like rubber.
What?
Seven five zero out of lax on Tuesday,
January 26 at 1:50 PM uh,
the benefit was on the 26th I was
supposed to be flying out on the 23rd.
They pushed it three fucking days and
I was going to leave for 15 east coast
time when the show starts at seven. So
I'm like, well, that's not gonna work.
So I call my travel agent,
you know?
And so she got me a flight on JetBlue,
7:45 AM on
Sunday, the 24th. So I'm like, no worries.
All right, so I miss a day, no big deal.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
Right. And then I get a call,
I get a call like the night before,
I'm all packed up,
got my shit right next to the door,
and there's like,
there's other Connie from jet blue eel
bite, whatever, bad at a piece of paper.
Right? And then they fucking pumped
me to fucking Tuesday. So I said,
fuck these guys. I call my travel
agent again. Now I'm on virgin.
All right.
I don't know why they call
it Virgin Airlines and then
it looks so Jesse in that
fucking thing. It's like at the
w hotel was a plane, you know,
with the fucking aquarium lighting that
just says no one wants to see a good
look at their face in a mirror after
they do what they do in here. Right.
So they booked me on that fucking
thing and they're like, well,
the time we can get you out is right when
the New England patriots game starts.
And I'm like, oh, that guy, he
got TV, I fucking put me on it.
Right.
And then that one got canceled.
So at that point I did deduced
if I'm using the word properly,
that, uh, that the fucking every,
every poor bastard from Saturday
and Sunday, now that those flights,
it all been canceled. We're now eating up
all the Monday and Tuesday once. So, um,
I had my travel agent go after another
flight and then meanwhile I called my
manager,
who knows all these big guys and I said,
can you get me a replacement in case I,
I'm not going to be able to get it.
Long story short,
I wasn't able to get in in time.
We got a replacement and a,
I wish I could have been there because
a rich vos who crushed it as a host once
again this year. And he said, uh,
blah, blah, blah, blah. Unfortunately,
Bill Burke can't be here. And
everyone's like, oh, what the fuck?
Where is the red country? Right. And he
said, uh, that's the bad news. He said,
the good news is Louis C K and Louis
CK walked down and they would fucking
absolutely mental. And uh, you know,
I was replaced one balding redhead
with another balding redhead with more
credits. So nobody misses me. Um,
and I guess he fucking murdered it and
then the all had to do is 15 and he,
cause he's such a great
guy, did like 25, um,
and just fucking destroyed and
everybody had a great time. And, uh,
somebody sent me a picture of, um,
of everybody in the end coming out. Al
Del Benny flew in all the way from Sydney,
Australia.
That's another reason why I didn't want
to reschedule cause this guy flew in
from the other side of the
fucking world. And um, Oh,
who else was there? Rachel fine find sign.
Greer Barnes who absolutely murdered,
you know, one of the greatest,
who ever did it? Greer Barnes. Um,
Jim Norton. I don't have it in
front of me. I wasn't there too,
so I know I'm going to end up
forgetting somebody. But uh, anyways,
everybody Godfrey did it.
Everybody fucking killed. And
uh, they had a great time.
So anyway,
so I was out here and I was supposed
to be in New York from Saturday until
Wednesday, so nobody knew
that I was out here, you know,
so I was just like, well fuck it.
I'm not telling anybody I'm here.
And I just started handling a bunch
of shit that I've been putting off for
months, if not years. Um,
I did everything from, uh,
get my last will together, my,
you know,
when I die or whatever.
It makes sure that everything goes
to the people it needs to go to.
So there's no fighting
hopefully, uh, which is actually,
it's really morbid, but it's also
fucking kind of cool. It's like, yeah,
fucking you take this and you take that
in a, I'm out of here. Good luck to you.
I had a great time and a great ass.
Um,
I rolled change that we hadn't jars.
I handled that and I dropped my fucking
Prius off and I had all the fucking
dense repaired. You should say.
It looks brand fucking new.
There's a couple of little ones
that they just, they left in there,
they'd buffed the whole thing up. I
didn't get new believers because you know,
you have new bumpers out here.
They last for about three days before
somebody just bumps into him. So, uh,
I just had a buff those things
up and it looks fucking great.
And I'll tell you right now,
having a paid off Prius with
80,000 something miles on it in La,
La is the greatest fucking car
you could ever drive. It's just,
it's the shit and it takes the too,
it's like Ben Roethlisberger.
It just fucking shakes him
off and he'd get, keeps going.
And no matter how bad the gas prices get,
I've never paid more
than 40 bucks a gallon.
I don't give a fuck if
somebody runs into it. Um,
I could park it wherever I want. Nobody's
going to take it. It's fucking perfect.
Right. I bought my wife a nice
car. It's nice. I can't stand it.
I can't, you know, I feel like when
I'm driving that thing. Do you make,
do you guys ever see that
fucking hilarious Howard
Stern's movie, private parts?
Do you remember when he would show him
himself when he first became a DJ in lake?
When he went to put the
needle on the record and he,
he scratched and he fucked the
whole thing up. Remember that noise?
Who's making it was going to
woo.
That's
what I feel like when I drive that car.
Like I'll be going to the grocery
store and I'll just be thinking like,
God damn and I need to go in there, buy
some fucking hamburger. But you know,
if I don't see a bunch of wide open
spaces, I want parking in there.
Cause I know somebody's going to come
in and just park right next to it and
fucking oh fun that door right into
the side of it and it's gonna make me
fucking sick. You know, it's like
when you go to a movie, right?
Like right now's a great time to go see
star wars. Maybe in another fucking weak,
right? Nobody's going to be there.
You go see a matinee, right.
And it's during the work week. You're
a comedian, you got a Gig that night.
You say, fuck it, I'm going to go.
I'm going to go see a matinee showing
of star wars fucking six weeks after it
came out, right? You go in there,
there's nobody fucking there.
You get your feet up,
you having a great time.
It is fucking inevitable that someone's
going to walk in during the fucking
trailers.
They going to sit down and right behind
you and they're going to talk or munch
popcorn fucking loudly,
or they're going to be fucking dressed
like Chewbacca and is getting, getting,
getting hair in their mouth.
The other thing we'll be doing that the
entire fucking time, it's an at the same,
the same way that is inevitable.
If you park in a, in a, in
a parking lot, some con,
even if there's a bunch of fucking spaces
is going to pull in right next to you
and they can open the fucking
door right into it, you know,
and that's just regular people
forget about out of shape.
People who they got to like put stress
on the hinges of their doors to just make
it wide enough, you know? You know,
that's when you know you're fat.
When you get like one of those Formula
One fucking steering wheels that just
pops out so you can get you to gut out.
He keep lying to yourself,
I'll tell you.
And they don't make these for Broncos as
big as they used to. Yeah, they do. Yeah,
they do. They most
certainly fucking do. Um,
so anyway, speaking of cars too, and I
saw there's somebody up the street, man.
It's got to kill a fucking car.
It's one of those Volkswagen. Uh,
it's not the bug. It's not the Karmann
Ghias it's the fucking station wagon.
And they put some white walls on
it and some fucking fog lights.
They got the luggage rack
on it. It's fucking cool as
shit. I love station wagon.
I love a station wagon. Um, sorry,
I got a little fucking,
uh, who's that guy?
It's as big as a whale and
it's about to set sail.
Okay.
Hang on. Sorry. Sorry. I'm
singing all these fucking songs.
It's a little old place where you
could get together and do what,
what kind of depravity
goes on in the love shack.
Okay.
Did that song even makes sense.
They just went out to a shack
and they fucked, I mean,
maybe I'm taking it too literally. Uh,
what was I looking up? Oh yeah, the, uh,
the Volkswagen station wagon.
The Volkswagen will dissolve
Volkswagen station wagon,
a classic VW station wagon on,
let's see what this things called.
There it is.
Okay.
The fuck is it called? So I got
all the, uh, the pictures of it.
That's such a fucking cool car,
man. I love the front end on it.
And the guy also had it in a stick shift,
which I think is a,
a picture below a rear view of the
Volkswagen Beetle from 61 to 70, 67.
That's not what I wanted. One of
these days. One of these days,
I'm just going to look shit up.
Yeah.
You know,
before it starts.
And I'll have a nice news podcasts.
I'm imitating my,
my science teacher from uh,
yeah,
from high school. When he was talking
about some sort of biology thing. He said,
there's this rough and smooth, I
forget what it was. And he was like,
there's aura and snooze.
It used to make a joke out of it and
everybody would laugh and you'd never get
it wrong on the test,
you know?
Do you know why there's not more funny
teachers is because they all become
comedians cause it just like,
all right,
I'm basically doing stand up here and uh,
I'm not making any money,
so fuck these kids and their future
Volkswagen type three square back.
That's all it's called. Come on.
They had to give it a better name than
that. Oh, this is some fucking gearhead.
Thank God damn fucking bastards.
Can you just tell me the
name of the fucking car?
Where
did formation,
okay.
You think I could look it up
by the mid sixties it was clear
that Volkswagen's iconoclastic,
thinks small campaign on behalf of
the lowly beetle had succeeded in
transforming the third hike.
Okay.
Wait a minute. Wait, what
is this about Hitler?
I'm trying to read about the
fucking Karmann Ghias typed to,
maybe it is a Karmann Ghia. I, you
know what the fuck I'm talking about.
You know what? I'll just put
a picture of. How about that?
How I put a picture of that. Hey, did
anybody see bill check a football life?
It was a two pipe and I gotta
admit I was bored shitless.
Okay.
I,
I've never been more bored watching a
football life even when it was him and Tom
Brady's sitting in the office. I
was, it was fucking eggheads shit,
but it was just all monotone. Just
going. Yeah. Yeah. Lions have a,
uh, a good defense. So, uh, you know,
I'm to put together a game plan
and then Tom Brady be like smiling,
but just going like, yeah. I
thought maybe we could have the, uh,
the running back come out
of the backfield. He could
explain some things, uh,
the underneath of there a secondary,
oh yeah, Tom, I'm going to,
I'll look into that. Okay.
Ville and that'd be like a
scene. It was like fucking,
yeah.
Even when he got emotional, when he
went to giant stadium, I was just like,
this is a, you know, he didn't
get in volt motion. I'm like,
if you want to see the emotional why
you got to see the Dick for me or one.
But I was, I, I can't even watch
it. I feel like a bad patriots fan.
I can not get fucking through it.
Um,
maybe I will eventually.
So actually that was another
thing I did when I was here.
I was just binge watching shit.
I watched the whole first
season of top boy on Netflix.
It's only four episodes
a fucking good show.
Matt and I just started
the second one last night.
And uh,
I watched this documentary
on na's who I never got,
I never got it. When illmatic came
out, I was like, I don't like this.
I don't get it right. And now I went
back and listened to it. I was like, oh,
wait a minute. This is fucking
unbelievable. You got to admit,
okay, when you're younger, there's a lot,
sometimes there's albums that come out or,
or artists that come by and you just
don't see him cause you're like, Eh,
you know, he's an older
guy. Like, like David Bowie.
I never went to see that guy live. And
now doing the classic, now that he's dead,
let me take another listen to his
fucking music. And I, you know,
I had that fucking album,
like everybody has that album.
I had the Ziggy stardust one and a,
that's still an amazing fucking album.
Obviously that's been played to death,
but that was killer.
But I downloaded diamond dogs and it's
fucking on. It's unreal. And I was like,
I many times could I have seen this guy,
I could have seen him on
the let's dance toilet dance
shows that dad's little blue.
Um, I could have seen him on any
of those and I never did. You know,
Bob Newhart's playing out Friday night,
I'm not going to get a chance to see him.
His fucking show is sold out. It's like
way the fuck out in the desert. And,
uh, I got something nine
30 the next morning, so I
can't go fucking see the guy.
And, uh, so I'm trying to make a bucket
list of guys. I gotta go fucking see.
I hope they don't, none
of, nobody plays his farm.
Cause I'm going to see them because
not only I respect him as an artist,
but I also saw, I'm afraid they're
going to die, you know? Uh,
I don't want to jinx anybody,
but you know they are.
Or even you just want to see him
before they quit touring. Right?
Everyone. Fuck Tony Bennett. Stevie wonder
to Bob Newhart to Morton Downey jr right.
I'm joking. I already saw him and he's
dead. All right, let's plow ahead.
I think I got to do a read
for the week here. Um,
why don't I do the read and I'll be
singing the melody to when I need love
done.
Lots of play
playoff speeds.
Now that the polls,
seasons,
leaf,
I can't do the whole thing that to the
pros kickoffs a year the right way with a
fresh blade shave.
That's why me and millions of others
have joined the dollar shave club.com
revolution.
Dollar Shave Club knows that the key to
getting an amazing shape is simple. One,
use a fresh dollar shave club
blade to use their fucking dog day
commies.
Easy Shave.
That's it.
Those shake com delivers amazing razors
right to my door for a third of the
price of those greedy
mega razor corporations.
That means listeners who switched now
can afford the luxury of shaving with a
fresh blade anytime and save
hundreds this year. And uh,
when you combine the fresh
blade, any, once you do,
if you really want to feel like a rich
guy is get one of those barbershop chairs
and fucking lay back and it and have one
of your drunk friends shave your face
for you. Don't have him go
up. You'll get ingrown hairs.
And when you combine that fresh blade
with the doctor cabbies easy shape butter,
it just glides.
Okay?
It's like lube for your face. It's
unimaginably smooth. Uh, I'm telling you,
it's not the average shame shave foam.
It won't dry out your skin.
The all natural ingredients.
Leave your skin feeling soft,
smooth and moisturized after every shave.
Take it from me.
Use a fresh dollar shave club, bay blade
with doctor cabbies. Easy shave butter.
Uh, if you want to the most
gentle shave imaginable,
join the dollar shave
club.com/bird revolution today.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar
hi
dollar shave club.com/
[inaudible] all right, legal zoom.
Okay.
All right before another year pass is
take the time to get your life organized
with legal zone. This is what I've
been doing. Do you have a family?
Do you have any assets or property?
If any of those answers are yes,
you should have an estate plan.
Fuck you man. I already did this.
This is for other people. Uh, don't
worry if that sounds complicated.
Legal Zoom can help. Yes, they
can. Legal Zoom is a state plan.
Bundles eliminates the
guesswork. Yes, they do. This is,
this is a personal testimony.
You don't have to figure out on your
own whether a will or living trucks.
Trust works better. Best for you. Instead,
you work with an independent
attorney available in most states,
the walk you through your options and
recommend an estate plan that offers the
best solution to fit your needs.
You know, it's funny, you know,
if it's not available in your state,
they don't think your states cool.
There's not enough fucking
for them to make money on.
Like if you're out there
and wow. I'm like, wow,
I think I'm doing a Gig
that coming up in Cheyenne.
I got a gig coming up in Denver.
All right.
They'll walk you through your options
and recommend an estate plan that offers
the best solution to fit your needs.
Since legal zoom is not a law firm,
you can count on the F
on efficiency and value.
Everything is your
schedule and your terms.
Plus you'll know what your estate
plan bundles costs up front instead of
worrying about hourly rates.
That's how legal zoom has
become the leader in helping
small business owners and
families with great with their legal what?
With their legal needs.
You get legal help and
walk away feeling great.
There's the great that I was
looking at a fucking line below.
Get your life organized with an estate
plan bundle@legalzoom.com today.
Don't forget to enter, burn the
referral box at checkout that code.
That's Code burr@legalzoom.com.
All right, there we go. And
that's the end of the reads. Uh,
what did I just want to talk
about? Something in there
reminded me of something.
Oh yeah, the fucking, I'm going to be
going to Denver when I go to Denver.
They're either going to be super bowl
champions or they're going to be depressed
that they lost,
but they're probably still going to
give me shit that they beat my patriots.
But I've got to tell you this man,
this is pretty cool.
Do you know Denver is the only team,
the New England patriots
have a losing record too.
And I know a lot of you guys log ah,
fuck or Denver.
And I'm actually thinking like,
I can't believe that's true because I
watched the Patriots before Tom Brady.
All right.
And I think there was very few people
that we had a winning record against and
the fact that,
uh,
who's kidding who bill Bella check came
in with drew Bledsoe and that really
started turning shit around. And, um,
just the way that they've won over the,
since like 2000 or 2001 I
really like the last 20 years,
the way they've won,
they were, let's see, 20,
35,
they were 35 years or 30,
33 years in or 32 years in when drew
Bledsoe took over and drew Bledsoe took
over 24 years ago. So, you know,
that's what it took.
It took two and a half decades to undo
fucking three decades of fucking up.
And, um, I think that's
amazing. Now you're probably
going, well, why, why the fuck?
What are the Broncos doing?
You always got to play in that altitude.
It was always snowing.
And then they had Craig Morton and
the orange crushed defense in the 70s.
And, uh, I think before that they had
that Floyd little great running back,
rainy granite shack, um, haven Moses,
Rick UPC church there.
They always had some fucking guys.
And then they got John Elway in
[inaudible] 83 and that fucked after Craig
Morton. They went, you know,
a few years and then 83 Elway came
in and that fucked us from 83 to 98.
So even when we had drew Bledsoe
for the first fucking Ah, six,
seven years, it was against, uh,
John Elway who's like top three all
time, I think, you know what I mean? Um,
I'd actually put him ahead
of, uh, Peyton Manning, um,
personally, personally speaking. Uh,
so I'm actually excited that there's
32 fucking teams were one of them.
So of the 31 other teams, 30 of them,
we had a winning record against.
Can anybody else make that claim? I
don't think they can. All right, sorry.
So anybody watched 60 minutes
this past week? They did a,
they did this feature feature on mountain
lions and our California is the only
state that has mountain
lions just walking around.
I, I'm going to fuck
this up in a, in a park,
I guess maybe the size of like
Griffith Park or Runyon Canyon or,
or whatever those ones are out in,
uh,
out in the valley. I guess they have
these fucking things. And, um, so anyways,
I was watching it because a few of the
places that was where I hike with my dog
and this thing has intermittently this,
this group of fucking mountain
lions has been around there.
But fortunately they try
to avoid you I guess, um,
at least during the day if then I fucking
hungry. But they showed this fucking,
uh, these people, this
mountain lion, right. Okay.
They were having some work done.
So they had somebody going underneath
the house into the crawlspace of their
house and they will write
up against this park.
And the guy went down there
and he immediately came
back up and he was fucking
like white as a ghost and they
were like a dawn day ace, you know,
fucking white people trying to
speak Spanish, right? Oh eight. Um,
is it French? I don't know. Um,
and the guy comes out of the fucking hole
and was like, yeah, man, I fucking, uh,
is a mount line down there. I just
came faced and then I get outta here.
He is shy, I guess that, and
they will, he's like, yeah, it's
fucking down there. And, and so anyways,
they interview this fucking La couple and
they had the quintessential fucking la
couple, you know what I mean? He looks
like the leading man of a B movie,
right? She's got like bleach blonde
hair. She's wearing fuck me pumps.
She's on 60 minutes where it fucked
me pumps. It's fucking hilarious.
Walking around, done up
to the nines. And um,
I actually, uh, it was pretty cool. I was
trying to figure out where the house was.
I Google mapped it and I
think I was able to find it,
but I'm a fuck this state is so
fucking insane with the droughts,
the fires, the rattlesnakes,
the coyotes, the mountain lions,
you know, and everybody's in this place is
so phony and so plastic. Well, you know,
it can get, uh, that can all go
pretty damn quick with the wildlife.
It's sort of like a fucking
Australia light, like super light.
You know what I mean?
As I was throwing that out there,
I just heard everybody down there.
I'll flow gimme a fucking brain of
flipping out about how dangerous their
fucking, yeah. You know,
how dangerous Australia is.
Let me tell you something right now.
There's no fucking snakes. It's Sydney,
Australia.
All right?
There's all that shit's in the
middle of their fucking country.
Every week there's some at the zoo,
right?
Every once in a while you'll see somebody,
you know,
goes to pick up a snake thinking
it's a garden snake. He goes,
fuck it.
Bit that goes jogging in it,
racist through his veins and he fucking
dies. Yes, that does happen. But you know,
people don't, you know what? Let's, let's
actually, let's look up some stats here.
Let's go to the stats here.
Cause I don't think you're going to
hear enough stats between now and the
Superbowl,
you know,
is the sell the game layups
start new talent Cam Newton,
whether it's whole careers ahead of them
coming up against the Lally last when
plate and Laderick who went to
Germany had God knows what happened,
but he's not on the Patriot.
So ESPN is not gonna cover it.
Um, I'm not a, I don't even think
he did anything, but you know,
put the accusation was out there. I
mean, it came from Al Jazeera. I mean,
who knows more about NFL football then?
Al Jazeera.
Al Jazeera. All right. What was, what
the fuck was I looking up? Alright.
Snake bite deaths.
Okay,
thank you. Australia comes right
up. This is all touristy shit. Like,
am I going to die if I go down there?
Snakebite dead.
2015 list of fatal snake
bites in Australia.
Got To love the Internet.
I'm not saying the information's right,
but they always have an answer.
All right. Snakebite del East,
eastern Brown snake.
It's responsible for about 60% of deaths
caused by snakebite and Australia.
All right, here's the
numbers, the 2000 tents.
All right? Uh, in 2015, there was one,
one brown snake or Thai pad,
okay.
Species is unconfirmed.
You know why?
Because the snake left didn't
hang out like Yo, I did that shit.
Like the little sound as a
snake. He get it. I'm sorry. Um,
in 2014,
there was two a right?
That's big, bad, dangerous. Fucking
Australia. Let's check out the US.
Yeah.
When I'm fuck love United States
list of fatal snake bites in the
u s all we got to do is be one.
One ties it and it goes in over.
And the 2010
we crushed. One, two, three,
four go fuck yourself.
Australia, Paula Herald.
How forest?
39 year old female, uh,
Green Mojave rattlesnake,
Russell Lee Davis.
39.
Jesus 39 was an unlucky
or timber rattlesnake.
Okay.
You want to do the story?
Dave was sitting around the fire at his
family's camp when he was bitten by a
rattlesnake. Jesus Christ in the balls
right in front of his whole family.
He was taken to the hospital and from
there air lifted to the Pittsburgh area
hospital.
While en route,
the helicoptered Davis
suffered a cardiac arrest. Dot.
Jesus.
Grant Thompson 18 male.
Yeah,
a Cobra.
Who the fuck has a cobra?
Okay.
He got hit by a car boy.
Thompson was found unresponsible
in his car in North Austin.
Lowe's in North Austin at a Lowe's store
parking lot. How the fuck do you get by?
Uh, uh, monocled Cobra. Oh,
it's got the one fucking glass on it too.
With little I grass because it's like it
was evil like it's a James Bond villain.
Okay.
All right.
It's a cobra species,
which is widespread across the
south and Southeast Asia. Oh, Jesus.
Somebody fucking ordered one.
Uh,
Monaco Colebra that he was known to own,
was missing and was
later found dead nearby.
Haven't been run over by a car.
Okay,
wait a minute. I, I'm sorry. We got,
we got to get to the bottom
of this fucking story.
So this fucking kid
ordered a Goddamn Cobra.
Wait a minute.
Do one of these people going to
fucking low? Let me, let me, let's,
let's not get crazy here. Let's, let's
find out what happened to this kid.
Jesus Christ.
Greg Thompson,
grant t h o m
Thompson Cobra.
All right. Greg Thompson committed
suicide by allowing a Cobra.
This is the most, this can't
be true. Suicide by snakebite.
Question mark is this click bay.
Okay.
I was going to say this kid looks just
like Lance Bass and it was actually click
bait on the side says Lance Bass shows
us the most expensive item from his
wedding registry.
Okay.
Isn't that a little disrespectful
to have next to this kid. All right,
so the kids sitting here, what?
The parrot from one of his,
uh,
when the was Beretta parrots.
Okay.
Police Texas teens
death after he leaves a
cryptic message on Facebook,
the DEX death of a Texas teen who was
killed after being bitten by a Cobra last
Tuesday is being
investigated as a suicide.
Austin police confirm to people.
Is this people magazine? Yeah.
They're in deer into what people
are doing. Grant Thompson was found
unresponsible inside his car and a Lowe's
parking lot last week with puncture
wounds to his wrist and
his snake cage beside him.
Kwtx reports he was discovered surrounded
by a large, by a number of animals,
including a non venomous snake,
six tarantulas in a frog.
But as pet cobra was missing,
this was in his fucking car.
Thompson was rushed to a blah,
blah, blah, or he later died. Yeah,
I don't think in Austin they're going to
have shit for a cobra unless they got a
zoo nearby.
Right.
It was located above about police believe
that Thompson committed suicide by
allowing the venomous snake to bite him.
Surely before he was found Tuesday,
the team posted a cryptic message to
his Facebook page. Writing, I'm sorry.
Thompson's family owns a
pet shot in temple, Texas.
He'd worked for the
store most of his life.
He could handle tarantulas
like they were kittens.
He loved animals and love spreading
awareness about animals in the community.
Knob Saatchi was performed Thursday,
but authorities are waiting for the toxin.
What the fuck Jesus do.
That is hardcore.
Okay.
Do you, have you heard those things? That
there is nothing like the
hiss of a fucking reptile
and that fucking rep Chilean
look like. What other look are
they going to have in that face?
How is Lance Bass reverse aging?
Jesus Christ
fucking teeth.
Or like does he even eat anything?
Okay.
His teeth are like brand new, like
out of the box. Um, all right,
I think it's time to wrap this
up. Wrap it up. I'll take it.
Um,
okay.
Wait a minute.
What the fuck am I here?
Where's the rest of this shit? Ah,
Jesus Christ. Bill, what are you doing?
All right. That's not it.
Is this it? That's not it.
That's the shit about my wealth.
I don't know what this is and I don't know
where my memory, just everything went.
I give up. Oh, fuck it. Anyway,
so that's the end of the podcast.
Jesus Christ, Mike and Dialysis
to anybody knew that kid. Holy,
you know what are the odds for, there's
no way he was covered for that. Huh?
And you're fucking insurance.
Accidental death accidentally getting
bit by a Cobra and the wrist and the
parking lot of a Lowe's in Austin,
Texas.
All right. Anyways, that's a podcast.
I hope you guys have a great weekend
and a stay away from the snakes.
So you know what Australia.
All right. That was deliberate.
So we can't count that one. So we, we, uh,
we had three times as
many deaths as you did.
So why don't you tone down how fucking
nuts you status or your country,
whatever it is, right island, you know,
it's not that fucking dangerous.
You know what it is?
We buy into it because of the fucking,
uh, the shrimp on the Barbie guy,
Paul Hogan and then the crocodile hunter.
You know,
and when you really think about it,
how did the crocodile hunter die?
Was it one of those snakes that he was
constantly fucking with? Was it any other,
the land animals that he was
constantly fucking with? It was not,
he fucked with the sting ray. And he
forgot that those things always are armed.
They always have a shank.
He got stuck right,
like a fucking prisoner.
Um, as enough time gone by,
then she can actually address
the foolishness of that death.
Like, let me fucking go. Just jump
on the back of a sting ray. You know,
and I'm not talking about the corvette
people I'm talking about the actual
fucking fish were boasting. Ray,
you gotta watch that little stab.
You in the heart.
You swim to the surface and pulleys loud.
I'm sorry. Anyways, this is the
podcast for this Thursday afternoon.
Have a wonderful weekend. You cuts, uh,
my condolences to that kid in the Lowe's
parking lot into the crocodile hunter.
Even a Paul Hogan. You know,
I don't know what he's up to.
I hope he's got a new hat though,
you know. Nice new fresh hat. Um,
and with that,
here's a little bit of music from
Andrew [inaudible] and a little bit of
throwback podcasts
from a,
from a year ago.
I'm not crazy.
I know Brown with assessment and Brett,
what'd Y'all bread?
And that was,
uh,
and that is, it built a bit of
a dilemma here for you. I'm an
18 year old male who's about to graduate
from high school. Congratulations.
Um, over the past few years I've been
told I'm a really good dancer. Uh,
not ballet or artsy stuff,
but just good dance floor dancing.
Oh my God. I'm going to take over the
dance floor. Hey Angie, watch me. Yeah.
John Travolta. This is great.
Do you go out to the, uh,
Staten Island Bridge and do headstands
with your, with your buddy Bobby?
You know,
if he didn't have an Afro,
he never would have fell off that
bridge if you had it high and tight.
Like all these Armenians out here, all,
every Armenian looks like they know, uh,
they, they know. Um, m m m a moose,
last time you saw an Armenian dude in
his twenties or thirties and he did not
look like he could put you in an arm bar
within two seconds if you want it to,
if I would,
if I was a Dana white and I was running
the UFC at one point at this point,
what they're up to like what?
Like UFC 2006,
you know, they like run it, they've run
out of adjectives this time. It's really,
really personal. Right. Not Saying
I'm not a fan, I'm a huge fucking fan.
I'm just saying, you
know, the way they, they,
they have those things like every other
week there's only so many, like, you know,
redemption. Yeah. I mean,
you've running out of words. Um,
I'm such a fucking idiot. This is what
I would do if I was dating a white.
At some point I would have, you
know, you know what I would,
this is what I would branch off.
And when they had those
tough man competitions and
they would have just people
coming in,
throwing haymakers,
which is some of the best boxing ever
is when you watch people who just aren't
trained whatsoever and they just start,
you know,
cause somebody is going to connect.
Right.
I think that they should have one week
they should have the Armenians versus the
Russians. Tough man competition.
Because I really think that that needs,
it needs to be decided who is
the tougher of the two, uh,
cause up more now when it
comes to white people. That's,
that's who I got my money
on. All right. That, those,
those are the crips and the bloods of
white people is the army and the Russians,
all of them, they just have that vibe.
Does something you just like. Yeah,
I'm not fucking with that guy. Just
really, I'm really not doing it anyways.
Uh, not a ballet or artsy stuff. Uh,
but just ballroom dance in a
fucking dead soon over here. Uh,
I kind of think of think dancing is
gay from an outside point of view.
Um, I, I, it isn't, it really isn't.
That's just how white people look at it.
It's considered gay cause it involves
like letting yourself go and actually
admitting that you have emotions as a
man, as a white male. Yeah, it's, yeah,
it is. It's considered gay. Um,
as his crying as is showing any sort of
emotion as is not dying for no good God
damn. Before you're 56, um
Oh, not dying. I should say.
If you live to be 60, I believe amongst
white men, that's also considered gay.
Cause that means at some point you
cried something out of your chest and he
didn't have a heart attack.
Um, anyways, he says,
I think dancing is gay from
an outside point of view,
but I'll be the first one to admit that
I'm actually a pretty good dancer if I
didn't think so, I wouldn't be out
there doing it. Yeah. But Dude,
you gotta be getting some, I'll, I'll
fucking women love a guy who can dance.
Dude, if you can dance and you're wearing
like a silk scarf, it's fucking over.
It's going to be rain in policy.
As far as my outside view,
my freckled view from over in the bar
trying to stand out from underneath those
hot lights so I don't get burned.
Uh,
do you know red heads where the
closest thing to vampires, you know,
we have,
we have none of the powers of vampires,
but the sun affects us the same.
A friend of mine who was a female dead
keeps telling me I could make money doing
it on commercials or music videos.
Parentheses close on.
Or You could go to fucking Broadway.
It'd be like one of the five straight
men who dances on Broadway and just tag
every fucking lonely chick out
there who's all stretched out.
Just make sure you keep those shoes on.
Dancers' feet are always fucked up. Uh,
here's where it gets complicated.
I plan on becoming a policeman.
Okay?
Oh Dude, this is, this is a no
brainer. You need to dance it.
Bachelorette parties dressed
as a cop. All you need, dude,
is that a fig uniform on a boombox and
you're on your way to making money. Dude,
you should fucking do that in a second.
And then you write a book about it.
I was a gyrate and cop for Bachelorette
parties and you write a tell all book
about how many fucking broads who bought
ready got married? You get married,
sucked your Dick. You really
need help on this one. I mean,
I'm going to read the rest of it,
but I think I've already
come with a solution anyways.
How is anyone supposed to take
me seriously on the force?
If there's a video going with me,
pop and locking next, a little Wayne.
At the same time, I'll, dude, you
should fucking pull people over.
Okay.
You should pull people
over and fucking moon.
Walk up to their car
and just freak them out.
Even if they were reaching for a gun,
they'd be laughing too hard and they,
they wouldn't shoot you. Then you
can rest them and then you move up.
Next thing you know, you're a
commissioner. Alright. Nothing anyways,
at the same time, I'm getting laid a
lot because of it. Of course you are.
I'm a seven on a scale of 10. I like
this guy. He's honest and um, uh,
and like having a jump shot.
It's put me up to an eight
five I'm banging tense.
I've always wanted to be
a cop at the parks here.
Seen better if I was able to make
money doing it in the dancing thing,
I wouldn't just be getting hammers
for letting gross moms off on speeding
tickets. I could be bagging J
lo. She's into dancers. Right?
Thanks. Yeah, Dude. Apps
a Fuckin lutely dude.
You're basically saying,
what should I do here?
Should I bang j Lo's beat down at the
club and make all this fucking money or
should I take a job where I'm going
to get shot at and not be appreciated?
You know, I'll tell you every cop
out there with dance if they could,
as opposed to being a cop, I don't care
if they had like seven generations in.
Dude, this is what I think of as
far as like dancing. I think if I,
if I
like compare it to being a comedian,
oh the open mics would be getting a
piece of cardboard and being on a subway
platform,
making money that way.
And then when you move up to hosting a
show that would be addressed as a cop and
you're fucking dance at Bachelorette
parties. That's what you do on the side.
That's like you fucking day
job that bullshit. And then
during the day, I, yeah,
I would try out for those.
Fuck I don't,
do they make music videos
anymore or fucking uh,
I dunno. I, I believe it or not, I don't
know how to climb the ladder as a dancer.
But dude,
apps a Fuckin lutely if you
can make money doing that shit.
And then what the great thing is, is once
you get to a certain level to, to, uh,
make more money, you know, once
you got some credibility, you can,
you always have the, the fall back
where you can teach a class they get,
you can be like,
I danced for nine years and Chitty
Chitty Bang Bang and fucking banged every
fucking brought on there.
And then if you'd like to not have,
fuck the women in your cast
while still not losing your job,
come on down to Frankie's fucking
day in studio, whatever. Just,
you'll figure it out as you go in
there and um, yeah, absolutely.
Absolute fucking Luli I would
definitely do it. You want to do what?
He would've taken the
time, um, to write in.
So your big fears should be whatever.
But everybody's big fear.
It's like what if I fucking go after this
dream and I'm 30 and I'm sleeping on a
Fuckin futon and it hasn't happened yet.
Well I've got to tell you something sir.
I'd been there.
I was there at fucking 34.
I was still sleeping on a futon and a
fucking studio apartment that they called
a one bedroom cause they slammed a fucking
wall in there and put a door on it.
And then one day I was trying to bang
the girl upstairs who had the fucking
apartment right above me and
it was the exact same unit
and hers was a studio,
but she had been there longer so
they never slammed a wall in there.
And I realized, hey wait a minute,
I'm getting fucked. You know,
I should go down there and try to
get some money taken off of this.
I should go down to the,
uh, they're fucking me over
rental board. But I didn't,
I said fucking just keep writing
jokes, right? So whatever,
oh, you got to do, you just got
to commit to this shit and uh,
and then realize that,
you know,
sleeping on food tone when you're
30 is not the worst thing. It isn't.
You don't see them. You know, it's
worse than sleeping on futons if 30,
sleeping in a king bed next to a fuck
a woman you're not really in love with,
but for some reason and uh,
you've got a couple of kids and you've
got a job that you fucking hate, okay?
You'll be laying there fantasizing about
fucking sleeping on a, on a, on a, uh,
on a futon there.
There's no risk when you go after a dream,
it's all fucking reward.
It's all going to lead to something good.
It always does.
There's a tremendous amount of
risk to playing it safe and uh,
that leads to unbelievable
levels of the retina,
which is something else I've also
experienced, cause I'm an old one.
Ah,
shit shy.
This is entitled the freight to
break up with girlfriend gonna read slow.
So this takes up as much time
as possible. Hey Bill. Um,
I'd like to get your advice on something.
I've been dating my girlfriend for
almost a year now and I've been thinking
about breaking up with her. Well, it's
time to break up with their sir. Alright.
In Dayton and for a year,
you know,
you have to still even thinking
about breaking it. It's time. Okay.
He says we get along fine and we rarely
argue. I was just thinking of a great,
a great way to break up with someone
they should invent like a breakup suit,
right?
Just something where you just can not
get injured and you just put the thing on
with the fucking helmet.
You don't wear the helmet,
you just put the ones the zip up on and
which totally protects everything. Right?
And then you get in the passenger
seat and you let her drive. Oh,
why are you gonna let me drive?
Why did you just drive tonight?
But you always liked to drive
honey, you just drive. Okay,
why are you wearing that suit? It's all
gonna make sense in about five miles,
right?
You get out on the fucking highway.
He just started talking to her and out
of no way, he just put the helmet on,
you know, when she says, what are
you doing? And just say, listen,
I don't want to go out with you anymore.
And then she goes, what? And you go, hey,
watch this. He just opened the door
and you roll out of the fucking car.
That's it. You're out. You know,
type up a fake police report.
You told me you died and
then she feels bad for you.
You don't have to deal with any
sort of repercussions. Um, anyways,
he says we get along
fine and we rarely argue,
but I'm starting to realize I don't really
want to be with her for the long haul.
And we started dating,
oh, this fucking thing.
These iPad suck by the way. All
right. You know what an Ipad is?
It's it's fucking laptop for pussies.
What's a matter? You laptop is too heavy.
You fucking douchebag this thing doesn't
have a keyboard. It's got nothing.
You think that they don't know how to
make this thing into a fucking laptop
already?
Of course they do.
This is this Steve jobs way of doing
things rather than just giving you the
whole fucking thing. He's going to
give you tea an inch increments,
like a God damn drug dealer.
You know I,
that's why I haven't bought one of
these yet. This is knee is by the way,
bar of this fucking thing and I am
not enjoying it. As you can tell us,
I'm throwing a temper tan from here.
You know what?
I'm going to buy a fucking IPAD.
I'm going to buy it when it is a laptop,
when it is a little light laptop.
Until then I'm not,
I'm not having this fucking this. This is
like a, this is like when you, you know,
you go, I, you know,
I really want to get the new Camaro
and then you get the one with the v six
engine rather than getting the
full out one with the stick shift,
which is a laptop, right.
He's too heavy, you know,
fucking deuce. Do Shoulders
at the gym next time you do
that. Okay. Maybe do that.
Maybe to do some stuff to
build up your risks. Oh God,
they'll can you get through the question?
All right. I, well, um, he says, uh,
when we first started dating,
I loved hanging out with her,
but I'm just not into anymore. Does
that make me an asshole? No, it doesn't.
Why would your own true feelings
make you an Asshole, sir?
How awful were your parents? Um, he
says, I'm 23 years old with the somewhat,
why am I, you know, something to
really being a cunt this week,
guys asking for my advice. Let's, let's
try to bring the younger down. Bill,
you're frustrated.
It's fucking hot in here.
You can't open the window
because you say cunt too much.
This building's a co op and
they'll kick you up. Okay.
That's what's going on here. It has
nothing to do with this person. Okay.
Why don't you just try to be a nice
guy so I should've done off the mic.
Like I'm scolding myself.
Just try to be a nice guy.
Let's not take out your bad
day on everyone else. Okay?
You're embarrassing me.
All right.
I'm 23 years old,
but somewhat of a decent job and really
just want to go back to being single for
a while. Exactly. Dude,
you're 23 years old. Dude,
you're fucking movie star at that age.
I don't care what you're
doing for a living. Should
definitely be single. I said,
the problem is she's got a lot less,
she's got a lot of stress in her
life right now. Not your problem.
She's finishing nursing school and
trying to find a job. All right,
well tell her to put on the outfit
Banger one more time and hey, watch this.
You bail out of the car.
That's mean. Um, anyways.
He says, oh, and she has a history
of depression over the past year.
I feel like she's becoming
emotionally dependent on me.
Like I'm keeping her going or something.
Well,
Jesus Christ and what do you want to
get rid of her? You don't want this,
you know,
you want something that someone
that's going to be fun to be around.
You don't want her, you know,
it's sunny out and she's like,
it's raining out that fucking
head under the pillow.
Okay,
well these days,
you know he stayed with that long
enough one these days you just going to,
it's going to smother it
with that pillow is anyways.
So how do I go about breaking up with
her while causing the least amount of
damage?
Uh,
he said also she always leaves some
of her shit and my apartment. Yes.
Cause she's, she wants to
fucking, she's clinging onto you.
It says close blanket.
Other random shit.
I tried to get her to take a shit home
with her, but how do I avoid after, uh,
the after break up coming over
to get my stuff. I hate that.
Anyway. Go Fuck Yourself. All right,
look,
there's no way. There's no easy way
to break up with somebody. All right.
There's just easier ways.
Uh,
the sooner the better.
MMM.
Oh Diane, I'll do it. This is like, this
is like dismantling a bomb. So you know,
what you would like to do is
say, Hey, can you come by today?
I want to talk to you about something.
Right. And she always share.
I'll be right over and then
immediately just take out a box,
put all of her shit in it, tape it up
and then she rings the bell. Bing Bong.
You opened the door, he got, yeah,
don't want to date you anymore.
And he just handed the
box and close the door.
Right to this money to
be made in this man.
Does anybody have a professional breakup
service at such a pussy thing to do?
But that would be phenomenal.
You know it, you feel,
you make a person feel
like they got fired.
You're like when a corporation fires
you and just to security people show up,
you know, confiscate your computer and
then escort you out of the building.
When that be great do,
that's what you should do.
Just hire to your friends to
dress up like security guards.
Tell her you want to break up,
you know,
and then they have all their shit
in the box. Then they escort,
escort or right out of your apartment
building. Like she got fired.
They come off as professional
rather than like personal. Um,
how do you go about breaking up with
it? You know what I would do? Uh,
I wouldn't put all his shit in the box
because that's going to come off cold,
you know, and you don't want to hurt her
failings like that. So I would just, uh,
uh, fuck it. I don't know. I don't know
how to do it. Why did I drink last night?
And then I got up and did opie and
Anthony, what the fuck is wrong with me?
I knew I had a podcast to
do. He embarrassing. Um,
okay.
I don't fucking know. Have a
come over and just say, listen,
I'm not happy. Oh, that's a great
one. That's a classic. You know,
like if you were a singer songwriter
the second he said that the whole crowd
would start applauding,
recognizing the big hit,
you know,
of all the girls I do before, you know,
they all start fucking clapping. You know,
if they just came out, you just had
classic breakup monologues, listen, um,
I'm just not happy.
Everyone just at smattering of applause.
You wait for it to die down.
Let the orchestra come around again.
She jumped back in on
the one, um, matched.
Tell you're not happy. I'm
not happy anymore. And Dude,
let me tell you something.
Her being depressed is not your
fucking problem. All right?
Her being depressed is the fucking
problem. How can you do this to me?
What do you mean? How can I do this
too? You don't want to be words.
If I fucking stayed with you and I didn't
love you, I don't love you anymore.
I don't love you.
Depressed whore.
Okay.
I just called you a whore as a
generic term. You know, I don't, I'm,
I'm not happy. I want to, okay. I just
feel like want to be single right now.
I just don't feel like I'm going
to be with you in long haul. Uh,
would just be wasting each other's time.
My time is important and so is yours.
All right? I don't want to go
anymore, but I'll tell you what.
If you go to stamps.com, they'll give
you $55 free stamps to the scale.
That's what you do. Just tag every mean
thing you say with all the advertising.
You know, if you go to amazon.com
so bill burrs website, you know,
click on the Little Amazon banner,
whatever you buy, you know,
portion of that money
goes back to bill burn.
Then the percentage of that goes
to the wounded warriors project.
So I know I'm breaking up with
you right now, but you could,
we could also support the troops,
right,
sir? Look, there's no
fucking easy way to do this.
And you're going to be sitting there.
How many more holidays?
How many more birthdays? How many more
Christmases, which is a holiday? Sorry,
he always need three examples. Do you
want to go through with this person?
How many more times do you want to go
out and rent bikes? Go to a picnic,
sit there on a sunny day. Is she sitting
there with that cloud over fucking head?
You know,
don't you know,
don't do that to yourself.
He might have fucking people who have
just wonderful human beings and they just
end up with assholes. I
swear to God, assholes.
They look for wonderful
human beings because other
assholes are not going to put
up with them, you know? So you need to be
an ass hole here and you know the, the,
the how society looks as an, as an
asshole. Like you're being selfish,
not being selfish, all
right? Choose yourself,
choose your own fucking life
dumper and get on with your life.
You don't,
this is what you do.
You get yourself by six of fucking
Pale Ale or whatever beer you like.
You stick a couple of glasses
in the fucking freezer.
All right?
Like anticipation of this championship
that you know you're gonna win. You know,
like they did in the red sox dugout when
they had the champagne on ice in game
six in 1986 before they had
to quickly wheel it out, okay?
Except you're not going to let
this one go through your legs.
Are you kicking this one right in the
cunt and you taking home the fucking
championship and when it's over all
you got to be just thinking about those
frosty fucking bruise in the fridge.
Just think about that.
Just look at the clock when she walks in.
All right.
Let's say she comes in at 10 past two.
Just say to yourself,
worst scenario by three fucking 30,
I'm going to be sitting down in
this fucking couch. All right,
with my goddamn phone off,
drinking a couple of five or six
of these things and then that's it.
All right.
And then don't fucking
have a post breakup sex.
Don't do that. Cause then she'll
think that you're back together again.
Fuck all of that. All right. In
your mind, just think gotta come by.
Yeah, my staff. Okay. When
do you want to come by?
This is coming off really cold.
She's got to do all of that and just
try to keep dragging you back into the
fucking thing.
Um,
I dunno if this is a punk thing to do,
but after you break up with her,
just don't answer the phone when she calls
and then she'll find, just say, listen,
I got a, I got to come by. Get
my stuff. Can you text her back?
I fucking just be a man. What is
she going to do? Body Slam you.
She's just going to make you feel bad.
All right?
Ooh
is a good little blue you would do.
No, it's cause you're a mopey.
You're sucking the life out of me.
You know when,
when you get that sad look on your face,
you look like a muppet there.
I said it all right.
There's your shit over
there in the corner.
I got a couple of cool ones in the fridge,
so why don't you do me a favor.
All right, get over there. Bend
Down, lift with your knees,
get your shit and get the fuck
out of here. When he say that,
touch your prince charming is
out there somewhere. You know,
and it ain't here. I'm not
riding that horse anymore. Okay?
I just shot it in the back
of the head. It's over. Okay,
so why don't you trudge on out of here?
They're fucking Cinderella.
Go look at a mirror. I go climb up in
a tower and fucking drop your hair out.
Whatever the fuck he supposed
to do. Kiss a frog. All right,
I got drinking to do [inaudible] beat it.
Something like that. Like I said, all
that bullshit. I said 10 past two,
it's over by three 30. By
three 30, you're boozing.
All right.
I don't know.
Now they're fucking brutal breaking up
often this at this fight.
But other than that
[inaudible] [inaudible]
I
dunno,
I've been all over the map politically,
but it's why like, you know,
certain ways of looking at shit,
like when people talk about guns,
like let's just make them won't,
let's just make them illegal and
that nobody will have, um, you know,
like that's sort of like
thought process is you're,
you're acting as though the world is a
utopia and that there's not morons and
that there's not, uh, people who say,
I don't give a fuck what the rules are.
You're totally not even
taking into consideration
sociopath's which is why that
new fucking thing that Obama signed,
that whole defense package where now they
can just arrest people without a trial.
Jay put you in jail forever with,
without a trial because they just think
you're a fucking terrorist. Geeky kid.
Give people that level of power.
I'm a fucking moron.
And I know you can't do that.
Historically,
no one has ever handled
that level of power. Well,
anybody here want to go live in China?
Oh,
we out there practicing and nunchucks
wearing your wooden slippers and all of a
sudden a van pulls up and you
disappear and that's it forever.
You want to live there?
Of course you don't.
You want to live here where they can't
fucking do it. Well, they can do it now.
You know? They just put in a fucking
order for a bunch of black fans.
That's what I heard. Gordon Dot. Holy
shit.com that's what's going down.
I don't understand why stuff at that
level that affects citizens to that level.
Why we don't get to vote on it.
Do you think it's because
we'd say, Hey, you know what?
Fuck that you want to stand like
that is just a jump off point.
Do you think like that's just
how it's going to smell as well.
You're not a terrorist dinner.
You ain't got to fuck bro.
You think it's just
going to stop with that.
That's not how you take away freedom.
You don't just fucking do it all in
one fail swoop. It's incremental.
It's just like when you're dating some
fucking woman and you're not paying
attention and she just gradually, every
day it takes another foot of real estate.
Next thing you know you're
in goal line day going,
how the fuck did I end up in
this situation? He started
at the 50 little push,
a little poll, right? Everything
was fine. [inaudible] casino,
you're up against the Golan.
You think that they're just going to keep
it with the terrorist thing, you know?
You know they'll wait for a whole nother
generation of babies to be born and
they always grew up with government having
that level of power and then they add
something else to it. Then they
had something else. Then that's it.
You can't have,
okay,
if tiger woods can't handle the
level of free pussy on a golf tour,
how the fuck is our government going
to handle a new defense package?
Which basically gave them a mute button.
Okay.
When you love the Ha, how would you
handle that if you had that power, do you,
how long before you just
started abusing that?
If you could just hit mute on anybody
who ever disagreed with you and it just,
and you could have them whisked away.
I mean that is just sociopath's wet dream.
That's what that is.
That is a fucking mute button,
Mr Style and don't you think that's it?
He hit mute. You're done. You're gone.
See Ya. I think, I think it's,
it's fucking insane and I'm,
the only thing that I get out of it is
that I feel like I was proven correct
that I don't think it
matters at that level.
Whether you vote Democrat or Republican
Obama, the first black president ever,
you would think this would be the most
liberal a politician in the history of
this country.
Okay.
Because of his background, you would
think that he signed off on that shit.
Okay.
All right. I'm telling you, I don't know
what happens when you become president,
but I think they let you peek just
enough behind the curtain and there was a
fucking agenda that we are
moving towards because it does.
I don't think it fucking matters.
I really don't,
which is why I always
vote for the Ralph Nader,
the fucking Ron Paul, all those guys that
all those fucking idiots go, oh, do Kush.
You did that. You've ruined
the election. Really? Did I?
Yeah.
I feel like those guys wouldn't
have signed shit like that.
I feel like their track record shows
that they would not sign shit like that.
I, I dunno. I have no,
I imagine I'm going to get a ton of
fucking emails I'm going with somebody was
yelling at me one time saying that
because I voted for Ralph Nader in 2000.
That's why George W.
Bush won.
And they was just going on and on and
on about it. And I was like, dude,
I live in New York. Al
Gore won my state. Okay.
Do you understand that? So
your whole fucking theory
right now is out the window.
I voted for Ralph Nader in New
York and Al Gore still one mistake.
So go fuck yourself. What
I'm trying to do, uh,
Mister fucking red and blue tie here,
I'm trying to fucking encourage
more people like that to vote.
So mission accomplished. That's what I'm
trying to fuck and have to vote to run,
you know
uncorruptible how far can you get if
you're uncorruptible I would say that you
can get to the, uh, what,
whatever level politics is when you
decide whether or not they should put a
gazebo in the center of town.
I think beat, once you get
beyond that, you got it.
You got to be a little dirty.
Right.
I love talking about this shit
cause it just stirs people up,
you know?
Oh you know,
maybe you should all read a little more
before the next time you fucking own.
Really. What are you reading? What
are you reading? What they give you?
Is that what you're reading?
Fuck head.
Why you acting like you have clearance
to the bottom floors of the fucking
Pentagon, you're guessing?
Just like I am. All right,
Mr informed I read the pamphlet.
I don't buy a fucking word of it.
You know,
you can use coca cola to take rust
off of metal. You can use it for that.
You know,
you understand that yet they're
still able to sell it to us.
Like it's refreshing.
I Dunno what that point meant either
[inaudible] [inaudible]
no,
Jackie Ladies and gentlemen.