Hey, what's going on as bill burn?
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast and, Huh?
Just checking. Just checking in
on you. Just checking in on you.
What's going on now? It's
been a sad week, you know,
for standup comedians.
It's been a sad week.
Joe De Rosa has decided to
retire. No, I'm kidding. Um,
why didn't I pick, why did I pick John
Rosell? Because his birthday's coming up.
Everybody wished Joe to Rosa. Happy
Birthday on Sunday. All right.
On Twitter
you call them twinkle toes.
You call them whatever you want, but just,
just, just wishing me happy birthday.
Anyways. Um, what am I
talking about here? Uh,
it's a sad day in stand up comedy because,
uh,
that fucking Scaramucci guy got fired.
I know it happened a few days ago,
but I don't pay attention and I'll
do a podcast every couple of days.
What do you want from me? Well Bill,
you know, we'd like it though, you know,
you know some Douche sent me something
on Twitter. He goes, hey bill,
please read the news before you
do your podcast on North Korea.
Shot off a nuclear warhead
or a missile or something,
and I'm tilting my head to
go, there wasn't no killer
was some sort of ballistic,
whatever the fuck that means. It's a
giant mad that could make it to Chicago.
That's the way I heard it.
And I looked it up and it wasn't nuclear,
so I wrote him back.
I said,
it wasn't no Kyla,
you fucking dope.
Stop acting like you're too smart to
listen to my podcast. I Dunno. And then,
and whenever I call people out on it, they
go, oh, she was looking for reaction. Oh,
where are you? Oh yeah, yeah. Take your
comment and fucking go home. Right.
You're not in the sandbox anymore.
He's gonna to run away. Huh?
You're going to go down there and
hide under this skirty Yamada.
Huh? Um, SCARAMUCCI got fired.
Fucking sucks.
Everybody says they want somebody honest.
And this guy goes in and he literally
just says what he's thinking.
I didn't know how to say
that. Guy Rents. He reacts.
R. E. I. N. C. E. Tell me what
it means to me. Um, rents.
He says he's a fucking
paranoid schizophrenia.
Yeah.
Uh, paranoiacs whatever the hell that
means. And he goes, I'm not sure,
like Steve Bannon.
I'm not trying to suck my old cock.
I'm not trying to build my own brand.
I'm here to serve the country. I mean,
Jesus Christ.
What more do you want from
somebody in the White House? Is it,
cause he said Cock,
is it,
cause he said fucking like these people
who go in there like Obama who speak
eloquently and, and
just fucking, you know,
we hit a jump shot every fucking once
in a while. Now. My God, he's so cool.
I don't, I really don't under, I, I
fucking given up on people. You know,
that's how people are. And
when, when, when fucking, uh,
what George Carlin died
and what's his face?
The guy there who fucking was always
grabbing a whatever the hell was doing,
kept settling out of court,
you know, like led Zepplin.
Yeah,
he does his tribute to George Carlin.
It's him to sit in as shitting on
him for fucking curse too much. Okay.
I Dunno.
That's a fucking shame,
man. That is a, uh,
that is a real fucking shame
at that guy is gone yet.
L So what did we get it?
We're going to have somebody who we're
gonna have a clean comic go in there who
still lies his ass off. But
where's the sweater? I mean,
if you can get past cock and fucking,
he basically said,
I'm not here for my own needs.
I'm not here to,
to advance myself. Actually, you
know, that's a lie. No, right.
He's a liar too. But he was a
fun liar. Come on, people leave.
Fuck the guy was fun.
Yeah.
He goes, I'm not a backstabber. I'm
more of a front stabber. I mean, this,
this was like, it's like
what if, what a fucking,
somebody who watched Goodfellas too
much got to be in the office. Right.
And he never took it to debate in class
and no one ever told them not to curse
and to the microphone. I
mean, is it this one? I mean,
isn't that what the Internet is all about?
Isn't that why the Internet blew
up at the end of the fucking day?
Isn't that why it blew up?
It's not because you want it to go on
there and research how fucking seagulls
fly from one side of the beach to the
other and all those other fun filled facts
you can find on a website you went
on cause you wanted to see Teddy's,
you wanted to see some pussy and
you wanted some uncensored language.
Isn't that what you wanted?
And look how much better society
is now because of the Internet.
Uh, you know something, if I
was ever on the debating team,
there wouldn't need to be another
person there. Okay. First of all,
because I'm not good at debating.
And second of all,
I end up undoing all of my points
during my argument. You know,
like if you ever debated
me like the worst,
the most apprehensive you'd
get is you bring your eyebrows
up like half. Like, oh,
okay, they come back then, okay,
he just fucked the whole thing up.
He just fucked it all up
like Scaramucci did they,
aren't you going them
all? Look who's here. Hey,
I know you're doing your podcast and
then leaving. So what are you guys going?
Wow. You got oatmeal on your forearm to
clean up and get ready to start the day.
Okay. Kiss Goodbye. Little princess you.
Huh? You eating oatmeal and banana? It's
just like Yo man now. Huh? You got to,
we got a mushroom up pretty good.
This is called the podcast sweetheart.
Woo.
No, Hey, I'm talking about SCARAMUCCI.
So mooch,
Scaramucci audios will catch
the daily news. Addie. Oh,
smooth Chacha and then the other ones,
a
Henry and our writings riding.
When Henry Good milk came up with a MOOC.
There it is. Okay. That's what he
would have had for the fucking great.
Okay. All right ladies.
Okay, I'll go to work.
Why those before you leave,
right?
Yeah, but you know something.
Parenting is entered a new scary phase.
This is where she's mobile. She's
going mobile and I don't give a shit.
Like if there was a cobra on the floor,
she'd grab it by its neck and try
to stick it into her mouth. I mean,
I hit her on the floor the other day.
I thought I had everything all cleaned
up and I got one of these casino rugs.
Basically you're the ones with all the
different colors on it. You're like,
oh my God. Is that from the Orient?
No, it's from fucking leash.
Right. And uh, it's fucking, you know,
you can't see stuff.
So I remember I was stretching
before I worked out like an old man.
I got a stretch right.
And I saw one of those spongy earplugs on,
on the ground and I was like note to self
pick that up. And I was just, you know,
being a neat freak, cause I've
never had a baby crawling around.
So long story short,
I'm hanging out here with my lovely wife.
My daughter's crawling on the
floor and I see her in a tongue,
looks like it's purple and I'm like,
what says enter tongue?
What the fuck's going over the tongue?
And then she kinda was
moving it around a guy.
I guess it's all right cause the
earplug was purple by the way.
She wasn't like losing oxygen and then
Diego's yeah, no, she's looking down.
She's fine. Jesus Christ.
I can pull that out
and I can't even begin
to tell you like the,
when something like hap that
happens to you, to your kid,
when you drive to work,
you get in a cab and you're going to see
in the subway however the fuck you get
to work, you ride a tricycle
with the giant front wheel,
however you get to work,
you're not even paying
attention to what you're doing.
All it's going on is a
fucking movie in your head.
That would make Stanley Kubrick fucking,
I dunno what Steven came one of
those fucking guys freak out.
Like just the stuff I was thinking about
like you know the worst case scenario
of all of that and now so now there is
nothing on the fucking ground. All right,
we got those things. You stick on
the tables on the corner so you know,
so you don't hit the corner with
their head. Evidently it's okay.
The rest of it they fucking give themself
a face rub along the fucking Tasha.
What does the Dasher most of you are going
to ask? Cause you're not hockey fans.
That's a little ledge that goes
around the boards, the fucking board.
So anyways,
we're doing the table read today for
episode three Oh three three three three
episode three Oh three.
We're moving along.
We're doing an episode three Oh four
next week we'll have five of them done by
the end of the month and half way there.
Halfway there to writing
and then rewriting and then
the rewriting starts. Um,
but it's,
I think,
I feel like everybody knows the characters
this year and we're cruising along.
Knock on wood, knock on wood. So I
think this'll be a nice table read.
But Oh my God. Every once in a while
a nice fucking lay up comes in.
He needed that guy. You needed scare
a mulch to fucking balance out Trump.
Cause everybody's doing Trump jokes
enough with the fucking Trump jokes.
Jesus fucking Christ. Oh my
God. What's going to happen?
The same fucking thing that happened
when Obama was in office. You're morons.
The exact same fucking thing.
Watch.
Just watch. Watch how much
our foreign policy to watch.
How much in fucking corporations have
to pay attention to the environment.
Watch how much bankers go to jail. It's
going to be the exact same fucking thing.
And I'm not talking about minorities,
I'm not talking about illegal aliens.
It's white people. Stop acting like
you fucking life is gonna Change.
Like somebody is going to come
in and take your fucking SUV,
your little fucking bran
muffin or whatever the fuck
else she got at Starbucks.
All of these fucking assholes freaking
the fuck out, which I understand,
but where was this for the
last fucking eight years
and the eight years before they had
the AP eight all the way back to Jimmy
Carter.
Jimmy Carter was the last fucking real
man that was in the God damn office.
Look at him out there.
He's not out there fucking doing Payton's
waiting for his library to be built is
out there building houses.
I could, Goddamn man,
it's put his fucking hammer
where his mouth this,
these other fucking guys just sitting
around waiting for their library. But yet,
you know,
there's a Roman,
all those presidential libraries that
you go in there for the rest of your life
and there's a group, he
just standing there, right?
And she just blows you the second you
walk in and the whole time she does,
it's fucking true. All right.
If you don't think that's true,
then you need to get on
the Goddamn Internet. Um,
anyways,
plowing ahead here.
But he had a blue tie.
Um, anyways, people, I don't, I don't
pay attention to politics. I don't,
I just do all of this shit.
So then people can air quote
correct me on the fucking,
on Twitter with their own misinformation.
It's a little game I like to call.
I don't have a name for it. Um, anyway.
Scaramucci God dammit,
that guy should have
his own fucking podcast.
I would listen to that every fucking week.
Isn't that what you do now?
I love how everybody,
when they get fucking,
when they totally ruined their career,
their first fucking option is what I do.
They did. They start doing, stand up.
Remember Charlie Shanie fucking two guys,
a girl and a fucking pizza place. He was
on that whatever the fuck his thing was.
Hey, there's two guys in there
as a kid and there's no check.
I know you know exactly
what you're gonna do.
200 fucking episodes and make
it to syndication. Let me guess.
Do you got two dates in the same fucking
night? Now what are going to do? But up,
but up up is the story. No wonder he
ended up doing all those fucking drug.
So would I. How many fucking times can
you just sit there doing another episode?
Those poor people on those
fucking sick comp Smith.
Once you get up to like
episode 80, 90, and just like,
and you know that you don't care anymore,
you know,
it's bad enough when you don't care.
Just the cruise there.
I just can't imagine walking out in
front of that fucking studio audience.
You know, you guys missed
it. I was actually,
I was in Hollywood during the
fucking heyday of that shit.
And uh,
used to always hear these stories
about all of these fucking shows.
The stay would be in like the,
uh,
they were in the seventh season
and they'd be like, dude, they,
I heard they don't come in until Thursday.
You know,
most of them don't even
show up to the table read.
Then they would blow off for her.
So Tuesday and Wednesday,
they wouldn't even
fucking come in Thursday.
They just do the block and
cause they have, it's so down,
you know,
I know I go sit on it, Richie,
and then I jumped in the air,
cross my legs and sit and Howard
Cunningham's chair. I got it.
How many of these fucking
episodes do we got to do? Right.
They'd show up for the camera blocking,
which is basically,
so you know where you stand.
So you're going to be on camera,
you won't block anybody else.
And then the next day they do the
taping and then that was it. Yeah.
Um, anyway, so these mother fuckers, he's,
I bet he does a podcast. You know,
they should start a podcast network.
Just the outcasts. Right. And it
should be like fucking Paula Deen.
Um,
uh,
who's that guy who was like
fed fucking really weird guy.
Glenn Beck dead. That guy. Jesus Christ.
You know, I used to watch him
just to feel emotionally stable.
He was like a character on a wrestling
like Kinda like a, a fucking,
I dunno like one of those high pitched,
uh,
who's that high pitch guy
who had the megaphone?
It was like Bret Hart.
Giuseppe was built like that
guy from gladiator gladiator.
I forget what that movie was called.
Um, anyways, they should have them.
Bill O'reilly.
Should you just stick them all on the
same network and they just sell them like,
you know, the main stream couldn't
handle us. It couldn't handle our truth.
We went out day or shade it
lag. [inaudible] everybody
is, that's what I do.
You know our American playboy can't
hate on me because I tell it like it is.
That's the male version
of when a woman goes like,
guides are like intimidated by me.
Now you're a cunt and you
sir are a racist moron. Okay.
You're not telling it how it is.
Okay.
You're telling it how
you're fucking racist.
Parents told you how it is and then you
never left your town and then somehow
you got on television and then you started
saying the shit that you heard at the
local diner. Right. And then everybody
else with dirty boots are like,
right.
That's how it was.
So it was people, I don't know what
I'm talking about right now, you know?
I have no idea. Oh Man. Oh Jesus.
I'll tell you, me and my wife all,
we almost got into it. Oh, he almost
got into it this morning, you know,
fucking unreal. I had to work out this
morning to keep my figure in shape. Okay,
I've got to do this fucking podcast.
Then I got to go over the script and
then I have to go do a table read.
I got to do all of that before 10 o'clock
in the morning and I forget whatever
the fucking branch of the armed serve
we do more before booking Millenium oh
yeah, you got a table
read. What do you deal?
You march around and sing dirty limericks
wait up
Hashtag,
Huh?
Oh right.
That's what the fuck you do.
And then you do some pull ups and all
of a sudden I'm supposed to fucking sit
there and feel like I
haven't done anything.
I got to do what those guys that doing.
I've always wanted another adult with
more lines on the side of his sleeve
screaming at me. How can I
sign up for that? You know,
if I was a gun nut, I joined
the fucking military that, that,
that's what you want to do, right?
You know, you know what the deal is.
You start off with tin cans, then you move
up to squirrels, then you shoot a bird,
right? And then eventually
you get in the fucking board.
Cause at the end of the day,
no matter how difficult it is,
they matter how much deer urine
you've got to put on yourself.
You shooting something dumber than you.
At some point you want to go
after the ultimate brain, okay?
You've watched Jurassic
Park too many times.
You realize there's no real Velo Rasa,
[inaudible], whatever the fuck they they,
God damn thinks where you realize there
aren't enough of those. You'd like,
I'm joining the God damn military.
Right. That's what you do.
I wonder how many psychos did that,
you know,
they always say that they're doing
it for your freedom. Right? I joined,
I show a sharp don't happen.
And I was like, I'm not done.
Then there are those people, come
on, somebody write me an anonymous,
what branch of the service or you
went, Huh? Are you in the coast guard?
Yeah. We get to sense what are the
people you're working with? Joy.
Just because they wanted to see someone
half eaten by shark pull 'em out of the
water just to see what it looks like. You
know, I think the coast guard, that's,
that's like the worst fucking
like out of all the jobs,
because the war never ends.
It never ends. You know,
hopefully at some point this shit will
end over in the Middle East, you know?
Um, I don't know how it ends, but
who the fuck knows? But anyways, um,
the coast guard,
it never fucking,
and that right there, I mean,
can you get the metal of,
they should have a civilian saving a
dumb civilian medal of honor for the
fucking coast guard.
Do you realize every time there's like
a bad storm coming and that telling
everybody to stay inside and you get
like, oh you get excited. You know,
cause all they sent me
home from work early,
all we get to light a fire
in the fireplace, you know,
let's watch raising Arizona,
get the kids together,
all wrap up in a blanket and
you have a great fucking time.
Oh Beg some smarts. That's
why I love you lady. Right?
You're getting ready. You know what the
fuck they're doing. And the coast guard,
they have fucking palms are sweating.
Their stomach is in a knot because they
know some stupid fuck is going to get in
his God damn boat around his fucking
surfboard or his boogie board or some dumb
shit is gonna go on a fucking hike.
All right.
And he's going to Alton,
you gotta come get me.
And these people who are completely
safe got to get in there.
Fucking got to get in
a fucking helicopter,
fly out the middle of a fucking hurricane,
defy some fucking dope in his silly
named yacht who had to take the fucking
thing out,
right.
Had to show off in front of his trophy
fucking wipe and now they got to go out
there.
It's some poor bastard.
He's got a fucking jump out of a
helicopter in a hurricane into the fucking
ocean to try to get these fucking
dopes out of there, back to the land.
So what they can breed and
make more stupid people.
So the people at the top of the coast
guard can keep making their fucking blood
money.
We're taking college.
Okay.
That right there is the
scariest fucking job.
I am terrified to the fucking ocean.
Okay.
You would not want to have a bunch
of mes in the Coast Guard. Okay.
Those fucking boats would just be sitting
there in the sun and on the day will
be yet that would be it. I would fucking,
I would be, we would be on the dock.
I'd be on the boat with a life jacket on
playing cards and I would get like this
distress car.
Yeah.
Yes.
Good. I'd be like, Hey Roger Dad. Well
what the fuck are you doing out there?
Well, I don't, what the
fuck, what the fuck?
That would be me,
I would have that meltdown every dime
and then I would do the job because
basically at the end of the day,
if I was in the coast guard,
that's how I have to
fucking make my limit.
And now I have to go out there and
fish some fucking dope out there.
Is Anybody in the Coast
Guard listening to this?
Can you please tell me there's no way
when you phish somebody out of the ocean.
Okay. And then they, you
got to fucking go last.
Okay.
And then they send that
fucking hook down again. Right?
It's just sitting there
and 40 foot waves are
going up and down.
When they wrote,
when they fucking crank you back
up in that Goddamn helicopter,
there is no fucking way,
you know,
talk some shit to that guy is he's
sitting there with that fucking,
I almost got swallowed by the ocean.
Look on his face.
Whatever the fuck that looks like.
He knows he's fucking dumb. Right?
Do you must look them right
in the heg take fuck head.
Next time he take your boat out,
why don't you make sure the fucking sun's
out and it's not a fucking whatever.
Well, how are they rate a hurricane?
Fucking got goddamn five or a cake.
It's unbelievable. You know what I
always think that they fucking look like?
I mean,
you just,
I would be so fucking embarrassed if I
ever did some dumb shit like that and
somebody had to go out wrist.
If fucking life fly a fucking helicopter.
You're not supposed to fly. And turbulence
with helicopters. As far as Mike,
my little knowledge of it
and these fucking guys got
to go fly out and then that
shit
unfucking believable.
They ever make a movie about
the Coast Guard, Huh? Well,
I didn't say it.
I'm fucking making movies about,
made a whole TV show about a
fucking dolphin saving people.
They call him flipper.
He can pray.
You can hold his breath and then it
comes up I think if supposed to be there.
All right,
let me make a fucking TV show
about a of of a guy saving fish.
You know that f beached themselves and
you throw it pay and maybe they did.
Was it free willy? We
actually, we captured that one.
I don't know if I think I probably owe
coast guard ever fishes me out of the
fucking ocean. You know what the
look I'm going to have on my face.
Do you remember when Oj got arrested the
second time and he knew he was fucked,
but he was trying to smile.
Remember that fucking that's the
fucking look I would have on my face.
I just forgot. I know. I know. You
don't have to say is that they do,
you shouldn't say a fucking word to those
people after you pull them out of the
water. Even the gold
digging whores, you know?
Yeah.
Just talk to her. Yeah.
He had enough heavy,
had enough rich old caulk at this point.
Sweetheart, why don't you go back,
finish up at community college and
build a real fucking life. Okay.
No,
we didn't find your other glass high heel.
You're fucking stripper it. Oh, and
they did take it back to the base.
Um, anyways, sorry. Most of that
was just the stress of my day.
23 fucking minutes. All right,
let's read a little sweet,
a little bit of advertising here.
Shelly people
the Coast Guard.
What's their fight song?
If you're fucking Dharmana I have to
go out in the ocean during a hurricane.
It's our fucking job to go get you
even though we want you to drown.
Um, all right, let me get to the
advertising here. All right. Um,
Shit. Here we go. All right, looking good.
Looking good.
Doesn't need to cost a fortune five
four club is revolutionizing the way men
shop at fam folk club.
They found a way to make great
looking clothes affordable for every
Gary Oldman.
Fat Folk Club also understands that
your time is extremely valuable.
You have video games to play
and porn to jerk off to.
Why wasted at the mall or
wandering around in the stores.
Why read a book each month?
They send you a curated box of two to
three items that are handpicked to match
the current season and your style
partners with partners,
with cutting edge designers and brands.
So you'll get the same quality as
top designers clothes for way less.
They've been helping men with
fashion forever, forever 15 years,
and shipped to over
100,000 men every month.
Chris Paul and Mark Walberg use five
folk club and Fido is featured in Gq,
vice and instyle among other publications.
They know what they're doing.
So if you don't, that's okay.
Five Boat Club will help you build
your wardrobe one time a month.
I never fucking read an, uh, an uh,
piece of advertisement that says
their fucking name more than this.
This is like listening to an
arrogant athlete. You know,
you know, talking in first portable
Barry bonds, gotta go dead Dewberry Mum.
Because when you look good, you
feel good. It's a fact of life.
You get $120 worth of
clothes for just $60 a month.
You can pause or cancel anytime.
No Commandments.
And as a club member,
you'll also receive up to 50% off items
in their online shop and access to
exclusive members only items.
Oh Geez. Do you get the jacket,
the free shipping and size exchanges?
Go to five folk club.com right
now and enter Promo Code burpee.
You are our and they'll give you 50%
off your first month package plus a free
pair of sunglasses. Aw,
who wants to look cool?
That's 50% off your first package yet.
Folk Club,
spelled Fiv,
F o u r o club.com Promo code birth five
four club.com Promo Code [inaudible] oh
look who's back. Oh Jesus
Christ. But Oh dope,
dope me undies me undies.
I got fat balls, Doo Doo,
Doo Doo. It was a birth
defect. I got too many nuts.
Fivefold Bolles makes
fucking nine but don't worry,
my boss feel fine because I got dead
velvety under wherever up my giant
stretched out fucking nuts sack.
I really mean. All right. Mondays.
Mondays are the softest, most comfortable
underwear you'll ever wear, period.
And a fucking story.
And summer is the perfect time to upgrade.
Upgrade your underwear drawer because
everyone is thinking about looking good
and feeling good.
Everyone is on social media and me
undies are the ultimate feel good undies.
Wouldn't you love to take a
Selfie with your nuts? What?
You couldn't do it before this underwear
put your scrotum in a good mood.
Every pair of me undies is sustainably
sourced and made from micro modal, modal,
a fabric that is three times softer than
cotton according to the people at me
undies.
Because me undies comes in all kinds of
colors and patterns and they release new
limited edition patterns each
month that will always sell out.
You know what me undies
needs to go up against a,
what's said gay underwear brand.
Uh,
a filthy pig or nasty pigman.
At that time I told you I
was unfortunately going to
Charlie Murphy's funeral
and I didn't pack enough underwear and
the only fucking underwear place in my
neighborhood was right across the street
and it had like the banana hammock shit.
And I walked in there and there was
like cock rings and all this shit.
I ever tell you this story. So I
got it. So I'm looking for the,
all the underwear is just like
fucking like atlas that all this.
So I finally go to the guy behind the
counter. I go, eight skews me, but I go,
do you got any? Uh, you
got any normal underwear?
And he goes to find normal.
And I was like, I dunno,
it doesn't say nasty pig
and the fucking waistband
does it say stretch out my ass on the
fucking right across the booty cheeks.
Can you just got a pair of black
or gray or white ones? I'm sorry,
my life isn't as exciting as yours be.
These audit go up against those guys.
You know,
you're doing all the different
colors and the patterns. You know,
people will buy nasty pig underwear.
Maybe you could get them on.
I don't think nasty pig is made
out of micro Modo. Modot uh,
you got to see them for yourself for,
for right now,
you'll get 20% off your first pair
and receive free. Only at me. Undies.
Dotcom. Slash. Burn.
There's a reason me undies has
sold over 5 million pairs to date.
You'll feel it when you put them on.
Your Dick will stand at attention.
If you don't love your first
pair me undies, they're free.
Get 20% off your first pair plus free
shipping@meundies.com slash. Bird.
That is me, undies.com/. Bird. Yeah,
Andy's dot com slash bear the by
me on was not written by me undies.
And none of the things I've Elbert
said is mirrored in any way.
Reflects the feelings of anybody over
here and trying to make it dick feel good
in a pair of underwear, pro flowers,
everybody. Pro Flowers. Hey,
it's August.
Why don't you take a bouquet of flowers
and put them in your girlfriend's face?
Huh?
Um,
talk about the last time you spontaneously
surprise someone with something
completely unexpected and how
it felt. Uh, Jesus Christ.
I hope you don't send
this to fucking hope.
There's no serial killers with
podcast talking about the last time he
spontaneously surprise someone with
something completely unexpected and how it
felt.
Picture in Hannibal Lecter. I remember
it was heart rate wouldn't even go up.
He's listening to the classical
music. I don't know. Um,
I would surprise my wife
but she snoops too much.
She always figures out what the fuck
I'm doing and then I just be all right.
Fucking here it is.
All right.
Talk about what the Rose Bouquet bouquet
bouquet recently sent to you by profile
is look like and your overall impression
of it. Uh, well I didn't receive it,
but I have seen bouquets of roses before
and I know what they look like when
they're in the vase and
uh, you know, it was,
yeah, those are flowers
and they really smell like.
All right. Pro Flowers wants to help you
surprise someone for no reason at all.
Well, in other words, you want
to make more money selling
flowers. In other words,
there's no real fucking
holiday this month.
All while also surprising you with
a special deal. For my listeners,
get 20% off any other of their unique
summer Rose Rose bouquets or any other
bouquet of 29. Why are they trying
to fucking do this? Just saying,
what the fuck you mean here? This
is the deal. There's no eastern,
there's no mother's Day.
There's no fucking Valentine's
Day unless it's her birthday.
There's no fucking reason to
get a flowers other than this.
Shut the fuck up for a couple of hours,
okay? If you, if your girlfriend's
birthday isn't this month, okay.
And God knows Jesus didn't do anything
in August cause just like Fyi,
he took the month off. Okay,
so there's no Jesus holiday.
I don't know what Muhammad did.
I don't even want to get into Buddha.
But as far as me as a white
male, white male, Christian,
there's no holiday this month. Okay,
so you're probably sitting there going,
why the fuck would I get her flowers?
You know why? Because it means something.
It means more.
You're supposed to do it on mother's Day.
You're supposed to do
it on their birthday.
You're supposed to tip them upside down
on Christmas and use their fucking clam
is a vase on Christmas.
We all know this. Okay,
but you're not supposed to do it in
August and that's why you do it. Okay?
This is like when Michael Jordan used to
come to practice and rather than acting
like he was the best guy in the league,
he would practice like
he was going to get cut.
That's what you want to do with pro
flowers. So fuck their copy. All right?
You can get 20% off the summertime. Roses.
Go get some for your mother in August.
Just get them for and be like,
Yo, why you should do this?
Because you're the best mother
I ever could have asked for. Oh,
that's what you're going to
get right there. All right?
And you get 20% off some or roses
or any other bootcamp. Okay?
For fucking $29 a more.
Go to proflowers.com use my code.
Berbee you are are a checkout.
That's proflowers.com code.
[inaudible] don't wake to make
someone's Day. That's it. 32 minutes.
32 like Oj Simpson. He's
going to be ready. Wow.
Come October. Uh, what
you gonna do when? Oh,
Jane comes running wild on you.
I've had a pretty nonconfrontational life.
Yes, you did. Oj. Except for that night.
He killed two people. Other than that.
That was it.
You ever see that fucking documentary
about how we got fucking arrested the
second time when he went down
there to go get his shit, you know,
and then he had his buddy take out
his gun and then they didn't have his
memorabilia that he thought.
So then these other fucking assholes
started grabbing autograph Pete Rose
Baseballs,
and then they took the guy's cell phone
and then it became an armed robbery.
I mean, I would assume also
think, depending on how that
got got the memorabilia,
I don't really remember. All
I know is it's like, dude,
I can tell you this man.
Okay.
If I was a black guy who got away with
killing two white people and I would not
leave the fucking house for the rest
in me, it's what the fucking guy,
I don't know what he's thinking.
You know,
you run for 2000 yards in a 14 game
season and then all of a sudden you think
you're invincible.
That fucking look on his face when he
gets arrested the second time where he
knows he's fucked and
yet he's trying to smile.
I was talking about that
yesterday in the writer's room.
It's one of the funniest fucking
things I've ever seen. It's like that,
and there's one of ric flair
with somebody's interviewing
him and they're asking
him, what was it like the last time you
went to Japan and you see his love for
wrestling, and he knew it was his
last day, said, look at this picture.
What was going on? And
he was like, this was,
I knew this was my last time I was going
to Japan and he starts to fucking cry
and he doesn't want to cry,
you know,
cause he's the nature boy
and he's trying not to cry.
So he's smiling while he's trying.
I can try not to cry.
I've never seen an actor do that in a
seat because of an actor's starts to cry,
they can't help it. They're
like, oh good, I'm crying.
This is what the director wants.
Crying equals good acting.
I'm going to get an award.
All right,
Denzel gets one with one tier.
I got to tears coming down
that aren't, I mean, die.
Get a Golden Globe and a fucking Oscar.
Right. All right, that's the podcast.
Please listen to this wonderful
music. Oh, by the way,
you know what am I finally
fucking got into? And I,
I used to trash them all the time.
Joe Rosa was right about Frank Zappa.
I could never get into a,
granted I was listening to fucking
hair metal. It was two. And I always,
people always said Joe's garage.
Every time I read a fucking drummer
magazine for fucking 15 years,
every drum was trying
to get Vinnie Callie,
you as high hat sound and Geogebra Joe's
garage. That's what they always said.
You know, I wanted to get that Vinny
call you to high hats and Joe's garage.
And I always got to put on and I was like,
what the fuck is this?
I don't even know what's going on.
Is,
is frank mocking music is easy
trying to take what I just,
it was so far beyond anything. I was
listening to it. It didn't sound good,
if you can believe that. And, um,
I finally just put it on in the car and
I also fucking had another 15 years of
listening to music and actually trying
to expand my horizons from top 40 Horse
Shit that I had been listening to. And,
uh, it's fucking unbelievable album.
It's fucking unbelievable.
So, uh, Joe de Rosa,
I trashed him so many goddamn times
about Frank Zappa so many times.
And I was like, Joe, you're contrarian.
You just like it cause it's different djs.
I swear to God, if everybody liked Frank
Zappa, you wouldn't fucking like him.
And he goes, that is a true bill. I,
I, I'd hate you and your freckled face.
And we would go back and forth,
back and forth as we drank the fucking
the brown devil then that's what we would
do. Okay. And Joe Rosa, I'll
tell you right now, and I'm
going to tell him his son,
his birthday, he was never more right
about Frank Zappa and he was never more,
he was right about the brown album with
Primus. And he was right about the,
the fucking golden girls.
Okay. I saw the golden girls.
I saw four old ladies, Joe,
to Rosa saw comedy gold.
I didn't see it the other night I
was sitting and they weren't on,
they were having a marathon.
I was trying to get my daughter to go to
sleep and I'm watching the shit that's
like 30 years old and I'm laughing my
ass off. I fucking love that show now.
You know.
So my apologies to the great Joe to Rosa
and happy birthday to him and oh by the
way,
if you guys would like to do me the
biggest fucking favor you could ever do,
there's a few fucking tickets left
for Paul Versey standup special,
his first one, his first
hour, then me, Pete Davidson,
Al Madrigal and all things comedy. We'll
be producing our first standup special.
We would love to sell this place
out. Okay. Was So fucking close.
We could lie to Paul and
say this is sold out.
We just want to sell these last
few tickets. If he could do it,
if he can make it down.
Okay.
It's at the Tarrytown theater in
beautiful Tarrytown, New York. I mean,
this is like one of the,
the beginning of a Tom Hanks movie,
when he has the perfect life before he
decides to fucking go out there and it
gets stuck on a Goddamn island
talking to a volleyball, right?
This is where they would
start maybe his neighborhood.
And like big when he was riding the
fucking ball with a little kid was riding
the bike. That's what this place looks
like. He could bring you lady up,
you can have a nice fucking dinner.
Me and Pete Davidson are going to go on
stage and fuck around at the same time
trying out new bits, getting you guys
warmed up. And then Paul [inaudible],
he's going to absolutely fucking
crush it. All right. And all things,
but he is producing it and
it's going to be great.
So please come down if you can.
I'll be hanging out in between shows.
You want to get a picture?
I'll sign shit.
Whatever the fuck I gotta do to get you
into the goddamn building. Um, that's it.
I'll be tweeting out a link. Uh,
let's make it happen. Okay. That's it.
Enjoy the music and we'll be playing
some a greatest hits of a Thursday
afternoon just before Monday morning,
Friday,
fucking whatever the hell he called
this thing on the Thursday gone by and
another year.
Awesome. Alright, go fuck yourselves.
Have a great weekend consent.
I'll talk to you.
Okay.
Hey
Mom.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
August the third 2009
why the fuck does it say November? You
know what? I thought I finally had it.
I was going to be like,
it's 77 degrees out.
Chance of a high of 83 and now I'm
looking at says fucking November.
Why is that? I Dunno.
Why the fuck it does it?
That does to meet every God damn
week. I'll gives a shit, whatever.
It's August 3rd all right.
Another year flying by Jesus Christ.
Where is the summer going?
Huh?
How many people have said that to you
already? Everybody always says that.
Where is the summer go egg every year.
It just seems to go by even faster.
I'd say it's amazing like the
first 20 years of my life,
it just seemed like it took forever
about today. Once she had 30 those years,
they just, they just, they fly by. Oh,
and if you have a kid, forget about it.
Just for fun. Yeah. I mean, I don't,
I don't even remember 35
to 46 nobody cares, lady.
Nobody cares. You're, you're
saying the same shit. We got it.
Life goes by fast.
Okay.
Where is the time going?
I don't know.
I'm wasting a lot right now
listening to you, going on your big,
long fucking seemingly
philosophical little rant
about where the fucking time is
going. While you're not really being,
you're not presenting any what?
A philosophical shit.
Now you like that people,
this is going to be a hybrid of
podcasts where I hit you with terms like
philosophical shit.
All right?
So I'll be coming at me acting like I'm,
I'm getting all upper crust here.
That's your own insecurity
because you get nervous when I,
when I use terms like that.
All right? That's not my fault.
You went to a community college,
you know,
and you didn't have great teachers to
teach you about philosophical shit.
All right, whatever. This is
the Monday morning podcast.
I do one of these every single week
and um, I really enjoy doing them.
Um,
I don't know why cause you know why?
Cause I walk around my apartment and I
talked to myself anyways and when I have,
um, when I have headphones on and
I have talking into a microphone,
I don't feel as crazy while
my dog is already asleep.
She's in heat right now.
Jesus Christ walking around
with the fucking swollen pussy.
That's what I got. Huh? How is that? Yeah.
I hope you were eating when I just said
that as disgusting as one of the most
disgusting things I've ever said.
But anyways,
this is really going off
the rails quick this week.
People brand new conductor
here. Um, all right, let's,
let's get down to some shit here that
I want to talk about. First of all,
I have some homework for all of you guys,
everyone who's listening
to this podcast and um,
I got to admit my podcast.
I think it's finally taking off because
in the last couple of weeks I've learned
that I don't have enough bandwidth
on iTunes for the amount of people
downloading it.
So I appreciate all the new listeners.
I got a computer nerd friend around
the corner who hopefully will solve the
problem tomorrow.
You know,
teach me how to get some
more bandwidth or whatever,
so more people can listen to it. I
get a ton of questions. So anyway,
so I feel like I'm starting to
build a force here. All right?
So maybe I can use this force for,
for like my own wishes. You
know that Jesus Christ at
the, even for my own wishes,
for, for my own desires. There we go.
So this is the required homework
for all of you this week.
All of you have to go out and you got,
you have to go see the movie, the orphan.
All right?
It is required because I want to
talk about that movie for a good 10,
15 minutes. I want to
talk about that movie. Um,
but I don't want to ruin it for people.
All right?
You have to go see that movie.
That movie is a throwback to classic,
I would say mid maybe late
eighties horror films where,
um,
they just kind of went off the
rails and they building suspense.
So the whole thing just became funny
cause it was inadvertently a fucking
hilarious movie.
And uh,
I dunno. Ah, Shit. I
want to talk about this.
I'm giving you guys one fucking week
next week I'm talking about that movie
because it was so, uh, it
was so ridiculous. You know,
this is how I know it's a good horror
movie is if I go and see it and then when
I get home and I'm turning the lights out,
you know,
I'm creeped out in my own apartment.
You know,
as I walked by a hallway and there's no
light on, you know, like to this day,
to this day, when I'm on the road
and I go back to my hotel room,
every once in a while I'll put the fucking
lights out and I'll expect like the
TV to come on and see the girl crawling
out of the well or to hear the phone
ring. And I pick it up and it's
going to go seven days, you know,
because that movie,
I don't know what it was about the ring,
that one stayed with me,
the Blair witch,
which was really a polarizing movie where
a lot of people look to those fucking
stupid. I won't fucking scared at
all. I was just fucking laughing.
You know those people,
those people who go to scary movies and
they got to talk about how it didn't
scare them and how they laughed the
whole time as if that means if they were
actually confronted by
a psycho on the street,
they would have a better
chance of, uh, you know,
of surviving because they laughed
in a movie theater. I mean,
anybody can sit in a fucking movie and
just take themselves out of the movie and
just fell. It's just an actor. Oh, it's
fake blood. You can do that. You know,
I dunno.
Maybe this is me just getting fucking
defensive because the Blair witch scared
the shit out of me. You know, I
fucking bought that movie hook,
line and sinker and the end when that
dude was standing there facing the fucking
corner, it was just creepy. I
like when I can't see the monster.
That's my thing.
Is that your thing bill?
I don't remember asking you what your
thing is. Well then don't fucking listen.
Sorry. I'm going to, I'm kind of
in a mood right now. There's a lot.
I had a lot of devastating shit happened
to me this week. And not only that,
I was driving,
uh,
down the street out here and I
saw some lady had a, a, a sign on,
on the back of her,
her as Suzu trooper,
everybody 1988,
Isuzu Trooper Zuzu however the
fuck you say it. And it says, uh,
I might be slow, but I'm in front of you.
You know, and that's the kind of person,
if someone dragged them out of the car
and started beating them repeatedly about
the head and neck,
as much as I would feel bad for
the person who's driving the zoo,
trooper [inaudible] kind of
be kind of asking for it,
you know, why are you baiting
people to beat the shit?
That's what you're doing right there.
That's like Nananana ass shit. And uh,
you know, it's like, uh, I don't know.
That would be like me a,
I don't know,
in the 60s when the race
riots were going on, you know,
and having some fucking racial
shit on my isn't really bill,
is it really to that level?
Now? You're right, it is.
And I don't even go down a fucking robot,
a moron. Um, but anyway, speaking of the,
in the 1988 Zuzu trooper, and that's kind
of been a new thing that I have on my,
uh,
my myspace page is I'm taking pictures
of random vehicles out here in Los
Angeles. Um, because I, I just,
you can't believe how long,
if you're from the east coast,
you cannot believe how
long cars last out here.
Some of the cars that like,
oh,
you have a hang out with your friends,
you know, some high school buddies,
you know,
you haven't seen in awhile.
And then they bring up some kid who
moved in the second grade, you know,
hey, remember John Sarno
everything and you were like,
holy fuck,
I have not thought about that kid since
1982 dad is what it's like walking,
driving around out here. I don't know if
I told you this a couple of months back,
I saw a Pontiac t 1000 in
good condition out here.
Chocolate, Brown, Pontiac t 1000. And
for those of you who aren't in the car,
you probably think, oh, teen 1000
probably had some bulls. You know,
you could probably do a
burnout or whatever fucking
stupid thing those gearheads
do. Um, that I'm jealous of because
I don't know how to fix a car myself.
Um,
Pontiac team 1000 was actually
the Pontiac's answer to the shoe.
A Chevy Chevette,
which was a hatchback Chevy
Chevette and was also a very,
um, on its way to becoming
a hugely hacky joke.
When I first started in stand up,
one of the classic hacky jokes
when I first started was,
uh, people get on stage and be like,
Hey, I'm doing pretty good. You know,
you see my car outside? Yeah, I got,
the vet has Chevette and I'd be like,
yeah,
Oh shit. I thought he was
Doug about it, love it.
And then the guy and his,
everyone's laughing.
The guy would be adjusted his sport
coat sleeves to make sure that they were
three quarters of the way
down his forearms to let you
know that he wasn't in an
office.
You know,
that's why he had the pastel colored tee
shirt underneath his sport coat to let
you know that he was, he was off
the grid. He was out of the Matrix.
He found a way to find
your daily grind uniform,
a fucking edgy.
That might be one of the worst periods
of fucking dress ever. The late eighties,
standup comedian,
remember that with this skinny ties or
the fuck he's just, it's just in the,
and the, the, the was
basically the feathered mullet.
It was like Farrah Fawcett
met. Uh, I don't know,
Billy Ray Cyrus. I got, I
got fucking nothing on that
one. But speaking of which,
let, let's, let's plow ahead.
So anyways, I, I have, uh,
I've been taking some pictures of
some pretty random fucking vehicles,
one of which I don't even know what
it was. It looks like a big RV.
I thought it was a Volkswagen.
It's missing the bumpers.
It literally looks like it's made out
of Styrofoam Styrofoam and I'm convinced
someone's living in it. Um, but anyways,
check those out on my myspace page
if you're bored. But, hey, bill,
why don't you get back to the
podcast? Fine. I will. And I will,
you're probably wondering,
you know,
a couple of minutes ago I said I
kind of had a devastating week.
Um, how do I get into this? All right.
Once again,
going back about a month
ago when the subject of,
uh, steroids in baseball came
up. I did not name a name,
but I said if one particular person
were to some for some reason get busted,
I guess it wasn't roids it was HGH, but
whatever was HDH whatever the fuck it is.
If they were to get busted debt, I was
going to be done with baseball and, uh,
the person got busted and,
uh, that's it. I'm out.
I'm out.
Okay,
I'm out. Fuck baseball. I don't know if
I'm going to be out forever, but fuck it.
I did catch myself for half
a second watching a Dodgers.
I think they're playing the cardinals.
I can't watch it.
I watch for like three seconds. And then
Manny Ramirez came up and I was like, Oh,
here we go again. I'm done. I'm
fucking done with, you know,
what bugs me the most about all of
this shit. And um, you know, I got,
I got emails from a couple of
Yankee fans going on, right? Gold.
Now what now what you say
[inaudible] you know what a yeah,
you're right. You're absolutely
right. But I'll tell you,
us against you is even roids verse Roids
and Europe where you're actually still
a couple ahead of us. But
no, it's roids verse Roids.
All right, if you want to
argue the 2004 championship,
because I can't really think of
a cardinal that got caught. Uh,
I would have that argument
with somebody from St Louis.
But as far as Yankee fans go, I mean,
come on dude. All right. We, we, we,
you know, you guys did everything but
send a fucking center up to the plate.
You know what? That's what the Yankees
and red sox should be right now.
They should just have half men,
half horses and they
just go up to the plate,
you know,
and they got to put on a jersey,
cause you can't look at
that little fucking, uh, you
can't look at that. You know,
you know what it is when they
come up to bat, they're good.
They're going to need a
shirt cause they're going to
need a little pocket to put
that little fucking pan
flute in when they come up.
I think that that's what they should do.
So I gotta be honest with you,
I don't know what is going on at baseball,
but uh,
I'm not even mad at the players anymore.
What's really pissing me off at this point
is how the owners made all that money
and they're not being held
accountable on any level.
I really think like the last 10 years
of baseball was just a big marketing
okay.
Like scheme to get everybody,
like how insane is this
country into baseball now,
I don't know if you guys remember,
but back in the early mid nineties,
it was really going downhill even
before the strike and all that.
Basically all you had was cal Ripkin
was going to break Lou Gehrig's record
record record record and um,
yeah,
he was like this throwback guy and he
was doing something that was really
respectable. W uh, you know,
it was a record that, okay,
how much, I can't even talk.
What the fuck is wrong with me?
It's like Lou Gehrig went back to an
era that was considered, you know,
a golden age during America as far
as hard work and World War II when
segregation and water fountains and
all that other fucked up shit that they
don't really see. You ever noticed
that when they go back in time,
you know when they talk
about the golden years, they,
they or they talk about racism.
They never tell those two stories
at the same time. You know, America,
we made all this, you know,
made steel, steel workers.
I don't know all this type of shit in
the American car and all that type of
stuff. But they always, and then if
they're going to tell the racism story,
they just tell that one separately,
you know? All right, you could,
you could beat your, your wife.
The rule of thumb, you know,
what was the rule of thumb?
You could, you could,
you could beat your wife with a stick
no bigger than your thumb. You know,
you can't tell me girls weren't looking
at guys. Thumbs on first dates back then,
those little five foot,
six inches do with little fucking little
sausage fingers so that Jesus could I
take the beat down from this guy
and I don't think I could, you know,
but then again, the women back then,
it was like big milkmaids, you know,
they were all doughy.
Okay.
You ever see like the paintings from
way back in the day of like sexy women?
You know, they were raw.
They were definitely healthy.
So healthy fucking women. All right, I'm
getting off the track here. All right,
so let's get back to baseball. So you
fucking, so basically what they did was,
I think basketball and football
were overtaking him. I mean,
that's what I was watching. Bird
Magic, Jordan, Isaiah Thomas,
all those great teams, Dominique
Wilkins, all that stuff was going on.
Then in football,
I mean,
I went from the late seventies Roger
Staubach beaten the Denver Broncos.
That was the first Superbowl I watched.
And I went right through, you know,
the last two Terry Bradshaw's Steeler
championships into Joe Montana,
Dan Marino, John Elway, right
on through, right on, through,
right up til like,
uh,
I would say the end was maybe a
cowboys dynasty.
Okay.
That year with the fuck happened
when the 40 niners played the,
the chargers in the super
bowl. That's, that's when,
that's when the golden age ended.
That was a bad one. Um, anyways,
but whatever. So no one was fucking
watching baseball son. And they just want,
they want, they, they juiced up the
ball, they made the ballpark smaller,
and then they just look the other way as
these fucking roided out dudes came up
and hit like 80 home runs as a third
baseman and they all made a shit load of
money and now they're leaving the
players to hold the fucking bag. Uh,
I don't know. I think it's
bullshit. So because of that,
I actually,
I'm beginning to try to find a
different sport that I can watch in the
summertime. And, uh,
I went to the x games in Carson,
California on Saturday and I watched
a little motorcross man. It was,
that was definitely, it was cool. But I,
I've never felt so old in my
life going down to that thing.
And I also did not fit in.
If you've never been to the x games,
a motorcross SORTA skateboard, all that
type of shit to describe the crowd.
It's Sorta if Travis Barker and dog,
the bounty hunter had children,
that's what the crowd would fucking live.
Somehow they had 30,000 children.
That's what the fucking crowd would look
like. It was very, uh, everybody there,
it looked like they had at least
one felony, you know, and I'm dirty,
filthy, filthy, Skanky fucking women just,
you know, I, you know, it's, it's, it,
it's getting a tattoo. Is that out yet?
Is that it?
Has that gone the way of the bell bottom?
There is nothing more
skanky or then just fucking,
just tattoos on a woman. It's
just, you know, I don't know.
I remember there was a period where they
were kind of cute or whatever and then,
I dunno, it jumped the shark when
whoever coined the term the tramp stamp.
And if you live under a fucking log,
that's basically the tattoo when the
small of a woman's back that just really
just says that, you know, I fucked
a lot of guys in my sorority.
That's another major red flag.
When you see a girl who has like a
sorority tattoo down around her ankle that
yeah. Um, I dunno, I'm not
saying don't marry her,
I'm just saying don't go to any of her
high school or college reunions because
there's going to be a lot of guys going
up shaking your hand with that look on
their face.
Like does this guy know that me and my
buddy fucking double teamed his fucking
wife, the mother of his children and
I know a lot of females right now.
What you saying right now? That's the
double Sandra. That's as I was saying,
how can we as a come a guy can go out and
blah, blah blah. And if a woman does it,
she's a whore. I'll tell you why.
This is actually a bit for my act.
I'm going to burn in my podcast.
I'll tell you why.
Because for a woman to
get laid is absolutely,
there's no fucking skill involved.
All right.
You getting laid is like me trying to
get a fat kid eat ice cream. You know,
it's really, there's not a
lot of, you know, I guess,
see what it is is a guy, his men
have to make women want to fuck us.
We have come up, we have to
dazzle. We got to put on a show.
We got to come up with some
sort of fucking angle to
get someone of the opposite
sex to touch us. You guys can, you can
just fucking lay down in a pool table.
You could bang everybody fucking bar.
There's no skill.
It's gluttonous. That's
what it is. It's gluttonous.
It's like watching a fat guy eat
ice cream in public and listen
[inaudible] nobody gives a shit.
But when I do do a Google
would've figured fuck
because you're a fat fuck.
That's why.
So getting back to the woman thing,
no respect,
no respect for your numbers.
Because you have a vagina.
All right. There we
go. Jesus Christ. Bill,
you went a long way on that one.
Eric.
We're 20 minutes in and I don't think
I've ever felt more ignorant. Um,
all right, continuing on. Here's
something that I wanted to, uh,
and I just realized the record
levels are kind of high here.
I hope I'm not my screaming
into this thing. Um, anyways,
whenever it gives a fuck, uh, this is
what you get. This is what you get.
What did they want to say
this week? Oh, I know.
This is something I would like,
if anybody out there,
does anybody out there have a VHS
copy of the Superbowl with the rams?
Beat the titans?
I've never seen that.
Superbowl and it bugs me.
It's the only Superbowl
since 1978 Broncos,
cowboys. It's the only one that I
missed. And when I say I missed it,
I missed the whole fucking thing.
Um,
and why was that?
I was dating some girl
and she wasn't into it.
Are you seeing my dog here?
Just go.
Sometimes I feel like I'm telling a story
and she's actually board. Um, anyway,
she wasn't into it and uh,
yeah,
so I ended up fucking hanging out with
her and stead. Wow. Was that embarrassing?
And an end up being course ended up being
one of the greatest Superbowls fucking
ever and I've never seen it.
So if anybody has a copy of it,
please can you make me a copy?
Send me an email and send it my way.
I'll trade you.
I'll trade you a fucking
DVD for a VHS copy of that.
Um, all right. There we go. That was,
it was a really fucking long way to go.
All right, let's throw it to
get this thing back on track.
She can tell you can't you guys always
tell when I'm searching on my computer
and my sentences become more
choppy? All right. Hey, Bill. Uh,
you talked about inadvertent racism on
your July 27th podcasts and I see what
you're saying.
Uh,
simply recognizing that certain dialects
can be found in whites, blacks, Asians,
et Cetera,
isn't really racist.
But the woman who emailed you about
shiny suits on Conan called you working
class or blue collar or some shit,
presumably based on your Boston accent
and you seem to take offense to it.
Just thought you'd want to know.
Uh,
you're talking out of two sides
of your mouse here, miles here.
And I am emailed her back and told her
that basically my entire act and the
podcast are based on talking
out of both sides of my mouth.
So I found that email hilarious.
But my point,
and I'm not going to stop blaming people
for not getting my point because I
understand how my complete inability
to present my points. Clearly.
My point is that,
you know,
each race does have an accent.
Okay.
So if you were to say that sounds
sounded like an Asian dude. Oh,
that sounded like a black dude.
It's not racist.
You know,
it isn't,
I still can't fucking explain this
without sounding like a dick. I look if,
if, if some, if you were talking to some
guy on the phone and he's like, oh, hello,
I be over there. Very, very
sure. And again, it comes
over and it was a black guy,
wouldn't you be in the back? He
had like Jesus Christ, this guy,
he sounded like like a fucking Asian dude.
Now I'm not saying that all
Asian guys sound like that,
but if somebody sounds like that,
they are going to sound like they're Asian
and I'm also not a master of dialects,
so I am going to be doing an
exaggerated version of your people.
That's it. The same way def
jam comic go on TV and imitate.
White Guy's gone. Oh Gee, I got
to go do my taxes. Holy Heck Gee.
Willikers Jimmy, do you
have any cricket? I mean,
nobody knows anyone who talks like that,
but you know what this say plus it's
comedy. It's a fucking joke, right?
That's all I'm saying. Okay, so
way back in the day, the Oj trial,
when a neighbor heard a voice and
it said is sounded like a black guy,
and they tried to sit there
and make that unbelievable,
the most racist thing
ever. It wasn't, you know,
believe in an like,
let's look at gay guys.
One of the most fascinating accents ever.
Here's another bit I used to do on my act.
How gay guys come from all over
the country, all over the world.
Let's just stick with this country.
They come from all 50 states,
yet there is a gay accent.
Hi, how are you doing? Yes, Jesus, right?
Hacky, absolutely. But a
hundred percent not true.
You can't say that.
And that fascinates me because I think
if you're a gay guy from down south,
you should be like, hey buddy, I know
and I want to suck your fucking Dick.
What do you think about that? You
really got a nice bump there, buddy.
You know what I mean? Ah. It gives a fuck.
I'm so sick of trying to explain my
uninformed fucking views. Whatever.
It's a podcast. Don't take it seriously.
Some people take it seriously. Yeah,
it gives a shit. Yeah. Just get
to no, they take it seriously.
Then it gives me something to read. So
please, for the love of God, keep uh,
keep taking this shit
seriously. Um, all right,
here's another one for you.
We're going to be dealing a lot with
racist week evidently. Here's a very, uh,
he's a very, some of these emails,
they're getting a little serious here.
Here's one for you. Hey Bill, I'm an,
I'm an 18 age old black man.
You know,
do you guys proof read these things?
And I've always wanted to
interracially date since middle school.
I'm sorry. Just had some
fucking weed checks. So
that literally sounded like
I was getting choked up.
I've always wanted the interracially
dates. It's middle school. Um,
but there is one short five 11 guy
that is always there and a mess up.
Something good. My Dad, my dad is
what you would call a buzzkill.
I'm a photographer for my school and
there was a girl that I've been friends
with for awhile and uh,
almost every halftime at
the football games we would
talk one time she said, hey,
can I take a picture with you?
I was not going to say no because
the more you please women,
you went a little closer
to her pleasing you.
Oh God. Is that hilarious?
That's how a young man thinks.
That's a whole nother subject.
You know what,
you actually want to be going in the
opposite direction a lot of the times.
But if she's a nice girl, yes. Be
Nice to wear anyways. Um, so anyways,
years she gets close to pleasing you.
But uh, as she climbed out of the stands,
I was running through my,
it was running through my head what my
old man would say because he makes me
show him the photos to see my progress.
I guess as a photographer,
um,
we had someone snapped the photo of us
and when I got home and put the photos up
for my old man,
I tried to skip it,
but he saw that I had to sit there for
an hour in 45 minutes and listen to how
white people did US wrong for 400 years.
And if you, if you start liking them,
it's because you want to be them.
Bill A,
that's just the light version.
A couple of weeks ago we were at our
family reunion and we were watching tiger
woods. I said, the tiger
woods had a hot wife.
I really wish you recorded all of this.
And my dad butted in and said, is she hot?
Is she hot because she's white.
Bill,
I tried to tell this shit head that I
love all women no matter what race. Um,
one, no matter what the race is,
my old man flew off the handle.
I had to sit for three hours and listen
to him rant about the same shit I've
heard since I was 13. Stuff like,
you just hate black women, don't you?
You just want mud kids,
don't you? Jesus Christ.
If you do marry them,
you'll just be a dog to them.
And I always know and I always
knew that that yellow Skinner,
yours would go to your head.
Uh,
I guess that's light skin.
It's like a whole nother fucking thing.
Ah, high yella. Doesn't
that mean light skinned?
Anybody out there of a African persuasion
that can explain that to white people?
Red Boned and all that
shit. Um, anyways, uh,
so whatever. More light skinned. So
thinks he's a cut above. Can't hang out.
So what does your dad,
does your dad look like?
Keith Robinson. All right,
that's for standup fans anyways. Uh, where
are we going? What am I going with this?
I just lost my fucking plates.
Mud kids,
yellow skin. Jesus, one of them fucking
ugliest emails ever. Um, Bill, this is,
uh, Bill, this is just
I short on me. I don't know what you're
writing here. I'm six. One love Jennifer.
Love Hewitt,
Vanessa and Hughes Riana.
Oh Jesus Christ.
What the fuck?
And I always,
and I always that that
Chris Brown would backfire.
I always knew that that Chris Brown would
backfire and that Asian girls from the
beat and that age girl from the
beginning of true lies a girl is a girl.
And when you're, and when you are
hungry like a wolf, this kid hilarious.
You do not want to settle for just one
kind of food. This guy basically. Yeah,
he's 18.
He wants to fuck on every continent.
He wants to bang a girl from every
racist is total normal behavior. Bill,
I've hated my family.
This is really become a doctor Phil here.
Bill,
I have hated my family for fucking up my
life from birth with their divorce and
my mom died when I was 14. She us
iron man. I forgot about that part.
I would have been laughing here, but I
hated her like m and m hated his mom.
I'm living with my dad now for now because
I'm about to head to college and that
same girl is going to the same
college and she wants to hook up.
Bill helped me find an easy
way to tell my dad the fuck off
while do, I dunno if you've
been listening to my podcast,
but do you really think I'm qualified
on any level to address the shit that's
going on here?
Do this is like,
this is like the perfect storm of stuff.
All right. All right. The first of all,
the mistake your dad's making
is by ranting and raving
at you for an hour and 45
minutes about what he doesn't want you
to do is the quickest way to make you run
out and go do it. All
right. And from what I,
I've my experience as a kid,
obviously I don't have any kids and uh,
yeah, he should be able to
date whoever you want to date.
I will say this, you're
18, don't get a girlfriend.
All right? Stay single. Get out
there, figure out what you want.
And as you're going around fucking the,
uh,
entire rainbow of color out there,
be making a mental list.
What you're looking for in somebody to,
uh,
to settle down with. This is
the shit that, this is all
the shit that I didn't do
is I rudderlessly just bounced
from one fucking chick to another.
Um,
okay.
Nice way to tell you I, and easy
way to tell you dad to fuck off. Uh,
you know what, why don't you try agreeing
with them? You know, when he goes,
yeah, I knew that yellow skin
would go to your head and be like,
you're absolutely right. Data. I can't
even believe that I'm talking to you.
In fact,
when we walk in public,
is there any way that you could kind of
walk like 40 feet behind me so people
don't know that we're together?
You can, I don't mean,
I don't know if your dad gets physical
and you starts fucking slapping you
around like some lifetime movie. But,
uh, I've used this technique on, uh,
a number of people after a while,
when you just get sick,
you have to get somebody, they just
get, they just get, I dunno, they,
they get,
they get pissed cause they know you're
going to go out and possibly enjoy life
more than they have. You know,
like I had a couple people,
uh, you know, when I moved down in New
York, I had friends given me shit like a,
you know, hey I got a new apartment
here but it's not New York City.
And then I'd always find myself having
to knock living in New York City,
like tone down my shit so they could feel
better about where the hell they lived.
And after a while I was just like, yeah,
I just start agreeing with them. Yeah,
you're right. It isn't New York. New York
is the shit. It's the Paris of America.
You know. It's too bad you
don't live there cause it's
fucking awesome. You just,
you just agree with them.
Oh you think you're the shit now could
you live down there? Yeah, I know.
It's unbelievable.
My Ego is completely out of
control and you know, just,
I dunno.
Okay.
I don't know what to tell
you, dude. That that's,
that's a really tough one
because no matter what,
you're always going to want
your dad's approval. Um,
but just watch out for the anger that's
building up in you and just make sure
that you don't start making spiteful
decisions towards him about your own life
and the path you want to go down because,
uh,
then you get, you're going to end up in
some miserable play. Yeah, you'll start,
you'll literally start dating
someone just to piss him off.
I'm not saying you might, you'll do.
Maybe you will. I don't know. Um,
I dunno dude, that there's, there's a
lot of shit going on there, but you know,
I'm glad you brought all of this stuff
up because you remember that bit I was
doing that.
Get out of the pool,
make it fun of those movies where
they show like racist white people.
And this right here is
the point of that bit,
which is they've made 80 million
movies about white people being racist.
And I was laughing that that
started off with slavery.
One of the most horrific things that's
ever happened in this country other than
I guess the straight up
genocide of the the Indians,
native Americans are the fuck he supposed
to call them and there's been so many
movies made about that shit that now
it's all the way down to like swimming.
That was the joke and I know I like,
I stopped doing the jokes
wants they're on TV,
but I know I said at some point are
white people the only ones who think evil
shit.
I came,
remember how the joke when isn't there
some Mexican guy making fun of an Asian
dude or whatever.
This is what the fuck I'm talking about.
This is what I'm talking about and it
just gets annoying after a while that you
take a movie like guess who's
coming to dinner when it's,
when it's the white girl bringing home
the Black Guy, the original movie.
Then it's this drama and it's this really
serious fucking thing that needs to be
addressed. But when you flip it and it's
a black girl, bring an Ashton Kutcher,
all of a sudden now, now it's a
comedy. And, and what's his face?
The Dad there, you know, not wanting
her to bring home a white dude.
Now it's fucking hilarious.
I mean, I guess I get it
because of a, on some level,
because it's not like black
people and slave white people.
So though the rules are fucking different,
but you know what I'm saying?
Something I'm just saying, I'm just, I
don't fucking know. I don't want him,
you know what I mean? You
know what the fuck. I mean,
I'm just saying it's like I
got it. I understand. You know,
there's 80,000 fucking movies
about white people being racist.
How about we switch it up every once in
awhile and make a movie about Mexicans
stabbing Puerto Ricans after a boxing
match. How about that? You know,
we ever see that like whenever a Mexican
fire fights a Puerto Rican fighter,
guaranteed somebody getting stabbed
in the Bronx, that's all I'm saying.
I mean, maybe that's not a movie. Maybe
that's more of a, uh, a short, but a,
you know, he could have the
hackey characters in there. Right.
And what the fuck I'm talking about.
Anyways, that's a move on here.
Let's recommend, so my youtube
videos for the week. Um, here we go.
Here's ones that you guys can search.
I don't have time to fucking look.
I watch all of these,
but this is just becoming way too big
to try to watch all of these and try to
come up with the greatest one ever. My,
my, my youtube video of the year is tough.
A tough talk in college,
Girl. That one. Um,
here's some other ones that
people are also suggesting.
If you're at work and you
don't want to work, um,
go on Youtube and search killer dwarf,
midget Muay Thai fighting.
And if you don't wanna watch that and
you want something a little cuter,
watch a search, Charlie bit my finger,
which literally has 90 million views.
So if you haven't seen it yet,
you're one of those people who
not only does not watch TV,
but you don't have a computer. Uh,
this is a weird one. Dog Malfunction.
I went to show that to my
girlfriend and she was just like,
is he going to shit himself? Like shit
all over the place? It's like, no,
it's something different.
A guy with gun confront skateboarder,
I can't remember if I told you that
one last week, but that's a decent,
that's actually a really good one.
And a here's a really good one.
A boxer beats up two guys.
I love this video because the box or
dude is basically what every man wants to
be in this video.
Basically two guys do something fucked
up to his girl and without even without
even a moment's hesitation, he fucks
up these two. This guy is like,
you know who all those guys and like
the action movies pretend to be.
This guy's the guy in
real life. Um, all right,
well getting up here in time,
aren't we? 37 minutes. Okay,
we got to start winding down here.
MMM.
All right. Here's something
sneaky corporations. All right.
And I know I keep saying that.
I'm done trying to tell people not to
use those automated machines at the
grocery store. I had another guy
telling me how much easy there. Oh yeah.
I'm in and out of there in two minutes.
Really?
You scan a week's worth of groceries
and you have them in a bag and you're in
and out of there in two minutes.
Oh yeah. I'm sure. I'm sure it's,
I'm sure it's way easier than having
someone who's trained to do it.
Do it for you and stick it in a bag
as you sit there rubbing your balls,
doing nothing. I'm sure
it's way fucking easier. Ah,
idiots. Idiots who want to
work for free. Have Fun. Um,
anyways, there's another one
sneaky corporation thing. Um, Bill,
I share your and Bubba, Bubba, bubba.
MMM.
Here's an article you should check out.
I'll sum up the basic idea of the
article. Essentially, here's one for you.
Starbucks opened a coffee shop in Seattle
called 15th Avenue Coffee and tea.
They have nothing blatant to
indicate that they are a Starbucks.
They've gone out of their way to disguise
their company as an independent coffee
shop. They even sent scouts to check
out independently owned coffee shop.
I'm assuming to better emulate them.
50th Avenue coffee and tea
will serve beers and wines.
It will have cheese platters
and entertainment at night.
I think this is a new direction that
corporations go into these days.
They create new brands and new images
to trick people into supporting their
company.
And you can't tell who owns what anymore.
So for overrated,
underrated, I say overrated.
The 15th Avenue Coffee and tea,
Aka Starbucks and disguise.
How fucking creepy is that?
You know what?
I Bet I've gone in and spent
money to place like that.
I was go out there and
as long as it's not a,
as long as it's not like a, uh,
a chain name that I recognize.
Okay,
I know some of this shit, like I know
like, uh, but this is a chain anyway,
so I wouldn't eat there with see that
chipolte Lei is actually owned by
Mcdonald's. But anyways, they,
I fucking hate your post lay.
I don't know if you've noticed,
you haven't noticed.
They always open right across the street
from like a really good a Mexican food
restaurant. That's how they didn't just
fucking put those guys out of business.
I tried to, I tried to stay away from
those, but I'll have to, I'll have to,
I gotta be honest with you. I didn't
even read the article. You know,
that's what I do.
Somebody just tells something that's all
you gotta do is just tell me something
and it becomes here because
I'm not going to look at it.
I'm on bullshit and I'm actually going
to read it. All right. Um, horror films.
Bill, after hearing your story
about the movie curtains,
it brought back memories of a
movie that I saw when I was young.
It was called the unseen.
All right.
You guys get to hear the description
of this movie and just to let you know,
he ruins the ending, but I still have
to see this. This is a fucking classic.
He goes,
I haven't seen it since I was a kid
back in the 80s but being six and seeing
this one did a number on me for a while.
Pretty much.
The movie is about three chicks
who can't find a hotel to stay in.
So they end up at a bed and
breakfast type place. Jesus,
there's an original beginning to a
horror movie. Um, so there's some quote,
there's some quote unquote thing that
attacks these people that stay there.
The part that screwed me up is
that the thing that attack them,
um, would attack through the oversized
air vents in the walls and floors,
pulling them through and killing them.
So after watching it,
I was terrified to go into the bathroom
because all of our bathrooms in our
house had Vince right behind me.
As I took a piss for the longest time,
I would have to use the bathroom with
the door open in case something would try
to get me. I look back at it now and think
to myself, what a pussy I was. But Hey,
I guess that's why six year olds
shouldn't watch horror flicks.
Here's to four months of pissing
with the door open. All right,
now here's the spoiler
alert. Everybody. Here's a,
if you're going to rent curtains,
you don't want to hear, uh,
you don't want to hear this last part.
Um, and of course, okay. By the way,
the thing in the movie turns
out to be a retarded kid,
that the parents kept locked in the
basement and all he wanted to do was play
with people.
Apparently his play was a little rough.
How many of those horror
movies are basically,
it always comes down to some, somebody
being shunned as a kid, I swear to God.
I think most of those,
most of those horror movies have something
to do with the person who wrote the
movie, their childhood. A lot of
writers, they're fucking nerds.
So they had these awful childhoods
and then they had like these fucking
fantasies of what the,
what they wanted to do to people and then
they just move it a little to the left
and they turn it rather from,
you know,
just some kid having
some murderous fantasy.
They turned it into a fucking monster star
and then you got to goddamn movie.
Does that make any sense?
That I just say that retarded
people are writing movie scripts.
I think I did. I think that's how
the math works out on that one. Wow.
Let's blow by that. All right,
bill question. I love your calm.
This is the questions for
the week and then I'm done.
Let me hype what I got going on this week.
I'm going to be at the comedy
connection in Providence,
Rhode Island on Friday
and Saturday of this week.
That would be a,
what's today?
The third Friday is four days a
seventh and the eighth. All right.
I'm going to be back there doing two shows
both nights. He can go on my website,
[inaudible] dot com and just click
to the link. Please show up and uh,
watch my new hour of hilarity.
And the following week I'm going to
be at the punchline in, um, Atlanta,
Georgia and I believe I have the dates
wrong. I'm going to be there Thursday,
Friday, Saturday. I have it down
as Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
I have to change that and hopefully
by the time you listen to this I have,
um, and other than that, I'm
going to be in Stockholm,
Sweden at the end of the month and that's
going to be end of my summer and I'll
be enjoying being in Stockholm,
Sweden cause I'm not going to be missing
baseball. I will not because I am done.
I'm fucking, I don't know
if I'm done forever, but I'm
taking a break. I've had it.
I don't give a fuck anymore.
Okay.
I think what that guy in the white
sox said, the coach there was true.
He's just like for the love of God,
just release, just released the list,
you know, so you can just
get on with it. You know,
I don't understand about these guys.
They get on roids and then they get off
roids and now they're clean and they're
still the same size that they
were. The only guy, like I said,
the only tie guy ever saw gets
smaller was uh, Jason Giambi.
That's the only fucking guy. All the
rest of them, they look the exact same.
So I don't know. I have. Fuck it.
I feel like a dope getting all excited
the last 10 years, boy. Oh boy.
Did you see that? A home run all
boil pool. It's all bullshit.
All right. Questions. Hey Bill. Uh,
let the comedy podcasts I read recently
started working at a retail store.
And during the hiring process they gave
me a choice between direct deposit or a
debit card that they provided.
Yeah.
Basically saying,
um,
I wouldn't be getting a
physical check every other week.
I asked why they did that and the lady
said, that's just the way we, they do it.
Isn't that how you, isn't that the
response you always get from corporations?
Yeah.
You know what, why, why do I have to do
it? Oh, that's stay just they make us.
That's just, that's just
how they do it. So anyways,
like every other person
I said, oh, all right.
And even though that's the way they do it,
didn't answer my question.
So I guess my question to you is,
do you think that this is just a way for
paper money to be turned into numbers
on a computer?
Is it really easier to have my money
directly deposited in a bank or say,
or on some debit card rather than me going
to the bank and physically getting my
money. If I may use your
reference about it, um,
about if your iPod crashes
and all your songs are gone,
but if you physically had
the cds back to back it up,
then you will be okay.
Okay.
Uh, did any of that makes sense?
Not The way I'm reading it. No,
I'm just saying I would rather get the
physical checks than to be doing things
online, but I guess that's just the way
they do it. Yeah, dude, that's brutal.
That's fucking brutal.
See what they're doing is they're
forcing the herd into a direction.
So when guys like me don't play
ball with that, just out of,
I'm going to have to play ball the
same way with those automated machines.
Everyone's going to start using them
and then there aren't going to be any
cashier people and then I'm
going to be fucked, you know?
So, um, yeah, that,
that's what they're doing
is they're phasing out cash.
So anybody who has any cash hidden in
their walls are in their bed or any of
that type of shit.
Um,
that stuff eventually will become obsolete
unless you take it out and then you
give it to them and then there'll be like,
well, where the fuck did you get this?
And then they'll tax the shit out of you.
Um,
and I know a lot of you right now going,
well,
you should have fucking reported the
money anyways and all this type of stuff.
And if you really read about the Federal
Reserve and all and how fucking corrupt
it is there,
there's a link on the Internet right now
where it's where some guy used to work
at the Federal Reserve just called
it a Ponzi scheme on television,
on CNBC said it's basically
nothing more than a Ponzi scheme.
I don't know if the guy, actually, let me,
let me get, let me get that link for you.
Um, if you really want to
check this shit out, go, uh,
it's called the daily bail.com
and all this is, this is
when they have the, oh,
that's a woman testifying
for the Federal Reserve.
When they've asked if they have
any, you know, they put it,
give them $1 trillion and there was no
record of where it went or who took it.
And they just keep talking in circles
while we have a person that is looking
into that.
But right now I can't give
you an answer on that.
Like that's the way they
answered everything.
Do the whole thing's a fucking scam. It's
all a scam. What they're trying to do is
they're trying to phase out cash.
So there'll be no way for you to ever,
like everything you do
will have to be reported.
They'll know where all your money is
at all times. And then not only that,
they're going to have all your money
at all times. It's, I don't know how,
how do you know how to,
it's so fucking huge.
I never know where to begin
to try to explain what,
how little that I understand
about this is just, just,
let me put it this way. The amount of
money that you've made in your life,
how much of it have you
actually held in your hand?
How many times have you gone out and you
work all week and then they just typed
some numbers on a piece
of paper and then you,
you know the check and then you just
go down to the bank and then it just
becomes this number on a computer screen.
The amount of number, that's money,
money that's out there versus the amount
of money that's actually printed first.
The amount of money that actually has
gold behind it, it's fucking terrifying.
It's a,
it's the biggest fucking scam
I think in the history of the world.
Okay.
It's the biggest fucking scam.
And when you get a mortgage like I have,
and I'm sitting here trying
to figure out how to get
out from underneath that debt and meet,
realizing that me getting
out from underneath the debt
will actually cost me an
extra four grand a year in taxes.
Okay.
If not even more, I think all the way I
worked it out. Yeah. It would cost me,
I pay about 24 grand a year in
taxes or something like that,
and we go up to 28 I can't even remember.
I tried to work all of this shit out,
but basically my best move was
to just
take 30 years to pay off a mortgage.
Okay.
To basically pay 200%
interest on six figures.
I Dunno. You know what?
I can't even explain it.
I'm probably sounded like a
moron right now. Just, just,
I dunno. Read up on this
stuff. It's fuck. It's brutal.
It's just fucking brutal. I
can't even, I don't know. I'm,
I'm coming off like a moron.
I wasn't prepared to discuss this
and what little I knew about it.
Now you guys are probably gone.
This guy's just a fucking idiot.
Okay.
I don't know where the fuck do
you begin to try to explain this?
It's actually funny.
Like I'm really stammering right now.
I feel like I committed a murder right
now and I'm trying to say that I didn't
and I didn't take time to fucking
come up with a, with an alibi.
Okay.
Um, I don't think that you should
put your money in the bank is basic.
What I'm saying,
you know these guys fucking,
you'd take your money.
Okay. He put it in a bank.
Okay.
All right.
They give you like fucking 0.5% interest
on it and then they take your money and
then they turn around and they loan it
back to you with everybody else's money
at some ridiculous fucking interest rate.
And then on top of that,
they come up with these fucking loans
that make homeless people qualified to get
homes,
which drives the price,
artificially drives the
prices of houses up.
If it comes like Superbowl
tickets, everybody wants to
go. So now a fourth thing,
something that's worth $400 face
value now becomes worth four grand.
It's not fucking worth for grants.
So then you go out and you pay like
a couple hundred grand more than your
fucking places actually worth and
you're paying interest on it. And who?
Who drove the price up?
The bank.
And how does a bank
make money on interest?
Okay,
so they dig,
just basically created loan so they
can make houses more fucking expenses.
So expensive so they can make even
more money. The whole thing was,
was bullshit.
It was completely criminal
actually. You know what? It wasn't
criminal. That was a great thing.
It was actually legal,
what they were doing.
That's how much fucking power they have.
And then when the whole thing fucking
topples, they make us fucking pay for it.
We pay for it and they
keep the fucking money.
They're beyond fucking corrupt.
It's the most corrupt bullshit
on the planet.
I think it's worse.
It's worse than than anything that's
going on in the planet right now.
It's right up there with genocide.
What
the fuck they're doing is
because basically they're
in slaving the entire planet
and right now they rather you know it
or not. You are financially enslaved.
You're fucking indentured, sir. I really
sound like a fucking crazy. I'm serious.
You're,
you're fucking year and a dent might my
own guy who invest my money when I was
trying to figure out how to get out
of this bullshit, he said it to me.
This is a guy who actually could probably
obviously and a much more intelligent
way explain this fucking
game. He said, Bill, face it.
We're all indentured
servants to the banks. Um,
I dunno dude.
I Dunno.
What the fuck happened back in
the day when you moved to town.
We went from having a house raising party
to having a 30 year fucking mortgage.
Will you pay 200% interest on the
fucking money that you were loaned?
And by the time you pay it off,
you in a fucking wheelchair?
Yeah,
there has to be a happy medium.
I don't want to live in a log cabin.
I don't want to live in a cave. But, um,
if you think that the
government is above the banks,
you're out of your fucking mind.
And a great example is when the president
tells bankers after they fucked up the
economy not to take a bonus,
and they basically say, hey,
go fuck yourself with taking a bonus
anyways. And then he just says, oh, okay.
I think that should basically tell you,
you know who the fuck is running stuff.
So I know that came off
as completely ignorant,
but read up on it. Okay, I can't,
I'm just a fucking comedian.
I really shouldn't get
into this type of shit.
But that fucking question
really set me off. It's a,
I dunno, it's frightening.
It's frightening.
It's why I'm trying to pay off
my apartment as quickly as I can.
I don't think I'm going to make
it because of the end of it.
I want to have something of some sort of
fucking value that I can go out and get
a sandwich with.
You know,
maybe I can rent out a part
of my apartment because I
don't think money is going
to be worth anything if they just keep
printing it. They're phasing the shit out.
Okay.
It's, it's bad. It's bad.
People don't do that.
Don't get direct deposit.
Don't do that.
Don't do your fucking
banking on the Internet.
It's the level of faith you,
you're, you're, you're an
idiot. If you're doing that,
you think you're the only
guy looking at that shit.
I'll tell you what pisses me off
with someone sent me an email said,
even if you don't do banking on,
on the Internet,
all your information is up
there anyways just in case.
Yeah.
Just in case you want to go online now,
I don't think that they should have
the right to do it. It's my money.
I should be the one who tells him,
listen,
I don't want my information
out there like that,
but they can do whatever the fuck
they wanted. It's just, it's all,
it's not your money, everybody. It's
not your money. They give you money,
you and your job is to go out and get
into as much debt as you possibly can
sustain.
And if you don't,
then they just take it from you so you
can never become rich and they keep
getting fucking richer.
That's what the fuck is going on.
And this has nothing to do
with Republican or Democrat.
This just has to do with a select few
group of evil people at the fucking top
who are running everything.
I know I sound like a motto,
my fucking mind and I probably am.
Um,
but I welcome the debate.
Anybody who is an economics or whatever
who majored in that Shit and you want it,
you want to email me and
you want to explain to me,
okay?
I mean,
am I wrong thinking that the Federal
Reserve is a private corporation that does
not have to answer to the u s government
that has never been audited. Am I wrong?
Okay.
Aren't they in charge? I know the
treasury physically prints the money.
Am I wrong?
I'm just asking am I wrong when I say
that they are the ones that are in charge
of how much gets printed and when and
that the u s government or the banks then
take that money and have
to pay interest on it.
And that creates this debt that
we can never fucking get out of.
And isn't that what happened over in
Europe and isn't that why they are now on
the fucking euro and are we
now moving towards the Amera?
Huh?
This is me just regurgitating
all my Wikipedia youtube shit.
That even sounded dumb to me,
but I dunno. That's the general,
you know what I mean?
Um,
you know what I'm like right now
I'm a guy who just started watching,
like it'd be like me trying to
intelligently talk about the x games.
Then when I went to the x games once
and I'm like, you do the backside.
Fakey all right, whatever. Let's
plow ahead. Hey Bill, I love the,
uh, the podcast here.
Okay. Bill Hill. Bill,
have you ever been offered to do, to
be on the show, last comic standing,
um, offered to be on it? No, I did. I
could audition for it, but I didn't.
Um,
I just thought it was,
I thought it was good for Comedians
at a certain level and I thought I was
beyond the level where it was good and I
would have just looked cheesy on there,
you know what I mean?
Plus I to, I knew myself,
I wouldn't have done any
of the competitions. I just
would have been, well, no,
I'm not fucking doing that.
Just challenged me and I'll go up and
I'll do three minutes and if you beat me,
then I don't have to live in a
house with seven other comedians,
which would be kind of enjoyable.
In other words,
I wouldn't have been good on the show.
So now I never, uh, I never got offered,
but I, I could've auditioned and I didn't
think it was for me. All right, Bill. Hey,
love your comedy, uh, on the podcast.
Thank you. I have a question for you.
I need your advice. My brother passed
away two weeks ago at 34 years old.
All right. This is kind of a fucked
up one to end on, but I'm gonna um,
needless to say, I'm crushed.
Sorry to hear that, man.
That's really a brutal solve my
condolences. Um, here's the issue.
My inlaws haven't said anything to
me. No phone call, no cards, nothing.
I'm devastated. You would think
that them being parents themselves,
um, that they may care about me
since I am married to their daughter.
Um, they will, they would have said
something. Um, they didn't say anything.
I don't really want anything
to do with them now.
I relationship was fine before this
as good as you can be within laws.
I'm just not feeling
much like seeing them.
It hasn't come up yet with my wife,
but she is really close with them
and likes for us to go over, um,
likes to go over there to hang out.
What should I do?
Should I just drop it and pretend like
they couldn't have cared less that my
brother died or do I stand my ground and
fuse to go over to any functions until
I hear something? Obviously the latter
choice would cause friction at home.
I'm the first choice would kill me
inside the one being to go over there.
What do you think? Uh, you know
what this podcast is? This,
it should just be,
Bill just talks about shit that he's not
qualified to talk about. Okay. And uh,
that includes all that banking stuff.
Even though I know on my gut level,
somewhere in there I'm right.
Um,
okay.
All right. My Gut is telling me, uh,
You're obviously, you're,
you're angry right now and uh,
you have to go through that stuff.
I think the move here is it's a bad move.
Okay.
To, um, you know,
basically you going to be married to
your wife for the rest of your life.
You don't need the fucking not getting
along with the in laws to make it a
miserable situation. Um, I don't
know anything about your in laws.
I don't know if they're not
good with emotions. I don't
know if they're like, he,
I don't know what to say. I mean, I
don't know how old they are. I mean,
a lot of these people who come from
the pre Oprah fucking Winfrey show,
especially guys and a lot of
women, they don't, you know,
they don't know how to express shit
like the, when stuff like this comes up,
they don't know what to do.
So the move is right now is you have to
talk to your wife and you have to tell
her how devastated you are that your
in laws haven't expressed any sort of
condolences.
And you have to tell her that it's making
you not want to do anything with them
ever again.
And just say that you're putting it.
You really have to communicate that to
your wife because what you're doing right
now is you're already gone
through something devastating
and you could possibly,
through your grief,
make your own personal life,
which I'm guessing was happy up to this
point. Even worse because you're gonna,
you're gonna push away your in laws and
then push away your wife at the same
time. So what you have to do, you
have to go to her and in a calm way,
just tell how hurt you are that they
didn't, that they didn't. Um, they didn't,
you know, send a car to flowers or
anything like that. Um, some ways I know,
ask somebody about this.
And they actually brought up a
great point that they had some,
a friend of theirs pass away and there
was so many flowers at the funeral and
people were coming up going,
hey, did you get the flowers?
Did you get the flowers I sent? And it's
like, you know, they're dealing with,
you know, the, the funeral stuff
that they got to take care of,
picking out the coffin and all that
awful stuff so they don't get a chance to
look at all the flowers. So for all, you
know, they might've sent some flowers.
So the first, Oh, there you go
dude. There's your jump off point.
You have to say to your wife that, listen,
I need to talk to you about something.
And you just say, obviously you know
what happened. And as far as I know,
uh, you know, has your,
have your parents sent a card or
any flowers that I didn't get?
Let her answer that.
And if she says she doesn't know,
then that's when you go
and say, look, you know,
obviously this is a big thing to me.
And they haven't expressed any condolences
and this is making me want to do x, y,
and z. That's how you do it.
So just use the jump off point,
you know,
with that question,
that's something I've learned in my
life was shit a lot less devastating,
which is basically the first thing you
do is you have to find out if what you're
thinking is correct before you go off
on somebody. Going off is step two.
All right? I can't tell you how many times
in my life someone comes up and says,
hey,
so and so says this,
and then I just take that as law rather
than going up to the person going, hey,
you know, I'm not saying
you did this, but somebody,
somebody saying that you said this shit,
and then you're supposed to do
it that way rather than just
flipping out.
Because
if you flip out and they actually
sent flowers, you're, you're,
you're really going to look bad and then
you made already a, a brutal situation.
Even worse. Alright, there you go.
I'm done. Babylon for a week. Dude,
I'm sorry to hear about [inaudible]
your loss. I hope, uh, you know, I hope,
I hope shit works out for you with your
in laws and all that type of stuff.
All right. Ah, that's a devastating way to
end this podcast. And it's over an hour.
These things are getting
way too fucking long.
And I apologize for all my babbling
this weekend. Yes, I know. I am a moron.
So I would love to hear from all
you economic majors out there.
MMM.
Or someone who is even in banking.
Please. Somebody for the love of God.
If you're in banking, please defend
it because I got to tell you,
I'm not one of these psycho conspiracy
theorists who thinks he's 100% right.
I want to be fucking
wrong on all of this shit.
I want to be wrong on the
automated cashier things.
I want to be wrong and all I want to
say that they're actually sitting there
going,
how can we make less money and pass
savings on to the fucking customer?
How come I yacht be smaller?
All right, that's it. Um,
I should like, I should have lost
a lot of credibility on that one.
I really stammered my way through that
banking thing and I'd be lying to you if
I wasn't embarrassed. All right. And then
is it, that is a podcast for this week.
Thanks for listening everybody.
I'm gonna try to get the bandwidth up
so more people can enjoy my completely
uninformed
means every week. Alright. God bless you,
boss.
Yeah.