Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr and
it's time for the Monday morning part. No,
it isn't it. What am I talking about? It's
time for the Thursday afternoon. Friday,
just before Friday.
Fucking Monday morning podcast.
Just checking. Oh, Narnia. What's
going on? You're like, dad,
that was a little siren version for you.
You know,
it's the little things that make your day.
Um, all right. How's it going? I haven't
done shit. Why does it sound weird?
People are going to trash me again.
Sorry about last week because a on Monday
I didn't have it plugged in all the
way and it came out like a
fucking 1940s Benny Goodman.
It wasn't a stereo is what I'm
trying to say. There was no stereo,
no stereo for you. But look at Thursday,
Huh? Oh, you know, it was, I was,
it was a metaphor.
It was a metaphor for a Monday.
You know what I mean? That everything
just seems bleak and there's no way to go,
you know? So you don't get
stereo on Monday on Thursday,
right. Why? What happened?
What do you have on Thursday? What do you
got? Uh, you got your fucking paycheck.
He got money in hand. You can see
the light at the end of the tunnel.
That broad came in
wearing that little outfit
fit your Dick's going dough,
cheese wearing it for yo man.
She's wearing it for you and make a move.
Right?
So you get Stereo Stereo on Thursdays.
Sorry, this still sounds like
I'm inside of a fucking 10 can.
And I know a lot of guys are saying,
well bill, why don't you get a producer?
And I just say,
why don't you go fuck yourself?
I don't do this to have a job. I turned
it on. I do the best I can. All right.
You know,
most of you guys are probably not even
saying this and I'm just yelling at you.
I don't know why I'm yelling at you.
I'm on fucking vacation.
I'm psyched. It's two 30 out here in
la, which means in an hour and a half,
uh, I'm going to watch my Boston Bruins
take on the Minnesota north stars or the
wild as the kids call them
after we fucking lost a San
Jose. We're just, we just,
you know what it is? It's like we play
one period and you're like, you know what?
They could be as 16 and then the next
period. Yeah. I don't know what happens.
It's just up and down and it's
frustrating. But, uh, I'm still,
I know the fuck.
I'm going to watch them.
I think they're going to turn it around
called Julian's too good at coach.
We've got too many pieces
leftover from our Stanley Cup.
They're going to whip these guys into
shape or they're going to fucking dig.
Going to send a few people
a next thing you know,
freckles here might get to try out. I
could be a good grinder on a fourth line.
Right?
Get out there on the penny penalty kill
skate nor all around my face is red as a
fucking tomato. I do it. Um, yeah,
I don't think you could do
that. Uh, who the fuck does a,
who the fuck is on a
Minnesota is where they get it?
They got Zach per Reezy who's on their
lines. You know who's at first line?
Who says second line? Oh, that's right.
I'll go to fucking daily face off.com.
You know these kinds of, to throw me
a fucking hot dog or something, man.
I hype the shit out of this. Where
am I going here? Minnesota wild.
You Click right there and then all of
a sudden the lines are looking at him
right there. Thomas Vanek, the
former fucking save. All right.
Did he go to the islanders and that
fuck another trade or something?
I don't know any of these guys.
Mikael Granlund. Jason Palmerville.
Okay,
Jason. Hey, wait a minute.
Where's Zack for easy. Did
you get traded? Is he injured?
Is He, he is nice. I don't
wish ill will on anybody.
I hope we just twisted his fuck.
Maybe he's got a hangnail you don't.
Every time he puts his gloves
on it hurts and he goes, oh
yeah,
try it again, Zach. Oh, ah. You Know
Jack, you could shut it out tonight.
Maybe we'll get a win.
Oh, look at that guy.
The fucking right wing on
the second line. NATO. NATO.
NATO Renner.
Yeah.
Yeah. Jason. Um, anyways, let's get
skip back to the podcast here. So, uh,
I have been not doing shit. I slept
for like two straight fucking days.
It's all I did.
I put on my old PJ's all Billy PJ's,
I didn't do fucking shit for two days.
I haven't drank, I haven't smoked.
I haven't left the fucking
house other than a walk my dog
and I'm still exhausted. I think
that last, uh, the last, you know,
you go hard for a month, people,
you know, when you're 47 and,
and basically a half, if I can
say my age, like a little kid,
I'm 47 and five months, um, you know,
and your drink every night for like
a month straight essentially. Uh,
yeah, that's going to do some
damage. So, uh, I figured, you know,
I beat the shit out of
my body for 30 days,
balance it out by taking four days off.
That math works out in my world.
Um, speaking of which
two, do you know what,
somebody sent me this
book and I'm only in,
I read the foreword and um,
into the first chapter and if
you're into standup comedy, um,
this book so far, it seems unfucking
believable. It's called the Comedians,
um, drunks, thieves, scoundrels,
and the history of
American comedy by cliffK ,
l I.
P h nest or off.
And I have to tell you already,
I'm absolutely blown away by just
the stories from the Vaudeville days.
And even like in the middle of the book
when I'm looking at these pictures of
some of these comics that
I never heard of. Um,
uh,
what the fuck is this guy?
There was a guy in like 1962 we used to
be like a blueberry bluegrass musician
and he became a standup comedian. And he
did this album called the first family,
uh,
1962 von meter.
I hope I'm saying his name had the highest
selling comedy record of all time up
until 1962. And I'm assuming doing
his impression of President Kennedy,
all right. When the president
was assassinated, uh,
meter plunged into a meltdown,
a mental breakdown. By the way,
there's a typo on this,
said Vietor Vaughn Meader,
they call them Vietor and the
next line. Um, but anyways, yeah.
So he was crushing it,
doing this Kennedy impression,
and then Kennedy gets whacked and he's
completely fucked. And uh, in fact,
I wrote,
there's another story in here would
that night I kind of just blew the joke,
but a Lenny Bruce did not cancel the show.
Most people did reminded me in
nine 11 while they just sort of,
there was no comedy shows for about
three, four days. Uh, but nobody, uh,
I guess the cancer all comedy shows,
but Lenny Bruce did is any way and uh,
walked on stage, very solemn and
kind of look down at the ground.
The crowd was all quiet and he
just looked up and was like, man,
von meters fucked.
Never dealt what he was.
I felt bad for the guy.
1962, he was riding high. 63.
The guy does the impression
of gets whacked. 1965,
he's broke flat, fucking broke, can't get
a God damn job by the early seventies.
He's back in Maine singing
bluegrass music. Once again,
the name of the book is
the Comedians by cliff k.
L. I. P. H. Nesteroff, n e. S t like nest.
Like what a bird sits in till it
gets booted out by its mother nest.
He are off. Um, two F's.
Okay. It's not, it's not
Nesterov it's an SRF, but uh,
it seems great so far.
And um,
okay.
Is already just looking at the pictures.
I didn't know Joan Rivers was,
was not in a comedy team.
She was in a comedy almost troop with
two other fucking guys and she lasted six
months with them before. She's just
like, yeah, fuck this. I'm out. I'm so,
I can't wait to read the rest of that. But
anyways, I have not been doing shit. Um,
I just went over and I did a, I had
a voiceover for a, uh, for a TV show,
which is cool man. You know, uh,
did that in the morning and
then I was going to go over
okay
and do something productive and ended
up being in a part of the city where
somebody show me where
there was a good bargain.
I got the Burger and then down the street
there was this place where you get an
ice cream sandwich that has a fucking
that instead of having the sandwich part,
it's actually a donut. I know what
you think it built Jesus Christ,
what are you doing? And it's like, I'm
on the rails and I'm off the rails.
I ate perfectly the last three days
I was over in that part of the city.
My wife was there. She always knows
every good place to eat. I folded.
I just wanted her to know that I knew
were some places where a to, you know,
and we'd already gotten into a fight.
We had a brutal fight today.
She fucking screamed at me and I didn't
say anything because she was right.
What happened was, was I was in bumper
to bumper traffic out here, right?
So we got a green light,
but I can't get across the
intersection without blocking it.
So I'm waiting for the people
to pull up as the light screen.
So I hit this guy behind me,
beep.
Then all of a sudden he tries
to pass me on the right,
like he's just going to go around me
like I'm some sort of bitch, right?
So I step on the gas if my Prius
and we fucking drive up and he's trying
to cut in and I fucking cut this guy off.
He came within a coat of
paint of hitting us, right?
But I fucking boxed him out between me
and the parked car and he had to give in.
So now we're just parallel.
Nia screamed like, oh,
like a person who was not driving the car
and was sitting in the passenger seat,
right.
Fucking screamed.
And initially she starts yelling at
the guy and I'm yelling at the guy.
He puts the window down. I'm like, dude,
what the fuck is wrong? He was a boy.
Fuck you still blew the
fucking greenlight. I'm like,
there's no fucking Ramis.
He's like, blah, blah, blah, knees
screaming at him. And then I go, dude,
you're a fucking psycho point in my own
head. You ever fucking psycho? He goes,
you're a fucking psycho too. Now
looking back, I should have been like I,
it's a decent point,
but you know, I wasn't,
I wasn't in psycho move until you did
that Mad Max shit. You fucking cunt.
And then this is what kills me.
Nia rolls the window up and then the
fucking guy goes around me on the left.
This time it makes a left and leaves.
So that's the end for him.
Now Nia is just sitting there like shaking
with their arms crossed and I'm like,
Oh fuck, here we go. And I just saw, I'm
trying to be funny about it and I'm like,
Hey Nia, great job. You
really gave that guy hell.
And,
and then she just fucking
staring ahead and I'm like,
I might get you mad at me. And
she just screamed like, Hey,
all of us at this side of the
car that's site that I was on,
like freaking out. And I
was just like, yeah, Jesus.
And then I wanted to apologize and I
started thinking about Johnny Roast beef
and good fellas.
You know when he bites the pink Cadillac,
you know,
it's fucking Jimmy's going,
what's the matter with you?
What's the matter if you and
just keeps going. Sorry, it's,
it's in my grandmother's name. Like I,
I just kept picturing as dumped face.
Unfortunate.
She didn't look at me cause I had a smirk
on my face because that's what I felt
like could she goes, she was a
hundred percent right. So, uh,
like a good 10 miles of
silence in stop and go traffic.
So that's the equivalent of like 40 miles.
If I didn't live in such an overcrowded
city and she's just like, you know,
she,
her face,
she has like three different levels of
mad and she was at like the top level of
Matt and I kept looking over,
you know,
her bottom lift was still
stuck out like a, you know,
she laid a little dog that was mad.
You know,
he's a little brother right before he
cries, you're like, is he going to cry?
You're going to punch me in the head.
You know when you do that,
when you push it a little brother
too far, he like, he's eating,
they start swinging and I start crying.
I Dunno.
Might want to lean back a little bit.
Get the arms up right.
She had that look on her face and the
next time I looked over it was just an
angry face and then I looked over again,
then our arms would just crossed.
So I know at that point that you
can actually talk to her. So I, uh,
I try to cute my way out
of it. I said, listen,
okay,
you were 100% right. She goes,
that's right. I was, I go,
all right, let me rephrase
that. You are 110% right.
And she gave me shit back again. And I
said, all right, look, you are 120% right.
And that's my final offer. All right,
got a little bit of a smile out of it,
but she was fucking mad
at me. Uh, I don't know.
Then I tried to turn it around on her,
tried to say like,
that's why I'm successful, because I
don't take shit from other people. Like,
like that's a situation that you,
you,
you need to take shit and just let the
fucking maniac go. Who gives a shit bill?
Why do you give a fuck?
Why do you immediately go into like,
like a lunatic mode?
And I was actually thinking
about it when I was driving home,
how my wife's energy is so much
more chill than mine. And I'm like,
am I just like,
like a car engine that just idles
higher and I can't fucking, you know,
I'm just burning through the tank of
gas or do I wake up in the morning chill
like she does and I just don't
let life affect me. No one I let,
she doesn't let life affect
her the way it affects me.
And I actually think it's a,
I think it's a little more,
the second one. I think I just
need to fucking relax a little bit.
What the fuck is wrong with
me? I'm yelling at the guy.
You're a fucking psycho.
You're in for,
what do I draw?
I know that guy knows all that Jujitsu
shit singing now he's got me down.
You know, he's passed my guard.
I'm laying on the street, you know.
Oh.
So my Prius goes into gear and it runs
over my wrist and snaps my watchband but
doesn't break any bones cause it's a
Prius. Right. Fuck is wrong with me.
So it was like a perfect day.
I'm on vacation.
She was loving that I was relaxed and
all of that. And within two seconds,
one cunt fucked up my whole day.
And what was really making me
laugh was that guy was by himself.
So the second he went around me and
made the left, it was over. He left.
And then there I was getting yelled at
by my wife for the next fucking 10 miles.
And I was kind of laughed to myself.
God on son of a bitch.
One I thought I won one. I, he didn't get
in. I thought I won. I didn't. It did.
And I won the first round. Then
got the old right there, Fred,
when I went to the judges.
Right. So it's fucking pathetic.
Um, anyways, what a Dick. I
didn't think it was him like,
cause he had like this foreign car,
but it had like an American car sounding
horn. So I didn't think it was him.
So I was off my game and he almost
got around me. I don't know.
It's probably stupid, right? Oh fuck
you. You, you don't make mistakes.
We all make mistakes. Ooh. All right.
Let's read a little
advertising here for this week.
Um, let's see here. Uh,
blue apron, everybody.
Oh, flowy blue apron. You
need to know how to cook.
Not only do you feel like you know
your way around a kitchen, uh,
but cooking at home means eating healthier
and saving money instead of ordering
expensive takeout. Again. Yeah.
Nobody shuts you off at the Bra.
But where do you start? Blue Apron has
you covered for less than $10 per meal.
Blue Apron delivers all the fresh
ingredients you need to create home cooked
meals. Just follow the easy
step by steps. Instructions. Uh,
each meal can be prepared
in 40 minutes or less.
No overwhelming trips to the
grocery store. No more sad takeout.
Uh,
no matter your dietary preferences,
Blue Apron makes it a breeze to discover
and prepare dishes like filets and fish
and chicken prepared all types of ways,
right in your own kitchen.
Coke with ingredients that you've never
used before. Like watermelon, radishes,
Pharaoh or Pharrell of Ferraro and purple
potatoes and recipes are between 500
to 700 calories proportion.
That's pretty good man.
And then he crushed waters for the
rest of the day. Rest of the evening.
Beautiful Save money. You don't got
to go out and you get a flat stomach.
Delicious and good for you.
Right now you can get your first two
meals for free at blue apron. Got Dotcom,
slash. Bird. That's blue apron.com/bar hi,
blue apron.com/birth it's a
better way to cook. All right,
Boll and branch.
Yeah,
ball and branch. B. O. L. L. A.
You probably spend more time with your
bedsheets than anything else you own.
You really shouldn't
skimp on your bedding,
but most people do because
great sheets are very expensive,
but thanks to bowl a ball,
a ball, l, l and branch.
That's not the case anymore.
And when you spend a big chunk,
big bucks on sheets with
a super high thread count,
you think you're getting the best,
but what you're really getting
is marketing Mumbo jumbo
thread count has nothing
to do with quality and don't get me
started on the so called Egyptian cotton
over there.
That's just the name of a plant grown
in Pakistan and China doesn't mean Shit.
All right,
the upbringing up Egyptian cotton,
listen,
you value sleep, right? Of course you do.
But whenever you had
to a department store,
you're forced to pay a huge markup for
sheets that aren't even that great.
Boll and branch sheets that different.
First of all,
you can only get them at Boland,
branch.com p o l l and branch.com so you
know you're paying for quality sheets
and that for overhead.
And quite frankly then the most
comfortable sheets in the world,
they're made from it.
The entirely organic from an with entirely
organic cotton in a nights sleeping
on boll and branch sheets.
Make sure day so much better.
Three US presidents slept and bang
mistresses on Boll and branch sheets.
These are people who can afford
asleep on any brand of sheets they
want. I Bet Marilyn Monroe
got fucked on a pair of these,
probably what she did.
Happy Birthday this to
president. All right. I, uh,
get over there when the boll and branch,
they even cut out the middleman
department store markups, which means,
which means, uh, by the way, up
to 800% that you're going to save.
So you get an amazing luxury. Okay?
We got it to get to the fucking India.
Bola branch is so confident.
You'll love the sheets. Uh,
they'll let you try him completely
risk free for 30 nights.
And then what? I don't like him. I send
it back. Then. What do you do with them?
Gross.
It's even better if you order right now.
They'll give you $50 off a set
of sheets plus free shipping.
Go the Boll and branch.com and use the
Promo Code [inaudible]. That's right.
Get $50 off a sheet set
immediately by going to be o, l,
L and B r a n c h.
Dot com and using the Promo
Code Burr Jesus Christ.
I could barely get through that.
Um,
I'll tell you what I didn't have a
problem getting through is over the last
couple of days when I wasn't sleeping,
um,
me and cleo watched all of season one
of peaky blinders and you have know
nothing about no robbery. Um,
what a fucking show that was.
Um, and by the way, if
you want to get into it,
I'm gonna let you know the first episode
and a half is a little slow because
it's setting up the story.
Also,
you got to go into captions and just have
English subtitles going the whole time.
It will really help you out because,
uh, you can't understand. I mean,
I can't understand a lot of what the
fuck they're saying. And then you,
you understand most of it
except for the last word.
And it's a completely
different, like, you know,
they say whore har effect can,
hi,
what? I mean I knew he was calling
her a whore because of the situation,
but he just said he just stuck his
face right now. Grilling just goes, hi
thought he's a pirate,
like error every meeting now he's calling
her effect affecting higher get second
hire. Um, alright. Which
one to use in charge?
They'll be oldest.
Roy,
I can say that you making
fun of me brother. Right?
So he's the oldest and you're the
thickest so you must be in charge.
They got lines like that and it's
just, it's fucking great. Um,
I watched all of the first season and
now I'm going to binge watch the next
season as I read this book on comedy
because I am on fucking vacation.
I'm not playing drums. I'm not flying
helicopters. I'm not doing shows.
I'm not doing shit.
All right.
I'm trying to eat right and
working out a little bit,
but I'm just laying in my fucking bed.
Like that fucking dude with the spruce
goose plane. What the fuck was his name?
Howard Hughes.
All right.
That's all Billy booze is laying here
like Howard Hughes until I feel like
getting up again.
I ain't doing the Bruins.
Come on and an hour and 12 minutes.
I'm watching those fuckers.
I got Thursday night football.
I'm sitting here with my dog,
it's the fucking best. Um, best year
of my life. Best Year of stand up,
the best Gig I could have possibly. And I
did on, I'm still flying high over that.
It's just fucking perfect.
And it's getting to that time of
year out here in la where it's cold,
it starts to rain this,
the fucking air quality's way better.
It's not even the small og man because
the cars burnt so much cleaner nowadays.
It's, it's really just all the dust and
sand and dirt and fucking just, you know,
Shit from other human beings. It just
kinda gets settles down to the ground.
It's fucking does a snow cap
mountain out here that you can,
you can't see most of the year
it starts to come out. You know,
people start going home for the holidays
to city becomes more of the level of
population it should be. It's
just fucking great. And um,
yeah, nothing but nothing but good.
Uh, good thoughts that I mentioned.
I'm going to go see the king's hawks game.
November 28 it staples center.
I mean, to me, I feel like in
a hockey way that's like a,
it's kind of like back
in the day when the 70s,
when the Steelers and cowboys
played where you just like,
how many hall of famers are in this
fucking game? Um, although the hawks,
I don't know why they let so many people
go, but Teva is going to make it right.
Patrick Kane is going to make
it get at least two over there.
Okay.
Fucking, uh, my quick is gonna make
it, what the fuck is that guy's name?
It looks like Dave Grohl to
doubt he's gonna make it. I mean,
it's just a bunch of, you know, who
knows? Maybe Copa Tar, I don't know.
So you get the numbers. I'm not good at
that shit. I just know like these are,
these are the two, fuck,
these are two fucking teams.
As much as the Canadians are playing well,
and I want to watch them on the package
because I don't even know what's a
Canadian. And I like
watching great hockey. Uh,
they're in the east so I would watch the,
the,
the habs if they played the hawks are
the kings of the stars or somebody out
there, um, on the west. Cause I just
still think it's all about the west.
I just, I fucking bastards. They, they'd
been dominating forever. Yeah. So I'm,
I'm gonna I'm going to
check that game out. Uh,
Steph Curry's come into town tonight.
I'm going to watch him. You know,
it was cool.
Kevin Durant's said he's the greatest
shooter of all time and that sounds like a
Versie thing. Like how he says that so
early on. But I got to tell you, uh,
I don't disagree like this is the one
time where I'm like, he's he dude,
this guy's, he's doing shit. Like he
seemed like the Harlem Globe trotters,
but he's fucking doing it in a real
game. He's unbelievable. And a,
that's on my bucket list to see him live.
I can't go to the game tonight, but, uh,
I definitely want to see him
like when he plays the Lakers,
cause I feel like Colby is going to dig
down deep and try to have another one of
his back in the day games, you know. Um,
but it's unreal. So
anyways, uh, not boozing,
not smoking any cigars and a rest and up.
So it's not too hard not to for me.
It's not that hard to just quit booze and,
and smoking, uh, when
I'm this tired. But, uh,
I got a feeling of,
you know,
there's a place down the fucking street
somebody told me about has got this
cognac that's like, I dunno.
I Dunno what happened.
Like fucking Louis the 14th get whacked
in the back of the head and his fucking
cognac slid down his sock and into a
fucking hole and somebody found anyway,
somebody got a bottle
of this shit. So, uh,
I'm already thinking I got to go
down to try. What are you doing bill?
The fuck are you doing? What's, what's,
what's, what's wrong with you? Um,
but anyways, I'm not doing any
standard. I'm not doing shit,
so I really don't have anything
to fucking talk about. Oh,
did you guys see that fucking Guy School?
Those two people on uh,
on, uh, he schooled me too by
the way on my saying schools,
I'm not too fucking old to say that.
Um,
made some great points that the people
on CNN could not refute when he was
talking about people who are just blaming
the Muslim religion for terrorism.
Like everybody there,
everyone who's a Muslim wants to fucking
mutilate women and do all this fucking
shit.
This guy was just strong.
Yeah.
These two people on CNN and what blew my
mind is in a lot of ways the people on
CNN when it came to the Muslim religion
where justice uninformed as I am in a
lot of ways,
like a,
okay.
You know, when they were talking about
those mutilating women shit, hey,
the guy's just going like, yeah,
that happens in this country,
in this like Sudan as see named like
two African countries and they're like,
yeah, that was a Muslim countries.
He goes, no, they're not.
They're Christian countries.
And he really just broke it down
where it's not the religion,
it's depending on what country they
would trash and like Turkey or something
like kind of lump them in and he goes,
no, they don't do that in Turkey.
They don't mutilate women and Turkey.
They actually,
there's women rights and they've elected
more women to positions of political
power, you know, intelligent
and informed, logical,
like thought as opposed to these
morons that think that they're tough.
Who Go, we'd go to fuck, wipe them all
out to go to fucking kill everybody.
Fucking,
if you folk religion,
you use fucking chill like
dead dumb shit that they,
that what's kills me is
that CNN is starting to come
around too and just be like,
yeah, this is like a violent religion
and all that. Yeah. Look, look at the,
what kills me,
what fucking kills me,
especially with Christians is the lack of
honesty with your own fucking religion.
Are you really gonna fucking sit there?
Okay.
Cause if you're going to indict these
people because of their religion,
then I could go with you as
far as if you say all religion,
eventually you're going to have some wing
nuts that it's going to cause them to
do some fucking shit.
You know what I mean?
You can't as a fucking Krish,
especially a Catholic. I should,
I'll just speak for my religion here.
There's fucking
rap sheet.
You know when they fucking,
whenever you watch like an Nyp de blue
or one of those built toto toto shows and
they always, there's always
that guy. He's got a rap sheet,
a mile long armed robbery,
fucking assault battery,
you know,
twisted park and meters off and spending
the change that are an arcade as kids
spend more days in jail that he has out.
That's my religion.
That's my fucking religion. Where
the inquisition, we had the crusades,
we were in bed with the Nazis,
do you know, Jewish people.
And they were trying to track where the
fuck they have debt property went to.
I ended up at the Vatican and
we're like, Oh, oh is that yours?
Oh, sorry. Uh, we will, you know,
we didn't know what was going to win.
So, you know, we kinda had a, you know,
fucking get in bed with Paul
people and uh, sorry about that.
Pedophilia torture. I mean,
just horrible shit. Torture,
genocide, you name it, you name it,
go right down the whole
fucking commandments.
They've broken every fucking one of them.
And uh,
see that,
what does that and that right there
is the kind of thing that makes me a
question, the validity of an
afterlife and being judged.
Okay. Cause that's what they're
peddling, but their actions,
they're not worried about
judgment on any fucking level.
So it makes me think that,
you know,
well maybe we just go
into the ground and we,
we decompose and we,
we give life to something else.
You know what I mean? But they
created this mommy and daddy thing,
you know,
either going to get an ice cream or get
a spanking to keep everybody in fucking
line.
And then maybe they know it's bullshit.
Like maybe when you get high enough in
the church, they just go, all right.
They close the door,
you know,
and they're sitting there and that stupid
getups right. And the guy just goes,
look,
here's something you need to know.
You can't tell anybody or will deny it
and we'll kill everybody that you know
and that you're related to. All
right, here's the real deal.
He looks left, he looks
right. It looks back at him.
He shrugs his shoulders and he just goes,
we made it all up.
Yeah. Yeah. We just made it up. Not being
good or bad, you know, being good, bad.
Again, it makes sense. It's the
moral compass you're born with,
but the whole afterlife is, and we
have no proof. We, we have no idea.
Yeah. Jesus. Yeah. I mean, he lived
by the, you know, we kind of, Eh, we,
we hyped it up a little, kind
of oversold it. You know,
maybe you didn't walk on water maybe.
Yeah.
Maybe waded into it a little bit and
was the first guy to do the butterfly
stroke or the backstroke maybe kinda which
back then, no one ever done that. No.
We thought to be on their back when
they swam. So that was equivalent to
walking on water and they didn't
have leprosy. They just had a,
they sat a rash and it just sort of
cleared up naturally anyways, but I,
they did talk to him, you know,
so whatever. But you know,
it's also why I don't watch the news. I
actually love, that's why I love Facebook.
I'm an old white guy.
I love Facebook.
I love going on it and just click it on
the fucking videos and I'll try to get a
link out of just don't know how to copy
and paste that ship out of that guy.
I'm just totally fucking
just making sense and not
demonizing everybody over there.
Whenever they start talking like that,
I swear to God, that's just like the,
it's unbelievably ignorant and all that
is, that's just big business talking,
you know, they're all evil or
getting the machine going there.
I'll ilow he got to fucking do all this
shit and spent all his fucking money and
then we'll make a ton of money.
And when the tab comes along
with giving it to you guys. Yeah,
go fuck yourself. I'm sorry.
That's just my own view by the way.
We F is for family trailer is out.
And a thank you everybody
who retweeted it.
We got over a million views
between Facebook and youtube. Uh,
tremendous positive response to it.
I'm very,
very excited and um,
my phone is going fucking nuts here.
What's going on here?
Um, Oh, you know what?
I got another, uh, I got an, I'm actually
gonna post a clip here to my Twitter.
A Cup. Sorry. I got the hiccups.
Unless it happens to when you have burgers
and a fucking ice cream sandwich at
jerk. Um, I'm actually going to
tweet this out right now. Uh,
it's a video of just
showing frank that get the,
the character's face and I'm doing the
voice for which is an amalgam of my dad
and everybody's dad in the writer's room
and they have some of the outtakes of
some of the shit I said. So, uh, I'm going
to post that today. Um, oh, and also,
oh my God,
I almost forgot the Patrice O'neil,
the fourth annual Patrice
O'Neal comedy benefit. Uh,
the benefit is surviving family members
and also to keep the name alive of the
greatest standup comic I ever saw live.
And I'm not understating it at all.
It's going to be Tuesday,
January 26th,
all the proceeds other than what we have
to pay out to rent the fucking building,
which isn't that bad.
Everything else goes to his, uh,
to his loved ones. And, uh, it's been a
tremendous, tremendous success every year.
And it's become like this
high school reunion and we
got some new blood in there.
We got the classics. Uh, you know, David
tells going to be there at Jim Norton.
Rich Vos has always will be hosting.
And uh,
we got Russ minivan who's a great friend
to Patrice hilarious comic and uh,
uh, they will forever writing
scripts, trying to get it.
Patrice has voice on TV and uh,
Godfrey's going to be on there.
I'm already lang.
It's going to be there this year
that's going to be fucking sick. Um,
I will be down there and uh, I know
Rachel Feinstein is going to be there.
Who else?
I'm the worst.
I should have had all that information
out in front and I'll have it for you on
Monday, but, uh, tickets are on
sale now. Um, I tweeted it out.
I Facebook the whole fucking thing.
I'll, I'll do it again. But um,
it's going to be Tuesday,
January 26th, and uh,
it's going to be a wonderful night
as always. So, uh, thank you guys.
Do everybody's already bought tickets
were already almost halfway sold out and
the GIG isn't for
another couple of months,
so get your tickets now while
you still can. And that is it.
That's it for the Thursday
afternoon podcast. God bless Ya. Uh,
have a great weekend,
your country.
And he's a little bit of music that I
don't know what it's going to be and I'm
not the guy who picks it out and you know
I did because it's not arena rock from
the 1980s. Um, I am the worst.
I'm like 15 years behind in music.
You know,
I know a little bit of this
shit just cause, cause I'm
okay.
You know, cause I ride them around
with me every once in a while.
Okay.
I know
Dec and only me one thing, right?
So if there's something Yo yo,
Yo, that guy call you on yourself. Uh,
[inaudible] uh,
um,
I do like the drums on that
because I'm a drum nerve. Right.
Goes fucking 16th of 30 seconds to 68th
note triplets on the high hat while they
keep the fucking groove the same or you
think I'm not going to go fuck with that
my pajamas.
Yeah.
Well it make me a better person. I don't
know. All right. Have a great weekend.
You can't sell.
Talk to you right
Monday.
Huh? Maybe to go holiday shopping with
all these fucking maniacs and get pepper
sprayed. Cause I'm trying to buy
a juicer. You know I haven't,
I don't have one ounce of fucking
sympathy for any fucking idiot out there.
I don't give a fuck about your
financial goddamn position.
Go make a popsicle stick
house. Okay? Don't fucking go
down to Walmart and sit there with your
God damn fucking big gulps face pressed
against the glass trying to run down
a fucking an aisle with foreign other,
the crazed maniacs trying to get a
waffle iron. The fuck is wrong with you.
Walk in there like a gentlemen.
All right,
go in there some other time
when it's not fucking mayhem.
It, why don't you do this? Pay
Full price and buy less shit.
Why don't you do that? You know, or
well, let me guess. Is this incidence?
Oh, I'm about to people that don't
have any money. Well then you've just
shit how you know you don't want.
The fastest fucking way to still having
no money is to go down to a fucking
department store and buy a ton of shit.
These people that they're there,
they're fucking idiots. You know?
I'm not saying that they weren't blessed
that they didn't get some gifts from a
high up.
I'm not saying that.
I'm not saying that some of them can't
sing a song, can't do a dance, uh,
can't fix a fucking motor.
I'm not saying that.
This is why I'm saying you're a fucking
idiot because you're buying into the
hype the same way.
Those stupid fucking nerd cons buy
into this fucking I whatever I pad,
Ipod, the new iPhone,
every fucking God, damn,
six months they get themselves all worked
up into this fucking frenzy and they
go on the website trying to sell.
How many are there?
How many of there it's,
it's completely,
it's false panic.
It's manmade. I swear to God. You
know what kills me is Walmart has,
has an, I have not been able
to find their reaction, um,
to basically, I mean,
aren't they in a sales way?
Screaming fire in a crowded movie theater.
Isn't this what I mean?
Every fucking year I remember
this security guard got trampled.
He had a fucking heart attack guy died
because somebody is trying to go down and
buy a fucking he man doll for half price,
you know,
so somebody can pop the head off and
have a toddler get it lodged in their
throat. These are all facts.
People, all this shit's happened.
Alright. Porter ranch. Where
the fuck is porter ranch?
That just sounds like the one of
those, none of those states, right?
Just a good old boy,
mayor.
Meaning no harm.
Went down to the Walmart to get some
fucking chaps and his shadow on our man.
Gotten his challenger and
Lily fucking drove away.
What the fuck is it? I lost it. Woman
pepper sprayed porter ranch. All right.
Porter ranch.
Uh,
would you like balsamic vinegar Grad
or would you like the porter ranch?
Here we go. Uh, Yukon Porter ranch.
Now that's fucking Los Angeles.
Get the fuck outta here is in a fluid
neighborhood and the northwest region of
the San Fernando Valley. See, look at
me getting exposed for the moron. I am.
That's even worse.
You know,
I refuse to believe that rich people went
down to a fucking Walmart with pepper
spray.
I'm not buying this one.
Have they seen the lady
who did it anyways?
People stop buying into this fucking crap.
You know,
take some power back in your own life.
You know what you should do
on Black Friday? Stay home.
Saint Patrick's Day. A bunch
of poop morons going out,
drinking their faces off,
being loud,
the green allegate as in these stupid
songs with plastic hats and they heads and
eventually they're either going to punch
you in the face or throw up on your
shoes. Stay home like a
fucking gentlemen. Go Out,
go down to the liquor store,
get yourself a nice bottle of Scotch,
have a few friends come over, you know,
make you corn, beef sandwiches there,
you know, and then watch
some fucking Irish mob movie.
Go Watch state of grace of some shit.
I don't fucking know. But you know,
go down there for that horse shit.
You don't go out on Valentine's,
go on a Valentine's,
go get yourself Sushi that's been
marked up 300% go fuck yourself.
You go out on the 15th I can't say
I love you on that day. You know,
independent thought people
on a very low level.
I'm not reinventing the wheel.
I'm just realizing there's other days in
the year where you can go and walk into
a store and buy a fucking Flowbee without,
they'll get run through with the
fucking swifter mop handle. Ah,
US just should have said swifter.
There's a lesson in comedy without
getting run through by a fucking swifter.
That would have been funny,
but I was,
I've got run through whether
it's swift or mop handle.
It's like I was in a band and I
stopped fucking late. Oh, Jesus.
Oh Jesus. Bill, you can't even say
it funny. Let's read about this.
Porter ranch. All right. Porter ranch,
the woman accused of shooting pepper
sprayed other customers at a busy Walmart
store in Porter ranch,
injuring 20 was described by police.
Today is about five foot,
three inches tall between the ages of
30 to 38 with black hair and brown eyes.
A police do not have a description of
the vehicle. The woman was driving. Well,
I'd like to make a guess if I could.
Um,
I'm going to say she was driving
some sort of Chrysler vehicle,
probably some rusted out cab
forward designed, you know,
with one of the tail lights, you know,
the backup lights hanging down. Um,
Los Angeles police department.
Fucking detective said
detectives are actively
working on the case but are not expected
to receive surveillance video from
Walmart until early next week
because of technical glitches.
How hilarious is that?
Okay.
I bet if that bitch went in there and
rob the fucking store cleaned out all the
registers, how quickly to think Walmart
when it got that video over. Yeah.
You know we can,
we don't have technical glitches.
That's how fucking powerful Walmart is.
They just told the cops to stand down.
We'll get you the video when our
lawyers are dumb looking at it.
That's what the fuck that means.
The how much money we generate
for this community officer.
Huh?
I live in a gated community with my own
fucking private police force that has
better guns than yours.
We'll get you the video when we're
good and God damn fucking ready.
No wonder Walmart hasn't made a comment.
Okay.
You know,
they never used to have this shit when
I was a kid or at the very least it was
never reported. You know,
they'd start to have sales,
but it wasn't this fucking mania.
I'm an asshole.
I got to do that next year.
Next year I'm going to hire a camera crew,
okay.
And I'm going to go down there and I went
to just fucking start talking to these
people and ask him what is
all the excitement about?
What do you think is in there
that's gonna make your life better?
Huh?
What do you think's in there
and don't give you the sad sack fucking
story about how you got kids and it's
Christmas time. And if there's no
presence under the fucking tree,
what's going to happen? Gee, I don't know.
Okay.
Biggie small seed to make it work.
Didn't he?
He just rapped about being broke
and everyone related to it.
And then he made a soul, a bunch
albums, and then he got shot. All right.
That was a bad example.
Um,
look,
all I'm saying is this,
all right.
There's no reason.
You know,
you're probably thinking that
I'm trashing you for going.
I just don't want you,
I want you to just have
fucking respect for yourself.
Like those fucking idiots when they go
to a Goddamn game and they'll skip and
jackass has come out with the free
tee shirts and everybody reaching over
everybody.
Okay.
I just wish once I could just have some
sort of crowd mind control and as they
sat there, you know skipping
around with their eyebrows up
like ha ha,
do you want it?
Everybody just sort of sits there staring
back at them until it's so fucking
awkward.
They just have to throw it and then
it just sort of lands in the aisle and
nobody picks it up. Right.
Then of course the people,
the arenas like,
well someone's going to trip on that.
We're going to get sued and then they
got to send those skip and Jack asses to
go pick up all the tee shirts that nobody
wanted and then they're left with the
fucking truck load of them.
That's what I would like to see happen.
Shop trying to get me excited about
shit you at Walmart has in it.
It has a bunch of shit. What do
they really have in their bicycles?
Forming grills. Shack. It's rakes.
What else do they got?
Fucking DVD player. I mean,
you can't get one of those for
$9 on the Goddamn Internet.
Okay.
I Dunno.
I just think if you're in a financial
position where you have to risk being
trampled to death,
where you basically have to go to the
store version of the running of the Bulls
to get a God damn fucking,
I dunno.
Grilled cheese maker are running
out of dumb shit to talk about.
Okay.
Or a playstation or whatever the
fuck it is. If you have to do that,
you can't afford it. And if you
go out and buy the fucking thing,
he just sticking yourself
further behind the fucking rock.
Why don't you just have a couple of
light Christmases so then he can have a
better Christmas. You know, why don't
you do that instead of doing what?
All these fucking dump concent, that
real housewife wife show, do you know,
pay for that cash money. Those fucking
morons who do not understand money,
you know?
Oh, I'm on my soapbox this week. Okay.
Yeah.
Just live with nothing for awhile.
As long as you can fucking eat.
And you got plenty of water,
you find,
do you realize if you have
enough to eat and you have water,
do you realize that you're,
you're living better than probably a
third of the world just doing that,
having a place to take a shit,
having clothes on your back,
having toothpaste and toothbrush.
Do you understand how
fucking far ahead you are?
You don't need any of that shit.
And yes, it's nice to have,
but it's not worth going down there
in fallen down and having your wig fall
off or your fucking ass crack hanging
out.
All this shit that I've seen dislocate
and your knee having some poor bastard
trying to hold people back and has
a heart attack and he dies. Oh,
you saw som too small.
I need a competitive edge.
Let me go get some bear mace.
Okay.
Like do you want to stand like how
caught up into the fucking frenzy you are
that you make those goddamn decisions.
You know what? You need to be down there.
Just go down to a fucking,
uh,
Oscoe drug to those things still exist.
Whatever happened to the old
days, leach mayors. Remember that?
He's talking about that with some buddies
yesterday. Go down a leach mirrors.
What'd you go down to the lumber yard?
Go make some toys. Like a fucking else.
Yeah.
Anything.
Anything you know other than,
I mean, couldn't you just go like,
look, we don't have to say to your kids,
we don't have money for Christmas
this year. All right, we don't,
but I do have money. Take you to a ball
game. I'll take us all out to a ball game.
All right? It just know this. We're
going to have better Christmases,
but the most important thing is that
we're all together and we all love each
other and that we don't get trampled
by some hot dog eating jackass with a can.
A fucking bear mace.
It's more important to me
fucking showing up Christmas,
you know,
dressed up as Santa Claus
with a dislocated shoulder
and your fucking eyes are
all red. Oh, Ooh, don't hug.
Santa said hurts. Um, I don't know.
I'm sure I'm going to get some
fucking hate mail over this.
That was so insensitive to
people who don't have money.
I know they don't have money, but
they have fucking brains. Bill,
why do you always only have one TV?
Cause I live within my means,
which is why I don't go
down to black Friday.
Get trampled by some fucking big gulp.
Top of shit with a can of mace. All right.
Those people who got mace date
that that lady did them a favor.
Do you think any of those consequent
going to come back next Friday or next
black Friday? You think they're going
to come down there for that shit?
They're not. They got the
beat down. They deserved.
Which brings me to our one and
only youtube video of the week.
Did you guys see the,
the beat down and Mcdonald's with that
dude was standing there and these two
ladies came into the Mcdonald's.
It's the one right down there on uh,
uh,
you get off the west fourth street eat
train right there down in the village,
you know, two blocks over at Joe's pizza.
That's a good slice of pizza. All right,
right. Did you come out of there and spike
Lee's probably filming people playing
basketball and handball go,
well yo get your New York City right.
I trashed him on Twitter yesterday. He
was talking shit about my Boston Celtics,
you know,
so I,
I said something but I kept
at funny hoping that he
would still put me in one of
his movies,
you know,
and I could either play a complete nerdy
white guy who doesn't understand black
people or an over the top racist.
Um, anyways, I give a fuck,
get me in a movie, I'll do it.
So anyways, that Mcdonald's down there,
so these two ladies, they walk into the,
okay and they try and buy a goddamn
big Mac and a happy meal and they,
they, they throw a $50 bill
on the counter right there.
Major Red Flag.
Who the fuck pays for McDonald's with a
$50 bill who even has $50 and it's going
to go into Mcdonald's?
Nobody,
there's not been a $50 bill in Mcdonald's
since they started that fucking place.
So these ladies try to pass this 50 and
the guy behind the counter and he starts
looking at the 50 and he's like,
excuse me ladies,
I don't think that this is real.
So they go, listen motherfucker,
you better give us a God damn
fish fillet and uh, whatever,
quarter pounder with cheese and give us
a fucking change or we're going to fuck
you up. And he said, um, I don't think so.
And then this girl just
hauls off and slaps the guy,
slapped some and then the other one and
then she climbs up over the counter.
Now the other one just starts just really
slowly just walking around the counter
like, well I guess we got to fuck
this guy up. This is what we do.
And the guy backs up into the fryer later
area and I don't know where the fuck
he found this God damn lead pipe.
It was like a car.
Do you know like in the cartoons when
bugs bunny would just sorta, you know,
he'd be standing sideways,
you'd save a side view and he'd have a
problem and he would just turn it to it.
To the blind side and all of a sudden
he'd have a giant hammer and he hit Elmer
Fudd over their head. You'd be like,
where the fuck did that come from?
Was that leaning up against his right
rabbit leg? And I didn't see it.
How did Elmer Fudd not fucking see it?
How would that gigantic head of his,
how did he not view that as a threat?
This guy did the real life version
of that. He was backing up,
backing up and he was next to some French
fries and next thing you know he's got
this lead pipe.
Oh.
And he just fucking starts wearing
these girls out with it. Bam, Bam,
Bam. I got to give it up to those
girls. They took a good three,
four each and then they disappeared under
the counter and he just keeps fucking
hitting him. Bam, Bam, Bam.
And this lady's got what's
and he just keeps fucking going like a
fucking like this bitch is screaming.
It's like those little Doggie toys,
you know those little Doggie
toys that squeak that you know,
you make those little noises.
You know why dogs get so excited?
Cause it sounds like a
fucking animal dying.
It taps into their wild animal side.
So this bitch is thinking she's helping
shit. She should have been like,
excuse me, is that something you
really want to do instead? She's gone
and this guys, he just fucking,
he won't stop hitting him.
Will Not Stop fucking hitting him.
All right?
So you know the shit works.
Fucking two ladies attack guy.
It doesn't make a difference.
They can sit there and slap you
around like you're a fucking cartoon.
You're supposed to be like, they're
women. I need to respect them.
This guy said fuck that.
Fuck that.
And like bugs bunny turned to the side
and there was this magic lead pipe and he
fucking kicked the shit
out of both of them.
So of course he gets arrested for assault.
Um,
and I got to admit, I was
totally supporting what he
was doing through the first
three seven hits.
It's the last 19 then I'm just like,
all right. All right. Okay. Okay.
Neil was saying he actually was like that
dude and drive when he stomped at kids.
That guy's head in and the elevator,
he kind of went to that level,
but at the end of the day I'm like,
well,
that's why you don't go around slapping
people in the fucking face because they
might have gone to magician school and
they know how to magically have a fucking
goddamn lead pipe on a nowhere.
All right,
so this guy is going to trial and
I'm thinking there's no fucking way.
Then you find out this
dude actually has a record.
This guy went to jail for manslaughter,
all right?
And he got out and there's only two
places that you can get a job after you've
gone to jail for manslaughter.
You can either get into show business
or you can work at Mcdonald's,
all right? You can't get a
job at fucking Macy's there.
There is a glass ceiling when you
go to jail for fucking manslaughter.
That's it. Unless your dad owns a
company, you can get into sales.
You can sell somebody a
fucking piece of shit car,
but you're not selling a Mercedes.
You're going to be at a Sam's hot
car lot down the street, all right?
Reservoir dogs. Anybody.
That's why right there, okay.
Before even continue talking
about the story, that right there,
ladies and gentlemen,
is why you don't walk around slapping
perfect strangers in the face.
It's because you don't know
their backstory. You don't
know what they've done.
You don't know what
they're capable of doing.
This is a guy who already took somebody's
life and you're looking at him like,
oh, hey, what's up? Their
mic? French fry guy.
Take this 50 or I'm going
to slap the Shit Outta you.
And you don't realize that this
guy has been in fucking prison.
All right?
He probably knows how to turn that
piece of paper with Ulysses s grant.
He turned that into a fucking
shank. Somehow he figured
out how to fucking do it.
You know what I mean?
So these two ladies get an unbelievable
life lesson in why you can't walk around
acting like you're some
action hero in real life.
So anyway, so it goes trial and I
can't fucking believe it. I'm like,
there's no way this guy's not getting
convicted. He's fucking, he's a guy.
He beat down to women with a fucking pipe.
He went above and beyond with this
shit. And he's, he has a record.
It's fucking over right over.
He's not rich,
you know, it's over. This guy is going
to jail. I can't fucking believe it.
He got off,
the guy got acquitted.
So for once on the podcast,
I'm actually happy and
I can tell you this,
if they convicted him of a lesser
charge because he just kept hitting,
I wouldn't have been mad cause I would
have been like, dude, they were down,
they were fucking down and they were
down and then they were part of the tile
and you was still fucking hitting him.
Uh, we have this clip, by the way, um,
on the podcast page has now been
turned over the new fan page.
It's just bill bird.com. You
just go to my podcast page. Um,
and anyways, we'll have the video up
there and all that shit. So anyway, she,
um, he got off and they
charge the women was shit.
And I don't think that they're getting
off the property get lesser because there,
because they're women, you know
what I mean? And that's just,
women always get less
time, it seems, you know,
because at the end of the
day, the judge thinks, well,
maybe if I give him a little less time,
they'll come over here and blow me under
my robe. I don't know what the deal is.
I told you this story a few weeks ago
when I saw that this amazing trumpet
player, you know, and I was like,
man, I never heard of this guy.
And I find out he was murdered by his
fucking girlfriend in 1972 and she got out
of jail in 1978
okay.
I would go to jail longer for parking
tickets. Then she did for killing a guy,
shot him right up on the bandstand,
took out a gun and fucking shut this.
They had an argument.
She left,
she came back with the gun and she shot
this dude on the fucking band, Stan,
all these God damn witnesses.
And she did that in
[inaudible] 72 it was out by 78
so let's just say they, they, they
went, they flew through her trial,
set a right to trial.
She still only did five and a half years.
I Dunno. I Dunno how
that fucking works. Um,
and I bet she was able to forgive herself,
the fucking sociopath that she is and
she was able to go on and live her life
and then that guy is in the ground
cold is his God damn trumpet.
Yo
don't know
if vice for the week number one belt,
my wife and I
are both workout people, triathlons,
half marathons, et cetera.
You guys are going to get his and her
hip replacements and your fucking early
sixties, uh, last year we
started attending a class.
I'll do, this is fucked up.
I remember this one last year we started
attending a class to help with this,
uh, to help with this or are working out
and the instructors seemed like a good
shit. We got along great and he
works for the same company we do.
This is a huge company in,
I'm not going to say where,
so it's not like he sits next
to me or something. Anyway,
we really enjoyed this guy's class and
he would email all the people that took
the class regularly, telling them what
they needed for that day's class weights,
uh, Matt, jump rope, et
cetera. It's P90x oriented. Uh,
since we were both on the mailing
lists, we knew, uh, his email address.
I started to see these things happening.
Um,
my wife was emailing him a lot.
He was emailing her a lot.
It was a conversation between them via
work, email, which is okay, I guess.
But then they started texting each other,
oh,
GG.
And it was frequent.
I come downstairs and hear a phone,
snapchat and I'd say,
who you talking to?
She would always say no one or just
checking my messages, et Cetera.
Being that I'm a system
engineer and technology,
I called bullshit and proceeded to
capture her passwords on the laptop
downstairs. Jesus Christ. He goes, I
know, but I wanted to see what was up.
So I got a password logged into her
phone account online and Lo and behold,
she was texting this guy back
and forth. First of all, do it.
How did you capture her password?
This is why I don't bank online.
I don't do any of that shit. This is
the kid's a secure site. No, it isn't.
Um,
anyways,
so he finds out that
she's texting this dude.
Both of them are texting back and forth
and he says, I'm not just saying, uh,
during the day,
a few times I'm saying throughout the
day and up until 11:00 PM at night,
even after midnight and while
I'm lying in bed next to her,
she would always get pissed if I said
anything about who the fuck are you
talking to at 11:00 PM?
Um,
we became mutual friends with
this person from the start.
And I asked some girls I knew and some
guys and some guys that I that both knew
him and they both said,
yeah, you need to address it.
So I called the dude one
night and pretty much said,
stop fucking texting my
wife at night. Uh, are,
are you and I are going to have a problem.
And he immediately shut it down.
This guy, five, seven, 150 pounds
and not some stutter or anything.
I'm six [inaudible] 200 pounds.
It could easily stomp his ass out.
Um,
okay.
Oh, let's see. He's an endurance
runner, not some super jacked guy.
He immediately stopped and every time I
saw him in the locker room or the gym,
he was very cautious
around me and way too nice.
Almost like it was his
way of saying sorry oof,
everything's stopped after that. My
question is, was I right doing this,
addressing it with him?
Uh,
basically texting has blurred the lines
between what's okay and what's not.
Guys and girls always say, oh, it
was just a text, but no big deal.
But I think that's horseshit.
MMM.
It's this,
it's the same as a phone call to me.
So if you want to call my wife while
I'm in bed with her, go for it.
But they won't.
Texting is a bitch move,
which is why so many people get busted
doing it. If they were with a want to,
eem emailed each other at work and
discuss workout routines, I get it.
But having that instant
connection through your phone,
no matter where they are is a little odd.
Especially while I'm in
bed right next to her.
Am I wrong for putting this bitch
in line and telling him to stop it?
Uh, yeah, dude.
You know what?
The only reason why you're asking me if
you're wrong is because you busted your
fucking wife. And right now she's
mine. Fucking you manipulating you,
trying to get you
she, she's basically almost done.
It. Almost flipped it around.
You were actually questioning,
am I fucking wrong for four
fucking catching my wife
texting with this other guy
at 11 o'clock at night.
Get,
there's only one reason you text somebody
at 11 o'clock at night. Two reasons.
Either you ran out of gas.
Oh, you trying to fuck them.
That's the only two reasons people
text at that fucking hour than I.
He's trying to fuck your wife.
All right.
And I don't know what's up with
your wife. Okay? Cause you're going.
Who are you texting? Oh, nobody right
there. The fact that she goes, oh,
nobody in slams the fucking
phone shot right there.
She knows she's doing something
that ain't fucking cool.
This is a very fucking touchy subject.
All right?
Because this involves the woman cheating
and guys solve problems with violence.
So I'm not trying to fucking
egg you on here, sir,
but you definitely did the right thing
and that's really a what the fuck
situation that you're in. That
ain't fucking cool. All right,
I'm going to step outside
of your situation now, sir.
All right. Other than that,
say that you 100% did the right thing
and do not let her fucking worm her way
out of it.
Okay?
All right.
Personally speaking now,
now I'm talking about make
stepping away from this story.
If I caught my girl doing it,
that's a fucking rap. It's over.
The relationship is fucking go fuck
yourself. All right, it's over.
It's over. I know where the fuck this is
going. I know where the hell this is. Lee.
What the fuck he Texas guy for 11 o'clock
at night. You want to suck his dick?
Why?
W w what was he telling you?
How to do the the perfect
jumping Jack at 1130 at night?
He couldn't tell you that.
If four he has to email you,
text you fucking 9,000 times during the
course of the day to tell you how to do
a fucking pushup. Give me a fucking
break. You're flirting with this guy.
You want to fuck them.
So relationship is over.
Happy fucking
bum buddied up on Mudita.
Mudita right. That be trails too. You
get the fuck out of here. It's over.
That's that's,
that's how you got to handle it.
Then the same way fucking Colbys wife
when she busted him cheating rather than
taking that big tweety bird
diamond that she got from him.
Sheets that right there, the relationship,
it's fucking over. It's fucking over.
Trust is gone. It's fucking over. But he's
worth hundreds of millions of dollars,
which for some reason she's entitled
to half of it. So she stuck around.
She stuck around,
put in her 10 years now he has to pay
for her fucking life for the rest of her
life. He has to fucking support her, but
she's a God damn child and it's legal.
Somebody please justify that.
I'll never get over it. People,
I'll keep going back to it.
To one of you motherfuckers can morally
justify the reasoning behind that
fucking law.
Please stop wasting my time by telling
me what the law is in speculating.
Well, at the tables were flipped,
Colby, what had done ad caught caught.
I'm not saying who would have
done what I'm saying morally.
Tell me the reasoning behind
that fucking law. Okay.
The only thing I can think of is that
back in the day guys would start families
and then jump on the horse and say, I'm
fucking Outta here. And they just left.
And then you had this poor woman with
four kids and they were in poverty.
I get that. You want to fucking avoid
that. Okay. If that's what the justify,
if you're going to try and
justify it that way, I get it.
But what I would like to
introduce is a, is a, uh,
a new modification of that law
with is some sort of salary cap.
Okay. I don't think just because you
married somebody who's rich, man or woman,
that that gives you the fucking right to
sit on your goddamn ass for the rest of
your fucking life and get arrogant license
plates say in his money, her money.
I didn't pay for it. Ha
ha ha. I mean right there.
You wonder why people get killed.
That's the kind of shit right there.
That's two minutes for
instigating right there.
If he comes over and fucking slaps
the Goddamn spit out of your mouth,
what did you do it? Look at her license
plate, your honor. Eh? You know what?
That makes sense.
The fuck is wrong with you.
What do you have that license plate for?
That's not how it works.
I don't care that she's being a cunt.
That's no excuse for treating or like one
hello.
No,
no.
Geez.