Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burnham.
Yeah.
Yay.
Just checking on you on an ar for a
Thursday afternoon. Hope all is well.
I'll deal the enjoy your
last couple of days.
I hope Tuesday and Wednesday
was everything that you
thought it was going to be.
You know what was the last time you look
forward to a Tuesday or a Wednesday?
You never do.
You never do unless you have the day off,
which is why you have to go
and kill your boss. Okay.
And I think there's not a jury in the
world that would convict you if you just
said,
listen,
I just wanted for once in my life to be
able to look forward to a Tuesday and on
Wednesday,
you know?
Okay.
And they would all put their heads to
the side and they'd smile and be like,
you know what, that that person
did. That man deserves to die. Okay.
Not to be a chauvinist, but I just
assumed the boss is a man, you know,
with all the squawk
and from the feminists,
like you know how they're not fucking,
I dunno, I dunno what that problem is.
You know, if there's not enough gum
drops in their fucking ice cream.
Evidently I think that's their basis.
I'm not gonna start that shit again.
By the way, me and me, it
had a great time on Monday.
Most people thought it was a great time,
enjoyed us having a good time,
and then other people
got a little sensitive.
I thought you a little bit
too hard on her, did ya?
Did you really think I was a little
harder? You think she couldn't take it?
She was fucking destroying me.
You know, there's always one do.
She just has to take everything to fucking
seriously and for some reason in this
day and age,
then the whole world,
the whole world will listen to one douche
bag and think that it's a tsunami of
fucking human beings. A tsunami bill.
Hey, I'm, I'm fucking refund here.
Every once in a while the wrong
fucking reference will come out.
10 people fucking complain and
they'll act like it's all a China.
So dumb as shit.
Just like,
I really think someone needs to look at
these fucking groups and be like, hey,
hey, hey, shut up.
Shut the fuck up.
You're fucking bullies.
Okay.
That's all you're doing. The exact
fucking thing you don't want done to you.
Now you're doing everybody else. There's
such cons. Who Bill, which groups?
All of them generally speaking about
the way they go about with their mission
statement.
They really are.
They don't give a fuck who the fuck
they destroy as long as in the the end
result is there a,
you know,
most of the time you know what they
want to do I think is a good thing.
But the way they go about it, what the
fuck is my computer talking about now?
A script on this page may be
busy or it may have stopped.
I don't give a fuck telling
me about it for um, all right,
my computer's going to be a
pain in the ass to me this week.
I can already tell cause I'm trying to
fucking upload some files to an external
hard drive so I can have them on there
so I can never look at them again.
How many external hard drives
do you fucking have? You know,
all these important pictures,
all these selfies you took while
you were shit faced in a bar,
got to keep all of them right. You
know, some dumb thing sent you,
but you save for some reason to show
somebody else and then that's there and
then that's in your fucking hard
drive. All right. I get it. I get it.
I get a computer. Okay. Stop the script.
Fuck it. Okay. I'll get off my life.
Um, so anyways, uh, yeah,
like last year when a couple of weeks ago,
and I told you that hilarious story,
the white kid fucking than the clean shirt
and the beautiful glasses and the, uh,
the rope necklace was asking
for money and how, uh,
you know, I was teasing her
about how good he looked.
So then he handed the money back,
so I took it and gave it back to my
friends and then the guy in the wheelchair
came and then they gave it to him and
the fucking white kid flipped out.
And how funny it was. Right. Um,
somebody got all pissed at me on Twitter
about that and said, you know what? Yeah.
That was great.
You don't,
the only thing it's funny isn't that is
me not go to Amazon League when they go
to Amazon. It's like, all right.
Yeah, do that. There you go.
My entire fucking economy was based
on you going to fucking Amazon.
I don't give a fuck. I don't pressure
anybody to do that. If you want to do it,
I appreciate it. If you don't, don't,
then you're going to have your fucking
reasons. Stop fucking send me tweets.
Like that's going to like,
I'm gonna like feet brought to my niece.
Bill power will not be at the comedy
store this weekend because one can't
decided not to use is Amazon link.
Now what's he going to deal?
He can't afford the gas to get over here.
Speaking of which,
oh, fractals, I am sold
on that fucking Tesla.
A buddy of mine last night, uh, comic,
he got one. He just got the ass model.
It was the sickest fucking car. He
got an in blue. It was the shit.
Um,
I woke up this morning thinking about
that car smiling and that's usually a good
thing when you wake up. Thinking
about something smiling, you know,
unless you're murdered somebody the night
before and you're smiling about that,
then I guess you'd be
a psycho. Um, but, uh,
I'm Solon the fucking car
and I want to get the,
I want to get the one that fucks
with the core of that. The p,
the series one where it's got two motors.
I want to get one of those fucking things.
And I was talking to another comedy.
He goes, well, you know what? If
there's a power outage, it's like, okay,
you never going to have to buy gas again
and you're worried about a power outage.
Power outage. Think about your cell
phone. Think about your cell phone.
When was the law?
That thing needs electricity.
When was the last time there was a power
outage and you couldn't use your cell
phone for some ridiculous period of time?
Can you remember?
Okay, now, now that you're off the
ledge, go out and go buy the fucking car.
Fucking dope.
Dope.
What do I do that anybody doesn't think
what I think is then a dope? Yeah,
he's just fucking, your word is wrong
with me. I Dunno. So anyways, um,
had a great time last night.
I want to thank everybody that came
down to the comedy store for the, uh,
the all things comedy,
uh, showcase last night.
Everybody had a great time and Joe Rogan
was nice enough to jump on in the end.
Had a great time hanging out
with him. Al Madrigal, bird fry.
Um, Jill Barton, the Rosebowl
legend was there. Um,
Neil Brennan, Dean del Ray was just,
it was just a fucking awesome time.
And you know,
what's the greatest thing about it?
At no point did anybody periscope
backstage that's becoming the new fucking
thing,
you know,
the new desperate thing to try to sell
your fucking love songs on, you know, hey,
this is fucking Lao.
Love it on periscope.
This is what my face looks like when I
take his shit in my fucking bathroom.
And a, by the way, uh, this bathroom
was done in a Victorian style.
Um, I fucking hate periscope. I,
I don't, you know what, I
just, I haven't even seen it.
It's just the people who have used it,
it's so fucking intrusive.
If somebody just comes walking in the
wrong, I'm on terrorists scope right now.
It's just like,
did I ask to be on this fucking thing?
Don't have to sign a release or am I just
guilty of being out in public then and
now it's like everybody's
becoming like TMZ. Um, I dunno,
I'm not, you know me, I'm
not a fucking fan of that.
The only thing I don't like about the
Tesla is that giant supersized fucking
iPad. I hate that thing. Everything
else about the car I love,
but I'm so I'm already thinking about,
uh,
I know this guy that does custom car shit
and I'll just have a window shade made
for that thing and I'll just fucking
pull it down. I don't want that thing,
you know,
glaring in my face.
Like I opened that thing and
Raiders of the lost Ark can,
every time I'd drive down the fucking
street, you know, other than that,
I think that car is, uh, I think
that car is pretty sick personally,
personally is what I'm thinking.
So anyways,
this is Thursday afternoon and
for all you hockey fans out there,
all you fans of the game of hockey, you
have to be unbelievably excited, Huh?
To game seven. It's one tonight though.
Rages against the fucking lightening.
And then tomorrow night the Black Hawks
got to go to Anaheim and play the ducks.
Man. Um, I can honestly tell you, I have
no idea who's going to win either one,
either one of those series.
Um,
but I do think whoever wins black cops
ducks is going to take the a is going to
win the cup.
Unfortunately,
the West is just been stronger than the
east for fucking ever. And I'm honest,
that van, the Bruins one in all 2011
and I say oh 11th, then I almost say,
oh 11 is that what I fucking did?
Um,
I was trying to get onto this fucking
website here. I got it here. There's a a,
some of you, this is something
people wanted me to talk about it.
If you want me to go off on something,
just a tweet at me with Hashtag
t a m m p Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast just before Friday.
Um,
this is feminist upset over statue
of a man and a woman talking.
I'm seeing, okay, here's the scene.
All right, this is in Washington DC.
You're a woman's sitting
on a bench reading a book.
Your male friends sees you on the,
and it comes
over to say hello and talk.
You put down your book,
Lean back against the bench and smile.
He doesn't sit next to you.
Instead he puts his foot on the
bench and leads over on his knee. Uh,
so sexist, right? Uh,
that scene is depicted in a statue at
the University of incarnate word in San
Antonio, Texas. And despite no sign
of distress or physical assertion,
some women have decided it is a statue.
Oh my God,
this is of mansplaining.
A term used to describe men
condescendingly explaining
something to a woman.
Yeah,
Dude, how much do they fucking
hate us? Like they never do that.
Jesus Christ,
every five seconds,
they're trying to fixture
then change how you are.
Why don't they see the balance in that?
That's fucking nuts to me anyways.
Seriously.
Here's the actual statue
and the claim of a massage.
Massage Uni. Um, okay. It's some,
some woman wrote of friends spider
this and Texas Hashtag mansplaining
the statue. Oh my God. I have to
start explaining shit to women.
If this fucking annoys him, all you
gotta do is just do it more. Uh,
the tweet went viral over
Memorial Day weekend.
It all started when Ash Hernandez saw
the statue on her way to a teacher's
certification tests.
She was so outraged that she ran back
to her car to get her phone to snap a
picture. Uh, the sculpture
just screamed at mansplaining.
Let me just fucking try
to be open and honest,
which was really difficult for
me because I'm such a cunt.
But when I look at this thing,
um,
I don't see her smiling. She actually
looks like her lips are purse.
Like she's going really? But he, he,
he seems like a nice guy.
He's got a nice full head of hair.
He's wearing a pair of slacks.
He's got his shirt tucked in.
He does seem like she,
she seems annoyed by him.
I will say that the way
she's looking up at him,
I don't fuck do we make this a little
bigger? But I mean, if I saw this,
I would be like this guy striking out.
She's not having it.
I Dunno. I Dunno what the deal
is. He definitely, I got to admit,
he definitely does look like
he interrupted her. You know,
she's got her legs crossed.
She's got the book there.
She was reading and he came over.
I know this is mansplaining.
I think the guy's kind of a douche bag
and he's taken a fucking, you know,
he's second to swing. Um, I think
feminists have to understand that, uh,
in order for us to get laid, we have
to initiate the, uh, the interactions.
So, uh, you know,
maybe he didn't have to put
as low for up on the bench,
but I don't think that's a reason to
take the whole fucking thing down. Like,
I wouldn't walk by that statue was a guy
and be like, you know what, I'm gonna
do that next time I see
a line reading a book,
I'm going to put my fucking foot on there.
Mansplaining is hilarious.
Just for the record ladies.
They do it to us too.
There's always that fucking person,
you know, that person. It's,
it's usually a person who's
either they're not educated or they're
overly impressed with their education.
Like someone who didn't go to college
is always trying to constantly, uh,
throw out some information about something
that they're well read on that they
rent,
you know,
to overcompensate for the fact that they
didn't fucking throw a hundred grand
into the god damn toilet going
of going away to school. Um,
or you get those people
that, um, you know,
I went to Undergrad here and
then I matriculated Holford
to fucking blah, blah,
blah for my graduate and my
baccalaureate degree. You know,
those fucking people.
And you know,
and I'm not saying that they can't be
cool and I'm not saying someone that
doesn't go to a fucking call, never
didn't go. It didn't go to college.
Can't be fucking cool, but I'm just
saying generally fucking speaking. Um,
those are the two types of people.
They overexplain shit.
You know, I've had people
who don't live in California.
Tell me what California is like,
you know,
and then you just sit in there going
like, dude, I lived there. The to La.
It's just everybody's plastic.
Everybody's got plastic surgery in Botox.
It's like, no, no. There's a lot of
unbelievably talented Pete. You know,
all those fucking shows you love
all those shows that blow your mind.
This golden age of TV.
Most of the people writing those in
shooting those live in Los Angeles.
So know that. All right. No, that okay.
You want to see a lot of plastic surgery?
I'd go down to Orange County. All
right. I'd go down there. Okay.
They even got laid. Off you go. I
thought that there was just going to be,
uh, you know, my wife watches the
real housewives of Orange County.
I thought it was bullshit.
I was like, all right.
They picked the six biggest
freaks down here, you know,
and then of course made
this place look bad.
And then I went down there and I did a
couple of weekends down in Irvine and I
was like, oh, why can't I see,
I see what's going on now
I see what's going on.
53 year old woman wearing spaghetti
straps, you know, freckled shoulders.
You can see they're still working out,
but you know,
your skin just loses the elasticity
and it just, it doesn't look good,
doesn't look good. No one should wear
a tank top man or a woman over 50.
You just shouldn't do it. You
know, even Jake a jackal lane,
we had the decency to wear that funds.
He fucking onesy zip up.
He was still in great shape, but he knew,
he knew what was going on. You know,
varicose vein here or there. You
cover it up, you know, you, you,
you keep yourself in shape
and you wear a lot of clothes.
Hey,
by the way,
all freckles is turning the ship
around this big fucking tugboat of a,
of a belly that I've put on here.
Uh, I was a buck 87 or something.
I think I, I've dropped a couple, you
know, when you first started dating,
you can drop a couple of times in a few
days just by, just by eating healthy,
just by going from the beginning of
the day to the end of the day. So, um,
I've been doing the oatmeal in the
morning with a banana and then between
breakfast and lunch I have an
orange. And then for lunch, uh,
I've been just doing like a,
what did I have yesterday?
Had a giant salad and then I had
a little bit of steak in there.
And what are they have
a little bit tuna later.
And then for dinner I was
running out the door and I just,
I had this salary already fucking chopped
up at a big glob of peanut butter and
I just did that. And uh, do,
that's a game changer, man.
If you have salary with
a glove of peanut butter,
if you can fucking tough your way through
that and deal with people going like,
what are you doing? A
remake of fucking, uh,
outcast or whatever that fucking movie
Tom Hanks did where he talked to the ball.
Was that called Lone
survivor? Oh, Jesus Christ.
I know this one.
It begins with an o not outcast,
shipwrecked overcast weather.
Okay.
The fuck was that called?
God dammit. Anyways,
didn't being with an, Oh, let me add
the big beard. Well said. Well said.
Okay.
All right. You're on an island.
His ship wrecked castaway.
Gasaway.
What does a castaway is that
when they throw you overboard
and they fucking stole, you've been
cached away. Not to fucking safe.
Let's say one of the worst things
ever is getting keel hauled.
Can you imagine that shit just fucking
drag you underneath the boat til you pass
out from sucking in water? I mean, like,
it's just a fact that that could
be a punishment. The egg shells,
that I would be walking on it,
whatever that fucking one legged maniac
told me to do that was fucking driving
the boat. I would do I fucking do
anything. He cannot fucking Keel, homey.
And your friends is fucking sitting
there strapping me up for that ride.
And you're sitting there going,
come on guys under your breath
like [inaudible]. [inaudible] um,
oh my God,
I could never live back then.
I would been y'all this shit
that I talk right now. You know,
I talk all this shit right
now because there's no,
none of that belly of the beast. No iron
maiden's left. None of that fucking shit,
at least in this part of the
world or at least where I live.
You know what I mean?
But we don't to fucking set you on fire
and do all that fucking horrific shit
that we've done to people
throughout the years. All right,
let's get off this subject.
It's a, it's Kinda creepy, Huh?
All right.
What do we got here?
Other shit people wanted me to talk
about battle rapper holds nothing back on
the fat jokes. Uh, uh, post that
video, I started to watch it,
but he was going so goddamn
slow. Um, it was annoying me.
Ah, Shit. I gotta hit pause. Hang
on, hang on, hang on. Hang on.
All right,
sorry about that.
He sent to make sure that was somebody's
calling me about something to have
later on in the day,
and I got to make sure I'm not gonna
we laid over there. Um, it's something
else. Somebody wanted me to go off on. Um,
cancer charities allegedly missed,
used $187 million for
concerts and dating sites,
luxury cars for cancer charities.
I think I already talked about this.
Use more than a hundred to $87
million to buy luxury cars,
luxury cruises, concert tickets,
and even dating members.
Memberships for families and friends.
It's one of the largest charity frauds
accusations ever leveled in the u s well,
I gotta be honest with you.
So many of them.
Okay.
If you dig a little bit,
it seems like a,
I can't say like say
like five hour energy.
Gee, they just got a thing now
that every time you buy something,
five hour energy, they're going to
donate to this fucking costs. All right?
And basically what they're going to do
is they, but they have it on the screen.
They say we're going to give at least
200 grand and we're going to give 5 cents
on every five hour energy thing that we
sell. And I got to be, when I'm talking,
I don't think that that's
bad because they're being,
they're being upfront about it.
MMM.
Oh, Jesus Christ, you
blocked me and jerk face,
close the driveway gates and lock the
front door. I had to move your rental car.
That's a nice block. My wife and I are
driving like an asshole. Um, anyways,
um,
I don't think that that's bad.
MMM.
But I,
I just,
you just have to pay attention to a up
a portion of the proceeds is the big
thing and it becomes like what portion
of the proceeds and then it becomes like,
well,
what charity can I give to that?
The most amount is going to go to
the actual people that are suffering.
Now you have to have some sort
of infrastructure and the people,
if they donating 100% of
their time to the charity,
they have to make a living where they
can pay a mortgage. So I get all of that.
But, um, there is, there is a thing
where it becomes like, well, how much,
how much are you making a year?
Like if you're taking in $10 million,
you're paying yourself a
fucking $1 million a year.
Then that's when it starts getting
weird where it's just like, all right,
so you're a fucking millionaire right
now because people have rickets or
whatever, you know, I don't
fucking know who the fuck knows.
All I can tell you is that my charity.
Okay.
Okay. The all freckles.
All right. To raise, uh,
to raise awareness on skin cancer is,
is going to be a,
I'm going to get that in motion
for a 2021 even in 2015, 2016
I'm going to set it up. All right? And
every time you guys go, oh, Jane's is,
I'm going to, uh, I can't do that. I
will go broke if I, um, I don't know.
I'll come up with some more shit.
I can fuck you guys out of money and make
it seem like you guys are doing a good
thing and I'm doing a good thing.
And then one day you'll find out that I
completely fucked you over and then I'll
have like no comment as I get out of my,
you guys find out that you bought
my Tesla. Can you imagine that if I,
you know what kills me about
people do shit like that is,
it's funny to me like if they can
sleep at night or if, if they can't,
if they're out or if it's the other way
and they're just fucking wide awake at
night going out Jesus
Christ like a hey man,
those alligator shoes who sings like
Tom Ford, like 12 fucking grand. Yeah.
How did you get dosed?
Ah,
raising awareness for a kidney stones.
You know,
while we raised a ton of money and I just
take a percentage, 90% and I, you know,
um, I do, I'm doing God's
work. Glad plash shit.
You're doing God's work.
You do God's guides work.
I run a nonprofit. Oh yeah.
Then how do you pay your bills?
Okay.
Ball's in your court, Sweetheart.
I just asked you a question.
Don't stare at me like,
how do you run a nonprofit and
fucking put fruit loops on the table?
I want to know at some
point while I draw a salary,
they go, you are profiting,
you profit. But whatever.
I guess I, I'm, I'm
starting to think like,
I'm overly critical of a lot of
these charities that uh, you know,
people do have to make a living,
you know what I mean?
But then there's that weird thing
where it's like the bigger the event,
they feel like the more money that
they're going to make I guess.
And then they got to start renting
out these sick ass fucking places.
And that's why I think it
starts getting weird. I Dunno,
there's a good movie in that somewhere,
somewhere in there,
there's a good movie script about somebody
that starts a fucking nonprofit for
the right reasons. And
then the end, you know,
the money's coming in
and they get a nicer car.
All of a sudden that driving
around you ain't gold digging.
Whores starts showing up.
You make a statue of it,
some broad walking into class doesn't
like it. She fucking tweets about it.
Nine people lose their minds.
So 15 people lose their jobs.
Isn't that how it works? And I'll bill
you is such a Douche. Shut up. All right.
Fuck you. All right, let me,
let me, um, oh by the way, uh,
the,
uh,
the extra posters that then I had
leftover from the Billy Bible belt tour,
they're all autographed and they
went on sale yesterday and uh,
much to my, uh, happiness there.
They're going really fast. So,
um, if you want to get one there,
uh, I made sure I autographed
all of them and um,
I dunno, we get a, I
don't know to get left,
I'm like 150 left or something like that.
So if you'd like to get one, you know,
if you can't make it to my
shows or somebody, you know,
you know that deal if like it to get it.
If you
don't, I fucking get it.
All right. Um, so anyways,
what are we up to here?
23, fuck, 24 minutes. Um,
let me do a little read here. A
little advertising. Read a blue apron.
A fuck is this blue apron.
It's okay.
You can admit the last thing anybody
wants to do after work is waiting in line
at a grocery store. Schlep home
and cook. Cook a complicated meal.
I agree with that. I agree with
this copy so far and expensive,
unhealthy takeoff take out is hardly
better. I'll put it, it's delicious.
That's where the new
service blue apron comes in.
Blue Apron delivers farm fresh ingredients
and step by step recipes to your
home,
allowing you to create healthy handcrafted
meals at home without going to the
grocery store. The less than
$10 per meal. Blue Apron,
why is it blue sends you fresh
ingredients, perfectly proportioned,
making cookie help, cookie
making, cooking healthy meals,
really easy and fun.
No trips to the grocery store and no
waste waste from unused ingredients.
Plus you'll learn to cook with special
ingredients that are normally hard to
find.
Blue Apron is perfect for a date night
cooking with friends and they even offer
family friend a family plants
with kid friendly ingredients,
so the whole family,
all you can eat well and our fun.
Preparing meals,
preparing the meals together.
Could you pass me the stalts? One
person's going to do it. Come on.
Each balanced meal is 500 to 700
calories per serving and so tasty.
You'd never know.
I love when they do that.
Acting like healthy food doesn't taste
good. Cooking takes half an hour.
Shipping is flexible and free
and the menus are always new.
They won't send the same meal twice.
They work around your schedule and
dietary preferences and blue paper and
experts source only the best
seasonal ingredients, uh,
from incredible meals like sliced pork.
Steak was smashed potatoes and
strawberry rhubarb compote.
What component?
Cal Zone with Broccoli Rabe.
The fuck is this food.
Which Chili Garlic Mozzarella,
ricotta cheese with the creamy dip baby.
You'll cook incredible meals and be
blown away by the quality and freshness.
Blue Apron.
It's a better way to cook.
Check out this week's menu and get your
first two meals for free by going to
blue apron.com/barbie you are uh,
my treat.
Really the first two meals are on me.
When you go to blue apron.com/birth well,
they're not on me. They're on. You
guys at least tried to do that.
They always try to put words in your
mouth. These people, you know what I mean?
I just put on my blue apron
and I feel like a million buck.
My deck is standing at
attention a has everybody.
Chances are if you have feet,
you wear socks and face it.
Socks haven't changed since they were
invented and the hour they'd fucking mass
by crying
Asians or people down in El Salvador.
It's disgusting. It's changed a lot.
Back in the day your mom made him sat
down and knitted him, hey bond this,
why don't you fucking,
you know,
read a little bit of history before he
started throwing up crazy shit like that.
Uh, they were all, they fall down,
they wear out and there's always that
toasting that's never in the right place.
Our new sponsor bond buzz has changed.
All of that bomb is dedicated two years
to engineering socks that stay up last
forever and feel amazing on your feet.
Um, evidently I have a pair of Obama's,
I probably dope gives a fuck.
New socks are awesome and these guys are
going to send them to you if it's got
to this. Let's cut to the chase
here. There's so comfortable.
The honeycomb stitching. I'm a big fan
of honeycomb stitching. Hugs your foot.
So whether you're walking or running,
your feet feel perfect.
This is such an old guy thing.
Young guys, you got LR ladies,
you got to get into this shit.
You got to take care of your feet
because as you get older, man,
those are the things that talk to
you first. She got damn dogs. Um,
um, anyways, uh,
you might find yourself washing them
over and over so you can wear them again.
You need to get more of you buddy.
If you haven't gotten them yet to know
what you, what you're talking about.
I'm checking all the eyes here. You need
to really try a pair of for yourself.
But listen, bombers don't stop with
your comfort with every pair of socks.
Bombers sells a parish. Donate
it to someone in need. Yeah.
The person who had a fucking sewn together
for 2 cents an hour because socks is,
it turns out are the number one requested
thing at the homeless shelters. Uh,
right now from our limited time bomb is,
is offering my listeners 20% off
their first order and free shipping.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com
slash birds B o m B a s.com/burr.
Do what now for 20% off the
most comfortable socks in
the planet and a pair of
for someone in need, go to [inaudible]
dot com slash burr a that's Bob,
B o m B a s.com/barbie.
You are r.
Um, she's just quite how fucking
hard. If people work in these days,
they don't have time to shop.
They don't have time to get food.
It's fucking unreal. Do you guys remember
that cartoon? The Jetsons? You know,
meet George Jetson [inaudible] data to
do his boy [inaudible] daughter Judy.
Um, Jane, his wife,
Dang Dude.
Ooh.
And His fucking car folded up and do a
briefcase that was supposed to be in the
future. And the whole premise
was, is pool's getting,
it was the Flintstones flipped on its ear.
It's just like the Flintstones,
but it's in the future. No, Dino,
you got astro, right? No, Bam, Bam.
You got Ellroy whenever the fuck
I'm talking about. So anyways, they,
the big premise about that was technology.
Technology was going to be
so fucking insane that uh,
we were going to have three day work
weeks and that was a running joke on that.
George Jetson would always say, oh my God,
these three day work weeks are murder.
And,
and I guess that hasn't happened.
People are working more than they
have a fucking worked. And uh,
to the point they don't have time to
go to a goddamned grocery store growth,
some fucking vegetables. I'll
pick up a pair of socks, you know,
or afford a pair razor blades down at cvs.
So then all the shit that
I'm fucking than I, than I,
all these people that advertise, you
don't have time to go to the post office.
You don't get time to fucking do
anything anymore. Why is that?
Did we, did we not understand that the
technology was now going to own us?
Like look at all this shit.
I'm fucking sitting there uploading
all these fucking photos that I'm never
going to look at it and it's making my
computer freeze the fuck am I doing when
I've been dealing with this thing.
I don't even know what the problem is.
It's been, it's, it started last
night and it's still hasn't uploaded.
It won't let me stop the process.
It doesn't give me an
option or probably a dozen.
I don't know how to fucking do it,
you know,
and it just becomes something else that
I got to fucking deal with. So I dunno.
Would you guys ever have the balls to go
back to a flip phone like some of these
kids are doing?
Actually I heard this comic did that.
He just got sick of fucking being on his,
his iPhone or his fucking whatever the
elements are. What are the other ones?
You know Hitachi,
who else makes it?
Who else makes a a phone?
There's the other one,
the really big one and
I don't fucking know.
All I know is I don't talk on mine
anymore. I just, I used the speaker.
I'm big on the speaker, man. I
don't hold it up to my fucking head.
After that kid in mobile,
Alabama told me his dad died of a brain
tumor on the side of his head that he's
talking to a cell phone all the fucking
time and he's convinced that that's what
it was.
And I remember hearing Roger Ebert say
that about gene Siskel the same fucking
thing. So, um, uh,
I hope I didn't wait too long because
God knows I can't remember shit.
This is getting really fucking depressing.
All right,
we're up to a half hour
here. Um, all right, so a,
I didn't talk to me about any basketball.
Let me talk about that real quick. Uh,
the basketball man, who do
you like? Who Do you like?
Um,
I love that the Golden State Warriors
it back in it for the first time since
what, 75. And um,
I love that they play in
that old ass fucking arena.
There's a lot to like about them,
but for some reason, you know,
Lebron going back after they hated him
and they burned all these jerseys and
shit.
Him going back and becoming a champion,
showing that he didn't have to be part
of a fucking pile on team with all,
you know, all the injuries that
got, I dunno, I can tell you this,
I'm going to be happy with the,
the team that wins and um,
but I think, uh, I think
Lebron's going to get,
he's just such a fucking force,
but I will say,
and I don't know shit about
basketball and that fucking,
what's his Stephon Curry said, I
you say his name Steve. Dan Curry.
Stephon Curry. I don't know
his fucking name was. I've not,
I've never seen a guy shoot
threes like that in my life.
He's like Larry Bird level
unconscious every fucking game.
Uv starts bad. All of a sudden he just,
he starts, I haven't seen anybody.
There was the greatest three
point shooters I've seen
in my life is Larry Bird,
Reggie Miller,
and just for degree of difficulty,
the amount of times I saw Colby take a
turnaround jumper with two guys hanging
on him and he fucking hits it.
Um,
I mean those, those rhino, right.
Wral and I guess I never
watched him when he was playing.
What do you play with the bucks?
The Sonics? I don't fucking know.
I'm not a basketball guy. All
I know is this guy. Is He,
the way he shoots every fucking game
is like a career game. He's the one,
he's the greatest three
point shooter I've ever seen.
I would say Reggie Miller
second and then Larry Bird.
I've never seen anything like this kid.
So,
but I don't think that
that's going to be enough.
Him just fucking flicking that wrist
and it going right through the net to
compensate for the,
the domination of Lebron.
I just think that that guy is,
um,
I dunno if he's just on another level,
just another level.
And I think according to law head,
Cleveland has a fucking amazing defense.
Defense wins championships or what?
That little tidbit of information from
La had day of golf. That's my prediction.
I'm saying the Cavaliers win
a championship. All right.
And Lebron goes down with Cleveland
legends. I think it's funny.
You gotta go back to Jim Brown
and Bob Feller and then Lebron,
right? That's going to be
there. Bobby or Ted Williams,
Larry Berg, Tom Brady,
right. Those are ours.
Those are our four.
You gotta throw Bill Russell and
another though 11 championships.
Um, who's getting hurt? We got so
many fucking champions were fun.
So many fucking champions.
So many champions so that they have to
suspend one of the great quarterbacks of
all time of over. Absolutely
fucking nothing. Um,
do you guys read up on Jim Marsay
how he had a, a, you know his,
his mistress there. He bought her a house
and she fucking hoe dating it. You know,
he's a great guy. Okay. You
know, it's solid fucking dude.
You should be listening to that guy,
Bill.
Are you really going to whine about
it again? You're right. You're right.
It's over. It's done. It's
going to happen. So anyways,
thank you for listening.
Enjoy the throwback clip here.
Have yourselves a wonderful weekend
if cons and I will love talk to you on
Monday.
Okay.
Uh,
alright, next question.
Alright. Hey, fill huge fan.
Not sure if this is where we ask podcasts
questions or what,
but what are some of your guilty pleasure?
My guilty pleasures.
Desperate housewives.
A pint of Haagen Daas Ryan Seacrest's.
Guilty pleasure. You know what?
I gotta give it up to this guy.
And he did call himself out for
asking kind of a faggy question.
What are some of my guilty pleasures?
Uh,
Jesus Christ. I don't know. You know what?
This looks like a job for iTunes.
Let's look at my iPod.
Let me going to scroll down here and
let's look at Kate Alice in chains.
This is the last few things I
downloaded. Alison chains, Jar flies,
the new foo fighters.
That's all respectable. Um,
somebody was walking by staring at me.
I'm doing this podcast in
my car by the way. Uh Oh,
there's one Rosanna by toto.
Fuck Yo. I like the drum beat. I want
to learn how to play it. All right.
God dammit. And I want to do it either
way. It could be, yeah, it's a gay song.
All right. That's a guilty
pleasure. Um, nine, I'm going
to get a bunch of comments.
Everybody was fucking total pictures.
Just make sure Jeff Macarthur was in it,
so who won't get fooled again?
That's kind of Hacky, muddy waters.
I'm ready. The Allman brothers
one way out. Kanye West.
I Dunno, some people don't like him.
Gym Class Heroes. Oh, wait a minute.
Wait a minute. There's one
poison. Every rose has it's thorn.
Oh. You know, it's funny.
I love that song and I can't listen to
it without every time I listened to what
I always picture people I know,
watching me listen, catching me,
listening to that song. So I always get
embarrassed during the breakdown park.
You know, where he just Sorta strums
the guitar, Dan in Aa, that part.
Um, yeah. I actually get embarrassed.
And a lot of times I say 30% of the
time I have to shut off the fucking sun.
I don't know what that says about me.
Ben Harper, does that make me a Douche?
I Dunno. Uh, loving spoonful. Maya,
I got some,
I got some weird ones here.
Band of horses kind of
makes me a hipster Douche.
Dionne Warwick walk on by.
I didn't download that today.
Fucked about it. Up On my,
I'm the only one to use. Is this
bathroom really exposing myself here? Uh,
what else do I got here?
Beastie boys. Men at work. Work
overkill. What did it all, you
know why I downloaded that? I wait,
what does that move? What's
that show with it? Scrubs.
The guy plays the, uh, the doctor,
the guy with that fucking, uh,
show them with the black dude.
Can I see your funny show?
And they had that one time the
guy came on, he, you know, you,
you don't have a song like you don't
think you like it or maybe you don't even
like it and it's in a movie,
then all of a sudden everybody likes it.
It's kind of like black people all of
a sudden, like in sweet home Alabama.
Was that because they played that
in, uh, what was it a con air?
Was that the first time and then
that guy rapped over it anyway,
black listening to that you should really
do is you should look at the words to
that song.
I don't think you'd like that song.
Especially the second
verse that in Birmingham,
they love the good near Ooh, Ooh, Ooh.
That they're talking about governor
Wallace who was pro segregation.
So think of that.
Next time you're a,
you're walking it out down there
and hot Atlanta. That's not a,
I don't think that's a pro black song.
It's got a nice beat and you could dance
to it though. I will give him that.
All right.
Does that pretty much pretty much
answered this the question I got to redeem
myself.
What are we gonna be a tool?
You can tell him blowing by a bunch.
I don't want to tell you.
I'm just scrolling down here.
Grace Jones. Demolition man.
Yeah, yeah, yes. Somebody is,
I just took a chance on temptation.
I got a whole bunch of ACDC,
uh,
oh my God.
Actually have that pink song that's
been on that forever though. Amazon, um,
come in and say, you better get
the buddy [inaudible] add up done.
And I downloaded that.
There was a moment in my life where I
actually wanted to hear that song again.
It's Kinda like Nickelback
I have one of those songs,
that song photograph there go back
as amazing to me where it's like,
the first time you hear the song
you're like, Eh, Eh, it's not that bad.
Why they get so much, so much shit. Then
the second time you hear it, you're like,
hey, I kinda like that.
Maybe I'll download it. Then
the third time you hear it,
you're like, I want to find that
group. Hunt them down, kill them.
You know, like a deer. Have
some ravens. Oh my back.
Wait for me to fucking got them so the
meat doesn't go bad and then they kind of
fly in. We need the end trails. You ever
watch? You ever watch someone ravens?
I just watched someone Raven's
the other day. All right,
let's move on to the next question.
This is my guilty pleasures.
So
[inaudible] so,
so what happens then? Is that a,
uh, you know, they, we, we, we,
we auditioned him at the comedy
connection. We go to do it live.
We had done it in a room and they said,
we want to see you live and we bond bond.
It's just like, it's sucking silence now.
What do you think? Wait a minute. Wait,
so the first time you ever
did it on comedy stage,
now I've always said the first
time if I bombed the first time,
I don't know if I would ever have the
courage to go back and do it again. Well,
well that, that that's a difference
between people that are, are, are,
are hooked on it and people,
yeah.
People who are born comics and people
who are just, you know, dabbling.
Is that like really, if you bond you
would have done it again. It would've,
it would've taken me a minute. I
would had it been like the, just the,
the sheer fucking embarrassment of a,
I mean you can still, this is deal with
standup is you can still eat it today.
I'm 18 years in, I kind of, yeah, you
can't eat it fun. But this is the thing,
you have years of good shows
to be like, well, you know,
I know I don't suck at this.
I had a bad night,
but you know it right out of the gate.
Oh yeah. The bad night thing is hard to,
to really get around you had,
cause it still hurts me if I bombed,
but when you're up there and you know, you
have this whole idea that you know, uh,
it's, it's never, the
audience is bullshit. I mean
sometimes it's the audience,
right. And you know, like
you, you can tell, you know,
you've done your shit and you can see
where they're peaking laughter wise and
you know,
after a certain point that they're
not going to go any further with that.
So I'll get after it.
I'm just going to have to realize this
is the best I'm going to do in this
situation and either eat it
and you don't take the hit or,
or make light of the fact. Yeah. I've,
I've learned like there's nothing worse
than being angry on stage. But I heard,
I actually heard a funny story last night.
I was doing a kick and uh, this, uh,
this book or Jeff Wills from the
uh, yeah, he was telling a story.
He saw one night,
uh,
said Bill Hicks it an entire show
with his back to the audience.
There was like a Bachelorette party. There
was every fucking thing it did. Yeah.
Those, you know, those Booker's they love
to talk about those stories, you know.
But if anyone else did that now,
they would never fucking work in that
club again. All these guys pretend like,
you know, like, oh,
Bill Hicks was the guy and he went on
stage and angrily tanked in a brilliant
inspired way almost all the time.
But if someone existed like that
now he wouldn't have a fucking shot.
You think so? Absolutely. Well, I bet.
I bet he was still selling tickets at
that point. Cause you can't, you can't,
you can't turn your back
on a fucking crowd and,
and ever think that you're going to work.
I don't think that's true.
I think that the reason he got booked in
this country primarily was to make club
owners feel like they were,
you know,
they were at least championing something
terrific. Like I think they innate,
we knew this guy was special.
There was no one like him.
And even the fact that he didn't sell
tickets or alienated the audience every
time they were gonna have him twice a
year to keep their content straight. Oh.
So that can be dicks to everybody else
basically. But just to sort of like, to,
to at least support that,
at least they knew well enough
that he was an inspired guy.
But I've gotten angry on stage. I did
it the other night, dude, not in it.
And it would've been a long time because
I used to snap all the tabs and say,
that's kind of an understatement
coming from you. Yeah. But,
but that's like me saying, I've
snapped. No, but, but you know,
I'm pretty accessible now. Not, Oh
yeah, you're your way, your way. Uh,
but it happened at the store, dude,
it happened at this how long ago?
Two nights ago. And I, I, I, I
could do this whole thing. Yeah,
much better now. Much better
enough. I snapped one time.
What was it, 48 hours ago?
I couldn't believe I did. It was
such a different person. You know,
that place brings it out of here.
Come on.
The comedy store brings it
out of here sometimes. I,
that's what I love it though.
It's so fucking soul on
stage. It is evil. It is.
It's just painted and heat,
you know,
you feel the walls wanting you to lose
it, you know, if it's just in the place,
so I'm on stage,
it's like 40 people in the room and like,
I'm already like just right when
I get in there. You have some kid,
that kid David Taylor, you know that
kid, he's a tall guy, used to do comedy.
He's very cynical and negative and I just,
I wasn't in the mood for it.
I hadn't seen them in months and
I said hi to him and he goes,
I'm staying around just to see you.
You better be good.
And so right away I'm like,
I haven't seen you in a fucking long time.
You have no right to fucking talk like
that to me enough with the negative shit,
you know?
And I stormed off
and I walked back and made me feel
really good about myself by that cause
usually I sound like the angry psycho.
I can be like the happy person.
That's where take, take a
break. Yeah. Thank you. Oh go
ahead. You Go. All right. So,
so I get on stage magical one on who I
think is just terrific. I love al. He's,
I think he's fucking hilarious. It's
really original, unique stylists,
real storyteller. He does good, you know,
and then he brings me up
and then I'm getting laughs.
There's only like 30 or 40 people
in the or and it's going fine.
There's an old couple up front,
the Oh maybe in their mid
fifties early sixties and they,
if someone talked to him and [inaudible]
and they asked him about religion,
I think Neal Brennan did. They said
they were Jews. I'm like, fine.
So I'm doing my show and
they're not laughing at nothing.
And I looked at them and I said,
uh, I'm sorry, my two filthy,
you want me to talk some political
stuff, you know, is, is that what it is?
And then the old man looks at me, he
goes, you're not funny. Yeah. And I,
and I just had this moment where I'm like,
all right, dude, all right. And I said,
you know what, I am
funny. I know I'm funny.
I'm doing well with the rest
of the audience. All right.
And, and I, and, and I,
I understand what you're saying. And, uh,
and then like for some reason
I just looked at him, I said,
but the fact that that's what you had
to pull out of your guts to say to me in
this situation makes me fucking hate you.
And,
and, and the real punchline there, mark.
So now you lose the rest of the crowd.
That's right. This is quite in the room.
And I'm like, what? That wasn't funny.
What did I say? Did Not come out funny
now you turn on the rest of them.
All right. Then I turned on the rest of
them. And then, uh, and then he goes,
you know, you asked and I said, well, you
didn't, you could have qualified it. Like,
how about you're not funny to me.
All of a sudden you're the god of this
fucking room. You're the Almighty.
You're the one that has the last
word. Fuck that. Right. And so that,
and then like you were in a bad mood
before you got there because you're going
to say the read of this guy
saying you are not funny.
Sounds to me like you said some
shit that he didn't want to hear.
It was more of a subject thing. Not,
not, no, I just, it was a general thing.
So then I,
and the rest of the act,
I'm doing my act and everyone's
laughing every time everyone else will.
After I looked at him and I went,
Huh, Huh. And then like, you know,
at the end of my set and bringing
that Brenda is easy and he,
he stands up with his wife and they
walk out and while I'm still on stage
bringing up Steve and I got very
powerful statement, very powerful.
I'll see you later, dad. Oh
Jesus mark. Cause that's what
I said to him. I said, hey,
like you know, it's like every fucking
Jewish guy that has that kind of judgment.
That's your age.
You just some surrogate for my
father and I understand I'm trans,
I'm transposing some contempt on you,
but you could have fucking
shows a different way. All
right. All right. Anyways,
Mark Marin here on Monday morning,
but that's not funny. No, no, no.
I'm just letting people know I'm acting.
You know what I just did there?
I acted like this was a live show.
I like it. We'll take some callers
[inaudible].