Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Just checking.
I'm just checking in on you.
Seeing how you're doing. How are
you today? Huh? Are you upset?
Thursday afternoon, the Thursday
night football. What happened?
What happened during the song this time
that made people upset and decided that
they were going to get all up in arms
about their corner of the fucking world.
Unbelievable. I'm so fucking an hour.
I'm going to be the guy talking.
I'm so fucking listening to people making
that thing about what they want it to
be about. It's like, that's not
what the initial protest was about.
If you would like to discuss
police brutality are more
than willing to listen to
what, I don't want to hear
your fucking Soliloquy.
You know all those people who are
like, you know, want to be the revenue.
Like I don't even care. I don't even
he, yeah, of course you don't care.
It doesn't fuck what they talking about
doesn't affect you. It's not about you.
Okay. But gives a fuck. It's one
moment at the beginning of the game
commenting on something that people are
trying to fix. That's all. That's all
my biggest complaint about tonight's game
between the bears and the fucking pack
is they stop the game because there's
potential of lightning God for fucking
bed. Somebody gets
electrocuted. It's unbelievable.
It's unbelievable how important human
being still consider other human beings.
I just don't have it. It really
isn't about that. It's like full.
Do you think the NFL gives a
fuck about you? They don't.
They don't give a shit about you.
They don't want you to get electrocuted
because then you can't go out and buy
another jersey or another
ticket or NFL Sunday ticket.
That's what they care about and some
are, they're going to get blamed, right,
because everybody in the crowd
is going to be like, well,
they should've known that
God was going to do that.
Okay.
You should have known what the weather was
going to be. You know? There's no more,
Hey, Fucko, you went outside,
you know what's outside lightning and you
went outside and God dammit lightening
found you and that's your own dumb luck.
Guess what?
You can have your own Wikipedia page now.
You don't have one now.
Nobody knows who the fuck you are,
but you get struck by lightening.
Okay,
Jami is going to find you on Wikipedia.
Maybe you won't get your own page.
You might be on a page.
That's just the list of people struck by
lightning in 2017 or in or in whatever
the fuck we're calling this decade.
It has to be an extraordinary
circumstance to when you
get struck by lightening,
for you to get your own Wikipedia page,
you'd have to get struck by lightening
and then something else happens.
He struck by lightning.
You catch on fire and you run into
a paper machine factory. All right?
With a bunch of children there,
hose make a wish was that they could go
to or make our fucking paper machine a
factory.
Then you run in there and and then it all
goes up and all those little kids died.
Then now they need to have to share
it with the kids. It's a tough thing.
It's hard to get struck by lightning
and get your own Wikipedia page,
you know? You know what's funny
is if that actually happened,
you got struck by lightning. You had a
nice afro going, you catches on fire,
you run into a paper, Ms Shea
factory, there was a bunch of,
make a wish kids in there and
then they all fucking died.
The funniest fucking thing about all
of that is how much shit your relatives
would get. You know what I mean?
Saying Ah, you know that gag guy,
he's one of those Wilson
kids. Yeah. You know,
his fucking brother gets struck by
lightning instead of just die and laying
there burning the fucking asshole content.
He has runs into a paper machine factory
and kills a bunch of kids that were
already dying anyways.
You know,
then everybody treats them like shit.
Like you can keep your wits about
you when your head's on fire.
The bottom line is, is uh, I don't
know what happened to football.
I don't ever remember it being
stopped because of weather used to be,
they play in all kinds of weather.
Right.
And you had the ice bowl
up there in green bay.
You had that game when all the locust to
send it down on the Kansas city chiefs
when they played the fucking uh,
New York titans.
I'm just making up shit at this point.
I don't know what happened to the game,
but now any time there's going
to be a little bit of crosswind,
what if it blows somebody's sunglasses
off and goes into somebody's eye?
I mean Jesus Christ, those, those
people that, that's what's constant.
The amount of layers of clothes and
blubber you have to go through after the
lightning strikes him to even like,
you know,
rattle a few fillings loose of the
average person in Wisconsin. These are,
these are, these are wholesome
people up there. Okay.
They get that ll bean catalog and
to those people that is formal,
where do you understand that? You know,
when you get married in Wisconsin,
you can actually show up, you
know, you know like everybody,
you're going to wear
tails with your Tuxedo.
They ask him if they're going to wear
those fucking, you know, his rubber pants.
It was fucking with the suspenders.
When you go trout fishing,
somebody was saying there was some
fucking guy, he walked out into the ocean.
I don't know why the fuck he was in a
river, some sort of water, a watery area,
and he walked in there and this wave
came in and washed into his fucking pants
at telecom,
tipped him over and he couldn't get up
because the combination of the weight of
his ass and his legs, those rubber
pants and all the water in it,
it just fucking a heat drought.
I don't know if that's true.
That sounds like something a
fucking old lady with Tyson.
All this fucking old lady. When
I was a kid, you know back when,
you know parents didn't watch their kids
like parenting back in the day you woke
up, you gave him fucking, you
know the multicolored cereal.
He opened the door and they went outside
and they just met other kids and with
your kid brains, you figured out what
you were going to do that day. Well,
there was this old lady who lived around
the corner and she still always tell us
all these crazy fucking stories.
She had terrible candy to where you'd
still show up. I don't know why.
And she used to be a one time
now. I mean, she may know,
and Jamie and we gauge guy any,
he tried to stomp his foot down on the
brakes to stop so he wouldn't go to their
job shining. She said that his leg when
all the way up until his body and his,
and it was like six inches shorter
in front of the rest of his life.
He walked around and he couldn't get him.
You know,
I used to come home and I'd repeat the
stories to my mother. Right. I'd be like,
mom, he key it. Yeah. You know, one
tiny, I was a guy, his leg went,
been to his body and she, one day she
just finally, I think was listened to me.
She just looked at me. She goes, who
told you that? And I was like, oh,
the lady down this cheat. She goes,
don't listen to her. She's crazy.
I don't know why my mother talk like that.
I needed to do a different voice.
She doesn't smoke.
I Dunno what the fuck I'm talking about.
But what would you expect from
someone who forgot it was Thursday.
That's how awesome my life is.
I forgot it was Thursday.
Now sometimes you can forget it's Thursday
because your life is fucking terrible,
right? Your roundup, right?
You're on a fucking bender or you're,
you're like,
I don't know what you're fucking,
um,
I dunno. You fucking,
you're a political prisoner.
You forget what date is your in Shawshank.
All right.
Sometimes you fight them off.
Sometimes you don't.
You're marking off the days he
got Rita Hayworth on the wall.
You don't know what fucking date is.
Not even if you're Andy do frain and
you're good with numbers, you lose track.
And the only other people
that lose track of that,
of people who work for themselves, which
I don't, I work for Netflix now, I guess.
I don't know. I just, you
know, after awhile you just
said, what fucking day is it?
I Dunno. Another day.
Living the dream day. Um,
anyways. Okay. Football, Sundays
coming up. What a bomb booty booty.
I'm going to start doing my
gambling pick of the week,
my gambling pick of the week.
All right.
I'm guaranteeing you that
if you gamble on this game,
money is going to change hands either
out of your pocket or into your pocket or
it might be a push.
I'm guaranteeing that he called me up
at one 800 freckles, fat, fat, fat.
Um,
the giants getting three and Tampa Bay,
that giants, the O in three
giants. Everybody looking
at him like that, washed up,
forgetting that Eli Manning has won two
super bowls against the reigning super
bowl champions. They beat
bill Bellacheck two times. Um,
you guys got two rings, you know
he's got, he's got two rings,
he's got no respect and he's
got half an offensive line,
but I think this week to get
in three there under dogs,
they did fine. Fine against Philly
last week. That came back late.
But who gives a shit?
They still scored 20 something points.
I didn't really pay attention. Right?
And then they lost on a 61 fucking year,
right?
Some fucking dude from nine oh
two one o came walking in. Right.
They just fucking kicked the God damn
thing like the end of a Hollywood movie.
All right.
Ain't going to happen. They're going to
go down to Tampa. Okay. First of all,
nobody respects the Tampa Bay Buccaneers.
You know why?
Because they have a giant pirates of
the Caribbean ship inside their stadium.
I don't know what they're trying to do.
I don't understand how
the Oakland Raiders, okay.
Who have like a pirate on the side of
their helmet are able to achieve the
baddest, baddest fucking uniform in all
the sports. As far as I'm concerned.
They, when they moved to Vegas and
they have the white home jerseys,
they better go back to the silver numbers
or I'm or my name isn't Billy fat tits.
Alright.
Tampa Bay Buccaneers,
I don't understand is what is
a buccaneer. Exactly. Okay,
let's look this up because
judging by their colors,
I feel like it's more like the
musical theater sort of pirate.
It's much more,
let's just go out and have an adventure
rather than raping and pillaging.
Okay.
What do we got here? All right, and
then fucking Buccaneers loss last week,
34 to 17 so they're coming off a big loss.
That's always a concern.
What the fuck is a buccaneer? Buccaneer.
All right. Buccaneers were a kind.
Okay.
A privater or pirate. What's
a privater? Private tier.
Okay.
A private tier was a private person.
Also, they keep to themselves. Well,
that's not really good
in a team sport is it?
Or a ship that engaged in
maritime warfare. Okay.
Under a commission of war.
Yeah.
All right. Well, they did it
very officially. All right.
Okay.
Particularly to the Caribbean Sea. Yeah.
Pirates of the Caribbean. That's right.
Originally the name applied to the
landless hunters of wild boars and cattle,
and they largely uninhabited areas of Tor,
Toga and Hispaniola.
The mic caught.
They smoked over a slow fire. Where
the fire, what are we talking about?
Something about jerk me or Jerky.
Why should we fear these people?
Do you know what?
This is just a whole bunch of reading
that I don't want to do it when caught by
anti pirate English authorities. Seventh
all right. You know what I need to do?
What's the dose screen? A pirate in a
buccaneer. Oh, what's the difference?
What's the difference
between a or and O'quinn read
in a buccaneer I would say
about 30 pounds, judge.
I've been, well, I've never
been to the Tampa stadium.
Might be there in a few weeks. So, okay.
Buccaneer verse rate or
what's The difference?
This is why you got to love the Internet.
I'm not saying they have a right answer,
but they always have an answer.
What's the difference?
A buccaneer is a synonym
of radar as nouns.
The difference between a buccaneer in a
raider is that buccaneer is an UN is not
a goal.
Any of a group of semen.
TJ's no.
See men who cruised on their own account
on the Spanish main and in the Pacific
in the 17th century,
similar to pirates,
but did not pray on ships of their own
nation while a raid is one who gauges,
engages in a raid, colon,
semicolon, a plunderer.
Okay,
well what the fuck is a raid and
what is a plunderer? See this,
this is what you do.
You have fucking,
okay.
Plunderer.
Okay.
The plunderer is a fictional character,
so they, they don't even exist.
I don't want this fucking,
yeah,
that was actually a superhero.
Dare Devil fought the plover.
Okay.
Plunderer come on man. Come
on. Give me something. Give
me something. Hey, your cons.
Plunder.
Wikipedia is just such a one trick pony.
Sometimes they just keep guiding
you back to the same fucking
okay.
To plunder the public treasury to take
wrongfully as pillage. Yeah. Okay.
All right. You know what? I don't even
give a shit anymore. How about that?
All I know is whoever fucking drew the
Raiders logo did not draw the Buccaneers
logo. That first one at least
and less. He was a rate of fence.
It was like these for these fucking
guys saying that kind of like us.
We already took this name.
Let me see. Tampa Bay
fucking ears speed.
Like a porno logo.
What do we got here? That's sort
of a pirate. Oh, the day, you know,
they kind of ripped off.
They're trying to rip off the old fucking
oh find to rip off the Raiders here.
Well, let's see. They're fucking original.
Their original logo was just like,
I think it was Tom Selleck.
I don't know what it was. Nah, man,
I'm really Tom Selleck
sort of winking at you.
Okay.
Tiniest of knives in his fucking mouth.
There's the one I remember right there.
The creamsicle.
Okay.
Yeah, I don't what that was. He
looked like a three musketeer.
You look like a good guy.
I think that that was the problem.
Was there a point to any of that? I
don't think there was. Um, anyways,
this is one of the,
this is one of the greatest times of the
year in United States sports and who's
kitty? Our sports are the
best. If you don't believe it,
if you don't believe our athletes
are the best, I'm telling you,
you need to watch the Olympics.
Okay.
All of our white athletes
dominating all of those games.
Well, maybe we do. We do well in the
Winter Olympics though, we now we don't,
we lose to the fucking Canadians.
We beat the Canadians in like the juniors.
We always beat them because anybody like
our age is already made it up to the
fucking Nhl, you know? But you got
to give those Canadian something
hockey. They got [inaudible]
you got to let him have hockey.
Even though the Russians are kind
of slowly taken away from them.
A lot of European players,
the game is slowly being taken away from
their sticky served fingers up there.
Okay. We all understand this. All right.
And they're going to hang on for
dear fucking life. Cause if Canada,
God forbid ever was to lose hockey,
what would they be left with?
[inaudible]
what would they be left with
that shuffleboard on ice that they play?
What do they call it?
What do they call that? Uh, what
the fuck is it? And you slide.
He just let that fucker go right.
That big
sort of a wheel, isn't it? It's a rim.
Kind of looks like a rim off of a jeep
that they turned into a giant hockey puck.
That's what it says. An obese hockey
puck. What the fuck do you call it? Curly.
I don't know why they call it curly.
There's no hooking.
There's nothing like that, you
know, fucking, I have no idea. Um,
anyways,
so you have playoff baseball's coming up.
Who is going to start hockey's going to
start college and pro football's going.
The CFL is getting close to the Grey Cup.
All right.
I mean just what else could you want?
Okay.
The Formula One in Moto GP are going to
be wrapping up here in the next 40 days.
Mrs. Exciting fucking times. Let's check
out the baseball standing. Shall We?
Everybody. Who Do, we got here,
those Boston red sox
hanging on for dear life,
three games ahead of the New York,
the New York Yankees.
Um,
Tampa Bay devil rays,
soon to be Montreal Expos.
Spoiler alert. Um, I've been
telling you guys that story.
I must have told this story at the time.
I went to the Montreal
Expos game by myself.
I was doing this Gig in upstate
New York and um, you know,
I was trying to go to all the fucking
stadiums. So I was like, all right, well,
you know, let's see
this Montreal, the end,
they got a fucking game and the game the
next day. So I went up, I did this Gig,
I think I did the Lake Ontario playhouse.
I know I've told this story before,
but what maybe I've got a few listeners
maybe from something from checking. Yeah.
Is Listening. Maybe
somebody from Romania. Um,
anyways,
so there was a game the next day,
so I ended up trying to cross the border
into Canada. Uh, this is pre nine 11,
by the way,
in a very weird spot by myself.
So I get stopped at the border and the
guy tells you, guy asked me, he was like,
oh, it's well, what are you doing there
fella? He's Canadian dude. And I said,
I'm going to an expo game now. The Expos
had lost probably about, I don't know,
like 120 games at that
point during the season.
And he goes off, you're making some
friends up there. And I was like,
nope. Going by myself. And he was like,
Oh hey Paul, would you mind pulling
over right there for a second?
So he asked me, pull over and like two
more of these fucking guys come out
and they start ripping apart my car and
they send me inside and I'm like, what?
The Pfizer is some sort of random
drug search and I'm just sitting there
watching them and they're ripping
it apart and ripping her apart.
And then it suddenly fucking dawns on me
like,
what kind of a fucking loser? I
mean, I was like two hours away.
It was a drive two hours out of my way
to go up there to go to Montreal Expos,
game by myself.
This guy could not fathom
that any human being,
even one that looked like me would have
that much of a pathetic moment in their
life. He was convinced I was some
sort of drug mule or whatever,
I guess drug meals.
It was that when you have it up your ass,
but they never checked my ass.
They just check the fucking car.
So it suddenly dawned on me that they
thought there was no way that I was that
pathetic, but I knew the real
answer was yes. I was apathetic.
So it just struck me as funny and I
started laughing and I couldn't stop.
And I remember the cop looking over at
me and he saw me laughing and I think he
thought I was laughing,
like he couldn't find the drug,
so they were out there for
like a fucking half hour. Okay.
And then once I knew that
they thought I had drugs,
then I was just kind of acting like a
dick and I had a shitty and grin on my
face as I came walking up smiling. Okay.
And they will, the guy was getting mad,
like I was smiling,
like he didn't find it or whatever.
And uh,
then I went up there and went up there
and this fucking French con acted like he
didn't understand what I said when I
asked him to take my picture because I
didn't have anybody to take my picture
because I was by myself and one of those
disposable cameras and it just that the
story just keeps getting worse and worse.
Um, when I called him a conti
laughed and walked away. Um,
so anyways, I was sitting out
in like fucking left field
and uh,
it was such an old stadium. I
don't know, just under budget.
I think it's socialism up there,
you know,
and they just don't step on the
poor the way we do up here. Um,
out in the outfield. Your seat only had
one arm rest. That's what I remember.
Even on the left or on the right,
I can't remember what,
and I was sitting out there and all the
fans not paying attention to the game,
the fans had showed up and they would
just sing in Ole, Ole, Ole, Ole,
that soccer fucking song. And
I was watching, I swear to God,
I saw this guy and I'm like,
I watched this guy steal home plate
and I'm way out in left field.
So I jumped up. I was like, yeah,
when he stole home plate
and nobody else jumped up,
Whitney and it was really quiet in
the stadium. So then I was like,
oh fuck. Maybe that was
something else. Maybe, I don't
know. Maybe it's a pass ball.
Maybe a, it was a Bach.
I didn't know what.
So I fucking sat back down and felt
stupid cause everyone was looking at me.
And then later on that night,
I was back at the fucking
hotel and I was watching TSN.
That's their ESPN up there. And
they're like, they're like, oh,
it's something you don't see every day.
And they showed a guy stealing home
plate and I was like, fuck it. You know,
that's my expo story. Matt.
Riveting, but not boring. All right.
Then he got the Cleveland
Indians crushing it, crushing it,
one 22 winters of 22 in a row. Um, I
feel like they've won like maybe what,
like, like 25 of they last 30, not 27. Um,
they're in. And who else?
The Houston Astros. Ah,
wow. Well, look who's finally
in the American league.
Finally put on your big boy pants
and he gets stopped playing.
Hit and run and get yourself nice and Roy
it up and try to hit it over the fence.
Uh, uh, the Washington
senators in first place,
I didn't fucking know that the
cubs look into repeat the Dodgers.
I went to the dodger game last night.
They went fucking tend to nothing. Uh,
had a great time.
We sat right down on the field,
like terrifyingly close,
like I tried to make sure I watched
every damn pitch and uh, you know,
I'm not boozing.
So you know,
that's also scary if you booze
and you know, you're all relaxed,
so your heads like fucking foam
rubber, you know what I mean? It's,
you just bounces off at one app and
whether, you know, you don't know,
you order another fucking
round. Right. But, um,
I've stone sober sitting
there, so actually realize
what the fuck it happened.
So I was staying right on it.
What a great stadium that is.
Just a great stadium, great fans
out there. You know what I mean?
As long as you don't wear a different
colored Jersey and you don't sit on the
bleachers, you know what I mean? As
long as you're not with your kids. Um,
it's a great stadium. It's a great, so
long as you rooting for the Dodgers.
It's a wonderful time. And I went
there. I had a pretty good time.
I had a great time, I should say. I
meant to say I ate pretty good eight.
Pretty good. I got a little off my diet
diet when I was in fucking Toronto.
So I think my calf is healed up.
We're going to try to hit the elliptical
tomorrow. Hey, guess what? Old freckles,
freckles. His plane. Um,
the Monte Carlo tomorrow in Las Vegas.
Uh,
it's going to be great.
Bunch of people from F is for family
are coming out or a bunch of writers are
going to be at the show. So I'm
hoping I'm going to have a good one.
I'm very excited to play that
one. That's the one from um, uh,
not river Phoenix.
What was the name of that fucking movie?
Ocean's 13 or 1215?
Whatever the fuck it was called where
everybody's still all those good looking
fellow. He stood out there,
right? Looking at the, uh,
the uh, what was it though? The
fonts, the font shooting off.
You guys saw them over? Yeah, that's
stick to casino. I'm playing that one.
I've always wanted to play that one.
And we said it was the cleanest in class.
He's looking one, at least from the
outside you walk in and the things,
they all look the same. But anyway,
so let's, let's get onto the um,
okay.
It's going onto the a, what
do we got here? A little bit
of a advertising here. Oh,
draft kings, everybody. Draftkings
okay. And I said I, what did I say?
Giants getting three giants getting
three on three. Ready. All right.
Draft Kings football season has begun.
What are your political prisoners?
You don't realize that but it's not too
late to get closer to the game you love
with draft kings one
week fantasy football.
This is draft kings is hosting a 100,000.
Sorry, this is capitals. I
screamed. Capitals, thanks
gift. They have a capital.
I'm going to scream it.
Dollar contest.
That is totally to enter
when draft with draft kings.
There are many ways to play but only one
way to choose between public contests,
butts with big cash prizes or private
contest where you can compete against a
group of your friends.
No saying mean stuff in here.
Let's make this a safe place.
Draft kings also has a beginner in cat.
Oh,
you're a big boy.
Degenerate and casual contest.
Will you play against people
of a similar skill level?
And you'll never burn up the waiver
wire trying to replace injured players
because you get to pick a
new team every God damn week.
That's the beauty of one
week fantasy and draft kings.
She'll get to graph kings.com now,
now and use Promo Code Bar to play in
draft kings free contest with a $100,000
dollars in prizes.
[inaudible] Sunday.
That's Promo Code Burr to compete for
your share of a 100,000 a hundred thousand
dollars in prizes. The contest,
it's totally free to enter.
Why wouldn't you try draft
kings that game inside the game?
Eligibility restrictions apply.
See draft kings dotcoms for details.
All right. Oh look who's back. Bateau doe
Mandy's me undies taken a fucking need
to do to do beyond ease from seed to
fucking chain change.
The white people say it means this
and black people say it means that
Barb, we are good. Where Nice,
comfortable underwear with a
guts hanging over our ball.
Bags me undies.
You want to look good and your
underwear and be comfortable,
but that perfect balance
is hard to find every day.
One of your balls is hanging a little bit
more to the right than the left. Well,
don't sacrifice style
or comfort or your nuts.
Checkout me undies.com and find the
best pair of underwear in the world.
Talk about why me undies is the
best underwear you will ever own.
I'll tell you why because they're the only
underwear company paying me right now.
Me undies has an exclusive offer just
for my listeners and probably a thousand
other podcasts.
Get 20% off your first pair and free
shipping and me undies is so sure you will
love their underwear.
They even offer a 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
You order a pair and if you don't love
your first pair, get a full refund.
This is a no brainer to try 20% off free
shipping and our percent satisfaction
guarantee.
What are you waiting for to get 20%
off and free shipping and their 100%
satisfaction guarantee and get the best
price and softest underwear you will
ever own.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] this is
a limited time offer that
I've been reading for like fucking a
year now. So what are you waiting for?
Start wearing the best
underwear of your life.
Don't you think your clam and nuts
deserve it? It's changed my life.
Evidently it's time to let
me undies change yours.
Go to me undies.com/burr right now.
All right,
last one lastly,
but not leastly legal zoom.
Everybody.
Ya know when you run your own business,
you know that time equals money.
It's not just an old saying,
it's a fucking fact.
So why waste your valuable time dealing
with issues that legal zoom can help you
with?
Huh?
You may already know that over 2 million
people have used legal zoom to start
their businesses,
but legal zoom services do not end.
They're running a business
comes with taxes, contracts,
hiring employees, changing the filter
and the air conditioning system.
Basically a lot of fine print.
That's why legal zoom built a network
of independent attorneys licensed in all
50 states.
They can provide the advice you need to
get through the daily grind of running
your business.
And you don't have to worry about billable
hours since legal zoom is not a law
firm.
Instead you can count on upfront pricing
and clarity and invest your time and
money in growing your business and let
legal zoom help out with the legal stuff.
For special savings,
be sure to enter Promo Code Bur bur
are in the referral box at checkout.
That's Promo Code Bar for a special
savings only@legalzoomdotcomlegalzoom.com.
All right, there you go. There you go. Um,
somebody asked me do a bent benefit today
way
they'll Rico, those poor bastards are
still without power door. You know,
after you have to getting hit by that
hurricane and everybody's over here
talking about somebody taking a knee.
I actually think taking a knee is more
respectful than standing up, isn't it?
Christ the guys on his fucking knees.
Um,
so hopefully I'll be able to do that.
Hopefully people stops focusing on the
song and start focusing more on the
heroin epidemic,
right arm on my soap box.
The fact that we're feeding cows to
other cows and cutting the beaks off of
birds that I walked around doing face
plants because their breasts are too
fucking big.
You know,
he can't even give them a big to
fucking land on. That's like dent.
Mack said gets smart episode where they
put them in the Gurney and they strapped
him in and then there was only one of
those fucking rotary doors and they stood
him up.
You ever seen that one?
They push them through and
he does the fucking face
plant. Oh, that bit killed me.
I loved it back in the day.
Can you tell them a huge me TV fan?
I've been taping the twilight zones over
there and not only is the twilight some
great. What's awesome about it
is afterwards I then get to do,
my favorite thing is Google to see
how much of the cast is dead and I was
surprised.
I watched the one that was the bewitched
pool and the both of the little kids is
still alive. They're in their
sixties the mother is still alive,
still alive and kicking like 89 years old.
However,
the dad fucking dropped like less than
10 years later in the early seventies had
a heart attack. You know what I mean?
That was a big thing back in the day,
guys died of heart attacks in women
died of accidental overdose overdoses.
You know, cause anytime they
got air quote hysterical,
they would give them black beauties
and only case a Holly itself, you know,
they'd get slapped around and the
doctor's office and then, you know,
to make sure the swelling went down,
they would give him these relax of fires
for their cheeks in their, in their,
in the rest of their body. Something
like that. And I forget how it goes,
but that's what I do.
Like I watch Hawaii five o just about
every night and the other night they had
this episode called to hell with
Babe Ruth. And that was a big rumor,
right? That back in the day, back
in the day when that was young,
I'm not acute anymore. They used to, um,
hello,
but come on in,
turn the KNOB.
Oh, I thought you were coming
in. So back in the day,
uh Oh, it's still lovely. Nia.
I can't,
I can't stay though. Well, get out.
Why'd you come in there?
Oh yeah.
What are you ordering like,
um,
like Armenian for like, you
know, Middle Eastern food,
lamb and rice and that sort of
thing. Lamin right. All right.
Well and I already ate for the evening.
I and another two bullies salad with
chicken. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's fascinating. So I'm
gonna go order dinner. Hi.
I haven't seen you in so long. We were
supposed to have a date night tonight.
Yeah. And you blew me off. Not that blew
me off. I didn't blow you off. I just
papa, Papa. All right. To
hell with Babe Ruth. Okay.
This is alleged allegedly,
is it over officially done?
Yes. You're being dismissed. You
know what, Nia, you're fired.
No Am I am at the end of the podcast
here and I was telling them about that to
hell with Babe Ruth thing.
Remember the Hawaii five o I was showing
you when they had the white guy playing
the Japanese guy? Yes. But then
the lady, he was with boost.
I don't know if she was Japanese,
but she was definitely Asian. Yes.
And so she's got to sit there and look
at him with this fucking white guy,
stupid thing. And then they put
this awful makeup around his eyes.
This is 50 years ago.
Yep.
There you go. I don't want to say
about it. I'm just bringing it up.
That was terrible. Well, it's true. If
it was half a century ago, and he said,
come on the podcast again.
Okay. No. [inaudible] dokie.
So anyways,
um,
okay.
Allegedly during the World War II,
when the Japanese soldiers
would do a bunch I charge,
which just was fucking as suicidal
charge I guess, or whatever.
Like Japan was not fucking around.
There was no quitting.
Okay. There was no, everybody
gets a ribbon. All right?
They would just,
if you fucking did,
there was no surrendering to your
fucking enemy. So during those Buns,
I charges allegedly,
I don't know if this is propaganda,
they would yell either to hell with
Babe Ruth or fuck babe Ruth is what they
would yell.
Right.
So Babe Ruth got wind of it and
there's a quote in the New York Times,
I got to get this right. I don't
want to misquote the sultan of Swat.
The only man who ever had a ballpark
built around it is fucking abilities. Um,
let me see if I can find this. Uh, you
can't. I can't find it. He basically said,
he goes, any JAP that says that
I hope they, I hope he get shot.
He goes,
and while we're at it,
it goes to hell with all the jabs that
was written in the New York Times.
You know,
you could never do that in 1969 by the
time that episode of Hawaii five o came
out,
but what you could do was have a white
guy with the worst makeup ever around.
I'm going to fucking,
I'm going to post the picture.
I got to post a picture I, which I, I
don't know if I'm going to do it either.
I just want to make sure. Oh, I just
got a picture of John Daly in a fucking,
in his sweatpants
fucking
making a chocolate shake from self in
a glass that had the Arkansas razorback
thing on it. Is there anything
about John Daly? That is an awesome
anything.
Um,
so anyways,
I was watching this episode and this guy,
I'm watching the whole time going, that
guy is not Japanese. What the fuck?
I was looking, there's something
wrong with his eyes or whatever.
And I finally looked up the actor.
I don't know what he was,
he was first generation something
or other, but it was not cheap.
You should just see the seats face his
whole face, his fucking white features.
Then he had his, like, he was
sort of squinting his eyes.
All I was just was horrific. Felt
bad for the lady across from, I
can't imagine what she said when
she came home and just playing.
He gave the didn't even look good.
So anyways, I guess what I'm saying, it's,
it's about time we make a
World War Two movie, you know,
we actually have Japanese
people play Japanese soldiers.
Can we at least do that?
Hasn't been done. I don't
know. I watch sports, okay?
And there is no fact checking
whatsoever when it comes to a,
when it comes to this podcast,
guys,
I audit the greatest fucking motherfucking
cock sucking fucking whiskey glass
you will ever own in your fucking life
and it's so awesome that I know when you
see it, you're going
to want it. All right?
This guy's got a small operation,
so I'm not going to tell you who it is
until I ordered some more and get my
order in and then I'm going
to let you know on Monday,
Monday, Monday. I can't be that much
of a cunt. This is a great gift.
If you have a fucking person who loves,
hang on a second,
loves to drink with me,
and the holidays are coming up. Please
tell me he says the guy's name on it.
Hang on a second. God dammit. I
got to give you the name. Ethan,
the greatest fucking whiskey glasses ever.
This guy, he a and is this,
does this sound right? This
sounds kind of perverted.
He blows his own glass.
It was a bad time to pause and that
how he blows his own three, two,
one glass. Um, Nate Cotterman, n a t.
E C o. T. T. E r m.
A N Nate Cotterman Dotcom,
um,
can make you all kinds of things.
I actually fucked up my order.
I called the number up and he, the
guy just picked up, he's like, hello?
I'm like, ah, yes. Night there. He's,
I guess. And I, I'm like, yeah, dude.
I ordered the Riaa put an order for
eight glasses. I ordered the wrong ones.
I wanted the ones with the square cube.
And he goes, Hey, I saw that. All right,
I'll take care of that.
How'd you hear about us?
I was just looking at Wiki
whiskey glasses. This is
what the guy does. All right,
for all you guys out there and you
drink the top shelf boots. All right.
You're a self made man or you were
born into it. Give a fuck. Right?
You got you a woman in line.
No. Um, and you've got to,
you got to top shelf,
bottle of booze and you respect the booze.
He respect the artists,
artists who fucking whatever the fuck
did whatever he did to make it as smooth
and is and is and his tasty God.
This is going to make me go right off
the wagon and it's tasty as it is in and
you, but you want it cold, you know?
So there's all these different things.
There's these giant ice cubes you can
put in there, these big square ones,
but eventually towards the end,
you know the,
the water's going to start
leaking into the booze.
You get me talking tap water
here. Okay? Like beavers,
shit in this stuff it is is mixing
in with your God Damn Booze.
You can't have that.
Okay.
The, the aroma of duck feet is, is,
is coming in Dt or pristine
firewater here. Right?
So then they also have, they
got these metal cubes or
whatever, but then you know,
no matter what,
there's going to be some sort of metallic,
maybe Blahblahblahblahblah.
This guy Nate,
all hail Nate,
he makes a whiskey glass
and then he makes a,
a square glass fucking ice cube
and marries that to the glow.
It becomes part of the glass.
Then you take the whole fucking glass,
you stick it in the fridge, the freezer
or whatever, and then everything's called.
Okay. And then you pour it in there.
Okay. The Bose has nowhere to hide.
It's surrounded on all
sides by nice chilled,
frigid glass.
But none of it leaks into the boots.
So you can drink it neat
and have it ice cold.
You can have your fucking cake
and eat it with these glasses.
I cannot say enough about them.
I absolutely love these fucking glasses
and I haven't even used them yet.
They got a little way to them too. So if
you, if your limp wristed and you know,
if you're, you know, I
don't know if you, you know,
back in the day you got an old
roller blading injury and you're,
you're broke both your wrists.
These might not be for you. Okay.
But I fucking love these glasses that
Janet and the coolest Shit, Nick Carter,
man with a c. All right.
That's it. Enjoy the music.
And,
uh,
we've got another half hour shit coming
up from a Thursday afternoon just before
Monday morning podcasts and
a Thursday gone by, you know,
possibly earlier share. Maybe it was from
a three years ago. I don't fucking know.
I don't pick them. All
right. Have a great weekend.
I'll see you in Vegas
and uh, that's it, right?
Yeah.
Yay.
Oh,
this way.
Well, you know what, I didn't
even get to the fucking,
you see that reporter that died?
Let me get to where the
hell is that story here.
This writer for rolling stone,
which I have a subscription to.
Okay.
One of the magazines, few magazines
that I actually read every episode,
every installment. Um, Michael Hastings,
uh,
he had a horrible death.
He fucking was going down,
I believe it was Highland,
just south of Melrose is Mercedes
was traveling at ridiculous speeds.
He hit a fucking tree and
the whole thing exploded,
burst into flames and they had to
identify him by his dental records and uh,
allegedly this guy knew,
okay.
I guess he wrote some fucking article
in rolling stone where he was over in
Afghanistan talking to some higher ups
in the military and they were saying some
shit that they thought was off the record
and he put it all in the article and
there's people conspiracy there is
trying to say that his car was cyber
attacked.
Now I'm not even going to get into that,
but dude,
how fucked up is the world getting if
like that's actually something that
somebody could do. I'm not saying
whether it was done by this guy or not.
I have no fucking idea. He might've
been hammered. I have no idea.
I have no fucking clue.
I don't know anything about it,
but I'm just saying that the fact
that somebody could hack into your
computer and cause your car to speed up.
Okay,
and there's nothing you can,
you can't shut the car off.
Okay.
This is why I don't know that I don't
believe that it's just like his evil is
that is we got to eliminate this guy.
Isn't there a zillion other ways to
kill them without doing that? Like,
what if he slammed into like
a fucking minivan with the F,
you know, a married couple
in their three, four kids.
Okay.
You know, it's gotta be, you know,
can't they just spray some mist on him?
Okay.
You know, just walk up to
them in a mall like, Hi sir,
would you like to try this fragrance?
You just spray it on him and
then the guy like, you know,
10 minutes later and he's trying
on some slacks, he just keels over.
You can't just do it that way.
But anyways, is this true?
Is can they actually do that shit?
And this makes me feel glad that you know,
half my time out here, I drive
around in a classic car, you know,
because now like I'm many sort of a
threat. But what I'm saying is if that,
if I just would think if you
had the ability to do that,
some fucking nerds would just do it
just to do it. Cause it would be funny,
just speed you up for a second and
slow you down just to freak you out.
Okay.
You know,
like,
do you remember back in the day
when this is like pre Internet fun?
What you would do is you'd
take your garage door opener.
Yeah.
Right.
And you would drive around
the neighborhood and he'd
pointed at every garage
until you found somebody
that had the same one as you.
And back in the day they just had
a, like, it wasn't sophisticated.
So not only yours open, not only
yours, it opened the other ones too.
So you'd,
you'd eventually find somebody that had
the same garage door brand is you and
you could open and close the garage
so at least you could my fucking
neighborhood. So you just find,
you use drive one person nuts.
Okay.
You just drive by and you just fuck it.
And every once in a while
would just open it and it,
and I don't know why we would do it.
We were assholes, but so using that,
if you could fucking do that,
um,
with cars, wouldn't, wouldn't
like these people like, you know,
hack into steel, like credit
card numbers and shit. I mean,
wouldn't that be somebody just doing that?
Just to do it like you're bored.
It was this, the, was this the
dumbest part of the podcast?
Everybody did I stick the landing starting
off with ignorance and then a well,
why wouldn't they? Well, fuck,
you know what the reality,
if I ever book a commercial,
I'm going to be, you know,
that commercial where the adults sits
there with all the kids and they go,
you know,
what would you,
what would you do if you had a zillion
dollars and then the kids that I could
buy an island made out
of candy. Yeah, we get,
have hot fudge waterfalls and shit.
I would be sitting there right with,
except it wouldn't be like
the basketball one way.
They were like making fun of the fact,
like I would be like,
you don't want to say I'm saying I'm okay
buddy.
I'm all right for the birds.
Hey Bill,
I got these two parakeets. My problem is
that these little dudes don't like me.
Uh, I've tried whistling,
petting them. I don't know.
You can pet a bird and
squirting them with water.
Okay.
Uh, do they like water? I'm
guessing that that's a good thing.
Parakeets like water.
I don't know.
Why don't we ask the fucking Jimmy's
guy to write a fucking nine pages on it?
I love all them upset with that guy
because he actually did the research as
opposed to me who were like, oh yeah,
I overheard this in a bar. So anyways,
this guy's petting his birds.
He's fucking, he getting
them with the water hose.
He's Westlawn Adam.
Whoo.
I'm all to no avail.
I know they're only birds,
but I feel they hold a deep resentment
towards me where you clip their wings and
you stuck them in a cage.
How would you feel if somebody cut
your fucking nuts off, came by,
started whistling at you
and throwing water at you?
You know,
I got an idea. Why don't you leave
him alone? She opened the cage,
right?
Why don't you take them
to one of those car dash?
She had doctors and I get a little botox
in their fucking wings and let them fly
away.
Okay.
Would that be annoying to you?
If you are in a cage,
your arm's cut off at the FEC and elbows
and somebody came up and rather than
whistle and they started speaking English.
Yeah. You speak in English at you.
He goes, I think it's because I yelled
at them. Oh, here we go. He goes,
I think they resent me
because I yelled at them.
Yeah.
What did you, what, what, what were
they doing a, I said, no, we're fine.
During my shows,
uh,
basically I had to scold them
for pooping in their water dish,
but I had their best interest in mind.
So do you understand how fucking insane
you are that you feel like you can talk
to a bird?
You know,
why don't you like not
stick the water dish,
you know,
underwear that that was
it underneath the swing.
Or what I would do is I just get a
bigger cage. I get a bigger fucking cage.
I put the water in the center that
isn't near any of those trapeze bars and
hopefully they won't be at the top
of the cage is still shit down on it.
Or I would accept the fact
that it's a burden, a cage,
and that it's,
you know,
okay.
Basically anything at
the bottom of the cage.
Mine as well be the city of Dresden.
Right.
I would just take that as part of it.
I wouldn't yell at the birds,
but it was this guy. He had to scold
them for pooping in their water,
but I had their best interest in mind.
I heard if they drink contaminated water,
it can cause a disease that makes
all their feathers fall off.
While you could also read up on it,
as opposed to me who just repeats
shits that they, here he goes,
I do a lot for those little guys,
but putting jackets on nude parakeets
isn't one of them. Even if I wanted to,
I couldn't. They don't even let me
pet them, let alone dress them. Dude,
you're not a bird guy. You should
have got a dog, a, he goes,
when I originally bought them,
I imagine I would have one pair
keyed on each shoulder. Why?
Hanging out around my house,
but whenever I approached the case,
they freeze and horror every time.
They do that. I can't help her.
Remember my brother's face when he fell
through the ice. We had to pull him out.
I thought maybe if I bought
them more toys, they would,
that would somehow help to birds.
Motivation isn't more toys.
Their motivation is you not having energy.
Like I'm going to fucking twist your head
off to their wings are clipped so they
can't escape. You got him stuck in a cage
that terrified and you yelled at him.
I would say more than on one
occasion you yelled at them.
All right.
Um,
you need to fucking relax.
All right,
listen to this.
Would you,
would you want to be like your job
to be in a cage all day? You know,
and then some,
you know,
I dunno.
Some giant comes home and puts you on
his fucking shoulders and your whole job
is to enhance the giants fucking life.
You know what?
I'm having a little bit of
empathy for the fucking birds.
What I would do is I would just have a
totally relaxed energy and hope that they
forget that you're screamed at them,
treat them nicely.
Don't try to pet them, just don't fuck
with them. Every time you come over,
they'll graduate to be like, Oh, this is
the guy who feeds us. Scale brings water.
This guys on our side,
you know,
as opposed to the mixed messages
that you send to them. Um,
yeah. Purchase. Don't
give a fuck about toys,
you know,
do they? I don't think
they do. Um, he said,
I bought them a new toy every Friday
on my way home from work and this is a
ridiculous amount of toys in the cage.
And here's the kicker.
They haven't played with this
single one. Not once. We'll do,
do you look at the birds outside there?
They're not out there.
If you leave your toddler's toys
outside, they don't go, oh good.
They left and then they go down and they
start playing on his fucking tricycle.
He goes, they just stare at
me. I took them to the vet,
but he spent more time looking at
his phone and the birds. Anyways.
Any advice would be greatly appreciated.
Um, I think you should find a bird lover,
sir.
Okay.
And now give the birds
away and then, um, I dunno.
I think you should get your temper in
check and before and before you do that
yet, get your temper in check.
And then if you want to get a dog,
it seems like you want more
interaction with the pet.
Most people get birds because they can
have an interaction with an animal,
but they don't have to walk it down
the street. And, uh, this is very,
a lot less interaction with them.
You seem like you want a bird to
act like a dog slash a little kid.
Like, Hey, daddy's home. I
bought you a fire engine. Oh boy.
Look at that as a bell work. You know,
somehow you want the bird to do that.
MMM,
yeah. Please stop yelling
at your birds. All right.
They can't help if they shit in
the water. You know, the birds,
they're not supposed to be in cages.
They fly around and they shit as they,
they shit when they're on branches,
when they have to go, they go,
they don't have any stress,
they don't have any shame and
there's water all over the place.
So then you've got him in this fucking
cage with little confined area water.
You know, what are, what are they
supposed to do? Well, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
What do I know about the restaurant?
Nay,
nay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and this is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
September 28th, 2009. Uh,
my voice is a little raspy
this morning cause a,
I did a lot of shows this
weekend getting ready for my, uh,
my next hour special that's going
to tape in December. And uh,
somebody actually sent me an
email questioning when, where,
and all that type of shit. And uh,
we're still solidifying all of that.
So the second I know,
I will let you guys know the chosen 14
listeners that I have on my podcast,
which I know at this point
it's more than that. You know,
I've checked out some Google trends and
saw that I think I'm up to about 17.
I have no fucking idea how many people
listen to this and I could give a shit.
All right. That's it. I mean, I, I give
a shit. I want people to fucking listen.
But, um, I don't do this
thing too. Uh, I dunno.
I don't know. It's weird. I don't fucking
hype this thing really. If you find it,
you find it. You fucking
cunts. Um, all right.
So this is my deal. It's Monday
and I'm still in Addison, Texas.
Why do you ask why bill? I
thought Monday was the day. Uh,
you went back to Hollywood and tried to
pursue your dreams of getting into a,
uh, a fucking movie here
or there. Well, I'm,
I'm hanging around one more day cause I'm
going to the cowboys game tonight on a
Monday night football cowboys playing the,
uh,
the fuck are they playing at Carolina
Panthers? I'm kind of out of sorts.
And you know, somebody's not
getting this podcast. Everybody.
You listen to it right now
and it's Tuesday morning.
And I'll tell you why he didn't fucking
get it is because he fucking assholes at
the hotel or rape and me on the Internet.
And you know,
I feel about corporations.
I don't fucking like them.
This is what these fucking assholes do,
right? You sign up for the Internet.
It's 13 bucks a day at this fucking
hotel, right? 13 bucks a day.
That's already ridiculous. All
right? But I'm on the road,
you know, whatever, I'm making some
money here. I'm doing all right.
And I need to fuck. I need the internet.
I lost my fucking blackberry. So I'm like,
all right, fuck it. I'll pay it.
So I sign up for this shit at about 10
o'clock at night after I had flown in
Wednesday night and the next,
you know, the next day, you know,
I signed up for it for four
fucking day. 24 hours, right?
My world a day is 24
hours. All right? So I,
um, you know, I wake up the next
day, I do the morning radio,
I hype my shows. I have a great fucking
time. I come back in the afternoon, I say,
you know what?
I think I'll go on that.
That their new fangled internet that
the kids are talking about, right?
I go to go on the Internet
and Lo and behold,
I'm not on the fucking Internet
anymore and I'm like, wait a minute.
Even though I went to fucking summer
school just about every goddamn year in
high school because of math, I
know how to fucking ad. All right?
Is that Algebra Shit and geometry and
Algebra two and trig and all that shit.
That fucked me up because I'm,
you know,
I'm not into shapes.
The second they started drawing
those triangles on the boy,
I just didn't give a shit.
It's just like really,
you know there's certain things
in life you just fucking, no,
you're never going to use it right now.
I know that you know a lot of the things.
I'm probably fucking the sitting in
this room right now because of geometry.
Look at all his shapes.
When I look around the wind of fucking
look out the window, that's a rectangle.
My doors are rectangle
with a fucking triangle.
Well that's a right angle on the
doorway. Hell, there's four of them,
right?
Is that geometry?
I don't know what the fuck it is because
I'm an Isosceles triangle over by my
phone. I don't fucking know. All right.
But I know, you know what I mean?
He just fucking know some stuff. You
know you're just going to suck at. So
whatever bill, get on comp, we're going
to have to stay on fucking track here.
Right. So anyways, so basically it was,
it had been about 14 hours since I
signed up for the Internet and all of a
sudden I'm not on the
fucking Internet again.
So I go back online to figure out what's
going on. And right after you'd sign,
you sign up for 24 hours.
It says in small print in parentheses
that it expires every day at noon time.
So basically I didn't sign up 24 hours.
What I signed up for was a, yeah,
14 hours.
I paid $13 for 14 hours
of fucking Internet,
eight of which I was
sleeping. Okay. So yeah,
they fucking raped me.
They came up with a new little fucky
fuck charge new little, you know,
they just sit around like these fucking
money grubbing little [inaudible] to
figure out some little fucking way,
you know,
that they can just somehow squeaked they,
I mean,
I'm sure if I sat down and
tried to figure out the map,
the math of like when people arrive in
a hotel and when they usually check out,
like how having it expire every day at
fucking noon gets them a little bit more
money, you know, so they can make
their yachts just a little bit bigger.
So you know what it was usual shit. What
do I do? I call the front desk, right?
And who do I get?
Do I get the head of the corporation that
runs this Internet scam? Of course not.
I get some fucking 25 year old person
who fucking majored in transportation or
fucking,
I dunno,
hotel management and now has no fucking
benefits and is working the front desk
and I'm pissed. So I say to
him, I say, hey, they're chippy.
This is bill Burke calling and
fucking room one zero one eight. Niner
I don't know why. Just wanted to get
military, their alpha red nine or
68 cross power trip, do whatever
the fuck you call it. Anyway,
so fucking call this guy up and I go,
look,
I just signed up for a fucking day and
now it shuts off at noon and the guy goes,
yeah and I,
um,
we don't have anything to do
with that here at the hotel.
The Internet is a
complete separate entity.
So even though you're in the hotel and
you're currently having their dick firmly
and your ass, we don't
have any responsibility on
that. If you'd like to see,
and you know how I can fucking complain,
I have to go back on the fucking Internet
and pay another 13 fucking dollars to
complain to these assholes.
So you know what? Fuck them.
Fuck them fucking assholes. You
know what? You dumped fucks.
You could have got 80 bucks out of me.
I was willing to pay 13 a day even
though that was a total fucking rip off
because you little fucking cunty attitude
now. You only get 13 bucks out of me.
All right.
Yeah.
I don't understand why they do
that. Why they just, I mean,
do people just give into it
trying to find the name of these assholes?
What is it? I see h or something like
that. I didn't know what the fuck it is.
Who gives a shit?
Right?
I'm just having one of these fucking
weeks and now I don't have any questions
because I haven't been on the
fucking internet this week,
so I'm just basically going
to have to wing this podcast.
But fortunately I have plenty of stories
from my wonderful stay out here in
Addison, Texas. Um, here's one for you.
I'm going to be on the road for the
next three weeks. So that's obviously
putting a strain on my relationship. Okay.
Something and maybe I'll do something
nice for the fucking two days.
I'm going to be home over
the next three weeks. And uh,
I'm a big fan of the corvette.
Everybody. Do you like the corvette?
Are you a middle aged American
man like me who never got married?
He doesn't have kids. So now
for some, that's what ends up.
That's when that's when that
car starts appealing to you.
You have to start thinking that
shit. You know, maybe I'll,
maybe I'll get myself a corvette.
Maybe I'll go hang out at an Applebee's
and start hitting on somebody who's at
least fucking born three decades after me.
No, I fucking love Corvettes.
I think they're there.
I just loved the look of the
car. I think it's, uh, you know,
it's an American made car. I think it's
a great value. You know what I mean?
I think, you know, they got a corvette
guy has like fucking 200 miles an hour.
Now granted, I know, I know
that one's like six figures,
but you can get a corvette. Can't you
get a corvette for like 65 grand? I mean,
all I know it's a shitload
of money. But, uh, you know,
I realized halfway through this,
I don't even know how much a Porsche cost.
Is it Porsche or Porsche?
I don't even know how to say it.
That's another car that I fucking love
that, uh, that you know, I can't afford.
You know how much money I'd have to
make a fucking year to justify blowing
basically a house on a
car, house, money on a car.
How's money granted it in fucking
Arkansas somewhere, but still,
you know what I mean? Um, so anyways,
I think the way to go is rather than
fucking going out and spending all that
fucking money on the car,
you just go rent one for a day.
So one day I landed in fucking Burbank
airport and I'm driving by Hertz rental
car. And what do I see? I see a
fucking yellow corvette sitting there.
I'm not into the yellow, but it's still
a core vet. And I'm thinking, you know,
I want, he said, why don't we just
fucking rent one for one day? You know,
I'll rent one full one day. What's that
going to cost? Right? 300 400 bucks.
That's a fuck load of money. But if
it's, it's way less than 70 grant,
75 grand, what the fuck? Why
not rent? One of those things,
you know,
I'll take my girl out,
we'll go for a cruise up in
the fucking Hollywood hills,
will tip it over,
will die.
Just like that fucking dude in the 50s
who look like Fonzie, but that's not him.
What is his name?
Johnny was his name.
Johnny was in every fucking
bad boy named Johnny back then.
Do you have notice that shit. One
of my favorite things to watch, um,
is old,
like those old black and white movies,
whenever the,
they're doing movies about gangs,
you know,
and it's always a bunch of white
actors and half of them are gay,
just flaming homosexuals and they're
trying to act tough and it's fucking
hilarious the way they flip up their
collar and they pull up their sleeves.
What the fuck did I watched the other
day was one of the worst fucking movies I
ever saw in my life
was a Marlon Brando movie.
That one where he's on the motorcycle
and he stops into the town if you want to
fucking, yeah. Do you ever
get embarrassed for someone?
Like somebody is doing something so
douchey that you just fill yourself just
wanting to crawl underneath a fucking
hotel bed and lay next to the dead hooker
that you didn't even realize was there.
You know what I mean?
There is a scene in that movie where
they are in this bar and these two guys
start talking in this street slang and,
and the old bartender just can't
keep up with it. And they go like,
Hey Daddy. Oh, if I can't even
do it, it's so fine. We got an,
I get embarrassed three even trying
to recreate it. It's fucking horrific.
So, uh, the fuck am I
talking about it? Yeah.
I want to rent this God damn car,
right? So I'm, I'll rent it for one day,
right? A for one day. And I tell you
some right now, La, during the day,
especially during these hotter months,
it's fucking horrible.
It's like living in a city.
Let's write outside of God's stove and,
and you know,
that doesn't make sense or trying to,
you know,
I was trying to say that the
joke I was trying to do is like,
you have a heat up an oven.
Sure. We all have. Ah,
at some point you tried to cook a fucking
Turkey. Oh, fucking remind me. I got,
I tell you about a great youtube video.
Y'All, you know what? I'm going to forget.
Let me get back to the stove thing.
Thanksgiving's coming up, everybody.
I now I'm all over the place. I'm going
to fucking finish some Brando thing.
I'm going to finish this stove thing and
I'm going to get back to the corvette
story,
but first I'm going to tell him and I'm
going to take a little break for the
holidays. All right. Over here in America
for all you people overseas, Bu, Bu,
Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, Bu, um,
that was supposed to be ladies and
gentlemen and all the ships at sea. Um,
we have,
we have a holiday over here called
Thanksgiving where we give thanks for the
fact that our founding fathers,
uh,
committed genocide and gave us
all this beautiful land out here.
Fuck you.
That's how the world works.
You knew we will come and you
saw a cutlasses, you know,
that's how the world works. Smash Mouth
Football, the black and blue division.
That's how it fucking works.
The Norris. Um, no it is.
And I don't have a Kate that shit,
but you know what, what it happened.
But you know,
they got their casinos,
we named a couple of golf courses after
him. You haven't noticed that shit.
That's what I like about white people.
We fucking slaughter people than we
named Shit after him. Once we feel bad.
Oh,
we'll call this a one want to tuck.
This is the one buttock grocery store
and this is the last and the Mohican.
Culdesac um, anyways,
Jesus Christ bill yet.
So I saw this youtube video
Thanksgiving's coming up or right.
And one of the big things as a man is
you have to know how to carve a God damn
okay.
And as much as all you fucking guys out
there want to act like you know how to
carve a Turkey most.
See you fucking don't.
But you're too afraid to ask because
you're worried that someone's going to
question your sexuality because that's
what it's like to be a man. Basically.
If you don't just somehow
know shit without ever having
any explained it to you,
that evidently means that you, you, you
want to have sex with another man. That's,
that's the laws that I learned
growing up. Um, so anyways,
there is a fucking youtube video out
there that of course I can't check because
he's constant charger me $13 every
fucking and expires every noon.
But there just go on,
go on to Youtube, right?
And just Google how to carve a Turkey.
There is a fucking dude on there, man.
I'm telling you, you, it's,
it's unbelievable the way he takes
his bird apart. It's masterful.
Okay. And don't make the mistake I made
last year because I carved the thing up
perfectly, but the problem was my
knives, we're a little bit dull.
Go get your knives professionally
sharpened this month. Okay.
And Jesse eat spaghetti until Thanksgiving
so you don't fuck them up because I
swear to God, I've tried with that
little sharpener that you get.
A lot of people just take
out that sharpener out of
that a little knife thing.
They just go week and there's a, you
have to fucking hold the thing at as a,
at a certain angle and you can actually
be making the thing Duller if you don't
know what the fuck you're doing.
Trust me, cause I did it. You know,
I watched a couple of the three stooges
things and I saw them, I saw curly.
Look, I can't even fucking do it. My
fucking voice is so trashed. Anyways,
there's this killer youtube video man.
And it's like literally when this
guy is done with the thing you got,
you've got the drumsticks,
the wings in the dark meat,
everything's lined up like that.
And then you got all the white meat with
just a little bit of skin on top of it,
lined up like a fucking deck of cards
and you come out with your serving tray.
I mean, if people faint, it looks so good,
that fucking carcass is just,
it's a maculate. All right,
so definitely check that shit out.
If you're going to make a Turkey,
and if you're one of those people too,
who wants to deep fry of fucking Turkey,
make sure you put the Turkey
in the deep fryer first. Okay.
And then fill it up with water so you
know how much fucking grease to put in
there.
Evidently that's what people do is they
fill it all the way up to the top and
then they dropped the bird in there
and then it overflows. Catches flame,
lights their deck on fire and
they burn down their house.
And that's not thanksgiving.
That's not even Halloween. Anyways,
let me get Ben and what if I
got it back up here? So anyways,
this fucking podcast is a mess.
Um, to fuck died. God's oven,
this is what I'm talking about. You have
a heat up, a fucking oven, you know,
and then you check it on
whatever you're cooking.
And rather than opening it and letting
the heat come out and then looking down
with your face,
you open the door with your face right
there and you get that fucking heat
furnace blast. That's what summer
is like in La in July and August.
But I'm gonna tell you at night, it's
absolutely gorgeous. I'm telling you,
you should do it at some point. You ever
come out to la? Fuck the Hollywood sign.
Fuck going on sunset.
Fuck all that.
Go up on Mulholland drive
and drive through the hills
late at night and look at
the valley and it looks like
Christmas, man. It's amazing.
So that's what I wanted to do.
I was going to get this fucking car
cruise around up there and uh, you know,
have a couple of drinks, wrap it
around a tree, run away from the scene,
blame it on a minority, you
know, I'm fucking with you. Um,
you know, I was kind of have a good
fucking time. It's what I wanted to do.
So I call these fucking
assholes up at Hertz.
I call him up cause I wanna rent this car.
That's going to cost me 350 bucks.
I'm going to throw a fucking iPod
right in the trash for one fucking day.
A fucking taking some s turns
up there in the hills, right?
So I call him up and I say, yeah, listen,
I want to rent that corvette you got
at the Burbank airport and they got a
attack. Oh, first of all, I had to
fucking get through their stupid, uh,
okay.
They're stupid. Whatever the, the, the,
the computer thing. And then you know,
of course they have this,
this automated voice,
and you can tell the
person did the voice over.
They told you to smile when she did it,
it says, this is the tone. Just goes,
thank you for calling her.
It's rental car.
You can actually get a better
deal if you go to here. It's dead.
Can needs big stupid fucking grin on
her face. And it wasn't bugging me.
I actually enjoyed it the first
time through because I'm like,
I'm going to get a corvette for one
fucking day. I'm going to live the dream.
Yeah,
I'm going to live the fucking dream.
I'm going to live the American fucking
dream before they collapsed the dollar
and combine us with fucking Canada and
Mexico and put a microchip in the middle
of our fucking forehead. I'm going to
do it when I get this God Damn Corvette,
right? So, you know,
he wanted to fucking have a toothbrush
shoved up your ass. Press one.
If you want to fucking do a cart wheel
press 19. So finally up, you get up to 20.
If you want to make a reservation, I
fucking hit that button. And then it,
then right?
Again [inaudible] right.
It takes me like fucking 20 minutes,
right?
Okay.
Press or say can't, right? I'm going
through all that shit. So finally,
I'm just like screaming
operator into the phone, right?
So finally I get someone and I say, you
know, listen, I want to rent. You know,
I saw this car corvette you had at
the Burbank airport and God damn it,
I'd like to rent it.
And they go, okay, um,
let me give you the number for the Hertz
rental car location and they can help
you with that, sir. And I said,
okay, ma'am. And she gives it to me.
All right?
So I hang up and what do I do?
I called the hertz location out in
Burbank. And what do I get again?
That same computer,
Smiley voice you recalling here at Uva?
Anal carer.
Gail picks me again,
right?
If you know the extension of the person,
how the fuck would I know that?
How would I know what fucking extension
would like to football players and they
have a hall of fame career and I know
fucking Brett Farve is extension for on a
fuck would I know that shit.
So once again,
operator screaming into the phone,
I want to fucking talk
to a goddamn person.
But of course I can't talk to a person.
What are they doing the entire time?
They keep steering me to the Internet,
basically saying in not so many words
that this would be a whole fucking lot
easier if he just went on the
Internet. He Hurts Dad Cam. Right?
You could just help us
eliminate more fucking jobs.
Yeah.
So we can eventually replace all of
you with fucking robots, you know?
So I'm like, fuck this. I want
to talk to a goddamn person.
So finally I get to the stupid,
you know,
all I get is if you
want to leave a message,
yeah.
You know, I'm like, I don't
want to leave a message.
Okay.
Right. And then they go, well you
didn't, you know, they come on, well,
I didn't make a decision.
I have to make a fucking decision.
I did make a decision. My decision is
I don't like any of the decisions you,
you fucking gave me to make.
So if they get,
if you want Moria change pace board,
Smiley face.
So I press four and then basically
if I wanted to talk to a person,
I could basically schedule a phone
call when they could call me back.
I could leave my phone number
or I could wait a half an hour.
So I hang up and I'm like,
you know what,
I've just wasted a half
hour my fucking life.
So I call these fucking assholes
back again at the national thank.
Thank you for calling her to be anal care.
I'm back in that shit again.
And I'm screaming operator to the phone
and I get somebody to say, listen,
who do I talk to to make a complaint?
Because at this point I'm like,
I'm not renting his
fucking car from there.
I know there's other places where they,
they, they rent these exotic cars.
Is it column that, um,
I was like, fuck it.
I'm just going to go through them,
but I'm,
but I'm going to make sure that
I complained to somebody. Okay.
And I'm not going on the internet
and sending a fucking email. Right.
So actually get a person and they
go, okay, well let me transfer. Okay,
I'm going to transfer you.
I'm sorry to hear that, sir.
I'm very sorry to hear that,
sir.
Let me transfer you to our complaints
department. I go, okay, thank you.
She clicks it over, dude. Thank
you for calling her manager.
I'm fucking back in it
again. Right. And they,
and they just fucking tell me
if I, if I'd like, I can't get,
I can't get to a fucking person. So
now I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm determined.
I'm going to get to
somebody I call back again.
[inaudible] it's go through the operator,
go through the bullshit again.
I get to someone,
I say listen.
Yeah.
Okay. You sitting down person
on the other side of the phone.
I would like to make a complaint.
I don't want to fill out a form.
I don't want to make an email.
I want to talk to a person.
I do not want to be transferred into
your national gang. Wriggling here.
It's fucking thing again. I didn't say
fuck cause I could have hung up on me.
National System again. I would like to
be transferred directly to a person.
I believe you call it a warm transfer
in the creepy corporate world.
So can you do a warm transfer,
meaning something alive
to something else alive.
They can communicate with me and
she goes, yes sir. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry you're having this
difficulty. I say, I understand lady.
I understand you're not on the yet. You're
not on the yard. You're on the dark.
Getting screamed at by guys like me every
day. That's not, I'm not yelling at you.
All right, fucking I'm on hold
again. She can't get to anybody.
Then I go back to her and then she hits
me with the form. What is your name, sir?
What'd they did? None of your fucking
business. You don't need to know my name.
What do you need to know my name for?
So you can stick me on the hostile
collar list because I had the audacity to
complain about your country
fucking system. I'm not
giving you my fucking name.
I want to talk to a person. Okay.
There I just, yeah, I just, okay.
Just following protocol. I understand
that ma'am. I'm not mad at you.
I didn't see any that country, that
fucks stuff. That's what I was thinking.
But I kept my God damn cool.
I kept my cool just like fucking Steve
McQueen in that movie where he eats the
deviled eggs, get mad at
damn eggs. So anyways,
I fucking,
I fucking
finally get to a person. All right. And
I just say really calmed me. I just say,
look,
you know,
I've been on the phone for 40 minutes
trying to give you guys 350 bucks.
Okay.
And for the life of me,
I can't do it because I keep talking to
computers and they keep sending me back
into your national system. Now, ma'am,
I know you have nothing to do with this.
All right?
But I want to know what is the best way
that I can try to complain so I can get
to the inner hive, the inner layer of
the hive here and actually get to that,
that person who's sitting there and those
loafers without any socks on sunning
himself on the deck of his yacht.
I want to get to that guy,
the guy who made this policy. Okay?
I like talking to people, ma'am.
I enjoy the fact that you still
have a job. Okay. That's what I,
that's what I like. Yeah. My
phone buzzing in my phone.
Buzz and hang on one second. Hey Paul,
let me call you right back. All right?
So, uh, you know what? It actually worked.
So basically what they did was,
is I got an email and they go,
you can send an email and I go and let me
guess. No one's going to call me. Right?
Someone's going to email me back and
act like it's the actual frigging person
that I'm talking to. But really it's going
to be an intern who's being, you know,
who's working there for free.
And also parttime reads those books for
Oprah's book club so she can come on TV
and acts like she fucking reads a 400
page book every fucking week. Right?
Is that her? You're going to give me too,
cause if that's what the deal is I want,
I want somebody up high.
So basically they gave me allegedly the
email of the vice president at Hertz
reservations, Dat Cam. Um, and
I actually have the guy's name.
Now, whether this is true or not, I dunno,
but what I want to tell the guy is
that I was trying to fucking rent
that fucking flaming yellow corvette
that they have out there in Burbank,
California. For the life
of me. I couldn't do it.
And now I don't want to do it and I'm
going to bring my business somewhere else
and I would appreciate it if you know,
just hope against hope that maybe you'd
give some human beings some jobs because
my experience with your company is you
may be at best have six people fucking
working there
because you just,
you just keep trying to steer the herd
onto the Internet and all you dumb fucks
out there who are just constantly
helping them to get rid of people's jobs.
You're Outta your fucking mind because
those people are going to need jobs and
eventually they're going to be willing
to do your fucking job for a lot less
fucking pay.
And considering we've sent 90% of our
factories out of this fucking country now,
so now the American worker is going to
have to fucking compete with sweatshop
labor to make some fucking track shoes.
You know,
why don't we try to keep
the jobs that we have.
I'm not going to hertz.com you try
to pay me off with better rates.
Go Fuck Yourself. But some fucking human
beings in there the way you used to,
and you know what?
You'd be $350 fucking rich,
or I'd be driving a corvette and
everybody would be fucking happier.
You can put some new varnish on
your deck or your fucking boat.
You fucking assholes.
So whatever.
I know there's gotta be a private place
out there in la that I can call right up
and they'll probably charge me
even more money. And you know what?
I don't give a fuck because
I'm going to go in there.
They'll probably give me a little piece
of champagne or give gimme a fucking
foot massage. All right?
They probably won't do that,
but I'll talk to a person and that's what
the fuck I want. That's all I wanted.
A little fucking human interaction San
asking too. Goddamn much. All right.
So anyways, there's that story. All right?
And I'm going to tell you another story.
They want you to tell you guys
some stories this week, all right,
why don't you put your pajamas on?
All right,
get a fire going and
you're fucking apartment.
If they haven't boarded the
thing up because they're
worried about getting sued.
Um, was that great back in the day where
if you started a fire was your fucking
fault as opposed to the
landlords as opposed to,
well, why did you have a
fireplace in there? Well,
they had a fireplace in there
in case it got fucking cold out.
Or maybe you want to have a romantic
evening with your girl and you want to
light a fucking fire. That's why there's
a fireplace in there. It's a fireplace.
It is a place for a fire. Now, if somehow
you burn down the fucking apartment,
evidently you didn't understand what
place to put the fucking firing you.
Dumb fuck.
Who does not use a fireplace?
Evidently there's enough fucking people.
So they need to be boarded up.
Boarding up a fireplace.
Jesus Christ.
Why don't you put Santa Claus in
jail while you're at it? All right.
That was a little big. Okay. I'm just
saying, you know, I like fireplaces.
I like a crack of the fire. I don't like
those fucking gas ones. Those fake fires.
Me. Technically it is a
fire. You know. I Dunno,
what am I talking about? Let me tell you
a fantastic fucking story last night.
All right, so I'm working the road
with Joe to Rosa Young Joe de Rosa,
the fucking teen idol from the opiate
Anthony Show who is actually going to be
on the cover of teen beat this,
uh, this month. And it's actually,
I saw a little bit of the photo shoot.
He's doing a tribute to a net, a fund,
a cello, and uh, that other
fucking guy was it Tony Curtis,
who the fuck she used to make those
beach movies with or whatever.
Joe's going to be there shirtless,
holding a surfboard and knock. He needs,
he's never looks sexier.
Um,
so, uh, the fuck am I
talking about? I Christ,
I don't even know anymore. Um, yeah,
so we go out last night, right?
We're doing the show is these two big
titted horse sitting in the front fucking
row. All right. So we're like,
Oh wow, look at these girls.
These girls would probably be fun,
right? And I'm going to relationship,
but you know, I like being the wing man.
You know, I love being in the wing, man.
I'd love it. I love talking shit.
The girls, I love hitting on girls.
I fucking do it all the time and then
I try to pawn them off to wherever the
fuck I am. And uh, you know, so I
don't have any goddamn guilt, you know.
So anyways,
so long story short,
we're talking to these broads and it's
clear that there's some sort of strippers.
I don't know what the fucking deal is.
Okay. So we meet everybody from whatever.
I'm going to stop naming names here.
Okay. So a huge group of us from the show,
from the crowd and everything. We go
and we head out to this bar, right?
So
one of the strippers is cool,
the other one has a voice that could
literally crack a flat screen TV.
All right?
So the cool one shows up.
First she sits down, I'm like,
Hey, are you doing, you know,
I like at the end of the week, I hang out
a buy a round for some people. You know,
I'm in a great mood. I had a good
time. I'm on my way home, you know,
up by some people, some drinks. So I say
to her, hey, what would you like to drink?
She's like, I'll have a Faq and gag at
Google, one of those fucking chick drinks.
So you know, so I get her a drink. I buy
young Joe to Rosa fucking drink, right?
Everybody's having a good time.
And then this other person shows up who
I knew and she was a real nice person.
I said, hey, what do you want
for a drink? And she was like,
I'll get a vodka red bull,
right? I got my $20 bill out.
And then the strip is like, yeah, make
it tail right. And I was like, wait,
what do you mean make it to you
haven't even finished your first make.
Don't be warding off my money. You've
finished your first one there, young lady.
All right, stand the fuck down.
You're not working right now.
Not some dip shit getting a
fucking lap dance. All right,
finish your fucking milk and
cookies first. So, needless to say,
the conversation cooled
between the two of us.
But I didn't give a fuck man. I was
having a good time, but whatever.
It was still kind of, you know,
whatever he's talking shit.
We were talking sports, the bartender
was cool, you know, we, everything,
everything was going great.
So with chill and out and all
of a sudden this fucking, uh,
the other fucking stripper girl
shows up out and was so fucking,
it was just such classic female shit.
She's got a tits hanging out.
She's got the fuck me pumps on
and she comes up, she goes, hey.
And she sees a friend with a drink and
she knows God damn well she didn't pay
for it. So she looks over
at me as much. It's like,
well that must have been the
SAP who fucking bought it.
Right? So she looks at me,
she goes, Hey Belle. And
she's like, she's like,
what are you Jake can write and I
know what she's doing. I'm like,
I'm drinking one of those
Sam Adams October fests
and is leaving like that nice and awkward.
Right?
Cause I know what she's trying
to get a drink out of me. Right?
So she doesn't know what to
do. She's like, ah, is it good?
I'm like, why? Yes.
Yes it is at this point
Derosa knows what's going on.
I don't know that he knows what's going
on. So she looks at me like, okay,
well evidently he's not buying any
more drinks. And then she looks at Jo,
she's like, ah, hey Joe, what do you it?
And Joe gets his shit eating
grin on his face. He goes, why?
I'm drinking a bud light.
Why would you like to buy me one?
And she didn't know what the fuck to
do. She's like, ah, I, yeah, I guess.
He goes,
you know what?
I think you should buy me a bud light
and you should buy my good friend bill
burr here, another October fest.
What do you think about that?
And at that point I'm fucking
dying laughing. The other
stripper girl next to me,
she's laughing her ass off
cause she knows what happened.
And then the fucking girl with this
screechy voice is sitting there.
She doesn't know what the fuck to
do. We fucking nailed it. And then,
and then like she's going, she didn't know
what to do. And Joe's just going, yes,
why don't you pay it forward for all the
drinks that guys have boughten you and
that you've drank. And then immediately
turned around and fucking walked away.
Why don't you for once by a Goddamn by
a couple of drinks for a couple of guys
and she's at high and you put
it that way. Fine. I, well I,
well I'm by effecting Janke and
Joe's like, how bout some shots too?
And she just was, I don't know what
her fucking ego is that she goes,
final fucking do that too.
So we actually got a stripper to
buy us two beers and two shots.
So we're filling like
the kings of the world.
And then all of a sudden we found out
from this waitress that on the sly she
tried to put it on a boyfriends fucking
credit card. What a scumbag. Right?
So we bused her and we all we,
and when this big commotion breaks
out right before the fucking bar,
chances are about ready to swipe the
boyfriend's credit card. We were like,
don't chill. Joette I just like
an officer and a gentlemen.
I got nowhere else to go.
Right.
We get them to stop and they take out
her ATM and she had to fucking pay for it
and it was a done deal.
We had two drinks,
two shots from that fucking person who
you know is never paid for a drink since
she got her fucking tits. Right.
And this was the best part.
The second we got our drinks,
we said thanks a lot and we
both got up and we walked away.
Oh, it's tremendous. Tremendous.
It was the best night ever and I'm
just standing there drinking my drink.
Like 20 minutes later I'm
milking it for all it's worth.
This free fucking beer that a
stripper bought me was awesome.
Brian and Joe was talking to some girl
across the way and he looked at it and
all of a sudden I just yelled over, I go,
Joe. And he looks over at me and I did,
I did the Robert Deniro line from
when he was eating at Joe Peci,
his mom right before they hacked up Billy
batts. Right. He looks up and he's like,
what's up?
And I just pointed at the beer,
the stripper at bought and I
just went delicious. Delicious.
And that was my evening. And then at
that, there's another story for you.
Would it be 35 minutes? Then you got any
more stories? As a matter of fact, I do.
What else did I do this
fucking weekend? Oh, I know.
I took a trip to the cotton bowl.
What is the cotton bowl bill? Well,
cotton bowl is a stadium
that's been around,
I believe since the twenties and it's
the first place that the Dallas cowboys
played in and the Dallas Texans
in the old AFL. And God dammit,
I found out it's still existed. So I
wanted to go fucking take a look at it.
So I went down there and lo and behold,
they were having their say Texas there.
Dallas,
Texas state motherfuck unfair
that they have every God damn year.
I got a new text message, I here,
my little 16 year old phone,
call me when you wake up.
I want to please you asshole. Um, anyways,
so I go to take a tour of this thing
means the first place Tom Landry coach,
you know, the first season
of the Dallas cowboys, right?
The Dallas Cowboys team that I love,
which was basically the Tom Landry years.
And I never got into the Jimmy Johnson
ones because watching Tom Landry leave,
I mean, it was like watching
Johnny Carson go, you know,
no disrespect to the next people.
It's just, it's just not Johnny.
It's not Tom Landry. You know what I'm
saying? So, uh, I never got into them.
So like this, you know, it was a big
deal to go check this out. So I go to,
you know, go to this tour and it was the
worst fucking tour ever took in my life.
It wasn't bad. It was an awesome
tour, but just the lady was cute,
but she just didn't fucking know anything
about the stadium. She goes, uh, oil,
you can see on either side.
They added some thethe.
They added thethe all the shiny
silver ones though than the new ones.
And I was like, how many, how many people?
That place is fucking huge. You go home,
people does this place hold.
She's like,
I think like 20 3020 3009 all you
guys aren't sports the way I am.
23,000 is like a little hockey arena.
Okay.
You know you have a hockey game.
You sell at a hockey game.
23,000 this is where fucking Texas
longhorns in the fucking Oklahoma sooners
play.
All right.
College stadiums do not hold 23,000
at the Division One fucking level,
especially Texas, Oklahoma. You
know what I mean? So I'm like, ah.
I think it's a little more,
I guess like 45,000 I didn't fucking know.
And she looks, and she goes, yeah,
I think it's 23,000 and then she looked
at it a little pamphlets. She goes, Oh,
I'm sorry,
it's 97,000
and I got to tell you right now, right
there, the stadium tour is fucking over.
It's over.
I don't want to hear another word from
you because that is the first point.
If you're doing a tour of a stadium,
like if you want the family feud.
Yeah.
And the, and the, and the queue.
The first question was, you know,
you're standing there with one arm
behind your back so you can't cheat.
I don't understand why you have to
do that on the family feud. Right?
Like what if you lunch with two hands,
you're quicker diving in
like fucking Pete rose. Um,
anyways, if the, if the
question was, um, you know, you
taking a tour of the stadium,
what's the first question you're going
ask? And you fucking slam your hand down.
The first thing you would say is how
many people does this stadium hold?
How many people does this stadium home?
Fucking number one answer.
That's what it would be.
That's just check acted like I asked
her what the fuck and consistency of the
concrete was for the of the stadium.
She had no fucking idea.
Okay.
And then she tried to say that,
that,
okay,
back in the day, the cotton
bowl, the cotton bowl.
Okay.
B O w l like a cereal bowl
was open ended on both sides.
Think about that for a second.
A stadium that's called the,
you ever seen the Rose Bowl? The rose
bowl is an open on any either side, is it?
No,
it's shaped like a fucking bowl.
She tried to say that the cotton bowl was
open on both ends for a while and just
in 2002 they closed it off.
What they actually did was they put an
upper deck and as far as I could tell,
they knocked down the end zone,
lower level. And they just,
they rebuilt that and
they put an upper deck.
But she was trying to say that it was
open ended until 2002 and in my head I'm
going,
I don't think that that's right.
Okay.
I don't think that that's right either.
And then we went into the
media room and Lo and behold,
they have a picture of the
cotton bowl in 1958 and closed.
You know, I, you know, and
I, it just, I don't know,
but we've got to go down staying
right down near the field.
Come right down where all the
players came out and uh, you know,
it was awesome. It Len Dawson Hanks,
dram, Bob Lilly, chuck Howley,
you know all that shit right up till now.
All the modern day players,
Ricky Williams played there.
Who else played on the Longhorn?
So many fucking guys, that
guy, Vince young, all those
fucking dudes. I don't know.
Billy Sims, Earl Campbell, you
know, it was a fucking great time.
Then I walked of there and they,
and I went to,
I walked around the little state
fair isn't a little state fair.
It's actually a big state
fair that they have. And uh,
evidently down here in
Texas what they do is,
and you people overseas who hate on
Americans are going to love this shit.
It's just this classic here.
What they do down here in Texas is every
year they fry some, every year with fry,
something different.
Last year was Oreos.
Year before that it was Twinkies.
We Fried Coq one year fried pizza.
I'm not even lying.
They fried all of this shit.
Somebody told me they fried Coca
Cola and I had the fuck you do that.
But they said they did it. I don't know
how to do it. What do you freeze the coke,
Huh? And it fucking roll around in some
fly. I don't. I have no fucking idea,
but all I know.
You know what?
Evidently they're out of fucking ideas
because this year, you know what?
They were frying.
They were frying butter.
I swear to God,
they were selling fried
fucking butter and I'm like,
that is the most disgusting fucking
thing I've ever heard in my life.
God dammit. I have to
try it. I got to try it.
I have to see what it is like I
made a little fucking youtube video.
Actually,
I got to have the kid I was with.
Okay.
Made a little video of me
trying that little law delicacy,
that little Texas delicacy.
Dude,
it was the most disgusting fucking thing
I ever had. I've asked. The Guy said,
all right,
well first thing I wanted to do was get
the fried Oreo because evidently that
was a big hit.
That kind of made sense to me.
Fried Oreo is fucked up is that is
I would figure because it's fried,
it's going to be salty,
but then he got the sugary cookie
to kind of offset the two, you know?
Yeah.
It's Kinda like, you know, he did
some lines in I drinking some alcohol,
the even yourself out. Same fucking
thing. Just in a food way. Right. So, uh,
I went over to that one first and I go,
yeah, let me get in. The guy's like, hi,
don't, I'm like, yeah, let me get one
of those fried Oreos Oreo cookies.
And he goes, ah, ah, I'm sorry. We can't,
we can't cook yet until the
health inspector comes up and uh,
and gives us the,
okay.
The Hiltons Elton Health Inspector
has to inspect our booth first.
So my next logical question was like,
well, how do you think you're going to do,
I know I walked into a restaurant,
like, hang on a second,
I'd love to have you give it sounds.
So let's just have the health inspector
go through first. Let's just see a,
we have an acceptable amount
of roaches. So I said, fuck it.
And I went straight to the fried butter
and evidently they had already been
inspected. And I said, all right. He
goes, well, how can I help you? I go,
I got to get some of that fried
butter. And the guy goes, all right,
what do you want? You want original? You
want something else to something else?
And I go, let me get the original. And
he goes, all right. And he goes, uh,
uh, well, he, yes, he said,
the your choice of toppings.
I forget what the fuck they were,
but I went with the Welch's grape jelly.
I know this is disgusting.
You know what's funny is probably as
somebody working on a treadmill right now,
listening
to this feeling a lot better about
themselves. So they basically,
they look like these little,
you Dunkin Munchkins a doughnut holes.
That's what it looked like.
And then there was like the grape jelly.
There was, there was the, uh, the grape
jelly, sorry, my phone keeps ringing.
Um, so I dip it in the grape jelly
and I took a bite out of it. And Dude,
it was the most disgusting fucking
thing I've ever tasted in my life.
It tasted like a flavor list doughnut.
And then you know that awful gum that
has this squirting inside that was like
the inside, except it was butter. It
was just a little nugget of like butter.
It was fucking gross and
it was so disgusting.
I had to have another
one because you know one,
you know one for each ventricle
or ventral cause you got,
if you've got more than two,
maybe that's why I'm still fucking living.
I don't know what,
but I had another one just to be like his,
was it that bad and a yes it was.
It was a,
yeah,
it was wrong. It was just,
that's all I can say.
I was just fucking wrong and
should not be done. And uh,
yeah,
I'm just gonna leave it dad.
I think I'm gonna end the podcast right
here cause I'm out of stories and a
Jesus Christ, my fucking phone wants
to, I got it. I have a voicemail.
I'm going to New York next week
and I'm going to get my blackberry,
but I get a new blackberry again.
I didn't get one out in la
cause if you do it down in La,
they can't give you a New York number.
You know,
and I want to keep that number just
because at this point I've had the number
forever. You know, I don't want to
have to call fucking 9,000 people.
I don't know. I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about. All right.
This has been the Monday morning podcast.
I Apologize I didn't have any,
I didn't have any questions this week.
Did I?
I don't have anything cause I couldn't
get to my email. I had a couple,
this is September 24th.
Um,
all right, I'm going to read one here. Um,
this is actually a commenting on rugby
and women. All right, here we go.
Gala Bill. After hearing your show
this week regarding rugby, um,
where you asked whether or not any
rugby player has played in the NFL,
I decided to do some research on
the subject. Uh, what I found out,
mmm.
That there've been several rugby players
who've crossed over to play in the NFL.
Many of their names won't ring a bell
because it appears they are all kickers
and punters. The two names that came
up the most often were Ben Graham,
a kicker who I think played for the jets
and Mick Luckhurst was also a kicker
who played for the
Falcons from 1981 to 1987.
What I found funny was that the rugby
guys who attempted to try out for other
positions such as linebacker or running
back or often considered too small,
too slow or too weak to do damage on
the field against a much larger NFL
players.
Um,
now I know a lot of people in England
are going to flip out about that shit.
Well, you know what? They say that all
the time that American football players,
they're a bunch of pussies because they
wear helmets, all that type of shit.
Well,
I got news for you.
There's a great article in Gq
magazine that I actually read.
I never read Gq because a,
it's kind of like the male cosmo where
you just open it up and there's a ton of
articles.
Not Articles is a ton of advertising.
You can't find where the fucking
articles are and it smells like Cologne.
I swear to God it does. It's really
a fucking, it's a really, uh,
it's awful magazine. But I
gotta tell you this, there was,
there's a woman on the
cover of this magazine,
Olivia Wilde might be the most beautiful
woman I've ever seen in my life.
She's just ridiculous. And I was like,
I have to read this article about this,
this,
this female.
And it turned out there was an article
in there about concussions and about
football players going crazy
and killing themselves.
Professional football players.
And they were talking about Mike Webster,
the center for a, the Pittsburgh Steelers.
It's an unbelievable article. It's a uh,
Olivia Wilde is on the cover.
And basically they were saying the helmets
cause that's the number one thing I
hear these English guys can say that the,
you know American football players of
pussy cause they were like the helmets and
the pads. Evidently all the helmet
does is it protects the skull.
It doesn't protect the brain cause the
brain sits in like fluid and it moves
around. So when you get slammed in the
side of the head and not only mention,
they was saying the way they build these
helmets is back when they had leather
helmets. You know back in the
days, the three stooges days,
if you watch the guys play football,
they didn't lead with their heads
because you get knocked out.
But now in an effort
to protect their heads,
they were basically saying what they've
done with these helmets is they created
a weapon. And these football players,
especially the Lyman, every play,
if you watch them, they just slam
into each other with their heads.
And I have a dental. He, they're doing
unbelievable amounts of brain damage.
And Mike, his brain, he basically,
he went crazy and he couldn't
fucking remember shit. So
they, during the autopsy,
they removed his brain,
they sliced it in half,
and he had lists all Simon,
I don't know that this plaque,
I don't know what they called it,
but it was like a,
they said it should have been the brain
of like an 89 or 90 year old guy in this
guy died at 50.
So A,
I'm not saying that rugby guys
are pussies or anything like that,
I was just giving people shit or whatever,
but I'm just defending American
football players saying that, you know,
just cause they have that fucking
helmet on. You know what I mean?
I find that really interesting like you,
cause I used to always watch guys
were riding motorcycles and my duty.
How do you fucking mind,
do you realize that brain damage you're
going to get if your head slams off a
curb like Gary Busey did?
And uh, evidently obviously,
you know, if you're wearing a helmet,
you know, you protect and you know,
from literally putting a hole in your
head so you should wear it. But you know,
I, it never really
dawned on me, obviously,
because I'm a comedian and not a fucking,
that just be,
you can have a helmet on and your
brain can, you can have just as much,
I think basically just
as much brain damage.
I think what you would have to have
is some sort of like hard shell in the
middle and then like 80 feet of nerf
on the outside of our spongy fucking
material on the outside.
So we would have to start to slow
your head down before it came to the,
to the, uh, what am I trying to
say? I think beyond a certain speed,
it doesn't make a difference whether
you have a fucking helmet on or not,
because your brain is going to slam
against the inside of your skull.
So fucking hard, uh, that is not
going to matter. And they go,
that's coming from a comedian. So, you
know, it's, it's medically accurate.
All right, let's move on here. Um,
and once again, to those people go,
I have no disrespect. It's rugby guys
are fucking tough sons of bitches.
I have no, but no, no.
Uh, questions about that,
but you really have to stop saying that
American football players are pussies
because they have pads on
those fucking guys. You know,
you, you wouldn't want to play rugby
against him. Put it that way. All right.
All right, let's plow ahead here.
Alright, Bill. A use also stated some,
some ways you can tell when you've
won an argument with the woman. Um,
stuff like the crying
and when they begin to,
to switch your words to talk about pass
topics in the middle of an argument.
Yeah. They bring up other shit that you
did because they're losing the shit that
you're talking about right then and there.
I guess guys do that too. But anyways,
let's plow ahead here. He said, well,
I have a better one on my way to work.
My wife and I were arguing over me hurting
her feelings because I came home from
a 10 hour day at work and three and a
half hours of night school just wanting to
go to bed. So, even though my
sexy Latin woman was an, it was a,
was ready for some action,
I simply took a shower,
crawled into bed next to her and went to
sleep. Needless to say, she was pissed.
So this morning we were
fussing about it and she says,
that really hurt my feelings,
um,
because it felt like you didn't
want me. And he said, um,
and I don't know what, what came over me,
but instead of being an angry black man,
I simply smiled, grabbed,
grabbed her hand, kissed it,
and commonly said in a soft voice,
now you know how I felt last week?
And she said,
absolutely nothing.
She just stared at me like she
wanted to start the waterworks,
but she couldn't get a going.
I dropped her off at the office where
she kissed me and actually apologized.
I smiled the entire way to work.
Wow.
I actually thought she was going to get
mad because that was kind of harsh the
way you said it. That's like
stand up. Applause, break.
Stand up comedy. Well now,
you know, I felt last week
if fucking Twat, that's how
I would have delivered it.
But I guess you said it nice and calmly,
but yeah,
you know that is kind of fucked up.
That's one of the things that I have
found like in relationship is, you know,
you got to watch out because
for the most I think I would,
I would venture to guess without
doing a survey as always,
I would venture to guess
that 92% of relationships,
women control the sex because guys
will do it basically whenever.
I really sound like a hacky comedian
guys, we don't give him a shit, woo woo,
but it's seriously and then
women kind of use it as a uh,
they start using. Yeah, he's still
a bit about that as a reward.
You took out the trash here at good boy
and you get like a hand job. You know,
you can't do that if you really
want to equalize, you know,
the whole sex in your relationship.
You why you got to,
you got to continue to rub
one out every once in a while.
So that way you know if they don't
want to have sex then you're like,
alright that's cool. You
know, and then she, I keep it,
keep it on any then you create no war
cause I would say then what you do is
next time they want to have it then you
act like you don't have it.
That's not the way to go about doing
it because then you start playing games
with each other. What you probably
should say is a, I don't know,
just basically what I've said the
woman which is, Oh yeah, bell,
we should say exactly what you said cause
you have your fucking life figured out.
Your fucking single 40 year olds
psychopath. Yeah. Once again,
I want to say don't ever
listen to what I say on here.
You know I am not a trained person and
I'm worried at some point someone's going
to take my advice,
they're going to get punched in
the face and I'm going to get sued.
So you've got to understand that you're
talking to a comedian here who's may be
read three books in his life.
Two of them had pictures on every
other page. All right. That's,
that's what you're dealing with
here. Now way she, I'm telling you,
the big thing with women is, if you
want to get your way, is not to get mad,
not to play a fucking game with them.
You just have to tell them
how what they're doing is
making you feel they can't
get around it. If you have a legitimate
complaint, you know, let me, if you,
I got something ridiculous like,
Hey,
I want to put it in your
ass and you won't let me.
It's really making me feel like
you don't trust me. I mean, that's,
I think you're going to lose
that one. All right. But um,
oh Jesus, I'm sorry to get back on
track here. If you fucking, you know,
like some serious like that
we just like, look, you know,
I feel like anytime you want to have sex,
I'm willing,
but there's a lot of times I want to
have it and you don't want to have it.
And that was so now I kind of feel like
this thing that we're allegedly sharing
together, you, you totally control and uh,
that doesn't make me happy.
Thoughts,
whatever you power the fuck you said.
You said calmly without saying, fuck,
and I'm telling you,
well, what can they do?
They got to sit there and answer
it and I can guarantee you that'll,
that'll work out good for you for at
least three fucking days before it slides
back to normal again. It's a
never ending fight. All right?
But what you gotta do is
you've got to have the fights.
You got to have the fights and protect
your real estate. Are you going to spend,
you're going to spend your entire
time and goal line fucking d.
That's the worst fucking relationship
you've given up so many fucking the whole
time.
It's fourth and goal first and Galt.
What am I talking about first
and fucking goal, right?
And you just jumped off sides. So it's
half the distance to the fucking go.
We got it built. You're in
a bad situation. All right,
that's all I'm saying. Okay,
that's the end of the podcast. Thank
you everybody for listening. All right,
here's what I got coming up.
Um,
I'm going to be at the stress
factory in New Brunswick,
New Jersey coming up this Friday,
Saturday and Sunday. Well,
what are the dates, bill? Well,
why don't you hold on a second
and I'll get them for you.
God knows I can't go on the fucking
Internet. Um, that's going to be a Friday.
Um, October 2nd. Oh my God.
Where is this year going?
Saturday, October 3rd
and Sunday, October 4th,
I am going to be, um, at the stress
factory in New Brunswick, New Jersey,
fans of the opion Anthony and little
Jiminny Jiminny radio program.
I'm going to be on there on a Friday,
September 2nd and I believe Monday,
Friday,
October 2nd, and I believe
Monday, October 5th, uh,
those two days I am going
to be in studio with uh,
my best friends of all time in radio,
the opie and Anthony Show.
Really excited to see them,
sons of bitches again. And um,
after that I am going to be
at the Improv in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania on October 8th,
October 9th and October 10th.
And I will be,
um,
with Randy Bowman on DV fall.
You Pittsburgh people.
I will be on the morning radio program
on October 7th, eighth, and ninth.
So please listen. And, uh, and that is it.
I appreciate all you guys
listening to my podcast.
I apologize that I had to put this one
up on Tuesday, but I'm fighting the man,
man. All right. I'm fucking with
you. You guys all have a good week.
God bless all you take it easy.
Beep,
beep,
beep
killing it.
Yeah.