Hey, what's going on is bill burn
is time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. Yeah.
Just checking it on you.
What's, uh, what's going on?
I am actually doing this podcast.
I'm in the middle of a radio tour right
now and I have a 15 minute break and I'm
on my way to the fucking airport after
that and have to bike cleo. We, oh,
we're going to buy her some dog food, you
know, so my wife has some, the Fijian,
isn't that right buddy? All right,
get out of here. Go lay down. Qt. Um,
so I got a full day,
so I'm trying to knock out 15 minutes
before I go back to doing the radio tour,
which is why I sound like I'm already
off and running as opposed to my, you,
I guess I'm never chilled and laid back.
So I've been doing morning radio, um,
to hype my Saint Louis and Kansas City,
uh,
dates that are coming up and a,
and then also I got this a Canadian
tour that I'm doing. And, um,
so I just spent on the fucking radio
all day and everybody's just, you know,
I was taught more Canadian fucking Djs
were going to bust my balls about the
Bruins. I guess you can't, you know,
considering not one Canadian team is
going to make the fucking playoffs,
which is play off that, which is insane.
Not One of them. Cleo, can you believe it?
Not The fucking blue block.
A douche is not Ottawa,
Not Toronto. Toronto, Toronto.
Not The fuck at the Calgary flames.
The Edmonton oil is the Vancouver
Canucks l or the Winnipeg jets.
You know, I don't think that's
good for hockey. I mean,
it's a funny thing to bring
up as an American when I
go up there and believe me,
it will be brought up. No, I'm not going
to rub your face is in it. How could I,
yeah,
but Goddamn Bruins, you know,
we're a three seat now. We're,
we're like,
we've launched six of the last seven
fucking unbelievable.
Thank God for Toronto.
Got To left Toronto most
generous fucking team out there.
They're always there to pick
you up off the mat, aren't they?
That's the only team we beat.
Okay.
Fucking laws to everybody. Rangers,
Panthers, San Jose, Anaheim,
the kings.
And then we just fucking lost two to one
hat breaker to the fucking devil's now
like we're playing bad.
I still think we're going to get in there.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
I just want us to make the
playoffs so fucking clickbait. Uh,
Dan Shaughnessy doesn't start writing
his dumb ass fucking articles about how
they need to do something.
It's Sophie being a coach is so fucked
up cause you got deal with the dance.
Shauna's seas of the world.
How unathletic does that guy look?
You know what I mean? He doesn't
even look like he plays chess either.
He just looks like a dope
that's saying I don't,
but I've never just seen a deck.
Fucking guy should be run out of Boston.
Okay.
This whole fucking thing.
He lives for the moment when
the home team isn't doing well.
That's his whole fucking thing.
I had never forget that when the fucking,
I think it was one of the red sox won
the world series. Finally. He was like,
I don't even know how to write this
article because you doubt your negative
comment.
I bet it for fucking plane crashed into
the stadium and killed the whole fucking
home TV. That, that, that article would
be a breeze as you pretended to be sad.
Oh, Doug, that guy drives
me nuts. Drives me nuts.
He should be writing for
a New York newspaper.
He Shits on fucking Boston
teams so much. Um, so anyways,
anyways, where the fuck am
I? Clio for the love of God.
Are you allergic to your bed?
It's all you do is itch now.
Huh?
Look at that face.
That face that stupid that
my dog has such a classic
pooch face. It's ridiculous. Is
that what they call you? Clear off?
Was that your nickname in
high school? Oh, pooch face.
Can you get over there and lay down and
stop looking at me like I didn't take
you out. Why didn't take it out? I let you
down the stairs, but I also fed ya. Hey,
get over there. Lay down. Go on fucking
thing doesn't even listen to me anyway,
go on.
I shouldn't be yelling at my dog.
My dog's is senior now.
She's eight and a half years old,
so she's officially a senior.
So when I go and buy dog food,
I got buy, you know, I got
it by the advanced age shit,
you know the same stuff.
They're feeding your fucking Nanna and
your granddad or whatever the fuck you
know, putting them in a
fucking home. That's the worst.
Okay.
That's the fucking worst,
Matt.
At least according to every fucking movie
or news report you see, it's just like,
this is a wonderful facility.
They're going to be listening to Mitch
Miller the entire time they're here.
All of our facilities are top notch.
They're going to be getting a
wonderful food there and great care.
You can visit them whenever you want.
Right?
And then the fuck could second
you drive away. You know,
you fucking put a hard hat on your
grandmother and make her start doing some
fucking yard work.
Isn't that how it works?
Trying to steal or pension or is this
just all some Hollywood drama? Shit,
I dunno.
Like I said,
so I'm gonna have to tap out here
and then come back and about, um,
what the fuck is it in like nine minutes.
I want it to go back out to the
fucking world of morning radio.
I literally had one of these
guys this morning clean.
I'll get over there and lay down.
You know what's weird about this dog?
The thing won't shit unless I take
it down the street, which is great.
Is that what it is?
You gotta take a shit?
Yeah.
Is that why you staring at me?
Is that what you're trying to
communicate right now? Huh?
Like someone who's still sound of mine,
but he's lost the ability to speak.
This is like a metallic of video.
[inaudible] stop fucking
looking at me like that.
I'm going to take you down the street.
All right buddy. I'm going to do it.
Fucking thing is staring
all through my head.
Yeah.
I just left you outside fucking
10 minutes. Why won't you go?
Okay.
All right. This is going to
kill me. Okay. All right. Well,
I'm going to be talking to guys who
not born that my dog's taking a shit.
Evidently. Um, so anyways,
like I've been at least morning
fucking radio guys are hilarious.
They literally sit there and they go
like, uh, they'll just be talking to you.
A couple of them, but like the
classic guys like just to clean.
I'll get over there and laid out
going, get over there. Get over there.
All right.
I wish dogs understood.
Just give me five minutes Cleo.
Get the fuck over there.
Lay down.
I actually know what I think it is.
I think she wants to get up on the
couch with me. It's just fucking lyrics.
I have a pit bull in the, any sound
of wind. Wind freaks her the fuck out.
A Sasquatch could literally come into
my house and she'd be like, all right,
let's fucking do this.
Okay.
But if she hears a noise and she
can't see where it's coming from,
she just freaks the fuck out right now.
I have the heat on.
I think that's bugging her and then
all of a sudden she becomes like this.
She turns into like a Chihuahua.
You know,
those dogs always look like they're feed
in for something. Like, come on man,
just give me another hit, man. She starts
getting that look. She starts like,
she's not shaking yet.
Thank God. Um, but anyways,
a couple of these morning djs were
the classic, like they just talk,
they call you up and be like, hey bill,
how you doing? Uh, so and so from K,
whatever, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Yeah. So listen,
we're going to be a
talk in here in about a,
about a minute coming out of this
commercial. Is there anything,
any subject she want me
to hit on a and thing? Uh,
you want me to steer you towards, Hey, you
know, whatever I'm talking about a blah,
blah, blah, and he's that guy. All right,
we'll be on a right at
the end of this break.
And then all of a sudden it just goes,
it was,
wow how Lou bill bell scale of that.
And also you just like,
dude,
what happened to the guy I
was just fucking talking to
dragged to add is 18 we have a rock.
To Abby,
got some laps coming your way,
coming to the local Yuk Yuk. Fuck,
fuck bill, but have a lab.
Well, what's been on your map?
Um, I almost said it to
the guy. Be like, dude,
what happened to the guy was just
talking to five minutes ago. Um,
other than that,
the rest of them have been fine.
I have no fucking idea what I'm doing
here. But anyways, I'm getting ready to,
I'm ready to, um, to do this tour here,
going through Canada. And uh, you know,
I had those big shows last week,
so I feel like I'm,
I've been doing spots around town.
I'm fucking ready to go.
I'm going to be doing the
treadmill, by the way. My Home Gym,
the gym that I'm going to have at home.
They're a did.
They're doing the floor.
It's a three day process.
Cause I got the fucking, the
autocall days, I got the,
it's called the lava finish or some
shit. I know. Stupid fucking name,
but it looks sick, man. It's fucking
a, it's going to look shiny and clean,
exciting and new.
Lift some weights
and become a shredded freckled.
Cons.
He's Bill Burke.
He's tired of looking like
a sack of mash potatoes.
He's going to do some dips,
walk down the street shirtless
and gets sun poisoning. Um, yes.
Everything's coming. So today, all the
gym shit is dropping off today, right?
Which was so fucking funny
courses today I'm going to leave.
So it's coming ups and they're just
like a, you know, basically, you know,
we're going to be there sometime
between 3:00 AM and 12 midnight. Good.
Could you just try to be home in course.
I'm not going to be here.
She's now I've got to tell the lovely
Nia and I was just like a sweetie,
what did you have planned
tomorrow? She's like, well,
I was going to go to the show,
like cancel it.
She got so fucking mad at me
so it can all this stuff to do.
It's like it's one fucking day to have
a free gym for the rest of your life.
Okay. You're going to get to go
out there. You're going to listen.
You're going to get to listen to your
music as opposed to the gyms, music.
Now I know that you can put headphones on,
but every has those ear buds and the
fucking Jammin in your ears and you're
basically blowing out your ear drums,
giving yourself tinnitus or tetanus.
However the fuck you say it. Um,
cause you don't want to listen to, uh,
what's that song they always play.
Ah, we assault assault, right?
It takes me to make a Bingo.
Right.
You know, they play that for some reason
Jim music stopped in the early nineties.
That girl is poison.
They're even play shit like that.
Did they stay place?
I don't want to fall in love.
It sounds like he called.
Is that Banana Rama? Who to,
who the fuck I remember this song.
You start thinking to the
chicky would dating at the time.
You start thinking about all the
fucking, all the time. Oh, who's kidding?
Who the chick you wanted to date but
didn't have the balls to see you hooked up
with that fucking monster who is
working in customer service. Right.
It's be a little more accurate here.
Um,
yeah, I don't like, uh, I'm not into
that shit. So anyways, so she has,
the poor thing's got to be home all
day today. You know, with any luck,
it's actually between, like they said,
between 10 30 or 10 and five or some shit.
So hopefully I'm really
hoping that it's going to, um,
it's going to come early, you
know what I mean? For the, uh,
the amount of pouting that she did about,
you know, you know what's so funny too,
is whenever somebody says they can't
do something and they go, why, why,
what are you doing? And then they tell
you what the donuts, it's like, yeah,
you're not doing shit.
You know,
because you're so focused on
what you want them to do for you.
Yeah.
It's just like, yeah, you know, I, I, I
lost my passport and somebody found this.
I didn't do that tomorrow.
Yeah.
Yeah. I have a dialysis. I don't
know if I told you I have, you know,
double kidney failure, so I have to do
it. If I don't do this, I'm going to die.
You can't put it off the
fucking eight hours for me.
Wait,
come on.
It's kind of going into that mode.
Um,
okay.
But anyways, Jesus Christ, who the fuck?
I don't even want to look the fuck.
Am I Bruins playing next? This funny
when the Bruins are winning or you know,
kind of paying attention,
but whenever they were in trouble,
that's when I fucking sit down and
watch. Cause I'm a real fan. I'm the,
I'm there for during the bad times.
That's half the reason why I
watched so many games this year.
I was just sitting there going like, well
they got rid of the whole fucking team.
You know, this is going to be a tough
year. So, all right, I'm going to see a,
I don't know, I'm a fucking nerd.
Like I watched, I like watching the,
the rebuilding of a team
so you can be there.
I remember when they brought that
guy up, dude, I fucking called it.
How about the fucking filthy flyers?
They all in the capitals.
Hey,
capital fence,
you guys finally going to fucking push
through a you east coast San Jose Sharks.
Are you ever going to
make the fucking finals?
Can you do that for your God
damn fence? Huh? Um, all right,
let's look up the Bruins here. Scores,
news, video stats, standing schedules,
players Fucker, the teams teams.
There we go. Oh, by the way,
I've been going on at that French
site. I've been figuring shit out. Um,
I'm sticking to what the dude, I'm
like 33 33 days in here. All right.
Watch episode 12 during
an off day in California.
Well, the hell is this
guy, frank Foote, tran
and the Bruins. Rookies explore La. Oh,
rough stretch of the ice improves
with a win over the leafs.
Why?
I don't understand.
Watching these fucking soap operas
about your God damn teams, you know,
behind enemy lines or whatever
the fuck they were always doing.
What do they do that in the NFL?
Okay.
You know, jock itch. What does
something like unnecessary roughness?
What do they call it?
What does that thing,
that fucking thing they do on
HBO where Rex Ryan's like, Hey,
we'll be any fucking team
and he's fucking league.
You know that he gets fired. Ah, fuck.
Our next game is tomorrow night
against the St Louis Blues
and then on Monday we play
the fucking black hawks.
Both of those are away games.
Yeah.
Then we have the hurricanes.
Then we have the red wings
and then we have Ottawa.
Fuck,
this is fucking unbelievable. Are We?
We are we going to blow this? Oh wait,
what the fuck was that story about?
Okay,
well got there.
What
we call here,
this is some rookie.
Why can't you fast forward
your way through the, God damn.
I don't want to watch the episode 12 of
rookie sitting on a fucking beach in La
talking about hockey. I
don't give a shit. Okay.
I thought they were showing me some new
prospect. That Bruins half God knows.
We'll bring them up. We could use
a ninth annual cuts for a cause.
Everybody gets say head shaved
and hopefully at least you know,
half of one half of 1% will actually
go to the fucking, because dude,
I'm so down on every goddamn charity now.
Every,
I mean I have to be honest with you.
I've done charities my
entire fucking career,
but I have never seen just the
sheer number of cherry. Ah,
there it is. High bail you out so
I could walk. All right, I got,
I'm going to call you back.
Talk to you in a minute.
Okay.
All right. I'm back. Just knocked
out another two and I am done.
Probably talk politics
too much on that last one.
Everybody wants to talk politics.
I got to sell you a bill yellow with all
this stuff. Let's go a lot of politics.
There's gonna be a great,
it's like, yeah, no,
it really isn't this one for some reason
it's depressed the shit out of me.
You know what I mean? Jesus Christ,
eh? It's just, you know, I'll tell you
right now, you can take that Donald Trump.
You can wire them up in a ball.
Okay? You stick and write up.
You know who's who ha your roll her down
the street into the fucking garbage bin.
All right? And then you fucking, then
you got to take Bernie Sanders, right?
And you've got to give him that gun.
Did fucking
Scarface had at the end
of the fucking movie.
And then you just got to send them in.
You know,
you got to send them into one of
those bank or fucking meetings.
And he just comes in when, if,
if, no, when they're doing the,
the annual international
bankers slash family picnic,
right? So you've got everybody
there, you've got the evil cuts,
and then you have the spawn of the evil
cots and you just got to go with there.
I mean, even then, right?
What are you going to do?
Let's just say we buy into the fairy tale
that everybody was super fucking rich
is fucking evil. And then regular
people were fucking good people,
you know?
Then we'll have their level of power,
then we move up and then we become
them, right? And then you know,
you know what's going to happen.
You're going to be a can have power.
You can have influence here
come though whores. Ah, right.
Did come the whores.
It comes to temptation.
There's the pile of gold you supposed
to be watching for everybody else.
You know,
you could do the right thing or you could
go out and get yourself your fucking
Bentley Lamborghini.
You could stay with your wife or you
could start bagging a 22 year old Victoria
secret model. You know, decisions. Yeah.
Becomes tough. You know, and then
it's like an earthquake when
the earth splits, right.
And your morals are on one side and
all the horrors and the gold are on the
other and it's very hard. You
know, you got to jump over early,
jump over early, Ra get you, you go,
you go too far down and then it's just,
isn't it? What can you tell? You're just,
you're caught up in it. You
fucking caught up in it, you know?
And that's when I actually
feel lucky to be a balding,
redheaded fuck because it
really keeps me in check.
So sad. Um, anyway, so let me do
a little fucking read here. Um,
it was the last time there was a
balding red headed fuck, you know,
of any influence, you know,
I think it's high time.
A balding redheaded fuck. Got a chance to
drive the bus, Huh? All right, Larry, go.
Oh,
our old friends here is zip recruiter.
Hey everybody, are you hiring? Are you?
Oh God bless you. Do you know where to
post your job to find the best candidates?
Okay.
Yeah. Wow. Posting your jobs
in one place. You know what?
Evidently, that isn't enough to find
quality candidates. Not these days.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your job on
all the top job sites. Well,
how the fuck can you do
that? Well, now you can.
All right with zip recruiter.com you
can post your job to 100 plus job sites
including social media networks
like the Facebook and the Twitter,
all with a single click. That's how you
know you're old. When you say the right,
the Twitter, the Facebook, the Instagram.
These children are out of control.
Taking the Molly,
find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your
qualified candidates roll in to Zip,
but great,
easy to use interface.
No juggling emails or calls to your
office quickly scan candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
I don't like that person.
They're fat and ugly.
You keep that under wraps.
You're not supposed to say that.
You're supposed to say, hey,
that person with the dead tooth, you know
that I don't want to look at every day.
You know, at the end of the day, they
are the best quality quality candidate,
right?
All the one I look at it say Aye.
Okay.
All the want to fucking hire
the hot chick with the 10 days.
Ah, she's a jolly good fellow. Um,
find out today.
Why Zip?
Okay.
Recruiter has been used by over 800,000
businesses and right now my listeners
can try zip
accrued up by for free.
Go to ziprecruiter.com/bird.
That's ziprecruiter.com/bar zip
recruiter.com/ [inaudible] alright,
that's it for the reeds.
That's it for the reeds. Cleo,
can you get over there and lay down
please buddy, can you get over there?
Just get over there and lay down.
Stop staring at me going,
get over there and lay down. Go on.
Go on. Go on. Oh, for God's sakes.
Yeah. Step on my laptop with the
acute web toes. Cleal get over there.
Go on. Oh, you're testing me today. Go on.
It's a fucking bed.
It's comfortable.
Do you know he used to be a wolf and you
had to sleep outside trying to find a
spot that didn't have acorns
underneath you. Tell you this dog.
It's fucking thing has no respect.
Um,
I thought it had to go to the
bathroom. It doesn't, cause I actually,
during a radio interview I went outside
and she took a big dump in my backyard
that I now have to go pick up
with a plastic bag because that's,
that's what a man does.
And 20 fucking 16. Right?
So now I realize that she just wants to
come up on the couch. She's all a scared.
All right.
You know what?
I know there's so many fucking dog
lovers out there right now that you know
nothing would make you feel better
than if I fucking brought her up here.
All right, come on. [inaudible].
Come here. Come on buddy. Come here.
Dog Training would be pissed right now.
He gave into her. Alright, there you go.
See you then look at Ya snug like a
bug in a rug. Now you're fine, right?
All right, good kid. Um,
anyways, yeah. Jesus Christ. I
saw people want to talk about,
they just want to fucking talk
about politics and I go, hey,
I don't want to talk politics. I'm
not paying attention. I don't want,
I'm talking about, I don't like, I don't
like any of them. And then everybody just,
I, you know. Yeah, but don't
you take it? Did you take,
it's all really just talking
about Trump and being like,
can you fucking believe this guy? He's
still doing it. Nobody Talks Hillary.
Nobody talks Bernie Sanders.
Huh? Is he related to the, uh,
the chicken guy there?
Okay.
He's Kinda got the same hair piece.
Either that or the fucking the oats guy.
Right. One of the other is that was
nice to fucking hacky references.
Did you enjoy those? No. Jesus,
I got to go to the airport.
I have not even packed and I still
have eight more fucking minutes.
I got a needy pit sitting
in my fucking lap.
I have to some out eat and not
become a fat fuck today. You know,
I think I'm going to do, I'm going to
pack a lunch like a goddamn second grader.
I'm going to make a peanut butter and
jelly sandwich with some cheese and
crackers and like an apple and you know,
and as much as all these fucking weird
looking shredded 50 year olds that are
spray tanned out there and all those
people and they've gotten their first
fucking uh, can you tuck the, uh, the
parachute under my Chin behind my years,
they've had that fucking procedure,
you know,
so they still have the heart
monitor forehead, you know,
with the lines going across it. But then
like they're fucking neck, you know,
they're looking like a WHO's
who is a classic fucking,
she's got a great dad and a Jesus Christ.
I don't know any of the fucking act,
you know, class of the actor
face. You know what I mean?
Joe Jetting out confidently,
you know the jet black fucking hair,
right? He used to dance in
the fountain on friends.
You know, now you're Ron Oj. My wife's
been watching the shit out of that thing.
Huh? I can't get into it. You know,
I can't get anyone to it cause I already
know what happens. It's like yes,
spoiler alert, he's,
he's found not guilty.
I watched the first one just cause I want
to see them dramatize whatever he was
doing in the back of the Bronco.
And I can't tell you as
much as the tragedy happens,
whenever I see clips of that, it
always makes me think like, dude,
I would love a white full size bronco.
That's such a bad ass vehicle.
It's big, it's safe. You know
what's great about those,
those full sized Broncos
back in the day was the, uh,
I've talked about this before.
What do you call,
they'll the middle area between the,
the front two bucket bucket
seats are captains chairs,
I believe they used to call them.
Um,
what I loved about the console there in
the middle, when you open that thing up,
that was big enough that
if you insulated it,
you could throw ice in there and have
a 12 pack of Budweiser. You know,
they make it so hard to drink
and drive and enjoy yourself.
You know, nowadays back in the day, if
you had a big truck like that, okay,
you know your,
your biggest problem was how am I gonna
What Am I going to pee it too while I
continue driving down the street,
taking everybody's life into my hands.
You know,
I shouldn't even say that.
A friend of mine got fucking hit
by a drunk driver. You and I do.
And like fucking 90 her damn car looked
like it was torn in half and I got to
tell you the way they make these
fucking cars nowadays, it's amazing.
Oh by the way. So I find more information
on the 27 Lincoln Continental.
Evidently it's going to start at like
like 45 grand or something like that.
They're trying to take out the Mercedes
Benz e class and rather than going
performance and that they're trying to
go elegance. Like we're a little more,
you know,
you're riding on a cloud over here
as opposed to though I have a fucking
Mercedes Benz. I don't know if
that's the right way to go. But, um,
I also talked to the guy who,
who rebuilt my truck, um,
and I, I called them up.
I said, hey, this is the prototype,
the concept card has the suicide
doors. He goes, oh my God,
that looks fucking sick and all
that type of shit. And I go,
they're not making them that
way. He goes, I was like,
can you do if I buy this
car and I ship it to you,
can you fucking put suicide doors
in it? He goes, I got it. You know,
he had to look it up. He said, basically,
you're making the car a lot more unsafe.
You're weakening the overall frame.
When you take out that middle piece,
that's between the front and the
second, uh, in the back door,
the be frame, fucking post,
whatever the fuck he called it.
Um, and I'm thinking like, you know
what? I haven't been in an accident.
Okay.
You know, I drive like a fucking
old man. I can take out the middle,
the be beam, post fucking thing,
whatever the fuck you call it. Right.
You know, I feel like it's like, you
know when you have to get a permit,
like you can knock down a wall yourself
in your house and interior wall as long
as it's not a load bearing wall.
I feel like that's what I would
be knocking out on my continental.
So then I would have like the suicide
doors led lights and things would look
fucking sick and then I would like rear
end a smartcar and I'd go through the
fucking windshield
or I'd just go into a spin and I'd
be objected out. Those two food,
those two like cool
doors. So, um, I dunno,
you would think this day and age if they,
if they want it to,
is that way suicide doors went away
where they considered not safe.
I learned that doing the
Seinfeld comedians in cars
where I asked him two times,
like an idiot, I go, why can't they make
cars that look cool like this anymore?
And he basically answered saying,
because of the,
the safety regulations are so strict
that they're basically basically creating
in such a small space, all of them, um,
that they're all going
to kind of look the same.
And then we saw another car
and I said, look at that
thing. I mean, I was like, why?
Why can't they, why can't they make cars
like that anymore? And Jerry just went,
I already answered that question.
It felt like such a fucking dope.
Um, anyways, so, you know,
it's funny as I just talked to some people
on the radio in Saint Louis and I was
telling him how,
how much I was not looking forward to
watching my team having to try to get a
point or two off of them that's coming
up Friday. And uh, they were like, well,
you know,
who knows,
maybe when you come out here and
Saint Louis will be in the playoff,
she can go to a game.
And I was like,
that was the one happy hockey
thought I've had in the last,
I'm not going to lie to you like I was,
I've been so busy that I didn't even
notice like the first three games that we
lost. Um, and also like I wasn't,
I'm not one of those guys
that looks at the standings.
I just knew we were three seats. I'm
like, all right, so we're in, I'll watch,
you know, as many games as they
can towards the end of the season.
And I'll enjoy is the first one in the
playoffs. I'm going to be sitting there,
right. My Budweiser, my little shorty
there a little fucking thing at Jamison.
I have one of those a period. Right? So by
the end of it, I'm either like, you know,
happy that we won or I just
passed out drunk. You know,
if we start to lose the game,
then I do two,
two Budweisers and to James since
in the third period, then you just,
you fall asleep and the next day you wake
up and you're still fucking hung over.
You don't give a shit that you lost.
You just trying to get yourself
physically back to where you need to be.
That's how I do it. That's the way an
alcoholic doesn't. I don't do that. Okay.
You fucking literal cuts. Why
would somebody do something
like that? So anyways,
I am going to be in wins tomorrow night.
Oh,
let me read the dates to wrap
up the podcast here. Well,
the first half of it before we then
listen to some Andrew assembled demo,
this mood music, and then we move
into some of the classic stuff, um,
from back in the day from podcasting.
Okay.
Back in yesteryear.
All right,
so I'm going to be at
the coliseum at Caesars.
Doesn't that sound impressive?
It's probably a 40 seat room. Um,
I'm going to be there tomorrow night,
April 1st.
April fool's April 2nd.
I'm going to be at the
Casino Roma in Rama, Ontario,
wherever the fuck that is.
Then I'm going to be at TD place
stadium in Ottawa, Ontario.
And then I'm doing the lol festival
in Sud, the Sudbury Arena Ontario,
which is actually a, uh, it's
a minor league hockey arena.
The way they, you know, they set it up
so you can still do standup in that too.
I'm not like fucking center
rice. It's not get crazier. Huh.
And then later on this month,
the 22nd, 23rd and 24th of April,
I'm going to be doing a run
St Louis, Missouri, Kansas
City, Missouri in Ames, Iowa.
I have not been to Iowa since I did the
rich bitch tour with Charlie Murphy and
Darnell Rawlings way back in the day.
And I believe we did one of the penguins
comedy clubs and that's the last time I
was there.
I am so excited to go to Iowa in April.
I've never,
the only time I've ever been to Iowa has
always been the dead of fucking winter
and all the crops are cut down and it's
like you're walking on the surface of
the moon,
it's overcast and all of that.
And I told you for the
longest time I was like,
how did slip not come from out
here? Like my idea, I should say,
of what Iowa was, you
know, just, you know.
Okay.
Beautiful Pony tailed girls
running through fucking yeah.
Uh,
fucking stalks of corn. You know, if their
flannel shirts tied off going, hey, oh,
you know, I'm just the girl next door,
except he's, they got a southern accent,
you know, apple pies in the window.
Like that's what I pictured.
And then you get there and you're like,
oh my God.
Okay,
this is what Armageddon looks like.
Going to fucking Iowa in the
middle of January and February.
I'm telling you, you've
never seen anything like it.
All the crops are cut down.
The gray sky meets the barren
earth and you're like, I get it.
I get slipknot,
I get meth.
Okay,
I understand madness. I get
this. This is fucking insane.
So I'm so excited to go there and
actually see it when it's lush.
And I watched like, wow, these people
feed the country. I want to see that.
All right. So anyways, looking
forward to that. Um, anyways,
so that is the podcast. Can I say
anyways, one more fucking time?
That is the podcast. Uh,
thank you guys for listening.
Have a wonderful weekend. You conch and
I will talk to you on Monday and um,
thank you to everybody that's going to
come out to the shows here in Canada.
Okay. All right. I'll see.
[inaudible]
who's that big going on in Minnesota
with that weird last name that has like
three letter bs and an end in it or some
shit. I don't fucking know. Anyways,
let's plow ahead with the podcast. This
is the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
March 1st the antipasto and um,
yeah,
I had a hell of a fucking weekend
out there in Houston, Texas.
I want to thank everybody who
came out to the Improv and um,
I had great shows Friday night that led
into Saturday night and Saturday night.
I think I might've had two of the best
shows I've had in recent memory. Um,
they were just, uh,
everything sort of clicked.
I kind of sitting in
this restaurant, um, Eh,
this is, this is how
clean living I am. Okay.
It's right before 7:00 AM I having
a salad with fucking, uh, uh,
chicken breast in it, right.
I got my laptop, I'm typing
out this fucking script,
finishing it up, drinking a glass of
water, getting the shit out of the way.
And I just remember like,
just having this feeling like this,
this is what Tony Robbins does.
You know,
that's how he has that fucking psycho.
Terminally happy fucking smile
on his face, you know? And um,
I don't know. I realized some shit in
that moment. I brought it to stage.
I started riffing though fucking
thing worked and I recorded it. But
beautiful thing about the universities,
when you hit something great happens,
something else has to balance it out.
Like I skipped to see Peyton manning fuck
up the Superbowl and thus make me feel
vindicated.
And then two weeks later,
a crushing fucking overtime loss.
It wasn't crushing cause they used,
they used to beat us by fucking, these
will be just like seven to one. All right,
you got to admit, okay, you Canada fucks.
Remember that back in the day it was a
joke. Our hockey was a joke. First of all,
90% of the people in the
league were all from Canada.
Granted they were only six
fucking teams, but still, um,
and you guys used to crush us and now
we're breathing down your neck and you
better enjoy that gold medal because I
got a feeling that's the last one you're
going to be fucking having for
awhile. How do you like that? Huh? Ah,
you wait till fucking next year buddy.
Now can you guys handle that shit talking?
All right. Anyways, so twice this,
I had incidents with people in the crowd.
Um,
and both of them were women and a,
I'm the first to tell you that I do have
fucking issues with women, but the, uh,
the first night, um, I was on stage
and there was this woman right down,
I don't know if it's stage left to
stage right from where I'm fucking added
stage left.
All right?
So I think that's the proper terminology.
Why the fuck do you guys need
to know stage left stage, right?
You're in the crowd. You
know, I go down to Mitis.
Do I need to know what fucking wrench
they're going to use? I don't need, okay,
so stage left or right. I'm looking down
and uh, this fucking girl is, she's,
you know, she's talking, continue on with
my jokes. It look down, she still talking.
So finally I say, hey, it is sweet tits.
Why don't you, uh, what's the
problem? What are you talking about?
And then she does the usual,
you know,
I wouldn't say she was attractive
if she was in from a small town,
she be a Hottie, you know, just
out of percentages. But, um,
so she did the usual
like, what, what I have a,
I have no idea what the fuck I'm doing.
You know, 10 minutes later I looked back,
she's still fucking talking,
gets a little more heated.
I basically went to her table about six
times until I finally told her to shut
the fuck up and then a,
and aren't really even fucking
remember that all of a sudden,
next thing you know,
she's hammered and she's getting kicked
out when I got like five minutes left in
my show. So she threatened to sue the
place and all this type of shit. Now,
usually that's the end of the night.
You know,
the whole crowd is fucking clapping as
she's leaving because she's been fucking
annoying. Everybody around
them who paid to see the show.
All right. So, uh, usually that's the end
of it. But you know what this psycho did.
She actually sent a letter to the Improv
and she tried to pretend that that she
wasn't herself.
She tried to pretend that she was an
impartial member of the audience who
completely agreed with her and thought
that I was a fucking idiot. So, uh,
I want to read you a little bit
of this fucking letter here. Um,
to whom it may concern,
I attended bill burrs first
show on Friday the 26th,
and was utterly appalled by his
performance. I love comedy. Oh,
this is what you always have
to do whenever you bitch. Um,
and you're not there in person,
so they can't see what a
radiant human being you are.
You have to then after
you state your bitch,
you then have to fucking show how easy
going you are as a human being. So anyway,
she saw my show. She was utterly appalled
by by my performance, and then she goes,
I love comedy and I certainly
expect there to be rudeness,
crudity and what can be offensive topics.
That's what comedy is all about. It
makes it fun. That being said, okay,
now she's established how fucking cool
and laid back she is back to trash and
old fucking howdy duty. Here
she goes. That being said,
Bill Bird took it way too far and he was
quite unprofessional to say the least.
While there was indeed quite
a lot to laugh at. Yeah,
that was the part where you were sober.
You're fucking lightweight.
That was the beginning of the show
when you weren't fucking on your ninth
fucking drink and you were actually
paying attention to the show. So yeah,
initially there was indeed quite a lot
to laugh at us like as a person is trying
to write as if it's medieval times and
I should be like fucking holding this
thing like a goddamn scroll. I know that
isn't medieval ish, but she's using,
she's doing that biblical thing,
which she's using extra fucking words
to try to sound intelligent. Well,
initially there was indeed quite a lot
to laugh at instead of being at first he
was funny. Um, anyways, the show ended up,
the show ended up being a complete
disappointment okay for it. Okay.
This is her complaint here for at
least 30 minutes. He blasts for me,
God and the name of Jesus Christ.
He outright degraded the
Catholic religion. All right.
Now that's complete bullshit.
I only blasphemy God,
the name of Jesus Christ and the Catholic
religion for about seven minutes.
30 minutes.
What am I fucking George Carlin.
I can't talk about
anything but 30 minutes.
Maybe you weren't so fucking
hammered. You dumb cunt. You know,
you'd have a better perception of,
of, of how much time had elapsed.
Okay.
Oh Jesus. All right, let's
continue. Although I'll get,
this isn't another thing. Nothing was
she's, she's pulling this move again.
He outright to graded
the Catholic religion,
although I do not belong to this religion.
So now you supposed to be like,
wow,
she's not even part of that religion.
And even she found it offensive.
Have you guys picked up on that?
On Youtube at all? Like when
someone wants to trash Obama, um,
they'll say like, Obama is the worst
president ever. And then they'll write,
and I'm a democrat. You don't
like, you can prove it either way.
Just trying to cut people off the
pass before they go, fuck you.
You fuck news watching right
wing, but whatever. You know,
women need to shut the fuck up. And
I'm a girl, that dumb shits. Okay.
So evidently she was,
she was offended and she's not even,
she's not even Catholic anyway, she said
it was offensive and what he said, uh,
went on and on again while this
type of thing should be except, uh,
expected.
He took it way too far and
there was a young lady who like,
I and my friends was becoming offended.
Yeah,
of course she was because she's you, you
fucking psycho. Can you believe that?
She thinks I'm this fucking stupid.
And I know what this point is.
Probably not obvious to you guys,
but wait till I finish the rest of this.
All right. I'm probably going
to sound like some maniac here,
but I don't give a fuck.
I said,
there was a young lady who liked I and
my friends was becoming offended and said
a few words. It's said a few
words to someone at our table,
you fucking lying sack
a twat. Anyways, uh,
she, she said, uh, when he
rudely addressed her, that's
when I said, Hey lady,
I guess lady his route.
Hey Lady,
could you do me a favor and maybe
look at the show at some point? Um,
he said when he really addressed her,
she told him that she was Catholic.
That never happened.
He had no apologies or considerations.
Just utter disrespect. Okay. First
of all, she never said that out.
She never said she was Catholic.
And if she did, she said,
it's so quietly that I couldn't hear it.
So how the fuck could this random fucking
woman in the crowd here what she said?
Okay.
Oh, this fucking thing. It's gonna make
me mad again. All right, let's continue.
After he finally got off that subject,
his show just got worse.
This is when she's on
about her six strength.
It appeared to my friends and I that he
may have been getting heat from some of
the audience and that
he felt uncomfortable.
This may very well be the reason why
he continued to pick on the lady,
the lady. This is why I'm
picking on her, not because I,
and as I'm doing my act,
by the way,
I keep looking down and she's getting
some sort of Martini thing that looks like
there's a beer in it.
I don't know what the fuck it was.
It's one of those chick fucking drinks,
you know?
Like what if we took root bear and
second fucking roofie in it, you know,
she was drinking those
things. Okay. And uh,
so now she goes from this
very male, uh, it goes,
this may very well be the reason why he
continued to pick on that lady even at
one point telling her to shut the fuck up.
Yeah.
I told you to shut the fuck up because
you were talking the entire time.
You twat anyways. A, this is downright
on professional. Who said that?
Someone cannot say a few words
to people at their table.
Did you see how obvious this is that
this is this the actual fucking woman who
would give a fuck this much that
you would write three pages.
They were quietly speaking and not
making any noise whatsoever. Oh,
yet you heard her say that she was
Catholic on the other side of the stage.
There was another table talking quite a
bit more and they were louder due to the
drinks yet he did not pick on
them. Do you own it? You fucking
okay.
All right. Let me just fucking
relax. So this is even funny anymore.
Like I totally lost it. I've, I've
lost the whole humor and this,
this is fucking making me so mad.
They were more disruptive than anything,
although he of course made jokes about it.
All right.
There was this table next to me.
They were also drinking,
but they were more doing that church thing
where I would say something funny and
then there was sorta like
fucking repeating it. So
they were a little bit rowdy,
but they were acceptable.
This woman who was fucking out drinking
every one at the other table had
basically essentially her fucking back
to me to the point that if I fucking
punched her in the back of the head,
I woulda got two minutes for boarding pat.
Possibly a fucking game misconduct.
All right. There's something for you.
Olympic hockey, fucking people.
Anyways, let's, let's, let's
continue here. Actually,
that would be roughing,
wouldn't it?
Let's say I took the mic stand
and I turned it sideways.
I could across checked her on the
fucking neck. All right, here we go.
Now we are convinced that his wrong
demeanor was due to his discomfort.
After realizing that he had offended
some of the audience in order to justify
himself and ease any tension
coming from the audience member.
He said something along the lines,
don't listen to me.
I'm just an idiot up here speaking.
Pray for me please.
That was obviously a demonstration
of his uneasiness that this is,
this is how drunk she was.
What I was doing was I was,
I was telling people in the crowd that
if they were religious that I respected
their religion. All right. I just had,
I just personally don't buy into it.
Okay.
So I'm only stopping right now to
say this because I know some of you,
you get so religious,
you get so into it that you can add,
you get so holy that you
can actually commit murder.
Okay.
You know, God's usually Angela
tool a row, you know, vengeance.
I think that was the line I used. I said,
okay, you shouldn't be getting mad at me.
You should pray for me
to help me see the light.
And everyone got a huge fucking
laugh at it about it. Okay.
And this lady is basically us.
I can't wait to email her back.
I don't know. I, I've, I've flipped
flopped a hundred times in my head.
What I was going to say.
Okay.
You know, I just can't wait to, uh,
I think I'm just gonna write back
something really quickly. Like, Ruth,
you actually pretending to not be the
dumb drunk bitch in the crowd is one of
the funniest things I've ever read.
Something to that effect.
Basically let her know that I know that
it's her and I'll see you next year.
At the Improv. You can't. Um, anyways,
I'm very supplies prize at your,
this is where she tries to,
um,
this is what she tries to
get me banned from the club.
I'm very surprised that uh,
your club hosted this comedian.
It was a true disappointment.
I am embarrassed as I was the
one who suggested the Improv.
When my friends and I were planning
to on seeing a comedy show,
I do hope that you will consider not
having this comedian back as he gives your
club a bad name. If this is a, this
had been my first time to the Improv,
I never would have returned. You might
consider hiring some local talent.
There are several good
comedians in the area.
We are good friends with one of them.
If you like his name,
I'll be happy to give it a
bit bit, bit, bit. All right.
As for the lady who we picked on,
she and her table,
we're unjustifiably asked to leave.
There was no grounds on having them
escorted from the show right in the middle
of it.
That's how drunk she was.
She got escorted out 50 minutes
into my one hour set and she's like,
she was escorted out in the middle of it.
Do you understand how drunk this one was?
I taught for Geez about Jesus for 30
minutes. No actually it was seven minutes.
I was escorted out in the middle.
No,
you were actually escorted out 50 minutes
into the show when you were on your
fucking six drink.
You're drunk content.
There were no grounds of on
having them escorted from uh,
from the show right in the middle of it.
Again,
they were not being
disruptive at all. This, this,
this impartial person just wants to keep
talking about how innocent this fucking
lady is that she never met. If it hadn't
been for bill burr picking on them,
no one would even notice them kick
the kid you tell. This is just the,
the fucking drunk argument they had and
the crowd and the car on the ride home,
the loud table.
And the other side though is the one
that took away attention from his show.
I do understand that it is private
property and that anyone can be asked to
leave at any time, but this was wrong
to do. This is a wrong to do it.
I personally believe that she should
receive an apology from the Improv,
but mostly from bill burr. That's
clearly not my call. Just a thought.
What a fucking, uh, I don't know.
Did I take too long reading that
fucking thing. There you go.
You want to be a standup comedian?
That's what the fuck are
you have to deal with?
She's actually like a total
fucking control freak.
And what happened that night was
she completely lost on all levels.
Yeah.
You know it's weird.
You become like a part time psychologist
as you're breaking down the crowd as a
comedian and she sat at the power
position at the table. The table.
Is that like a fucking, we'll say like
a 30 degree angle coming in stage left.
This is going to get technical, right? You
fucks. Don't, don't, don't leave me here.
She, you know, she didn't sit
at the chair furthest away.
If you sit furthest away,
everybody you're at the table with
has the back of their head to you.
So then when you want to fucking
talk it's, it's a difficult time.
What she did was not only did
she sit in the first chair,
she sat on the first chair closest to me,
so the,
so all she had to do was turn around.
She had the whole fucking tables
attention and when she stood up,
when she went to leave her whole table
stood up like a bunch of fucking minions.
You know,
like you remember that dude,
he used to carry the fucking umbrella
for puffy. That's how they all got up.
It was pathetic.
And people like that surround themselves
with fucking weak people like that
because any normal people, person,
you know, think about that.
All you guys listening to right now,
if your,
if your body was being a drunk fucking
asshole and got booted from the club,
would you get up and leave immediately?
Stand up like the fucking general just
got up. I mean, I guess maybe you would,
could you be [inaudible] drunk?
Maybe he's going to go fucking walk
out and pee on a cop or something.
I guess maybe, I dunno. Anyways,
you know, before I emailed her back,
what do you guys think I should write
back and come up with something clever
other than calling her a cunt
like I did. I think I'm just, I'm,
I'm going to write back something to the
effect that I realized that it was her
and um, I dunno. I don't fucking know.
Was that just a big waste of time?
Should I not have been bothered
with all of that? You know,
I dunno then and I had another
incident with another fucking person.
I don't know. I have issues with,
with a beautiful women. I really do.
This is actually a bit I want to
do on stage and I'll just, I'll,
maybe I'll do part of it for you
here at bay. The basic idea, I just,
I don't respect them on a certain level.
I feel like I had to do something.
Okay
to achieve in life. All they had to do
was basically they were born beautiful.
This is really not an accomplishment
I guess. You go to the gym,
you stay beautiful past a certain age.
It is an accomplishment I guess. But,
you know,
yeah,
I dunno. For an order as a guide
to get around beautiful women,
you have to accomplish all this shit in
life and all they have to do to get to
where the fuck you're at
after accomplishing all this
shit is basically take a
shower and feather the hair back like
Farrah Fawcett and they're in the fucking
VIP. You know? I also
don't like him because, uh,
I dunno. I Dunno if they're
smart, if they're smart.
They're absolutely stunning though.
I have to admit that. But you know,
okay.
If they're, if they're dumb, that's like,
it's like he got a Lamborghini but you
find out it has a four cylinder in it,
or even worse. My fucking hybrid. Did
that make any fucking sense? You know,
they have that one default emotion.
Oh my God.
And they give 58 different reads.
You know,
if they see something cute like a
little puppy, they're like, oh, Mike.
Yeah.
You know, if you do something
sweet from, Oh my God,
okay,
they, you know, you do something
that they fucking hate. Oh my God,
fucking idiots.
They got three words floating around
there and there were in VIP,
you know,
he
said, uh, was actually saying like,
I was trying to figure out why I was
finding these fucking women so attractive
other than the obvious that they were good
looking women. This guy actually said,
hey, bill, uh, beside the obvious hot
women vigorously scrubbing the floor,
I really set that up bad.
He's saying,
this is why men find women curlers
attractive. I just blew that joke.
He said, besides the obvious hot
women vigorously scrubbing the floor,
I have to do you,
are you so deserved a huge laugh on
that and I just fucked you out of it.
I'm sorry about that.
Um, anyways, he says,
I figured out why we love watching this
so much. When they released that stone,
the way they let it slide it out of their
hand is reminiscent of the way a skill
for woman releases your cock after
delivering a massive hand job.
First of all,
I hope you're a surfer cause that's the
only reason why to the massive head job,
Bruh. I'm fucking massive change up.
Or maybe you just have a fucking bit,
oh maybe I'll just, you have a fat cock.
I Dunno. So anyways, she goes, uh,
they don't drop it. Don't push it.
Just let it slide out naturally as I go
to sleep with my boxes around my ankles.
Oh, I forgot. That was
creepy. I know, I read it.
I was supposed to just read the beginning
joke cause I thought the joke was
fucking great. I forgot the
fucking picture. And his
guys with those fucking insect
looking legs on guy's legs.
Look like insects with that fucking
hair all over skinny fucking legs were a
mess. Fucking mess. I'm
like praying mantis legs.
Anyways, I'm a long time ago. I talked
about unacceptable. This is when,
you know the podcast sucks and I'm just
plowing from fucking topic to topic and
there's just no sort of a no
segue other than dead silence.
[inaudible]
in some somebody to do a Bob
Dole impression. Like I had a,
can I tap out at this fucking point
37 minutes in a bad wedding stories.
Um, hey bill, I haven't listened to
your podcast since the beginning.
Decided it was about time they emailed
you and told you how much I enjoy it.
Thank you very much. Uh, the, okay,
let's get to the, uh, let's
get to the marriage thing.
Um,
okay.
I got a marriage story when I was 23.
I was dating a girl and she got pregnant.
Uh, dude. Okay. Uh, so we
decided to get married.
Okay. Stupid. Fucking move number two,
even though a month before this I
was thinking about dumping her ass.
Stupid mistake number three. Actually
that was the smart move. That was,
that was the three card Monte right there.
Don't knock her up.
Don't fucking merrier. White. Knock
her up. Mary, her dump her ass.
You know which one had the
marble? You fucked up. All right,
so all the plans are made, our families
meet each other. Okay. Just cause I,
you know,
had to do that stupid three card Monte
joke in a desperate attempt to try to be
remotely funny at this point.
You know what it was.
I have a blue wind screen this week.
I'm going to blow that. I'm going to,
I'm going to blame it on that one. You
know my fucking dog ate the orange one,
so I'm going to blame it on the blue
wind screen. Anyway. So basically,
sky's 23 years old.
He knocks up this fucking girl.
He decides to get married
even though he just,
he thought about dumping our
a month before. So anyways,
so all the plans are made.
Um,
families meet each other, invitations
are sent out, all that bullshit.
So three days before the wedding,
I'm watching some stupid movie where
this guy tells his other guy that his dad
told him before his wedding,
it's never too late to change your mind,
to which his friends says, but
you're not married. And I guess it,
there's, that's a lap. So anyways, uh,
so taking this as a sign from God that I
just happened to be watching this movie.
I canceled the wedding.
Great. Fucking move.
All right. Which suffice to say,
brought a shitstorm into my life.
The worst part is that I actually
felt so bad. I marry the chick.
Three months later I'll,
dude, you were out.
You were fucking out.
So basically I was a pussy.
Yeah. Yeah. But two, that's a hard than
you were dealing with a lot of shit at 23.
Your parents were crying.
She was knocked up. Yeah.
I would say you were pussy. You
gave into peer pressure. Anyways,
we were married for seven years with every
year being worse than the year before.
So we're divorced,
so we're divorced now.
So I guess I should have gone
with my gut to wrap this up,
I got a little gripe with,
with chicks.
My ex used to ask me when the marriage
was going down, if I could go back,
would I not meet her? Which
I would say, fuck yeah,
I would avoid you like the
plague. Which she would say, uh,
but at which point she would say,
but you wouldn't have our two kids.
Don't you love them? And then he
would say, yeah, but then I'd say,
but I would never have met you.
So I would have never had the kids.
So in that scenario,
the kids aren't even a thought.
This of course would lead to a
huge fight about my lack of caring,
a moral to the story. Don't use logic
when talking to chicks. All right?
That's actually not the moral
to the story. What it is,
is you got to think how women think, you
know, which you know, if you're lucky,
at some point when you're 90,
you'll know,
you'll understand 10% of what the
fuck is going on in that brain. Um,
basically when she's asking you that,
she was asking that,
I would guess one of two reasons.
One, she was insecure that, you know,
you knocked her up and then you married
her and you know that you were Gunna
merrier. Then you broke it off and
then you fucking married her. Uh,
believe it or not, I'm sure that's not
how she dreamed of getting married.
She probably dreamed of
meeting her soulmate and they
was so hopelessly in love
that everyone in the crowd had tears in
their lives for, they never found a love.
So as great as theirs,
she could have been thinking that and
she wanted you to reassure her or she
probably was just banging you,
you know,
it didn't want to fucking marry you
and didn't think that you were the one
either.
And all of a sudden she got knocked up
and she's probably sitting there looking
at the side of your fucking head.
One morning you're eating pancakes,
trying to find where in
the world she loves you.
You know, on what fucking level. You know,
just watching your temples going
in and out as you're chewing,
just fighting that fucking urge to
slam a toaster over your fucking head.
You know, just wondering how the hell
did I ended up with this fucking guy?
Why did I say Yes to this guy?
Why did I let him fucking drop a fucking
load in me? What is wrong with me?
And just trying to make the fact
that you had these two kids,
just a justice enough, you know, that's
what the fuck was probably going on.
But, uh, I dunno, dude,
you didn't really talk about how much
of a nightmare the wedding was that that
was the meat of the story there.
I think you at the beginning and the end,
but what are you thinking is
she's coming down the aisle.
Okay.
What is your family thinking?
You're knocked her up and then you
dumped her and yet, and you're like, oh,
fuck it. I'll marry, or
anyways, and you're only 23.
They know you don't want to do it.
Okay.
Those weren't tears of
joy, my friend. You know?
What are you thinking is you're up there,
you know,
was your Cumber Bun like wringing wet
with flop sweat as you were standing out?
I can't imagine that.
Ah,
has anybody ever just ran out the side
door? Because I can definitely see like,
oh my God, I don't know what to
say. How do I get out of this shit?
And then just in a
panic when they started,
Eh, Eh, Eh, Eh, Eh, Eh,
Eh,
turn around looking, where is she? Oh,
why the fuck didn't I have some wedding
music underneath this would've would've
been hilarious if I fucking prepared.
You know, you're looking for the bitch,
where the fuck is he?
And then she comes around the corner
and you're trying to make yourself lover
and she comes around the corner and you
just see that fucking face and you see
those eyebrows at,
you know,
we're going to be touching by the time
she's 40 and you just fucking run out the
side door in those cheap
tuxedo bowling shoes
and you know what I mean? And you're
in such a fucking panic, you know,
there's no way
you're going to be able to get your car
keys out in time, get them into the door,
open the door,
lock the door and get in there.
And it's like people are
going to be coming out,
running out of the church like
some fucking Zombie movie is,
you're trying to get your car started.
I made the move there. Is She,
if anybody does that, don't go
to your car. You keep running.
Okay.
Most people get married in the suburbs,
so headed head for a wooded
area. All right? Go Online.
Learn how to turn your fucking
cumber bun and do a tent.
Hang out there for a couple of days.
Let's shit cool off. Grow a beard,
come back to town, get some provisions.
That point you'll be so fucking filthy.
You just another homeless guy
wearing a suit. You know what I mean?
Just let her forget all about you.
Then maybe they'll think that you're
mentally ill and then uh, you know,
one day you just show up on your
mother's front steps and she faints.
Her Dad catches you and punches you in
the face cause he's a former marine.
You know, haven't we all seen
this movie? I'm trying to say.
Run out the fucking door.
Okay.
I run out the fucking door. If you're in
that situation, during that situation.
All right. Uh, Bill, longtime
listener, first time writer.
I got a winning story to tell you.
I'm 23 years old now.
The 23 year old I had been,
uh, here's one for Ya. Uh,
don't go to a wedding or
getting married at 23.
They all seem to have bad stories.
Um,
I've been to a few weddings and let
me start by saying in this story,
it wasn't actually a wedding I witnessed.
It was a wicking,
a Wiccan hand fastening. Okay. Now though,
for those of you not familiar
with the wicked religion, uh,
I just want to state at this
point, neither am I. Um,
I can't remember if that's the one that
actually has all those pagan symbols
that,
you know,
the Catholic Church then said that
they were devil signs according to the
fucking Rosetta Stone or whatever that
fucking movie was. I read the book too.
What the fuck is the name of that
Davinci Code? Um, whatever it was called,
a Wiccan hand.
Fascinating.
And I know that because my sister
didn't invite people to our wedding,
she invited them to her hand.
Fascinating.
That's why he knew it was a Wiccan hand.
And not a wedding because she said,
I'd like to invite you to my
hand fastening Jesus Christ.
Um, he said, if you're 41,
you still don't know when a hand
fascinating is congratulations. Thank you.
Because I didn't, so anyways, he goes,
I'm 17 at the time, my sister's 23 or 24.
We both still live with our parents
or boyfriend and unemployed,
alcoholic living off money. His
mom left him when she died. Ah,
there you go ladies.
There you go.
You don't have to settle for less when
this guys like him out there. Um, anyways,
um,
the fuck am I,
why didn't I make this type bigger? Jesus.
What a flop this podcast is. So anyways,
so this fucking alcoholic was
over for dinner one night.
He tapped his fork on the glass a few
times to get everyone's attention.
We were three feet from him
and immediately my stomach
knotted up because I knew
this moron was about to say something
stupid. You got, I got to meet you.
You guys are fucking funny writers,
man. Some really talented people.
Listen to this fucking podcast. You
guys write better than I do. Anyways.
Basically he announced his engagement
to my sister in front of my mom and dad
pulled out to onyx rings and they put
them on each other's middle fingers.
You know, I went to the Onyx Strip
club and the Houston last night.
How funny is that? Anyways,
it was dead silent and um,
the look of a repressed horror on
my mom's face was unmistakable.
It was so awkward.
So I just started clapping going Yay.
Quietly because nobody else joined in.
Oh, that's great. Is that
your role in the family?
You're the person who always tries to
make it better. Uh, God bless Ya. Anyways,
it was just dead silence and my sister
and her boyfriend kissing each other like
everything was fine.
A few months later I found out they were
financing those rings and going into
payments on them.
Every week my sister's collecting child
support and neither of them have a job
and they are financing onyx hand.
Fascinating rinks.
Jesus Christ,
Jesus Christ.
I can't believe there's more to
this story. All right, here we go.
Fucking knee deep. I got to go the rest of
the way. All right. Anyway, so I finally,
uh,
it finally gets to their hand fastening
day and they're doing the ceremony right
on Newport beach.
It's in the middle of the day on a,
on Sunday in the summer,
they didn't have, oh,
they didn't reserve a piece of beach or
anything. They just showed up and go, hey,
let's have the wedding here.
Um,
the family we had, ah, fuck, I got
to sit close to the damn screen.
I can't read anymore. The family we have
near the beach mostly all showed up.
All the people who lived near
the beach mostly showed all, uh,
there were about 30 or 40 of us.
None of us,
none of us are dressed in beach close.
Half of them are in suits and dresses.
There are no chairs.
There's not even an altar.
Everybody's just standing around hot and
they can't sit down because there's no
chairs and they don't,
they don't want to ruin their clothes.
My sister shows up in an all
black gown with the veil.
The boyfriend is wearing like a Tux
with his face painted like one of the
misfits, kind of like a
skeleton face. Jesus Christ.
It sounds like the episode of the office.
Anyways,
they don't do any
traditional wedding stuff.
They just go right up front of the crowd
with their Wiccan priest or whatever.
The wicked priest is basically
just a friend of theirs.
He reads a bunch of a bunch of stuff
from a book in some other language.
My sister and the boyfriend and
responding in some of their language.
Nobody has any idea what's going on.
Then all of a sudden the boyfriend pulls
out this crazy looking knife with a
what? A hilt. I don't know what that
is. Uses it to cut my sister's veil.
Then pokes the end of it into
his finger until he's bleeding.
He sticks the knife into the sand and
wraps his bloody hand around my sister's
neck while they kiss the stone.
Hippie priest holds up his book and
said something loud in that different
language.
I assume it was he equivalent equivalent
of I now pronounce you husband and
wife.
I'm sure being comedian.
You've heard the sound of 50
people gasping simultaneously.
Family members in suits and dresses
are just walking away at this point.
A lifeguard saw what the boyfriend did
with the knife called the cop and the day
ended prematurely with him getting cuffed
and driven away in a police cruiser.
Jesus Christ. Anyways, thanks
for the podcast. They really
enjoy it. Jesus Christ.
How about a fucking round of
applause for that story? All right.
I think I have to read up on
the a Wiccan religion. You know,
one thing I did like about that,
I did like the fact that they just showed
up and just decided to have a wedding
and they avoided all those other costs.
Um,
cause wanted to say halfway
through that like, you
know, they didn't have,
they didn't reserve that piece of the
beach or anything and I was thinking like,
well he never had to back in the day,
you know what I mean?
He just fucking had a wedding.
There was,
it wasn't like nine zillion fucking
dollars. It didn't matter where you were.
But I guess you have to do that now
because there's nine zillion people.
And a bankers run the fucking world.
Hey, speaking of that, did you get,
somebody sent me an email the other day,
evidently Europe elected a president.
Do you hear that? Europe elected a
president, not England, not France.
Europe. The entire continent
now has a fucking president,
has one guy in charge of all of them.
See that just like those three d
TVs that are only a few months away,
that new world daughter is going to be
available right down at the best coming,
sewed, come and fucking soon. If you go
on to read about the uh, the bailout,
uh,
rolling stone has a great article and a,
usually I try to stay away from their
politics because there's so brutally to
the left. It's fucking
ridiculous. Um, you know,
they never trashed Democrats or when
they do, it's so like light hand.
They just doing it just because
they trashed a republican so bad.
They're trying to show that they're fair
and balanced like those other fucking
maniacs. Um, Fox News actually has a
store now when you go through the airport,
which I think is hilarious. They sell
water and that type of shit. So I dunno.
It's going to be,
this will be one fucking news channel.
This is going to be one president
and one fucking currency of muddy,
and you better do what they say.
That's going to be the end of it,
my friends.
Okay.
[inaudible].