Yes.
Hey,
what's going on is bill bar and
it's the a Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast
just before Friday. It. Ah,
just checking in on you.
Lovely.
Nia in the background. What's going
on? Oh, are you? How's your week going?
Oh, freckles made it. Oh,
freckles made. It is 72 days.
I didn't drink 72 days.
It just became a part of me life and
the fuck can check in dead. It was over.
I went to the apartment, had
40 drinks. Uh, yes I did.
I had been boozing. Uh, I might actually
be legally drunk right now. I just had a,
just had a beer. Um, what,
oh you said shout out. I thought
you said shut up. Look to,
if you're going to be on the podcast,
be on the podcast.
Don't be on in the background.
You know what kills me is
you saw me setting up my
fucking mixer and you sitting
there in the background and it's
just like, why the fuck you know,
why would you just keep waiting?
Where the hell's the other microphone?
Go get the other microphone. It's
in the drawer over there. Um,
anyways, while she does that bullshit. Uh,
let's address some of the top news
stories of the week, shall we?
I don't watch the news, so I don't
know what's going on internationally,
but I do know this,
the buffalo bills a talking all
kinds of shit. You know what I mean?
Talking, oh, we're gonna do
this and we're going to do that.
And a wonderful grammatic sentences like,
don't nobody liked the patriots.
Um, you know, the usual
shit, and this is the thing,
they have a good enough defense.
They'll beat us once this year,
probably going to split with them and
they're going to talk all kinds of crap
and fucking rex. Ryan's going to wear a
wig and smell somebody's feet and Yada,
Yada, fucking Yada, the whole goddamn
thing. And at the end of the fucking day,
the bills aren't going to win the
Superbowl. So let me ask you this.
You miserable constantly. She's putting
on the fucking wind. Think sock there.
You got an auction. You're hearing.
All right. Just hang on a second.
I've got to get through this.
So let me ask you this.
You miserable cunts out in western
New York, who at the end of the day,
if you just beat the Patriots won,
let's say you fucking take the whole,
you wind bolt, which you're not
going to do, but anything can happen.
Let's just say you do that, you know,
and then you don't win the Superbowl.
What was all the fucking talk about?
Huh? You know what the deal is?
If you give Rex Ryan of fucking defend,
this is what I loved when Rex Ryan had
a defense with the jets and he had a gay
manager, quarterback. He talked
to all this shit, Yada Yad,
I'm going to win the fucking Superbowl.
Blahblahblahblahblah even
beat the Patriots at home
and the playoffs kicked our
ass if remember correctly.
Right.
Then all of a sudden all those players
left and then Rex Ryan didn't talk shit
anymore and they were sitting there going,
yeah,
I think rex has learned his lesson.
You know, he's a little older,
a little more mature. Well blue, blue,
blue, blue, blue, blue, blue, and now,
no,
he wasn't.
He kept his fucking mouth shut cause
he didn't have the team to do it.
So now all of a sudden he's got a defense
again and look at them whey the fuck
out in Western fucking New York.
Buffalo,
Buffalo, one of those one
professional sports towns.
You only got one fucking team.
It don't even bring up the savers.
You fucking assholes. You never even
been to a Stanley Cup final hall.
That's right. You're dead.
After further review,
the goal counts.
Why am I doing this to you guys?
I actually like Buffalo.
I really enjoy that town. I don't know
what the fucking problem is out there.
Maybe if I lived there every day and I
was out there with a bunch of miserable
cons that we're sick of buffalo wings
and there was nothing else to out to eat
there other than some Nachos
or some salads. I have no idea.
I don't know what your fucking
problem is. Hey, people are buffalo.
Why don't you fucking grow up? All
right. We're in the same division.
We're playing each other two times a
year and for the last fucking time. Okay.
I know you don't understand this cause
your team's never won a Superbowl.
If you win a game in September,
it doesn't mean shit.
So there's really no reason to be
sitting here talking shit and all that.
All right,
so I love it that you're doing it.
I love that rex is doing it and the
fan base is going to take on Rex Ryan's
personality. You know what I mean?
I actually think if I had to guess,
if there was going to be any,
yeah.
Head coach and the professional league.
Okay.
To go from being rex to be an a,
what's a woman's name
begins with an r Rashida.
What's a white woman's name near a white
woman's individuals are Rachel to go
from Rec Black Rachel's too. Well, I mean,
yeah, you can name a white baby Rachel.
Nobody freaks out. They're
like, oh, I get it. Yeah.
Nobody would freak out if you
named a black baby. Rachel,
What is wrong with you saying? Can I
ask a question though? Is this one,
what it means to be a sports fan is
just to antagonize other sports fans who
aren't a fan of your particular
team that you support.
It's just like nonstop antagonizing.
Yeah.
In the words of John Rambo,
they drew first blood.
They drew first blood.
Okay.
I wasn't talking 80 showed
them a compliment and buffalo
the whole fucking year
cause I got a nice thing. Amazing.
I think rex Ryan's support
poking at and the Vermont,
the reminding of how they didn't go
to the Stanley Cup or if they did,
they didn't win. Does that
kind of needling? Antagonizing?
Yeah,
it's,
it's just like the real housewives
with a dash left less like continents.
You know, you, you guys instead Cardenas
and the sports fandom. No. Yeah,
but we don't go like a, you know,
that's why you had an abortion and
you're fucking babies got three thumbs.
That of shit that people
say to the players are men.
And we would watch that 60 minutes
thing and it was all about how like,
but you know there's a certain generation
that feels like they can't take their
kids to ball games anymore
because the amount of lag,
just vitriol and hatred coming from
the scan. That wasn't just a story.
So then they told us the story. So
it wasn't, it wasn't a real thing.
It wasn't a thing that happens where
people are up there and they're like,
that's why you know Bob,
like they're just saying all
this horrible personal shit.
They're screaming it at players.
No, this is what it was,
was that was the point
they wanted to prove.
So they went out and got footage to prove
it out to eat. They think it's bad now.
Dude, it was fucking animals when I
was growing up, when I was growing up,
he would stab still and fucking
at dodger stadium a few
years ago did not go well.
Look what happened on Sally Jessy.
Raphael.
Did one fucking guests kill
another guests? I mean,
you're going to have those moments.
You're talking about Jenny
Jones and Jenny 30 years ago,
but it happened talking about stuff
that is happening currently today. Okay.
And then that happened at the Dodger's
stadium. That was three years ago.
That's not currently today.
I feel like it's pretty current versus
something that happened on like, Hey,
two home games a fucking year.
Why can't you over 10 years is almost
a thousand fucking home game meant that
people like there are a certain,
I'm not saying all Hashtag
not all sports fans,
I'm just saying there's not a certain
section of sports fans that will yell the
most inappropriate, disgusting,
horrible things at the players.
Philly's pretty bad. Philly's pretty
bad. But generally speaking non yeah,
you go to games and they had like,
people like they won't let you go to
your fucking seat while the balls in play
and you have to stand there while some
old lady holds up a sign that says not
yet. And then finally turns around and
says, okay, now that you can't go out the,
uh, the Roland Garros and the other, um,
had a task that snooty shit,
that's it. Like Games now,
unless you go to like an old stadium,
like the old stadium,
Connie has like the old guard, but there's
not a lot of old stadiums left. Like A,
I will say this like fans on the west
coast or fucking lunatics like out in
California, like, I don't
like going to games. Uh,
you're afraid you're going to get
stabbed in the parking lot? No,
I just feel like I'm just not
literally get stabbed. It's just,
it's not a fun environment.
Like I used to wear my red sox shit to
a Yankee stadium before we won the world
series and I got a ton of shit. But
the, once they saw that I, you know,
I was good natured about it or
whatever, and then they'd be like, Hey,
what's up man? How long you in the city?
Boy, he lived down here at Blah Blah.
They were cool. But out in California
at that turn never happens.
It's just, you're, you're wearing
the other team's stuff and fuck you.
You're a bitch. Blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah. And it's
just nonstop, nonstop, nonstop.
And it's like, you know, even if you
were a buddy of mine, Jason [inaudible],
Jason ally had worn Indians Jersey
to a Dodgers game one time and um,
the doctors now when this guy was,
you know,
take that fucking thing out of the hall
is shit. So I don't understand that.
Like what?
Yeah,
what is that about that fuck that that
like I hate you because you are a fan of
another team.
Like I automatically hate you.
It's like they're taking
that competitiveness that's
obviously it's supposed to
be on the field,
right.
Drives a whole game and the whole business
and they're like internalizing it and
it's the male version of real housewives,
you know,
I don't understand who
actually says the same thing.
She actually feels like that's our
sort of version of sports and I always
counter but women like sports as well,
so I don't really feel like it's the
girl version of sports because women like
sports and play sports.
Can I tell you something?
Finding a woman that likes sports is
like, it's a, it's a diamond in the rough.
Like when you find like that's
a big thing with guys don't add.
She's into sports. She fucking loves them.
I mean that's like unbelievable. Okay.
Okay. No, I mean, okay.
I mean your first okay.
Wasn't like that I Merced. Okay. It
was like, so I just stay. You Go.
That's what you see are first.
Okay. Was in your point is,
and then you tried to be like, oh, okay.
That first. Okay. Was how you felt.
It's just funny to me that that's like,
that's like a thing as she likes sports.
Yeah.
And she's into the sheet that's like it.
You'd be like Eddie and he likes going
to Brunch. I would never say that.
That would never be
a reality TV.
Yeah. It's still not a thing that I
would like need to check off a list.
Well isn't that convenient and be
excited about and he loves the real
housewives.
Well that's a big thing.
Some of our biggest arguments have been
the bullshit fucking horrific moronic TV
that you watch. Reality TV was
that you had in my life. Mike.
The understand amplification
of sound. Oh No, I'm sorry.
I haven't been like on the stage
for the past like 25 years. So no,
I guess I don't understand
how microphones work.
Well I guess you don't cause you keep
fucking taking, you had away from it.
I don't know what you had to attack me
and my career for me saying this is like
your thousandth guest spot.
How many times you're going to be
like I just moved away when I do it.
It's for comedic effect.
I just feel like you're crying
or you're trying to
measure it is I have to,
I am the sexiest mentorship I've ever had.
No,
I'm crying. I have to be like the
guy who records it in the guy,
the sound guy at the same time.
So you rarely wearing a lot of hats really
wearing a lot of hats on this podcast
that you're doing in your underwear? Yup.
Not In my underwear were regular old. No.
You've got white shorts on when I just
realized that there's ventilation and the
inner thigh and the Crotch area.
Look at this all the way across.
These are tennis shorts.
So you got to some air and that.
That's right.
You gotta make sure your
balls are breathing while
you're trying to win a grand
slam.
All
right. You're done. I guess done
shitting on me. You can't fuck with me.
Yes, I go ahead. Yeah, the week I had,
I don't give a fuck what you say to me.
You really feel like you're a design
like this whole other level. Now what?
You know what you kind of,
I don't know.
But you are though because violin
like a make a wish kid. That was a,
that was a once in a lifetime
experience you had. Which one? Oh Jesus.
See this is where you
start becoming a news.
You're mad at me cause I
had a great fucking week.
Are you mad at me that I moved away from
the mic and like the perfect way just
now? No, I'm not. I though it was actually
great though. But it was great though.
Great. Fucking weak. Yes.
When are you talking about you tell
the people about your week. Huh?
If they haven't heard already.
Cause it's all over the news, honey.
And I love how you resent it on
some level. You know what I resent?
I have a whole time in making the decision
to go because I was tired and I had
to pack. I was, I, I'm, I'm the
maybe or the whole fucking song.
All right,
here's two things that happened
this week. One, um, Thursday night,
a week ago,
uh,
Queens of the Stone Age was
getting ready for a tour.
So they were doing like a tuneup show.
You know,
those secrets shows you always hear
about like, oh my God, you know,
Queens of the stone age prince just
played in front of 40 people down in a
coffee house. You know,
you didn't hear about it
and I never hear about it. I
never hear about, I'm like, Whoa,
I could have got you in dude. You know,
you don't follow him on fucking Instagram.
Like what up?
Somehow I don't even know how people
find out about those fucking things.
I don't know how either
people who are really into like one
particular thing like prince and they're
following his every move, they're like
googling him all the time. They just
super secret fucking like whenever there's
like a band that could sell out like
a fucking stadium and then they, they're
going to go play some waffle house.
There's always like,
like the hipsters always Dixie somehow.
They know and I never fucking
know and I'm just like,
you gotta you fucking saw them.
Like yeah,
that guy was standing like fucking
two feet away. It was awesome.
They did like two hours and in the end
they gave everybody a hug and shit.
He's just like,
I have some thing.
Hipster is being hip to all this shit.
What's going on? What's going on? Right.
And a lot of this shit that hip those,
I'm pretty nice,
like a lot of the food that
they like. Anyways, so, um,
I got to open for them on that show,
which was the most insane thing ever.
And you know, I play drums.
I'm a total drum geek,
so I got to stand at the side of the
stage and watch John Theodore [inaudible]
John, yeah. All of those. It was,
they were fucking unbelievable.
They were incredible. And Josh
Homie is, he's just the coolest guy.
He's the coolest guy.
All I know. All I know,
this is when I watched that
band play. Yeah, I was,
I was immediately thinking I have to
get better as a comedian like that.
I was just like,
I don't do what I do at the level of
these guys are doing what they're doing.
They'll fucking unreal.
I never saw them live before.
I heard a couple of their songs,
but like they are,
they're an incredible band though.
I wanted to see them forever.
Tremendous musicians.
I wanted to see them forever and like
most huge bands when they play and they
come through La, it's on a Saturday
night when you're working. Yeah.
And I'm usually out of town and like
that's the story in my let dude,
you want to go to this? And
I'm like, I'd love to go. Uh,
but I'm playing,
you know,
uncle fuckees in God knows
where and then I'm never,
what did the security was never there.
Um, the road manager know who has it.
The guy that we met, oh, I'm forgetting
his name now. Bill at the elbow,
another bill for us. Jesus
Christ. He said, what did he
say that you were playing?
Oh yeah.
Fake name for a comedy club.
It wasn't, it wasn't
the Yak, Yak, Yak, Yak.
Yes. It's said you
playing Yakety Yak. Yeah.
Which was hilarious to me
because that wasn't even funny.
But just meant like your
update just running your Yap.
Great. Yeah. So anyways, uh,
so you open and Queens of the Stone Age
and the reason why that came about was
because it, Dean del Rey, Dean del
Rey, Dean del Rey who got into, uh,
a brutal motorcycle accident, who's
he's actually already is. Okay.
Thank God as fucking
road rash. Like, I mean,
yeah, saving private Ryan level,
fucking road rash dude is brutal.
He got hit by someone who car jack the
fucking escalate and came on the highway
and he said to me, he goes, yeah. He
goes, you know what's funny? He goes, uh,
I was just thinking right before I got
here because it was nobody on the road
going on. Yeah. What a
beautiful day to ride.
And he was going over Marin's house
to have lunch or something. Oh.
And this person came on the
highway on the lefthand side.
I think it just went across four lanes.
Thank God he's okay though. Oh yeah, no,
he almost lost if he said if it was a
foot like it clipped his back tire then he
high sided incentive flying.
But um,
but shout out to Dean del Right for him
that up through the, and I got to know,
I got to know John and then John asked me,
yeah.
He said, hey, he goes, because
we're doing this show. He goes,
would you want to come down and do it
now opening for bands is death is fucking
death usually death.
So that can be really bad because it's
just like they tried it a little bit,
but you handled it well. Yeah. That
one lady. So I was like, you know,
you know the, the smart part of me was
going like, no, no, no. Don't do it.
Don't do it. It's going to
suck. Right. Something else
was like, no, it was amazing.
Yeah. So that was third. But at one lady,
one lady who was drunk and everybody
around her hated her. She was going, uh,
she's gone.
Oh my God.
The around her were so pissed off.
They were so annoyed.
And like everyone there was like this
Collette collective embarrassment you feel
when someone is just absolutely unabashed,
nakedly making an ass of them.
This is all like embarrassed
and then you feel rage
is all I did was I trashed her, you
know, Blah Blah Blah. Oh my God,
somebody's going to marry that the usual
way that she's going to be a nightmare.
But then
it's like someone's going to marry.
But then the panic clock was turned on.
I didn't show it on my face,
but internally I'm like, all right,
right now that woman is annoying people.
But in about three more jokes,
they're going to start to see your point.
I need to leave second to be like,
yeah, you know what? She's right.
We didn't come down in a sea of freckled
albino content, get off the stage.
So I did like
one more little thing and then
I got out of there and uh,
then I was able to sit down and
watch the show and it was, oh man,
James is Christ Jesus Christ.
It was really fun. Yeah.
I'll tell you a right now,
if you never see Queens of the stone
age live view, you are an asshole.
Even if you don't think that you
like the Stone Age, just go do,
are not into that kind of music
or whatever the fuck you saying.
Please go see them.
Like even music that you feel like
you don't like when you see it live.
I feel like it turns like if I went to
a country, I don't, generally speaking,
I'm not into country. Cause when I
went to lady Gaga I was still like, no,
this thanks not because
that's you and you being you.
She came out in a fucking horse.
That horse,
that poor horse horse was so
beautiful and horses on the road,
road horse rode a horse, you know,
it's getting shitty oats and stuff.
Okay,
so that was Thursday and then on Saturday,
so Saturday. All right. So,
all right, this is, this is,
this is more rock and roll.
I know.
And I have no business because no matter
the end of the day I looked like Ron
Howard, so like, uh, so, uh, on, um,
I don't know, it's some
part of the week. This is,
this is actually an f is for family promo.
The guy who was one of the guys who was
doing the music for the F is for family
cartoon is Dave Cushner who played
in velvet revolver. All right.
So those guys have been
doing some sick ass job.
Just someone else we saw live
in la at the Wiltern. Yeah.
It's not the of it revolving this.
We did. They were great. Yes,
we did with like one of the gods,
the last performances with
them. Yes. So anyways, so uh,
he was doing, um, you know, he's
been doing the music for it.
So anyways,
he puts together a lot of benefits.
So he's putting together this benefit
thing for, uh, for some public schools.
Something. I didn't know what
it was, but he goes, hey,
you know all these guys are
going to be down here playing
nice opportunity for you to
plug the charity. Yeah, yeah.
Remember that's the thing too. I
never, that's another thing too.
You play all these charities and I'm
like, oh what was the charity for you? I,
yeah, no, but you do because
it's Richie cause you
hear is for charity and you'd do
it because you're a good person,
you have a good heart, but you damned
if you notice bad shit in my life,
I'm going to balance out my Karma.
So all I do is right before I go on stage,
I always look on my goal,
what is this for again?
And then they tell me what it's for and
then I just make sure I steer clear.
I don't go out there and make a reference
to that and then I just go out and do
the other 99% of my act.
You're like a pop star that doesn't know
what city she's in and see they what
Cleveland.
I don't know what disease it's for,
but I know it's a disease
and we want to stop it.
Isn't it enough that I showed up
for free? You? I can fucking shit.
The next thing you know,
you're gonna tell him this fall.
You don't know what charity it's right.
I never know.
Some of the funniest
things I've ever seen,
some of the funniest ones I've ever seen
is when commerce go on stage and they
don't know what the benefits for and
they're killing, killing, killing.
And then they start doing a bit
that it has to do, you know,
and then everyone gets all quiet like,
yeah,
they somehow make an autism reference
or cancer or they do something and then
the crowd totally pulls back.
And the greatest is when this
so early into their career,
they don't understand why.
And they're like, dude, what
the fuck she guys problem?
Jesus Christ.
What did
everybody, I'm an autistic baby here.
Like they don't even know what's going on.
And the whole crowd, the magic.
And then the person like,
like directing us in the
back, like cut off the mic,
cut up to Mike.
Right.
What's funny is when you get a
seasoned comic and they do it,
you see the look on their face
and there'll be like, oh fuck.
And then they'll literally ask, is
this a benefit for cancer? Sorry,
I didn't know a fucking sorry. I'm the
worst person ever. So anyways, Mike leg,
knees charity. Huh? Mike leg, knees.
We weren't Mike leg knees.
Are we talking about how you were Oh,
lag niece works at wild west. Oh,
sorry. Hey Mike, you got to shout out.
So anyways, so of course he goes, hey man,
all these fucking guys are going to be
there. Um, blah blah blah, blah, blah.
You know, he knows that I play drums
and then I'm amount then you know,
I'm a fucking nerd. I'm a nerd.
I'm a drum NERC, right? So he goes,
you want to come down and watch these
guys play? And I'm like, yeah, fuck yeah.
You know, I'm working in the comedy
store later. Let's, let's fucking do it.
So like two days before the event, he
texted me and he goes, uh, he goes, hey,
do what you want to sit in
and play a song. And of course
I want to, but I'm like,
I'm not going to be that fucking asshole
where it's just like you got all these
studio level and professional guys.
I'm not going to be the fucking guy.
Come in there, boom, boom,
boom. That fucking guy,
just embarrassing.
And them just fucking tolerating me.
It's like I'm not fucking doing that shit.
Um, so then he writes back, goes bad,
they don't give a fuck. They don't give
a shit company if you want to play,
go ahead and fucking play.
He goes,
but I'm not going to be that guy who
pressures you or whatever. So I say, fine.
So once again,
I'm driving around and it's like two
days before the thing and I was like,
Oh bill,
stop being such a fucking bitch.
Most of this is the reason
why you're saying no,
it's not out of respect for
the professional musicians
just because you'd be in
a fucking pussy right now. So I
said, so I texted him, right? I was,
I'm not gonna lie to you. I was scared.
I would have been scared too. So I said,
I said, I text him, I said,
fuck it, let's do it. So he
goes, he writes back, Oh shit,
right? And he goes, all right, learn
whole lot of love. See on Saturday,
and it's Thursday,
whole lot of love.
I've never been able to play
that fucking song. Right?
And the fucking bottom starts,
all the fills on like three goes over,
the bar comes back. I mean, I, I
can't, and I'm trying. So I start,
I go to the drum room and I'm
fucking woodshed in his shit, right?
And I cannot, he's got this and get,
get that ended up [inaudible] De de,
De, De, De, De, De, de, De, de.
But boom, boom, boom. Right?
And it's for aunt out one.
I could never fucking, I can't, I can't
fucking do it. I can't fucking do it.
So finally I got, I ripped off two of
his fills and I was like, all right,
I'm playing these two fills 60
fucking times during this song.
And I'm gonna hope nobody notices.
So fortunately,
like a day before the event,
uh,
cushion or text me and he goes, hey man,
we're just going to do highway to hell.
And I was like, thank God, that's so
much easier. It's slower to man for this.
It's more like the, I don't think
there's really any fills in it.
There's a couple of places where you stop
and then it starts again or whatever.
Okay. I'm really quickly in
Phil's is when the, it's like
that did, do, do, do, do, do,
do like talking about, okay.
Yeah. Got It. So, uh, so anyways,
so I fucking, you know, dust
off that fucking song. Right.
And,
uh,
that's a song I used to play with two
of my brothers back in the day when, uh,
I was in my parents' basement.
Right. And, uh, we still blessed,
one of the songs that we used to butcher
was highway to hell. So I'm like, oh,
that's Kinda cool.
We're going to fucking play this song.
So I show up to the event and um,
he's got all the like, you know,
it's like it's some fucking
tennis club or some shit.
It's like some real rich
people kind of thing. And uh,
and the kind of people
that need shanti, no, no.
They were doing it for public schools
and they weren't doing it for themselves.
American greed, they have charities
for themselves. So anyways,
so I show up and like,
like the band's playing and
everybody there is a fucking monster.
So as I'm meeting the people,
I'm then like trying to fucking
Google in this shit, you know?
And it was a, the people that was
Cushner Frankie Perez who sang in, uh,
he plays in this apocalyptic IA or
something like that. This, this,
Finland's psycho fucking string band.
Amazing voice sang in slashes ban.
I think it makes it one Finnish and
Swedish and like they're really into like,
they don't fuck around all day. Fucking
love that fucking death metal music.
[inaudible] I think it's called. They
don't fuck around. They're really, really,
they really embrace the idea,
I think of like death as a part of life.
And happens and just rock out to, and I
don't know, I'm this because they sit,
I'm like ma'am, 23 hours of darkness,
six months of the fucking year,
negative, you know, 20
degree weather. Yeah.
So then as a cold, dark hell
yeah, Christian, he's there.
The Bass player from a Jane's addiction
since 2002, he's fucking playing ankle.
Uh, and then the drummer, I
hope we say his name right Todd,
while watching, I got it
written down here. He, he,
he like does like blue man
group and all these Vegas.
She like big studio Guy Monster,
which was playing,
I was playing all this Keith
Moon Shit wasn't staying.
And then this other studio guy,
Andrew Wyatt and these guys are fucking
slaying it. Is that true though?
You know, we were saying the guy
that does, um, blue man group,
those kinds of musicians who do play
like a variety of different gigs at like,
they really can't play everything right.
And that's why they get hired all the
time because they're versatile and they
can just kind of, I think they think
there's like, you're the bad guy.
Or then you're like the studio guy.
When the studio guys like you don't know
who you're going to be playing with.
So you have to, you don't just
know your band's catalog is like,
these guys can play all these different
styles they have there. They're all,
whether you're in a band or whatever, you
get to that fucking level. You're obese.
So these guys, so I show up and these
guys, you know the fucking around,
then they start playing and I was
like, oh my God, Oh my God. Oh my God.
And then I start feeling like, you know,
and I was like, what did I say Yes to?
This could have just been hearing
the jewelry it, right. So anyways,
so then we go up, they go, hey
bill, you want to, you know, they,
they blow through all these fucking songs.
The whole lot of love.
The fuck in a won't get fooled again.
All of this shit fucking destroy it.
And then I go up,
this is just during the sound check and
there's like nobody there if this tennis
club right. And I keep thinking of
good fellas, you know, when he went,
he met the fuck he met Karen and you know,
and he gives him that
little fucking half ass,
that jerk off handshake foreshadowing that
he wasn't going to get along with. Um,
so anyways,
so I went up and we play
this fucking song and uh,
and it went good. It sounded good. And
they're like, man, that sounds all right.
They go, you want to play it again?
I was like, Nah, I'm cool. I'm cool.
And like high shelves at nine
come back then. So, you know,
I had heard that slash and duff,
we'll maybe going to be there, right?
But I didn't, you didn't know, you know,
whatever, whatever. So anyways,
long story fucking short, I, uh,
I come back at nine o'clock and now all
of a sudden there's a bunch of people
there,
so the nerves are even higher and now
these guys aren't doing sound check.
Now they're not fucking around.
Now they're doing the show.
And the show starts and it just
fucking raping, killing it,
fucking killing it.
And the songs that just whipping by.
And with each song that's going by,
like I see on the setlist,
they're going to do roadhouse blues
and I know that I'm next. So I'm like,
Oh fuck, I'm going to be next out.
Jesus Christ. Why did they say yes this?
I'm like Phil, right Phil, right to
four, just two, four. Don't fuck it up.
Just don't look up at anybody and just
plow through it and you'll be done. Right.
So,
um,
it finished roadhouse boot blues and then
I can sort of sneak up on to the band
stand there and uh,
you know,
Todd leaves and I sit down
behind the kit as I sit down,
everybody else in the band
just like walked off the stage,
except for Dave and Frankie, the
singer. And I'm sitting here like, dude,
what the fuck in Christian goes,
hey, we got a special guests,
we've got some special guests on this
one. He goes it towards like, oh,
it's already back day goes on drum.
We've got built,
burn it. It was the funniest, the funniest
clap error. Like everyone's just like,
wait, what? Why is it special?
I think my face turned red.
I want her to crawl under the stool.
It was like I got a better round of
applause what I was doing open mikes in
front of eight people and they would
just keep it going for this next guy,
Bill Byrd built bar. They
would, it was fucking,
and I'm thinking like, what the fuck's
going on here? And then he goes, yeah,
I got a couple other friends are
going to help us out on this one.
And then they just fucking
walked out of the crowd.
Slash slash and duff and hours.
Yeah, I'm getting like nervous telling
us right now and they can't fucking stage
it.
Duff's already really tall.
So now he looks like nine feet fucking
tall and he shakes my hand. I'm like, hey,
how's it going? And then there's
fucking slash oh my God, I can now,
and this is the best part.
Of course she didn't go to the,
so of course Joe and Frankie turnaround
and that just laughing at this stunned
look on my face and I have all of three
seconds I felt to take this in and then
slash just goes Diana.
No, I was like, oh my God,
play this fucking song
with my brothers in, in,
in the basement and slash or standard.
One by one brother stood in Duff's
where the other and then cushion I was,
and they're just in Frankie's looking
back at me laughing at me and um,
I didn't remember what had just fucking,
just put my head down and like,
what the fuck?
You know? I really wish you guys
could see bill's face right now.
Like his eyes are shining.
He has the biggest smile.
Like there's like a glow rating
from it. You like it. This was,
I can tell this is one of the top
experiences. It's over. It's over.
You have like pure joy on
your face. No. Awesome.
I'm done. That's it. I love it. No,
I can't talk. I cannot top that. I
don't give a fuck either. That's a no,
that's awesome. I'm happy for you. I
can, I'm so excited that, that, that,
that happened. I'm so, I can't even
believe I missed it, but that's okay.
Cause that was your moment and your
year memory. So, yeah. All good.
And there's video,
so it does,
we'll live forever.
So this sickest fucking part was
in the end when the bad cuts out,
I'm on the way Gaga. And
then he's got, you know,
Frankie and I'm going dad all the way.
And then there's the end where he goes,
Whoa, whoa. And then there's like this,
the symbol wash starts in this drama,
the guitars.
So I to give the cue,
so when the band cuts out and
I'm going with that all the way,
and then dolphin slash Cushner basically
velvet revolver turns around and looks
at me. Dude, I almost fell
off. I almost fell off the bat.
That's amazing. Yeah. I,
I will never be able to believe
that that fucking happened.
I can't fucking believe it.
And I fucking believe it. And,
and it's funny cause the
song is like three minutes
long and I, it's weird. Like,
I don't remember it.
I remember every fucking second of know.
So thank you to her and Frankie,
cause they basically set it up and uh,
that was, I sent a cushion
or a text, I said, dude,
23 years in this business, 47 years
on the point at, there's nothing,
nothing could fucking that. I've never
had a feeling like that ever, ever.
I mean I'd have to go back to make the
first time I ever did standup and I was
so fucking psyched that I did it.
But it was different. Yeah. This was,
it was different than,
you know.
No, you're playing in a band with like
your heroes like and like rock gods,
rock royalty. That was like
legit rock gods. So yeah,
that's an amazing thing. I
love, I believe I missed it.
You know how much I love slash God no,
but I fucked you over.
Cause cause I said cause,
cause yeah,
at one point said, hey, maybe you
could jam with slash in those guys.
And I was just like, fuck
yeah, I'd love to do that.
But then when I went to the sound check,
they weren't there and we,
I ran the song with the other guys.
So you were going, I'm feeling
kind of tired and I go and I said,
and I have to pack. And I said, yeah, I
don't think it's going to happen. I go,
I think I'm going on early.
And then they're going to
close it out. So, you know,
and I remember I said to
you, I'm like, are you sure?
Like it's not annoying that you're like,
not a nut.
I'm just going to be in and out of there.
It's fine. It's just for the charity.
It'll be cool. It'll be really quick.
I'll go do my other sad, I'll come home.
That's it. And uh, go ahead.
There you go. So that fucking happened
and uh, now it's incredible. Yeah.
Over, over. It's over.
It's done. Washed away.
Anything I've ever
fucking accomplished ever.
Can we also talk about how earlier today
that you said that you were basically
in velvet revolver, kitchen
plan, that moment? Three. Four.
So in that moment and that moment I was,
I took over for Matt,
so I'm in my head,
in my head and Frankie took over
lead vocals. I'm, I stand by this.
My ego is completely a check. Hey,
I got to do a, I got to do some, uh,
I got to do some advertising for
this week and uh, then we'll,
we'll play some classic stuff here.
All right. Uh, oh Ba everybody, uh,
hey. Hey. Hey. You like
making great money, right?
Here's a really cool opportunity
I had to share with you dry.
This always starts off like it's a
drug deal. Like, Hey, hey man. Hey,
you like making good money,
right? Come on down the alley.
You got a car and a driver's license
driving with Uber. How old are you?
Uber's that popular smartphone. You don't
fucking, Amazon sent me a fucking email.
Mia. What do you mean?
Say and they might click,
they're going to close my
account by October 31st if I,
cause I never filled out the thing
that said I wasn't interacting.
I wasn't trying to interact with
people 13 years of age or lower.
What on my website,
on my website,
like I do the Amazon link going to Amazon.
If you just click the link and you go
there, it doesn't cost you any money.
But Amazon kicks me a little bit of money,
uh,
for driving traffic to their site and
I take 10% of that and I throw it to a
wounded warriors, wounded
warriors. Anybody.
Cause somebody told me that that was
a little sketchy. Is that sketchy?
I have no idea.
I don't know how to figure it out,
but I found that saint Jude's is good.
Yeah.
Well I don't think we just
signed it with light warriors.
Wounded warriors is sketchy. I don't
know if that, but I, I find like,
I feel like we shouldn't say that.
I feel like won't be boys.
I want to walk up to the wounded guys
and give them the money directly cause I
just feel like both the, do you want me
to give him an envelope and the mafia?
Why not?
Sure if you're going to locate all the
wounded warriors and then personal,
but I figured like whatever,
I'm going to give these organizations,
whatever I give helps one guy.
Why don't I just, well one woman,
why don't I just walk up to that one
person so there's no infrastructure and
I'll pay it.
I'll pay the gas money.
How do you propose that's going to work
now I've got a podcast. I just said it.
Okay, so everyone,
everyone sending emails,
he in like and claimed civilian job
and then I'll have like a little,
like one of those games shelter if
everybody's name in it and I'll flick up
Craig house like a Bingo, pull
it out. And the winner is,
yeah, but they can, all the fucking
money I'm giving goes to you,
but they can't prove that they're
wounded by interacting with them on the
Internet. That's why you have wounded
warriors and organizations like that.
Like cause how are you going to know?
Are you going to like do a home visit
and then look around and be like, hmm.
All right.
And then what about your checkbook?
You know, you'd really just took all the
sunshine out of that, didn't you? Sorry.
Anyways, um, so Amazon goes,
you never filled out something that
basically said that your website is not
interacting with people
under like 13 years of,
I don't know if they listen to the
podcast and it was fucking like me saying
content, all this stuff. And they're
like, what about children? Um,
oh, so people who don't like cursing, I
don't know what it is. So now I get it.
Not like Amazon. They made
me feel all creepy. Well,
why don't you just say that you're not
interacting with 13 year olds? Well,
why don't they fucking ask me from the
beginning and then not fucking come at me
later? Like he never said that. It's
like, dude, you never fucking asked me.
What do you mean? I thought you
said they did ask. You know,
they just send me a random email out
of nowhere going, you never said this.
It's like, dude, you never fucking
ask me. Well did you answer it?
No,
I have until the 31st
fuck you.
I'm talking about them
not asking the question.
And then coming at me like I'm some sort
of fucking Weirdo. You're ticking it.
Oops. It isn't personally. You don't have
somebody on the Internet go, are you?
Are you? Are you not interacting
with 13 aimed at 13 year olds?
Yes. Fucking weird, funky way.
Amazon fucking jerk offs. Sorry.
Oh, what are they going to do? Don't,
yeah. What are they going to do?
I don't know the webs.
What are they going to do?
Not Send me boxes of shit that
I don't need. Fucking assholes.
You want to send your packages by drones?
Huh?
Did they really? Yeah. A bunch of toilet
covers flying fish your fucking house
so they could save money so you don't
have to have some guide drive it.
You know what? Fuck Amazon and fuck the
fucking link. All right, Uber, everybody.
You are never going to have another
advertiser that's Modsy you again.
You realize that right? I don't do
it because of their, that's true.
He do it for the fans, man. Fun.
If you're dumb enough to fucking advertise
on my podcast just with my reading
skills alone, I've already compared the
Uber App to like fucking drug dealers.
I don't give a shit here. I don't
give a shit. I live within my means.
I'm wearing tennis shorts and
then suck it. You're such a rally.
I drive an eight year old rebel bill.
I drive an eight year old tennis
stories on the island of Nantucket.
Stop telling these maniacs. Where
am sorry. It's one of the rules.
You never tell them that you
just, you leave. I'm like,
why is he wearing tennis shorts?
Why would he be doing that?
This guy is even weirder than I thought.
I have to keep listening. Once you go, oh,
he's on fucking didn't Tuck it in and
they go, oh, now it all makes sense.
Now they're not listening and Uber
loses money. All right. Hey guys,
you like making great money,
right?
Here's a really cool
opportunity I evidently had
to share with you driving with
Uber.
Uber's that populace smartphone APP
that connects riders with drivers.
I take Uber a bunch.
Did you know that Nia?
I love them by the way. Oh boy. Oh boy.
Nothing I like better.
And then getting into a
complete stranger's car that
isn't regulated by any sort
of government fucking entity.
Hey Buddy, how are you?
Let's roll the dice again.
Some of them have really interesting
stories as to why they drive with Uber.
Fucking broke,
man,
I don't make enough money at my other
job. Jesus Christ. Is that interesting?
They love being their own boss.
Don't they work for Uber?
They earn great money while
their cars are halfway decent.
They must be invested in, in
real estate. It's easy to start.
This happened because your here,
you just need a car and a license.
Exactly. No other background
check is there. Driving
with Uber got off on a murderer, a
technicality. Hey, welcome to Uber.
Driving with Uber is great for
anyone who needs flexibility.
Parents, this is a really easy way to work
around your family schedule. Students,
you can make some extra money between
classes. Doesn't that sound filthy?
Now's the prime time to catch
in with driving with Uber.
You'll thank me for telling
you how to get paid every week.
I could be getting into your car when
you drive with Uber. Call to action.
You got a car and a license. Put
them both to work for you, uh,
for you and start earning serious
life changing money today.
Sign up to drive with Uber.
Visit drive with uber.com.
That's drive with U B E r.com.
Drive with uber.com.
All right, blue apron. Uh,
it's okay. You can admit it.
I don't like it. They put you
on the defensive. It's okay.
You can admit it.
What are we talking about here?
The last thing anyone wants to do after
work is wait in line at the grocery
store, Schlep home and cook a complicated
meal. I can admit that. Okay, well,
evidently it's okay with
blue apron and expensive,
unhealthy takeoff takeout
is hardly better. Uh,
that's where this new service,
blue apron comes in.
Blue Apron delivers farm fresh ingredients
and step by step recipes to your home,
allowing you to create healthy,
handcrafted meals at home without going
to the grocery store for less than $10
per meal. Blue Apron sends
you fresh ingredients,
perfectly proportioned, making,
cooking healthy fund meals,
really easy and fun.
No trips to the grocery store and
no waste from unused ingredients.
Plus you learn to cook with
special specialty ingredients
that are normally hard
to find.
Blue Apron is the is perfect for date
night cooking with friends and they even
and even other family plans with kid
friendly ingredients so the whole family
can eat well and have fun
preparing the meals together.
Each balanced meal is 500 to 700
calories per serving and so tasty.
You'd never know.
Cooking takes half an hour.
Shipping is flexible and free and the
menus are always knew they won't send the
same meal twice.
They work around your schedule and dietary
preferences and blue apron experts.
Boyfriends,
experts source out only the best seasonal
ingredients for incredible meals like
vegetarian Gnocchi with Mei, Mei, tocky,
Maytag, MIT, aqe may take in corn.
How do you say that? I don't know. Well
then exhale and you know what's going on.
No,
I'm just saying you and barbecued.
Roast pork with corn on the cob,
potato salad and quick pickles.
The fuck are those must be a little
ones, aren't you? A quick little fucker.
You'll cook incredible meals and be blown
away by the quality and the freshness.
Blue Apron.
It's a better way to cook.
Check out this week's menu and get your
first two meals for free by going to
blue apron.com/burr my tree.
Really the first two meals are on me
when you go to blue apron.com/burr oh he
got one here.
Next issue.
Your time is precious and you want to
feed your mind with the best of what's out
there, but who has the time
to sift and Wallace Shit,
all the nonsense on the Internet,
but those who us who want premium content
and don't have time to waste waste
finding it. There's next
issue, issue, issue, issue.
The next issue was the mobile APP.
They'll let you tap directly into the
world's most popular magazines anytime,
anywhere using your smartphone or tablet.
They've got all your favorites like sports
illustrated, maximum and fucking ass
and next issue lets you dive deeper into
the stories with interactive content
not available anywhere else.
What is that Ford Pass about giving
you a richer reading experience?
Dude, sports illustrated
maximum at Esquire. That's just,
yeah, that's airport shit.
Uh, the best part, next issue is
offering a free trial right now.
When you go to the next
issue.com/birth sign up for next issue.
Right now you'll get immediate access
to all of the top these top magazines,
including back issues and
exclusive videos and photos. Again,
you can try next issue for free.
Right now when you go to
next issue.com/burr that's
actually really smart
because less people are buying
magazine these days. Yep.
So if you can put them all together,
God dammit.
All it takes is one
brilliant idea like that.
Companies like that and blue apron I
have of those the first time I really
listened to that. Advertising all it
all it takes is one brilliant idea.
Everybody as opposed to the run of the
mill shit that I think of every day.
Well you think of like 50 things and one
of them will be brilliant, hopefully.
Hopefully. All right, well that's
the podcast. The Thursday afternoon,
just before Monday, just checking in on
your podcast. I hope you had a good time,
uh, listening this week. I hope you
have a wonderful weekend and I will,
uh, talk to you again on Monday.
Here's a wonderful throwback episode,
um, from, uh, some
Monday, a long time ago.
Turn to stone
[inaudible].
Now if you're new to my
podcast last week I was saying,
how come miles per gallon
on gas, uh, on cars, sorry,
as Ben has basically been
the same since the 70s.
So people were trying to suggest to me
that cars weighed more back in the 70s.
And I said, get the fuck Outta here.
Those God damn led back in the day.
They had metal
bumpers and full size spares. Get the fuck
Outta here. I remember when we had, uh,
we had like a 72 or 73 Buick
regal to door and it took two,
me and one of my brothers,
all of our might to open that fucking
car doors like opened up, God damn
like a bank vault.
But two things I forgot to do.
One actually look up the stats and to
realize that I was like fucking six years
old when I was trying to open it.
You know,
you ever think that shit
when you think it doesn't,
it doesn't really snow as much as it
used to, which it probably doesn't.
But as far as like the storm spent by you
like dude back in the day was up to my
waist. Yeah. And you were
about three feet tall.
That's why.
That's why,
that's why it seems so
fucking deep because you could
barely look over a coffee
table. Um, anyway, so I'll
give you guys that one.
I'll give you guys that one.
Okay.
And I would actually love to be wrong on
this one, but I just don't think I am.
Even though I was wrong that the cars
weighed more in the 70s so people show me
a bunch of stats cause God knows I'm
not going to look at them all right.
And people,
by the way,
who actually said that I really
sounded like a moron last week.
I May I invite you to listen to the
first four years of this podcast and just
see the reoccurring theme that that is
okay. I don't read it makes me sleepy.
I stated that before. I don't fucking
read. All right? I go with my gut.
Okay, I'll tell you this right now.
I don't know how to fill a tooth,
but I can go in and look at
a dentist and real and I can,
I can fucking judge that guy.
Whether or not he's gonna he's,
he's telling me the truth.
Does that make any sense?
Of course it doesn't go fuck yourself.
I've got a God damn hour to fill here.
This is what,
this is the problem I have,
I have with people who are defending
the oil companies here is basically when
you go back to the 70s okay?
And you prove to me that cars
did they weigh more now? Okay,
so you're right on that one.
Okay.
But your logic though is still based in
that the oil companies were telling the
truth in 1976 that whatever 35 miles per
gallon was the best that we could do.
So you use that as a jump off point to
then prove your point now that that's why
cars get the gas mileage that, that, that,
that they get today is basically,
I have to make the leap with you that
oil companies are telling the truth,
that there's $350 billion
industry. Okay. That,
that is
on numerous occasions,
openly got in the way of any
sort of progress. I remember
here out in California,
I think it was the late nineties.
Yeah,
it might've been 20 years ago.
I can't remember what it was before I
moved out here the first time or right
after I left.
Did the air quality out here.
So fucking horrific.
It's like,
I know a lot of people still
think it's real smoggy out here.
It definitely gets smog,
but it usually just in the summertime,
and it's definitely Oh, hazy out
here, but Hays is not fucking smog.
Smog is Brown.
You go hiking and you feel a burning
in your fucking chest back in the day,
in the late nineties. Okay. You
could see this shit. So anyway,
so they put this,
uh,
they put it to the vote for a people to
the people who actually would vote on
this shit.
And they passed this bill
that said by the year 2000,
whatever,
25% or 30% of cars had to
run on something other than,
you know, the gas oil get basically
the gas combustion engine.
They basically paved the way for the
big three to then basically start making
electric cars.
The fucking thing passed.
An oil companies got together with their
lobbyists and they went and they just
totally dismantled the whole thing
and the whole thing fucking went away.
Okay. Which for all you people out there
who are going to explain capitalism,
capitalism to me, I get it. That
is their prerogative to do that.
Why wouldn't they get in the way of that?
So let me ask you this.
You're telling me that they
would get in the way of that,
but they wouldn't get in the way of
any sort of progress just with the gas
combustion engine. They wouldn't get in
a way, have any of that type of progress.
They seem to not get in the
way of anything else. Safety,
they don't give a shit about. They won't
get in the way of that type of stuff.
Burning it cleaner. They don't give
a fuck about but miles per gallon,
which is their bottom line. Like do
you guys honestly think like today,
like what your car gets like that's
honestly the best that science can do that
is we are right up against the fucking
wall. Is that what you're telling me?
You know, considering if they
just even increased it by five,
10 miles a gallon per every new car,
that they would immediately lose
hundreds of millions of dollars.
Why would they do it? Why would they
do? Why would they allow that to happen?
Why wouldn't they get in the way of that?
That's all I'm asking here.
And you know something for all
you fucking assholes out there.
Who called me this? Whack job. Conspiracy
theorists. These are my conspiracies.
Okay.
Bankers are fucking evil.
Yeah.
Well,
companies lie to you.
Yeah.
And insurance companies are pieces
of shit. That's basically my three.
And then they have enough money
to basically buy elections.
That's basically yet,
okay. Those really aren't
groundbreaking conspiracies, are they?
I'm not saying that there's some
guy living in the fucking moon.
I'm not saying I saw a fucking flying
saucer come out of the god Damn Ocean.
Had fucking take a piss on somebody
sunbae then, and then, you know, I,
I saw Ronald Reagan waving out the
side of it and then it took off.
I'm not saying that shit, I
just, I don't buy it. Okay.
And I actually got emails from
people. Um, they sent me these,
these, these links. They
sent me this link of this,
this fucking kid,
14 year old kid with one of his classmates
built this futuristic looking Jetsons
car and they got close to 2000
miles per gallon. I'll, I'll,
I'll send you the link to this.
You can go on the [inaudible]
podcast and look at this thing. Mm.
The MM podcast.com look at the
picture of this thing. Okay.
And once you're done saying,
well, it's not a practical car.
It's not as heavy as the other ones.
It would never meet the safety
standards and Yada, Yada, Yada,
all that fucking shit.
Do you honestly think that airbags,
navigation systems,
crumple zones and all that?
You're honestly going to tell me that
that basically knocks off 1900 miles per
gallon.
Are you really going to fucking sit
there and tell me that you honestly think
that they're not?
Why wouldn't they get in the way of it?
They have the money to get in the way,
in the way of it. And not only that,
they're not even part of this
country in a way. They're borderless.
They're, they're worldwide.
I don't, I don't know.
So I did, I respectfully
apologize for not fucking, uh,
looking up the weight of the car.
I was 100% wrong in that,
but I still do not think that I'm
wrong or I'm fucking paranoid.
I had one guy, this guy's fucking
hilarious. This guy was just ripping me,
just saying, this is classic old
man. It's like, dude, I'm 43.
Jesus Christ. This guy's going old
man. Like I'm afraid of the world.
Yeah.
I'm afraid of the fucking world I have.
I at least can sit here and tell you that
I don't believe in all that religious
horse shit. Well, if I
was a scared old man,
when I be going to church every God
damn week when I'd be doing that stuff,
believing in the immaculate conception,
I think you go on the ground people,
I you don't want it.
That's, that's my theory.
I think when you died you go in the ground
and then you become a fossil fuel for
more people to fucking fight in,
in, in, in a lie about the, the,
do you know, you know what? I might,
my actually my Prius and I've
actually thought about doing this.
There's people granted it
fucks over your warrant, your,
your warranty on your car.
They can actually get a hundred miles per
gallon but bay and basically what they
do is they just, uh, they just fill
the ass end with a bunch of batteries,
you know?
Okay.
Which I'm sure those are
great for the environment.
Oh, you know what it is? People, I think
you know what a cup is down to the most.
Why is my fucking throat so dry?
Hang on a second.
Okay.
I think it comes down to the
amount of what we do. We're fucked.
But I just think that there's certain
entities that just have too much fucking
power.
I think when you start making $350
billion a year and you're nationwide,
at some point, some sort of government
should have some sort of power over you.
And I don't really think
that are ours does. I don't,
I don't think that they have any fucking
pilot. Well, what are they going to do?
They got us by the balls.
The second you start giving them shit,
they put their hand on the, on the nozzle,
the spicket go ahead. Keep talking.
We're going to, we'll shut
this fucking thing off. Huh?
You want to pay $9,000 for a cantaloupe
that shut your face for 25 a gallon?
Go Fuck Yourself. Next question.
Yes. This is our Marnie. MMM.
[inaudible]. Alright, plowing ahead here.
I really want you guys to look at this.
Okay?
You guys who actually fucking do research?
Um,
like here's one guy
tells me the 1987 Honda,
CRX got 57 miles on the highway.
Wait was 1800 pounds.
The 2011 CRX miles per gallon is 41 on
the highway and it weighs 2,600 pounds.
So I, I see, I see. They're
fucking argument. So right
there it's like, all right,
well the car was fucking 800 more pounds,
which is a lot when the first
one only wait 1800 you almost,
you're talking about, was
that 40% boys? 40% more?
Is it getting 40% less
on the gas? No, it isn't.
So that's actually a fucking improvement.
I will give you that.
But the jump off point, I'm not
buying it. I'm not buying that.
We can only get 50,
25 miles a gallon in 1975 I don't buy it.
I bet they easily could've got 200 at
that point. They're not going to do it,
dude. You talking about the
blue bloods at that point?
You're talking about that level
of fucking power. All right.
My apologies to everybody out there
were actually has some sort of science
background. Evidently people told
me that that Stan Stanley Mayer,
the water power car is
junk science and it's,
it's absolutely ridiculous as some would
even suggest that they could do that.
Uh, so I lost on that one. So this,
so you'd, so you guys, you guys one,
two thirds of the argument here with me.
All right.
So now that you've backed
me into the corner,
I want you to explain to me
why oil companies wouldn't
stand in the way of that
technology and w and to fold and why
you believe that what they tell you that
cars get is the best that we can do.
Why you believe that we can't
get 60 miles per gallon.
Okay,
well, you know there's
dairy steers, air bag and,
and other things and
satellites flying around this.
Here comes Santa Claus come samples
put me on the ground.
Oh,
bigger.
Now they cut the lights
down. Skin. Walmart.
All right,
here's one for you.
We're going to bring back a topic despite
the fact that I dropped this topic
because people told me that Daniel Tosh
does something like this on tosh 0.0 uh,
this person actually asked a great, this
is, I'm bringing back, is it racist,
racist, racist. I'm bringing this
topic back. By the way, I worked,
I worked with Daniel
Tosh, uh, on Wednesday,
this past week down at the
Wiltern theater for the, uh,
the Greg Giraldo benefit and um,
Jesus Christ,
that guy's a fucking beast.
Absolutely fucking hilarious.
Uh,
he might've had the set of the night
and then everybody down there was a,
was a headliner in their own right. And
I want to thank everybody who came down,
but Daniel Tosh was fucking hilarious.
Um,
I know you guys think that I say some mean
shit and I'm able to get away with it.
You got to see that guy, man. It's, it's,
it's every time I see him and he
always has like new jokes and shit.
You definitely be get a chance.
Definitely check that guy out. And a,
and with that, I evidently I'm going
to do one of the bits from his show.
Is it racist? All right bill. I love
the podcast consistently hilarious.
Turn on some friends and brothers tour it.
I really appreciate that.
Anybody who listens to this, please
tell your friends about it. Um, anyways,
here's my, is it racist thing?
And elderly white neighbor,
a neighbor lady came over and asked my
wife if she wanted this leftover rice,
obviously from takeout and she said,
maybe you can use it to make
some fried rice or something.
My wife who is Korean,
oh Jesus was cordial,
but later set a kind of pissed her off.
Here's the kicker.
She did end up making fried rice
out of it. Is it, is this racist?
Uh, thanks. Um, Oh man,
this is one of these ones that it,
it,
it's not racist.
It's
okay.
It walks the line of unnecessary.
Slash.
Offensive.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
It's, you know, she answered the question
by actually turning it into fried rice.
And I gotta be honest with you,
I've never understood the food thing,
why the food thing is racist.
I could see if you saved people a dumb,
you know,
all those classic clan things would they
say certain people aren't fucking human,
the, you know, fucking your
part, whatever like that.
But the food thing I never
got, I never understood it. Um,
okay.
I don't get why if you say what
I think is, it's always just,
just the way you say it.
I look at French people are
called frogs cause eat frog legs.
The Germans will call the
Krauts Sauerkraut, right?
There's always like something about
food that people flip out about you.
I gotta tell you it's really fucking
weird to have extra rice and just be like,
you know what, I the Korean lady
cross the street with like it.
I think that might be an example
of a white person trying to be,
I'm assuming the person's
white trying to be like, uh,
they think they don't want a good
thing. Like, oh, we have extra rice.
Let's give it what it,
what about the Korean lady?
Let's show that we know something about
her culture. So I just think it's,
uh, it's really bizarre. Um,
but I don't think that they at for it
to be racist, like I always said it,
it has to be like your intent.
Like if they did it because they
were trying to be like, here you go,
your receipt and son of a
bitch, then yeah, that that is a
okay
then it would be racist. But if they're
just doing the classic, you know,
white person just not knowing,
you know what I mean?
Like we have the reputation for doing
shit like that. Like we're trying,
but we just don't know. And then the
great thing is how other races act.
Like they know everything about
white people, which they don't,
despite how many episodes of family
ties, you know, like I actually saw it,
there was this website, uh, there
was something, I look it up,
it's called what white people do
and I believe it was written by, uh,
some black girl and she was basically
making fun of white people. But if you,
if you look at it, she's really
making fun of hipsters in Brooklyn.
She's making fun of the white
people around her and she's,
she's basically lumping all white
people. Like, this is what they do.
That is what they do. They're really
into taking a, what did she say?
What the fuck was it?
Uh,
taking time off to find themselves
or some shit like that. And, uh,
you know, I dunno, my
friends, we grew up, yeah,
we didn't take time off to find
ourselves. We were, uh, you know,
we were,
drunks
took time off.
We didn't take time off to find ourselves.
We flunked out of college. That's what
we did. That was our, or we fucked up.
We found ourselves in high school by
doing so bad in high school that we didn't
go to college, you know? Um, anyways,
I ain't, what the fuck I'm doing? Hey,
let's plow ahead. So I wouldn't say it
was racist. I think it's, it's just,
it's ignorant.
That would just be ignorant.
They think that they're
doing this great thing.
Okay.
You know, and their defense would probably
be something equally as ignorant. Like,
well, what, they eat it
all the time. Um, so yeah,
I wouldn't say that it's racist, but
yeah, people listened to the podcast.
It's probably not a good thing,
even if you're respecting the fact that
there's people starving around the world.
Um,
okay.
You know, I could see if you're always
bring over extra food now, you know,
something that what's fucked up. What
could we do? You guys can't afford rice.
The more I'm looking at this,
okay,
who the fuck would do that?
And you're gonna eat my leftover rice.
Like what do we fucking animals over here?
Okay.
But the thing is,
she did it.
You know what I dunno. I Dunno.
That could go either way.
I think that was one of those ones.
I'd have to be there.
I'd have to know a little about,
little bit about that.
The lady across the street and, and I,
I'd have to hear, I was, she said it,
but I would've given anything to
listen to your wife going like,
you believe those sons of bitches coming
over here, give me this goddamn rice,
you know, as she's taking out
the fucking, uh, what, how, how,
whatever the fuck you make
the fried rice then hold on.
Did you laugh when she actually cooked?
Yeah.
Hold on.
Yay.