Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast. And Ah,
just checking in on you.
Sorry,
I'm losing my voice is always
as I continue my way through.
Um,
the first leg of the tour is over.
I did Dublin, Belfast and
Galway, Ireland and um,
I could not have had a better time,
uh, caught a little bit of a cold,
but you know, that's what happens
when you go out. You know,
you have a couple of pops or whatever
and you didn't dress properly cause you
thought, you know, August and July over
here was going to be fucking warming shit.
Like it is where I live. It isn't
rains a lot. It's kind of cold.
And uh, I was running down so I got a
little bit of a cold, but I'm all right.
But um,
I don't think I had done Belfast.
MMM.
By Monday. I don't think I did. And
maybe I was just going up there.
I can't remember. But I got to tell you
about Belfast fucking amazing, right?
MMM.
I go up there and I was playing,
I wasn't aware of it.
The place I was playing was Ulster Hall,
which is a,
that's the first place of led Zeppelin
played it and that's the first place they
ever played stairway to heaven live.
So I was like,
you gotta be fucking kidding me.
So of course I googled that and then
some bootleg audio of it and uh,
the band actually said the
song didn't go over that well.
Sounded like they liked it enough,
although the person recording it was
kind of talking during some of it and I
found some pictures from when they
did the Gig there and there he is,
John Bonham sitting right
on the fucking stage.
MMM.
And then of course they had to look up
ACDC and 1979 they played there with Bond
Scott. And a lot of these places
you play by the time, you know,
I come around to them,
it's 40 30,
40 years after these people
that I love played them.
So they usually redid the place and
it doesn't look the same. All Hall,
they had not ridden the stage.
So I literally,
when I walked up on the stage,
got the fucking chills.
MMM.
Couldn't believe it.
So.
MMM.
I don't know.
The only way to describe the people
in Belfast as you have to go there,
even if you didn't even know any of the
history, like the second you get there,
you're there for about three to four
seconds before you like, you know what,
I'm not fucking with anybody up here.
Um, the guy, I swear to God,
the guy who was running Ulster Hall,
one of them was like really nice,
but there's, you know, just regular,
hey, you're doing really cool guy.
But the other guy was also a cool guy,
but I cannot describe his vibe other
than to say if he was in a movie,
he would instantly like a
legend. Like I, I can't,
I don't think I, it's been a
long time since I met somebody.
I can't explain the guys vibe,
but I just knew that, um,
once again, the second I met him, I was
like, this guy has seen a bunch of shit.
This guy's not to be fucked
with. And, um, it was,
I dunno, it was just a
really, really, uh, you know,
anytime you go to a new city,
it's so cool just to see all this new
stuff and when you go there and it's,
that's such a fucking unique vibe. I
never felt like a vibe and that, uh,
in my life. And then I get to
play this legendary place and uh,
do the guy running the place,
I swear to God he should have
been like in one of those fucking,
one of those great guy movies,
one of those gangster movies,
he just had that vibe like, oh,
this is the guy, this is the guy.
If I pissed this guy off,
I'm going to get fucking whacked.
That was literally the Vibe,
right?
So I go on stage and I'm up there and
my shit for the most part is working.
And at one point I'm doing
some stupid bit and I,
and I'm using like American
sports references and it's
like the second night in
a row, they're not fucking working. So I
finally just say to the crowd, I just go,
all right. All right. And I go, obviously
this is an American sports, you know,
references, you guys don't know what I'm
talking about or you don't give a fuck.
I go, who? So you know, I was trying
to talk about a great player. So I go,
so who's your best football slash soccer
player? You know, who's like, you know,
the greatest of all time. And
this guy in the crowd said, uh,
we'll Griggs. And I was like, who
will Greg? And they're like, no,
we'll Briggs. I go by will Greg's.
And then they all cheered, right?
And I was like, all right,
now I've got the right guy.
So I continued doing my bits and anytime
I need a sports big, I'm throwing out,
we'll Griggs.
Right?
And then there was something about the
way they were laughing and the fact that
I got picked on so much as a kid that it
started to feel familiar and I started
thinking in my head like, wait a minute,
I, they fucking with me right now.
So of course after like
a fucking half hour,
I'm making a complete asshole on myself.
Keep using.
We'll Greg's his fucking name,
like he's the second coming of Palae.
I finally look at the crowd and I go,
wait a minute, are you guys just
fucking with me? It's this guy,
a really good player or are you guys
just making me look like a fucking, uh,
is he just a piece of shit and you
think it's funny to say his name,
not a piece of shit.
Just a journeymen guy.
And they all laughed and
applauded that I figured it out.
And when I loved is after they did that,
I was like,
these motherfuckers got me again.
They like the best hecklers or this is
what killed me is after I figured out
that they just sat there and were content,
totally content to sit there and watch
me not figure it out or figure it out,
make an ass of myself or
eventually redeem myself.
Either way it was going to
be entertaining to them.
I really looked at the crowd and
it was people of all fucking ages.
I'm telling you the Irish sense of humor,
man,
it's every time I fucking go over there.
I told you in the last time
I went over there, I try,
I'm just going like, oh yeah,
you know, I didn't come from a touchy
feely family. My parents, you know,
my mother wasn't a big hugger and never
really hugged me, blah, blah, blah.
I was working to something else.
It wasn't the point.
I couldn't even get past that.
The whole crowd just goes, aw,
I know these are old stories,
but I've got to give you a refresher
just so you understand what happens to me
every time I go over there.
And then also I remember I was giving
out free autograph DVDs because I wanted
them to play him for their friends.
So hopefully I would draw more people in.
I'm literally at the end of my act.
Thank you so much for coming out. Uh,
I brought some DVDs, I
autographed them, they're free,
please just take one, blah, blah.
And I'm in the middle of just saying,
I'm giving you a free fucking DVD that I
loved over there from the other side of
the world. I'm in the middle of
it. And this guy in the back,
I just hear this guy go,
oh fuck off.
It just, I dunno, they're fucking great.
So anyway, so I figured that one out.
So the next day I drive out to Galway.
When you drive across the country,
which takes like three and a half hours
to go from the east coast to the west
coast, we go out there, some of the most
beautiful land I've ever seen in my life.
They got these fucking stone walls,
dry stone wall,
nothing holding them together other than
the fucking brains of the person that
figure out how to place each rock.
Absolutely backbreaking work that
some of the walls are like three,
400 years old. And, um,
the driver's telling me all these
great stories and all this shit.
So I get out to Galway and um,
I get it in my head
because I have a fucking,
I had caught a cold at that point that
I wanted to buy one of those Irish old
man sweaters. Um, and Aran Sweater,
a r a n or something like that.
They kept saying,
it sounded like they were
saying iron. Like I r, O,
n or they just call them jumpers.
Say there's,
well you won't get a jumper or some shit.
I thought that meant like a fucking
Ranko and like no one of those knitted
fucking,
you know,
I'm an Irish guy and I want to
have a fucking drink of some shit.
Sit next to a boat. They're like,
yeah, jumper. So I go, all right.
So I get in my head that I want to buy
one of these fucking things and um,
it's all like,
all right,
I'll do it the next morning before I
go back to Dublin and then head over to
England.
So I go down to do a,
my gig in a side of them.
I came up with the name of the fucking
venue and we will ride over and they just
kept going, hey, just to
let you know, you know,
this isn't the most fanciest venue
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And all I'm thinking of like,
there's no way this venue is worse than
some of the shit holes I played on the
way up. You know what I mean?
Or some of the fucking places,
the comedy condos. I stayed in and
I showed up and the place was great,
tremendous theater. They were more
talking about the dressing room,
cause it dressing room was
basically the men's room.
But even that was fine. They put
some carpet down. It wasn't bad.
So I'm waiting to go on and,
uh,
the act, who's is it up for me? She's
hilarious. What the fuck was her name?
I already forget. Oh God damn
it. It was an Italian name too.
She was hilarious. I'm
the worst. My apologies.
Um,
it was typical road,
like we've talked to each other for
like 20 minutes and then, I dunno,
not see each other again for
like five years. So anyways,
she says to me, uh, she
started telling me this story
right before I go on stage as to how like,
you know, back in the day, you know, if
you weren't married and you are a woman,
the fuck was her name. Adriana.
I have no worst. Anyways,
she starts telling me
that back in the day. Um,
you know,
if a,
if a woman got pregnant and she wasn't
married to save the embarrassment,
they'd send them to this fucking place
out there near Galway to basically have
the baby.
Then the church would take the baby,
the woman would go back to the family
and there'd be no embarrassment and then
the baby would then they'd make money
off the baby by fucking given it to some
rich white people in America who
wanted to adopt a white baby. Right.
And, but what happened was
to stay had a ton of babies,
cause evidently everybody over there,
I was doing a lot of fucking,
and they weren't using
any sheepskin right.
They didn't use that jumper and wrap it
around their fucking dick or maybe they
didn't the same and got through.
I have no idea. So anyways,
they had a ton of fucking
babies and toddlers and some
of them were getting sick
and it was kind of a big secret thing.
Everybody kind of knew,
but nobody said Shit. So I have
a deadly. When the babies died,
they just fucking put them in like this.
The comedian told me it was
like a fucking, not an oil drum,
like a what have you got?
A what do,
what do you call a big fucking thing
that holds oil and it's underground big
tank or some shit. Long story
short, one time when their,
whatever they went to dig it up,
whatever they put them in,
they found a mass grave of
800 dead babies and toddlers.
She tells me this fucking story, right?
It's right before I'm going to go on.
And then she laughed. She goes,
have a great set. Right? Um,
so of course that became the reference.
The entire show was the dead babies
that were out there because um,
Tom Rhodes told me that if he
could live anywhere in the world,
Galway is where he wants to fucking be.
That's where he would stay. And that guy,
he's been literally around the world.
So I'm going out there going, oh,
this is going to be the most quaint
fucking Irish fishing village ever.
And it was right before I go on stage.
Of course I got to hear about
800 dead fucking babies. Right?
So here's the,
of course,
anybody else who did that would be
world famous for being the fucking worst
person ever. Right. Would make
Hitler look like a Jay Walker,
you know? And, but of course
it was the Catholic church,
so there was really barely a fucking
investigation. Nobody got in trouble,
nobody went to fucking jail. Um, so that's
what I learned when I was out there.
And I also that there's a bear
out there called a Galway hooker.
And I went out there and I proceeded to
get so fucking hammered that the only
picture I took of Galway was
the fucking tap that you pulled.
It says Galway hooker. And I had to
kind of try and remember what it was.
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking bill,
you said you weren't going to drink a
lot on this tour. Well, I caught a cold,
so you know, you supposed to drink a lot
of liquids and flush in audience. So,
um,
anyway,
so the next day I wake up and um,
I dunno,
it was kind of freaking out about having
to drive all the way back to Dublin.
And then also having to go through customs
to fuck and then get into England and
show my fucking papers
and all of that shit.
Then I woke up and uh, I
just realized, I was like,
I don't have time to buy that fucking
sweater. It's an impulse fucking by,
I'll get one the next time I go there
and I'm probably just want to buy it,
you know,
because I'm in Ireland and I'm drinking
their beer and I'm getting all caught up
in it.
It's like he'd go to the Netherlands
and all of a sudden you buy some fucking
wooden shoes. What do you, what the
fuck are you going to do with them?
What do I need a fucking Irish knit
sweater for? I live in a Goddamn desert,
right? Although it does get
cold at night. All right,
and is the fucking worst thing,
do you know?
I haven't been able to stop thinking about
it and I'm like, you fucking asshole.
So now I'm going on their website.
I can't try it on.
I can't see which sweater I look like
the least amount of a Douche bag in.
And then there's selection isn't as good.
And I can't tell the story that I got
an in Galway Ireland when, you know,
cause if you have one of those sweaters
and you wear 'em out in fucking La,
you just going to look like
some fucking act to reduce,
trying to dress his type to get a part
in the next time they do the movie
departed. If I could actually
be like, no, you hipster cunt.
I actually bought that in Galway,
Ireland when I did a Gig out there.
So go fuck yourself.
By the way,
do you know about the 800 dead babies
that would shut anybody down? You know,
but I didn't buy it, so I already
have a fucking regret about that.
But the upside is, is that
just means that I, uh,
you know,
I have to go back and I have to buy one
and I'm not going online to fucking buy
one.
I'm going to go back to O'malley's out
there and I'm going to fucking buy when
next time I go out there. So, uh,
thank you to everybody out in Ireland,
came out to my shows. Um,
thank you. Do a shame.
My driver fucking drove like a
fucking lunatic and a good way,
made all kinds of great moves
to get me there and back. Um,
I wanted to see the peace walls when
I was up in Belfast and was just,
it got too late at night and we
were driving a nice car in the tags.
Just clearly showed that we
were from a, I guess, you know,
the Catholic side or whatever.
So they were just like, yeah,
we don't need to be driving by that wall.
So maybe next time.
And then also there's something weird
about all the pain and suffering.
Then everybody went through up there that
you fucking would want to drive by it
in like fucking rubber neck and
take pictures and shit. I always,
I always feel disrespectful when
I do shit like that. So, um,
anyways, the, uh, I ended
up making my flight.
I was way fucking early and um, I did, uh,
Bristol last night. Um, amazing
venue, unbelievable crowd,
Jesus Christ. I'm all, every
crowd I've got on stage.
The way that they've been
welcoming to me has been, uh,
I immediately go into my self
conscious fucking, you know, ah, Jesus,
their expectations are too high.
I'm going to do a bunch of Shit and
Dick Jokes and they're going to be like,
this show sucked or whatever.
Um, I've been having so much fun,
actually did a two hour
show last night and Bristol,
I apologize to the people in the crowd.
I mean,
as much as you like somebody
to go a little bit long,
that's too long to have people
sit in there. So my apologies. Um,
anyways, so today, uh,
also I get into Bristol,
I stayed in this really
cool, uh, in, you know,
and uh,
and actually had a key,
the name of my room was not a number,
it was just somebody named had
said Harvey's, you know, it's,
they had all these weird names and shits.
He kind of had to remember
what floor you're on. And uh,
I showed up and it was this really cool
ass looking room and they had left like
a little piece of chocolate cake with
some powdered sugar on it. And you know,
old freckles. I got a sweet
tooth, so I'm like fantastic.
I sit down to eat it and there's a bunch
of little fucking ants all over it.
Fucking gross. So I had it's take it
and I stuck it on the window sill.
I forgot to remove it
when I went to go leave.
So I hope the cleaning lady finds it.
Uh,
my apologies to whoever gets that room
after me. Um, if you get that room,
it's Harvey's and I
left it out on the deck.
It had this little deck area we could
sit down and it was just fucking ants and
they were all over the plate and I was
blowing them off the plate and I'm like,
what am I doing now? They're on the rug,
let's get this whole thing out of there.
And there was so many of them as I
was carrying them, I was filling them,
starting to climb on my hand
and I was just like that,
like running over to that little thing,
try to get it open and I stuck it out
there. So whatever the aunts love me,
cause I didn't kill any of them when
they all got a nice piece of cake. Um,
so this morning taking you
through the whole fucking trip,
I'm driving up to Manchester and I keep
saying legendary Manchester Cause I read
this book among the thugs.
If you ever want to read a
great book, it's about a, a,
an American journalists.
They Yank who goes and he
somehow ingratiates himself to,
to the supporters over there and he gets
really into the fucking the hood limbs
and all hoodlums, whatever and all
that type of shit back when, uh,
you know, you were basically
taking your life into your hand.
It's seemed anyways when you
went to a match back then. Um,
so anyways,
we would drive it up there today and I
actually finally a bucket list thing,
I got to,
uh,
go by John Bonham's grave
and pay my respects.
And once again, you know, as much
as I wanted to take a Selfie,
it was just such a quiet, peaceful
place. It just didn't seem right.
So I didn't, I did take a
picture of the grave, um,
because it was just really cool.
All the drum sticks and symbols and stuff
and the stuff that people leave there.
And I did go in and sign the
guest book and it's cool.
You go and you get to say
a nice thing about, uh,
the greatest rock drummer and
my opinion of all time. And, uh,
I still can't believe that
I got to go the, it's,
it's like, I dunno, you walk in there
and you're waiting for somebody to say,
tell you to stop. You know, nobody
does this, this little cemetery.
And you just sort of walking
around looking for the,
you looking for the drum sticks,
leaned up against the headstone and uh,
and then all of a sudden,
there it is. And I don't know,
just that guy is so big in my
head, I couldn't believe, you know,
even though he's been dead and
gone for 30 something years,
I'm 36 years coming up.
Uh,
I dunno. That's it. I don't know.
It was, it was an amazing feeling.
And uh,
so I did that earlier today.
And then we stopped off at a place,
got some fish and chips,
did the whole fucking English thing.
And uh,
now I'm up here in Manchester.
I'm having the greatest time. Uh,
these crowds have been awesome.
So I'm playing the Apollo theater tonight,
which a lot of all these fucking
bands that I listened to, you know,
the fucking Beatles played there. The
rolling stones, led Zeppelin played there.
I imagine James Brown,
all the people from that era.
I Bet Jimi Hendrix played there. It's
been there forever in all those people.
You know, we're coming up during
that time and played there. So, uh,
that's what I'm going to be doing for the
up until the show is trying to youtube
all like shows like that. So this, this
really feels like a fucking paid vacation.
Um, so anyways, let me, uh,
I got a little bit of advertising
here. I got to read. Uh,
if I can type in my password
and talk at the same time,
which we all know is difficult for me.
Come on bill,
you can do which you're almost there.
All right, it did it. Okay. Oh Jesus.
Here we go. Club Debbie, everybody
club. Debbie, I never been to England.
He when I was pressing, but I
don't remember. I wasn't drinking,
but my ass was squinting.
I couldn't tell.
I couldn't tell if I was in Rhode Island.
Right?
Club W is a revolutionary new wine club
that takes the guesswork out of choosing
your wine.
They have a simple six question pallet
quiz that will match you with delicious
high quality wine you are
guaranteed to love right now. Uh,
a club w should have voted for GMP should
have over GM is offering listeners $20
off your first order when
you go to club Debbie,
you and I got Donald trump.com/burn
and it gets even better.
I know you all hate paying for shipping.
So club Debbie and we'll actually pay
for your shipping on orders of four
bottles or more. So take something
off your to do lists and,
and just go,
just go to club.
Debbie Played Ping Pong
during the Vietnam war club,
w.com/bar to get $20 off your first order.
Now that's club w.com/burr.
All right.
Loot crate. Gimme the loot crate with
loot crate. You'll get collectibles,
apparel and more from your favorite pop
culture franchises delivered right to
your door every single month. We're
talking a new tee shirt in every crate.
Figures, comics stuff via kitchen,
a wide range of exclusive items.
Uh, you can't take any, you can't
get anywhere else from your fan.
Favorite franchises like Harry Potter,
Marvel Comics,
fallout four star wars and so many more
movies that I've never seen that I've
seen. Star Wars. Uh, and you could get
all of this for less than $20 a month.
Luke Craig, uh, come geek out with us.
Luke Craig is a monthly subscription box
service for epic Geek and Gamer items
and pop culture gear for
less than $20 a month.
He gets 68 items that include license
gear, a parable, collectibles, unique,
one of a kind items or more.
Then I just say this, all right.
You have until the 19th
at 9:00 PM Pacific time,
a US time to subscribe and
receive that month's crate.
And when the cutoff happens,
that's it. It's over.
There's no way for you to get you
a hope pajamas for adults anymore.
Make sure to head over to www
dot loot crate l o t crate,
crtv.com/burr and enter the code bird
to save $3 off on any new subscription.
Um Oh, what else? We August messaging.
What the fuck is this from?
Bad guys doing good things for the wrong
reason to good guys with questionable
tactics.
August is the perfect time to
explore the anti hero a walk.
The hero slash villain line with the
this 100% exclusive collection of items
from DC comics,
Archie dark horse and kill bill.
That includes two great collectibles.
Oh, that's cool. Okay. In a wearable,
a wearable, and of course our monthly
t. And don't forget the pin. All right?
That was, uh, August messaging.
I thought that was the name of a company
rather than read this during August. Oh,
Jesus. You too can have a podcast.
You don't have to be smart everybody.
Alright.
Zip Recruiter.
Yeah.
Are you hiring? Do you know where to post
your job to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place.
Isn't enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your job on all the
top job sites and now you can with zip
recruiter.com you can post
your job to 100 plus job sites,
including social media networks
like Facebook and Twitter,
all with a single click. Find candidates
in any city or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your
qualified candidates roll into zip.
Rick Proda.
Easy to use interface,
no juggling emails or calls to your
office. Quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire the right
person fast and find out why today.
Sip.
Okay.
Oh, your computer has been used by over
800,000 businesses and right now my
listeners can post jobs on zip
recruiter by for free by going
to ziprecruiter.com/bird that's
ziprecruiter.com/burr
one more time for free.
Go to ziprecruiter.com/burr. All right,
there you go. How much time I got left?
25 minutes. Um, you know
I was up late last night.
I couldn't sleep.
You know what I was reading up?
I was watching a bunch of youtube
videos trying to learn a couple of Mike
Johnston drum fills watching this kid,
show me how to shave my own head.
Um, and then also I stumbled upon
a, I dunno how I got onto it,
but I saw that whole fucking
Twitter thing with Leslie Jones,
one of the funniest fucking
Comedians I've ever seen. Um,
how she was I guess online or something
was on Twitter or whatever her movie
Ghostbusters was coming up right.
And a bunch of people attacked your road,
all this racist Shit,
you know, up to all about freedom
of speech. But this got to do,
you know what they should be on Facebook.
People should have to use their
real names and have their real face,
you know? And then if you want to go
say a bunch of racist Shit, you know,
rather than hiding behind your
faceless picture with the fucking egg,
it's just what, a bunch of just
a bunch of fucking pussies.
And that is so overwhelmingly depressing
that people still think that way.
You know?
I Dunno.
I also always wonder how people
who attract that is their fan base.
Never question what it
is that they're saying.
You know what I mean?
Like if that's how your fan base behaves.
And I'm not singling anybody out,
but I've had experience myself with
people like that. It's just like,
you know, I don't know, even like a
Donald Trump guy, it's some point,
he's never at any point addressed
like, hey, overtly racist people.
This is not what I'm
saying with my speeches.
He just completely fucking ignores it.
2016 it's fucking astounding.
So, um, whatever, in the end of the day,
Leslie's going to have the last laugh
because she's living her fucking dream and
you know something.
I don't wish those racist people
not to have their dreams come true.
I just wish that they travel a
little more, widen their fucking
array of friends and maybe they wouldn't
be such ignorant comments. All right,
I'm off my fucking soapbox.
So I'm in Manchester here tonight.
Uh,
I'm not going to lie. I have not
been eating as well as I should,
but you don't pay the price for it over
in Europe. The way we do in the states.
I don't know what their food is. It's
just, I know it's a better quality food.
Uh,
I can tell you right now,
I don't give a fuck.
We fish and ships don't Jesus Christ,
they put it in a fee,
wrap it up in this piece of paper in
the grease, but you can't even like,
as it's coming through,
the greases already been absorbed in
your body through like the skin in your
hands.
And I guess back in the day,
the promoted Gordon was
telling me, um, they use,
still wrap it up in like Dale newspaper.
So by the time you ate it,
some of your fries would have like,
would be blackened with
the ink from the newspaper.
And I guess they would up until
10 years ago, they finally,
they was still doing it until
somebody finally just said like, Hey,
this probably isn't the most
healthiest thing for us,
our citizens to dope.
You know, what to say.
We actually just use a sanitize
piece of paper. But, um,
I was sitting down where I don't
even know where the hell I was. Uh,
okay.
Right before we were going over
to go up to John Bottoms grave.
And,
uh,
you know, if you ever do that
by the way, like it's, it's,
it's an amazing thing to do and just,
uh, I dunno, I,
you'll see when you go there,
you're not going to fucking sit there.
I didn't want to say because someone
would do it just to be a Douche.
It's like one of the biggest asshole
things you could ever do is to do that
fucking, you know, that stupid
picture that all the kids do. The,
the Yolo Douche photo of, you know,
when you got the peace side, you know,
he'd have John Bonham's headstone
over your fucking head. Um,
you know, it's, I'm telling you,
even if you are one of those costs,
if you get there, you will
immediately just be like, yeah,
this is not the place for that
behavior. So, um, anyways,
that is the, uh, that's the podcast here.
Uh,
looking forward to all these gigs.
I do Manchester,
then I got two nights in London, then I
go to Amsterdam, then I go up to Scotland,
uh,
and then there's Germany.
And then fucking Belgium and then all
Billy freckles is going to meet up with
the lovely Nia and we're gone. I'm going
to be on vacation. I can't fucking wait.
Uh,
yeah.
And uh, I'm all right. I got
to whittle down my act though.
I can't do a two hour fucking special,
you know,
unless I call it for fuck sakes.
When you get to the point you freckled.
All right. That's it for the podcast.
Uh, have a good weekend. You constant.
I'll check in on Monday.
Sure.
Yeah.
What's going on? It's built,
it's the Monday morning podcast.
As you might have guessed.
I am a little bit under the weather.
Uh, I don't know what happened
actually. I know what happened.
I fucking traveled too,
too much.
I came back from my fucking vacation,
flew across the country,
was in la for one day,
got right back on a fucking plane.
You know that too with germs and that I
get four hours of radio in the morning
and that'll do it.
If you have a one to how comedian gets
a fucking cold in the middle of the
goddamn summer, you know, it was,
there was this lady in the
magazine store when I was in lax,
I went in to go buy a little trail mix,
you know,
trying to not spend
any fucking money what?
I'm on the plane because I'm sick of these
guys with all the other added charges.
So like I don't want to go to do,
that's a loud truck.
You let him get up the hill for
a second. All right. I was like,
I know what I've got to do. I'm going to
buy some trail mix and I'll get a water,
a couple of waters and uh,
just nibble on the fucking nuts and the
berries or whatever the crap I was going
to get. Uh, and uh, so anyway,
so I go to the magazine store
and this lady behind the cow,
this lady behind the counter had this
fucking middle of the winter cold.
I couldn't believe it. I
mean, I'm talking like,
you know when you get a cold that day
and a half where you know what I mean?
It's like if we lived in a
little more of a police state,
you'd be fucking quarantine.
You know?
It was like that part of the
cold and she's fucking at work.
She sounded like me except her nose was
running and shit and she's fucking like,
yes. Well not small, but she
just wished you had exact change.
You know what I'm saying?
You know anytime you stand in line
there's always that fucking asshole.
Usually a check who takes out the little
change purse and gives them the exact
fucking thing.
I bet they never get coats or at
least they don't get him for fucking
people in a magazine store or something.
I don't know what I'm saying.
You know that that's so much fucking
medicine I got in me right now.
I slept in 20 minute
increments last night.
Fucking blowing my nose.
Aos.
Funny is whenever I get a cold is I sound
like that guy from sexy beast to ever
see that movie. You know, the beginning
part when he's laying in the pool,
the next to the pool and he's just like,
I
did that. He had of sway
roasting
boy
like
swell.
It's like a sauna.
It's pretty good. Right? London,
well,
London,
every cab will allow face
Dell make me laugh. All right.
Oh my God,
my fucking head is killing me.
You know my fucking head is killing me
and I'm still doing the podcast is that's
how fucking dedicated I am. Actually,
yesterday was the worst part of it,
you know,
and I had the double Claude,
like some important cement in my nostrils,
so I had to walk around with my mouth
open like p diddy does and shack them.
I've talked about that,
that disease where your mouth is
open even when you're not talking,
you know,
maybe shack and p diddy I those,
those kinds of people who
they always have, you know,
you ever go to school with some of the,
always had a cold, you know what I mean?
It's like if we lived in the olden days,
the,
they're the ones who would have fucking,
you know,
got some sort of fever and died when
they were six and he's never had a chance
because there was no penicillin.
You know, looking at you,
you're like leather,
your leather man,
I can't get that fucking
movie out of my head.
I watched sexy beast the whole fucking
way up to Denver and the way vacs such a
great fucking movie. Teddy
Bass, Mr. Black Magic.
Um, all right, so if you knew
of my podcast, I'm usually,
I'm usually not sick.
In fact,
this might be the first time I've
ever been fucking sick. What?
I've done one of these and
it's horrible. It's just why not? Why is
it cold in the summertime? So much worse.
I don't usually, you guys
ask me questions. I got a
question for you. Why is that?
You know what I mean? I, I don't get it.
That's one of those moments where
you try to speak and then, you know,
it was just fucking clogs up so you to
swallow this just terrible. All right,
here we go. Let's get into the
fucking the questions question.
So you knew one of my podcasts, like
I said, I'm not usually fucking sick.
I usually don't have this
late night DJ sort of voice.
It's a little higher up like fucking
Steve Buscemi and uh, whatever.
People send me questions or I ask them
questions and I fucking bullshit around
and I hype stuff that I have
coming up. Like for example, um,
I have a one hour special called,
why do I do this coming out August 31st,
very easy to remember the last day of
August. It's a Sunday night. You know,
how'd you curl up with a
special someone and uh,
200 of your closest fucking Fred's.
Not even that.
Just find someone who has a
fucking Nielsen box. They know,
you know the old ladies who are in the
Jesus cause I think they're the only ones
who get boxes. If you think about that,
if you had a fucking, uh, Nielsen box,
like a, what would actually stay on
the air and what wouldn't, you know,
would you feel some
sort of responsibility?
Would you deliberately be an asshole and
watch bad shows just to keep them on?
Um, I don't fucking know.
All right, let's get,
I only got one question this week for
some fucking reason. I don't know why.
I know I got more,
I couldn't find them and I feel like shit.
So I'll go through and I'll try
to find it for fucking next week,
but as of right now,
this is the one and only
question for this week.
[inaudible] all right.
Uh,
I wanted to know that being
in your thirties I'm actually
40 do you feel you've
accomplished a lot as a comedian so far
or do you feel you should have a bigger
fan base and be a little more well
known among popular celebrities?
Not saying none. No. About you though.
Okay. There's a lot of questions
in there. Okay. First of all,
I'm 40 do you feel you've covered
a lot as a comedian? Yes I do.
Do I feel I should have a bigger fan base?
I feel I could have been
smarter as a business person.
I don't know. You know what, I'm
right where I'm supposed to be.
And that's how you have to think
when you're in this business,
because if you start looking at other
people and compare and that's the quickest
way to be fucking miserable. And I already
have a cold and I'm already miserable.
So why start beating myself up? Um, no,
I actually think I have,
uh,
a great level of note notoriety where I
feel I'm a respected as a comic and a,
that's what I wanted, you know,
as far as being bigger, you know,
I had to get good and uh,
you know,
I'm not going to come up with the
catch phrase and shit like that,
but I'm getting better at the business.
Like I haven't taken all my sets with
stupid shit happens with the crowd.
I've been putting them up,
you know,
try to put them up on youtube to
keep my fucking face out there.
So I'm trying to get a little bit better,
but you know,
but do I think that should be more
well known among popular celebrities?
You know, it's fucking hilarious
is for some reason in my world,
celebrities don't watch TV.
They don't watch movies and they
have no idea they're just on TV.
You know what I mean? So
I would just, you know,
I always assumed they didn't watch it. You
know, kind of like if you're a mailman,
you wouldn't go home and then watch
somebody deliver mail. He'd be like, dude,
I did that all day, you know? But, uh,
I dunno.
I did that Spike TV awards and there
was a ton of fucking celebrities there.
And I gotta be honest with you,
none of them know who the fuck I was,
which, you know, I think is about right.
Cause I need to be honest with myself.
I can walk down the street and
I don't get mobbed. You know,
when I go walk down the street to
get a slice of pie or some shit,
it doesn't end up on TMZ.
Right. Oh my God, you got,
you got to see this. Bill Berg
got a fucking snickers bar. Okay.
It's like he couldn't even open the
wrapper and then have that old guy on the
show. He's just like, oh fuck.
That's definitely making this show.
That show is, uh, it's unwatchable.
It's unwatchable not because of
the clips I've watched the clip,
but when they go to their little fucking
home center and they try to act like
absolutely nothing is something,
you know,
when I like fucking Hell Nah,
I don't even know.
I can not only make it pass that open
apart where they just started talking
about, you know, okay, Meryl Streep.
Evidently she's in the deal point add.
She wants to make this
fucking American flag.
The old boy as she forgot to get yard.
So she was a little upset when
she drove back to the Onstar.
And then the old guy, oh my God,
that's making the shell, um,
roast in here,
boy.
Sweller and that's my favorite
word. He says. Sweller all right.
Uh, this is tremendous. All right. Uh,
last week I talked about shit that was
underrated or somebody asked me what I
thought the most underrated
overrated thing was,
which shut off a big debate here. And, uh,
so people send me and shit what they
think is underrated and what they think is
overrated. Okay? So let's start with
this first person. Uh, they would say,
I would say marriage is overrated.
Big Time.
I was married and it didn't work out,
so fuck it. I think it's overrated
as fucking hilarious. Anything that
you had a shitty experience with,
you know what I mean? You
just automatically thinks
it sucks. Like yourself.
Beautiful Girl. You know what
I mean? Eight. Oh, and you
sit in the top, your friend.
Oh my God, she's beautiful.
She's gorgeous. Uh, God,
what do I say to when you
go up and you ask her out,
ask her to dance and she turns you down.
Then immediately he like, she's a cunt.
Jan.
I don't think she's that hot.
Anytime anybody brings her
up for the rest of the time,
you get to say it's
overrated. So, you know what,
I don't think marriage is overrated.
I think if you're with the right person,
that's got to be a great thing.
You know?
Cause what happens is as
you get fucking old like me,
you become susceptible to colds in
the middle of the fucking winter.
And uh, you know what I mean? Or
what are you going to do? You know,
at some point he wants some
sort of companionship and uh,
I dunno, I'm gradually getting towards
that. I don't want to be fucking alone,
you know what I mean?
Is that why people get married though?
I think people get bad.
That's when it's because they want to
have kids and I think people get married
their forties cause they don't want
to be alone. You know what I mean?
Why am I talking to you guys?
Like you can fucking respond.
Like this is some sort of live shit.
Like this is some sort of fancy
fucking technology. It is it. Okay,
next thing somebody said, John Mayer is
overrated. He's a boring guitar player.
He's boring. People need to stop
saying he's like Jimi Hendrix.
I didn't know they were saying that.
I knew that all of a sudden
he stopped doing that.
I want to run down the hall,
my High School,
whatever avenue that screaming
at the top of his lungs.
All of a sudden he's
playing with Steve Jordan,
my favorite fucking drummer of all time.
Um,
okay. You think he's overrated? I
might go with that a little bit.
I want to go there a little bit.
I think he's definitely a fuckin awesome
guitar player. He's got a ways to go,
but they already got them up on guitar
center where they got like Stevie Ray
Vaughan clapped it and
then it goes John Mayer.
I think that's a little bit premature,
you know,
and a guitar center since the fuck do I
know. I catch colds and fucking summer.
All right, next one. Underrated.
I would go with underrated.
I would go with friendship.
Isn't that a nice answer?
It's something a lot of
people take for granted.
People want to go out and meet a check
and hook up and yeah, I do that. Oh,
look at this guy. If I could talk himself
up. Yeah. People want a two onward,
you know, fuck it happens.
You wear the right shirt.
You got a good rap like me. Um, anyways,
but good friends are always there for you.
No one ever goes out looking for a friend.
But I'm glad I've got some,
I hope that didn't come across as
lame as the funny thing about a guy,
if you ever remotely open up emotionally,
you have to do a preemptive strike and
kind of call yourself half a fag before
somebody else did. What did I, sweet
little paragraph. He wrote that.
But good friends are always there for you.
No one ever goes out looking for Fred,
but I'm glad I have. So that's how he
heard in his head and he's like, oh fuck,
I need to correct as quickly. Uh,
do some damage. Corrosion control.
I know that there's a couple of
crosses lave, uh, by the way,
if somebody is blowing me, write down.
Yes, it is a female. All right. Uh,
what else we got? All
right. The crazy chefs. Oh,
was the question I asked.
If you watch that hell's kitchen,
my girlfriend watches that shit
and I can't watch it because,
uh, when that guy starts
yelling at those people, I just,
I lose all respect for because there's
no way I could fucking sit there.
You know, bad enough, I got to go.
Yes, chef. You know what I mean?
Like he's fucking General Schwarzkopf
or something, you know, uh, top of that.
If he's going to be screaming at me like,
well I know his dacha,
who's the fuck is wrong
with you? I would just, Oh,
the whole plate of Nachos. I would heat
up the cheese first. I'm talking fucking,
I do it just to the side of his face,
you know what I mean?
Just to make his life more miserable
because he was just totally fucking just
get them, you know, just half his face.
So we looked like that guy and Dick Tracy
and he'd always have to cheat to his
right or his left while I
was really fucking evil and
I really thought that out.
They're not. Um, but anyways,
the person said the crazy chef
could act the way it does.
Cause apparently his food is amazing.
I don't know for sure.
I can't afford to heat this restaurants.
You really don't know what the
fuck you talking about. The uh,
okay. Uh, I can understand why you
don't understand Bruce Springsteen.
It's Kinda like how I am with Bob Dylan.
That's another fucking
guy I think is overrated.
And I know that's unbelievably,
I guess ignorant because there's a whole
generation of people that freak out.
I don't get it. I don't get it. He, he
sounds like he has a cold all the time.
They're retired aged guy.
I got too much of cold.
I used to be able to imitate him,
but fucking throw a bucket of Plato,
one bad knee this week.
All right.
That was the worst fucking depression
I've ever done. Hey, don't leave.
Still got level songs to play.
Um,
that's actually a quote somebody I knew
had when Bob Dylan was going through his
shitty fucking time in the 80s when he
was playing with Tom Petty and somebody
opened for him and blew him on
stage and everybody was walking out.
And I guess Bob Dylan, the fucking
legend of the 60s was onstage gold. Hey,
do leave. Still got a lot
more songs to play. Um,
alright. Uh, what else we got here?
Now listen, I love this person's cool.
If they made a nice quick list. What
enough to read a whole fucking paragraph.
Overrated. Colby Bryant. Um,
I dunno if he's over it cause
that guy does get a ton of shit,
but I was one of those people before
last season I was saying that he had the
skills to Jordan and then I watched
classic sports and I watch Michael Jordan
and then I went, oh yeah, that's
right. I forgot about that.
Um, he still his shit though.
All right. Number two,
a rod rod's overrated.
That I is a all over the amount of
buddy's fucking plump getting paid.
He's never won a ring. I'd go
at that. The Spiderman movies,
that might be my favorite thing
that someone has said is overrated.
Those movies fucking suck.
Does movies other worst fuck that.
Just bad.
That was such a great cartoon.
And then they just, ah,
what the fuck was his name? Uh,
he's going to say no. Wiley.
That's a guy for prevention.
They learn it's,
what's the name of the dude who fucking,
this is like two stars out there
that look exactly the same to me.
And I don't know that fucking I know
Alijah would is that the rings guy at the
Lord of the rigs,
the Lord of the Rings Guy and the guy
from Spiderman look the exact same ad.
If you were to scalp Josh Hartnett,
they'd all have the exact
same fucking haircut.
It's sort of an updated mo from the three
stooges. But those, those movies suck.
Um, I didn't see the last one
where they had the black suit.
That was my favorite period in Spiderman
when he got the black suit and made
them be fucking evil and
he couldn't control it.
But judging by the first two movies,
I was assuming they were
going to fuck it up. You know,
I just realized is that
a paranoid thought?
What if a guy have directed the
Spiderman movies for some reason,
knew who the fuck I was getting back
to celebrities of that type of shit.
A decided to fucking listen to my
podcast. He's like, this guy is great.
He's funny. Even way as a cold, he
can get a couple of lasts. Bob Dylan.
Freshman sucks,
but you know,
he's played on one day and then all of a
sudden I trash his trilogy. It was like,
I yo fuck him.
And he calls up an aging Donnie
most alright. Underrated. Uh,
I thought they said Robert De Niro,
this is the way I have dyslexia
person actually wrote Roberto Duran.
Uh, yes. Reverted to rent was
fucked after the no mas fight.
But uh, yeah, hands of stone.
Yeah. I, you know what?
It always goes back to fucking sugar
ray Leonard and I don't like how Marvin
Hagler actually plays second fiddle to
fucking sugar ray Leonard. Marvin be him.
All right, I'll fucking sugar ray
Leonard. Did he do that little flashy,
those little poo poo poo poo fucking
punches at the last 30 seconds.
He fucking steel around that he had on
shiny his shorts and next thing you know,
he went to the fucking fight.
It was bullshit. Um, well,
I'll tell you else Tommy Hearns go on
youtube and once with Tommy hard knocks
out,
Roberta Duran,
it's one of the most vicious fucking
left folks I've ever seen in my life.
He's like,
he's one of those freaks of nature
where he weighed like 150 860 pounds,
but somehow he was like six one or six
two so he could hit you from across the
room if you watch his arm when he throws.
It's kind of like the molar technique.
Huh? Anybody else? Anybody else tried
to learn that shit on the drums? Uh,
underrated. Number two,
voting, uh, is underrated.
You know what I think protest is?
I think people need to learn on
a protest to get in this country.
I couldn't protest, man. If
I fucking went to a protest,
I would feel like I was on the set of a
movie about protesting because it seems
so cliched. You know what I mean?
Maybe they could get some new chance.
It's like everything
has to rhyme with four.
You have a nurse sat at a fucking
protest and it's always one, two, three,
four window.
I have fucking war,
or solid sells a fucking Oer,
but we're walking out the door.
Whatever it is, you give really
limited. You know what I mean?
It needs to be set that the
IAB protesting. It needs,
it needs to progress.
I'll tell you, it was fucked
up. I was just in Denver, right?
Had an awesome time up there at
the comedy works and they have,
the Democratic national convention is
coming to town and this is how much of a
fucking police state we suddenly
live in in this country.
They actually have a designated
area where people can protest.
It's 200 yards away from where people
are going to be speaking it going in.
So when you watch it on TV,
you're not going to see the protest as,
you're not going to see that there's
any sorta addressed. It's really,
it's really a bad, bad, bad thing. And
I know you have to protect these people,
the politicians and that type of stuff.
But if the people of this country
are unhappy, that should be shelled,
which is the danger of having seven
guys own all the fucking media in this
country. You know? Fuck a Rupert
Murdoch, even though it's my space.
Bloody Hell. Every con with a love
face. All right. Uh, number three.
This is my, this is a good one
too. Underrated phone, sex,
phone, sex cures aids.
Okay, you've heard it here.
First people out there,
people out there,
there are their labs and they're
shaking stuff up and fucking graduated
cylinders uptown with you.
Alright.
Phone sex is better than having sex
with a condom cause condoms suck.
Okay. But if you don't wear a
condom that Danielle like, Oh,
let me ask you this county
times you guys done that,
how many times have you made a mistake
and then gone and got yourself fucking
tested? You know what I
mean? He just sitting there.
That's what you always renew your
relationship with God when you're in the
waiting room for your yearly physical.
You know,
I did it like three times. I fucked up
while I was just like sitting in that way.
We're going, I swear to
God. I know I said it,
but I swear to God I will never do that
again and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Unfortunately, I have not had to
live through that. Hell and you,
but uh, that's what brings
it back to phone. Sex.
That's why I sky is fucking great
because there's no worry STD,
there's no problem with, you know, if you
just met the person be want, do you know,
if you're in a relationship, obviously
you want to be there with the person,
but like, you know, that awkward moment
after you hook up with somebody and,
and you just want them to fucking
leave and maybe even they want leave,
but it somehow has to be finessed.
There's no real FIDESSA. I see.
You have to finesse a little bit after
the phone sex. You got to kind of be like,
oh, this is what are you doing this
week? But you could make faces like, God,
I fucking hate with it. She can be
doing that because you're on the phone.
You know what I mean? I thought it was
funny. I actually, I had is actually bad,
actually hung up on someone
during that phone. Sex.
It's one of the meat things
they have a fucking did. Uh,
I was drunk and the
person's stuck at it and uh,
they were annoying me and
it was frustrating. And
you know,
like when you're sober and you think,
why don't you just do this and you like,
because it's really fucking mean.
But when you drunk, whoever that
person is is your head who says,
don't fucking do that.
Goes away. They take a nap.
I think that's the first thing that
passes out in your head when you drink is
that person that says,
don't fucking say that or don't do that.
So I was in the middle of it and I just
hung up on the person and then they
called back and I was like, ah, Shit.
Now if I was smart and I was sober,
first of all, I wasn't hung up on him.
And even if I did hang up on them,
I wouldn't answer the phone.
And then they would have
thought it was a dropped call.
But me being drunk like a fucking idiot,
I picked the phone up and I was like,
oh wow. And she was like,
did you hang up on me?
And I was trying to come up with a lie,
but I was just too drunk and I just went,
ah,
yeah,
I swear to God, you know, if
I don't make it to heaven,
it's got to because B could
be because of that moment.
That's one of the meters fucking things
I haven't did to somebody. And uh,
you know what,
I never apologize maybe how to do that.
It's like that fucking TV show or
that show called pay it forward.
My name is Earl. Yeah, that's it. I should
really, you know, she really try to Wa
they should really try to set that
straight. So a false sex. Yes.
It's definitely underrated. But you've
got to watch out though now because, uh,
the government can listen to your phone
calls because they're trying to get the
terrorists.
It's not because they're trying to put
more of a stranglehold on your fucking
freedoms. Oh, hey,
here's something for you.
Someone was telling me that they sort of
subtly part of a bill passed some shit
where when you cross state lines,
the cops can pull you over and take
your laptop and your cell phone,
no questions asked. You know what I
mean? What the fuck is that about?
And like always, I didn't even
research this. Someone just said it.
I took it as law and now putting it out
there and it really just sort of freaked
me out.
You know what?
I really think that we are heading
towards a very violent period in this
country's history.
I don't know what the fuck is going on.
You know they're building this
highway from Mexico to Canada,
which is not bullshit. That's actually
true. Mexico's going to own it.
I don't get what we're doing. I don't
like it. I'll tell you right now,
I don't fucking like it.
I'm going to get a Spanish villa and I'm
gonna lay out there and a little yellow
speedo getting a sunburn.
A bloody has.
Um, all right. I'm literally fucking,
I'm clammy right now.
That's got to be one of the most
disgusting words and the fucking English
language.
Clammy picture.
The one famous person you would
love to meet and hook up with.
Now picture them clammy. Then
that just wrote it for you. Huh?
All you ladies out there.
How about a clammy Brad Pitt?
Oh, that's disgusting. All right.
A couple more underrated overrated things.
Then I'll wrap this fucking thing
up here. Uh, what are we doing here?
I never got spinners on cars.
I never understood spinners on cars.
Especially minivans. Who the
fuck are they kidding? Yeah,
those spinners things were, uh,
those are in for a minute. Allegedly.
The first guy to have of the debut one
was Latrell. Sprewell. Is that true?
Because the first time I heard them,
they were called the trails. Uh,
Jesus Christ. What the fuck
did that memory come from?
Uh, one more thing. I never,
oh, biggest the hype. The segue.
Remember that fucking thing?
That's another great one.
The segway.
Remember that he just stand on it and
you can lean forward and it goes forward.
Now they just have cops using them
in meter maids. I don't fucking know.
Is that who does it? I have no fucking
idea. All right. You know what?
I think what I said I was clammy. That
was the time to fucking hang up. So, um,
so there you go. There's your whole, uh,
is your whole fucking list there.
All right.
There's a bunch of underrated than
overrated. Thanks. I got it was,
I don't know why I got to do, I've got
to drink liquids. Who the fuck belt?
You know what I did try and get rid
of a fucking cold. Just how dumb I am.
I went on the fucking Internet, right? And
I always heard garlic was good for you.
So I go on the Internet and
I just go to like fucking,
you know what's up with
garlic.com or some bullshit?
This part,
like they got people on Youtube who eat
raw garlic trying to say that it helps
you. You can put it in peanut
butter. Fucking nasty. Right?
But I'm feeling so bad and I had three
shows Saturday night at the fucking
comedy works. I'm, I'm desperate.
So I actually got honey lemon
fucking tea or whatever it was.
I don't know what the fuck was.
I put honey in there and then
I put two raw garlic clothes.
Fucking just dice them up and
put them in there. And uh,
I don't think it helped me,
but I'll tell you,
it definitely fucking distracted
me. But I guess, I don't know,
does anybody know about that shit?
Supposed to be if he had garlic, uh,
we fucking do you want to talk about
fucking overrated or underrated?
It's gotta be gone.
Like you go to their goddamn website,
they got a cure and everything from
fucking the cold to AFC cancer, you know,
they said back in the day, if you had a
warrant, people used to rub garlic on it.
And I'm like, really? I'm thinking,
Oh shit, maybe that does work.
And then I'm thinking,
or maybe they didn't have compound w,
you know what I mean? So they had
to fucking put food. You know,
you had an appendicitis, you put fucking
chips Ahoy, you're on your stomach.
That doesn't make any sense but does it,
I'm going to that conspiracy to that,
these fucking drugs of bullshit and that
we should have listened to the native
Americans more. Let it be
great if you went to doctor
then got in, slice, you open.
He just fucking dressed up like that.
Eyes Wide Shut party in the end of the
movie and just sort of danced around a
little bit and through some Bays Alanya
how much you need that visit would cost,
right? Would need fucking
nationwide healthcare with that.
All you'd need was a balcony
and a little bit of sunlight.
That's the gas thing I've ever
seen. All right, that's it. Um,
I got to update my website here.
Uh, my next show is, is in Miami.
It's in, uh, which is in Florida. I'm
not going to be at the Improv now.
Allegedly white comedians
don't do well down there.
That's what I was told the last time.
White comics do not do well
down there because uh, you know,
they just go to see Latino people cause
there's a bunch of Cubans down there and
uh, so if you're Cuban, give
this white guy a chance and uh,
if you've got a white friend,
why don't you bring them out to
sort of balance out the crowd?
I'll just bring one so I got a familiar
face in the crowd, you know what I mean?
Cause the only thing I know about Cuba
fucking scar face, that's it. I know that.
I know they fucking got great cigars.
Wait, am I know some shit about Cuba.
They all drive around in cars
from the 1950s because of, uh,
our economic sanctions or what they'd
say is because communism doesn't fucking
work. Um, you know what?
None of it fucking works because people
can't handle power, myself included.
You have a nurse that shit.
Take the average night's fucking dude.
You make them a bouncer.
He's instantly a fucking asshole.
And it just has to do with,
it has to do with that shit.
So I don't give a fuck anyway.
Fuck I'm talking about right now.
And I go from Cuba talking about bouncing.
Oh Shit.
The headache went away walking around.
Now I'm roast in hand and it I,
if this podcast blame it on fucking
Tylenol pm Theraflu airborne and too raw
garlic cloves, cause none of that shit
fucking worked. All right. They go,
thank you for listening and please
watch my special, my CD is in stores,
I think today, my new CD,
which is the audio for my
upcoming, yeah, fucking special.
Oh No. Comes out August 5th all right.
That is it. Thank you for listening.
Hope I made you guys laugh in
my clammy states. All right.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
okay.