Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Dan,
just checking in on you.
How are you?
We've got the lovely kneel with
me. Hello. What's going on?
Oh it's Christmas needy.
I know. Shady sidewalks.
Pretty ladies.
Everybody walking around
spending money on p Bull Dad.
I know them.
Yeah.
Take Your Dick out and a charger game.
Robin up.
Bad fucking no,
I feel so bad for that kid.
Why? Why do you feel bad?
Cause I have a dick and I know how hard
it is. You know how hard it is? No, sorry.
No Pun intended. He was in public. I know,
but he just looked like that kind of guy.
He did not talk to look if
he's a fucking like seriously.
I mean if he's fucking like you can't
control rubbing his dick and public.
It was entrapment dad,
like 12 fucking scantily clad
women and the whole thing to me,
I should question,
he was at a game.
There's cheerleaders there and how were
they dressed? Oh, so it's their fault.
How are they dressed?
Cheerleader is the way she leaves.
And always waitress that this,
why can't you guys ever be flattered
when a man flash and shit fucking woman
never just whipped her who
are out? Because I look so
good. No fucking tee shirt.
It would just fucking make my day long.
She stayed away from me. I mean, he was,
she was doing his own thing.
You know what's hilarious?
The way you bring in a public?
You know what?
I loved the way he had his arms
crossed. He was like, well,
I can't see what I'm doing.
That means no one else can get an idea.
Get a fucking the new technique,
and I haven't tried the overhand before
God across the crossover overhead.
That's like a Olympic level jerking
off through his pants. You know, look,
everybody you know you, that's how
you get caught. You know, you fucking,
you can't shoot you. He got greedy is
what happened. Do you know what I mean?
He thought he could. He, you
know, he thought he could do,
I was like fucking 20,000 people
staring right at them yet.
Yeah. But you know, okay, look what
I'm talking about. Those cheerleaders.
Why are they out there near?
Why are they really out there to
stir the crowd up to cheer more now?
They're not spreadsheets.
They dress him like fucking
like just shy of who is.
That's what they're out there for.
They got their cleavage,
they got their butt cheeks hanging out.
Everything's barely covered.
Everything's all shiny, glittery,
glittery and shit. You know?
Hey, what? What? What the fuck
was he supposed to do? You know,
not touch his dick in public.
That's what he was supposed to do there,
but for the grace of God go,
I really try to say that you would be
in a position where you would just be
jerking off through your pants
in like that. I have 300 shoes.
I've never stood next to 12 women all
dressed in the same sparkly outfit
touching their toes in front of me.
Wearing some very user friendly slacks,
actions, Laxmi Action slacks. They were,
and in art you're saying you
wouldn't be able to control yourself?
I would say half to touch.
If I have to take my my life savings,
if I have to take my life saving says
no way. I'm betting on black slacks.
I'm not, there's no way I'm
going to put it all on one thing.
I don't know what I would do if I had a
couple drinks in me. You know? Who knows?
Might do the old law. Who knows?
Who Know? Every guy's done that.
Don't watch your common blah.
Oh, absolutely. Now they have to.
At some point they did something. They
were in their car. They rubbed one out.
They did something. They weren't a porch.
Well, guys are always talking on a plane,
on a plane. They went to the bathroom and
just rubbed one out. The amount of men,
I'm just saying the amount of
fucking men have done it. Yeah.
You got to understand when weight
and when you eat. What's that?
Are you saying that you've gone to a plane
like a bathroom on a plane and jerked
off? I swear. No, I have not done that.
What are you going to do? I don't know.
Scold me. Yes. Gold's you,
Shane. I know. Listen guys,
I've talked to other guys, Shit that
they've done or whatever, you know, hey,
we've all done stuff we're not proud of.
You know,
didn't Jesus say he was not fucking
rubbed what out to a fucking cheerleader?
You fucking cast cast the front.
You know what I hate?
Is it that that's the worst
at that kid does. Okay.
Which is basically all he did was
completely humiliate himself. All right?
And his life is fucking over it. I mean,
isn't that enough? I feel bad for them.
I do.
Unless he's like really a pervert and
he's running around grabbing women and
he's ruining people's lives,
then yeah, then you know,
put the kid down like a rabid dog without
a doubt. But if his worst fucking,
you know, I love about it is
they say men can't multitask.
There was a man clearly
operating as a security person
while rubbing one out that is
multitasking and one hand free.
So I don't really feel like he was at
his full capacity as a security guard
while a lot of securities just presence,
just people seeing you,
seeing you with the, or taking your
hand. He had his gun in his hand.
I feel bad for them. Don't feel
bad. Just hear those sleigh bells.
Ring a link. Tink, tink tingling too.
He's like, you know a homeless child.
Come on and rub one up a fucking
cheerleader or to keep it rubbing.
Keep the rubber wild.
Everyone watches. Oh my God,
they're poor bastard. A tweet
that this person has Sunday, man.
I Dunno. Can you stay focused
here? Can I tell you my top?
Can I tell you my story today? I
went out my hair. I went into, oh,
you don't have to be here. What are
we watching on TV? Nia. It's the,
it's The Washington capitols first.
The Philadelphia. Oh wait, now I don't,
you know,
said chargers.
Philadelphia fucking fly fly is,
this is rivalry Wednesday. That's
weighing sadness. I can't get up.
I have my feet up and I'm pregnant
and I'm the size of a house.
That's why I'm here. No, you're not.
You'll go get an Igloo more than a house
that's you look like asshole.
Oh, just the shootout.
What do you think of the awe? That
was a nice movie. He had him too many,
skipped off his stick.
I don't like the flyer.
I don't like the gold numbers on that.
Why you'd fly.
He's got such a great uniform that
kind of fucks it up a little bit.
You know somebody's got to buy it.
You know that guy just paints his
room fucking orange and white. Oh,
biggest fair number. You know, you know
if you dedicate your whole bedroom,
you know painting it,
your team color,
there's no way you could judge that kid
on the charges because you definitely
wear slacks and you rub one out in public.
Oh sheet.
Just fuck you.
That was a fuck you.
I don't respect you as a goaltender. Did
he even do a move? He just stared at him.
I was like, this is going
in the net bitch. And that's
exactly what the fuck cap.
Look at this Jesus Christ.
Yeah. Dee Dee on it,
right? Yeah. Fred. Fuck you. That's one.
Nothing in overtime. Oh, sorry. Two, two.
All right, here comes another
flag comes down. He Dempsey.
I'll little handbill hot. Too many
fucking Moe's. See what he did.
Claude Euro I liked, I loved the
head fake and hockey. I mean,
it works in basketball and fucking
if you're a wide receiver, but he,
you're gliding and it just never seems to
work. Uh, he stayed home. He stayed home.
All right. No one wants to
listen to this shit. So anyways,
so I go to target today. You literally
just had your arm over your eyes.
Like it was the most torturous thing
ever to listen. I'm exhausted, you know,
I'm fucking tired. Exhausted. Yeah.
I have friends way fatter than you
and they're doing much more stuff.
I Dunno what you're complaining about.
I have some few friends that
have like morbidly obese. Okay.
And they're more active than you are?
I think you'd be.
Are they just dating life? Hmm. I Dunno.
It just dating means do they have
another human being and as a nice goal,
Holy Shit. Taking all their food.
We miss sucking all of their energy.
Huh?
Do they have that increasing their
blood flow and their water retention and
there, no, but they probably have a woman
in their life. Fucking Yammer. And Adam,
that was a goal.
I don't think I put the fucking number of,
I don't want to be a part of this podcast.
Oh you don't?
No I don't cause I don't like your
attitude right now. Oh okay. I'm sorry.
How about this?
You don't hear what you're doing right
now is one of the most special things
that has ever been done on the planet.
Granted most of the people on the planet,
we'll do it at some point cause more.
Most people are women,
you know in gas.
Don't like wearing rubbers.
Sorry. Um, all right,
so I go to target today was Jesus Christ.
Wade Simmons.
When you told me that earlier,
I just couldn't even imagine you
going into target on your own accord.
It just doesn't seem like something was
buying you a Christmas gift from target.
Yeah, from target. And I couldn't
walk and fine what I wanted.
Why are you buying Macra?
You know what?
Let me stop cause I'm
about to sound really.
You're going to sound like what you are.
Well I'm an asshole to twos.
The final score. I'm fucking old.
I can't see what, what's the,
the overtime score we have to
get our eyes examined this year.
I mean 2017 and we both have to
go to the optometrist. Listen,
I think we have enough
activities together. I already
went to the optometrist.
It's together. It's not an activity.
Then I also said I already got,
I got fucking four and I fly.
I got glasses so I can see the radio
channels and glass. I'd Glenstone.
I got the, I got the half moon things
where like I'm regular. I'm a freak.
I'm regular. I'm a freak. Bye Bye bye
focal. Yeah. I don't know what they are.
Yeah, they're fucking great. I've
never seen you in these glasses.
It's cause you won't fly with me.
You lie with me.
I'll take you over the ocean.
I did fly with you and we'll see some
people sitting on some surfboards as they
wait for a fucking wave.
When you fly with me,
I'll fly you wherever.
The Santa Monica Pier,
I entered the whole
snapchat story. It. Yeah,
but she won't go unless some
with an instructor of course.
Well that right then all that
does is motivate me. Goes,
you're a comedian. Yeah,
a pilot and you're a comedian.
That's like saying, I'm a comedian.
I don't have a license to
drive a car. No, it isn't.
What do you mean it's the same thing?
I'm not a professional driver.
I don't drive at the Indy 500 I
don't fly for American Airlines.
You get me in a Robinson 22 where the
old 44 then I'll take you for a fucking
ride legally.
Okay.
I don't know if I have enough hours
for 44 but the 22 the two seater.
Yeah. You can try this fucking
woman thing that you guys all do.
Did fuck that yanking on the
fucking range that you guys all do.
Anytime you see a guy doing something
new, you got to have that. Hmm. Well,
he thinks he fed her, but he'll always
shitting on our fucking hobbies.
That's what you guys do. I would love
for you to get a hobby. Excuse me.
You know what? I'm going to get
you. I'm going to get you a flight.
Listen to me when I speak.
I am the man in this relationship.
I'm going to get you a widow and kit.
I'm not shitting on your hobbies.
I'm just saying like I would feel more
secure with there is a person there who
is a professional flying with us.
Fair enough. That's so bad. It isn't.
It's fair enough. But there's this also
part of it. It, it did. It motivates me.
Motivates me. That's all. Okay.
Wow. All right. See you then. Okay,
well what does that, what do you want
me to do for me? You always say that.
What do you want from me? Hey,
what do you want for, you know,
I'm going to get you a
little woodwind on the kit.
I'm going to get you a fucking hobby.
Know,
know what my hobby is dealing with you.
Oh snap.
When we return near with
more fucking snappy answers,
just tell your target story. Now I'm
going to find you a hobby. What about,
what about, uh, what's that thing that
had happened to Bobby and ghost? You know?
Oh God. Oh. Tibo Marlow.
When Patrick Swayze sat on Whoopi.
Oh,
a pot plants.
Well,
I'll get it. I'll get it for you.
You can feel Patrick Swayze. No, no,
don't tell. Don't tell me. Don't tell me
I'm going to get it. It's one of those,
there's one a sick. Fuck
it. It's one of those boots.
One of those stupid fucking
songs is one of those songs.
Is it woman and read and
you're talking about what?
She's parts with me while singing the
soundtrack to another Patrick Swayze
movie. You've got near to Patrick
Swayze movies. Yeah. Reside there.
That's still pretty good.
I'm in the ballpark.
Patrick Swayze and made a lot of movies.
Um,
you're talking about when the night
no. Here's cool. No, he wasn't.
And there's a body by the train tracks and
stand by me. Was He in San by me? Yeah,
he played one of the main guys
with key for Sullivan. Hey,
you little shits and I'll fucking talk
about the dead body or I'll cut your
daddy rough. You're fucking freak.
Hey, I'm fat now Mary do it.
Model.
Oh yeah,
this is you describing everybody
I've done was Leonardo Dicaprio,
but it's a river Phoenix. That one's too
sad. So I'm not going to do that one.
And then the other guy, hey, I'm going
to fuck it. Then there's the other dude,
right? Who does the
Thriller Dance Still? Right?
Daddy, BB. Me
But Hulu Do, do, do, do, do, do, do, do.
It's fucking 2016 I'm still doing
when this stupid fuck a dance.
I feel like you're talking
about Corey Feldman.
If he wasn't not in stand by
me that he was was he was,
he was the dude with the fucked up here.
We wanted to fight with the glass.
Oh yeah. Yeah. I liked him.
So they would go originally you were
talking about goes and then you started
singing the song from dirty dancing.
Don't tell me cause I'm going to get it.
I'll get it by the end of the podcast.
You know what are my goals in
2017 I'm going to get a fake id.
I'm going to have fake id for all
those fucking times. I'm on the road.
I want to use a gym and they all can.
We need an ID and they want to
take a fucking copy of my life. No,
I had a fake ID is illegal.
Right? I'm going with,
my name's going to be frank Fallujah.
I like alliteration. Bill Burr, Frank
Falucia, right? Teddy pendegrass.
All right,
so I go and do I go into target,
right to buy you a gift that
evidently you, you're up above
that was going to get you a flan
off right next to the bicycles
targets so fucked up. It's like, what do
you guys want to be? I don't like target.
They like that person who just morphed
themselves into what they youth,
they think you want them to be
so they can be friends with you.
It's just like pick a fucking angle.
It's like you walk in,
you're looking at TVs in the
next to cereal. What the fuck is,
this is like a fucking yard
sale, but everything's, no, um,
all right, so I go into target and I'm
looking for your fucking shit and every,
you know what's funny about target is
everybody looks like they work there.
So you got to ask like nine fucking
people who work here and they get all
offended, but you look like you don't,
you don't find the clothes here.
Your ass all. If they're wearing a
red shirt, they work at target. Yeah,
but there's different levels.
It's like the military.
There's different kinds of red shirts
does the people with the Pete Carroll
dockers and then the red shirt
tucked in there like management.
Then there's the grumpy,
filthy people who got to like fucking
unload the trucks all day and they never
let them go home.
Then I'm going to answer shit and then
this sort of dumpy women walking around
like, I dunno. I Dunno
what they're thinking.
It's like they took a pot cookies and
every once in a while you meet that one
that's on the ball. Who's not going to
be there long scar that that was new.
Sorry.
That's a highlight.
That was a nice fucking wrap around goal.
Oh, you got to love the wrap around.
Oh, he saved it. He had saved that
fucking thing. Did he? That's a goal.
That's a goal. I would love to
review the flood completely.
Sleuths so like as I'm leaving,
I bought you a high end gift.
They're at target,
right?
I bet your floral apron with a
frozen burrito in the pocket and
I got to keep it in the
freezer until right before,
twice the night before Christmas
and all through the house.
Not a creature was stirring except for
this bald freckled fuck taken a frozen
burrito. I'm sticking it in the stocking
by the way. Underrated stockings,
stockings.
I don't know about you guys.
Like I know some people are like they
start with the stockings or that we always
end on the stocking and the stockings
always like the bump bump, a bomb, Bam.
Like you already got your cool gift.
Then you go over to the stocking and
it's like a, it's like a, you know,
a gift certificate to a book club and
you've got to sit there acting like,
oh yeah. Thank you. I get to read.
Awesome. What else is in
here? Oh, new socks. I mean,
who could use these gold toe? Oh,
you shouldn't have. Literally,
I would rather wear one stock and walking
down the street than a pair of gold
told socks just because
of what they represent.
There's a lot of blood in shame on
all those gold toed socks. You know,
DME hookers have laid on motel rooms.
And the last thing that
they saw with somebody,
bloody gold told sock
walking towards them so bad,
so bad during the holiday season,
silver bells leaving
your family going to get,
oh hooker,
the goose cools double life.
Serial killer.
Cops show up one day and you confess to
40 other killings and your wife says,
who the fuck are you?
What did I do with the last three decades?
And you stare at her with
no feeling behind your eyes.
Anybody got you? Go on this one.
They're Nini. You're egging me on here.
Like your dark holiday care off.
Cause I hate that song.
I hate silver bells.
It just goes on for,
it's like it's just song and a fucking
loop. There's no way. This is one song.
Oh, did fucking fish record
this fucking thing? It's like
20 minutes long. Then, um,
silver bells and I hate Jingle Bell Rock.
It's just such an attempt of like white
people trying to be here. You know,
we're going to, jazz is one, a Ginkgo,
managing demand. Jingle Bell Rock. Hey,
jingle bells.
It's that thing where you kind of just
shaking your head and your ass at the
same time. You know, as you're snapping
your fingers with your fucking loafers,
that's when somebody, you know, if
you're at a party and there's a piano,
when somebody knows how to play, they're
going to sing that at the holidays,
you know?
Oh yeah.
And then there's going to be the
undersexed fucking 20 year old,
20 years married chick with the red
wine teeth always start dancing.
And it's like, all right, all right,
let's get her outta here. Get a cow.
Caricom send her home.
I just don't know why they stay
together. Um, so I'm leaving target.
I'm leaving target and a,
it looks fucking confused.
He was getting interviewed here. Huh. Um,
so I'm leaving target
and as I'm walking out,
all of a sudden I just hear
this guy go on, get off me.
And I look over and there's two target
ladies there at the Pete Carroll level of
the target thing and a in a,
in a target guy.
Two women in a guy are just
fucking grabbing this dude
and they're dragging them
into like this windowless office and
the guys going, this isn't legal.
And they just dragging them
in and everybody's just
watching like what the fuck?
And then like the door starts to close
and then it opens your fucking clothes as
again and then another.
And then they finally got him to calm
down and they closed the door and this
older manager just closed
the door and he did that.
You know it's smile you do when you
walk by a stranger because you're hoping
they don't have an ax. You know that
little purse lip. We kind of do.
You lift your eyebrows up. He kind of did
that like well that's the end of that.
And it's like that's an
American citizen in there, sir.
What the fuck just happened?
But nobody said anything cause its target,
you just don't expect it.
So I said to the lady next to me,
I go, did he steal something?
She goes, no, I don't think so.
And then somebody else goes,
I think he's autistic.
And he was acting a little weird.
Drag them into this by
me. The back room. Yeah.
I don't think that that's makes sense. It
doesn't make sense. Does it make sense?
But I feel like why would they take
it upon themselves to drag him away?
Why wouldn't they call the police?
I know it looked like that Scientology
show that you're watching that the stuff
that they do to people, except
it was a target. You know?
I wonder if one of those people
were going to do a two TV show,
exposing target and what?
What really goes on there?
They probably wanted him to work
all three shifts on Christmas.
He said no, they just dragged them in
there. They don't fuck around at target.
I guess not.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Did that guy just score
from the other side of the,
I'm just watching the highlights.
That's pathetic. And that was it.
And that was the end of a,
and then I just sort of walked out and
I have to admit when he rolls of paper
towel. Yes. Merry Christmas Neal.
I'm expecting a lot of big tears
next year. Big Tears. Big Tears.
It's been someone who was,
I should probably read some
advertising here. I'm like,
oh, this is fucking, what a great
night we got the fire going. Oh,
tell them how much I like Eggnog.
A lot of people don't like Eggnog.
I like you love Eggnog. I
love now too. Well what it is,
this was always shy about
it cause I was like, yeah,
I don't know if it's my thing,
but it's delicious. Yeah,
but people pour you a giant fucking glass
of it. It's, it's like in a, it's a, uh,
like a, what are they not an aphrodisiac?
What'd they say? What's that shit?
You're drinking Italy after
year after year. That's what
it is. But with did Jeff.
Steve, that's it. Yeah.
Digestive. You have a big meal.
You sip on a little egg. Nog
It's like mountain ice cream.
And I like it.
Wait, hold up. The podcast where
I type in my fucking park, Jess,
it tastes like Malkin melted ice cream.
And I like it.
I know,
I'm sorry,
but can I spelled stocking that look
right to me now when I look back and I'll
be the dumbest person
ever. S T, O, l, K, I,
n stocking stuffers,
underrated.
Let's see, I wrote some ideas. Silver
Bells, kid jerking off Christmas break.
Stoeckle Stouffer's underrated. Oh, oh,
this is the one I wanted
to talk about when I was,
I went into best buy afterwards.
Oh,
I was hitting all the corporations
and I'm standing in line,
this pathetic line of fucking people just
waiting till the last minute to shop.
We're all fucking hate in
life and I'm still, you know,
and you going through like the Disney
world line where you got to fucking go all
the way back and forth, back and
forth. So I'm standing, I'm final.
The last rung and this guy walks up
to stand in line behind 18 people.
You know what his tee shirt said?
Wa do epic Shit.
First of all, what kind of a fucking
adult? Where's that stupid tee shirt?
Why would you wear it? Going to, to
stand in line at best buy, right.
That's a new fucking thing where people
try to motivate people with their
workout videos and shits, like get the,
you know, like they're doing it for you.
Like, what am I supposed, when I see
that guy with that t shirt like, wow,
that guy's doing epic shit and he's
standing in line at best buy. No,
he's taking a break.
He just,
he was doing that point break
shit earlier up in Santa Monica.
Like you got helicoptered out.
Just some sort of fucking a
burning man out in the ocean.
Whatever they do when they know
big waves coming, you know,
everybody else runs for cover. They
go, we got to go right out at it, man.
Another Patrick Swayze movie. Yes
it is. I saw the remake of it.
I enjoyed it, you know. Oh
yeah. Was it about surfing?
It's not about anything. It's
like fast and furious. It's,
it's just about fucking fast.
And fairies is about the cars.
A point break is about, you know, the
stunt man and everybody do, you know,
in the flying squirrel suits
and riding waves and shit,
that's all it's about, you know?
Yeah. I've never seen that movie.
Possibly hot women with mysterious
attitudes who can't walk a straight line
without crossing one foot
in front of the other.
They're always in some rainy alley.
Possibly. It went, it was
mysterious. Added to. Yeah.
They always fuck under
these fire escapes and Shit.
It's the same fudges alley,
whatever that is.
It's like in every fits in
every fucking movie. Ah, hell
no. When a fog to next
to this fucking dumpster.
Oh,
uh,
so rad when you bend me over. No. Um,
yeah.
They fucking the same alley where that
dude from brothers got Scott his throat
cut in that fucking,
that movie where the guy who was always
screaming yeah. Goes everyone. No,
not everyone.
He goes up.
Remember that to Sean Penn?
No,
the guy who plays a commissioner
Gordon Gary Oldman. Okay.
He was in a, but it was based on
you talking about the professional.
It was just when he goes, no, no,
no. It's not that one I fucked up.
It's the one that was, it was based
on that book. The westies, I dunno.
Uh, who's Ed Harris was
fucking great in it. And uh,
this was before that dude did fucking
boogie nights. He's on, he's on,
he's on a adult swim. He's in like in
every fucking movie he played chest,
Roswell, bronzy railing, John C. Reilly,
when he gets his throat slit days.
Christ.
So low long fucking way to go.
That's the same fucking alley where all
those women get fucked in all those,
those movies, you know.
Okay. All right. What was,
what is this song when they make the,
make the pot
unchained melody.
Whoa.
Oh, they played that song.
Whether I'm making a pot.
No wonder I know fucking could get
through that movie. Ma. Darlene.
I just felt your head going down on my
shoulder while the movie's on. Just ugh.
I hate when women do that.
I always hate it when I was on a date.
And you deliberately took him to some
fucking Schmaltzy shit cause you knew they
wanted to see it and then it comes that
stupid fucking moment in the movie,
whatever. What's decided song go. It's
just sing the song. Well I tell you what
Manda right.
And then you feel it.
Stupid head starts going under
your shoulder and you know,
you're kind of excited cause
she's becoming intimate.
But there's another party that
just wants to fucking do what?
Tido me did the off Samuelson when
they were standing in front of the net.
All right.
That's it.
So slowly we're baking fun pot
making you don't tip it over.
I knew it was one of those things wasn't
will Ferrel's father and that band and
what van? The righteous brothers.
Is that the righteous brothers? Yes.
Are the righteous brothers
white? Yes. Oh, Jesus Christ.
Okay. I didn't know that. All right.
The white shirt, the white, just
the righteous brothers are white. I
didn't realize that. Okay. All right.
I need to read. I need to read some. Uh,
let's read some advertising while I
sing while you sing Christmas carols.
All right. Oh, you know,
zip and re and crew and turn.
Are you hire ring?
Did you know where to fucking pose your
most favorite job up a post your giants?
Okay.
Are you hiring?
Are you,
do you know where to post your job
to find the best candidates? You,
it's funny your neighbors probably
think I'm yelling at you. God dammit.
Goddammit was my dinner.
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates. Man.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you know,
in the future you gonna have to have
like do your fucking ad and like those
virtual reality glasses that people like,
oh wow, fucking hate that commercial.
If it's old people acting like they're
blown away, you find a fucking war.
Act like it.
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your job on all the top
job sites and now you can with old zip
[inaudible] dot com you can post
your job to 100 plus job sites,
including social media networks like
Facebook and Twitter, all with a single,
oh, isn't that genius?
Everybody's on that shit.
Can we get a little more fucking DP,
a zip recruiter?
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your qualified
candidates roll in to Ziprecruiter's.
Easy to use interface, no juggling
emails or calls to your office.
Quickly screen the candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
Find out today why zip
has been used by over 1 million businesses
and right now my listeners can post
their jobs on ZipRecruiter for free by
going to ziprecruiter.com/bird that's
ziprecruiter.com/bird one more time.
That's it.
[inaudible] dot com slash burb all right,
distilled genes,
Dstl d.
All right. Uh, okay.
The problem with jeans is that the really
good parents cost two and 300 get the
fuck outta here is $300 for jeans.
What are you ric flair easily.
And the bargain brands just fall apart
or look terrible. That's dad jeans.
Distilled.
Pronounced distilled has revolutionized
the fashion industry by creating
timeless luxury grade denim.
So you get genes that would cost you
hundreds of dollars starting at 65 bucks.
How do they do it? By refusing to work
with it. The Guy, I know how they do it,
they scream at the kids in the sweatshop.
Make a faster by refusing to work with
department stores and retail middlemen.
There's no markup, no bullshit, just
great jeans at an unbelievable price.
Just go to distill gene stock out,
distill.com d s t l d
um, spelled Dstl d.com. Find
the perfect pair with the,
the perfect fit. That's Delta
Sierra, tango, Lima Delta,
little pilot shit there. And Yeah,
you'll fly with me now, won't you?
They'll ship them to you for
free and guarantee the fit or uh,
we'll send you a new pair till
they are perfect. Alright,
see why all the a list celebrities have
been spotted in magazines like vogue, Gq,
wearing distilled jeans,
even c list celebrities like me.
Look at that a little self deprecation.
I've got a pair of the raw denim
and that the fit as a mate you want,
I haven't gotten,
I did get them.
You dig and you said they look good and
look great on you. Yeah, no bull said.
Okay. All right. Well,
65 bucks people you could
look like a bald red head.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bird right now and get $10 off your first
pair. That's DSTL. d.com/birth
for $10 off right now.
Five letters. Everybody. D
as in Dick, s as in shaft,
t like taint l like, ah, Jesus.
What's that lumbar? What's the thing
in your vagina that begins with an Elf?
Dbs. Lavia there you go.
I never took a health
plan of the falls. I know how
to, um, I didn't want to say,
I didn't want to say, listen, I
know what to do with it. Okay.
How did I like Helix,
Helix and to
God, I cannot believe you haven't
learned how to pronounce this word yet.
Shut up. You're unique. You're, oh, I like
how they just butter you up right here.
Helix hate Nia. I don't know
if I ever told you this. What?
You're unique. You don't. You are. You
don't walk like everyone else, right?
Talk Lock. This sounds like a drill
sergeant. Good. I'll teach you to walk.
But everyone else talk like everyone
shoot shit or like anyone else.
So why is your mattress
one size fits all well,
because there's an average height of
human beings. They're mass produced.
It's a cost effective thick.
All right?
Because it truly customized mattress
will cost you five to 10,000 bucks right
now. Go to helix, sleep.com.
Answer a few simple questions
and they'll run a three d book.
Just read it. It was just funny.
The questions they're gonna ask you.
You know you actually have a unique body.
You don't have the ball.
Can you balls hang up and over your leg?
Okay,
this bed mattress is going to
have to be a little wider. A,
they run a three D biomechanical model
of your body through the proprietary
algorithm they develop with the help of
the world's leading era Gomix and bio
mechanics. This is the fucking
Illuminati mapping your whole body.
It is. Words are too big for you, Huh?
Yeah, they are. What does era era go?
Nomics what does that mean?
Ergonomics.
Isn't that like how you have a chair
that's air denomic nominally correct.
Like it's,
it's good for your back.
Like it's supports all your back and like
the proper way all your vertebrae and
stuff.
Isn't that what it means?
What is biomechanics
mean? Oh, I have no idea.
I mean mechanics are
mechanics. Bio, it's like biology.
So the mechanics of the body, Ooh,
that's probably what it means. I'm like,
you sound like the fifth family member
on family feud when all the good answers
are gone and you just say
some dumb shit and like, hey,
you're right.
Show me mechanics at works in Bios.
Actually the biomechanics, they both
sounded right to me, but I'm a morning.
He looks, customers report a 30%
improvement in overall sleep quality.
How do you know you were asleep? Um, and
for couples, they customize each matches.
Each side of the mattress though,
you're going to talk about
fucking your magister arrived.
Or if a couple of lady you're
bang on this fucking thing.
I'm common 30% faster.
Your mattress arrives at your door and
about speaking of egg Nog in a bottle a
week, hey, come on. And
shipping is 100% free.
That's why everyone from Gq magazine to
Forbes are all talking about he likes
sleep. All right? Go to Hilo. How
do you get it? That's the key.
This is what you want, okay? You
have a hundred nights to try it out.
And if you don't love it,
they'll pick it up for free. And
it's always say they sharpen
those breaking bad fucking
suits with those giant
like you know when you're
going to catch an alligator,
except it's like a mattress thing, right?
And it's 100% refund, no questions asked.
Go to, he looked sleek.com/burn and
get $50 off your order and that's,
he likes sleep.com/burr he likes
sleep.com/our last one everybody.
And then we're going to be
rocking around the Christmas tree.
How fucking fat use ice. I
loaded that bitch up. Alright.
Siki you know I went to target
Nia and I fucking threw it out.
Seeking buying tickets online for
sports and concerts has been a confusing
process for a long time.
It's always been hard to find the best
deal for that game or show you want to go
to and none of those older
tickets sites want to change that.
But seek is different.
They've come along and created an amazing
APP and website that makes it easier
than ever for fans to
buy and sell tickets.
Everything about Siki cause designed to
make life easier for sports and music
fans.
Siki does all the price comparisons for
you by searching multiple tickets sites
and ensuring that you get
the best possible deal.
Seek does all the work and
you save time and money.
Best of all my listeners get a $20
rebate off their first SeatGeek purchase.
Uh, to get your $20 rebate rebate
on tickets, download the Sikh App,
go to the settings tab and click add
a promo code. Enter Promo Code Burr,
seek people, send you $20 after you've
made your first ticket purchase.
Download the seat Geek App and
enter Promo Code Bird today. So Nia,
yes, this is one of my favorite times
of year because I get to, you know,
hang at home for once,
you know,
sit by the fire and I got all the sports
packages [inaudible] asked me if I got
the NHL Center ice package. I yes, I do.
Ask me if I got the NBA hardcore,
whatever the fuck they call it of Cory.
I've got that toe
and asked me if I got an NFL
Sunday ticket. Nfl. Yes I do.
I got all three so I can watch my
patriots, my Celtics, and my Bruins.
And what I've noticed with the
Celtics and the Bruins. Okay.
If the Celtics Luiz Isaiah Thomas,
it's fucking over.
They lose,
like they lost like fucking three in a
row and he comes back and all of a sudden
when that Memphis game
was fucking incredible,
but my DVR shut off with like five seconds
to going over time. I think we want.
Um, and then the Bruins,
if Charlie goes down,
like that's been the thing the whole
time though. But, um, um, you know what?
I've been bitching about Michael Carneal.
When you rebuild a team,
it takes at least two to three seasons.
So we'll see which direction he's going
in. I don't know. I don't fucking know.
But it's been tough to watch him
this year cause I love him and, uh,
and I loved a lot of the guys they got
rid of and it's hard watching them on
other teams doing fucking great,
you know,
I know there's a salary
cap and all that shit.
I'm going to quit fucking
pitching. Um, so anyways,
I guess that's the podcast here
and you're going to fall asleep.
I know. Oh Jesus. Well, you know what?
I'm glad I knocked this thing
out before you fell asleep. Um,
everybody has no energy. It's all
right. Everybody have a merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas. Happy Hanukkah.
Happy Kwanzaa. Happy holidays.
Jewish people. I help you have
the best fucking Chinese food.
That sounds great though.
Not spending all that fucking cash.
You just have Chinese food. Go to a
fucking movie. A great, does that sound?
That sounds great. I liked that. I
think we ought to add that celebration
on the 26th right. We'll do
that. Merry Christmas everybody.
That's it. Happy New Year. I'll
talk to you on Monday anyways,
but I hope you guys all have a great,
happy,
safe one and all that stuff and I thank
you for everybody who's been listening
in all year. Uh, it is a privilege to
do this. All right. Go Fuck Yourself.
Get counts and I'll talk to you on Monday.
Okay,
please.
You
can,
as long as
you can sit around and wait for the phone
waiting.
Who's someone you
sit around and wonder what to mom?
Ooh.
Hmm.
[inaudible]
uh,
happy holidays.
It's the Monday morning podcast.
How did you like that little second
grade fucking recital? That was horrible.
I thought it was going to
get through it in one take.
I should have been asked and I shouldn't.
That's like the kind of guitar playing,
you hear it,
a benefit and whatever the benefit is,
like whatever the disease it's for.
Like if that guitar playing,
like I would have the disease that you
guys were raising money for and then in
the end they wheeled me out
and they'd be like, Hey,
here's a guy who has the disease that
we're trying to stop and now he's going to
play the guitar for you.
That's how I just played the guitar.
But I don't give a fuck.
You know,
I can't help it know I can't help it.
If from fucking,
not even going to say multitalented,
it's not the word.
What's the reverse of
multi one dimensional?
I can't help it if I'm a one trick pony.
Anyways,
this is the Monday morning
podcast for the, uh, uh,
the week of Christmas,
which is why I had my little recital.
Um, you know what's
hilarious is last year, um,
besides my guitar playing, um,
it was last year I took off.
I didn't do a podcast on the week of
Christmas or the week of new years and
everyone thought it was, cause I, you
know, I was taking a vacation or whatever.
But the reality is is is because I was
traveling and holiday travel sucks.
So as many of you know, this year I
was like, you know what? Fuck this.
Fuck everybody.
I'm not going home for the holidays
because I'm not dealing with that planes,
trains and automobiles shit.
And I got to tell you, man,
it's the smartest
goddamn thing I ever did.
I don't know what that says about me,
but I'm not spending it with my family
and I am absolutely fucking elated.
You know,
I'm not saying I don't like my family,
I'm just saying I don't need to go see
them when everyone else is going to go
see their family because uh,
cause it sucks.
I had a buddy of mine see,
you know,
trying to fly back east with
all this snow and all this shit.
He's down in Orange County calling me up.
That same situation I was in last year.
Do you believe it would plea?
Go to two old blue,
blue, blue, blue, blue. And
I was like, thank God, thank
God I made the right choice.
Fucking excited. I got a
Christmas tree, I got stockings,
I got a Ukulele. I mean, what, what, what,
what do you need with Morty
of fucking neat? I don't know.
Some inner peace maybe, but I don't
want to get greedy. Um, I'm, I'm,
I'm two inches away from
getting a dog. People, I know,
I've said it for about
two years on this podcast,
even though I've only been doing them for
a little over a year, I'm freaking out.
I'm terrified to get a dog because
I'm like, you know, what, if, uh,
what if I want to take off for a
couple of days? I mean, I don't,
I've never had to take care of
anything in my life, you know, and uh,
never been at a movie going, Oh my God,
what if taking a shit in my living room?
You know,
I don't want to be thinking that,
especially at this time of year when
there's all these great movies are out,
you know, speaking of which, um,
somebody sent me a great email and said,
we'll get back to the dog thing.
I want to get a dog.
And if I get a dog and getting a fucking
bulldog and I'm going to a breeder,
I know a lot of people. I'm going to,
God, you should rescue a dog. You know,
I don't have time for you. You
understand me? That's your cause.
You go down there and you, you, you
get all those, you get all those dogs,
you go down and you get them that I've
already learned how to fetch and they're
just completely over everything.
Nothing's exciting anymore.
You know what I mean?
I mean,
why don't I just pick up a fucking
divorce waitress with three kids that hate
her, you know, and,
and bring that into my life and I'll
just surround myself with people who are
just fucking over everything.
You know?
Sometimes I just really say stupid
shit. I don't, I don't feel any of that.
You know what,
I went down to the shelter.
I wanted to rescue all the dogs and
I don't fucking know. I don't know.
I'm talking about, I'm just
trying to kill time. People has,
I'm trying to find the thing
about the movie reviews. Yeah.
Somebody send me an email and they said,
hey bill,
I haven't heard movie reviews in a while.
Now some of my longtime
listeners of the podcast,
remember we stopped people
write in because I went and
I saw a shitty movie one
time and I was pissed.
You know,
I lost my 10 bucks or whatever
the fuck they're charging now. Um,
so people started, you know,
thrown in that 2 cents. So
here's some movie reviews.
This guy said punisher war zone
and he gives it three stars.
Punisher warzone what the fuck is that?
Um,
evidently he says there's tons of
over the top violence and shooting.
It doesn't try to be realistic at all.
Like the last one,
the first punisher warzone tried to be
real. That's funny with that name. Uh,
the story was very basic
with no real twist. You know
what? I can appreciate that.
Okay. So it's like commando.
They fucked with them.
He gotten his Bronco and he kicks
ass and then he wins. I like it.
I'm going to, I'm, you know
what, I'm not going to go see it,
but I will watch it on. Um, that'll
be the new part of the movie reviews.
I'll let you know if I'm going to
see it. I'm going to see that. Okay.
You guys fulfilled.
Now does this make any holidays?
I'm going to go see punish
awards. No, no. I'm gonna,
I'm gonna sit on my fucking huge
couch and I'm going to watch it. Um,
the next review he did, the day the earth
stood still, he gave it three stars.
Sky's very, uh, it's very
liberal with the stars here.
Some people who were in the theater
with me were pissed at it when it ended,
but it's a remake and I
knew it was going to happen.
It isn't really supposed to be an over
the top independence day blockbuster.
It's more story oriented.
And there was some surprise stars
that I didn't know were in it.
Like so and so and so and so.
Well, thanks for ruining it for me.
And I give a fuck.
I'm not really into those cameos.
I hate when people get
excited about cameos.
Tom Cruise Kid, I had no
idea he was in it. Yeah.
What are the more surprising if like
one of your relatives walked in?
It's not like Tom Cruise isn't an actor.
You know,
it's not like he hasn't been
doing movies for 25 years.
I can't believe that actor all of a sudden
showed up in a movie and was acting.
I W I was really blown away.
Um, oh, I'm in a pissy mood.
Um, let's see. Oh, this is the two
movies I saw this weekend. I saw a,
the wrestler with Mickey Rourke,
which was fucking awesome.
And uh, any, if you're a fan of wrestling,
if you're a fan of Mickey Rourke,
you got to go see it. He's
fucking great. And it, and uh,
they really capture the
more ronic wrestling fan,
which I was perfectly.
And then I also saw that movie milk
starring Sean Penn as Harvey Milk.
And I got to admit,
I was shying away from that movie.
I wanted to go see it because
I love Sean Penn, but every,
a male friend of mine was
saying, I was like, yeah,
I want to go see that movie milk. Uh,
did you see it? And they'd be like, yeah,
I saw it, but I just to warn
ya, lot of male kissing,
which is not a,
uh,
that's not a selling point with
a lot of guys, myself included.
And I was sitting there going, but I
got to go see it. It's Sean Penn and um,
I don't know, there wasn't a
lot of kissing, but it, it,
after awhile you sort of get used to it,
which I don't know if that's a good thing.
I'm really on the fence about that.
I don't know what the fuck. You
know what I mean? It's weird.
If I was on like a youporn or to bait
and I was watching two guys kissing,
people will be looking at me like, dude,
what the fuck is wrong with you? You know,
what's your deal? You got something to
tell me. I can't just sit there. We, oh,
it's just a porno. You
know, this is a, you know,
this is the, then he go see a movie
and then all of a sudden it's okay,
this is art. This is art. I don't
know. It wasn't that big a deal.
It wasn't an Sean Penn was fucking
unreal and uh, it was an amazing,
it's an amazing movie with a lot of
male kissing. You know, I got to met,
that's the first time I've seen an amazing
movie that had a lot of male kissing.
I think they started a whole
new genre. Um, so I don't know.
You know what I'm,
because I have OCD,
I plan on seeing like fucking
nine more movies this week.
There's some mob movie I wanted to go see.
What the fuck was the name of that.
I'm going to rise here.
This is Mrs Typical me.
Like I haven't seen a movie
in about eight months.
And then I go and I see one movie. Then
I'm like, I'm going to go see everything.
It's like, I don't understand why I
can't. This is why I don't do drugs.
I'm going to go see a Gamora, g. O,
m. O, r, r, a. H.
Evidently it's a mob movie
cause I got to wash off that,
that male kissing to prove to myself in
a cinematic way that I'm still a man.
Um,
I'm going to go see this movie.
Evidently it's a mob movie that kind of
takes away all the Glam of being in the
mom. You know what I mean? I
mean, when you watch Goodfellas,
you don't really think like, wow,
thank God I never joined the Mafia.
You know, you, you, you know,
you want the cars. I don't know.
You want the fucking, I dunno. I
can't say the women, the women,
pretty fucking nasty and good fellas.
The,
you know what it was that girl with a
cold sore just ruins it for every woman in
that.
Then I just think they all have herpes
and then it just fucking ends it for me.
Can I just messed this up here?
Sorry guys.
Is this going to be another slow podcast?
Fuck yourselves. I'm on vacation.
All right, let's get to the
podcast questions, Sally.
Um, if you new to my podcast,
people send me podcast questions every
single week and I try and answer them,
add to the best of my ability.
Um, so here we go. Podcasts,
podcasts came and talk. Question
number one. Uh, Bill, uh,
I have a question for you as
a well-informed hockey fan.
What are your thoughts on the Chicago
Blackhawks chances this season? Um,
also what the fuck? Why the fuck
did the Bruins get rid of Thornton?
Uh, what did they get rid of? Thorton.
Cause they didn't feel like they key
could lead them deep into the playoffs.
He played on a Bruins teams and that
people felt they didn't have any heart and
cause he was the big paid guy. They
blamed him, which was a, wasn't fair.
All I know is we didn't get shit from,
we didn't get shit for the guy.
How do I think the Blackhawks are going
to do this year? A transition year.
They're not going to do shit.
Speaking of that,
let's talk about the New York Yankees
and them throwing their fucking wallet's
around. Huh? It's Monday and I've
heard that. I haven't watched ESPN yet,
but I heard they had this
close to signing Manny Ramirez.
So they signed cc Sabathia that
white dude from Toronto, the pitcher.
And uh, I dunno, I fucking
love every, as a red sox fan,
I'm loving every second of it.
That's exactly right.
Go ahead and do the exact same fucking
thing. It's like watching an alcoholic,
just making the same fucking mistakes
over and over and over again thinking that
you're going to get a different result.
You've had a Rod Cheetah and Gian
be just in your fucking in field
for the last five years or whatever.
Or at least Jeter in Jambi,
that Combo you had for seven years. You
haven't done shit. You haven't won shit.
And Randy Johnson with those three
guys behind them. Plus, I mean,
look at the look at the list to
start when the Yankees were the shit,
they got it from their farm team,
I don't know.
And then they would pick up these fucking
nerds along the way. Paul O'Neill,
who knew Lee was great. Scott
Parotias, chuck Knoblauch, you know,
they just don't know.
I don't know what they're doing.
They always go out and they get the
fucking big swinging Dick and then you've
got, you got too much swinging
dick in your clubhouse house,
you're not going to win. You can't.
If it was just that fucking easy,
the Yankees would win it every year.
Wasn't they look a little bit over,
not the fucking the red sox
try doing that one year.
I remember that year we got a Eric gynae.
That guy almost fucked up our whole
season last year we got that big bloated
steroid jackass. Remember that?
And we had already added a,
what's his face there in right field?
I swear to God the second season as,
I can't even remember anybody's name.
I was going to say Trot Nixon know the
new guy a fucking uh, junior Felix.
What the fuck is his name out there?
The guy everybody says is a cunt and he
doesn't do well during the season and
then he shows up. He shows
up in October. That guy,
I thought that's the red sox
last year were very, uh, 2007.
We're teetering on that
Yankee esque sort of thing,
but they still had like four or five guys
from their, uh, from their farm team.
I don't understand what the Yankees are
doing, but I hope they keep doing it.
I hope to do it.
I hope they have a fucking $500 million
team and they get bounced out in the
first round.
That's going to be fucking a list of my
favorite part of the year in baseball is
when they pan down that Yankee dugout
and you just see one fucking zillionaire
after one hall of Famer after another,
just fucking sitting there
with that look on their face.
And I got Jesus Christ.
It looks like we're going home
early again this year. I don't know.
Fucking though, you know, I don't know.
But I will say this many
is worth the money and uh,
he's definitely worth the fucking money.
Cc Sabathia only because he's 26,
but I gotta tell you, man, that
guy is built like Bartolo Cologne.
All right.
And you can't walk around with that
sack of potatoes hanging right over your
dick for too long before you
started having lower back pain.
You can't pitch anymore.
It's like broads with big tits.
They can ride it out until like 35 37 and
after a while they're like, listen man,
I, I can't go today. I
just can't do it. You know,
I'm fucking my arm shot and it's the
end of their career and they get their
titties reduced.
So cc Sabathia it needs to
stop going to the fucking,
what the fuck would he go
when it's cc Sabathia see an olive
garden guy. He's got the money though.
I Dunno what he's doing.
He looks like he just has like one
of those MTV cribs refrigerators.
You know what I mean? When
they got like, you know,
they got like a case of fucking Coca
Cola and every bag of fucking junk food.
You know what I'm convinced
fat people eat at night.
That's where they get fat because if
you hang out with a fat person, you,
you know,
you hang out with them all day long.
They just saw eating
when you eat and yeah,
maybe they'll get an extra fucking
cheeseburger at Mcdonald's,
but they don't go anything crazy.
I think it's at night, at night,
that's when they get up and they just
start going through the cupboards and they
just,
they just start throwing the fuck down.
I think that's what cc Sabathia is going
to be doing on the road with any luck.
Um, I dunno. What the fuck
you gotta do. Um, what else?
I'm gonna keep talking about sports.
I think I'm going to piss off everybody.
At least half in New York.
He got so many fucking teams met fans.
Probably enjoyed that. What about those
jets? Huh? Can you fucking believe it?
They choked.
It gets the Goddamn Seahawks and they're
the patriots right in the thick of it.
And I know what you're going to say. You
can say, Bill, you're fucking bandwagon.
Well, that's bullshit because I got
a bet with the shred and Reagan show,
which I'm going to fuck.
Fuck it in columns. Too late.
The shred and Reagan show out in Buffalo,
New York.
I bet them the fucking week
when Tom Brady went down,
Reagan was talking all this shit
and I hope he's listening to this.
He was talking all this shit.
Bill Bella, check is a punk.
He's never one without a superstar
quarterback, Yada, Yada, Yada.
All this fucking crap. And I said,
let me tell you something, Reagan,
let me tell you something.
And Reagan not only are the
Patriots can have a winning season,
they are going to fucking
win the division. I called
that after Brady went down,
called it. I bet him 50 bucks, if I
lose, I own 50 bucks. But if I win,
Reagan has to read an uh,
an on air apology to bill
Belicheck that I get to write.
It's going to be great.
Now he negotiated it down to only
six sentences. It can only be,
the apology can only
be six sentences long,
but he's not familiar with
my ability with conjunctions.
Alright,
that fucking thing is going to be a page
and a half of what a brilliant coach
bill check is there. Those guys on
ESPN was saying that shit. You know,
he's never worn with Dota superstar
quarterback and neither did Vince Lombardi
needed a chuck Noll needed at Tom
Landry. Neither did Bill Walsh. Did.
Those guys all suck.
Joe Gibbs.
Joe Gibbs never really had
a superstar quarterback.
Doug Williams was a superstar who
just played for the Buccaneers.
You know what I mean? So
maybe he did, but he had what?
Mark Repin and Joe Fat.
Joe Theismann was on the fence.
It was like a Apollo Neal level guy. I
didn't, what the fuck I'm talking about?
All I know is next week, this is what
this is what I love about this situation.
Next week is New York can actually help
Boston have a great fucking new years.
If they can beat the shit out of the
dolphins, if they can show up, huh?
Your punk ass team will show up and when
a Goddamn game going out to Seattle and
lose, and you guys ought to be ashamed
of yourselves, why am I picking on jets?
Fans actually feel bad for you guys if
you didn't have man genie manned Genio
like, all right. He drove the
getaway car all those fucking years.
And then he read it out. Bill Belicheck.
Ooh, look, he's robbing a bank. Dude.
You're driving the car. Shut
the fuck up. Fucking baby.
All right.
Am I even doing questions at this point?
I'm just talking shit about sports.
How about those Bruins?
How about those Celtics? Huh? I
didn't need to go out for Christmas.
The fucking Boston teams
of bringing it home for me.
It got the NHL package.
I'm only watched the first period
of the Saint Louis Blues game.
Don't ruin it for me. Don't be a spoiler.
All right, question number two, Bill.
What do you think of MTV switched?
Sweet. Jesus Christ. I can read out loud.
I'm fucking Moron, Bill. Let's go slope.
What do you think of MTVs sweet 16 show
and part two. What did you do
for your sweet 16? All right.
What do I think of the sweet 16
show? A it makes me angry. Um,
I try to keep my mind that there
are only 16, but I just really,
I don't like dumb cons,
you know,
I don't like them when I'm walking down
the street and I'm certainly not going
to watch your show about it. So,
uh, that's how I feel about that.
And what did I do for my sweet 16?
I went down to the DMV and I got my,
my learner's permit. That's what I
did was always a big deal for me.
Learning how to drive and uh,
what did I do?
I have no idea. I have no fucking
night. I don't remember that Shit.
It's fucking 24 years
ago. Uh, number three.
I like how I took that
question and literally like,
what did you do for your sweet 16? You
know, I guess I was supposed to be like,
well, I put ribbons in my hair. I
literally took it like straight up.
Like I have no idea what I did.
That was 24 years ago. Well,
thanks for sucking all the comedy out of
that question, Bill. Sorry about that.
Whoever wrote that, he
sent me up. Beautiful.
You loved it over the net and I took a
big swing and a miss kind of like a rod
in October. Oh, he's
killing the Yankees. I, Nah,
there's somebody right now who already
has a fucking Manny Ramirez poster
hanging over his bed,
fucking Boston to Townsel fucking lame
everything and closes the Focalin tool.
New Folk morning. What? The fork? Yeah.
We also go out at seven 30 at
night and we start drinking.
You fucking jackass is still putting
on Cologne at 1130 at night. All right,
so fuck you and your city.
That open is open all night.
What a crock of shit that was.
You know what?
I'm first moved to New York another time
I took it literally like when they said
New York, the city that never
sleeps, it's open all night long.
I thought that meant everything.
Like banks, hardware stores,
you know what I mean?
Like I go, I could buy a lamp
at like three 30 in the morning,
but no, it does. It does shut down
and people do go to sleep and,
but their bars to stay up until four
in the morning. Other than that,
I fucked that. It's the greatest
Goddamn city. It's our Paris.
I'm not even gonna lie. It's
fucking awesome. I love it.
But I really don't like their sports
teams. Um, okay. If you didn't notice,
all right,
why don't you get back to the questions
and stop making it so fucking personal
with one city.
There's other cities listening and other
countries hello to all the people in
England that I've been getting
questions from lately. Um,
I'm going to be over that next year. You
mother fuckers. Um, so, uh, you know,
I dunno, whatever it is you do
to get prepared for comedy shows.
What do you do in English? Do you guys
really eat pork chops for breakfast?
Actually watch that show. You
are what you eat. You know,
which made me feel a lot better about how
auto shaped this country is when I saw
all those people over there. Like,
you know, w what do you start?
Do I start my day?
I have like I have a couple of fry
ups and for you Americans listening,
a fry up is rather than just
making an egg over easy, you know,
cooking it in butter, fried
frying an egg, they actually,
from what I gather from the
footage, because it's not
like they have the recipe,
they pour like cooking oil
into a pot and they boil it.
It's almost like you're
poaching an egg in Greece,
so they have like four of those to
start the day and then they have labor.
They have like these little fucking,
I don't know,
these little pork sandwiches and
they're really big on Indian food.
Why do you guys have so many Indians
over there? Literally people from India.
Is that the whole Winston Churchill thing?
You know,
that's another book I started
reading and I never got through.
I really wanted to get through that
book so I can sound intelligent at some
point. It was a whole book
about the relationship between,
or was it Winston Churchill and Gandhi
gets fucking whacked. Just,
you know, it's unbelievable.
All these people out there who think
that they're being dangerous on stage and
type of, you know, if nobody's
made an attempt on your life,
you're not saying anything.
That's when you know that you're on
stage saying something I think is when
somebody tries to fucking shoot you
in the back of the head at that point.
Right.
Then you're saying something,
but you know enough with
all these dangerous artists.
I really hate that shit.
When people take, they had head
shots and they have like a, you know,
they had like a piece of tape
over their mouth. Like, like the,
the government put it, you
know, if he said duck taping,
let's stupid fucking like,
Ooh, he's dangerous. He's
doing some spoken word.
He figured out a word that rhymes with
Illuminati. Everybody run for cover.
He's going to sing a song about the
work and man, you're not dangerous.
Okay, okay. If you dangerous, they
tried to kill you and they do.
All right. Okay. You know, did
fucking Martin Luther King,
I have a poster of himself with the
fucking, you know, in, you know,
piece of tape over his mouth and
shrugging his shoulder like, ugh.
Well either whether they
go, hey, but the good day.
All right. Um, let's get back to the
questions. Question number three. We'll,
have you ever been dealing the case of
the runs all day and had to go onstage?
Tough it out, cold sweats, bubbling
stomach, stomach, and all, you know,
I love this question is he could've asked
me anything and I would have answered
it. And he just basically said, yeah,
that go on stage and like, yeah,
to take a shit and really bad, you
know, like, well, what was that like?
Did that ever happened to me? Uh, yeah,
it's happened to me a number of times.
Mean I've been doing it
for almost 17 years. Um,
I've had an untimely fucking
salad that went right through me.
Garlic is another thing
I don't do well with.
And the amazing thing is the second
you go on stage, for the most part,
it stops, uh, I don't know,
some sort of survival adrenaline thing
kicks in that, uh, just says, oh,
wait a second, we're not shitting.
No, we're not. No, we're not. Okay.
So you just need to
shut down that thought.
You need to sit there and wait until I'm
done with this stuff that I've had the
hiccups right before I went
on stage going, oh my God,
I have hiccups. What am I,
what am I going to do? And the
second I get out there, they go away.
I don't know why, but they do. So
yeah, I've, I've got to do that.
I've heard of stories of
comedians literally being onstage,
stopping the show and just saying, I have
to, uh, I have to leave now. In fact,
I want to say Dana Gould told a story
like that the other day on the Adam
Carolla show. Um, I dunno.
I Dunno. I can't remember. Anyways, let's
get back to the question says Shanell.
Okay, here we go. Um, let's
see. Let's see. Let's see.
Question number four. Bill,
if you could be with
the girl of your dreams,
any girl marry her,
have great sex every night,
everything was great and you were happy,
but she had to sleep with one guy.
Any guy in the whole rural world,
who would the guy be and
who would the girl be?
Great fucking question. Let's get with the
guy. That's the easy one. That would be,
um, one of those unbelievably
over the top gay guys.
You know,
those guys who were just like this.
So they're the ones who actually,
they get gay bashed and the reason they
get gay bash because there's so putting
out a female vibe,
it confuses the mail.
That's why they, you know, and if you're
not, you know, if you're a psycho,
you get so pissed. Like, why am,
why am, why am I feeling like this?
This is a female.
When it's a guy you,
you just start punching it because you
don't know how to, I don't know. Well,
I don't know the motivation behind fucking
gay bash and all I could say, yeah,
I would find the most, uh, over
the top, but not like that dude.
On will and grace because
he's still a dude.
He's just sort of skipping around
I guess the most of feminine.
I'm trying to think maybe like one
of those, uh, if it's like Filipino,
some little Asian hairless dude,
I go that way. You know what
I mean? Yeah. I go that way.
Um, and if it had to be any girl
in the world, who would it be? Uh,
Jesus Christ.
Um,
I dunno.
Everybody goes with somebody famous,
what would it be? You know,
what, how, you know what I do?
I would go back to my adolescence
when I was innocent and you don't,
when you, back then when you actually
looked at a girl and you had like, uh,
like remember that the way that,
uh,
what the for that Biloxi blues
with our guide to describe that,
that little mini heart attack, you
know, when you lean back in a chair,
I had a couple of girls back in
the day when I looked at him,
I felt that like that lightening bolt,
which only happens when you're young,
when you get older, you just, you just
went through it too many times. And again,
look at those shoes. She probably
likes to get tied up. How old is she?
28 probably on her second fucking
major relationship, you know,
let's find out if her
parents are still together.
That's always a good fucking
measuring stick. You know,
you start thinking like
that and you just lose it.
So I would go back then and uh,
yeah I would do and I'm not
going to say the girl's name,
probably a girl back then.
Well one of the two or three girls back
there that fucking made me out of a
heart attack. I would hook
up with them. You know what?
That was actually a very sweet answer.
I've been,
I have a lot of females going ah,
really sweet.
He does have a this side. There's a
bunch of guys. What? I'm fucking queer.
Um, alright. Question number five bill.
I was searching,
I was searching through youtube and
I found this interesting video file.
It was Jesse Ventura talking about how
most of September 11th was caused by our
government. And I'll fill
you non wrestling fans are
political people out there.
Jesse Ventura used to be a professional
wrestler, went by Jesse the body Ventura.
And one of my favorite things,
they used to call Tito Tito Santana.
Santana used to call them Chico Santana.
And uh,
he was part of the tag
team champion who was,
it was Larry's Abisko Bisco Tony Garcia.
Who the fuck was Tito Santana?
Was he would Ivan pushkey
and Tito Santana. Let me,
I don't care about no Chico Santana.
He was awesome.
And then he also said that Song Jessie's
girl was about him. Um, but anyway,
I think he was also a fucking,
was he a senator in Minnesota?
So anyways, that's the guy's background
with my fucking digression there.
Say a former wrestler, former senator I
believe, or a representative of Minnesota.
And anyway,
he was talking about how most of September
11th was caused by our government and
how we blew up the two World
Trade Center towers towers.
He said from his experiences in the navy
seals that buildings don't fall at the
rate of gravity. Your
thoughts, thanks again. Um,
my first gut feeling is they don't teach
you how to implode a skyscraper when
you join.
The navy seals and um,
buildings don't fall
at the rate of gravity.
I don't feel that they teach you that.
The navy seals,
I think they teach you
how to swim underwater,
how to cut somebody with a knife from ear
to ear and not have any guilt over it.
How to move stealthily, how to kill
people. I don't think at any point,
I'm trying to think of anything that
the navy seals were accused of any
skyscraper implosions
that they were accused of,
but our government denied any sort of
knowledge of granted it would be top
secret.
Um,
I'm guessing he went on
youtube like me and a watch,
the same conspiracy
theories that I watched, uh,
those same videos and now he's trying to
act like he came up with it himself to
make himself sound a little more
intelligent by throwing in the navy seal's
thick, you know, from my
experience in the Navy Seals, uh,
buildings don't fall at the
rate of gravity. Really.
Did they teach you that when
you were putting on your
flippers, you jackass when,
when the fuck did they teach you that,
you know what I mean?
I'm sure they taught you how to climb
up the side of a building, but you know,
I don't really think it's
in, you know, we have,
we have [inaudible] means
to take down buildings.
We don't have fucking eight guys
in frog suits do that. You know,
I think he's just throwing it out there
that's like, well, you know, a bill.
What do you think about September
11th? Well, my experience as a,
a headlining comedian around the country
leads me to believe that a building's
don't fall at the rate of
gravity. So a, yeah. Oh,
excuse me. I have a third show tonight.
You know, if, if he was an architect,
I would believe that.
Um,
I guess you're asking me what
am I thoughts do I think,
I dunno what happened on September 11th.
I know there's a lot of,
there's a lot of questions and I don't
feel like we're being told the whole
story. And I'm not saying our government
did it, but I don't know what happened.
But I know it's not what they told me.
I think they told you some
of what happened and then
other stuff they felt like
they couldn't tell you.
And then other shit they use to manipulate
shits so they could do some other
shit, which is why we're all in a
big bag of shit right now. All right,
question number six. Bill parents
named their kid. Uh Oh yeah.
I saw this story to parents named
their kid, one of their kids,
Adolf Hitler and another one Arion nation.
I think it's great.
Now we can keep an eye on the
little fuckers. Oh, wait a minute.
That's my response. I was like, wow,
this kid agrees with me. Um, yeah,
I do think it's great. I think
it's, it's for that exact reason.
You know what I mean?
The next Adolf Hitler is not going to
be named Adolf Hitler or Arian nation.
His name is going to be like Mike
or Jason. You know what I mean?
You know? I don't know. I don't
know how the fuck he explain it.
It's like anything,
anytime somebody comes along and look,
they will do what he sees the
next Jimmy Hendrix, you know,
it's like there's never
another Jimi Hendrix.
There's never going to be another eight.
I'm not gonna be another
fucking guy with the same name.
You named the Kid Adolf Hitler. Joseph
Stalin. They're not going to walk.
They're not going to do anything.
You just, you gave them a tattoo.
You know Adolf Hitler came to power.
He actually ran for office when new,
nobody knew of the name Adolf Hitler.
And he got in there and once
he got in there with his guys,
that's when he started doing shit.
So if this little fucker rubber
runs for all for office, he can't,
you know, it's, it's great.
They're just hung a sign around
him. Pay Attention. My, uh,
my parents were fucking maniacs
and I'm filled with hate.
You know, he can't run for
office. Who? You, who you
voted for. You vote for Obama.
You voted for a fucking John Mccain.
Are you voting for I Adolf Hitler
and his running mate, Arion nation.
I think all racists should name their
kids. Stuff like that, you know,
just, you know, name. I'm
fucked up. Names like that.
And then they can all giggle about it.
Hey,
there's a little laid off and then
we'll, you know, it's like the, you know,
I don't know how many times can I make
the same fucking point and that's around.
I really don't give a shit. Um, I
don't think it's offensive either.
I think those people can name their kids,
whatever the fuck they want to name. Um,
and, uh, like I said,
it's a major red flag.
Dad, can I go my friend's house? Yes. Uh,
well what will we go over? You
don't know if Steve's house? No.
Adolf eight. His kids'
names. Adolph. Yeah.
What? What's his last
name? Hitler saw y'all.
Can I go? Ah, no, no,
you can't. Why not? Well,
I'll explain it to you.
Like,
why don't we sit down and watch the
history channel together. I know. Wanda,
what's boring? Shut the fuck up. You
Little Brat. Question number seven. Um,
since you've been traveling across
the country for the past decade or so,
what's the best urban
legend you ever heard of?
Okay. Urban legends. Uh, I've
heard so many good ones. Um,
I, well, I grew up in the 80s,
so there was a lot of fear
about a during that time.
And um, I remember there was
an urban legend about a guy.
He's in a bar,
he makes this chick,
she's totally smoke and looks
like a fucking supermodel.
They go back to her place,
you know, whatever, her hotel,
she gives him the best
blow job ever that bang.
And I've invited the
greatest fucking night ever.
He wakes up the next morning she's gone
and he walks into the bathroom and then
on the mirror is written in lipstick.
Congratulations.
Now we both have age because
evidently he didn't use a condom.
And I remember being in a room,
in a warehouse believing every word going,
really do what we do. Where
did that happen? I don't know,
Dude.
I think it was in Rhode Island.
I was a moron. I liked
that one. And I liked a,
there was another one
out there about a guy,
he meets a girl in a bar
and uh, she says, hey,
and she's totally smoking. And
she says, Hey, this is the deal.
You can come back to my place,
you can do whatever you want to me,
but in the end I get to do whatever
I want to you. I was like, yeah,
fucking let's go.
So you know,
he does anything you could possibly do
with the woman you know, has an orgasm,
everything's great. And she
goes, okay, now it's my turn.
And she ties him down to
the bed. So he's like, okay,
she's under this freaky Dominic for Shit,
whatever. She walks out of the room,
you know,
closes the door and all of a sudden the
door fucking kicks open and there's a
black dude dressed like Batman and he
comes in and he fucks the guy in the ass.
And I actually believed it. Like that
totally made sense to me. I was like,
once again, 1819. When did that happen?
I don't know.
I think it was in Chelsea.
Um, yeah, probably that one.
And then, then anyone, any,
any of the firecracker,
urban legends, you know,
somebody put an mat in somebody's
back pocket and blew half his ass off.
Always liked that one. Um, yeah,
I would say that. All right.
And it's the second part
of the question also.
Do you believe in Spooky
Supernatural Shit? No. Yes and no.
I believe in outer body experiences.
I believe in some sort of,
uh, I dunno, I don't even afterlife,
but so just some shit that we don't, we
don't understand and we can't happen too.
I definitely believe in that,
but I don't believe in ghosts
like there that you know,
that they're going to haunt me. I
just don't get what it goes. Can Do.
You know, it's invisible.
I can't see it. Okay.
So what does it rattles a land
and it goes boom. All right.
Now that I get used to
that, and um, you know,
the worst he can just be as a pain in
the ass, just knock shit off my dresser.
And I said, really? And I can just fuck
with him mentally. Just torture him.
Spec really when maybe that's why.
Maybe that's why you're a ghost.
You ever think about that?
Maybe you're just a content life in
your punishment is you don't get to go
anywhere and now you're
trapped in my awful apartment,
you know,
kind of a fucking loser ghost.
Are you weighing when you out there
looking up women's skirts and we get gay
ghost, why don't you go fucking
float over to Wa West, uh,
west splitting a dudes over there,
you know,
he'll get their balls. I know what
I'm talking about here. All right.
Um, anyways, he said my girlfriend
is obsessed with that show.
Goes Hunter Hunter hunters.
And I find it ridiculous.
Uh, yeah, I find that shows
that shows it's fucking stupid.
It's all all in the editing and they
act like they're going to find something
and they don't, and they never quite
get like a good angle on the ghost.
You know? It's like if you
had a good angle on the ghost,
you would kept the footage and you
would have just could've sold it to any
network out there for millions of dollars.
We finally have proof that goes to exist,
but they never do it.
So we shaky handheld. Blair witch.
All right. Question number eight.
Um, bill doing sets every week, do you
ever get bored of your own stories?
Jesus Christ? Yes, absolutely.
Which is Wa and thank God I do. If I
didn't, I would never write any new jokes.
Absolutely. Absolutely. And what ends up
happening is if it's a seven minute joke,
it becomes a five minute joke.
It becomes a two minute joke and then
it just becomes a joke that disappears.
It's kind of like,
you know,
you have it like break your arm or
something and someone's like, dude,
what happened to your arm?
And you tell the first person you tell
in total detail what happened to your arm
and it takes like fucking 10 minutes.
The next guy you tell,
you start telling again, you can fuck
you going over the same shit again,
becomes eight minutes and then the
very end, it's just what happened?
How I'm doing,
I fucking fell down and go fuck yourself.
What do you think happened?
It bent in a way it wasn't supposed
to bend in a broke. All right,
what happened to your face? All
right, question number nine.
How far into this podcast all we,
how many moms funny.
Shorten these things because
they're getting ridiculously long.
41 minutes. Jesus Christ. I should
sell cds at the end of this. All right,
question number nine, and I'm going
to wrap this up real quick. Um, Bill,
are there any movies that you,
that you know are God awful,
but for whatever reason you love them
anyways? Oh, I like this. This is a,
this is a good story here. Listen
to this shit. He says for me,
it's John Claude van Damme bloodsport
and kickboxer reason being is as about
nine or 10 when those movies came
out and they were the first movies,
my dad let me stay up and watch with
them even though my mom disapproved and I
saw kickboxer for the first time in a
while the other day and it really might be
one of the worst movies of all time,
especially the power van Damme gets
punched square in the face about 15 times
and rapid succession at the end of the
round. And at the end of the round,
the bad guy tells van dam that he fucked
his girlfriend at which point vent damn
spends the rest of a in between rounds
demanding to know the truth about his new
girlfriend.
He says,
if I were in the middle of a fight with
a grand champion of underground death
matches,
would you actually give a shit at point
who some girl you met two weeks ago.
Fuck exactly. And I'll never
forget the part with a bad vet.
Bad Guy's boss finally gets what's coming
to him because my dad would always be
going and take that you
Cambodian son of a bitch.
I don't even think the guy was supposed
to be Cambodian, but I, if I see them,
movie's going to be on, on
Cinemax 20 years from now.
Still sit down and watch it.
Yeah, I got movies like that. Um, I think
I already talked about this one airport,
1975 if he ever get a
chance to watch that movie,
that's the movie that basically the
movie airplane was making fun of,
I believe.
And believe it or not,
air as funny as the movie airplane
is airport 1975 is even funnier.
Just to give you a quick recap
of what the store, what it is.
It's a commercial airliner. You
know, some guys in a private plane,
he has a heart attack and has a
head on collision with like a DC 10,
which sucks one of the pilots out of the
front and blinds Efram Zimbalist Jr at
which point a stewardess who
I swear to God has a lazy eye,
has to fly the fucking plane and
it stars and unknown Erik Estrada,
who plays the character of I believe
heck door and has one line in it.
It's that fucking good. All right,
what am I going to end with here?
Um, let's end with a wishing all
you guys are merry Christmas. So,
because you know, you're Jewish,
had a happy Hanukkah. Um,
if your a,
is it just black only black people or is
it African Kwanza Happy Kwanza curation?
I Dunno what you do there.
Uh, oh, Jewish people, uh,
have Dolby up excellent Chinese food on
Christmas Day. I learned that little,
uh, that little tradition the other day.
Oh, here's a question I have for any,
any, you technically savvy guys out here
cause I really want to up the quality of
these podcasts. People keep talking
about this tapping, wait a minute.
Is it, is it this noise?
Is that the noise?
If that's the noise. Yeah, that's
me scrolling down on my computer.
I think we solved it.
Um,
son of a bitch anyways, so I
want to up the uh, the quality.
So let me know if that's the tapping
sound because some people were saying it
was my last saying I left like Popeye
in and annoyed them or is it this,
is that really annoying you guys?
Anyways, this is my question.
I saw something, I was
listening to a, what's his face?
Little Stephens underground Christmas.
If you guys ever listened to his show,
it's on Sunday nights.
Checkout locally.
He's just said please on this underground
music plays great music and I love the
way he talks.
Lou Stevens underground Christmas,
we got the remote moves.
I can't even do what he's just fucking
the coolest dude ever. But anyways,
he was talking about this shit on
there called the uh, the Olympus ls 10
and evidently it's this fucking
unbelievable recording record.
12 hours with a shit on it.
Bands can use it.
Like that's how much quality is that.
You can just set it in the middle of
the room and it picks up everything.
Like that cheesy guitar playing that
you heard at the beginning of this,
you could have really
told how awful it was.
If I get one of these devices
and any tech geeks out there,
I want to know if this thing is worth it.
The ls 10 if I start recording my
podcasts on this, then uploading them.
It's really adding in whole extra step
to the process. But I would like to,
you know, I'm getting a ton of
listeners, I'm not going to lie to you,
the podcast that kind of
starting to blow up. You know,
I think I'm in a triple digits at
this point. I don't even joke in San,
only have 14 listeners,
but I really think I got a,
I think I have about 106 at this point.
So I'm gonna we're going
to try to, well, you know,
try to up the quality here in 2009.
Um,
and with that I got an idea.
How about for next week's podcast?
You guys send me in some
New Year's resolutions.
How are you going to turn your lives
around you now you do this every year.
You lie to yourself, you're going to make
your life a little bit better. You know,
send me those in. And with that I'm going
to end this podcast here. I'm going to,
well actually hype a couple of dates
I have coming up. Um, all right,
this is the big one. Um, at the
Improv and Tampa, Florida and I,
last time I was there, you know, I dunno,
I didn't do so well as
far as drawing people.
I know it's kind of off the
beaten path down there in Tampa.
Maybe the hangover a year.
Fucking devil rays,
which kicked the shit out of my red sox
while we took you to seven games that
you guys are definitely the better
team. Maybe you guys, you know,
the lightening aren't doing so well,
that kind of an okay team come out to
one of my shows is what I'm saying.
January 8th, ninth, 10th. If you
saw my uh, last hour special,
I wrote well brand new hour of stuff and
I'm also going to be at the Improv and
Houston,
Texas on January 22nd through the 24th.
And then I'm making a hometown stop in
Boston at the Wilbur theater on February
the sixth. I really hope
you guys can come out. Um,
I'm going to be really
rested up over the holidays,
so I'm going to be extra funny.
I guaran fucking tee it and uh,
and that is it. I didn't quite get a
chance to get to some of this shit.
I got a couple of Nice reviews
on my podcast here.
This is all garbage time.
You don't even have to
listen to this ship it.
Here's a couple of Nice reviews I got.
And then I have another one,
another segment that I like to call it
back down to earth where somebody trashes
me. So here we go. Here's
a couple of Nice one. Um,
thanks for making me laugh all day long.
I just finished listening to all of your
podcast. How the fuck did you do that?
I'm trying to get my
wife to listen to them,
but she doesn't think it's
as funny as I think they are.
Anytime I have my headphones
on and I'm laughing, she says,
are you listening to your boyfriend
bill? Too Funny. Keep up the great work.
Don't you love when fucking women do shit
like that? Fuck her that she's jealous.
She's jealous that you're
year Gig. I, you know what?
You should play this part for her. What's
her name? Give me your name next week.
I'll, I'll have, I'll give her
a little talking to, you know,
and I'll be nice even though she doesn't
think I'm that funny. You know this.
Look, if you want to hold on, you know
I'm gonna do a right now, sweetheart.
If you want to hold onto your boyfriend,
he can't suffocate them. All right?
If he likes walking around, listening
to another man and his headphones,
you know us a little gay. I
understand that. You know,
he's got in touch with his feminine side.
All right?
But what you need to do is you
need to be an adult here, okay?
You have to understand that no
matter how stupid you think it is,
it's one of his hobbies. And
you have to respect that. Okay?
Don't do what Jennifer Lopez did to Ben
Affleck during their year and a half
relationship. What are you going to do?
Dress him up like a little Ken doll.
Stick him in a Tuxedo.
Huh?
He can walk around smiling,
pretending he's happy and everybody sees
the misery behind his eyes, you know?
And then one day, you know, you
just, he's just, I don't know,
you just see him crouched over in front
of his laptop looking at porn or just
something, something awful
and you're gonna blame him.
You're going to blame his childhood.
You know what? It's you lady. All right.
So why don't you back off during
the holidays. Okay? All right,
next one.
Hey Bill.
I think your podcast should come
with the public service disclaimer.
Since I fly a lot, I catch up
on your podcasts during flights.
I get such a kick out of this that people
are actually downloading these things
and listening to them. It's just
really cool. And so anyways,
on a plane and he says,
I sat next to this older lady during
a recent flight back from Portland.
It was your podcast about
chips and the 20 car pile ups.
I was frigging laughing so hard.
I couldn't breathe.
I thought I was going to be escorted
off the flight by air marshals.
This poor lady must've thought I was
a some psycho. All right. So yeah.
That's awesome. That makes me feel
good. Next one. One more good one.
And then I'm going to bring myself back
down to earth with somebody who trashed
me. All right, Bill. Then yesterday,
uh, it was the same one. Yes.
That was with my older daughter
and we were listening in the car.
This was a podcast about being a boxer
and reacting to punches by shrugging your
shoulders and turning your head. I, yeah,
that's how I react to when somebody
tries to punch me in the face.
I don't try to slip the punch.
I just bring my shoulders up to ear
level and then I turned my head away
to, I never want to fight
anyways. He said, uh,
we were both crying and gasping for air.
I could barely see the car in front of me.
Good God.
Warn people they should not be in public,
uh,
or operating heavy machinery
when listening. All right,
so that's the good review section.
Now here is the back down to
earth section of the podcast.
Bill, glad to see you've been working
on, you're reading out loud skills.
You sound like a special ed kid that
didn't bother getting out of the short bus
when it arrived at school.
I wonder how many times you've been in
public places reading out the podcast
questions into your phone and people
have walked by and thought, oh, how nice.
The mentally challenged man
over there is learning to read.
I guess he's really
coming along because he,
he's only sounding out every other word.
You know what's great about that?
Not only is that absolutely correct, I
actually had difficulty reading out loud.
The thing that he said,
insulting me, saying I can't
read out loud. Well, to shade,
to shade at Buddy. Um, anyways, happy
holidays everybody. Merry Christmas,
happy Hanukkah, happy Kwanzaa. And
if you don't celebrate any of it,
I hope you have a good break.
While the rest of us are spending money
on people that we resent on some level,
um, that is it. Um, let me know
your New Year's resolutions.
Please keep the podcast questions coming
and I hope in January I can have some
sort of update on my European tour
that I'm going to be doing, um,
next year.
So for my seven listeners in the UK,
um, I dunno if you guys celebrate.
You guys have Jesus over there.
I know you have Mcdonald's. All
right. God bless. Take it easy.
Talk to you next Monday.
Maybe somewhere down the road,
maybe somewhere down the road with
car.
I'm just glad to
be of
your dad.