Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? Is Bill Burn?
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And I am just checking in on you.
I'm not yelling it.
I'm in Houston right now and I have a,
I got a show here in a couple
of hours and you know, Bill is,
I am in an advanced age at this point.
You know,
this is how old I am.
I now qualify for something
I'd never heard of before.
It's called a p a r. P. I
don't know what it does.
It's for old guys like me.
We're not 65 with 50.
And evidently I can now go to
the movies for eight bucks.
I'd probably get a free side of Metamucil,
you know,
maybe a little Ben Tuba, Ben Gay
when I walk out, but I'm site. So,
um, yeah, don't let anybody ever tell
you that getting old fucking sucks.
Okay. Yeah, it does. You body breaks
down. Eventually you take a dirt nap.
Who's kidding? Who? You know,
you fucking surrounded by
loved ones as you lay in there,
everybody's bottom lip quiver and you
just sit. No. Was I a good person?
Was I a good person?
Right. Yeah. That sucks.
But there's a lot of shit that
balances it off. All right.
$8 tickets to movies,
Bam
talking shit to somebody in their
twenties. You know, like you're a bad ass,
but you're too old for
them to fuck with you.
So you look tough right in front
of your 50 year old wife. Boom.
MMM. I mean, that's pretty much
the extent of it. I haven't really,
I know I'm new to this being
fucking over the hill here, uh,
but you know,
getting to wear a stupid hat,
right? One of those fucking old
man coats. I can't fuck man. It's,
it's not like I can't wait, but
uh, I'm going to enjoy it. Um,
anyways, uh, before we get started, I
have a couple of things to promote. Oh,
rough and rowdy brawl. August 5th, uh,
the people over there were nice
enough l pres, Dave Portnoy's,
uh, was nice enough to invite me back
and of course I jumped at the chance.
I had such a great time the last
time when we were in fucking shallot.
Um,
it's so cool.
And I will show up to these things as long
as they have me because, uh, it's, uh,
it's ridiculously fun. So it's
going to be in Youngstown, Ohio.
All right.
Kids come out of the womb swinging.
Okay.
All right. When the doctor hits
the baby on the ass in Youngstown,
he's wearing headgear. That's all I'm
saying. And a mouthpiece. Um, all right.
But we get it to tough. All
right. Who knows. I don't
know what their deal is. They,
I don't know why they're so
tough there. I imagine, you know,
I think each little pool of people,
you know, starts off with a,
with a couple of Adam and eve. Right.
And they bang and then whatever,
if they're in the box, then
you get like Seattle, you know,
but if they got hammered and they
beat the shit out of each other, yeah.
You get Youngstown.
I haven't researched any of this,
but I don't know what all I know is,
I'm not looking at anybody in the eye
when I get there, cause I don't, I don't,
I don't need to be clocked by
fucking Kelly. Pavlics third cousin.
Um, but anyways, so I,
I got to do a Gig. A,
I'm going to do a gig right before I
get there. I'm going to be in Rochester,
New York.
All right.
I believe Home Steve Gadd childhood home.
I remember he was,
I remember that I used to watch that
instructional DVD that he had a zillion
times up close and he would talk about
how he got his hands together playing in
the Rochester Crusaders.
It was a drum corps. Um,
I know crazy inflammation, but whatever
it's in my head, I got to get it out. Um,
so that will be on August 4th, August
5th, I'll be driving down to Youngstown,
um,
for rough and rowdy.
So go to rough and rowdy
brawl.com to get your tickets,
um, to stream it. Whatever you got to
do, it's going to be fucking awesome.
And I've already seen
some of the highlights,
so I should really be tweet some of the,
some of the guys,
they got some Pittsburgh,
Cleveland guys,
no love lost there with all the Steelers
trophies and a Cleveland's baron shelf.
Cause for some reason they
don't count NFL titles,
which Cleveland one I think in 65 but
you know, as far as franchises go,
that went out to fucking
Baltimore, Baltimore, Scarface,
reference any hoo. I'm here in a,
okay.
Houston, Texas. Oh my God. I thought it
was going to be fucking brutally hot.
I was like, I was almost ready
to call my agent and be like,
how many fucking years have
you been in this business?
Slash how many years have you been
booking me that you would book a bald,
redheaded male?
Yeah,
that qualifies for Arp in Houston,
Texas in fucking July.
But um,
we were coming in for Atlanta and I was
looking out the window and all, all the,
you know, fields that I saw were
green. So I was like, all right,
maybe they getting some rain, I don't
know. But it's not that bad down here.
Okay.
The bad thing is, is I forgot
my show shoes. You know,
for those of you not in show business,
you have your shoes that you
walk around in your shoes,
your workout in or whatever. All right.
This is a very first world here, okay?
For those, those of you listening
in lesser countries, okay?
We are so privileged here that we
have shoes for different events.
I need to work out, right? I'm
going to fucking wear these shoes.
I'm good to go. Uh, I don't know. Go
run some. Oh, I think I'll grab those.
And then you got to put on a
show and dance like a monkey.
You have these other fucking shows and I
know other people, other towns, you know,
uh, countries I should say. You know,
you've got one pair of shoes if you lucky,
right?
You and 18 other people jump on a fucking
moped with 37 boxes and somehow you
don't tip over. You go down the street
making fucking Instagram videos.
I see out there, I see out there all
the time. I don't know how you do it.
Is it like young style where
you just grow up fighting?
You guys just grow up fucking stack
and shit up until it makes no sense and
somehow they stay upright.
Everybody always watches fucking evil
Knievel jumping over the buses with a,
with a motorcycle that probably weighed
like four to 500,000 fucking pounds.
You know, as great as that is,
as impressive as it is, you know,
to drive down the street with
all your personal belongings,
your wife and all of your kids.
Okay.
With that much to lose. I don't think
evil Knievel can touch that, you know,
cause if he wiped out,
he died. That was it.
He didn't lose fucking everything
and all his clothes. All right,
so that's one to grow on. Next
time they say evil Knievel is, is,
is the grandfather of
fucking, uh, uh, the x games.
All right? You know, there's
always somebody else.
Everybody talks about Edison.
There's always a Tesla. I'm
sorry, what do you want from me?
I got to fill up a fucking half hour here
and wait for my salad with the protein
coming.
Um,
I've been doing real well with the whole
eating and everything and I actually
got in contact with a nutritionist.
I took a long pause there for
all you guys would be like,
Oh gee you are you are you going
to do next? You get to get botox,
you fucking freckled can't.
Huh?
You going to find some ginger cat and
skin it and put the fucking hair on top of
your head?
Well maybe I will.
That makes me feel better about myself.
Fuck that cat
never been a cat person.
Right.
You know why they have such attitudes
is because they were allowed to shit in
the house and then they think you're on
the same level and then they're faster
than you and then it's over.
Then you can, you know,
you can instill like fucking martial
law with the water spray bottle.
You don't want to fucking do that.
Although I would enjoy doing that.
I would actually, you know, if I wasn't
in this business I would do that as a job.
Okay.
Um, cause I don't like
cats. I respect him.
Okay.
I do.
But I would get an a lot of enjoyment
spraying water at cats that jump on the
back of couches. Is that actually
a career? Can you do that?
Is that how my life's going to end?
Wait a minute.
Is that what's going to happen? Me,
I'm going to die alone with like a cat,
you know,
have a cigar,
a little glass of fucking
whiskey or something and
I'll just be sitting there in
my rocking chair and I have all these,
all these fucking cats.
So that'll be like my fucking
playstation 19 right. Cause I, you know,
I wouldn't have saved my money.
I'll have all these fucking cats and
then I'll just be spraying and I'm just
cackling laughing to like Keel over
like Brando in fucking the Godfather.
Jesus built you. Really? But I know,
I don't know what it is. You know,
I was doing so well with my
anger and just, I just fucking,
I just been losing it lately.
Fucking losing it.
I Dunno. I think I need to let
it out. It's Kinda like booze.
It's like if I don't do
it then it just builds up.
I went online yesterday looking up
like what do you, what you call that a,
it's not a fifth of Jack down
since it's the smaller ones.
The little brother to that one.
That's always been my favorite.
If you just going to get fucking hammered,
he'd get that sides of it. Right.
I was just talking to Nate Craig, who's,
who's going to be with me this weekend,
crushing it in front of me. I
was saying, I liked that size.
You're poured over on the rocks.
You don't get like,
there's no guilt that
you're, you're, you're,
you're wasting this booze that's been
in a barrel for fucking, I dunno,
since Nixon was in office and you
just sit in there getting shit faced,
watching a baseball game. It's,
you know, it's Jack Daniels, this,
there's plenty of it. Right. And
then when you finish the bottle,
you get like a sense of accomplishment.
So that's all like not boozing
does for me. It just makes me, uh,
makes me want to booze more.
And I think like not flipping
out is the same thing right now.
For those of you new to the podcast,
if you're questioning,
did he just justify not controlling
his emotions and his drinking problem?
Yes, I did. Yes I did. And
thank you for noticing.
Um,
I don't have fucking drinking problem.
I drink just fine.
What I have is a drinking buddy problem.
Can't seem to get anybody
I can fucking drink with.
That ain't going to be sitting there
counting my fucking drinks. All right.
And now we both went to public schools.
We can both count up to 20.
Yank pressing me. All right. You
wanna impress me by fucking round.
Quick reminded me that I drove tonight.
The fuck could fucking drive that car.
I'm my fucking sleep.
I'll back it on home.
We keep fucking talking.
That's my main or alcoholic
is a fucking redneck. Um,
anyways, oh, shout out to Chris
Hardwick. Congratulations.
They investigated and they found
out what most of us already knew.
You're a good guy.
And it was nice to see one of those
ones that seemed really sort of fucking
frivolous be investigated thoroughly
according to CNN entertainment.
And you know, that's a, that that was,
that needed to fucking
happened because uh, you know,
that whole me too movement was supposed
to be for people that were like victims.
It wasn't supposed to be, you
know, something to be used
to get back at somebody, you know, I don't
know. I shouldn't, I guess allegedly,
whatever the fuck you're supposed to say.
But it was nice to see that AMC
took the time to investigate it,
saw that nothing happened.
Yeah.
They were satisfied with it and they
brought the guy back. There you go.
There you go. I hope that
this is like, you know,
cause it kind of needed that. And then
there was the initial fucking, you know?
Yeah.
Because nobody listened to women.
So then to just be there was just
this floodgate of fucking anger.
You had to ride through it and just,
you knew eventually somebody who didn't
do shit was going to go down. So it's,
it's, it's nice to see that they,
they rectified that situation.
Did I just get myself in trouble by
saying rectified? Is that too much?
Like rectal? Then I just, I just
advocate something. You get me.
This is just a strange time, you know? Um,
anyways, um, plowing ahead here.
MMM.
Yeah. So I forgot my God
damn show shoes. All right.
Um, uh, you know, I'm becoming Billy
minimalist but not, not on this level.
Like I like to wear a nice pair of fucking
sneakers or shoes when I do my shows
and uh,
I don't have them what I have,
I just have my fucking workout sneakers.
So I'm going to go out there looking sharp
from the ankles up and then I'm going
to have these big clunky fucking,
yeah,
yeah.
50 year old white guy. My feet hurt
sometimes sneakers on. So, you know,
I give it about seven minutes
before somebody heckles me.
Well now that I've put it out there,
someone's going to do it
and think they're original.
Or maybe it's their way of saying that
they listened to the podcast. I Dunno,
but I'm going to beat all of you cause
I'm just going to come out and address it.
MMM.
Anyways, you know what they
look like? They actually,
they don't even look like men's sneakers.
You know those fucking sneakers that like
old lady was old ladies with big feet
get.
Yeah.
You know,
you see him on the bus and they just
have like you see in the cute little old
ladies and they just have these giant
fucking sneakers over their feet.
You know what I mean? That's
what they look like. No,
they're not all white Reeboks
from the late eighties.
MMM. Anyway, so I am
really looking forward to,
uh, I got two days here in Houston
and then I got one in Dallas. Uh,
Houston's going to be fun.
Thousand is going to be awesome,
but it's going to be a little sad.
Um,
because this is my first time going to
Dallas and with Vinnie Paul not being
around anymore and he was a big comedy
fan and he was somebody that I always
made sure I reached out to and I had a 50,
50 chance cause he also lived in Vegas
that uh, he was going to be in town,
but um, yeah, going to suck. I was just
talking to a buddy of mine who
was hanging out with Vinny, um,
just a few days before he passed.
And he was saying that he used to always
quote Comedians' bits and he would
always like mess him up. He was just the
funniest fucking guy ever, man. Goddammit.
Um,
anyway,
so I'll be going up there and in my
mind will be dedicating my show to him.
Saw that means I have to go hard,
but it's by the wave.
I don't know how I missed all of this
pant terra shit now that I'm like totally
fucking into them and like trying to play
drums along to their amazing music and
um,
yeah,
somebody sent me the uh,
the official video to unbroken,
which I never saw and what I love is they,
they spent enough time on Vinny that I
saw this shit that I was playing wrong as
far as uh, oh, whatever. Just, you know,
the two open and crashes like I didn't
know he had like four crashes to what
each side and then there was another part.
I thought he was playing an eighth
seems plain sixties pretty fucking cool.
You don't get that a lot.
And music videos,
music videos usually barely shows
the drummer. And when they do,
they have the snare when he's hitting the
snare or he or she's hitting the snare.
It's on the one in three and the bass,
the bass drums on two and four.
I cannot tell you how many fucking
times they do that. It's like,
are you even listening
to the music right now?
Yeah.
You're in the crack of the
snare and you got him fucking,
you're lining up the video
and he's hitting the fucking
bass drum, if anything.
Okay.
And the music videos
genre drove me more nuts.
There wasn't anything, it was that, that
they would never fucking show the drama.
And when they did they, it was
just like they didn't give a fuck.
I think they just looked at the right
hand to just line up the music and that
was it. And then it didn't
see what else we was fucking,
the amount of times they
cut to like the singer,
he sing in some part and you see the
drummer playing the f of Phil that you
don't even hear or you hear of Phil and
the guys just playing the beat. It, it's,
you know, all the fucking guitarist
does something. Oh Jesus Christ.
Okay.
Make sure we fucking line that up. Note
for note the singer, pay attention.
I always like fuck the drummer.
So anyways,
it's a great video because they did
not do that in that video. Sorry.
Look at me getting all worked
up over nothing. So anyways, um,
a friend of mine got me in touch with the
nutritionist and this is not code name
for a drug dealer, so we just knock on
my door. Oh Jesus. Hang on a second.
Anyways,
so,
uh,
I got this fucking nutritionist cause
I wanna learn, I wanna learn how to eat
well.
Um,
you know what I mean? I don't want
to just be this guy like, hey,
I'm going to fucking cut this out
and I'm going to start fucking doing
it. You know, like I mentioned before,
like how many,
like the amount of fat fucking vegans
I'm talking like back fat.
I'm not just saying they got a
little pooch or something like that.
I'm just talking about like,
okay,
you know, just looking at people,
like you just look at him like you,
you look like you're not healthy.
And there'll be like, oh,
I'm a vegetarian or I'm
fucking Vegan and all of that.
So when he was just like I mentioned, say
bring the fucking food trade over here,
there's like,
there's so much fucking like
misinformation. I don't know how to,
I don't know how to sift through it.
And I don't want to become a vegetarian,
you know what I mean?
But I also fucking hate working out,
you know what I mean? So I would
like to fucking just eat smarter
is what I'm trying to do, you know?
Now that I'm on the fucking road,
this is what always gets me, you know,
I come in, I'm grumpy from a flight,
you know,
and you look at the salads and when
you're in a fucking bad mood and you're
hungry, a salad never looks
like the right option, does it?
It never does. What do you do? You,
I'm gonna get a fucking burger and you're
trying to say, I want a side salad.
And then the lady's like,
do you want fries with that?
And in your head going, no,
Bill,
do it. And then he, yeah, yeah. Fuck it.
Gimme some Goddamn fries,
sir. You can order your food
without using that language.
I like to remind you all
you are in the bottle.
Yeah.
So I've been at Houston a thousand times,
so what am I supposed to do now? Am I
going to go to the fucking Alamo again?
Going out of that God forsaken, I
never even been in it. You don't?
And I'm not talking about the
original Alamo in San Antonio.
I'm talking about the
Houston Alamo. It's a, uh,
it's a mom and pop place.
You know, I don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about.
I just wanted us to say the
different cities, the wrong city,
so people could be all like,
oh, we should we each book
shaking my head. All right, let me
read some advertising here for Y'all.
Felix Gray, y'all. Um,
even if you've never heard
of digital eye strain.
Yeah.
Oh Shit. Yes. Oh, this is, this is
odd. Yeah. Okay. I remember this one.
This is a good one. Do you never heard
a digital eye strain? Chances are,
chances are you've experienced the
fucking effects symptoms like fatigue,
dry eyes,
and migraines.
I'm turning the hose on your cat.
All of these things can happen when you
stare at a computer screen for too long.
Now you can profit with
your eyes. Nike, Oh, sorry.
Now you can protect your eyes with a
beautifully designed pair of Felix Gray
computer glasses. I want
these things. Felix.
Grays lenses are specifically designed
to filter blue light and eliminate glare
from screens.
The two main culprits,
culprits behind digital eye strain,
whether you're at work or play,
they have the blue light filtering
technology embedded into the lens,
so they're effective without the
telltale telltale yellow tint or color
distortion of other blue light
filtering glasses, Felix Grays,
y'all frames are handcrafted
from premium Italian acetate,
Acetate,
I already forgot what that means.
This same material used by the biggest
designer brands in the world and they're
super stylish.
There's no prescription necessary.
Take him out of the box and slam them on
your face and get back to internet porn.
Their glasses are available
in nonprescription readers
and they just launched
prescription lenses so they
can so everyone can benefit
from wearing a pair of
Felix grace. All orders are
free shipping and free returns,
so you got nothing to lose. Go
to Felix Gray glasses. Y'All F,
e l I x,
g r a y glasses.com/burr to try a
pair of Felix Gray glasses today.
That's Felix Gray,
glasses.com/birth Felix gray,
glasses.com/bar I think that I need
glasses because of these fucking computers
that and I'm 50 hey,
I'm 50 I'll let you get in a
truck and go fuck a catfish man.
Butcher box.
Okay,
what's your box? I love that. I believe in
all the products. Now butcher box these,
these slbs butcher box delivers healthy
100% grass fed and grass finished beef
free range,
organic chicken and the top shelf.
The Johnnie Walker blue of all
meat, heritage, bread, pork.
The incredible quality I make my mouth
waters when I read this shit cause I like
to do is think about that
fucking pork chop. I apologize.
The incredible quality of butcher box
meets starts with the commitment to
raising animals humanely and free of
antibiotics and hormones before they kill
them. Each box comes with at
least nine to 11 pounds of meat.
Fucking porn star, which is enough
per 24 individual size meals.
You can choose from five
different box types. All beef,
beef and chicken,
beef and pork mixed box.
Custom box lets you choose your own cuts.
Antibiotic Hormone free.
A butcher box believes in healthier
food system where everyone has access to
meets the way nature intended.
Free of antibiotics and hormones and
humanely raised on an open pasture before
we kill them. Selection, butcher
box carefully cure rates,
the finest selection and cuts and
makes it a breeze to customize your own
delivery.
Build your own box to get exactly
what you and your family love.
Choose your delivery frequencies
with customizable subscriptions.
However you want to do this.
Recipes available, butcher box,
website and videos are available to follow
along on butcher box, youtube channel.
Um, I had the pork. It was
unbelievable. I loved it. Okay. Anyways,
um, it's a lot of words here
to receive free bacon for life.
The nerve of Jim Jefferies to say that,
that,
that this is not the
greatest country of all time.
Free Bacon for life and the
Good Bacon American Bacon,
not Canadian Bacon. That good shit, uh,
of scripts free breaking
full life up subscription.
What that's wrong that to
receive free bacon for life
of subscription. Oh, F plus $10 off
your order. Go to butcher box.com.
Click on the big bacon banner on the
homepage and use bird checkout. Go now.
Limited time offer. All
right. Stitch Fitch,
fix stitch fix.
Stitch fix has reimagined the
way we we find and buy clothes.
First of all,
hats off to these guys.
No Pun intended that they took the time
to figure out how to fix this boring
problem. Um, we've reimagined
it. Like Disney convenience,
stitch fix understands
that life gets busy.
So just tell them your sizes and your
favorite types of clothes and how much you
want to spend and your personal stylists
will pick out your clothing for you
based on your preferences.
Try before buying.
If an item doesn't fit or you just don't
like it, no worries. Just send it back.
Free of charge style. Some of
us have it, some of us don't.
But just because a sense of style seems
elusive for some doesn't mean it's
impossible. Doing Tane to attain, sorry.
There's no time like the present to
discover that style you never knew you had
and you can with a little help
from our friends at stitch fix.
This is like when they would go into the
musical montage in any eighties movie
when they would be like re
remaking the nerdy chick,
you know she wasn't good looking cause
she wore glasses and had our hair up.
Right. Then they'd let the hair
down and take the glasses off.
It's like Oh my God Megan,
you're beautiful.
This is what stitch fix
is going to do for you.
Stitch fix has reinvented how
we bought finding buy clothes.
Just answer some basic questions about
your sizes. Favorite styles and budget.
I feel like they already said this right
from your laptop, smart phone or tablet.
You're personalized stylist then
springs into action. God Christ,
they got to know their order.
Hand selecting five brand new clothing
items just for you. I know, I know.
Personal stylist sounds like something
only the rich and famous can afford but
you can't to stitch fix styling fee
is only 20 bucks which is applied as a
credit towards anything.
It keep.
And since your personal stylist uses
only your personal preferences to,
to pick your clothes,
your still in complete control.
Once your items have arrived,
try them on and pay for what you keep.
Don't like [inaudible]. Need another
size. Just send the items back. Grouse,
no questions asked.
And shipping is always free both ways.
Get your fix wherever you want or
sign up to receive a scheduled
shipments. The choice is yours. A,
you're going to love stitch
fix. And um, what is it?
How are you this? Stitch fix
stitch fix.com/burr to get statted.
Now keep all,
fight up five items in your box and
you'll get 25% off your entire purchase.
That stitch fix.com/bar hey,
stitch fix.com/burr.
All right.
Um,
okay.
So anyways,
I'm on the road.
I just sorted a salad and I got the beef.
Yeah,
probably should have get the chicken
who's got fish but a fish yesterday.
And you know what?
I always forget to tell them,
don't send me the fucking dinner rolls.
And now they got them all warm
underneath the Napkin with some butter.
And My mother taught me not to waste.
So what am I supposed to do here?
Huh?
I Dunno anyways, but I'm, I'm uh,
I'm liking the way I look right now.
I gave her a date, so I
would like to continue, uh,
with the nok booze and for a while I'm
not going to do with like the way I smoke
cigars like a chimney. No, I'm going to
drink the way I smoke cigars, which is,
you know, once every 10 minutes. No,
once every 10 to 14 days I have a cigar.
So I would like to get hammered or have
a couple of cocktails twice a month.
That's not bad. 24 times
a year, 24 times a year.
I just want to remind my liver
that this is not a game. Okay.
The pre season is over. All right. So
keep your head on a fucking swivel.
Stay on your God damn toes. Um, oh,
I got a night coming up. I'm going
to come off the wagon for one day.
Like what I would like to do,
come off the wagon for one day in August
and then I am not going to drink again
until I'm going to a Michigan Wolverine
game this year at the big house.
Oh,
I have not been to a game there
since 1999 and the only guy,
there was some guy in Michigan I believe
when the Heisman and if for some reason
I remember that Guy David Boston,
cause he had the last name Boston and
then he went to the chargers or something
like that. I can't remember.
But uh, I went to the uh,
Michigan Ohio state game,
you know,
the big fucking rivalry game at the
big house. That's a, that's a good one.
I've been to some good ones, man.
I've been to that one. I went to a,
what is it, the fucking,
uh, Texas versus Oklahoma.
I've been to that one.
Okay.
I haven't been to USC. Ucla, that's
fucked up. I don't hear for so long,
but the one I would love to go to,
I want to go to Alabama. Auburn.
I've seen Lsu or Alabama.
I've seen Texas a and
m with Johnny football.
Yeah.
First Alabama. I just like, you know,
those fucking sec games are the
best. Um, I shouldn't have said that.
Anomalous and everybody who actually you
big tangible can be be the BB. I get it.
I get it. You're, you're, you're partial
to where the fuck you're from. All right,
that's the podcast here. I
gotta go do my fucking show. Uh,
I hope you guys have a wonderful Thursday
and a great weekend. You Con, uh,
the music that we're going to be using
is Darren King. He did a cover of,
uh, is it Richie haven? Is that
his name? The guy from Woodstock.
He did a cover of his, uh, freedom. Um,
if you guys want to know who this
artist is staring king and uh,
he's done everything. He used to play
drums with mute math. He plays guitar,
he sings.
And from what I've heard,
he's going to be maybe doing
a small tour coming up. Um,
but I'm a big fan of this guy
is just like incredible artists.
So enjoy the music and then we'll
have a half hour greatest hits.
It's from a Thursday afternoon podcast,
just before Monday,
Thursday.
I know a couple of years ago when
maybe from earlier this year.
I don't know how it fucking works.
All right.
Have a great weekend and
I'll see you on Monday
three,
three
B.
I got a quick times Vegas other than
when I went down to the pool because I go
down to the pool.
I'm down there to me,
it's fucking j lie ahead who's been
killing it in front of me. And uh,
the lovely Niyyah and our cousins and
were hang around a cousin. I mean,
and we're hanging out down the pool and
they're doing the usual shit, you know,
if you're a redhead and he'd go
down to the pool, like, yeah,
you're just asking for people to all,
you know,
look how white you are. You
know, like, I never noticed.
It's like I'm fucking around myself.
I've been around myself since the 60s,
the late sixties.
I know how white I am and if
I ever forget how white I am,
there's always somebody
there to remind me.
Yeah,
sorry. I don't know if you've noticed
your skin tone. What am I meditating?
Floating up out of my body? All right,
so these people are with go, c'mon,
c'mon in the poor. And like, I
don't want to go in the pool.
I don't want to go on the fucking
pool. You know? They're like, why? No,
why don't you want to go to the pool?
You know why? Because the fucking,
yeah,
look at, look at these people. Look
at them, look at them. And you're gay.
You're getting you, you know,
would you take a bath with all,
with any one of the
people that you see here,
these fucking just masses of human beings.
There's not enough chlorine and a fucking
pool to kill whatever the fuck they're
dragging in the pool. You know, it was
like, I finally end up going to the pool.
Then everybody made fun of how white
my fucking alabaster chest was,
a da that I had to stay in
the shade of the fucking, uh,
the lifeguard's chair,
you know,
you know, I had a show to
do, I'm being a professional.
I can't come out stage later,
half in the bag looking like
a lot of stuff right now.
I've got to do my little song and
dance later on that night. So anyway,
so I ended up getting in the fucking pool
against what I wanted to do, you know?
Okay.
And then I get out of the
pool. First of all, for my age,
I am an absolutely
phenomenal top shelf shape.
All right? I got to tell you, the fucking,
just the deaf fuck the humanity
that I saw poolside in Las Vegas,
the fucking humanity
keyword manatee,
not the skep step on a Jim Gaffigan.
I just realized he used to use that
reference and I'm pretty sure he used it.
I can't remember how the fuck he used it,
but if he used it to
describe a fat pale torso,
not really pale border, whatever the
fucking Shit I saw the side of the,
he was dead on that.
Oh my God.
Is there anything worse than seeing
a tattoo come of age? You know?
Okay,
Jesus Christ, if you get
a tattoo, you better.
You better just make the mental decision
that you're going to pay 90 x for the
rest of your fucking life.
Cause when you don't do it,
I saw this guy down at the pool.
All right?
He had like not only the worst tattoo
she you've ever seen in your life,
like the worst placement.
You know what I mean?
Like you get one like on the side of
your arm up by your shoulder that looks
good, right on the bicep.
That looks good. You know Joe,
somebody got gets one right over there.
Voicebox like I don't give a fuck
what you have surrounding that.
That leads into that part of the,
of the, of the work or the piece,
whatever they call it. It looks fucking
horrible. Leg Tattoos, horrific,
horrific.
So this fucking jerk off.
He has basically the exact sort of like
tribal thing that the rock has except he
doesn't look tribal. He looks
like an accountant, you know,
and he doesn't work out.
So just imagine if the
rock was his pasty as I was
and it never worked down in his life,
but it has that same tattoo that
starts at the elbow, goes up the arm,
over the shoulder and
covers one whole peck.
But the way this guy had it done was
it didn't cover his whole packet,
came swinging in and went right above his,
his man nipple.
So now all of the,
all of that is like colored in.
So because of the pace genus of his torso,
your eye is just drawn
to his right nipple.
Is he standing in the fucking pool?
My neck was sore from shaking
my head at people. It was,
it was absolutely fucking
horrific, right? So, so anyways,
um, I go back up to the, uh, I go back
up to the hotel room, right? You know,
gotta make sure that I'm all shipshape
for my God damn show and I put on the
news and what are they ended
up doing a story about,
they start doing a story
about the amount of uh,
fecal matter found in public pools
right after I just got out
of a God damn pool. You know,
and I know what people always think,
oh, stay away from where the kids are.
Stay away from the Kiddie Pool.
Right. Stay away from that.
They always blame the fucking kids.
Will I,
you know something after seeing
what I saw a poolside, you know,
there weren't a lot of kids in there,
but I guarantee you somebody's got a cola.
I know this is fucking disgusting,
but people, you've,
you're basically bathing,
you know what's even more fucked
up is Vegas is just like, you know,
people fly in from all over the world.
You're taking a fucking aids bath,
you know, with a shot of fucking, ah,
what the hell is that shit that came out.
But it killed people so fast
that it just burned out.
Everybody just ran into the woods.
The fuck was that shit cold.
Ah, Christ. I can't
remember a bola. That's it.
With a shot of a Bulla or whatever.
Food poisoning.
I don't know what it is.
A salmon, Ellis shower,
whatever the fuck you want to call it.
I'm done with public pools.
The only pool that I will
ever swim in again is my pool.
If I ever get one or the pool of some
hot chick that I want to fucking bank
cause I have needs permission.
That's the only way it's going to go down.
Other than that, you know, I'll
just go, I'll just go take a bath.
That way I'm out of the sun. You know,
I'll take a couple of vitamin E pills,
whatever the fuck it is you get from
the sun. Other than skin cancer,
I'm done with it.
You know what America needs to implement
after years and years of calling the
French people smelly.
You know,
that's Kinda like the thing when we went
over to France and saved their ass for
the second time last century. Oh wait, did
we do it once? We did it one time, right?
I can't fucking remember.
So anyways,
we've always made fun of the
French father. They smell.
If you ever watched a bugs bunny
growing up, man, you saw pepe Le Pew.
If you noticed he had a French accent.
You know,
that's the kind of Shit you couldn't get
away with today because of a political
correctness. I guess they were basically
saying that you know, that they stuck.
But I'll tell you one thing that the
French have when it comes to hygiene over
Americans. All right? Is
the buddy day. All right?
I can guarantee you if I ever go
swimming in a public pool again,
it's going to be at Fred's
Ellis is a bunch of Americans.
I know. I've been over to England. I never
saw it, but day over there, you know,
but day is basically a car
wash for your asshole Ed. Uh,
you know, it leaves you feeling refreshed,
puts a fucking smile on your face.
And evidently in France, she's so fucking
happy. You forget to put on deodorant,
but I'll tell you right now, you can
jump in that pool. I bet the night,
but they're not talking
about that shit over there.
Hey, how are you? It's bill burr and it
is the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
July 26th,
2010 look at that hot
the last Monday in July,
another summer month flying by.
And once again there they are.
The goddamn banker cuts just
staring you in the face,
sticking their hands out there.
A little grubby fucking hands asking
for another pound of flesh as they do at
the end of every month.
Don't they actually talked to a buddy
mine who's outside the business and got to
check the other day, right? And was,
you know, bitching about the taxes,
was talking about all the taxes taken
out. And he goes, thanks a lot Obama,
you know,
and then I got into a fucking argument
trying to get this dude to stop blaming
the standing fucking president.
You got to get to the fucking guys
who pull, pull, put the dude in there.
Not even put the dude in there, but
can take the dude out. You know,
it doesn't fucking make a difference. I
remember I voted for Ron Paul. You know,
I always vote for those guys who,
Ralph Nader's and all that,
the Ross Perot's and
everybody always ever,
he always tells me it's a fucking
waste of a vote. Is it though?
You tell me one fucking thing different
that Obama's doing that McCain wouldn't
be doing. I know there's little subtle
differences, you know, he's going to,
rather than giving it to the fucking rich,
he's going to give it to the fucking poor.
You know, both their philosophy suck.
And now in bankers just keep
getting richer and fucking richer.
And it just, it just blows my mind.
You know, it's one thing I've,
I've learned finally figured out over
all this shit, that whole rich guy,
we'll give it to the rich and they'll
create jobs and it'll trickle down.
The keyword is trickle and we're all going
to be sitting there with that tongues.
Ah, Eh, trying to catch a
drop of fucking prosperity.
And then on the other side, if
you just give people shit, you,
you don't help them. They come back
the next day like a fucking cat,
you know, waiting for another
bowl of milk. It's like, no, dude,
I was trying to give you nourishment
so you could go fucking, you know,
have enough strength to go milk a cow
or whatever the fuck you supposed to do.
Oh, I didn't know. I thought
you were going to give a dog.
This is where I get the free
milk from. All right, day.
I get the fuck out of here.
Fucking piece of shit. You
know, anybody got a, I've got a,
I've got a bomb for a friend always
asking for money. You ever do that?
And you're doing well in your life and
you feel guilty and they get themselves
into a jam. Man, I'm in
fucking jam, you know,
and it's everybody's fucking fault.
But theirs and their girls got 'em on the
outs and the cops fucking arrested. Um,
and Eh, they're going to put
them in fucking jail. You know,
or whatever's going to happen.
They're going to take the fucking car
and they need 500 bucks and you fucking
give it to him. Right. And what do you do?
They get out of that jam for fucking 10
minutes and what within a month they're
in. Another fucking jam or
they learned anything. No,
and a lot of times it's
an even worst predicament.
I'm going to stop saying jam
like I'm in the fucking seventies
started off me doing the character.
I'm in a jam and then I just
started saying it is me.
And I felt like fucking the dude who
drives the mystery machine on Scooby Doo.
I wouldn't say that he was too much
of a square.
Right.
Fucking the hot chicken,
the missionary position.
Am I really doing Scooby Doo
jokes? Um, the fuck was his name.
Was it Fred? This ascot. Okay.
That's all I'm saying, dude.
It's all fucking bullshit.
I believe there's plenty of fucking money
if these fucking banker assholes will
stop taking all of it in
these corporations. I Dunno.
Does it, does it really cost?
Well, it really costs like
fucking 40 bucks a tee shirt.
If you pay somebody a decent wage to
make it the really got to have some eight
year old make $3 a fucking day.
You know?
Isn't there a a fucking middle ground?
Yeah, I don't get it. I just
don't get it. I, I just refuse.
I don't blame politicians anymore,
democrat or Republican.
I just don't fucking blame him anymore.
It's an absolute,
it's a fucking shit storm.
And look at,
look at a shitstorm Obama came
walking into, that's like, Yo,
y'all hosting one of those hoarder shows
and you walk into the house and it's
just piled high was shit.
Trillions of fucking things that
need to be thrown out. Right?
And then what?
You give the guy 10 minutes to clean out
the fucking house and then after that
it's his mass. Well, they'll
fucking mess you made
out of fucking though. I gotta I gotta
admit like politics is just like baseball.
I stopped watching in June of last year,
you know,
although I'm starting
to come around again,
I'm coming back around
to baseball and I'm, I'm,
I'm like in the nationals and I'm
liking the Pittsburgh pirates.
I'm coming back into the
fucking back door. All right,
going, I'm going down to tier three. I'm
bored shitless with Yankees, red sox.
I gotta admit I'm fucking burned out.
Burned out with this shit.
It's just like whatever.
We won the fucking world series.
Then we want another one that's the
end of the movie. Roll the credits.
I got to fucking try to give a shit,
act like I give a fuck
12 times a goddamn year.
Um, I don't know. Yeah. But I don't
watch politics either. Um, I just, uh,
and those, those political
fucking shows on TV, I just,
I can't get into them because,
uh,
there's nobody really taken the people
that I feel need to be taken to task.
And at the end of the day,
the people I feel need to
be taken to task are, uh,
it's, it's all based on shit I
watched on youtube, you know,
so who the fuck am I to bitch? So I just
tapped out. I just said, you know what?
Fuck it. Fuck it. I'm
going to get myself a bear.
Okay. You know, maybe get a pistol.
Learn how to shoot the fucking thing.
You know what a beer sounds
really good right now.
If I ever drank a beer
on the fucking podcast,
I think I'm gonna think I'm
going to go fucking get one.
Do I got time to go run and get it?
You know what?
It's not one of those beers you can really
drink out of a fucking can you get a
poured into a glass and I, you know
what? I have the ability to hit pause,
don't I? I really do. Let me see if
I know how to do it here. Ah, Jesus.
This is always tough. Do I hit
play? Do I hit record? Hit record.
All right.
And with the magic of the pause button,
I am back and I got to fucking
brew right in front of me. See,
this is what I'm doing.
I don't give a shit anymore.
I gave a fuck and a all you end
up doing it. You just start.
You just start yelling at people in bars.
That's all given a fuck get ya.
You know what are you gonna make a sign
in on some street corner honk.
If you give a fuck, that's,
that's going to stop the banks.
You can't do it. I quit. I give up.
I don't give a shit.
Just tell me what to believe.
I don't fucking care anymore.
I want to get a gun though.
I really do stand on my fucking
porch waving it at people.
Just be that guy. We always knew he
was going to be a problem. I mean,
you had a gun. I've got a gun too.
What? I'm responsible. I'll keep it in.
I'll keeping him safe. That
way. If somebody breaks in,
uh, I go, can you wait a second?
I've never understood that. You know,
it's like if you're going to
have a fucking gun, you know,
to really protect yourself,
don't you have to sleep with it.
Like fucking Tony Soprano.
And the second to last episode on the
Soprano's when you thought this Tony
Montana ending was going to happen
and then it didn't, I don't get this.
You keep it in the gun safe and then you
keep the bullets in the trunk of your
car, right? You keep the scope
up in the attic. You know,
as, as the intruder is chasing
you around your fucking house,
you grabbing different parts of the gun,
assembling it,
stick it under your fucking pillowcase.
Like Beretta is not what
you're supposed to do.
You know what?
I've never owned a nightstand in my life.
I'm going to get a gun too. This is a, I
should have done this on the 4th of July.
I'm doing a podcast.
I'm talking about getting a gun and
I'm drinking a fucking beer and I,
one of those pussy ones.
Either he's a fucking one
pint Boddington's pub Ale,
you know one of those ones,
you open it up and it's got that fucking,
I don't know what it has in there. That
metal ball at rattles around you look in,
you can never find it.
They had no idea what it is,
but for some reason he never had the
curiosity enough to fucking gut the can to
see what it looks like. I like the
mystery. I like the mystery of it.
I don't know what it is.
Isn't it weird how a fucking beer
like quenches your thirst and then
automatically makes you
thirsty again? Once the deal,
it, it cools. It's, Ooh, Ooh,
Ooh. Um, speaking of guns,
Oh, what'd you guys do? If I just got
absolutely shit faced on this podcast,
I feel great and I wouldn't even
think that I had a drinking problem.
I can just keep hitting pause.
You guys wouldn't even
know and technically because I'm
talking to you. I'm not drinking alone.
All right?
Isn't that what George Thorogood one off
the fucking rails when he did that song,
I drink alone.
The adjunct can loon
rarely and they started putting on the
weight and he's still wear those rattle
snake skin fucking pants with
matching top. You know, at
some point, I mean, dude,
I should fucking talk.
I should really talk with my fucking,
my God damn ma round,
smooth white belly.
It's fucking beer at Goddamn quarter
to nine at night is not going to help
least it's hot as fuck in here.
You know my old bastard fucking
neighbor downstairs is home.
You know, like I bring my voice down
because I don't need the bullshit.
I can't fucking wait in. I got a
new special coming out. All right,
it's coming out in September
and I get a feel on this thing.
It's going to fucking hit and it's going
to hit hard and I'm finally going to go
out and buy a gun damn house out here and
a day I do when I load up that fucking
you all right. You like that. Even
though I'm dreaming about buying a house,
I'm still a broke ass hole and I have to
move my shit myself when I load up that
you all okay?
And I bring that fucking tailgate
down one last time. All the way down.
That little fucking Faggot,
he little bumper,
that's only an inch off the ground to
make it easier for pussies like me to load
their bureau in there.
You know I'm going to ring his doorbell
and I'm going to get in his face and be
like, listen old man. I don't know when.
I don't know how,
but I'm going to fucking get back.
I'm going to do something to you.
I don't know what the fuck I'm gonna I,
you know I sound like I sound like
fucking jumping Jeff Farmer right now.
I'm coming at you full force.
You turn the tables on me
in the wrong way. Old Man.
No, I don't know. I can, I can, I, you
know what, I don't do the revenge thing.
I told you that guys a long time
ago. I don't do it. You know,
if I wasn't so worried that
he'd have a heart attack,
I really want to scare them one
day. Just do a fake sneeze, right
close to them, make them shit
his pants a little bit, you know,
take a Geritol shit and it's
fucking Dickies. Miserable bastard
really is.
He's really the fucking ghost of a,
was it future? Was that the one that
was a, I don't know what the fuck he is.
All right, let's move on here. I
talked about getting a gun. It's on,
and this is a thing too,
because I'm doing this podcast
so early in the week,
um,
you know, I, I actually, I went through
a bunch of old emails and you know,
I get a ton of emails
from you guys and uh,
and I know sometimes people get
upset when I don't read them.
I just get a ton of emails, but I just
went back because it's only Thursday.
So I didn't really have that
many current ones. And I, uh, I,
I saw some gems that I missed and I
guess one week I was talking about the
amount of people that Stalin
had killed verse Hitler.
And how come people
when they bring up evil,
they don't talk more about
Yosef Stalin considering it,
it seems to me that he killed like
three times plus a little bit more.
I mean what, what, what exactly
are Hitler's, uh, exact numbers?
Cause I know he says that they killed
600, 6 million, 600 and Jesus Christ,
6 million Jewish people.
But I also know that he killed gaze.
He killed, uh, uh, I think he killed
blacks. If there's only blacks in Germany.
Um, maybe some Catholics,
I dunno, whatever.
Traders, people who helped out
Jewish people. I mean what,
I mean did he get another
fucking million out of that?
I don't know what his exact number is,
but I'm pretty safe.
It's pretty safe to say that it's
under 10 million. So I was saying like,
you know, Joseph, Yosef, Stalin or where
the fuck you said, or you know, this,
this son of a bitch killed like twice
as many of that if you give Hitler 10
million. All right. So that was basically
what I've referred on. So this game,
this game made a great point. He
actually wrote to me and he said, um,
I ran across something I thought you
might find interesting. Uh, I know you're,
how you talk about Hitler versus
Mussolini Versus Stalin and the number of
deaths attributed to each one of them.
Well,
I don't think they actually
did much of the dirty work.
They outsourced it to a Indian kids
who did it for half the price. Hahaha.
And it's actually a decent joke.
If I read it better, I'm seriously,
they had it done and they
didn't do it themselves.
So thinking about the fact that they
didn't do much of the dirty work got me
thinking about who did the
dirty work for themselves. Um,
after a little research I came across,
uh,
the person who I think was the
baddest motherfucker of World War Two.
And A, I love the suspense. He
builds up. Was He from the u s no.
Was He from Germany? Ah. Was
He from England? No, cigar.
Mother fucker. Was He from
Philly? Finland? Fuck yeah. Seven.
This dude was from Finland.
The guy's name was,
and I'm going to butcher this because even
the, the, the phonetic pronunciation, I,
I don't know how to say the guy's name.
Maybe anybody in Finland.
And what's a fuck isn't, is that
Helsinki? I have no fucking idea. Uh, um,
CMO. Hey Ha. I don't know how the fuck
to say it. My best attempt at the,
at the pronunciation of the last name is,
what did he say?
How Ha as in hat hat?
How Ha Cmo, how hair, I don't know.
Anyways,
he was nicknamed white death due to the
fact that he would operate in the snow
and had a completely white uniform so
he couldn't be seen. All right, let's,
let's go onto the Wikipedia. Let me read
about this guy. The first thing you know,
if you look at, look at, look,
this guy up, it's s I m o h.
A.
Y. H. A. M. Live to be 96
years old. All right. Nickname.
The white death by the Russians is
highest recorded number of kills.
He was a sniper,
was 505.
He has the highest recorded number
of kills 505 kills in any major war.
All right. Uh, before entering
combat, he was a farmer and a hunter.
His farmhouse was reportedly full
of trophies for marksmanship.
So I guess he was a natural, he was kinda
like the Wayne Gretzky of killing shit.
Right? It was during war,
the world, the winter war,
1939 to 1940 between Finland
and the Soviet Union.
Isn't that interesting? They
call it the winter war. Um,
well maybe that was an aspect of
World War II. I have no idea. Anyways,
the winter war,
uh,
that he began his duty as a sniper and
fought for the Finnish army against the
Red Army and temperatures of minus
40 and minus 20 degrees Celsius.
So what's that like 80 degrees Fahrenheit?
I have no idea. It's fucking cold out.
Um, dress completely in white camouflage.
Hey Ha. Whatever the fuck he said.
Call his name. Hey Ya. Uh,
was credited with 505 confirmed
kills of Soviet soldiers.
542 unconfirmed if unconfirmed
deaths are included.
The unofficial finished frontline figure
with the battlefield battlefield of
Cola places the number
of his kills at over 800,
cause I guess he also had a sub machine
gun and people give him credit for
killing another 200 people,
thus bringing his credits up
to at least 705 remarkably,
this is the biggest thing here.
This motherfucker did this in fewer than
a hundred days with very limited amount
of daylight per day.
So he just sort of woke up,
I guess, you know, he's killing
like seven people a day.
If he's up for 16 hours
once every couple of hours.
Uh, what else can I
say about this guy? Um,
I missed a part where he got to formed
part of the way through there. He was, uh,
one
of the fuck is it now the tech
to hae a was to compact the snow.
You can pack the snow in front of him so
that the shot wouldn't disturb the snow
and reveal his position.
He also kept snow in his mouth so that
when breathing this steam would not give
them away. How have they not
made a movie about this guy?
He preferred to use iron sights
rather than telescopic sites.
For all your gun nuts to
present a smaller target.
Uh Oh,
I see.
Cause the sniper must raise his head
higher when using a telescopic sight to
prevent visibility risks. A telescopic
sights glass can fog up easily.
Okay.
I,
the Soviets tried a number of ways to
get rid of him counter sniper's artillery
strikes and filing.
On May 6th,
the guy was shot through the jaw during
combat by a Russian soldier. The,
the bullet tumbled upon
impact and left his head.
Fellow soldier picked him up.
Half his head was missing.
He regained consciousness
seven days later,
the day peace was declared. Shortly
after the war, uh, this dude was,
went straight from corporal
to a second lieutenant,
the highest jumping rank in the
history of the Finnish army. Uh Wow.
Did that bore, I'll be like, I didn't
bore you guys too much but a day ago.
And they asked him later on in
life, did, did it bother you?
The amount of people that you kill,
which is such a Douchey fucking question.
And he just basically said, look, I
was doing the job they told me to do.
Like they all end up fucking same.
Did it bother you?
Did it bothered me that I killed the
guys who were trying to kill me? Uh,
no it didn't.
I'm sure a couple of dumb fucks who
thought they were in the clear and got up
and took a Piss,
you know,
and he kind of felt bad like Jesus Christ
who can at least piss behind a tree.
You know? Maybe that wouldn't make
you feel bad. What do you guys think?
Do you think you'd feel bad?
Um,
I would just think if I went to war,
I've always felt this,
that the second the battle started,
I would be,
I would be the guy crying in the Fox hole.
But if I could ever just kill that first
fucking person, I would just be like,
all right, well, you know,
fuck it now. And, uh,
I just think I would be so
filled with anger and fear that,
uh,
I dunno.
I Dunno. That's, and I have no fucking,
and you know those people who fight in
wars, man, people that join the service,
Jesus Christ. I, I don't know. I,
I don't think I could, you know,
as much as people sit there
and they talk about, you know,
the balls it takes to do stand up,
you know,
it, it really pales in fucking
comparison when, you know,
if you just talk about someone who goes
into the peace corps and is trying to
bring water to a tribe, forget about
somebody who's fucking going to war.
And speaking of, let's talk about stand
up terminology. Here's something that, um,
has been bugging me lately
is I've noticed that, um,
in this happens, you know, people
come up with new words like a,
you know,
I'm chilling,
I'm going to use like hip hop slang
because that's always the easiest.
You know what I can,
as long as I can really think of,
and then they just become words. But,
uh, just as a, as a, as a standup comic,
purest I've noticed, you know,
when I get into it with the crowd,
when somebody heckles me and then
I give him shit back, I get emails.
I was at your second show,
sat on Saturday night.
I loved the way you heckled that guy
in the audience after he heckled you.
Um,
heckling is done by the crowd.
The comedian does not heckle the crowd.
He can play with the
crowd and he can fucking,
I don't even know what it's called. When
you, when you fucking murderer a heckler,
you destroy him but you're
not heckling him. All right,
you're up there trying to do your rack.
The only way for a comedian to,
to heckle a crowd as if he,
if he sat in the crowd and the hope and
the whole crowd got up on stage and then
tried to do some to some
sort of performance and I
interrupted and fucked up
their performance. But when they
tell me to go fuck themselves,
fuck myself, they're not
heckling me. Jesus Christ.
You would think that I would actually
have the decency to look up heckle.
Why don't I do that? Heckle
definition. Goddammit.
That beer tasted good and
I get a fucking 6:54 AM
definition for heckle.
Uh, okay. Here we go.
Try to embarrass and annoyed by questions.
Jibes or objections.
Badger try to annoy someone speaking
or performing in public by questions.
Jibes or objections in
bad. There you go. See,
that's why you can't because you're not
trying to perform in public. All right,
I skipped over the shit in parentheses,
so let me read that again.
Try to heckling is trying to embarrass
and annoy someone speaking or performing
in public by questions. Jibes or
objections, badger or whatever.
That's what it means.
So the comedian can't heckle the crowd
because the crowd is not on stage trying
to give a performance.
So for the love of God,
stop sending me fucking emails saying
you loved how I heckled the crowd.
I didn't do that. It's like telling
a guitarist, I love your drum solo.
Did that make any sense? Is this
alcohol taking? I haven't drank,
I haven't fucking eight in a minute.
You know,
this beer is fucking delicious. You know
what makes a beer like this? Tastes good.
A good beer glass.
Do you guys have beer glasses?
Talking to the men out there and the few
women out there who are, fuck you guys.
Women aren't into beer
glasses. Are you, you know,
do I have any lesbians on my podcast?
Maybe you guys have the brains to
like beer glasses. Um, Jesus Christ.
You know,
I usually don't make any sense but me
buzz doing this podcast is going to make
even less and less sense.
That's a fucking sign of maturity of
beer glass. And that's another thing.
If you want to stave off the fact
that you kind of think that you have a
drinking problem is if in your house,
if you have the proper glasses for
whatever alcohol you're drinking,
okay, you're drinking whiskey
out of a disc Dixie Cup.
Me Stuttering like a shit head.
That was a good line too.
If you're drinking whiskey out
of a Dixie Cup take to uh, yeah,
there's really no way,
you know,
a little vodka in a sippy cup.
She kids crying in the corner
because he's fucking hungry.
Uh, hang on one second. Hang on a
second. What do I go? What do I got here?
Hey Paul, let me call you back.
I'm doing my podcast. All right.
All right man. Take it easy. Um,
all right. Where the fuck am I?
Yeah. You know what I mean? But if you
have the right, you have the proper glass.
I have the classic 16 ounce,
you know,
you'd pour a Heineken
in this type of thing.
I actually got those
Sam Adams glasses too.
You know the ones that they had where
they got some sort of special glass thing
at the bottom and it makes the beer,
you know, the Sam Adams and swirl up.
They're really cool glasses. But what I
don't like is they only hold 12 ounces,
you know? And it's just
like, well, what about me?
Who likes to go 16 ounces at a time?
You know?
All right.
I'm not even being funny right now.
I'm just fucking sitting here enjoying a,
there's nothing better.
One Nice fucking beer.
But can you ever stop?
You know what's funny is my
girl's not here right now.
He'd be funny if I'm just sitting here
in my fucking boxers and just, just,
she comes home and I'm about ready to
go on the row front of the five days,
and then she just comes home and I'm just
fucking sitting him buzzed, you know,
t shirt, boxers, socks. I mean,
I'm just dressed like I'm unemployed
and all I gotta do is just start giving
a shit. Why am I such a Dick? All right,
let's continue on here. Um, yeah,
that would be unsightly will
in our speaking of shit.
That's just fucking
insightful. To use a, a,
a segue from the 1980s,
um,
I was flying back from New York and uh,
you know,
it's a real peppy pet
peeve of mine is these,
these mother fucking like regular
looking people who just get here.
They kicked his shoes off
during the flight. All right?
And then not wearing any socks.
All right?
So it's gross enough that she,
you have your bare feet on that airline
carpet where God knows what is in the
rug.
Okay.
You know how filthy the fucking
errors in the God damn tube.
They never recycled that fucking air.
You just breathing.
I mean it's like 80% carbon dioxide,
right?
So what the fuck you think is in the rug?
Have you ever seen him shampooer
goddamn rug in between flights.
They don't do it. And you put your
bare feet on it. This what kills me.
This is regular fucking people af
after they've kicked her shoes off,
they have to go to the bathroom.
They get up and they think walked down
the aisle into the bathroom with no
fucking socks or shoes on.
It's the most disgusting.
I saw this girl sitting next to me. She
had one of those uh, English Australian.
I can't pick out the accent,
you know,
the next time you fucking European
shit on what animals? We are over here.
One of your fucking, one of you fucking
birds who was sitting next to me,
got up with their flip flops on now kicked
them off. And then what? She actually,
I'll give her credit. She did walk halfway
to the bathroom and then came back,
you know, and I was like, all
right, she has some class,
but she had her hair up and
she had flakes behind her rear.
It's disgusting how fucking flight.
And I could stop looking at it every time
I'd glance over and then I would just
keep making these noises going.
Ah.
Then she sort of glance at me and I
pretend like I didn't do what she probably
thought I had Tourette's and she didn't
realize that I'm reacting to the fucking
fucking flakes behind you. You'll
kind of a mother, are you going to be,
you can't even clean behind
your own fucking years.
Put your head down and go walk
barefoot to the fucking airplane,
goddamn bathroom and clean yourself
up before I slap the shit out of you.
All right, what else do
we got here? All right,
here's a good youtube video for the
week as the fucking booze is starting to
kick in a Boddingtons. I highly recommend
it. All right, you youngsters out there,
you're probably not gonna
like it. Um, all right.
But as your voice gets deeper and your
ball stuck to drop even further into the
toilet bowl, I'm telling you it's a
beer you're going to fucking like,
what am I doing here? What
the hell am I? All right.
Note to self, don't drink when you
do the podcast anymore. Would you,
would you guys enjoy podcasts? So I just
got completely shit faced. The thing is,
is it's only an hour long, so it's
kind of hard to get drunk that quick.
I can get pretty buzzed,
you know, really bill,
is that what we're here we
were down to right now is like,
you're going to do like some fucking
stunt like David Blaine. Bill,
why don't you do the podcast in a
fucking block ice? He had dumb cunt.
I think it's time for a special guest.
At some point.
I gotta I gotta get another special
guest on this podcast. Um, all right,
plowing ahead here. Um, here's a
youtube video to watch for this week.
A baby preacher with subtitles.
Uh,
it's just fucking awesome.
It's a a,
I dunno,
this baby who guesses goes
to church every fucking day.
And his watched these preachers preaching
and then they gave the baby the Mike
and it's just sort of walking around
going, hey, eh, talking baby talk.
But somebody transcribes what the kid
is saying and I swear to God it the way
they put it up there it
right as you read it.
The baby says it and it sounds like
the baby's saying and it's fucking,
and it's a visual joke and I'm trying to
explain it here. All right. Underrated.
Overrated for this week.
I'm doing this at a half hour in knowing
full well that I have to somehow fill
up another 20 fucking minutes.
All right.
Overrated for this week. This
is a great one. Overrated.
When Chames this dude says,
I hate the annoying clink clank
sound with a fucking passion.
What is wrong with the people?
Huh? What's wrong with people?
Seriously, the world is not loud.
You have to fucking add to it.
You know they,
they do believe the sounds will make
them better people or make life better.
You know what dude?
You want such a great role to your right.
Brought that fucking sentence. Okay. Oh,
what do they believe the sounds will make
them better people or make their life
better? I found it most
annoying and of in invasive,
I find it the art. Jesus Christ. I'm
never drinking on the podcast again.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right. What
is wrong with Pete? Where am I?
I find it the most annoying and
invasive thing I am forced to listen to,
even with closed windows, but
there's so peaceful. Yeah.
Um,
if you fucking like the sound,
why don't you put them up inside your
home and have the fucking fan going
in any way? What gives anybody the right
to push their taste on others? Dude,
I totally agree. It's like if you're
going to make smokers smoke outside,
then you want to make these fucking wind
chime. People take that shit indoors.
I can't tell you how annoying that is.
It's an,
you know what's annoying about it is it's
an annoying sound that's trying to be
fucking spiritual. That's what
kills me. It's even, um, it's,
it's more annoying than just the loud,
annoying sound that's fucking annoying.
Cause at least the loud annoying sound
has the fucking courage to be annoying.
Those fucking things. They
actually, they're there.
They're there. You don't want,
when I go on youtube and just get some
fucking wind chime sounds for all you
dumb cons out there who do yoga,
you know and actually think that these
fucking things sound good. Here we go.
Wind fucking chimes. Youtube.
Let's see what we got. Here we go.
Yeah, cause somebody fucking loves
him so much. They put up a video.
Here we go for all you can't
see out there. Here it is. Okay.
Ooh,
I got to met.
Those are nice.
This isn't fair. This guy's got fuck. He's
got the professional grade level ones.
He thinks look like the exhaust on a
God damn. Oh that's giant wind chimes.
All right. I just learned
something. I don't mind. Giant
wind chimes. Oh, here's one.
Here's one of these little douchey. Once
you get it, a fucking hardware store.
Typical Youtube, you just can't put wind
chimes. Elliot, he beautiful wind chime.
It's just the Cantisano.
There it is.
You know what the great thing is,
is they're made out of metal.
So when you rip them off,
you have a fucking blunt object to beat
your neighbor to death with [inaudible].
That's what you do.
And then you dip it and fucking peroxide
bleach and you hook it back up again.
Let those a and e cuts
figure out that murder.
Well my and murdered on his porch.
You know, somehow they find,
you know, and a fucking, I don't know,
an eighth of an inch of his face
imprint on that fucking wind chime.
If you ever watch shows ane he
thinks how they catch people, it's,
it's like it's not even fucking fair.
Do you ever see the one as I take
another healthy swap. I got news for you.
I'm having another beer.
This might be the new thing.
I might do this shit Thursday night.
Take a night off from stand up.
Tell my chick to hit the fucking bricks.
Is anything better than
drinking your own goddamn house?
It just makes you want to start screaming
about the shit you own. You know
I paid for this shit.
You hear that old man downstairs,
I'm going to get louder and
he's going to come up here.
That would be the ultimate podcast.
You know the thing about old people is
you always have to worry that they are a
fucking [inaudible]. They fought in
a fucking work cause I never had,
I never have.
So I have total respect
for fucking veterans in the
fact that they still got it
in him. You know, that would be insane.
One night if I actually just totally
pissed him off and he really did fight in
the Korean War and he just fucking
through whatever that fucking thing is you
throw up when you, when you got to climb
up the rope on the side of the building,
you know that, that, that fucking
land fish hook thing throws it up.
Dan just climbs up,
comes over my railing as I'm sitting
here doing this podcast, half in the bag,
he's got a kitchen knife between
his teeth, like a fucking pirate.
What would I do?
I've probably taken 12 karate classes
in my life and they've all been like,
yeah, you know, six years apart. Yeah.
Fucking guide. Coming
and filet me, you know,
I don't fucking know. I just sat back
and I just lost the screen here. Yeah.
So whatever wind chimes are
fucking overrated. They really are.
But I gotta tell you, if you get
the giant ones, the giant ones,
a nice listen to the giant ones at
giant ones. Have a nice tone to him.
It's a little deeper.
I think I figured it out.
Yeah.
Ooh,
come on man. You gotta admit that's
not bad if you let go of the anger,
your childhood, right? Let
go your anger for a second.
Si
sound of a ship in the background.
Uh,
hoshin coming up on the beach.
You have it. Get to that point, right?
When are you going to get relaxed and let
go? And then you get so fucking scared.
You get right back into the anger and
then you want to punch somebody in fucking
yoga pants. Okay. Um, all right. Let
enough with the fucking wind chimes here.
That was really painting a picture
of their fucking Michael Winslow.
I think it's time for more booze.
What do you guys think?
How about a nice healthy sip?
Ah, God damn it. That's fucking delicious.
He poor bastards and oh and oh and a,
you pull pastors and Aa and that was
one good thing about the trip, uh,
when I went back is actually got to do
opening Anthony and I'm going to do it
again.
Um, next week, probably
again the Tuesday again,
I'm on the exact same flight
back to Los Angeles. I did it,
the opiate Anthony show this past Tuesday,
popped in there for like an hour.
I had a good fucking time.
Didn't get a chance to argue with Anthony,
but you know, it was still good
to see them as adorable as ever.
All right, let's uh,
let's plow ahead here. Um,
let's get to some more fucking
overrated shit. Overrated.
Super expensive TVS.
Who the fuck needs to
spend two grand on a TV?
I know the super clear, et Cetera,
but it's not like it's, it's some,
a huge jump.
My eight year old Sony still works great.
The picture is fine.
If I want to watch some great TV,
I'll just go to one of the a hundred
bars in the city that have 80 of them
slapped on the walls.
Which another thing,
which is another thing that's overrated
cookie cutter bars with a million TVs
and zero atmosphere.
But I digress
you guys.
You guys are fucking good writers and I
like how you said I digress rather than
me last week when I say,
but I digressed in the past tense because
I never used that expression animal
moron. Um, dude, I have to
totally agree with you. In fact,
I would still have an
old school TV if I'm,
I did move from New York, New York to La.
I was going to keep my old school one.
I had no problem watching the
game on the old school square TV.
It didn't bug me. You know, I don't
need to see that. The inside of shacks,
I don't need to see shacks. Fucking,
you know, knows Cartlidge. Ever.
When I first got HD TV,
I was watching,
I was watching ESPN and like Stuart Scott
or one of those guys is doing it and
I'm like looking at his pores and I
could see actually a little bit of the
inside of his nose. His nose wasn't dirty
or nothing, but it was just, it's like,
dude,
all I need is just to hear the scores.
I'll tell you,
you know what's fucking overrated too,
and I hope it flops like
fucking David Beckham in La are.
Here's one great overrated
is fucking Shit in three d.
All right,
Avatar in three day,
who gives a fuck some butterfly
flying near your face.
You've got damn ferry. The fuck is
wrong with you and all of these idiots.
We're going to go out and buy three d TVs.
You dumb fucks if you buy a three d TV,
you know what you like?
You like those.
You were like one of those dumb shits
who keeps buying the new razor blades.
Has any razor blade work
better than the fucking,
all you needed was to one sucked too
was the shit three doesn't do underneath
your nose.
You got to pinch your nose,
like you're in a barbershop
in the 19 fucking twenties,
getting a straight razor shave
during a fucking three stooges film.
And then it goes all the way up to four.
And then they knew they couldn't do
five or did they do five and now they're
trying to act like the blades or even
fucking sharper. It's all bullshit.
The worst thing that ever happened to me,
one time I was doing college or something,
I think I was in Florida and
it was the double whammy.
I had a toilet tree,
a bag from tough crowd,
one of my favorite fucking shows to
do. Tough crowd with Colin Quinn. Um,
and one of the, one of the, the gift
bags they gave you what it was, was this,
this toiletry bag. It's a tough
crowd on it and Shit, you know?
And uh,
not only did I leave that for God
and in the bathroom, but my, uh,
my razor,
my twin bladed razor was in it
and they don't sell them anymore.
And ever since then I've had the
triple one and it just sucks. Hey,
if there's one whisker right in that,
that the skin between your fucking
nostrils, I can't get it, can't get it.
And I got to do all these different
fucking tricks. I'm doing it right now.
You just, I gotta like, you know,
make my nose look like that fucking
chicks knows in the Batman revenge movie.
Um, I bet she has no
problem. I was kind of mean.
Yeah. So do you guys do me a
favor? All right. Don't buy
it. Don't buy three D TV's.
Don't fucking buy them. Okay. Two
dimensional football is still the shit.
Are you really going to sit there on
the couch with your friend wearing those
stupid fucking glasses?
So what tos balls can be in your face.
Come on.
You want to see it in three d?
Go to the fucking game.
Now watch the TVS will be awesome.
The TVS would be awesome.
And eventually I'll get them. If you
guys know what a fucking hypocrite I am,
I bought the Prius, I defended it. And
slowly I'm going towards a challenger.
You know, I'm fucking totally
into conspiracy theory.
I'm actually still into that shit.
And I don't give a fuck.
Now I'm just sitting here in my
underwear doing a podcast on Thursday,
drinking a beer.
You know,
I quit fucking quit.
You know what I realize the other
day too is you don't want to be yet.
You start talking shit.
When you get into conspiracy theory,
you actually think that
like, you know you, you're a,
you're on to something dangerous and
people are going to start watching you.
But the bottom line is,
is the second you recorded it and there's,
you know, I just look at what
Mel Gibson is going through,
what he's going through with the
recorded shit that he's fucking said.
I'm not saying I said
anything racist or anything,
but everything that I've done in the
podcast and last three fucking years,
I could never pull a Schwartzenegger.
Let's just fucking just like totally
get into fantasy here.
Let's pretend that I actually somehow
became a huge fucking movie star.
Did it for 20 years and then get sick
of it and decided to run for political
office.
You could pick any one of my podcasts and
that would be the end of the campaign.
You know,
especially those ones early on when I
said con to every other fucking word,
I just, I go through phases. I
didn't, I get into golf for a minute.
I got into conspiracy theory for a minute.
I got in to say and confirm
a minute and I dunno,
it just all goes by the fucking wayside.
This is one of the reasons why it
can't sustain a fucking relationship.
Although I've been able to sustain
this one. You know, I finally realized,
uh, I'm, I'm, I'm going to stop fucking
running like that fucking Eagle Song,
that stupid song. Desperado you
know, I would like to do that.
I would like to do a three stooges slap
to everybody in the eagles is great of,
of musicians that they are those
cheese balls, songs that they wrote.
Desperado why don't you come to,
you'll say it is shut up Don Henley.
Just play the fucking drums.
Why don't you make a good fucking song?
This song's a class. I want it.
What the fuck? Who am I kidding?
I'd love to be making the fucking
bank. Those guys are making, you know,
I'm going to warn you guys we have,
when I make some fucking
money in this business,
I'm going to sell out like you've never
seen anybody sell out in your fucking
life. I don't know what I'm going
to do, but I'm going to tap out.
I know I am. I'm going to buy a modest
house in the middle of fucking nowhere.
I was actually looking at property
in like Wyoming and Montana.
I'm getting into that shit.
Having a fucking ranch couple of fucking
JAKKS God damn pig that you can boot in
the ass when your well water
isn't coming up that day.
Fucking shit ain't working.
Thing running over the hill.
Who's gonna report you?
You're out there by yourself,
dude.
You live in fucking Wyoming or Montana.
You get yourself a spread.
You know you might as,
it's like you have your own country
just walk around naked on your property.
Nothing but you and your fucking timble.
It's
just shooting shit slowly go and crazy
best friends with like a pheasant.
You know,
I fucking love it.
Learn how to grow fucking
vegetables and shit.
You want to stand that?
How fucking awesome that would be
because I'll still do stand up.
Just listen to this.
This is the fucking dream that for
some reason this week I'm totally into,
I'm going to live like that.
And then every other week I get to leave
the Ponderosa and then I fly into a
fucking metropolis. All
right? Get this, you know,
hang out with everybody who's was
living on top of one another. You know,
soak up that vibe for a minute. Hang
an extra day and go to a football game.
You know, eat somebody barbecue
that they claim is the greatest,
but it's always some dried out fucking
ribs and chicken with some sweet sauce.
The sauce always tastes the best to
meet. Always sucks. You know, once again,
I had some more smoked fucking barbecue
when I whatever the hell it is,
I always eat it.
I always believe like this is going to
be the one that's going to make me like
it. Um, anyways.
Now Dude,
I would love to fucking do that shit.
I don't know if I could do it.
I don't know if I could live way
out in the middle of nowhere.
Um, but I'm telling you
man, that, that really the,
the longer I'm in this business and the
longer I'm on flights and I'm sitting
next to people with fucking flakes behind
their rears and they're getting up and
they're walking to the bathroom
without their fucking shoes on,
and I'm listening to the male stewardess
on the mic. We have a very full flight,
you know,
if he can feed,
if he can feed and if they can
fit in the seat and Frannie deal,
please be caring. Hands down the people
on the flight. And they never are.
They never are.
People up there just stick and shit that
could easily fit in front of the seat
in front of them. And I swear to
God, man, it'd be like John Denver.
I learned how to fly a plane and by some
experimental fucking thing and crashing
it in the side of him out.
That's the thing though. That's,
that's the ultimate right there.
That th I'll tell you right now,
if you guys want to know what
it's like to do the fucking road,
and I'm telling you right now,
I know salesman and people with
corporate jobs who have to fly around the
country.
What you do after a while as
you fantasize about the way,
um,
you want to do the road,
if you could do the fucking
road and I would love it.
I don't know if I could live in fucking
in the middle of nowhere like that, but,
well, let's just say I could,
so this would be the deal.
I live in the middle of nowhere
on the fucking Ponderosa, right?
Woodburn and stove.
It's,
it's like it's a fucking log cabin,
but you still got the flat screen.
I'll build a fucking ice rink out
back for the kids that I don't have,
you know,
have like four fucking dogs
because who gives a shit?
You could buy a mansion for
like 1200 bucks out there.
Have like four fucking
dogs keep I get got Cleo,
I'll get a fucking, okay. Pitbull boxer,
a fucking bulldog. And then
what else? I'd get a month.
I mean a bloodhound. Yeah.
Something that likes to Howl,
but also likes to lay around,
you know,
do my MTV cribs. And rather than
have a bunch of fucking cars,
they'll have the baddest of the
Lamborghini, the Ferrari, the Porsche,
and the fucking dodge challenger.
A dog's right line. I'm,
I'm up in my fucking dirt driveway,
you know, and then down the street,
somehow I'd have my own pride. This is,
this is the ultimate, right? I'd
have my own fucking private jet. Oh.
Meanwhile the business is also
sending me fucking movie scripts.
Just offer me begging me, begging
me, not only to be in the movie,
but all I got to be is like the
fucking six lead. And when I show up,
they shoot all my shit. You
know, you have me for five days,
shoot all my fucking scenes and I'm that
guy who was in the movie like fucking
three, four times, but kills it. So I
keep my career going. This is the dream.
Then I live in the middle of nowhere.
I fucking make my fucking, uh, God,
my garden in the back, fresh vegetables,
got a chicken coop every once in a while.
Who wants a fucking Burrito?
Hang on a second.
I'm going to go wring
the neck of something.
You grab it and you fucking
by the neck is how you do it.
You grab it by the neck and then you
spin their fucking body around and that's
it. All right. You have your
oldest son named John Boy,
and you have him plucked the shit.
You stick it in the set it and forget
it. You kept it as a joke, as a reminder,
a civilization. You fucking eat that
way. And then whenever I got a Gig,
I go down the fucking street
down the street, whatever,
rural road number 47,
and there's,
and there's a fucking airport and I
got my own jet and pilots on call.
All right.
And in the back of the plane,
that's just a big goddamn bed
with a huge fucking seat belt.
And they fucking knock me out if
it's a long flight. If it isn't,
I just sit there shooting the shit
with the pilots. And that's what I do.
And then I fly in, I do the Gig, and
then I fucking go to a sporting event.
Then I fly back.
That's my fucking dream.
That's my dream of how I'd like to do
the road. How do you like that? Huh?
Booze is good on the podcast,
isn't it?
I hope I'm not going to
listen back to this one.
I'm not buzzed and think
that this is fucked up,
but that's something I would like to
do. Um, but I gotta be honest with you.
I don't think that I could
live in Wyoming or Montana.
Um,
I do think that I could live,
where could I live?
I
could live in parts of Pennsylvania,
Connecticut,
upstate New York,
parts of northern New Jersey.
Uh,
maybe western Massachusetts.
I Dunno.
Maybe Northern California.
We get up there and they got some
redwoods and shit. I don't know.
That's fucked up, man. It's scary. You
want to do something fucked up. Go, uh,
go on a, go on Google maps and just, uh,
just look at Montana and then just pick,
um,
pick a town and then hit
satellite. And then just, you know,
drop that little man and then just go
down a fucking street and you'll see what
it's like out there. You know?
And if you don't hear Banjo music,
you're not a fucking human being. It's
scary. I'd love to go out there, man.
I want to check it out. You know, just
see what the fuck is going on up there.
I actually know a guy who has
a gig out in fucking Montana.
I've actually was thinking about
doing it just cause I've never been,
never been out that way. Um, all right,
let's get on with the overrated underrated
now or continue with it, I should say.
Uh, to do overrated. The word.
Oh, I like this one. Overrated.
The, the use of the word countless.
I hear it on the news all the time.
This tragedy has left countless
numbers of people homeless.
That's bullshit. I think there are
like six or 7 billion people on earth.
I know the numeric system works.
I can count to 7 billion. Hell,
I could count to 7
trillion given enough time.
I'm not saying the tragedies
that happen aren't bad,
but trying to jack up the fear quotient
by making it sound like the number of
people affected is just too
big to comprehend is bullshit.
I liked that. I never noticed that.
Leaving countless people homeless.
Uh, what do you mean by the
actually 1,247? Well, you know what?
I think I could count that high.
Are you saying that you don't care
about the homeless? No. You dumb cunt.
I'm saying that I can count that
high. So it's not countless. 1200 is,
it's countable leaving
countable people homeless.
This guy is absolutely right.
Or this woman,
whoever wrote it in
absolutely fucking right.
You are absolutely fucking correct
on that one. Uh, underrated, uh,
animated shows on TV today.
The Simpsons and family guy
are legitimately well done.
Shows and South Park to a lesser degree.
Dude,
I think South Park is still the best.
I'd go South Park,
the Simpsons and then the family guy.
South Park has the best social commentary
on TV. But I have to tell you this,
I don't watch that show. What the
fuck is it? I always mean to watch it.
It comes on Sunday night. The, uh,
I had, fuck do I describe
it? It's the, uh,
African American one. There
we go. Come on. You know it.
I don't know what it is,
but I heard that one is the shit.
What the fuck is the name of it? I can't
remember. I heard that one's awesome.
I got to get into watching that. I always
say I'm going to, and then I never do.
And there's also a billboard I've seen
on sunset boulevard out here for that
show. Children's hospital.
It looks creepy as hell.
And it's on a adult swim.
That's what I'm trying to say.
Adult swim is what that other, the
Boondocks, right? Is that the name of it?
And then there's the, um, I heard
that children's hospital is great.
I want to check that one out too.
All right. Um, what are we doing?
Where are we going? They hit OK. Ko, um,
cartoons that they have good writing,
good plot points and legitimate social
commentary. Totally agree on all of them.
This is what pisses me off though. I can
tell you that the number of times it's,
someone will ask me what
I've watched on television.
I will give them the plot of a Simpsons
episode, not mentioning any names,
um, or the fact that it's a cartoon and
they will tell me how funny they think it
is. But then when I tell them it's
the Simpsons of the family guy,
it's a Simpson or a family guy episode.
All of a sudden they turn their noses
up and say that they're adults and they
don't watch cartoons anymore.
What the fuck is up with that?
A funny show is a funny show,
Dude. I couldn't agree with more.
I couldn't agree with you more.
Let me take the last fucking Swig here
and I'm going to, uh, I'm going to,
I'm going to finish this thing off and
I'm gonna Finish up the podcast. Um,
here's something that I have learned
on a, on the podcast. Hang on a second.
Here we go. Let me get a little
more, a little more happy juice here.
Oh God. Damn. That's fucking perfect. Um,
anyways. Oh, by the way, uh,
I've been watching a lot of
the old Jackie Gleason. Um,
I used to watch him when I was a kid
and I never really noticed how many the,
the oldest shows.
It was weird.
I don't know what it was
because I came up in the 70s.
You have to understand that a lot of
the original shows weren't filmed,
so there was no syndication. That was
the brilliance of Ricky Ricardo there.
Uh, what's his face there? Ricky
Ricardo was his character named,
um,
Desi Arnaz that he actually
had the brilliance to film.
I love you. I love Lucy and get
the rights for the old episodes.
Like nobody in the business for saw
the money in reruns and they just,
they signed off and just gave them to
them basically for fucking nothing.
So anyways, it wasn't a lot of reruns.
Certainly from the 1950s. There's,
you know, a lot of those live shows, they
just went live and that was it. But, um,
so like what am I trying to
say? And actually television
was I this how old I am.
Television for the most
as far as the golden
age of television,
right up was only 20 years old
and there was only three networks.
So you basically got the best of the best.
And I used to watch like
the Jackie Gleason show,
they used to show reruns
of the Dean Martin show.
I know this makes me sound like
I'm older than fucking dirt,
but they used to play it. They
supply all that shit, three stooges,
all that type of shit.
And I used to watch the Jackie Gleason
show and he had this character,
Reginald van Gleason.
And um,
I don't know the character,
he just had this little brown mustache.
And before he would say anything,
he would cuss sort of hum and
then say whatever he said.
And I watched one the other
day where he was playing, uh,
just trying to solve a murder mystery.
And he comes walking in on this
couple is a dead body in there and a,
but before he starts questioning
them about the murder,
he actually sees a wet bar.
So he just puts his index finger up.
This is why I'd love to, but
Jackie Gleason was how, um,
without saying anything, he free
could go for like, you know,
minutes on end without saying anything
and just have you dying laughing. And He,
and, and he never rehearsed
either and he just fucked.
He puts his finger up and after he sees
the bar and he walks over to the wet bar
and he does all this exaggerated
shit of making the drink,
but before he walks with a second,
he's explaining this wrong, whatever,
he comes walking over to the bar,
the second he sees it,
he just goes booze,
right?
And it gets this huge fucking laugh.
I Dunno. I don't even know the,
I just love that old school shit.
We're fucking drinking and having
a drinking problem is funny.
This guy,
this is a dead body in the room and he's
going to make himself a drink first.
He obviously has,
he's preop priorities are out of
fucking whack and nobody gives a shit.
So whatever. But anyways, this last week
of this podcast, I really learned, man,
uh, how to do, uh, if I ever
want to do a fucking radio show,
there's three,
there's three topics that get me the
most email responses of either I totally
agree with you or you're fucking
annoying the shit out of me.
And they are politics,
sports and,
uh, in Jesus or any sort of religion.
If I go off on any of those,
like, uh, you know,
trashing the fucking, uh,
[inaudible] what did I do a
few weeks ago I trashed, um,
New York and the Knicks. I got all
these fucking emails from Knicks fans,
you know, last week I trashed the fucking,
uh, I didn't think I trashed the Lakers.
I thought it was just talking
about Kobe versus, um, um, Jordan.
But,
uh,
all these fucking Laker fans just
fucking writing in writing and capital
letters, flipping the fuck
out. And, uh, I dunno,
this podcast has been very in like
in like that level where it's like,
if I ever do a fucking radio show,
which I don't think I will,
I like doing this shit better.
And I always felt when I did on informed,
when we were actually able
to do episodes of that,
I always felt the collars
slowed down the show, you know,
and it was so many people just
fucking with you or whatever.
But if I ever get a situation,
I have to do a radio show
and I want to get college.
Those are the three fucking magic topics
that just get people flipping the fuck
out. I guess the fourth would be a fee
if you trash one of the sexist, you know,
I don't even,
what the fuck I'm saying here?
I'm just enjoying the nice buzz of one
fucking beer. That's a great thing to do.
Drink up,
drink a 16 ounce [inaudible] really
good beer on an empty fucking stomach,
you know,
and do a God damn podcast and tell me
you're not proud to be a fucking American.
All right, that's it. Okay.
I think we had a little bit of something
for everybody here. Wind chimes,
booze reminiscing, telling you my, my,
my dreams of how I want to
live in the fucking future.
I guess none of which included having
a spouse or children. Fucking creepy.
Is that, uh, that's it.
That's the podcast here that I
did it on a Thursday and I'm,
hopefully I'm going to try to
do Letterman again next week.
My set is more than ready to go and I'll
try to give you the heads up this time
if I, if I get bumped. Uh, but
whatever. It's actually, I actually,
I'm kind of psyched that I got bumped
because there's nothing cooler than going
to the Ed Sullivan Theater. It's just a
shit and you just, you come up beforehand,
they show you where your mark is and as
much as is showing you where your mark
is, you sit, sit in and God, Jesus
Christ, the fucking Beatles were here,
the stones were here, the doors came as
well. The doors came out and then, and,
and Jim Morrison,
whatever the fuck he wasn't supposed
to say. He said, it's incredible.
It's an incredible,
uh,
it's one of the few things left in show
business that is still as big as show
business was back in the day before
it all got splintered into like 400,
400 different channels. Um, so whatever,
all you young comics out there and never
done, let them, and I'm telling you,
it's not going to fucking disappoint
you. It's a, it's a huge thrill.
And this is my fifth time doing it and
I'm beyond excited and I'm really hoping
I get to get on this weekend. Ah, that's
it. That's the podcast for this week.
I hope all you guys enjoyed it.
And
I will talk to you next week.
He's [inaudible].