Dunes, Amazon, Amazon, and
then, um, they're going to do
something with a Promo Code.
If you put promo called Baron, you got
it for five bucks on my website. Do I,
do I have that? You want me to
just say what is that thing?
The whole fucking thing. Just a
little bit. Okay. Jesus Christ.
All right, we're ready
to go. Alright. Hey,
what's going on? It's bill bird is
time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday morning
podcast. Dan, just checking in on. Yeah,
just checking in on. You probably
think of what Jesus, Bill,
you went a little fast on that one.
You usually fucking stretch it
out a little bit longer. What,
do you have a special guest in the
studio or something? Why? Yes, yes I do.
I have,
uh,
the Great Jim Florentine
in studio here who has a,
a new stand up special coming out that
will be available on iTunes and Amazon
called a simple man, ladies
and gentlemen, New Jersey Zone,
Jim Florentine and filmed the New Jersey
of course, and filmed in New Jersey.
So how does the, the, the,
uh, the royalty of New Jersey,
it's got to go Bruce Springsteen,
Jon Bon Jovi, Jim Florentine,
maybe Artie Lange, no,
rich boss, rich foss.
How did I forget rich? The Duke of fucking
Trenton, whatever the hell he lives.
South Plainfield I heard is that he had
put out a CD I heard was fucking great.
Yeah. And he's the guys
pumping them out like a maniac.
I think that's a great thing.
And uh,
I love that you put it on Amazon and I
think the more specialists in more areas
so nobody gets too much power, if you
know what I mean. There absolutely.
That's got a good deal somewhere and he's
like, fuck you, you're not owning it,
you know,
and all that stuff.
So I liked the new model that's coming
out and basically to own your stuff,
you don't, that's what I'm hearing
through the music industry.
Like if you own Spotify and all
those other streaming sites,
basically enough to pay some big royalties
coming soon in like two, three years,
just like satellite radio
before they weren't paying shit.
They putting all the comedy
bits won't get a dime.
Then all of a sudden when they
merged, the governments are, well,
you have to start paying royalties.
They passed along to the consumer and
now you get nice checks from sound
exchange through because of the
satellite radio, Internet, radio,
and now the streaming sites to Spotify is,
all of those are gonna have to
start paying it about two years.
So if you own your shit fucking time,
I know. So if you own your master,
if you own the master and then you
also do, you know, you're a performer,
you get double checks. I swear
I saw a thing one time, uh,
there was, what was that,
that documentary and that
heavy metal band that just,
they came to la like the week
before Nirvana's album came out. Uh,
nevermind that just, you know, as, as,
as the, the, the, the, the legend goes,
that was the album that destroyed the
whole thing rather than 50,000 bands.
I'll sing the same fucking
song. Um, so that failed.
And then they moved back to like Indiana
or wherever the fuck they were from.
And hair metal still
survived another three years.
Then they tried to get into
grunge and all this shit.
And then they were just old
and they never really made it.
And they made this documentary in
at one point towards the end, the,
the biggest lesson in all of it. One of
the, the, um, the members said, he goes,
what I've learned,
he goes,
your better to have 100% ownership
and just sell 20,000 copies,
then you are to have no ownership
and sell like 20 million copies,
you'll actually make more money if
you own it. That's how bad they are.
They fucking rip you off. They just, they,
they rip, you know, they've, you know,
all of that shit all the way back to
the blues guys and all that, you know,
every fucking artists, they just, they,
uh, that's what, that's what happens. So,
and then also, yeah. And also like
those eighties videos with the,
you know the go feed with the hot
chick in it and they were, you know,
dance around on stage and doing whatever
those videos will like a half million
to $1 million to budgets on those.
So that came right off the top
of any money they sold. Oh yeah.
The record company put that money up.
So just to make a go.
And it was the same video as the guys
performing onstage and it was a hot check
and he starts out in black and white,
black.
And so when the rest of the band kicks
in and all of a sudden it was in color,
it was the ballot, they look tired.
You know it was Bon Jovi on the boss.
He looked tired cause he was looking at
the window and drive and know who is the
first w Bon Jovi cause you
do also do that metal show.
So that was [inaudible] 86
when that album came out,
a video was maybe 87
somewhere around there.
I think New Jersey was his big
record came out like 84 85 bond at.
That's slippery when wet. How old
was slippery when wet was probably,
I think 84 now. That was like 85 86
okay. Yeah, somewhere around there.
And then New Jersey came out after it up.
Slippery when wet as you give love a
bad name. Yeah. Wanted dead or alive.
All of that shit. They start the,
I'm tired on the tour bus journey.
Did member journey with uh,
Steve Perry had that bad mustache
and faithfully oh yeah. Yeah.
Remember he had the mustache?
Yeah. That, so that was,
that started the original tire. I'm
tired. I'm on tour and I'm exhausted.
What about when he was at
that San Francisco giant game?
They started playing the journey song
and all he had to do was smile and wave
and then he acted like somebody,
he acted like someone who is just a fan
of the band rather than the guy singing
it. And he just, he just went over
the fucking top with it. And it was,
I just felt like it was a moment that,
I don't know if he's not
selling tickets or whatever.
It's like he should just played that cool.
And he tried to be too regular and then
everybody just eviscerated him on the
fucking Internet. Did you
ever see that? Yeah. Oh yeah.
Cause I've seen him at giant.
I'm a big giant fan,
so I'll go out there and
I've seen him a game.
So he goes to like every game when his
kids, he can't hit those notes anymore,
so he knows I'm just laying low. Let the
Asian guy take over and do it. You know,
he's just collecting the
royalties off of go. Yeah.
So he doesn't need to do any of that
stuff. He doesn't care. Yeah, he, he's,
he could have been back in journey 10
years ago, but he's just like, I come on,
I'm not going to barass myself.
That's a smart move.
So I'll just do it once at a baseball
game. Yeah. Like, yeah, like Robert Plant,
Robert Plant knows he
ain't, ain't, no he hasn't.
He knows he's not going to hit those
notes. You don't have to tune down to la.
He sounded great in 2007
I know he sounded amazing.
You know what they got offered $14 million
for two two hour shows a thing in the
desert. What was the thing? If you
like a couple months ago,
you've got 14 million for two two
hour shows and Robert Plant started to
everybody else's app when it's like
of course, and he said no. Yeah,
I think he bought a bunch of
apartment buildings is what he did.
So he's making all this fucking
money. That's what I heard. Yeah.
I heard he's a really good businessman,
but why can't he just come out and go,
look,
this isn't going to be like 1976 I'm not
going to be able to hit all the notes,
but I'm going to go hang on.
My friends were going to jam,
have a good time and don't expect
much Elijah if you've thrown,
I have to be honest with you.
I think he's protecting the legacy
of the band by not doing it.
I mean, I think they did
that last one. I don't think.
I don't think they could do it
better than they did it in oh seven.
And he's always said, if you,
if you're just, you know,
if this is just a money grab Ben
there, done that. What did he say?
I'm just an old hippie,
blah blah blah.
Like he just doesn't see the reason to
do it. Now what I would do if I was,
the rest of them I'd get, I'd
get, uh, Jason Bonham on drums,
John Paul Jones and Jimmy page and I would
do a journey did and who gives a fuck
while they tried to do that after
too, you know, first of all,
Jay page and plant don't get along at all.
Like when they were rehearsing for that
2007 show, which Jason, I'm told to show,
told the story on that
metal show when it was on,
they were at each other's throats,
page and plant.
They just don't like each other. I
think it's more a plant, you know.
So after that they were hoping they were
going to do a reunion and plants said
once again, nope, I'm not doing what it.
So they actually audition Steven Tyler,
Sammy Hagar.
That's right.
And Myles Kennedy had the Gig Miles's
from all to bridge and slash or solos
thing, and he had the Gig and
they were ready to deal with it.
And then they just said, you know what? We
can't, we, let's just put it to the side.
We can't do that. We're not going to
sell us as led. Zepplin oh my God.
So it was called, but Myles Kennedy out of
nowhere, it got that Gig. But it did, uh,
Steven Tyler,
my hearing.
Then in my headphones,
I'll see la,
should we be concerned about the alarm?
Is it a fire?
I'll run out there. And how do
you know what it is? Oh, oh,
oh.
One of these times it's going to be
an actual, it's like when you were in,
when you're in a club and you hit,
hit it on a hot chick and you hear the
alarm go. He's like, I don't give a shit.
I ain't leaving by Labor.
Does nine guys read it?
Everybody to take my spot.
So I don't know if there's a fire up
one of those nine just pulled it to
absolutely to get me away from her.
So I understand plants thing where he
doesn't want to do it. He's like I'm not,
I don't want to do it from the guys
probably worth 300 million so he doesn't
need to do at this point. You just wish
it was a fan? Maybe just a few shows.
Yeah, cause you know
what I like when, when,
when Jason played in 2007 I thought he
was finally himself where he was like,
he didn't feel like he had to
do what his dad did, but he, he,
he was thrown in the teeth
through in so much shit.
A lot of it was some stuff that
his dad did live, but like he,
his personality was on it. I thought
he really fucking owned it on that one.
So I was kind of psyched to see them
go around. It's probably better.
It's probably better that they don't do
it because you know it didn't work well.
I remember that live aid when they
had the two fucking drummers and shit.
And that was only five
years after they had played.
But I heard Paige was so fucking upset
that he didn't play guitar for a while
after bond died. Like to the
point he had to tried to record,
remember how to fucking play. Um, that's
right. Cause then the story was um,
Paul Rogers came over one day
and was just hanging like three,
four years later and said, hey
dude, you can pick up their guitar.
Let's see if we can write some songs. And
they started the firm after that. Yeah.
So why doesn't he just fucking,
why don't you just come up with a new
name and just still do Zeplin shit plays
some firms stuff.
That fucking Jimmy page product project
with John Paul Jones and fucking,
I know what Jason, well member when
memoir now page was so pissed off at uh,
at Robert Plant that had got David
Coverdale and did the Coverdell page.
They did one album cause governor Chris
Robinson, they went out with him. Yeah.
Robert Plant hated David Coverdale
cause he thought he was a led Zeppelin,
you know, just so Robert Plant clone,
he looked like him. Sounded like, um,
and then pages.
So I'm going to get your arch enemy
and we're going to start her own band.
What do you think of that?
Well yeah, I think that'll
do a lot of damage, but yeah,
it did. It definitely didn't
help the guy 10 years younger.
They can still hit the fucking notes.
Well van Halen pulled it off cause
remember Sammy and Dave did that toward a
Sammy Hagar,
David Lee Roth tore together.
They hated each other cause of Van
Halen weren't talking to either.
And then right after that tour it,
I got back with Sammy.
So I guess Fannie Allen's like, what
are they? They're selling out arenas.
We should be doing this.
And they put Sammy back in the van
Sammie's back in the van now? No, no,
this is a while ago.
But Sammy and Dave cause to van Halen
brothers would just blowing them off.
They go,
okay,
let's the two old singers of Van
Halen and let's do a tour together.
And they do a tour and
they hated each other,
that whole tour because Sammy
and Dave hated each other.
They hated each other since day one,
but they just did it for the tour and
they were supposed to like rotate headline
in every night and Sam was trying to blow
them off the stage and, and Dave was,
and it was all the egos and all this shit.
So I would think Sammy would win
though. Did he win? Probably,
but Dave was still a voice of Van Halen.
I'd rather hear you know, and love again.
And you know,
Main Street then is this love?
Yeah. I always thought Sammy
Hagar, you, when you look at his,
I was just talking about
this in my last podcast. Um,
this is such like fucking white
guys in their forties talking. Um,
I always thought he shouldn't
had fucking joined the band.
There was no upside where it was like,
you're not going to follow Dave.
You're not going to be like, uh, you
just, it's just one of those things like,
why would you, why would you go
there? It was like Steve Young going,
I have to fucking Joe Montana,
no matter what the fuck he did,
he was always going to be not Joe Montana.
And even though he y one,
one a get the monkey
off my back or whatever,
I thought he should have just stayed
with his own fucking band. Man.
That guy was incredible
for live and all that.
I liked the direction of his solo
shit before that is this love.
And they're the keyboards and they were
all walking around in the fucking flesh
colored, uh, flashdance suits,
whatever the hell they were wearing.
Yeah. Um, you know, he um, he had
a great solo career before joining.
I know we really didn't have to,
I don't think he really thought
it was going to take off.
I don't know what I just said.
Let's start, start jamming.
And then by van actually got bigger
at that point they sold more records,
which Sammy, but that was the MTV days,
more like Dave was like the last of the,
you know,
Panama and jump and stuff like that.
But then when van Halen,
like 86 is when they put their first one,
I would,
would a Sammy there had all the videos
and stuff like that so that I sold a lot
more records. And Dave, all right, let's,
let's try to bring this
back into like this century.
I want to do something fucking hilarious.
It hit me the other night.
So a buddy of mine passed away, right?
We're at that age, people fucking die.
And uh, so we, we did a,
uh, a benefit for them.
So I got all these
fucking comics together.
There was a guy I did stand
up with from 90 to 99.
This Guy Pete come and just a great guy.
And then he became a writer and did all
these wonderful things and unfortunately
had a heart attack and died.
So I got all of his buddies from
fucking back in the day, you know,
like Austin, Boston, guys like, you know,
some guys who are like not
doing standup really anymore.
And we all fucking came out was hilarious.
We're all standing around fucking
dad jeans and bad hairlines and shit.
And I'm looking around going like,
wow man,
we have fucking old before the
show us just like Jesus Christ.
This crowd looks kind of young.
I hope this is going to go out right
in the fucking, it went perfect.
Perfect night. Uh, except
for one fucking dude,
but he was on some medication
and he was drinking bud lights.
He repeated a couple of jokes. It
was fucking hilarious. He, he had,
he had one guy at a tough set.
So I was on stage and um, I've,
I was making fun of fat
actresses complaining and Shit.
And then I was just going to be,
look at me, I'm fucking among bald,
redheaded male.
You don't think there's a glass ceiling
on the parts I can get out here and shit
like that. Right. So at the end of my set,
I'm doing the meet and greet
and this guy came up to me,
didn't even want to like
picture or anything.
He had one of those before and after
fucking hair club for men cards,
I guess he did it. He goes, dude, he goes,
I could get you your
hair back if you want it.
And it was the club that the guy was
like bald like me and then had like the
fucking, oh, really? I was just like, I
said to too. I'm like, no man, I'm good.
And he kept fucking showed it to me. I,
if I was just like, dude, I like, I go,
I liked the way I look. I don't
need that wavy shit. Right.
And he just fucking put his head down.
He walked out like a scolded child.
I felt like a fucking asshole. They, I
don't need that fucking well, what you,
at some point you're like, yeah, thanks
man, but I'm good. You know, like you,
you give them that, but then when
they keep pounding away, well,
it's one of those six dude, I had
hair at one point in time. I saw it.
It got me okay. I think I always said
if I was going to be the next Brad Pitt,
it would've happened before.
Like I had to wait till you were 48 Oh,
if you only had fucking hair. It's like,
no dude, it's, it's, it's a wrap. Yeah.
And then you can't put it on
now. Everybody knows. You know,
you had to do it in that transition stage
where you were losing a little, but,
and I was like, did he do something with
his hair? You can't do this. So many guys,
there was so many guys hanging off the
fucking ledge and all of a sudden pulled
themselves back up like this. So many
fucking guys. I just, I never, uh,
I just didn't give a shit like this,
this certain point of like,
you just gotta you know, just, you
just play the hand you're dealt,
you're going to look way fucking better.
Although some people that I know,
they got some really good ones, but, um,
I just don't, I don't
know. I, I don't get, dude,
I wouldn't even do that laser eye
surgery. Yeah, I won't do that either.
I'm waiting til like 100%.
You're fine. Yeah, exactly.
There's a couple cases of guys foggy and
he can't see, and, and then they say,
if you're over fucking 45, it only lasts
for this amount of years. And then what?
You're going to do it again?
Fuck that.
I know when they're operating
on your eyes. Yeah. Fuck it.
Fucking sitting there looking at it as
it doing it that that's too much. So,
but you did the right thing with
that guy, you said, Nah, I'm good.
And then he kept pounding away.
Some guy wanted it laughed.
I thought it was right. It was fucking
hilarious. And then when you say, dude,
I'm good, I'm good, I'm good.
Walked away. I was just like, dude,
I don't need that wavy shit because it's
always the guy with the wavy fucking
hair. It's never anybody with like
looking like those guys and that was it.
Always this, they never have that Beatles
hair cut. It's always the fucking wavy.
It was just like, yeah dude, I'm
good. And then just kind of put his,
that had happened to me.
Some guy wanted me to do it on
Ohio thing like this Ohio state.
I'm not a big college football fan
when I do all age. Ah, yeah, yeah.
I was doing a Gig and he's like, dude,
my friend's going to snapchat this.
Can you do this with me? I go, no. Oh
yeah, yeah, yeah. I'll go, first of all,
you're on fucking snapchat and you're,
you're like 40 years old.
You shouldn't be on snapchat. And
second like, I'm not doing that.
That's fucking corny. He's like, come on
man. I go, no, I'm not. I'm not doing it.
I'll take a picture with you.
I'll do whatever,
but I'm not the one all h I all
know it gets weird with that shit.
Like there was someone
in the line last night,
like I had like eight people back and
he's facetimeing with his friend and he's
got his friend's head pointing at me.
I'm like,
I'm looking at this person from like 30
yards away on the phone looking at me
and I just kept yelling to the guy,
just go and sorry,
I'm not going to talk to
that guy fucking phone on.
And he wasn't listening to it.
I was like,
can you tell that psycho back there
with his friend on the phone? I am not.
I'm not. It's bad enough when somebody
just hands you a fucking phone. Hey,
can you say hello to my fainted fucking,
you know what I started doing? I just,
I just did. I just channeled Patrice.
I would just start hanging up on them.
I just go right. Just hang it up. I had
a relative of mine will kept doing it go.
He used to, I used to call
it, he's calling, you know,
it's one of these guys I've talked to
like once or twice a year. Hey Bill,
how you doing? Blah Blah.
Hey, you know what I mean?
Are you home telling you
remember someone selling?
He would just hand the phone to them
and the person on the other end,
it didn't want to talk to me either.
Right.
And it was just the worst fucking
thing. So I would go, I don't do that.
Don't do it without any, would hand it to
me and the, hey. And then I just finally,
I just started fucking hanging up
and it just stopped it and he would,
he got so fucking mad at
me. It was just like, dude,
I'm asking you not to fucking do
this and you're still doing it.
You're leaving me no choice
here. And then he tried it. Oh,
what do you think you too. You too
good for that. Yeah, you are too.
Everybody's too good for them.
I want to talk to a complete
fucking stranger who doesn't
want to talk to you on
a phone. People used to do it to me like,
hey, say hello, my friend. I'm like, Hey,
how you doing? This isn't Jim Florence
and I'm a yeah, it is. He goes,
what are you doing in St Louis? Like
I'm doing a Gig. There's no way.
There's no way you were saying.
I'm like, all right. I go,
I'm not going to argue with you here.
Take the phone to phone back.
I'm not arguing with and go to my website.
I'm at the fucking funny ball and
whatever gives a shit. No, it never, uh,
it never fucking ends well, but
um, anyways, how's your, uh,
I know your team.
Don't tell me the dolphins had just went
to the Dolphin Raven game last week in
Baltimore. They got their ass kicked
to have ravens are always tough, man.
They did. The dolphins never played
good against physical teams. Never.
They just didn't, not a physical team,
you know, and it can push it around.
They got that in Dhamaka soother.
Yeah,
he's good because he gets
double and triple team. Then
other guys can get sacks,
but I just, they're just not a good
physical team. They just, uh, you know,
Tana Hill, they had some guys out
in the offensive line, disliked.
They're seven and five, so
I can't complain. I didn't
think that back. Good. Yeah.
This new coach,
I think he's pretty good.
What are the bills that bills are six
and six? Love it. They're out there.
They cannot make the playoffs.
You got to go lease tenant six,
11 and five and just to get a
wildcard this year. So there are,
I want to again go back to
being a defensive coordinator.
He get a Superbowl ring.
No, I know. He's just,
he's got too much of an ego and he's
got his brother there. What it is,
as well as making fun.
You know, in New Orleans,
they didn't let me do what I wanted to
do. Really. You had the worst defense,
you know,
in the history of the NFL for two years
in a row and you're trashing him on the
way out. That's a good thing to do.
Yeah. He's only made, he's, yeah,
he's been a coach for like 12 years.
Rob Ryan hit one of his teams,
made the playoffs once
and they got knocked out.
The first game was New Orleans
against Seattle a couple of years ago.
Other than that, never even
made a playoff. Did Rob
has been a head coach? No,
he's never but a defensive coordinator.
Cowboys. He's with the Raiders.
He's been all over the
place. Yeah. And I think,
I think rex does most of
the heavy lifting when it,
cause he always has
good defenses and then,
but now we actually has
a decent quarterback.
He just doesn't have anybody to
fucking throw to and tie Rod Taylor,
you cannot sack that guy.
It's unbelievable. He's
fucking amazing. I know.
Constantly getting out of
the way. Um, but you know,
and then the dolphins gift that they gave
us a Mario Williams, Mario Williams, uh,
they got released and he's terrible.
I don't know what happened then I'd do it.
He's on Miami now.
He's got like two tackles the whole year.
So buffalo new to get rid of him.
Uh, but yeah, Buffalo's out again.
It'll be 17 years,
no playoffs.
But they're bad or they're
better than than they were.
And Rex goes in and just sells,
as you know, does is all bullshit,
you know what I mean? Like I'm
not here to lose. Really? Wow.
I didn't go there to kisses.
Kisses rings. Yeah. I'm, I'm,
I'm here to make the playoffs. Oh,
that's good. Good, good to know.
You know I love this week was Brian
Cashman set after the Red Sox,
I guess sign some deals with
something he said. He just went, wow.
He goes to like the Golden State warriors
and I fucking died laughing like,
dude, they'll fucking
talk about the, well,
how would that expression to pot calling
the kettle black? You fucking assholes.
You invented that shit. How the fuck
you going to sit there and say it?
Like he should have been like,
wow,
those guys are ripping us off just
cause the last few years. Well,
it's basically since George
Steinbrenner died. Yeah.
The Sun's way more conservative and is
trying to do it with the farm system,
which I respect and I love. But Brian
Cashman was part of that of course,
a fees like a fucking
free agency war criminal.
And now he's fucking wagging his finger
at the fucking red sox for doing what
the, that what they did.
Now having said that, I,
it's the thing that turned me off about
baseball and I felt the red sox in oh
seven became the Yankees, you know,
when they signed all those people.
So it's been difficult for me to
get back into it. But I guess,
but also you gotta realize
yesterday the Yang,
the Yankees sign Chatman to close
or four years, 86 million for,
for a closer. And w w where did he play
again? Remember he was with the, um,
the reds.
He was with the Yankees last year.
They traded him at the trading deadline
that the cubs won the world series where
he throws 105 miles an hour.
He went to the cubs.
He was a free age and Yankees just
resigned. I'm going back four years,
86 million. He was there, but he was
one of the guys though who? Chapman.
He Chapman was originally with the reds.
He got in some trouble off the field and
the Yankees got 'em for half a season
trade.
And I'm that a cubs and reds.
What kind of trouble does
somebody get into it?
You fucking trade away 105
mile an hour pitcher. I know.
He just didn't die. He didn't
exude the uh, the what,
what we like to give to our fell. What did
they say? The, the persona of our team.
We have a code.
We have a code here in Cincinnati.
Why don't you throw it out the fucking
window? The guy still 105 miles an hour.
Exactly. Let him do what he
wants. He's going to grab
some titties. A fucking nuts.
Hooters. You know, it's
funny, as I was saying that,
I was like [inaudible] now
that going to be a thing,
you know the fucking Internet now
was he advocating social south?
You know that happens now if you little
fuck oh yeah, absolutely. You have this,
this like I didn't look into special.
I film like a little over a year
ago or year and a half actually.
It's been and this stuff on there.
I led a look back cause I was trying
to trying to do a trail and I'm like,
Holy Shit. I said that. I
go, it's probably what I
said a year and a half ago.
It was like, I can't believe he said that.
Right. And how quickly it could wait.
Where did you film it? In a George Street
playhouse in New Brunswick, New Jersey.
It's right down the street from the
stress factory. He was going to say, yeah,
it's like a 600 theat the seat theater.
It was Vinnie upset Navine health
center of any help promote it.
I had to get them at work. A man
and when his beak. Yeah, absolutely.
Because if any runs that town,
that fucking guy and he
was going to do a set,
he was going to open the show and
do 10 minutes to warm up the crowd.
Of course he was late and he didn't.
Uh, so yeah, I'm sorry. Goals,
that would have been like video.
I'm trying to have a good special here.
I know I had a backup just in case,
so, but yeah, so I cut Vinnie and on a,
basically they sold tickets to the stress
factory, so, oh, that's cool. Yeah.
So you kept everything.
Yeah. We're friends. We've,
we started comedy back together years ago.
What year did you guys start?
I started in 91. I started in [inaudible]
92. So he started in 91, too. Ah,
yeah. Yeah. 91. And he was probably
already married with like 19 kids. Yeah,
he had already, he was married
with three kids. He owned a Flores.
He was a fucking maniac.
I was booking like this open mic
thing on a Monday night, a strip club.
I remember when I,
when I met him in the mid nineties,
he was such an angry man. He was,
you could feel it off of him. It was,
he was going through that, that first, uh,
first go around and uh, then the,
he's just become the exact opposite.
Now he's like, fucking Santa Claus. It,
he used to just be like in the 90s, dude.
And, and I, I was an angry,
fucked up dude. So I,
every once in a while I would meet someone
who matched my anger or surpassed it.
And I was always just like, I, and I'm not
gonna fuck with that guy. Like I have, I,
we have a running joke mean oop,
uh,
from opie and Anthony and a whatever the
fuck they calling it now. Um, he, uh,
we recognize both of us were like this
fucking level of anger and just how
everybody got thrown under the bus on
that show. And eventually it was arguing.
I had a big army with Patrice on that
show. And, uh, I just, we both had,
I think he was the one who brought it up.
He's like, to the first time I met you,
I sense this fucking anger. And he was
like, I'm going to stay away from that.
I was like, I do not see what
the fuck I was. Because if you,
if you listen to the a is show,
you'll never find a clip of us.
Will it be everybody trashed and
everybody, we never lob one at each other.
I don't know what, there was just
something about the guy, I'm like,
this guy is a skies like he,
he might be even angrier than I am. So I
just completely stayed away. No, that's a,
that's a good move. No,
Vinny was very angry.
I remember it as a comic because Vinny
had the comedy club like in 94 he had the
stress factor was, it was another
little spot. So at a hotel or whatever,
and my friend, this Guy Eric and manic
local comic ago, he's, he books it.
Go give them your card and
he goes, Hey, I'm a comedian.
I lived in New Jersey cause I love
to do you call it, here's my card.
And when he goes to Chicago, he goes,
yeah. And it was a nice card at,
as a headshot on it. Vinny just
ripped it up right in front of them.
We just walked away.
Why?
And then he just stopped and then he
came back and thought it was funny.
And then the other dude was so pissed at
them. He's like, what a fucking asshole.
You know, Shit like that. And that's
just the way Vinnie was just a component.
The only boss, he was just
fucking around. That's hilarious.
I don't know if he was or not. He
just, but yeah, he was, he was angry.
That's why I liked them. I
loved, you know, I love the
angry dudes. Well, you know,
when the first time I did,
uh, the stress factory,
I worked with a already Fletcher.
Remember him? Yeah. He's,
he's still a friend of mine. He
tells everybody we are. So I, uh,
he's in Florida now. Yeah,
he's in Florida. So we
worked together and you know,
of course I didn't draw anybody,
like Vinny was giving me a shot and I
made fun of the club and I was just no
name comic. And I think it, cause he,
I didn't realize he built most of it at
the time. Now it's a really nice club.
I remember when he first opened it. I
mean it was, it was, uh, it was a dump.
So I fucking made fun
of it. And, uh, but I,
I still killed and making fun of
the club was killing and all that.
And then I remember he called my manager
at the time just being like, yeah,
you know,
you didn't get the job done.
He didn't get the job done
and he fucking wouldn't,
he didn't work me for like
seven years after that. And uh,
I don't think he fucking worked me until
after opie and Anthony maybe a little
before that.
He started to work me.
Was that what it was in the hotel because
he used to have it in a hotel before
we moved it to the same, I helped paint
that place when he moved it over there.
I was there when it, when it was, he
couldn't have been over them one too. Two,
three fucking years.
He had the creepy bicycle hanging from
the fucking ceiling and that stage was
fucked up. It was, it was, I can't, I
can't remember, but it was, it was a dump.
But then what happened over the years?
Then he redid the floor,
he got the smoke eater and all
of a sudden it was amazing.
It went from like this fucking d
level room to now like that's a play.
I love that place. Yeah. That's
one of my favorite clubs.
Vinnie probably wishes I got to that
part sooner in that fucking story.
Cause he's primary calling.
You're fucking trash and a club on the
God damn podcast or whatever he has.
He is normal now.
Like he's on the committee.
He was running for council and as
town and stuff like that. Yeah, he's,
he's um, he's evolved.
Yeah. That's funny though.
This when you get to be our age,
like the one of two things happens.
Either you fucking evolve,
you chill out and you learn how to like
enjoy life or you are literally the
exact same fucking person
you were. When, when,
whenever I see people either,
either way they become dads or whatever,
they just changed. They've
mellowed, they're not as angry,
they're happy, blah, blah,
blah.
Or they literally the exact same fucking
person they were when I met him in the
90s. Yeah. And you don't
want to be that guy.
I know that like when I got married
and had a kid and move to the suburbs,
I'm like man,
I'm going to be tough and that talk to
neighbors and hang out with them and talk
fucking, you know, school districts.
And then I got to go basketball camp and
sit next to them at chuck e cheese and
I love doing that.
I love how my more normal neighbors,
we walk our kids to the bus stop
every day we hang up, I go over there,
they come over my house.
It's fucking great.
I love being around other
parents and stuff like that.
I thought I was just
going to be a nightmare.
I wish I knew when I was
younger than that. That was uh,
you know that that actually I would
think helps your comedy because I always
thought like, you know, when we were
coming up, you just sell my God,
get married and have a kid. That's it.
It's all, yeah, your career's over it.
You're not going to make it.
That's what always cracks me up when
they talk about like the pressure,
like women have it becoming
pregnant. Like, if like,
how do I keep the career and
blah, blah, blah, blah, and,
and I understand that in the real world.
But like in show business,
I think everybody, man or woman,
if you're on the performance side,
it's just like that. I, I'm,
I'm fucking done. I like,
you just feel like I have to be at a
certain level of selling tickets for my
wife to still believe in me.
Because if you still like, you know,
not selling tickets,
they're going to be like,
you're doing this comedy thing on the
weekend. I need, I need a solid paycheck.
I need to know that there's money
coming in. Like I, you know,
how many fucking guys did you see though,
that that kid just fucking took him right
down to the mat? A ton, man. You know,
I always,
when I first started,
I remember Ray Romano was married
with two kids at the time.
Like how can he juggle both? I never knew
how he could do that. Yeah. I'm like,
how could it be funny and have a
family life and shit like that.
And I always thought,
there's no way I can have that.
I probably would have screwed it up in
my twenties and thirties once I got into
my forties I'm like, all right, I could
do it. Absolutely would have fucked it up.
I would have been a fucking
lunatic. And uh, you know,
I think there's a reason I waited
so, so, I mean, most of it was fear,
but a lot of it was I was a
fucking lunatic. Yeah. Same
Way. Same with, I'm like,
I'm going to screw this up.
I'm gonna fuck some girl on the road I
shouldn't be doing. You know what I mean?
As you get older, like that's,
it doesn't even, you know,
it's not even part of the equation.
When you have a bad set,
you take it home with
you. Oh, absolutely. Yeah.
Maybe if you know me fucking
doing the dishes all the time,
I know if I would've just got,
if you would allow me to take
a nap and I had to watch a kid,
you know how to work that
night, yell out shit. So No,
when I look back to all the
fucking shit that I went through,
the I really did not have
to go through. And, uh,
that's what verse he cracks me up.
You know, Paul Versey. Yeah, yeah.
Like I just was like, dude,
where the fuck were you?
I wish there was a version of you might,
maybe there wasn't.
I just didn't pay attention. Like he
has the most fucking normal life. Like,
and then he just goes on the
road, you know, as a comedian.
Then he comes home like completely
fucking normal and like,
he's like an 80 year old man and like
a 35 year old body and like it, like I,
he has like comics over and they
always say that like younger comics,
like his fucking age always going
over there like, oh my wow, dude.
So you just like, you
know, you got a wife,
couple of kids and see she's cool with you
going out and uh, he's like, yeah, yeah,
that was doing standup when I met
her and Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So I always think of like whenever I look
at the way I always tell him, you know,
cause uh, I always go, dude,
you're fucking doing it right.
No, absolutely doing it.
You, you did it. He's doing it. Like
that's the way Ray Romano did. Ray Romano,
who got married at the regular age,
started a family at the regular fucking
age and all of that and uh, still hit.
And you know, it's great to, was he,
he got 'em he got in before Seinfeld
hit that big payday on the syndication.
Cause I have a theory that
after they had to pay Seinfeld,
that Hollywood all got
together and was like,
how the fuck do we owe a stand up
comedian? Half a billion dollars?
How does this deal work?
Never give this deal out again.
Well Ray Romano is still has it.
Well he's the last one cause that was it.
Nobody ever got the, I don't think
anybody's gotten it created by,
it was a combination of the creative by
a performer, a producer and a writer.
Checky pull those four fucking
checks off the same goddamn show.
And then there wasn't the,
the influence of the Internet and video
games and all this shit. You know,
I've been making fun of that stupid,
those fucking virtual reality.
It's that thing.
You put the phone up to the glasses and
the level with which people are freaking
out. Like, Oh, I go, oh, like,
like you don't know you're still
in your living room. Right.
I fucking hate that's right up there
with the people when they're blindfolded
and they're uh, they're feeding them
all of garden and they, they'll,
when they can't tell, oh my God, it's
so decadent. It's like olive garden.
It's like a seventh grader can
make pasta like that. Yeah.
And the only people that
eat it all of garden,
it's right outside of a hotel and you
have no choice. It's business people.
You don't have a car and you'd have to
walk through. And I was broke. I used to,
and I loved it because they kept bringing
the bread and would just fill you up
slowly. My bread, I fucking
love that. I know I gotta.
I gotta wait until eats it a club
eight o'clock. So if I eat it too,
I'll fill up til eight.
And then I get a free meal at the club.
It was a long time. That was a class
he plays to bring a date for me.
They had wine. Yeah. You know, come on.
Even another glass of wine. Here we go.
Angel Hair, pasta, watching
your weight. So when uh,
when does this special come up? Friday,
December 9th. Friday, December 9th,
which is tomorrow. Um, I
guess, I don't know. Now.
It tastes way people listen to podcasts
and uh, we're going to have a look.
Do we have a link that I can, um,
text out here? Do we have anything?
Bueller? Okay. It is, can
I have it so I can say it?
Jesus Christ. I know we didn't
play in this, so this isn't
on you. I'm just saying.
All right, this is, this is the level of
professionalism that I have on my, uh,
my podcast. Well, you got,
you got any road date?
Is there anything you want to
plug coming up? Um, now just,
I'm doing a stand in New York City, New
Year's Eve. Nice. Yeah. I love that club.
Yeah. That's a fucking great
cloud. That's great. It's kind of,
it's like the seller 2.0 yeah. Just go
down there man. It's like, you know,
sometimes there's 10 people on a Thursday,
which is fucking beautiful.
I love that.
Yeah.
And just do what you know and just
record your sets and work it out.
And so I loved it. So I love
playing that place. And,
and Bennington is going to host at night.
Ron Bennington.
He's doing standup again. Yeah.
So he's a host at nine years.
I didn't even know he did stand up.
I guess he did it back in the day.
I guess he had a club down in
Florida when he was on, I don't know,
I don't remember this,
but that's what we're were saying.
And then I did this thing with
Bobby Kelly called creeps were kids.
It was made a bunch of the comics.
We had kids and we did a whole show on
Bennington hosted and did stand up on it
a couple of months ago. It creeps
with kids grades for kids. Yeah.
He wants to take that
around the country. He, uh,
I did one of his Ron Bennington,
whatever the fuck he call you on
mass and it was going to say exposed.
It just flashed the crown. Yeah. He's
a fucking great interviewer and all,
all of that.
I had no idea you did stand up.
I would love to see because he's funny.
He's fucking hell. He's great man.
Ron in Fez did. They don't do that shit
anymore. I don't know. Feds just um,
basically just quit. Or he did the Robert
Plant. Yeah, he just said, you know,
we peaked. He had done, he had his 14
million or whatever the fuck he had. Yeah.
So Ron does it with his
daughter. Oh, all right.
I got to get back east,
dude. I don't even,
I don't even know what's going on anymore.
Yeah, it's, it's every, every week.
It's something different. Opie's on in the
afternoon. Now Jim's on in the morning,
which Sam Roberts and Opie and Anthony
are talking again. I know, I see.
I'm wondering now is if they ever
do like if they ever have, you know,
like the rock and roll hall of fame,
how backstage,
how weird it must be with those bands
that had all the problems and then they
got to walk out together.
Like if there's ever like a radio hall
of fame at some point they got to bring
opie and Anthony. Jimmy I know.
So they all got to be there. Uh,
I'll hope when they get back together.
I think enough time has gone.
I don't know if enough time has
gone by, but uh, you know, I dunno.
I think they will at some
point. You know, I think he,
I think I'll be an Anthony at least.
Well and then hopefully Jim,
hopefully you'll be to trio back.
Why can't they do like the Mike and the
mechanics thing? We, you just go out,
you fucking do a couple of solo records.
Then you reform is genesis.
I know. I guess that doesn't work
with radio. You're going to kind of,
you can't just do little fucking,
hey,
we're going to be opening an Anthony for
six months and then we're doing that.
I'm going to do my side project.
I never had a good head for business.
How did you deal with the election?
Were you one of those people crying when
you sell a Hillary didn't break through
that final glass ceiling? No, not at all.
Did you watch it at all? I watch it. Yeah.
I fell asleep like around like one 30
and then I was down at Disney world,
my kid, and then everyone was crying
the next day at Disney. You know,
what am I going to tell my kids? I, I want
him to, Mike woke up, I go, Trump won.
He goes, okay. That's what I
told them. Yeah, I don't, uh,
this always happens. It always happens.
Like I remember after, after Bush,
it was just,
fuck anybody wearing a red
tie was everybody in and
all the blue guys came in.
Right. Same Bullshit happens,
right? Same fucking bullshit.
They forgive the banks still got
Guantanamo. We're not end the fucking war.
Beauvoir no, none of the fucking bankers
go to jail. And then it's like, hey,
it's still blue guy, ty fault.
Nothing but red tie. Like,
like this is going to be,
I have to tell you was fucking hilarious.
Was out of all the celebrities and it
was so many of them just, you know, um,
campaigning,
which is so fucked up to me cause I'm
old enough to remember what you didn't
tell anybody who you voted
for. And I think that they
actually hurt the camp. Uh,
it's just so weird. Like
why would I listen to, to an
actor, tell me, I know Jay z,
like even if I'm a Jay z Fan, am I going
to fit well? Who's he voted for? Okay,
I'll vote for him.
Like he pays attention.
They ain't fucking guy trying to keep his
fucking billion dollar business going.
Like he has the fucking time.
I don't have the time and
I'm not doing shit right.
I don't have time to keep up on it.
So,
but the funny one I just saw it
recently was Scott Bail, who I love, um,
the, the most like, you know,
make America great again.
I just loved how vague it was. Let's
make America great again. It's so,
he goes out, I guess at the
Republican National Convention,
Scott fucking bales there.
Why to match whoever the fuck
are the blue blue guys have.
So he goes out there, this
is what he said. He goes,
we're here not only to
make America great again,
but more importantly,
make America America again.
And he got a fucking applause
break. Like what the fuck is? Yeah,
what does that mean?
Let's make toast toast again.
What does that mean? Don't put butter on
it. Just just toast to thing and like,
what the fuck does that mean?
Now you can read all the way into it.
That means like, let's make it all
for fucking white people only again,
which is far as I can tell.
It really still kind of is for as much
as much as the people on the red red tide
site are complaining, it's still pretty
great for fucking white people. I don't,
I don't know what their problem is.
I think it's other white people with
all different types of ties working in
banks fucking them over. And for some
reason they, I don't know what they think.
It's a taxi driver.
I have no fucking idea.
But like make America America again.
Yeah, it's, it's ridiculous. You know, the
Hillary stuff, you know, people are like,
how can women voted for Trump? Like why
would a woman vote for Trump? I have to,
all that stuff came out of grabbing the
posting and all that stuff. It's like,
okay,
every girl that voted for fucking Trump
knows four guys that talk exactly like
him. They've known him since high school.
They don't have since gray. And He,
and they're over every
Sunday for football.
They were over for Thanksgiving and
they go, no new year's Eve party.
They all know that guy. They don't hate
them. They still hang around with them.
How I felt until all those women
came forward. And I was like, Oh,
I maybe the Hillary campaign
paid him until that one's,
the one lady goes, um, you know,
he started hitting on a corner and started
hitting on it and she goes, come on,
get real, get real. Cause he's so
fucking old, which is hilarious.
It's just exactly like what kind of
fantasy you live in that I'm so pathetic.
I'd hook up with a fucking skeleton
like you. So she goes, get real.
And then she goes,
he,
then he had his hands in his pocket or
something to thrusted as generalists
toward me and said,
get re and was just so
fucking the detail of it.
I was in the car, my wife and I was
like, oh my, I was like, that happened.
That definitely fucking
happen. Oh yeah, yeah.
He's been doing that stuff for
a long time and, but whatever.
But the women had no problem with what
Trump said, all of that stuff. He said,
you know, grabbing the pussy, it was a
pig. He did all of that and none of them.
That didn't factor anyone's decision.
Or like I know six creeps just like that.
That's the same way I think
my husband talks that way.
But I feel like if you're a woman in
your pussy isn't going to be near enough
Trump to be grabbed.
If he's going to give you a tax cut,
I think you're going to go with
it. Like I know, I don't know.
Proof people do what's good for them.
That's absolutely vote.
Like I would sit there, hey,
this guy's people yelling
Edward at the rally. I, yeah.
You know, I'm not into that,
but, but, but Hillary, blah
blah. So it's like, it's like,
so you don't care.
Like,
like most white people do not give a shit
about racism because it doesn't affect
them. You know what I mean? Yup.
That's the kind of thing that I would
love to say back in the day on Opie and
Anthony. Then they would talk
about like, you know, uh,
affirmative action. You know,
these white chairs can you in
the fuck school. It's like, dude,
if you can't beat out the inner city
kid who probably had fucking Shitty or
books 20 times,
you shouldn't be fucking go in there.
That's like when people are
out here, they'll run into
a bad club owner out here.
We like fucking La is not working out for
me. It's like, dude, if you can't get,
if you don't make it in this business,
cause a one fucking club owner or
something like that, then I mean Wa yeah.
Who gives a shit about that?
Yeah. It's just like it does this,
this is a Zillion fucking clubs
is a zillion doors to get through.
If you're just going to let give this
one person all of this fucking power.
It's that same thing like,
you know in the city,
there's a law in New York City is
11 clubs that do comedy every night.
I tell young, calm, so it would
just get in one or two. It doesn't,
don't worry about the other nine
and then eventually we'll get them.
And who cares?
That danger fields said you're not in
a room who's right for that room and
nobody knows nobody. Nobody's right
forever. I'm don't take that personally.
Go with the go work at the fucking
stand or stand up New York,
you'll do better there.
Anyway,
I did a pop in spot there about a year
ago at Dangerfield and it was like,
it was literally like no time had
gone by in that. Nothing had changed.
Their UB obviously different faces shower.
He was still a way to
there as far as I know,
and I fucking went up in front of
this crowd and just fucking ate it.
Ate it like I was a fucking three years
into the business. Just went up there.
They finally fixed the sound. Do you
remember at that club, the fucking reverb?
REVERB was cranked up?
Yes.
So fucking high for like fucking eight
years and there was this little mixer up
there and it was awesome.
He had to do was just fucking fade
something up or down or turn a knob and
nobody did it for eight years.
I just remember whenever,
if you did a bit that
was loud and it bombed,
how they would be that fucking echo.
Like when Dean Martin would
sing at Capitol records,
it had like that fucking echo
thing going on and it made it like,
it's almost like a bomb twice cause they
got to hear the echo of whatever they
just, they didn't fucking
laugh at. But uh, dude,
I haven't done the clubs back then and
so, uh, I've been out here for a while.
Well that room was, you know, they don't
tell you what the cover charges. You know,
a kid comes in 22 years old
when his girlfriend, some
chick, he's trying to bang.
Yeah, let's go to Dangerfield
Rodney Dangerfield yet. And
they, oh yeah, come on in,
come on, sit down, sit down
the cover charges like $19.
This is like in 1995 like 19 ahead and
the drinks are like $19 and it's a two
drink minimum. So you know,
you're the comedians up.
Then all of a sudden he's like,
Oh let's get out of it.
It's socks cause nobody's laughing.
You were in a pitch pitch black dark,
you can't see a fucking thing
in front of you. And then a kid,
the 19 year old kid that's trying to bang,
this chick gets a check for like $102.
He's been in the club for
30 minutes. Wow. 100 today.
And you just hear screaming in the
back though. You got to pay what?
I didn't know it cost $19 again at $19.
They don't tell you when nothing's
posted. Oh God. And then they do,
you know if you're going to a great
club though, it's a great class.
A little laid out. I don't want to shit on
all these. No, no, no, no, no. It's, it's,
it is for a comp and especially in New
York City where you could actually do 30,
25 to 30 minutes,
you can't do it at a most of the clubs.
Well Jim Norton was the guy that
got us all in there. He all,
you got to all of us on opiate Anthony
and he got all of us to do danger fields
before that because he was,
um, he was one of those few,
well I guess cause he was a Jersey guy,
but I was like,
somebody that's New York comics,
we're just content to just do,
you know the New York clubs,
you know the comic strip and that was it.
And do their 20 minutes and it's just
like, dude, don't you want to expand this?
At some point you're gonna
have to do back then,
remember it was 45 minutes to close,
then it became an hour and now
you gotta do like an hour plus.
But back when we started out
as the opener did like 10,
eight to 10 brought up the feature,
who did 20 and then a or 25 maybe
25 maybe a half at the most.
And then the headliner did 45 that was
your show. 90 minutes. So it's, yeah,
it's 1530 45 and I remember thinking,
Oh my God,
I don't fuck do you do 45 minutes?
How do you get that?
Last 15 minutes together.
Now it's like you gotta you gotta do
like a fucking hour and 10 minutes,
hour and 15.
Uh,
um,
what's his face last night? Uh,
Jesus Christ. I'm getting so old.
It just spaced on his fucking name.
The guy from black flag,
Henry Rollins, Rollins, he's the
one who spoke spoken word thing.
I got to stop fucking talking to myself.
I've got to go to those headpieces cause
I really think it's fucking with my
memory. Henry Rollins, right? I fucking
went to see that guy do debt, dude.
He does like two and a half hours
and it's just like he and he's like,
it's fucking unbelievable. And
he's intense, right? The whole two,
whenever that whole fucking at the
time it was funny. Droves. It goes.
I was with Jerome, I'm like this
fucking guy, dude. He comes out,
it's like when they go, ladies and
gentlemen, please welcome Henry Rollins.
They barely get the s of Rollins
and he's fucking out there, right?
And he comes walking out and he does
this bow and his fists are clenched and
then he takes the mic out of the mic
stand and he's such rapid the cord around
his fucking head. It was just, it was,
it was the guy was fucking amazing.
And um,
I made two rows.
I laughed my ass off cause cause we were
watching the guys, God, Jesus Christ,
the guys go fucking intense. And he goes
like, yeah dude and he's stone sober.
I was like, Yo, I gotta
tell you something.
I don't think I've ever seen a guy who
needs a drink more than this guy this
fucking like and he doesn't take on water.
Like he doesn't take a break.
I heard like he won't even
reach for water during his set.
I'm telling you it was like
just full on for two is yeah,
it was like a, I'm trying
to think of a band. Yeah,
I guess it would be like if you'd
never heard of ACDC, you know,
they don't play any ballads and if there
was no talking between songs and it was
all coal out of rosy,
right back and forth,
or even like raging against the machine
who doesn't talk when they were,
they were just, I've been to a million
old shows and it's just pure. No,
they don't talk and I just go one the one
song to another, to another, to another.
That's another band that their singer
won't do it. No, he won't do it.
There's so many of those fucking band.
There's millions and millions of
dollars on the table for them to do like
festivals over in Europe or the 80,000
people and do a tour to states and the
guy just won't do it. Well, here's,
this is the thing. If you're in a band,
okay,
and you start seeing your lead singer,
like reading a real estate
book or something on business,
you've got to burn that fucking thing
because he's going to invest his money
wisely and then he's not
going to need to do it.
And then you're going to be fucked.
I just can't imagine like,
mmm,
I can't in,
first of all,
I can't imagine the pressure of the
lead singer where it's like, what if,
what if the drummer fucked up
and it doesn't have his Goddamn,
it doesn't have money.
And it's just like you could just go
do a fucking tour just to help him out.
You got the pressure of him going,
come on man,
I'm going to lose my fucking house.
Him and his, and he'd be like,
during the 90s we made enough money.
You never shed at work again.
Well I was bad with money. Yeah,
well that's just do three kings,
that's the thing,
which is mostly what journey.
They all invest their money and that's
why Steven Perry has a lot of money.
They were like the first rock band real
really like put their money away and had
good financial planning and stuff.
So they didn't have to do that.
They didn't do anything for a
while until I got the Asian singer.
They had another guy in every four, but
they didn't have to do it. Um, but yeah,
a lot of bands like, but this guy in rage
against machine, he just, they have a,
they have a band meeting once a year.
He doesn't even have a cell phone.
They have to like call
somebody to call somebody.
It's almost like when they were,
you know,
like trying to find
bin Ladin he shows off.
They talk about rage against the machine
and you want to put this remaster I
whatever. Yeah, okay to hang for a couple
hours. And he goes, oh, I'll see you guys.
And then you don't see them for a year
when I like looked as about 80 million on
the table. If we do about 50 dates.
Nah Man, I'm good. I'm all right.
Jesus.
Well,
well supposedly supposedly the rumor what
guns and roses they got back together,
you know, slash going through a divorce
and I don't even know if it's final yet,
but he had no prenup.
Married for 20 years in La with two kids.
He was going to lose more
than 50% of his money.
And supposedly the cut is axle gets 50,
uh slash gets 25 and duff gets 25 and
slash we'll pay his other guys in the
band.
UFC Still Guy Richie forward us,
he's got his drummer and all that does
he read the keyboard at that comes out of
axles money.
But supposedly what I heard is a doff is
given some of his money to slash cause
Duff's made so many good investments has
so much money that he's like dude are
you going to need it?
Cause he's trying to pay this divorce off
of whatever the money is gonna have to
pay it.
Tufts actually given slash some of the
money and that's one of the main reasons
they got back together.
The axle never likes slash his wife.
So as soon as they got married 20 years
ago, whatever that everything fell apart.
As soon as they broke up they started
talking again and they've got the band
back together. But supposedly duff has
given a cut to slash to help him out.
Jesus Christ, 20 years.
California is a mother,
20 years and no prenup to kids.
How does it work? Like if you got married
in California, but then you move to,
to Washington and then
if it falls apart there,
do you then go by the laws of the state
that you got married in or the state
you're in there? I don't know. I don't
know how that works. Yeah, dude, it's,
did you see what happened in the
beautiful woman there on, uh,
you know the two gay guys, the guy of Al
Al Bundy from married with children. Uh,
what the fuck's the name of that show?
Alternative lifestyles. Mato Mato family.
Family. Yeah. That fucking show. Did you,
did you see what's what
she's going through? No,
she was with some guy and they were
gonna do that fucking in vitro,
so I don't know.
And he's Oh yeah.
And he's so in for the embryos named him.
Dude,
if that was my son, I'd be like, you
fucking piece of shit. Get a fucking job,
get a fucking job through that is dead.
Is the conti hust bitchy as fucking thing.
I've seen somebody doing a long fucking,
he named the embryos people do
me you fucking piece of shit.
You think of it as a waitress in
Hooters? Would it be then when us, no,
he just knows she has money and he
wants child support and he wants child
support.
That happened to something like my wife
was telling me that happened to some
other woman, same font. I
think fucking things like,
dude, that is just like, yeah,
that a woman from the view,
the black chick from the view that quit.
What's your name? A star
Jones. Was it? She did.
She had a baby with this
dude or whatever like that.
Star Jones was the one who fucking got
a stomach stapled and it was like, Nah,
I just been doing cardio.
Yeah, grapefruit. Yeah, I
had, I was our, yeah. Oh,
so she's at a number of, but she had
the other chick who was the other one.
Rosie O'donnell then called the route was
like, now you lang, you fucking get it.
Yeah, you got it stapled.
You know what's amazing,
rex? Ryan's getting fat
again. Like how do you,
how you fucking push that band right off.
He said that his brother ever since his
brother got in town that did squat and
they keep it, they can't stop eating. That
was as cues 20 heart, his brother after,
you know, it's funny like, yeah, if
you move to buffalo, you're in trouble.
There's no healthy place to eat. Yeah.
I think that was it duff, is it Duffy's?
Duffys the anchor bar and did the two
places that claim that they invented the
winks. Yeah, there's debt. Those two,
if he goes to Minnesota and they got
those juicy Lucy's, you know the Burgers,
we put the fucking cheese in the middle
of it. There's a lot of tough cities.
New York. You could actually eat healthy
though. You know he has rex Ryan.
If he's not going to fucking,
if he's going to stay skinny needs to
coach a team in like self-involved cities
only. Yeah. Like if he was the La Rams,
rams, rams, giants and jets, he be good.
San Diego, San Diego.
That's a, yeah, yeah, yeah.
He'd meet some that might fuck up his
marriage. So this is so many beautiful,
cool chicks down there. You might
have a fucking problem. You know,
they're all walking around in
sandals. He's into fee, you know,
you walking around with no
shirt on and shit, you know,
so. All right, we're gonna,
we're gonna wrap up here. Do it. It's
always so great to see. I'm so proud, man.
You've got this special coming out once
again called a simple man. Simple man.
Simple man. You can see it
starting tomorrow, December 9th,
2016 if you listen to this 20 year and
the years in the fucking future, um,
iTunes in on Amazon and uh, was
taped in New Jersey. And uh,
you said you taped it how long ago?
Like a year and a half ago.
It was about a year and a half. I'll see.
You already got your new hour. You Ready?
I'm ready. I'm ready. Don't want an
f in about a month, dude. I'm not.
Mine's coming out in January.
I taped it in October and I've just been
sitting around waiting for this kid to
show up. So, uh, oh. And the ones that
kid to the floodgates are going to open.
I know. Hundred. Hey, you haven't been
changing a diaper. What's up with that?
I don't want to be the front
and you won't be there.
I thought I was going to be to
cause all my friends, like, Oh men,
you and I have a kid.
You're not gonna be doing kid jokes.
You start tucking my shirt
in and wear a sport coat.
You know when you go on stage, the dad
shit with the fucking gap jeans. Yeah.
Well that's the thing.
When you first, you know,
the first six months is hairy
man has no sleep. Everyone's
cranky.
You're up every two hours.
You'd have to take shifts or whatever
like that and you just got to make sure
you're almost like don't put on that
extra that dad weight in the beginning.
Yeah, no, I'm actually trying,
I'm trying to drop a bunch of weight
before the kid gets there just because
we'll put them, we're going
to be so exhausted. If you,
whatever your work out is,
you're going to fuck that
I'm taking a nap. Yeah. Well,
that's why I think I'm not working
on the road until February,
but once I'm in February, in February,
I would like to, uh, you know,
just start going back out again because
I figure I'll have my hour together by
then enough to actually have somebody
paid to see me do standup again. And um,
the game plan is to, uh, you know, do my,
I still do my two weekends a month,
so I figured I'll just go out and just
sleep when I'm on the road, do my show,
go back, go to sleep and that, that'll
be my thing. And then with my wife,
I'm just going to one day a week,
I'm going to give it like a fucking
spa day where she just goes and fucking
probably sleeps during the
massage or whatever. I just,
I feel like my big thing is that I keep
her fucking chill and happy the best I
can then that that'll get through this.
Absolutely. Yeah. That's what I did.
I'd slept on the road. I did all my work
on the road to how old's your son now?
He's six. He just turned six. Six.
Yeah. Fuck of the year's going.
Holy Shit. Six years old and when he
plays drums and stuff, he's played drums.
He sings.
He's going in the recording studio and
next week that would cut two songs as if
he's got two originals ones called evil
pumpkin because he had a dream about a
pumpkin and you already wrote
the lyrics forward and let me,
let me want the heaven is a ballad
because he was a Motorhead fan.
He never got to meet Lemmy, so he sings
about it. He's a, he's a, he's insane.
Jesus Christ. Dude. You're
raising them, right? Oh yeah.
Taking them a dolphin games.
He's been to three games already this
year, is that right? Oh yeah. He loves it.
Dolphins game. Oh, I turned
them down in Miami twice.
We went to a ravens game last week down
in Baltimore. He almost meant Marino.
He's Big Marino Fang, some
friends, we'll Marino.
So we're trying to get on the field.
We code it and so he's like,
you got to meet you. I'm like,
luck. Yeah. He already met Ozzy.
He's pissed and he hasn't met Angus Young.
Oh my God.
That's a tough one to pull off.
I don't know if I can do,
he can't get rid of Nero's ACDC guys.
Brian Johnson when he was in a band
you could, but that's tough to get.
We had um, a once on that metal
show. I met him once and that's good.
Brian Johnson at all an Angus. Wow.
Yeah, Angus was on. How was that?
It was great.
Right when black ice come out.
That was like a 2008 we first
started doing the show. Yeah.
And I ran into you at the forum.
Yeah, we went to the show. Yeah. Uh,
I'm a huge ACDC fan. What would they
like? I know Brian's cool as well.
First of all, my son saw ACDC
with Brian Johnson and axle,
so he's seen him with two
different singers, which is great.
And He loved both of them. Well, axle
did a great job. He did an amazing job.
I saw it twice in one week. It was so
good. You know, what's amazing about,
about axles voices to fact that he
was a hermit and didn't tour forever.
He still has it.
It's amazing how that guy,
I give him the comeback player of the
year between guns and roses doing two and
a half hour shows and,
and pulling off the bond.
Scott and the Brian Johnson
ACDC stuff. He's like, I hate
supposedly he, he had uh,
you know, he just realized all these
guys die and David Bowie, you know,
everywhere all these rock stars dying.
He's like,
what am I doing seriously at this point,
let me just let me go back out there.
Let's get the band back together
and go have fun, play stadiums.
And then went and then he was a
huge ACDC fan at Bon Scott Fan.
I was his favorite band growing up.
He actually made the call,
he called them and said, hey, if you
guys need any help, just let me know.
And they go will come down and audition
and next thing you know, he had the Gig.
Wow.
And the bonds got shitty.
They were pulling out like the
stuff they haven't done in years.
If you want blood, you got
it. They were doing live.
Oh did they live wire killer shit.
Yeah.
Cause they hadn't played
that since bond died. Yeah.
And they did problem child the last night.
I sold it last night at a tour,
cliff Williams retired to bass player
and they played problem child on the
encore to go,
we haven't done this.
When we rehearsed it a
couple times they're going
to just did the prophet tired
from the day I retire from the band.
It was his last show in September. He,
I think he got that,
he's really close with Brian
and I think Brian got the shaft,
you know what I mean?
And they lit both live down in Florida.
They hang out in pubs, they drank and
shit like that. And it felt like Ah,
you know when I'm out man cause
it's just Angus left in a band.
Like what are you going
to do now? Oh God. So who,
who do they get through replace him
that nobody, cause the tour just ended.
So I didn't know what, you know, they'll
just hibernate for a couple of years.
So the band right now is Chris Slade,
Malcolm Young's brother Angus,
axel, axel and no bass players. Yeah.
So Angus is the only one, the original
guy in the band. So they can't come back.
They have to use axle.
They can't come back.
We're like a tribute singer from Texas,
you know,
and an appetite for destruction band.
They ain't no way.
They're not going to do arenas.
Um, man. So he stuck with it.
He had to come back. What happened? Brian?
Brian, he's hearing God. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. I know. Well, you
know, looking at 68 years old,
he can only do two shows a week.
Angus wanted to do four or five.
You don't want to sit in a hotel.
You got a crew of like 300 people.
It's expensive to be out on the road
and I can just wants to play, you know,
every other night.
Brian can only do it two nights.
Did you know it's a physical show
to do one, two and a half hours.
It's the singers. The big
thing. You can play guitar.
Angus l does fucking flop around on
the floor and shit. The guys that,
he's like 61 61 yeah.
Yeah. And he's still,
he's still still weighs
96 pounds and still,
I know he never drank or
did drugs back in the day.
Used to drink milkshakes and
shit just out and burn them off.
Smoke four packs of cigarettes a day.
Yeah, that was his vice, Huh? Fuck.
So I don't know what's going on but,
but Brian based,
so as soon as they found out something
as almost like a marriage, you know,
you're married like 30 years
and all of a sudden you know,
you see your wife was talking to an
old boyfriend on Facebook. That's it.
We're divorced. See, something's going
on. Like they were just, I think I liked,
they were looking for an excuse to let
Bryan goal because anger Angus still
wants to do it is Sangha [inaudible]
all the money that's out there,
he could play till he's 70 years old.
He could still run around.
So Brian was basically winding
down. So he's like, all right,
I got to get him out somehow.
Get somebody else in and continue this.
What they really should have done. Just
said, Brian said, hey, I'm going to,
I'm going to retire after it is,
and then, you know, good luck to,
those guys are going to get a new lead
singer and they're gonna carry on.
The fans would have bought that, but
there are a lot of them aren't buying it.
There was a lot of tickets, like they
were only doing about 10,000 people.
Like a lot of people returned to tickets.
Like,
fuck that you guys fucked
over Brian Johnson. I don't
give a shit who's singing?
We're not coming to see the band. So who
knows what they're going to do now that,
cause you know Jim Rowers to one who
broke that brewer hung out with Brian
Johnson like a week after the shit went
down and basically went on his podcast
and said, Brian's like, they fucked
me. I said, I have a hearing problem.
The next thing I know,
I hear on the news that the tour is off
and I'm out at a band and two days later
they shipped all my shit to my house.
Like a ups or a bail.
You U haul truck shows up with all
my equipment. Is that true? I, yeah.
Well that's what he told.
Borrower and brewer talked about it
and Brian had a back off. No, no,
it didn't go down like that, but
you know it did. He just said, look,
I got to hear him problem.
I'm just telling you that it's,
it's eventually going to be a bigger
problem, but you know, whatever.
We have 10 shows left.
Obviously I'm going to do one,
but I got to figure this shit out and
they just said the next day, all right,
he's out of the band. Goodbye. He's
retiring. He can't play anymore. Jesus,
that makes me happy. I'm a
comedian, you know? I know.
Just on us to deal with that.
Just to us, that level of shit. All right,
well that's the Thursday
afternoon podcast. I got to
read some advertising here.
I will not make you sit through
listening to me. I don't care, man.
But if you go to Jim florentine.com
put the Promo Code [inaudible],
you'll get it for five bucks to special.
If you don't, if you don't go to iTunes,
there's a sort of doing
that. Okay, well shit.
Guess what I'm doing when I get home?
Well I'm going to lamaze class.
The last fucking one we didn't
get into that I'd fucking out.
I did want to know is birthing natural
birthing classes. You know what,
we went to it like an infant
infant care thing and I, you know,
they taught us how to change a diaper
and shit. Like, so like I, you know,
I had younger brothers and sisters so
I knew how to do it, but then like a,
you know, I just hadn't done in a while.
So that one actually was just like,
oh yeah, okay. It's good to teach how
to ramp the kid up and that shit. Okay,
I get this. But that fucking, this is
the last one to dude, I'll tell you this,
this is the last one. And uh, I wish it
was a pub right across the fucking street,
cause I would go out and
celebrate that this fucking class.
I mean the ladies Nice who teaches it?
Everybody in the class and nice,
but he's just a fucking waste.
It's what the fuck are we doing?
I did the same thing when my
wife at the time and at one,
I remember one time she goes,
I have a headache. She's like,
I don't know if I'm going to be able
to make the class tonight. Are You mad?
I'm like, I got no, no, don't
worry about it. She goes, no,
I don't want to miss this one. Uh, you
know, if you, if you really want to go,
we'll go. Like I'm not, don't worry
about it. If you've got a headache,
let's just stay home. Who knows? It
could be something worse. I'm like,
fucking beautiful. You know,
cause you have to take the
bullet and go, yeah, no, go,
go. When you just sit
there and like, okay look,
this is going to be six other people in
the room that went to fucking school for
this for eight years. I'm just some
fucking asshole. How am I going to help?
It's the stupidest fucking,
it's the stupidest thing ever.
It is six doctors in there to
know what the hell the doin.
And I'm just standing there.
It's the only fucking procedure.
What medical procedure that you're
fucking in there. I worked in a dental
office, Mike, my dad would tell him,
get out of here cause they're going
to see blood. You're gonna Faint now.
I've got two patients in the fuck
out of here. I don't need you here.
One more dude. Just the amount of
fucking times I look at that clock, dude.
It's like, it's insane. It is
insane. It's like two hours, right?
So no one seven oh two seven oh four
don't look, don't look seven oh six fuck,
fuck. And then they bust out like
a film strip, a little video.
And I'm psyched again. It's like
I'm in high school again. Oh good.
A fucking film strip. I could just
fucking chill out and not think, well,
mine was shown like natural birth,
like an a in the bathtub.
And they had like there,
the woman was putting VHS tapes in
from women from like the 80s that had,
you know, kids at home and their
bathtub and they're showing,
they're showing the kid coming out
and he's big, hairy pussies, you know,
like these bushes that are
really high because it was,
it was so seriously from like the 80s
there were on like a camcorder and filmed
on him. Like you gotta be
fucking kidding me. Oh,
at least that's funny man. I
fucking like, dude. It was funny.
There was showing like, you know, if
the woman's having trouble they can make
an incision basically along the taint.
Yeah, I know. Sorry guys.
Either vertical or like fucking at
an angle and I'm looking at it and I,
and it's just as drawing and I
was going like, Jesus Christ,
why is the clit so big? And it was the
asshole. Like there was drones so bad that
my wife was dying because they just sort
of like drew a Bush a little bit like,
and then they just had like this black
hole and I couldn't tell if she was
laying on his stomach or on her back.
And I was just like, it was fun.
It was like a week later I said,
I said, yeah, and it's still,
why did they draw the clips?
No,
I figured out in the class
and then I laughed to myself.
Then I told my wife and she was
fucking dying laughing. I was like,
what did that look like? A
fucking asshole. It didn't,
they didn't draw it right.
All right, this is way off
topic. Um, uh, I was, uh, s uh,
iron narrative already forgot Jim
Florentine, a simple math simple men.
I want to set a sane man.
A simple man is going to be
once again iTunes and on Amazon.
I'm going to read some, uh,
advertising here. Jim, thank
you so much for coming by.
Absolutely. Always a pleasure to see
that. Thanks man. And, uh, I dunno.
I hope that I'll run into you it back
east and I will do a couple sets of
Dangerfield. Yeah. All right. Well, I want
to go back there. I want to do a prom.
Yeah. Two in the morning.
I put it all right.
Are you ready?
All right. Everybody has, Here's
the reeds for this week. Okay.
This is the comedy within the comedy where
you get to listen to me read out loud.
All right. Oh, it's our old
friend, Sherry's berries. Uh,
no matter who you're shopping for,
Sherry's berries,
it's the one stop shop
for everyone on your list.
You don't have to battle the crowds
to get the perfect gift shop with
convenience right from your home.
I love how Sherry's berries is talking.
This like,
you buying them a
fucking diamond. It's a strawberry fucking
chocolate covered strawberry. This is,
this is like, this is like
a fucking tertiary. There's
a stocking stuffer, right?
Anyways, Christmas is a,
it's only a, what's today?
I'm not doing the fucking math. You
know, when it says December 25th,
it's like 13 days away or
give or take with only, um,
all right. Fucking 25 minus 18.
Okay, that's fine. My 17 days,
17 days left to shop,
wrap and deliver your gifts.
Do you really want to deal with that shit?
Would it be great if there was
a lot of people on your list?
You could just give him chocolate
covered strawberries and just Frisbee,
right Adam? Well, this is the
place to go. Sherry's berries,
they offer freshly jipped strawberries
from Sherry's berries starting at just
1999, 20 bucks. Go Fuck Yourself.
See a next Christmas that's over a
30% saving or double the berries.
These a fat fuck right? For
just $10 more. All right,
you just need my code. Take
advantage of this deal. Uh,
to take advantage of the deal.
And the code is bur bur um,
descriptive words, decadent, fresh,
juicy, sweet, shareable and irresistible.
Um, anyways, with Christmas
right around the corner,
there's only one way to get the amazing
1999 Sherry's berries deal and help
support our show.
Just visit berries.com,
B e r r I e s.com.
Um,
and click on the microphone in the top
right hand corner and type in Bern.
All right, legacy box. All right.
This isn't some chick. Oh, he's wanting
to bang. All right. Legacy box. When the,
when was the last time you
watched your home movies? Um,
if you're like most Americans, there was
a box in your closet of videotapes, film,
film, reels, and photos that
you don't get. Don't get
washed to take it out. Worst,
they're actually deteriorating. I have
to fucking do this with my old standup.
Takes a introducing legacy box as simple
and affordable way to get your recorded
moments digitally preserved on DVD or
a thumb drive. Here's how it works.
Load legacy box with your old tapes,
film pictures and audio
recordings and send it back.
You'll get them back in a couple of
weeks on DVD or a convenient thumbdrive
ready to watch, share and
relive legacy. Bach, uh,
takes care of everything and provides
updates at every step of the process.
That's why over 250,000 families
have used them. The Huffington Post,
parents magazine, USA Today, the
viewer all talking about legacy box.
In other words, they're paying them. Uh,
even Disney has trusted legacy
box to digitize their media.
And for a limited time,
go to legacy,
but legacy box.com/burr to get
a 40% discount on your order.
That's legacy box.com/ [inaudible] that's
a legacy box.com/birth that's fucking
great. That's like, that's
a great Christmas gift.
You can get your significant other,
just get it all down to one frigging file
and then when the next thing comes out,
you've got the little thumb drive
right there. Get it on the uh,
the fucking index finger
drive. Sorry. Alright,
tracker everybody,
we're all fucking loses.
Newsweek reports.
The average American wastes 55 minutes
a day looking for things they owned but
can't find.
Share a story when you've lost something.
You needed a one time I wanted to
start a fire, but there was no would,
I couldn't find the log.
So I ended up cutting up a chair and right
after I cut it up and lit it on fire,
I was like dash that fucking log.
Sorry. Trackers makes losing things.
The thing of the past,
and I'll tell you how to get one for
free and a minute track is a coin side
device. That's the locates. Misplaced
keys, wallets, bags, computers,
anything in seconds.
Just pair of tracker to your smartphone,
attach it to anything and find his
precise location with the tap of a button.
It's that easy. Uh,
listeners to this show,
get a free tracker tracker
Bravel with any order,
go to the tracker.com like the Ohio state,
the tracker.com and enter
the Promo Code Burr. Um,
you're free tracker.
Bravo.
Yeah,
if you go to it right now, you got a free
track. Oh, Bravo with any order again.
That's tracker.com Promo Code Burr.
Okay, we're getting down to it here.
How many fucking more. All right. Oh Shit.
Here we go. Give me the Lou Lou Craig.
Be The envy of your friends.
You get 100% exclusive
crates at [inaudible] dot
com slash burr and enter my
code burr to save $3 off
on any new subscription.
What do you think people would do if I
brought a fucking 12 pack to this lamaze
class? You know, it's the last, I'll
bring frank. I'll bring some wine, right?
It's French and just get fucking
hammered and make my wife drive home.
That might be the way to go.
Right? Anyways, wait until
I tell you about a dis.
December's crate.
It will have you fighting the power
loot crate offers an epic range of pop
culture items for less than $20 a month.
If you're more fanatical or fashion Nissa
then try loot where monthly wearables
and accessories with cult classics and
your favorite franchises get ready for
December's rebellious theme revolution.
Uh, they're always watching.
They've designed a system to keep you
down, man and their, and their meddlesome.
Hello friends. It's time for a
revolution. December's crate.
Am I not supposed to read every paragraph?
Am I supposed to pick one of these?
Cause they sound like they say the same
shit over and over again. Um, all right.
It's revolution again.
Exclusive items from assassin's creed.
Mr. Robot Firefly,
our monthly tee shirt and pin and
more including an exclusive Funko pop.
Do not wait.
You haven't tilled the 19th at 9:00 PM
Pacific to subscribe for the Decembers
crate. When it's over,
it's over. No more crates.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burr and
enter my promo code bur bur are to save
$3 off on any new subscription today.
Ah,
is our favorite. Everybody. It's old zip
recruiter.
Are you hiring?
Do you know where to post your
job to find the best candidates?
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find candidates while shit,
where do we go?
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post all your jobs on the
one top site and now you can with old zip
grown up.com.
You can post your job to 100 plus job
sites including social media networks like
Facebook and Twitter,
all with one single click,
click find candidates in any
city or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your qualified
candidates roll into ZipRecruiter's.
Easy to use. Interface. No juggling
emails or calls to your office.
Quickly screen the candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
You don't have time. You know why
you're running a god business.
Over a million businesses have used them.
And right now my listeners can
post jobs for free by going to
ziprecruiter.com/bar that's zip
recruiter.com/burr one more time.
Hey,
zip
red grownup.com/. Birth all
right, finally. Oh Jesus,
one more wink winch, formerly club Debbie
Club. Debbie, let's look fit it tears.
Uh, I don't know how to say this. W. I. N.
C the holidays are coming up. Need
to send a gift. Here's a hint.
Send wine
since or wink makes it easy for you to
send an impressive gift this holiday
season. Wink or winds has tons of
great gift packages, options for wine.
The wine lover in your life.
Check out their gift cards or a
personalized wine gift packages.
Wink or wince works directly with wine
makers and growers from all over the
world to create delicious wine
and deliver it right to your door.
100% satisfaction guarantee means if
you don't like the bottle they send you
that were pace it with a bottle,
you'll love no questions asked. Hey,
any more alcoholics out there, see the
fucking loophole and that one, Yay.
And I didn't really like that one. They
just keep fucking sending them to you,
walking around with you, great teeth
drinking that and read shit. Um,
you don't just get set
in random bottles either.
It's personalized wine membership that
recommends wine specifically for you
based on the results of your
palate profile quiz. Also,
you can rate all the wines you
received from wink or wins. Uh,
they learn about you with every order
and constantly personalize the wine that
they send. How do you sign up? This
is what you do. Uh, the best part,
wink or wince is offering my listeners
$20 off right now. When you go to try,
try W I N c.com/burr,
they'll even cover the shipping.
Uh,
you can try this thing and get $20 off
plus a complimentary shipping right now.
When you go to try Winc,
try wince.com/bird.
That's t, r, Y,W , I n
c.com/burr. Alright, mercifully,
that's the end of it.
Once again,
thanks to Jim Florentine for coming on
the podcast, check out his new specialist.
Simple man on amazon.com or on iTunes.
You can also download it off his
website for five bucks. All right?
Have a nice weekend. Get consent.
I'll talk to you on Monday.
[inaudible]
right. It's one of those deals
every year. There's that Douche.
Then there's always the Doshi west to try
and top everybody's stories. You know,
you can be sitting there
with the fucking astronaut
each somehow try to top
them or correct them.
Okay.
Well, actually I thought, uh,
according to, uh, you know, when,
I don't know what video games,
some fucking astronaut video
game that Douche played,
he'd actually try to question a real
artist who even knows an astronaut at this
point,
aren't they all dead?
Okay?
Did the people who are on the space
shuttle where they consider it astronauts
because I didn't consider them astronauts.
You're not an astronaut if
you're in a plane. Okay.
And I know it's a big one and I know
it's got rockets on it initially.
All right?
Okay.
But all I know is that the
astronauts that I grew up on with,
we're fucking,
they were at the top of a missile.
That's what day did,
you didn't stare that fucking thing.
I mean how they got back,
they had a little capsule.
Think he just leaned to one side.
You kept rolling back towards
the earth hoping you'd reenter.
Right then the parachutes came out
and they couldn't fucking find you.
Cause all we had was binoculars. You
know, where is he? I don't see you.
All right. Hang on the star, not, they
ain't not, not the star board. Right.
And you're fucking sitting there in
the water, clinging to a sting ray.
If you lucky,
you landed on an island and then you
met a genie who called your master,
but for some reason you never fucked her.
But other than that,
that's what an astronaut was even
didn't flying a fucking plane, you know,
Wheaton spaghettios or
whatever the fuck they did.
And then land and get towed to the gate
by a fucking Toyota Tundra. All right.
That's not an astronaut.
To me,
that's a very impressive pilot.
Very impressed.
You went a lot higher than the jumbo jet.
I flew to Syracuse. Sin
Hat's off to you, sir.
[inaudible]
your thoughts do.
My question is in here somewhere.
I am nowhere near a conspiracy
freak or anything like that,
but I do admit I get a hard on for any
documentary on that secret military base
in Nevada that is called area 51
the government is suppose, well,
I mean believe in aliens.
Like
I don't know that.
That's really not that crazy.
You know, you think like how
big the fucking universes.
There's just life on one planet,
no life anywhere else.
Despite the fact that they see evidence
of water on Mars at some point.
You know, I'm telling you
guys, we're not that special.
If you're God and you made
the whole university the,
I'm just going to sit back,
watch in one fucking planet. Maybe
that's why the earth is so fucked up.
I don't think he's been watching
us for the last couple of thousand.
He wasn't last time he reached
out. Reach out, reach out.
All right.
When's the last time he fucking did that
was the last time he fucking was in a
burning Bush going, hey, hey, you there,
you there with the long fucking Kirby
stick next to the sheep. Come over here.
Come over to the burning Bush. You know,
when was the last time we did that?
I think he's been watching another earth.
I'm flipping through the channels,
you know,
can imagine how clear his fucking,
how big do you think
God's flat screen TV is?
How clear is that picture?
I bet even if you make it to heaven,
you know,
you don't even get to see it.
Like he comes out of his office and he
tried to peek in real quick and like the
human eye, you can just, it's just too
much of a fucking glare. Right. Um,
so anyways. Yeah and if you believe in
aliens, I mean, I mean, I don't know that,
that, that we can reach
one another. You know,
that whole flying saucer
fucking over shit. I mean,
how long can you go with, with
artificial breathe, you know,
some sort of atmosphere in there.
It was like on Star Trek.
I mean they just had this
limitless supply of fucking oxygen.
Oh
well just fucking flying through space.
Now look at them.
They landed on a lot of planets that
at oxygen they would just land on these
planets and they just had oxygen. I think
what they did was they opened the day,
landed the star ship enterprise and they
just opened the windows and they got
some more oxygen and then they flew
away. Right. Isn't that how it works?
Anyways?
Um,
the government supposedly is housing and
researching crashed Ufo goes and uses
deadly force to keep regular people out.
Do you have any opinion on the
subject? I think I just said, I mean,
I don't fuck do I think they
actually have the bodies of aliens?
Um,
did you realize like the level of secrecy
you would have to have if you actually
had that shit? That would be like one of
the things before they went in the room.
It's like,
okay,
we're going to let you in this room and
you got to understand when you go in
this room,
the doors closing and you're never getting
out because you're going to see some
fucking shit in here that I
don't give a fuck. You're not.
If you have one shot a Nyquil, you're,
you're going to be blabbering about it.
You can't do it. So I, I don't, I
don't know. I don't fucking know.
Um, anyways, he goes, what
your bullshit meter say?
I think there's way too much of a veil
of secrecy around the place to think
otherwise. I used to know someone
who was a career air force pilot.
Whenever the subject of that base
or those mysterious for flights,
serious lights over Phoenix
scene in 1997 came up.
He completely removed himself from the
conversation. Uh, those mysterious lights,
I don't even know what you're
talking about for all you know,
they're just testing some
psycho fucking weaponry,
you know, were looking for when the new
Yankee stadium came out and like, oh,
eight or oh nine and they will,
like, we'd have 2013 technology.
All right.
If those fucking morons that run that
place can have shit that we're not going
to have, you know, they can be
four or five years ahead of us.
Can you imagine what the government is?
I mean, they got to have shit from like,
I dunno, 2014 I have no
fucking idea. I Dunno. Anyways,
he says quite frankly,
the evenings lapse would end right
after the topic was brought up.
I believe in life outside of our universe
to think that we human and Oliver's in
habit and so the only life
anywhere is just plain ignorant.
I 100% agree with that.
Uh,
I'm sure you've heard
stories about President Nixon
secretly showing you fos and
aliens to his favorite
comedian Jackie Gleason. Uhh,
that's a complete crock of shit. Uh, what
would you like? He's going to do that.
All right. Now I'm know I'm
not supposed to show you the
Arrow when we call. It was a bad
Nixon impression right there. Um,
what would happen if you were
shown some stuff like that?
I imagine I would immediately
be microchipped or shot
in the back of the fucking
head.
Would you tell about it?
I would want to know about that.
That if I actually found out about that,
it would blow my fucking mind.
I,
you know what it is?
Look maybe that maybe your Air
Force Guy Buddy that has seen some,
because I would say that like all
converse. No, but you know what,
he laughs right up until that moment.
If he wasn't laughing at all throughout
all your conversation, then I would,
I would believe it more because I
know if I knew some shit like that.
Okay.
And then I would sit there and listening
to people talking about God and Holy
Shit that we believe down here that
didn't include aliens. I would,
I would feel like a fucking alien.
Okay.
Cause that would be like, ah,
yeah, we're just a speck of dust.
They are people and there's all
this other stuff out there and uh,
yeah, I mean it would drive me
nuts after awhile. Um, yeah. No,
I'm not cut out for that fucking, uh, the
kind of secrets I can keep our like, uh,
you know,
it stays in the locker room kind of shit.
You know what I mean?
You live your life or you want to
fucking live your life, you know,
and until like if you're a look,
if you porn shit into the water supply,
you know,
if you're dealing with stuff like that,
if you fucking vandalizing
the neighborhood I live
in, then go fuck yourself.
All right. But you know the
other bullshit, I looked
the other way, but if the,
if I knew there was fucking aliens,
yeah,
no does look up to fucking stupid.
There's no way they would tell it to me.
If I was in the air force. How far into
the air force you think I would get?
Do you think I'd get anywhere beyond
the guy with the two sticks guide in the
fucking plane and
no.
Okay.
[inaudible]
Hey, what's up? It's a bill.
Um, and this is the Monday
morning podcast. Hey, what's up?
This is build bar, you know, like,
it's going to be somebody else.
On my own, my space page. Would you
guys be disappointed if I did that?
If I suddenly got an assistant,
you know,
the fuck would get an assistant for a
podcast. All right, this is the deal.
This is the Monday morning podcast.
If you're new to my page,
I do one of these every single Monday.
People send me questions,
they send me lists of stuff that
they feel is overrated or underrated.
They correct me when they feel that I
say fucked up shit. And sometimes the,
that causes an argument
between listeners and um, yeah,
so it's going to be a very
subdued bill burr on this podcast.
And you notice my voice is a little bit
lower than it usually is that a lot of
screaming,
yelling this weekend at Caroline's comedy.
And uh,
I'm going to go see ACDC tonight at the
La Forum and then tomorrow morning I
have to get up early because
I'm shooting something.
So I got this weird thing where I'm
going to ACDC but I can't start screaming
and yelling, you know, so I
don't know what I'm going to do.
What am I doing? They stopped playing
the Jack. Am I going to lip sync?
I'll do it like Brittany Spears and I'll
put my fucking finger up to my ear and
act like I'm trying to hit
that note. You know? Um,
I have a fucking crazy week and,
um,
I'm at the age now where I'm going to
start drinking tea with a little bit of
honey in it before every one of my shows
because I don't what happens when I get
tired.
I start yelling from my throat rather
from down below where it's supposed to be
coming from. And I fucking
shred my voice a little bit. So,
um,
I really hope you're not new to my podcast
because that was one of the fucking
most boring minutes of my podcast,
I think in the history of
my podcasts as credible.
Why don't you fucking dropped the energy
through the God damn floor and let us
hear about your medical problems. It
was really fucking awful. But, um,
yeah, so I got a huge week. I'm going to
go see. Yeah, ACDC. And then later on,
you know, I'm shooting some bullshit
this week. And then after that, uh,
I'm going on a vacation,
I'm going on,
I'm going to go see some
hockey games up in Canada.
Friday night I'm going to the Calgary
cannot gang a catholic connect deep
fucking calvary flames came and I think
they're playing the Canucks, right?
Or whereas Edmonton playing the
Canucks, oh, Calgary's playing Florida.
Then I'm seeing,
uh,
Edmonton versus Vancouver and
Edmonton Ed Northlands coliseum.
And then I go over to fucking Vancouver.
And um,
if you're from up there and if
you're from Alberta or the, uh,
British Columbia and you can recommend
some bars for me to hit before or after
the games, let me know. Um, and uh,
if you know some convenient hotels,
that won't rape me because I've yet to
get a fucking hotel. Typical fucking guy.
I got the tickets first and then I'm
dealing with all sorts of food and hotel
shit later, which means basically I'll
get to the airport and I'll be like, oh,
what the fuck am I staying? Oh,
there's a super rate. I'm sorry.
There were all booked up.
What do you mean you were all booked up?
He had the fucking Alberta rough riders
of whatever fucking CFL team that I've
never heard of is in town
playing for the Grey Cup.
I really don't know shit about Canada.
My biggest,
the only thing I don't like about this
trip was I was hoping to drive from
Edmonton over to Vancouver,
but I just,
it would just take forever because
you've got to go through those mountains.
But I wanted to go through them.
I want to see, you know, uh,
what toothless rednecks look like in a
what mountain men looked like in, in uh,
Canada. And then, you know,
when you go to shit like that,
she ended up seeing an animal you never
seen before and the fucking freaks you
out.
You feel like Magellan or some shit.
Like I'm on one time I was driving through
Wyoming and I don't know what these
animals are,
but they look like good sales antelopes
they look like some shit you'd see on
the Serengeti.
And I saw one and I started
freaking freaking out by myself,
screaming, pointing at it as
I was driving by screaming,
what the fuck is that like something or
something was going to like the universe
was going to answer me. I just go,
what the fuck is that? What the fuck?
And I looked over at the guy,
you know,
I was kind of passing and he wasn't
even looking at it. And I'm like, why?
You know, he's not even excited
about do with that fucking thing.
What does that thing?
And then I went over the hill and then
there was a whole herd of them and I was
like, oh, that's why that guy's not
excited. These are like dead pigeons.
He doesn't give a fuck.
You probably annoyed by him.
He's probably stepped in
this shit at some point.
His life maybe even fell
down at the bus stop.
First Day of school sneakers and have
a clean again. He got a bad nickname.
It comes old. Uh, you know,
Allie fucking antelope, shit,
you know,
some sort of alliteration that remont
red fucking went along with whatever kind
of animal that once,
you know,
and then that name just sticks and it
actually affects the level of policy that
you're going to get, you know?
And he always told himself,
I'm getting the fuck out of this state,
man.
I'm getting the fuck out of this state.
How the hell am I going to get laid with
antelope? Shit is a fucking nickname.
You know, it's not going to happen. I
need to go south. I need to go to Greeley,
Colorado. And even if I'm
called fucking antelope shit,
the smell from that slaughterhouse
down there, nobody's going to care.
Nobody that greatly.
And it Kenny Colorado listeners,
this is the Shit I learned on the, on.
I go on the road in Greeley, Colorado,
they have this huge
slaughterhouse up there and uh,
it lingers in the air and some days
when they killed too many fucking,
they slaughter too many. Uh, whatever
the fuck they, I guess steer.
Um,
people actually call up,
they call bad smell days and then they
call up the the slaughterhouse and said,
Hey, can you, can you fucking lay off?
Can you lay off to slaughter a little bit?
And I don't know what they do with
the count. Like one Mississippi,
maybe they choke out of pheasant.
Speaking of stairs,
I was in New York City last week and Oh,
and if you don't know where
to steer is a steer is a,
I believe it's a bowl with no balls
and something else I learned when I was
driving on the road. I'm like, all
right, that's a cow. That's a bowl.
What the fuck is that? Someone's
like a steer. I'm like,
what the fuck has this stare? And
they told me, he said that's a bold,
doesn't know his balls. And
unlike what, why is that?
And I think it had to do
something with hamburgers.
I think that's what it is.
I think that's how they make beef.
They have both fuck cows.
I'm going to be wrong here.
I think the bowls fuck the cows.
And then they used the cows give
birth and it's either a cow or a bull,
but you know, if they want to
make the bowl, the hamburger
meat or steak, you know,
they cut his balls off and he
just stands around like, oh great,
you know, like that fucking unfunny
caveman and those Geico commercials,
those Geico commercials don't even
make sense anymore. He's like, oh,
I get it. You know something, something.
But I get it and he walks away. It's
like, you know what dude? I don't get it.
I don't get it.
I don't get the whole fucking thing.
I don't get how there's some
hot chick giving you attention.
And then she has a Geico key chain
and you, you can't handle that.
I can save if you're a woman,
that would be a deal breaker because you'd
have control over your fucking pussy.
But if you're a guy you don't
have control over your Dick.
So you know what I mean? She could
actually do wearing a fuck cavemen.
I hate fucking cavemen tee shirt, but if
she wasn't wearing a bra, it'd be like,
all right, well, you
know, simple equation.
I'll just bend her over and
I'll hate fucker. So anyway,
so I'm in a New York City,
I'm in New York and all somebody asked me
that day after you say something funny,
what is that clicking noise?
I Dunno if I'm just on a bad phone.
It's probably me laughing. I don't think
it sounds like clicking noises. Um,
anyways, Jesus Christ's they'll
get to the fucking point.
So I'm in New York City and I'm
working Carolines and a buddy of mine,
uh, always goes to the steak
steakhouse, Smith and Lewinsky. Uh,
Willinsky some 49th and third is like,
yeah, there's a guy that works up there.
He's a big fanny stuff. You should come
by and you know, I'm like, fuck yeah,
definitely. I'll go up there. You
know, I love going to steak houses.
That's one of the few places you
can actually feel like a man.
It's like old school,
you know, you fucking,
it's like classy. You're not like
a, it's not like that hacky shit.
You know what I mean? Like, you know,
these punks who sit there and they
watch a couple of rat pack videos,
then they go out and they buy themselves
a suit and they start walking around
thinking that they're recreating the
rat pack when there's just something too
glossy about the way they're doing it.
You know,
I don't know if it's their manicured
eyebrows or wherever the fuck guys are
doing nowadays, but they did.
They can't fucking pull it off.
But when you're going into those,
those steak houses that
had been there for awhile,
they got a lot of waiters
who've been there forever.
So they organically bring that vibe
and you raise up to their level,
you know what I mean? To come to the
table. They have the females order first,
that old school class. Classy Shit. You
know, I dunno. I like it. So anyway,
so like fucking go in there and you guys,
if you've been listening to my podcast,
you know, whenever I get sick,
I, uh, imitate that guy. Um,
a ray Winston from, uh, when stone
or whatever from fucking sexy beast,
my favorite movie ever. You
know, the beginning of the
movie where he's like, Eh,
I'm sweating
roasted bacon boiling.
It's like a sauna. That
bullshit. I fucking loved that
movie as my favorite movie.
So I'm in this fucking steak house and
I look over and I'm looking at this
fucking guy and I can tell he's somebody,
but he's got these big,
I'm a producer glasses on.
I thought it was Mickey worked for half
a fucking second cause I'm real bad at
that shit. And uh, and with like,
you know my girl and a couple other
people and they look over, they go,
that's fucking,
that's your boy there from the
movie that's fucking now wedding.
And I don't know what happened.
A little hung over, sorry.
He goes out to have a cigarette or a
fag is they call an ace fucking standing
out there and he's out there
with fucking teddy bass.
Mr. Black Magic. Fucking what's
his face? He and Mccallum.
Is that his name? I'm so bad with, I'm
watching that movie fucking 900 times.
I stole another God damn names.
He's standing there and the director,
all his shit. And, uh, I was like,
you gotta be fucking kidding
me. So my buddies, like,
we gotta go out there and we got to get
them, we got to get a picture with them.
And I'm like, Nah, man, I'm not
going to bug those guys. I saw him.
That's enough for me. I see him, I'm not
going to bug them. And he's like, dude,
you fucking kidding me. You
fucking kidding me. That's
not like it's, it's fucking,
uh, Ashton Kutcher. Those
are real fucking, you know,
great actors. The guy was in the fucking
depart. It stopped being a Douche.
Let's go.
So I said fuck.
And I went out there and they ended
up being in a hot shit and they were,
I guess there's another sexy
beast coming out. I Dunno.
They will fucking cool as
hell. And uh, I don't know.
I'm going to post the picture on
it at some point up on my website,
but I got to meet like half the cast
from sexy beast and I ate a steak.
You know what I mean?
Fucking doesn't get any better than that.
It's like one of those old Milwaukee
brew commercials and now, right.
There's no other fucking those commercials
when it doesn't get any better than
this or was that Bush, you know, it
doesn't get any better than this.
You know, we're a bunch of
guys. There's no broads around.
We're sitting in the woods. How could
I not get any better than that? Well,
because basically I think we've gotten
enough pussy in our lives and now we just
find females irritating.
That's the only way I could ever make
any sense out of that commercial.
Cause other than that,
you're outside.
You shouldn't in the woods
in this mosquitoes. And uh,
she there with five guys,
you know, one of them you didn't want to
come along, but someone else liked them.
Yeah. Which is probably why
you're drinking. All right,
let's get one with the questions
for this week. The subdued podcasts,
the easy listening podcast here and now
behave. I'm paying for your meal.
All right, question number one, Bill.
If you've died in some fucked up,
but still really funny way if you died
in some relief and some fucked up,
but really funny way.
How long do you think it would be before
your other comedian friends would start
busting your balls either in own
standup act? So just in public,
even though that would be kind of comfy.
How long til that fucking too
soon period was over? Well,
if I'm dead, I don't think that they
would be able to break my balls,
but I know what you mean.
Um,
I would say pretty much
after a day and a half,
someone would make the first joke and
a then it would just be open season
because then the other comics would
try to top what the other comic said.
And, uh, I dunno, outsiders
would view that as insensitive,
but I've always been fascinated how
people don't realize that, you know,
comedians always have a joke no matter
what the tragedy is and they think it's
because comedians are
insensitive assholes. I mean,
there is an element of truth to that,
but I'm making a joke when something
bad happened is also a way,
uh, it's like a defensive mechanism where
you like, oh my God, I'm feeling sad.
I don't want to feel this feeling. And
then you just say something ridiculous.
Everybody laughs. It gets rid of
the tension. You know, it's not,
they don't give a fuck, but, uh, sometimes
they don't. And I got to have made,
if I did die in a really stupid way,
uh,
I would be disappointed if people didn't,
you know,
trashed me till the end of the time
at Jesus Christ.
What?
I'm trying to think of a stupid waste
of die and I don't want to do that for
fucking chinks of myself. All right.
Question number two, pay bill.
I've been wanting to get into
standup since I was 20 years old.
I've been a huge pussy
for the past three years,
so I've just been writing jokes and not
performing them because I'm too scared
to go through with it.
Eventually I'm gonna man up and do it.
But now I have the problem of having
a three year stockpile of jokes.
How do I decide which ones to do for
my five minutes at the stress factory?
Um, I don't know. I would tick, you know,
some shit euro recently cause I figure
you've been writing for three years.
You probably just getting better at it.
And plus if you're doing topical material,
I don't think anybody gives a shit about,
uh,
I dunno what was topical three years ago?
2008 minus 2005. Oh, what's up with John?
Kerry is guy's face.
He's lugging it to fuck a peak.
[inaudible]
this guy knows what I'm talking about.
Asking you back me up now to just fucking
don't put that pressure on yourself.
Just write five minutes to ship that you
think is funny the first time you go on
stage.
I always tell this to people has nothing
to do with how good or bad you do.
It's just all about having the balls to
go up there when they call your name,
worry about what the fuck you're doing.
You know,
after you've done it two, three times,
you know what I mean? Then start to,
you know, cause you know you're
literally, you just jump in the deep end.
He just tried to swim to the side.
You know,
just make it to the end of his set it.
Don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it seriously too and
just always know the worst you bomb,
the better the story is. That's
it. When comedians sit around,
we don't tell stories
about killing me talk.
We sit around talking about the
night we ate our balls in front of a,
I dunno,
a bunch of navy seals that have corporate
party on a battleship or some dumb
shit. I don't fuck it. You'll
be fine. You'll be fine.
Just grabbed the mic and fucking talk
about what you think is funny and if you'd
bombs,
just make fun of yourself and then tell
people to go fuck themselves and say
thank you. Good night.
That's my first set advice.
All right, number three. Hey Bill.
Lately I haven't been flexing a ton of
girth and the flux autometer and my house
keeps going off. I think this is a
vaguely sort of a Dick joke here.
Any tips for keeping my girth
more stealth when I flex it?
Maybe a stealth flex or flex silencer.
Any idea if these products exist?
So do you have any other tips
so that I can flex more quietly?
I'm just trying to flex my girth more
stealth, you know? Yeah, absolutely. Well,
you've got to stop wearing those fucking,
you know,
Joey Ramone genes where people know
exactly how excited you are. You know,
I would go more with some a 50 cent,
what does he rough rider or whatever
the fuck his policies called. Yeah.
It just gets your, get
some different genes. Yes.
Stop back like you were in the strokes,
you know,
fucking loosen up your genes and you
can have a full on fucking woody and no
one's ever going to know.
Definitely do not wear sweat
pants and a or a short shorts.
You know, sitting down also helps,
especially if you're at a desk.
Other than that you and your
girth and run your own. All right.
You see that she knew my podcast.
She liked the wide variety of questions.
Anyways, question number four. Hey Bill,
do you think the media has ever treated
Donovan Donovan McNabb fairly. I mean,
the guys put up great stats over
the years and led his team to,
for NFC championships and won Superbowl.
It every year he gets
bashed for something.
Why does the media go after
the idiots of the league?
Why doesn't immediate go after the idiots
of the league instead of players who
stay out of trouble? Uh, I don't know.
You know what? I honestly don't know.
I didn't know Donovan Mad
got more shit than usual.
I know that fat Jack Ass from the
radio trashed him that one time.
And I know tio gave him shit, but I
always looked at Donovan that he was a,
he's a professional, handle this shit.
Well never throws a temper tantrum and uh,
I dunno, it might have to do with, uh,
Philly fans. You know, they got that,
they got that short fuse. I Dunno,
you know, something. I don't know.
I never looked at Dunham McNabb
like he was treated unfairly and no,
I guess,
uh,
he just had a couple of really high
profile douchebags give him shit and a
really bad way and uh, you
know, he handled it well.
He never really lashed out back.
He just was like, Hey, you know,
that's what they're, so what they're
doing. I'm going to go get some soup.
You know? I don't know. That was the
worst fucking answer have I have,
I have no idea. I don't fucking know. I
have no idea. But thank you for asking.
Thank you for thinking.
I actually could answer that question
intelligently and thank you for exposing
me on how fucking ignorant I am on
the whole Donovan McNabb crisis. Okay.
Question number five.
Hey Bill,
I've been listening to your podcast
for about half, half year now.
Bout it should say a half,
about a half a year. Now.
I don't think you've ever addressed
this. Okay. What does that jerk off? Oh,
this is the question.
What is,
what does that jerk off slash rapid
tapping noise you make just after you met?
Make a salient point or a
particularly funny joke.
For some reason that sound grates on me.
Like somebody raking their
teeth on a blackboard. You know,
I never listened to my podcast.
I think it's just me laughing and I have
a shitty cell phone so maybe it doesn't
pick it up right? I don't have no fucking
idea. What? I'm sorry. A grates on you.
Like somebody's raking their teeth
on a blackboard. Jesus Christ.
Fucking brutal image. All
right, now I'm self conscious.
I won't ever laugh again
during my podcasts. Is that
what you do? Huh? You know,
you walk around miserable and you tried
to suck the joy out other people's lives.
You know,
I think it's time you might want to
sit down in the mirror and you know,
take a little stock in yourself.
All right, question number six.
I don't know what it is. Dude. I have no
idea and I'm not going to look into it,
so I don't know what to tell you.
Um, question number six. Hey belt.
First off,
great job in the podcast.
I think it's cool that you're using this
technology to spread more predictable
mediocrity.
Oh Jesus Christ.
I'm getting trashed. Let me read that
again so you guys can enjoy that pounding.
That was funny. All right. First
off, great job in the podcast.
I think it's cool that you use technology
to spread more predictable mediocrity
than would have been ever
been possible 10 years ago.
Guilty as charged fucking son of a bitch.
Second question second.
Here's the question.
When should I shave my head?
I note that you have dealt with the old
receding hairline by trying your damn
this to look like Billy Corgan.
Jesus Christ.
I'm getting roasted here.
I suffer from the same affliction and
my plan is to sort of keep cutting it
shorter and shorter until
eventually take it to the scalp.
My hairline is about three and a half
inches from my eyebrows now and I'm using
the number four God on the clippers.
Any suggestion?
I think he got the right idea.
You know what,
and I applaud you for man and
up not doing that. Rogaine crap.
You know?
Or having some hair yanked out of the
back of your scalp and stapled on top of
your fucking head,
you know,
man up like fucking telly
Savalas you know, I dunno.
I Dunno. I Dunno what to tell you.
Yeah. As it gets shorter and shorter,
you just keep cutting it down. I don't
know why guys go through all that. I,
you know, I've actually heard
when people get hair plugs,
it can actually still continue to fall
out and I eat now you can't shave your
head because you've got this Frankenstein
scar in the back of your head.
This guy I know who will remain nameless,
he recently got a hair transplant.
I never knew what the fucking
difference between hair plugs and a hair
transplant,
but evidently a hair transplant,
they literally cut a swag one inch long
on the back of your head and take all
that hair out. And that's what they
use to put on top of your head.
And I guess the skin on your
scouts a little bit loose.
So then what they do with, now
that you got that one inch, um,
stretch your skin.
Now the back of your head,
they basically then push the skin
together and then they sew it shut.
And uh,
I don't know about you,
but that sounds pretty fucking terrific
when you can basically shave your head
and about three,
I don't know,
three minutes she'd done silver
and people look at you like,
what the fuck for two minutes.
And then they can't remember you the
other way unless you have a half hour HBO
special that reoccurs every
fucking six months. Um,
okay. Anyways, this is
the rest of it. He says,
I've been listening to you since you
first parents on our own Hay and I got to
see you live in Houston.
Atlanta.
I liked your comedy and I'm pulling for
you to blow up even bigger next time in
your Atlanta. If you still want
to know how to use a shotgun,
I'll teach you what I know.
Apps, the fucking lovely.
See that guy's odd shit. See that guy's
an old school guy and see what he did.
He broke my balls.
Gimme a couple of good jabs to the
face and he slaps me on the back. Hey,
just fucking with you.
I like your comedy.
Let me teach you how to
shoot a gun right there.
I bet that guy eats in a steak house.
All right, question number seven a bell.
I've been listening to your podcasts ever
since you did a show at Embry riddle,
that shitty little aviation school
in Arizona. I like that place.
I liked it. I was fascinated by the level
of intelligence that you guys actually,
literally, you literally
had rocket science to there.
Right? And you guys knew,
understood about fucking arrows,
space science,
technology fucking thing. I don't know
what it was. I was blown away by. Um, God,
I'm a moron. All right. Um,
you've mentioned that you're a big sports
fan and that you have the NHL package
as a fellow hockey fan.
Do you feel the national coverage
that pro hockey gets is fair?
I see highlights on sports center
that lasts about 30 seconds.
They'd rather talk about dumb,
pointless shit like tls comments after
a game and talk about it for 30 minutes.
So show pro bowling or women's college
volleyball and, and give you a pro hockey.
I'm more than a minute of their time.
What, what's the deal with that? Um,
all right, there's a lot of
questions in there. Um, let's see.
Let's get back to these.
Do I feel the national coverage
that pro hockey gets is fair?
Um, yeah, I do.
Because I think hockey is a rogue
sport and I like it like that. I,
I liked that it's not at the same level
of disgusting exposure that hockey,
baseball and basketball are at.
Um,
because I think that those three sports
suffer from them just trying to cross
pollinate and cross promote and just
make people who aren't into sports watch
sports and people who watch sports
and don't give a fuck about the Jonas
brothers watched the Jonas brothers play
at halftime or Brittany Spears or any
of that other shit or those dumb TV shows
they try to promote during the games.
Just trying to have that orgy of
horse shit that they always try to do.
I can't stand that shit. So I liked it.
Nobody likes hockey. I really like it.
And I liked the, um, I like that people
don't get why people fight in hockey.
Um,
I love all of that shit.
I just think it's a great fucking game
and I think it deserves to be up in
Canada and in the north northern part
of this country and people who give the
get it,
watch it and those who don't can ask
their same little faggy questions of,
you know,
I ain't just so you know,
the fighting and the
fighting is so fucking great.
Every other sports there's
such an unbelievable level
of shit talking that you
can get away with. Cause the second
people start throwing punches,
you'll hold teammate jumps in. You know
what I mean? It was like back in the day,
if you had to fight some kid after
school and you knew you were going to get
your ass kicked,
the best move you could make was start
swinging in the hallways because the
teachers were going to run out and break
it up before anything ever happened.
And by then you're down the office
and they say, if you guys fight again,
we're going to fucking expel you.
And now you've got your out.
That's what those other three sports are.
You know what I mean? You have a seat.
The basketball players try to fight.
They throw punches like they're trying
to throw somebody out from the fucking
warning track of three rivers stadium.
They throw like that dead Dave Parker
overhand right. I saw shat through that.
He threw eat, fucking eat through
it. Like I'm in a long time ago,
said Damon Wayans imitating
a big black girl fighting.
And that's the way Shaq threw a punch.
He fucking,
it was pathetic and he missed the guy.
Any fucking missed them.
Um, you know, I love
hockey. If you're a cunt,
you get the shit kicked out of you and
the guy only has to sit down for five
minutes for the simple fact
that he beat up a con. You know,
I don't understand why it's so difficult
to understand. You know, there's boxing.
Boxing is a sport and
that is fighting and um,
hockey, part of the sport is
fighting. That's a part of the sport.
If you don't like it, watch diving
or something else. All right.
I totally got off track there. Um,
why do I do? Um, and also, you know,
something I liked the,
I think ESPN doesn't show it because
they lost their contract with the NHL,
so they're kind of pissed about
it. So they're like, fine,
we're trying to have our little new world
order monopoly on all sports and you
don't want to play ball, so fuck
you. We won't show your highlights.
So instead they show nine hours of poker.
Is there anybody really
watching that anymore?
That shit was literally fascinating
for like the first six months and then,
you know, now I don't
give a shit, you know,
until this stupid nicknames and their
little fucking stupid glasses they call
them snake has, he's out of Arizona and
he weren't fucking, I don't give a shit,
you know, ed moneymaker, whatever the
fuck they call themselves. It's gay.
It's really gates horrifically
out of shape people.
And I don't give a fuck if the river
cards coming. Um, so there you go there.
To answer your question, I
don't know. I don't know. Yeah.
And Hl. We'll never get it's NHL gets the
level of exposure is fucking deserves.
They've tried everything
to get people into it.
They remember that when they had that
little gay little fucking flame coming out
of the back of the puck for people
who couldn't see it, that didn't work.
They tried everything and they should
just accept the fact that they are,
you know,
just
just be able to fuck you are stop trying
to be fucking something for everybody.
You know those other sports. I mean the
NFL is annoying. I don't like on the NFL,
they're trying to fucking deliberately
make me get a dish because it keeps
showing cool games on Thursdays
and they won't show it to me.
And let's say you have a
dish, you know, I don't,
I don't respond to terrorism just like
this country. I do not respond to it.
They'll fuck yourself. Sticking with
cable. Question Eight. Well what is this?
The last question too, by the way,
it's getting kind of long hitter.
What is your opinion on the
Christmas specials? On TV?
My wife is like, let's watch
some Christmas specials. Well,
I guess I'm supposed to do my
girl voice said my wife is like,
let's let some Christmas special.
I can't fucking stand them all.
I want to shoot Santa Rudolph and
Tim Allen in the fucking head,
but I don't, but I don't say that
cause I want to stay married also.
What is your favorite hockey rink?
Hockey memory. I'm a big hockey fan.
Love the podcasts. Um, all right.
What is my opinion of Christmas specials?
Um,
I haven't watched them in 20 years
and I'm watching them Michelle,
cause I'm trying to get into the
spirit and I'm actually enjoying him.
Son of them are better than others.
Um,
I liked the one where Burl Ives sinks
have a Holly jolly Christmas as the
snowman. Um, I like that shit. I
actually decorated my apartment.
I went all out this year, so
I don't, I don't mind them,
but if it depends on how
annoying your wife is every,
if every five seconds she's like,
then yeah, that would, that would
annoy the shit out of me. I know.
I don't know, Dude. I don't know
what to tell you. Just fucking,
you know what he'd do? This
is what you do. He said, yeah,
let's get into the Christmas spirit.
You get some eggnog and you put a bunch
of booze in it and then you'll start
equating the Christmas specials with
boozing and not having to listen to your
wife. And uh, maybe you'll start
looking forward to them. You know,
they'll probably start, you know, watching
the great pumpkin in October. Okay.
Oh wait, there was one other
fucking question I didn't get to.
Somebody sent me a really good question
about the hype on Britney Spears.
Where the fuck can I put that?
What's going on here?
All right.
Let me read some old rate on the under
and I got to find this last question real
quick. All right. Overweight
if number one. Um,
I know if you knew one of
my podcast people send me
their list of shit that they
feel is overrated and their list of shit
that they think is underrated. Alright.
Overrated.
The bcs standings.
Every year people complain and beg for a
playoff system. Not even our president.
Now, even our plight president, Alexis,
we should have a playoff system.
Do you ever think these rich
pricks will allow it to happen? Um,
no and I don't think they should
have a playoff system. Um,
just for the simple fact that you can
blow out your knee and end your career and
they're basically playing for free other
than bullshit money that they get from a
college boosters. Is that
what they call them? No,
I don't think they should play more games.
I liked that everybody gets all
pissed at the end of the fucking year.
There's 9,000 fucking teams. What do
you want? They do the best they can.
It works for me.
I don't care when I liked it.
Someone's always pissed in the end
as a nice level of controversy.
I think they kind of have
a playoff system with bcs.
They just need to expand it to 14.
That's all.
And if anybody complains after that, they,
you know, they can go fuck themselves.
They go, problem solved. Um, actually
I'm going to the Rose Bowl, this shift,
not bragging, but I'm going to write up
the fucking street now to NFL overtime,
uh,
first and thinks this is overrated.
How is it exciting scene teams when
it with the field goal in overtime?
How bad of a reader in my, I'm like,
how is it exciting seeing teens,
what it with a field goal trying
to read this most smoother.
How is it exciting seeing teams when it
with the field golden over time or even
tie like the eagles verse the Bangles.
Uh,
they should take a lesson from college
football and make their overtime just
like there, it would be
a lot more exciting. Um,
um, I don't know. I liked that they're
different. I really don't have a problem.
I don't have a problem with
college football or pro football.
I just have a problem with the fucking
NFL trying to make me buy a dish. But,
um,
I guess it would be more exciting if they
could have half a field and they just
keep going at it. Um, I dunno.
I just think it gets
back to that thing again.
Now you're dealing with
even older football players
and they could get the shit
kicked out of them and blow out
there. Fucking the, I have no idea.
You guys are really asking me a lot of
fucking, not too difficult questions,
but for some reason I can't fucking
answer them this week. I'll wait a second.
Wearing God's name was this question.
This guy sent me,
God dammit. You know what? I
can basically paraphrase it.
This kid was asking me, Oh this
guy, this gentleman who was female,
I can't remember who wrote it,
was basically saying,
what's with all this talk about
Brittany Spears coming back.
People are actually really buying into it.
I don't understand what the big deal is.
People were saying she's crazy.
Just cause you shave your head,
it doesn't mean you fucking crazy.
So I dunno. What do you think?
It's like a big media ploy.
I have no idea.
All I know is that I,
when I think somebody is music sucks, I
don't care about their comeback. You know,
kind of like Madonna. Madonna has a
couple of the tunes. But other than that,
you know, I, I don't understand
what the big deal is just, I mean,
granted you gotta give her
credit every five years.
She comes up with a new way
to fucking dress like a horse.
You got to give her that.
Um,
but I really think it's time
for her to, uh, you know,
put some more clothes on than
I talk about that last week.
What have I happened to? Elegance.
You know what I mean? Blake,
women in their forties and 50s
can, can, can be beautiful,
but not if they dress like they're 18.
Same thing with guys that just comes that
point where you've got to stop wearing
your how Colgan fucking wife beater.
You know, at that point,
you know, you know,
you got your fucking flabby grandmother
arms. It's just not going to work out.
People in their forties and
50s need to wear more clothes.
They need to look classy. That's what
you in your class a year, you're older,
you're wiser. You know what I mean?
You can't fucking sit there. Uh,
it's weird cause Madonna
is in great shape,
but like this is still 50.
You're a shredded 50 year old,
put on some fucking pants. Jesus
Christ. Get a skirt down to your knees.
At least, you know, I, I don't
understand it. And like, uh,
now that I'm on the subject,
the plastic surgery,
I saw an interview the other day with
her, you know, it's just, I don't know.
What did she do to her fucking face?
It was like
you looked normal and I don't get that.
Like you,
you look your age. Okay. You look,
you looked 48 two years ago
and now two years later,
now you look like a,
a 33 year old alien.
I mean, I mean, is that,
what the fuck? I don't know.
That's basically they don't
have it down yet. I don't know.
A few people have noticed,
you know,
with the plastic you want to get a tummy
tuck or get your ankles and large to
whatever the fuck people are doing.
Any of that shit below the neck.
I guess I can kind of understand it.
But if the face they
don't have to face down,
I didn't think they have
the other shit down.
It's just that when I talked to somebody,
I don't stare at their fucking stomach,
you know?
But if they're wearing a half shirt and
that's where that fucking mouth was,
I would be looking at the stomach
going, Oh god, why did they do that?
I don't fucking know. So basically what
I think about the Brittany Spears thing,
I honestly, I don't give a
shit. I don't give a shit.
I don't give a shit about, you know,
people who basically, you know,
you want to run with no underwear on.
Yeah. Now the Paparazzi falls you around.
But even then,
I don't even believe that.
I think you fucking called
them and let them, let them
know, hey, I don't make God,
I'm going down to Starbucks and I
maybe forgot my panties. I like,
I like the fucking Paparazzi
gets this credit, like,
like they have like this Pentagon ability,
you know what I mean?
Like they're tracking her
on her cell phone. Did Not,
there were a bunch of fucking,
I don't know what the fuck they are,
but I'm not buying it. Oh, you
know what isn't as convenient.
Here's a telephone call. And let's just,
when I was going to end the podcast.
All right, well, thanks for listening
and I will talk to you guys next week.
Have a great week.
And,
uh,
so
[inaudible].