Hey, what's going on? Spill burden.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast. And I'll just checking in on,
do you,
how was your week going?
Is that the way you planned it?
Is 28 t turning out to be
the year you wanted it to be?
Um, I'll be getting my,
my transformation of my,
my fucking wardrobe bill.
You new clothes. Uh,
you know something I never
took seriously with socks.
I'd go down to the fucking foot block
and I just grab a pair of, you know,
a package of those things and I
would wear them for like three years.
I don't own any white
socks. They're all gray. Um,
I dunno. It's just something I've never
been into. And then for Christmas,
somebody actually got me some
new socks and they were great,
but they weren't like a, you know,
like dress socks or some shit.
Like,
oh great,
I gotta wait till somebody dies and
gets married before I wear these fucking
things. They were just like, you know,
they weren't athletic socks,
they would just sort of socks.
You could still wear it with sneakers.
They were a little thicker, you know,
I'm an old man. I was like, keys
show real comfy on my feet. So,
uh, that was it. I, I, you know,
and then I had him sitting in my sock
drawer next to all these sad grey socks
that had been loyal for all these years
and all the old socks were looking at me
like, Bill, you, you're not going to
move the company to another country.
Are you a man?
You're not going to break up the union.
Okay.
We been there for you for a long time,
man. I was like, you will get nothing.
I owe the public nothing. Whose quote
was that? I owe the public nothing.
It's one of those robber baron guys back
in the day. And who even knows if they,
if they robbed anybody, maybe they were
just better at business. And most people,
maybe they had it in him to tell some
old lady to hit the bricks you would done
with them.
Let me see something who said,
was it Andrew Carnegie or
Carnegie is a say in Pittsburgh.
Um,
I owe the public
nothing over
j p Morgan. Oh, JP JP, the original heal,
how great would he have been? You know,
I bet if he lived right now, he'd be,
he'd be working for Vince Mcmahon,
crushing it on the mic.
I owe the public nothing
that is so fucking mean,
so wrong and so right.
All at the same time.
I've never quite felt,
I never really felt one way
or another about that one.
At first I was like, what
a fucking Dick. You know?
And then what happens is you start doing
a little well in life and then all of a
sudden some douche bag and your life
starts giving you shit about it and want
you to give them fucking money
just for being there, you know?
And you start going, well, I,
I guess I kind of understand what
JP Morgan was saying. Granted,
you know what I mean?
I didn't fucking create the
Federal Reserve system that
enslaves fucking people,
you know, taken away from this.
I want to get that. I don't know.
I don't want to go down that rabbit hole.
You know?
This is always been my rule as
far as helping people out. Okay.
If you laying in a ditch
and you're reaching up,
I'll reach down and try to pull you out.
All right.
But if you face down in the ditch,
digging a deeper every day. Yeah.
I'm not throwing money in that.
Get your shit together. Okay.
Get a little streak going.
A little street. Go on of doing
the right fucking thing that, uh,
you'll be surprised how much the world,
we'll help you out, I would think.
But what do I know?
I'm a privileged white male.
I remember what I was born and
I was on my dad's yacht by,
and we were talking to the next seven
presidential candidates and, uh,
they were letting me decide who was
going to be present. It's, it's,
if you're not white,
I'm sorry to let you in on this
unbelievable level of privilege,
but that's basically what my
childhood was like. It was incredible.
I remember when I, um, when I turned 14, I
was given my first shot. I remember that,
you know, and I was in a bad mood
because my chauffeur was just,
I dunno if I wanted to get fucking ice
cream and he wouldn't take me there.
And I was very upset. Um, and
I was like, you work for me,
you work for me. And he just
ignored me that day. And I was like,
I'm going to tell daddy and
you're going to be fired.
And a while I didn't realize is was he
was under instructions from my father to
take me down to the, the, uh,
the wharf at than sound like
a good rich word. The, uh,
the doc that President Roosevelt gave
them, my great grandfather. And, uh,
they gave me my first shot and I
was like, oh, I feel so foolish. Um,
but my dad's still fired my
show for just for upsetting me,
even though it was his idea.
What,
we'll revisit my privileged
childhood later on in this podcast,
but let's get back to, well, let's get
back to what went down this fucking week.
Damn God. Damn. Motherfuckers, Alabama,
Crimson,
Tad one yet another fucking championship.
Uh, God dammit. Georgia had a
bad, I'm on the fucking ropes.
And then the second half
came along and what happened?
Georgia goes right out there
and blocks a punt and I don't,
I can somebody tell me how that guy was?
Offsites.
Can somebody tell me why a bigger deal
was not made other than on the mad dog
show?
They blew too brutal fucking calls when
Alabama was making a great comeback.
Okay,
great coaching decision by Nick Saban to
put that freshman kidded a quarterback
and just stick with them.
And I bought the, uh,
the start and not being a cunt about it.
That was all great.
And then they had that running back that
came in and they started using in many
ways in the second half, Alabama. And he
was just killing Georgia. But however,
I don't, I don't use that fucking guy
was not offsites. They blocked the punt.
You looking at at least three
points on that drive. Granted,
people can miss field goals.
God knows Alabama knows about
that come the end of the game.
Then they miss the facemask call and they
call a ticky tack pass interference on
third night.
Um,
those are the games when you're rooting
for you and your team's getting fucked
you, you literally sit there going
like, this is literally, it's just a t,
it's a TV show. He can't have one team
just beat the shit out of the other team.
Everybody's going to turn the channel.
Is that a real,
that football game was like watching an
episode of the Super French back in the
day, right. Every fucking episode was the
exact same with the super friends. Okay.
Something would happen and then all of
a sudden it just looked like, you know,
whatever.
Superman had kryptonite around his neck,
a Batman and Robin would tied together
and not like they think like they cared,
but you know,
time down on the heading towards a
bud saw and all that type of shit.
And then something would happen.
That stupid fucking monkey from the
wonder twins would do something.
And the second they
played that song right.
And then
I remember I would get a sense of relief
every time I was watching that cartoon.
I'm like, Oh fuck, is this the episode
Superman dies? I mean, I was young,
I didn't know any better. And the second
they would start playing that song,
I knew that they will,
they were going to make that come back.
That's what the Alabama fucking band
should have been playing when they,
when Alabama came running out
in the fucking second half.
Oh, maybe when they called
off sides in that block pond,
you got to give it up to Alabama.
Even though I'm kind of being a cunt,
bring in those things up. But Hey, I
mean that did happen. That was bullshit.
The guy didn't even fucking
move. I Dunno. Maybe.
Maybe the referee had a better
angle. I don't know. I don't,
I don't get how you miss a face mask
when it was done to the guy carry in the
football. I mean the whole fucking
stadium is looking at the guy.
His head turns around, Eh, we
didn't say it. We didn't say it.
Um, here's what I want to know.
Who's more hateable bill bell,
a check or a Nick Saban.
And secondly,
why do you hate them? Like everyone
says, Nick Saban is the devil.
Why is he the devil?
Because he's so good at what he does.
You know,
I dunno.
I think the media fucking hates bill
Bellacheck cause he makes that job so
fucking because he knows
that if he opens his mouth,
the media is going to make his job more
difficult by exaggerating anything that
he said given the other team.
Bolton board material. Um,
masterful. The way he handles
the press, he gives them nothing.
He looks at them and he's like,
you people are not my fucking friends.
I am required by the NFL to stand
here and answer your questions,
but I am not required to give you anything
more than two fucking syllables per
question.
All right.
I love it.
I wish more coaches would do that.
More players would do that. You know,
Shaq used to do it. You have a
seat shack like when I, when he,
but he's still in like on TBS or whatever.
T and t, whoever does the fucking NBA,
just total nice guy.
Affable brick area stair.
I say right now.
But when he would do like a,
he's talking joking around
animated and all that.
And then what we used to do those,
those interviews at the end of the game,
he just be like Colbert
getting rid of the ball
to year. He just went into like power. Uh,
you see on any other show,
it seems like a completely different guy.
That's what you learn after you get burned
by those fucking nonathletic fat fuck
concepts that are in the sports media.
You know,
and this is what I can't stand about
them is they choose themselves,
their own self preservation over any
sort of loyalty towards the home team.
You know,
the local Boston sports media sitting
there fanning the flames of that fucking
horse shit about Tom
Brady's personal assistant,
whatever. Not Personal assistant
is fucking personal trainer.
Can you fucking believe they tried that?
That's all they could get.
And then they were like, well whatever
man, we got a spark blow on it.
Yeah.
And what kills me is fucking patriots
fans will continue to listen to those
sports shows at second. I hear that and
go fuck these guys. Well Bell, I mean,
when it had the media and isn't star
eight, we have to address that. Yeah.
Um, do you just have to say
what everybody else is saying?
Is that what you're required to bill?
What happened?
You started off in such a good mood.
Um,
Nick Saban now has, uh, he
has six championships. Never.
He was doing, he has six championships.
He's 66 years old. Six, six, six.
He's the devil. Well then he just turned
into the devil. What was he when it was,
you know,
five championships and he was 65.
What's two to fives?
What does that mean?
You're going to go play
that on a scratch card?
MMM.
I don't think either one
of them and the devil.
I just think they're really good at what
they do. And a, at the end of the day,
the game is 60 minutes long.
You've got to keep coaching and uh,
you know what's funny?
Nowhere? No, no. In the,
all the top four can force sports.
All right.
Nothing hurts you more than playing,
not to lose in football.
I've seen more goddamn games,
more fucking games lost that way.
I feel like Oklahoma lost the
rose bowl because of that.
They stopped going no huddle. You
know, if you want to be a Douche,
she could say maybe Georgia,
you know,
Kinda took the foot off the gas
a little bit there. I Dunno.
Once you start thinking about
how to chew up the clock,
it fucks up everybody's rhythm.
I don't know.
Or maybe I just love when Alabama lose.
It's like my favorite part of that
Gabe was fucking Nick Saban's face at
halftime. I don't want
you to do that. Fucking
what are you going to do that interview,
that stupid fucking interview.
Why they stopped those poor bastards
of the most important game of their God
career and they got to sit there and
talk to fucking Susie sweet shoes.
Is it before they go in there?
Hey,
you know why I fucking
really liked on Alabama?
Was that number 14 guys a fucking maniac.
He was all over the
field breaking up passes.
Anytime there was a sweet pea come
out of nowhere and he was amazing.
And I also think Georgia's
front forward incredible.
Like that interception that kid had.
I mean,
usually the offensive
linemen, uh, I dunno,
they're just not quick enough.
Ricocheted off the how many he found
it in the air and then caught it, um,
in that close to the quarterback.
That usually does not happen. And uh,
yeah,
they amazing front for and George's
quarterback to the freshmen obviously kind
of sucks that they ended up
losing the game. I forget.
I actually will tell you this,
I felt bad for Nick Saban when that
kid missed that field goal. It's funny,
for some reason I didn't feel bad for
the kid. I felt bad for Nick Saban.
I forget what he did. He
just throws fucking arms up.
Like, what do I have to do?
How big a genius do I have
to fucking be to fuck it?
Help you sons of bitches across the God
damn goal lines so we can win this thing
a go, go home. I'm, well,
what more do I have to do?
I would love to interview
coaches and be like,
what goes through your fucking brain?
All right.
Like an offensive coordinator,
whatever you call all the right place,
you play it fucking
high stakes chess,
where you literally,
your house,
your family standard of living is
on the line because if you suck,
you're going to get fired. And then
what then where you're going to go,
you're gonna have to fucking sell your
house. You Ain't know the deal pill.
We know the deal and you
call all the right place.
60 minutes of playing chess on
television where every fucking Dosha,
the world like myself is going to second
guess you who has never even coached
the game at a pop Warner level.
You get all the way down there.
It's a fucking chip shot.
Yeah.
And this soccer style con goes in there
and fucking Mississippi, like just what?
Like how do you sleep
that night? I, I can't,
I can't imagine.
You know what I mean?
Everybody talks about the field goal
kickers when they miss it and what they
have to deal with. You know,
it's, it's very simple. Okay.
Nobody knows what a field goal kicker
looks like. He move out of this state.
You start selling cars, you begin a new
life, egg, noodles and ketchup somewhere.
Right?
Okay.
I can't imagine the coach. So you got
it. Like how do you go to sleep at night?
You know, and you know, your wife
doesn't understand. Carl is just a game.
Come back to bed.
I don't as to what is wrong with you?
You're scaring the children,
Michael Guys.
Just I would,
you know what I would do?
I would just be standing up in my living
room drinking with my headset still on
staring at the fucking wall. Okay. Kids,
we're going to go to bed early tonight.
Your father's had a tough day.
I Dunno. That's what I see when
I, when Nick Saban's losing,
when I look at that guy's fucking
face, it's just like, I would not,
it's just not a guy you'd want.
You would want to piss off. Um,
I love those guys that are going bald
and they still dye their hair and they
still keep it like long. I don't
know. What is Nick Saban doing?
So he's got cotton candy
on top of his head. Um,
anyways, let's plow ahead. By the way,
Nhl fans. Did you happen to catch?
Did you happen to see the
Falcon best game of the year?
At least the ones that I saw.
Do you watch the Bruins first of penguins?
That game. It was like a game from
the 80s, except there was no fights,
which there should have been when the
puck somehow got lost in a shower,
his Jersey and that guy came up and
just sort of looked at him and then push
them down like a kid on the
playground. And I was like, all right,
somebody's got to drop the gloves there.
Even though what he did was totally legal.
That doesn't make a difference.
This is hockey. Can't just have
him push a captain down like that.
Um, then nobody did shit cause that's the
new game because they're trying to get
everybody to fucking watch,
which they're not going to do.
Fighting is basically out of hockey
and all of these fucking, uh,
Olympic ice hockey watching cons
are still not watching. They're not,
they're not going to watch
it. All right. Basketball.
They'll keep watching that fucking
players going into the stance x Deli,
punching a woman,
trying to get to some guy in a track
suit that through a fucking cocacola on
your face. Right? People keep watching.
They don't give a shit. Right.
Players fucking getting busted for shit
and bring it up. Other players names,
nobody gives a fuck. They keep fucking
watch it. And then the exam, you go,
you get to fighting on a hockey
rarely. Oh, tell you what.
Why don't you get the fighting out
of boxing first and then, then I'll,
I'll actually believe that you're
against violence. I'm sorry. Anyways,
okay.
Broads first penguins. This is how
the scoring went. One, nothing Bruins.
Then it was one one, then two,
one pens, then three one peds.
Right now my GAF, fuck. Hey.
Well yeah, we just, we keep,
we can and what? What, what?
What are we doing here? Right. Then in
the fucking second period it became,
it was three to two penguins,
three to three 43 Bruins,
five to three broads.
Okay, so we scored the first goal,
penguins scored the next three.
Then we scored the next four w and this
isn't even the end of the fucking second
period yet.
Okay.
All right.
Eight fucking goals.
This is back when like Gretzky
with scoring a goal, a game.
I felt like I was watching this,
this game on the fucking
USA network was amazing. Um,
okay.
And then right before the period ends,
you know, I was thinking like don't let,
don't give up a goal to give them hope.
Don't fucking do that shit.
And what do they do?
They fucking give up a goddamn goal.
Okay.
And it ends up being five to four
at the end of this second period.
Nine fucking goals, right?
Third period starts at like,
we got to get the next one. We've got
to get the next one. Penguin score,
the fucking next one.
Now it's five to five.
And it was just play off love,
play off, play off level hockey,
the tire rest of the fucking game.
Unbelievable passes. Unbelievable.
I can't believe I'll fucking
fast. Abroads sir. Um,
got all these young kids out there.
It's amazing. And ended the game.
Brad Marshawn comes down on
sort of like a mini break away.
Sky's slashes him on his right hand,
right.
And he goes down and a, the ref calls a
fucking penalty shot when I love does.
Even after he called the penalty shot,
Marshawn was still shaking
his hand to make sure, you
know, they'll wrap. You see,
look at east slash me this
hand, this hand, right. And uh,
I'm like, wow, Sean's going
to score this fucking goal.
He's going to fucking score this goal.
It comes down and gets a BA fucking
head of steam a little this way.
Little that way.
Fucking five hole opens up.
He goes to Tuck it in and that fucking
penguins con just got the top of his pad
on it to block it.
We go into overtime and I'm unbelievable.
Three on three hockey and then
fucking if wasn't market Pissy,
the one who scored. I mean, penguins
are tough and all the time, you know,
they got Crosby on one line pan
mark and another three on three,
all that open ice and Phil Kessel,
former Bro and farmer Brian that we
traded to Toronto because of that trade.
We want a cup, so I don't want
to fucking hear about it. Um,
incredible game unfortunately didn't win.
But uh,
the Bruins are very excited to watch
this year as exciting as the Celtics.
Dare I say, dare I say, um,
I have no advertising today.
Everybody,
people are slowly walking away
from my podcast. Evidentaly
you know what I say? I say
that's their loss. Ah, admitted.
When you guys listen to other fucking
podcast and they just do a straight read,
your fucking, you blow through
it, you blow through it.
These assholes did not understand
what I was doing. I was misunderstood.
Was like that Guy Tucker used to make
those cars except I was the advertising
illiterate version of it.
Right.
You know what's annoying as I tried to
print something out before I started
doing this podcast and my
printer's out of paper.
So that stupid fucking printer
icon keeps jumping up and down.
You know
like when you have a big family and
there's that one kid you don't really like
any kind of senses it. So he tries
to do extra shit to get attention.
That's what it's doing right now.
MMM.
Anyways,
I'm going to be at a COBB's comedy club.
Yeah.
This Saturday night with
Rosebowl tailgate legend.
Okay.
10 Year Vet Joe Part Nick.
10 Years Tommy. So should, I'm sorry,
10 games in a row at the rose bowl.
Do you know we were there
and they introduced it.
We thought we were bad ass with that 10
10 games in a row and they out of this
fucking print or jumping up and down.
I get it.
MMM.
Somebody was at the game and he
was at his 70th rose bowl in a row.
Sky's been going since 1948
okay.
No,
cause I was already thinking like
the, the, the guys that we had seen
like the,
that have then gone,
it'll either gone pro or one like the
Heisman trophy or something like Jess just
in the first like, uh, I
don't know how many years.
That kid on the titans
who went to Stanford, that
white kid who's really fast,
who scored that touchdown
last week, whatever his name
is, McCaffrey Assam Shit.
We saw him.
So Mark Sanchez Sanchez the first year.
Jamison Winston.
What's that?
Mary Yoda Kit Macgyver for whatever his
name is for the titans up too old to
remember the fucking names. And then
we saw that Ted kid on Penn state,
the running back.
Okay.
Shane and whatever his name is,
we saw him last year
and this year we saw Brewster
baker and the six pack,
whatever that fucking name is.
Who's Bruce to bake or how come on old
people who've remember cable when it
first came out back when these
entertainment industry was so amazing.
They let Kenny Rogers started movies.
Do you realize Kenny Rogers
has all kinds of hit records?
He started a fucking movie and uh,
had fast food chicken restaurant.
I don't know if he still has all that,
but they had to have been a point, you
know, at some point he had to look at it.
Whoever was his manager just be like,
dude,
I'm kind of spreading it and I'm spreading
it a little thin out of fucking you
keep putting out hit records
and make sure, you know,
nobody's putting their
hands in the register.
It's your 40 fucking Kenny
Rogers chicken places.
How much do you love Kenny Rogers
that you like? You know what?
I bet he makes good chicken too.
Like how much you believe in him
as an artist and you're like, well,
is an art form too? So, you know,
I mean I love led Zeppelin, but if John
Bottom started making fucking meat pies,
I mean I,
I think I'm going to pass,
I don't remember that being part of his
fantasy during the song remains the same.
Watching him make it some sort of fucking,
you know,
fry up or a fucking fish and chips.
He wasn't,
he was out on the tractors and in a
drag race, so that, that makes sense.
Um, he's such a horribly
misunderstood musician,
such a horribly misunderstood by myself.
Also,
you know, I was talking to somebody the
other day, there's always been like this,
this myth about bond him that he used
to play with these sticks that will only
like tree trunks.
And I remember like trying to get his
sound and I went out and I bought like a
pair of like two bs or something like
that. So if you don't know what those are,
I mean this thing is so big around
that, like, you know, 80 years ago,
legally you probably couldn't beat
your wife with it. I mean, that's,
that's how big this fucking
piece of wood was. Right?
Thinking that you are going
to get that sound. And uh,
there's a couple of fucking
pictures that I've looked up though.
If you really look at,
it looks like he's just using like
almost like a five a or five B,
just a regular size stick.
It's just he just knew any,
if you really look at him play,
he's like,
he never really brings his hands
up and slams down on the drums.
It's kind of wrist and fingers.
He just knew how to fucking hit the drum.
I'll tell you another guy who was amazing.
I was talking to my drum teacher about
this as I watched this clip of a James
Gadson who uh,
played with that,
that Watson hundred third street band,
but you know the ones spray deet
deet deet deet deet deet beep,
beep, beep, beep beep,
whatever that fucking song was.
Bill withers basically
took that rhythm section
and he went out on the road,
made albums with them and there's
a live version of him. Uh,
James Gadson playing and he's playing
like 16th notes and he's doing a little
ghost notes on the snare and whenever
you would go to hit the backbeat,
it didn't even look like he came
like two inches up off the drum.
It's like as ghosts notes with
down in about a half an inch.
And then he would just go
main.
Mathematically that works out cause he's
like four times higher. It should sound,
but how the crack he was getting
off the snare drum is incredible.
Um, anyways, I have no idea what
I'm doing, what I'm trying to do.
I'm just trying to fill up fucking 30
minutes talking about the intricacies of
different fucking drummers
some 40, 50 years ago. Um,
yeah, so that's it. Billy new
wardrobe. All right. And uh,
I got all these fucking clothes
that fit me. Even if I'm a fat fuck,
uh, old Billy booze bag. So
when I'm doing is I am a,
I'm given all of that away and I'm
not taking it over to the fucking, um,
what do you call it? Goodwill.
I don't believe in those guys.
You go over there and people anything
that, that, that they don't want,
they just drop off over there. So they
only have the guilt, you know, it's like,
let's let these people throw
it in the fucking ocean. Right?
Actually have a friend of
mine that actually is, uh,
works for this place,
you know,
people recovering addicts and all of
that type of shit. What I'm saying?
Is this going to be some really
well dressed x junkies out there?
Not to say that have the greatest
taste. I'm just say that, you know,
the homeless people, my neighborhood
it can be looking at. Right. Um,
what do you do with socks?
So even if you wash them,
I can't get my gray socks to people.
You know what I mean? Underwear.
You definitely have to fucking throw out.
And it goes without saying,
even though I just said it. Um, but uh,
I am in very happy with the shape I'm
in right now and I'm going to just,
I'm going to buy clothes that just
fit this fucking shape. That's it.
So if I start getting out of shape,
all of a sudden my sheer,
it'll start creeping up.
My fucking white belly will be hanging
out and I'm just going to have to take it
because I'm not buying bigger clothes.
That's what I'm going to do,
you know?
It's all about not becoming a fat fuck,
And I've finally turned the
corner with my shoulder.
I didn't have to do any Colby Bryant
fucking Peyton manning blood in the
centrifuge and fucking Transylvania.
And I got blessed those two guys for doing
that too because now like you can get
that everybody's getting it done,
you know what I mean? And uh,
you know, pretty soon they'll level and
stem cell research and all that shit.
I'm just waiting like, uh, I'm still
too afraid to get lasik eye surgery.
I'm not going to do the stem cell shit.
What's his face?
Rogan was trying to hook me up with
that and I just, I that's too, I,
I get a little nervous about
that. You know, what does that,
they take a placenta out and they put it
in one of those kitchen aid things and
then then uh,
dropped a little virgin blood in there.
It just seemed a little too
fucking crazy to me. Like,
and then you just get this brand
new shoulder and it's like,
and then that's just it.
There's no price to pay.
I don't have like a slight fucking
tick in my personality. You know,
like those fucking movies
where you get like a hand transplant and
they took it off the cadaver or someone
who was a mass murderer and all of a
sudden the hand wants to keep murdering
people.
You know,
you get your shoulder fixed and all of a
sudden you check your grandmother. Yeah.
Boarding.
You know,
she's bent down in her house coat to
pick up a slipper and you just send her
into the fireplace. You're like,
man, I don't know why it did that.
It's not being good. It's by no
shoulder. Like, you know, whatever.
I'm a fucking idiot. All right,
that's the podcast. Enjoy the music.
And now we're going to give you a
little half hour of, um, some, uh,
classic Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcasts from Thursday
gone by in a year that already happened or
possibly earlier this year.
Congratulations Alabama.
Uh,
you guys are the fucking Yankees.
You're the fucking Celtic Shear,
the Montreal Canadiens via
the Green Bay packers of the,
of, of college football. You can't
debate it. You guys are the best.
All right. Congratulations. You
fucking cunt. All right, that's it.
I'll, I'll to have a great weekend.
You consult to talk to you on Monday.
Yeah.
Resubmit.
What's
going on? It's bill burn. It's the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
January 11th, 2010. You know,
I was going to try to start this
podcast just by saying hello.
But now it's like such like a a uh,
it's a tick. It's like I have to say it,
I got to say, Hey, what's going
on? It can't just be like, hello,
this is bill Burke. You know, I can't
switch it up. That's my catch phrase.
What's going on? Um, you know, I
figured out what this cough is.
Did I tell you about it?
I'm coughing up what tastes like
lighter fluid and it's actually the,
the chemical that they put
on the outside of those,
those Kingsford or
whatever the fuck they are.
Those bricks have been grilling
a lot and every, you know,
when you grill on a Hibachi,
I dunno what it is. Um,
somehow no matter you stand,
it's always blowing in your face.
So, uh, anyway, so let's get
down to business here this week.
I won't be whispering this
week because, uh, you know,
if that was just like a one day
vigil for, for old people, you know,
I flew the flag at half mast and a,
I also was doing that doing the podcast.
By the way,
I was doing it last last week.
I did it Sunday night
at 11 o'clock at night.
So all you fucking morons
who sent me emails going on,
you wrote the book. I mean,
did you see the comedy in that,
that a 41 year old guy was whispering?
Do you got to take everything
at face fucking value?
Like I was going to whisper for the rest
of my podcast yet dumps Fox got like
five emails about that,
you know,
and it's not even like I
don't like these people.
It just reminds me of how fucking stupid
I am. I, you know, as a human being,
if this is what I attract and believe me,
I got a lot of shit this week.
The Jesus freaks came
out and force this week.
Um, I'll be reading those later and uh,
I have some questions for you people.
Okay. So all right. Um,
evidently is come to my attention
that g cast, which is the server,
is that the correct computer word?
Um,
why is it same as 46 degrees out here?
It's not 46 degrees.
Just sat on my fucking Hoodie
was dying out there anyways.
It's kind of my attention that g cast,
the server that I post all my podcasts
on is not going to be accepting any new
podcasters or any new
podcasts as of February 1st.
So what that means is,
I'm sad to say that the Monday
morning podcast is coming to a close.
All right? It's a, you know,
everything has a beginning,
everything has a metal
and everything has an end.
So say be shared should say it'd be done.
All right,
so I'm riding this fucker out till
January 31st and then that is it.
No more and Nada, you guys are
on your own on Mondays. Okay.
Cause I'm not playing this fucking
Internet game anymore. You know,
I already went from fucking my space
over to Facebook and now I got to go to g
CAS to fucking age cast.
Fuck all of them.
All right, you want to hear my
jokes? You come out and you see me,
you put money in my pocket,
then I'll dance for you.
I'm just fucking with you.
I need some help on that.
I just said that cause you know,
you know like someone who's not going
to kill themselves but they just say
they're going to so they can just
find out how much people care. No,
don't you then how we love you.
You have so much to live for.
You have a Monte Carlo,
you have for Laura seats,
you're going to get the air conditioning
sixth and even if you don't,
you still have the tee tops.
Um,
no I'm not gonna I'm not going to quit.
What? Just cause g cast is tapping out.
You don't, and you know why they're
tapping out is because of guys like me.
You know what I mean? It's this whole
fucking free entertainment thing.
I don't charge charge for the podcast.
They don't charge me for uploaded.
Nobody's making any fucking
money. We're just, we're, we're,
we're dancing for free and we're getting
sweaty and our shiny shirts a stick
into our chest and was starting to go,
what the fuck are we doing here?
We want to get paid. So I think that
that's what's going on. Um, I dunno,
I consider the podcast more of a hobby,
but I gotta tell you when I get into
my 50s and eight or nine years here,
believe it or not, Jesus, um, yeah,
there's gonna come a moment where I'm not
going to be wanting to go on the road.
And,
uh,
at that point I'll have to start charging
for the podcast and I really shouldn't
have said in my fifties, because I
might start doing it when I turned 42.
You know, whatever, you guys can't get
mad at me. I'm trying to live the dream.
Would it be awesome if you could just
fucking lay around all day, you know,
Talk Shit into a microphone.
Right. You know? Right.
What the hell the accent come from,
right? You talk shit new microflow right.
Just think about this dream. Okay?
You fucking, you sit around all day,
you talk shit, you rubbing your balls.
So you have the JJ as Oprah says,
don't you hate it? Which fucking older
women talk about their fucking privates.
Yeah. Know it's just, it's fucking
old people shouldn't do that.
You don't have that. She's old, but she's
old enough to know. Just like Madonna,
you know, puts you a clam away.
Okay? You're going to give people,
you being went down on Madonna at this
point. You'd get like food poisoning.
I'm sorry. That was disgusting. You know,
fuck. Speaking of that, and I'll
be in Seattle. Speaking of fish,
I'm going to be just
thought a fisherman's wharf.
I'm going to be up in Seattle this
week. And uh, doing uh, Marty reamers,
uh, funny fest at the
paramount theater. Uh,
all the information is up on [inaudible]
Dot Com B u r r.com. You go there,
you click on the link, you buy tickets
should come out. I talk, I tell my jokes.
She'd go, wow, that was really funny.
And then you go home to your life. And A,
I go back to a hotel and I stare
at the ceiling. Um, all right,
let's stay on course here. Um, yeah,
so I need to know what the next g cast is.
All right.
You guys gradually helped me go
from my space on to Facebook and a,
which I'm doing, which sucks, by the
way. Thanks a lot for the advice.
You know,
Facebook sucks.
All these fucking people can find you
out of nowhere and they start talking to
you. And then I also found out
that I can only add 5,000 people.
I got to start my own page.
There's already a fan page.
Now I've got to figure out how to take
the fucking thing over. Yeah, I dunno.
I Dunno. It's, it's uh, you
know, it's fucking weird.
Then all of a sudden somebody kicked
in the balls and third grade find you.
It's just weird. It's just
a weird, I don't know.
I don't fucking, I dunno. My space
was better. My space is better.
I could just say this is me
and I could start my own page.
I didn't have to fucking say,
oh,
this is just a fan page and pretend
like it's not me, but it really is me.
You know, there was a truth
in my space that I liked.
This is me whoring myself out. How
are you as opposed to now? Gee,
Bill, why don't you explain
it 15 different fucking ways.
We've been on Facebook for three years.
You'd think we don't know what it is. Um,
so anyways, if you guys know what the
new, uh, the new g cast is going to be,
if you could help me out. Um, I'm
also going to call up other comedians,
um, such as Mark Marin.
All right. Mark Marin,
who does,
uh,
the WTF as in what the fuck
podcast every week. And uh,
I actually was on his show last
week and had an, I had a great time,
just had a great time. And uh, these
podcasts are fucking unbelievable.
I'm really like a,
a,
a huge fan of these and how like a bunch
of comedians are doing them now and
then you get like different Comedians,
uh,
can go on together and shoot the shit.
I think it's a,
it's tremendous.
I wish they had these back in the day
when I was coming up and I was listening
to my favorite Comedians,
you know,
I would love to hear them shoot the
shit with each other, but you know,
they didn't have computers
back then. We'll, they did.
They had those ones that were the size
of a fucking elementary school, you know,
and they had those big reel to reel tapes.
Remember that?
I used to love how like on
like the $6 million man,
they just had all those fake
computers in the background.
It was just like Christmas tree lights
that were just blinking on and off.
Then there was always
like, like the big, yeah,
the big reel to reel three
quarter inch tape. Um, anyways,
so I'm going to be on that as
of today. Um, I got to find,
God dammit, I got to look that
up. I think it's, what the fuck.
I hope Maryn doesn't listen to this cause
I told him I was going to hype it and
then I did. And let me
look it up. What WTF?
Pod cast typing with my middle finger.
There we go.
Mark Marin podcasts yet WTF
pod dot L I B s y n.com.
Go on that and you'll listen
to me talking to, you know,
I actually covered some of the material,
not material,
just sort of riffing from last week.
I did tell them the story of
the old man yelling at me and a,
for those of you who are going to be like,
cool you already,
you already said you repeat.
You repeated a couple things dude.
So you said you're kind of like you
do when something happens to you,
when you retell the story
becomes a story and you tell it.
Listen to that here, that lighter fluid.
Hey, sound like fucking Lucille Ball.
Do you remember how,
how fucking old I was talking with
the fuck was I talking to this about?
About how quickly people got old
back in the day. Like celebrities,
like Lucille ball is
unbelief. She looks, you know,
she looks gorgeous on I love
Lucy. You know, I love Lucy, um,
faces all smooth or whatever.
And then, I don't know,
her next show is in color that show with
Mr. Mooney and she just comes out and
he say,
they said here that that fucking
camel unfiltered cigarette.
I think that's cause yeah,
back then they smoke kind of
unfiltered cigarettes and um,
okay.
Being Tan was really big for a
celebrity and she was a redhead.
I don't fucking know. I don't know
what happens. So anyways, that, that,
that is where I'm at.
I need some help here as
far as where I'm going to,
where I'm going to post these,
uh, these latest podcasts and a,
and that's it. Now we're into the podcast.
I just bullshitted for 10 minutes.
All right.
Um,
last week I talked about the old guy
downstairs and how I was having a problem
with him and I got to tell you,
I was really surprised at the
feedback that I got from that. Um,
some of your suggestions,
I know a lot of you were joking,
but nobody really gave me any good advice
that I really saw other than, you know,
he's all just fucking let him
be and whatever people go, dude,
you know what I would do?
I fucking turned my TV up as loud as they
fucking cloud Jode I'd put this chair,
I buy a fucking Tuba, right?
I buy a toolbar at high,
the fucking porch in
the second he came out,
I just fucking blow into it and the guy
would think that he shared his pants.
Right.
You just keep fucking doing it till he
really does start shitting his pants.
What idiots. I love that whole, you know,
I would be loud as humanly possible.
What?
So I can actually piss off the same
neighbors in my complex who are actually
paying a decent amount of rent.
When they start complaining,
then I'm in fucking trouble. Okay.
I'll let fucking, uh, you know,
this one guy was just like,
you know, I think, Oh God,
I got to find this fucking email.
This guy tried to suggest that because
the guy downstairs use the term hip that
he was actually a racist
because,
and he used the definition of hip from
way back in the day and zoot suits and I
didn't even know what the
fuck he was talking about.
I was just like your projecting
this on him. It's like, okay,
so you can project what you
want to project on them.
Okay.
I don't know why am I taking this shit
seriously? Alright, let's move on here.
You guys were here, so he has a couple
of youtube videos you want to check out.
This one is, this one is
actually not a youtube video. Um,
this is just a great one about this
kid who had a party down in that got
completely out of control and now his
parents are being sued for 20 grand.
He sorta the Australian Jeff Spicoli
and they put him on the news and the,
uh,
the news lady keeps trying to get him to
apologize and he doesn't really give a
shit. It's fucking great.
Um, and this is what it is.
Get you a little pens and pencils
out. All right, grab your post.
Its it's on [inaudible] dot com and uh,
the name of the video is funny kid isn't
sorry about huge party break.com p r e
a k.com and um,
I don't know,
I really want to tell you what happens
but then I'll ruin it and it's um,
actually you know,
something that made me feel better
about America when I saw that because it
looked that looked like an American
story and the newscaster look, you know,
it's just nice to see that those stories
about nothing that don't even matter
exist in other countries and if you,
if you are in another country and uh,
you have some shit like that because
people always trash in America about how
fat and fucking stupid we are and I'll,
you know, we're just being fed bullshit.
This is a classic,
classic kind of store that you see on
the news here in the states as they call
them. So it's just great to see that
down under, you know, by the way,
speaking of Australia, what is the
deal? What's the deal with that?
Foster's lager with that
depth charge size beer.
Can I,
that's why I've never drank one.
I never understood like the
40 ounce either. It's like,
let me hold this in my hand until
it gets pissed warm, you know,
why wouldn't you just,
or you get those big Oktoberfest beer
steins and they pour like 19 beers in
there. It's like, why
don't you just have a beer,
finish it and then move
on to the next one.
It can be nice and cold and you see that
little frosty smoke coming out the top.
Oh my God, I'm getting
fucking thirsty by the way.
I'm 10 days into my sobriety and um,
I got to say, I, uh, I miss it.
I really miss it and I don't crave it.
I like it.
Did I already talk about this last week?
I can't even fucking remember. And uh,
if I told you guys what I did this week,
I went to that guitar center drum off
friend of mine hooked me up with some
tickets and I saw these fucking
unbelievably talented drummers.
I got to be backstage and it was just
like every fucking famous drummer you
could. Kenny Aronoff, Tommy Lee,
Allen White, uh, Taylor Hawkins.
Who the fuck else was
there? Uh, Danny Carry,
Chad Smith was fucking everybody.
Jason Bonham. Everybody was,
it was fucking unreal.
I wanted to get pictures with all of them,
but I didn't know it was just like, cause
I could tell they were all fucking day,
you know, cause they're all
on the road all the time.
They never get to see each other.
Now they're all just hanging in there
talking drums. And I want to be like,
you know, like that fat guy in animal
house. Like, hey you guys playing cards.
I didn't want to do it. So I just,
you know, I was just like, all right,
just remember everything that's here
and this is what sucks is I was on the
wagon and I could have
done a shot a Jaeger with
somebody's fucking super famous
and I fucking turned it down just
because I was on the fucking wag. It's,
I don't know if that means I'm
smart or I'm fucking stupid.
But at the bottom line it was, it was
Jaeger, which I've never understood.
It's like, it's like motor oil and
syrup and you know, something that,
that does become an age where you
don't drink. He Yeager anymore. Dude,
you want to do a or bump? No, I don't.
I'll drink some fucking fix some vodka,
maybe a little scotch.
And I'll pretend like I'm a fucking man,
you know,
and I'm shaving designs into
my chest hair. Um, all right.
So anyways, uh, yeah, I got to admit,
I fucking miss it and there's No God damn
way I'm going to make it until March.
I know I'm not, but I'm
just taking it a, you know,
yeah.
I'm not an alcoholic.
I just really enjoy it. You
know, this is this, like for me,
quitting alcohol forever is
the same as just being like a,
yeah.
Just saying like, I'm never going to
have ice cream again. It's like, why?
Why wouldn't you, why ice
cream is awesome. You know,
you don't have it every day and you've,
so you've become a fat fuck.
I'm not saying to do that, but to never
have it again. You know, to never have a,
you know, a beer or a glass of wine,
you know, I don't, I don't know.
There's no fucking way I'm making it.
This is really making me thirsty.
And you know what else sucks is I
got all these great beer glasses,
like those glasses they have
on the commercials, you know,
even got those Sam Adam
once for Christmas and uh,
I've just been filling them
up with water drinking.
It's fucking religious
dude.
I don't know if this cop's going
to go away. Um, so anyways, uh,
oh yeah, somebody wrote me
who was at the rose bowl,
evidently cheap trick was playing there
and she was giving me shit for drinking,
which she should have. And
she goes, I feel bad for you.
And one of the reasons
why she goes is you,
you missed the greatest band in the
world. Cheap trick. And uh, you know,
come on, really at this point, cheap
trick is still the greatest band ever.
Do you really want to see people
who are pushing 60 singing?
I want you to want me.
That really goes back to Oprah.
Say and for JJ or Madonna walking around
with one of her pussy lips hanging out.
It's like,
you know,
at some point you got to put your genitals
away and just realize it's over. Okay.
Okay.
I don't know, but what are you supposed
to do? You've got to make money.
You got to sing the
hits, right? That's okay.
What is lady Gaga I going to sing about?
And she really going to walk around with
no fucking pants that I just bring up.
Lady Gaga. Look at me. Look at me
bringing up the new shit music.
Is it me or is this like the worst music
of all time with that auto tune? Um,
I don't even give a shit
about that tea pots of topic.
I'm just a fucking scrolling around
here. Okay. Another youtube thing.
I actually, somebody sent me this
great link that I, of course I lost.
There's been a couple of people who,
um,
have been taking clips from my
podcast and adding pictures to them.
Um, I guess if you just search my name,
somebody did one where I was talking to,
somebody asked me the question,
if you are in a gymnasium
full of eight year olds,
how many of them do you think you could
kill before they overpowered you? And, uh,
somebody put pictures to
the answer to my story.
And I actually really enjoyed it because,
uh, I kind of forgot that question.
You know,
it's been long enough where I actually
got to listen to it like it was somebody
else and they did a great job with it.
So whoever did that or is doing those,
I really appreciate that
because they're fucking funny.
They're really cool looking and maybe
I'll sell a couple extra tickets at the
uncle fucky shit, check whoever
the hell on performing. Um,
so thank you for wherever the hell is
doing those. Um, all right. That's it.
Yeah. Okay. Next topic.
This is really fucking,
it's just really just I need to
booze again tonight, you know,
to make it flow more.
Um,
somebody asked me this
question or actually told me
a story of a friend of his,
this is sort of a reoccurring story that
I've heard over the years. Okay. Uh,
do it.
A friend of mine was hanging out and
this famous athlete was there and,
uh, they had a couple of
drinks and next thing you know,
it's like the guys kind of hitting on
them, you know, what the fuck, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
So this guy was telling this story about
this professional athlete, I guess, who,
uh,
allegedly was hitting on a friend of his.
And in the end he's like, dude, you know,
I don't, I don't really, uh, you know,
it doesn't bother me anyways, but
he said, so what do you think,
what do you think about gay
people in Pro Sports? I mean,
the amount of people who play
in the various pro sports,
that has to be more than a couple.
Um, what do you think about it?
Um,
I think it's fucking hilarious and I
hope somebody comes out at some point
because it, and I hope it's a
football player because it's such a,
you know, they're always fucking thumping
their chest and shit and screaming.
And it would just be funny,
especially if it was somebody really
dominant. You know what I mean?
Like just some psycho middle linebacker.
He's just fucking drill at night.
That's a bad word.
Who's just fucking stick and everything
about it is gay drilling, sticking,
you know, football is a really gay
sport when you look it, you know,
this is really hacky material,
but you know, you know,
I've made whatever it was the quarterback
and then the center's got a bend over
in front of them.
And then the whole fucking thing,
just the uncomfortableness
alone in the locker room.
And then what's even better is,
you know,
those people who show up at sports bars
and they have the name of their favorite
player on the back,
which I always thought was
hilarious because it's always
this sort of an element
of like, it always reminded
me of, uh, of high school.
Like when the cheerleader would be
dating the quarterback heat, she'd,
where is Letterman jacket?
Jesus Christ built.
What'd you go to high school in
the fifties you know what I mean?
She'd fucking wear his jacket.
So I always thought it was a,
I was always some buddies yesterday in
the sports bar and they were talking
about that,
that the only Jersey you can wear as like
the Jersey of a guy who was like, uh,
who was the shit when you were a kid?
Cause then then it was okay to wear like
a Roger Staubach Jersey or something.
But when you're an adult and
you're wearing the Jersey
of a guy who's like just,
it's, it's Kinda Gay, the whole
fucking thing is kinda gay.
So what did it make sense? You know,
they're always patting each other on the,
I think it would be fucking hilarious.
But the problem is,
is I don't think a lot of other people
would that that's like one of those
certain times.
There's certain stories that come out
and I just kind of stay off the Internet
for like four days because I just
don't want to see the fucking,
the hate and all the, the shit that,
you know, it would start with that.
And then it would eventually go over to
TV and then they would get caught up in
the air, quote, hysteria. Um,
and then the Bible people would come out
and they would start talking about the
Lord says that it's a man should never
lay with another man and all that fucking
shit.
And then they would say role models that
the classic hysteria over absolutely
nothing that like literally 8% of the
population would be freaking out about.
And the other 92% would
either be watching and just,
or just completely not
even give a shit. So, uh,
I don't know if that's what I feel. I
don't think, I don't think it's, look,
if you can fucking catch the ball and make
my table and, uh, I don't give a fuck.
I'll take a whole team of fags
to not have what happened to my team
yesterday against the fucking ravens.
I don't give a shit.
They can all skip onto the field.
I could give a fuck just
when the Goddamn game. Wow.
Hats off
to the fucking ravens. That fucking
a, that was total domination.
And I gotta tell you,
I'm really disappointed in patriots fans
with the amount of fans that fucking
left. But I got to tell
you, I'm not surprised.
I'm really not surprised because that
is a through line through all of fucking
sports. The amount of people
who show up when you're winning,
everybody shows up when the
fucking winning, you know,
and then all of a sudden you
go through rough waters. Right.
And then where does everybody
go? They all fucking leave. Oh,
I'm the watch new shit and everybody
fucking storms out at that. That was,
that was embarrassing.
He stayed at the end.
I stayed at the end of the sports bar
taking shit from people. I'll do it.
Speaking of which, how much of this
sports bar and this fucking ravens fan?
It was almost like performance art.
Like you know what,
like when you go to a sports bar,
the one thing that sucks is going to be
the people who are rooting for the other
team. You know, people are going to
break balls like as a patriots fan.
Do you know, you go in there,
if you're going to wear any
sorta patriots, you know,
tee shirt or a hat, you know,
somebody's going to be like,
ah, you fucking cheaters.
Or uh, you know, fuck the
Patriots. And you know what I,
whenever the fuck they
gonna say, um, you know,
break Tom Brady's other knee,
the usual bullshit.
But then there's always those people who
take it like too far and it starts to
get to the point of, uh, you know,
there's going to be a fight. All right,
this guy,
I've never seen anything like this guy.
When the Ravens, the Ravens scored
a touchdown on their first play,
literally handed the ball off and ray
rice just runs right up the gut and then
breaks it to the left and just goes right.
Okay. And as they're doing it right.
This guy who everyone was saying look
like it was like Kevin James Sort of build
with the head of Shrek and I'm not even
joking and he just starts going like as
the guys, when he scored the
touchdown, this guy did like this.
I can't even just, I can't, I wish
I was doing a video podcast and no,
I'm not going to start doing
those. Um, he just started going,
he started doing like if just magic,
if you exaggerated like walking,
like if he just were bringing your
knees up really high and you will like
bringing your fucking arms up,
almost like you power walking but you're
doing it in slow motion and he just was
going,
ah,
like as long as you could do
it until you out of breath.
And then the funniest thing ever
was winning at the end of it.
He yelled out super bowl,
I almost fucking fell down into my
breakfast burrito when he yelled out super
bowl.
It's fucking a wildcard game.
You just went up seven and nothing on
the first play. And this guy, he's,
he's calling Superbowl already.
And Dude, I'm telling you.
And this was the thing when he was
doing okay and immediately I'm like,
all right, he is going to be
this loud, the whole game.
I am going into the other room.
So this is where it gets bad.
Now I'm in the other room. You want to be
that fucking loud, be that fucking loud.
But now when he starts doing is
anytime the ravens make a great play,
he comes in.
Oh,
I notice you don't like when Kevin Garnett
fucking dunks the ball and you just
see him screaming.
That's what he was doing.
Anytime the ravens were doing anything,
he was doing that. Like he was doing it.
So what we started, because he was
fat, we started yelling out appetizers.
He'd be like, La Ravens,
we like potato skins,
fucking buffalo wings.
Right?
And it just,
and it started off funny and then by the
end it just started getting really ugly
and it almost was like escalating into a,
I don't know, I'll do it. He just,
it was just one of those
classic situations where, um,
you know what I kept thinking of, I just
was wishing Joe pass, she was there,
you know when casino,
where he stabs the person in the neck
with the pen and then they're down in the
ground like Ooh, he goes, he goes,
hey, is that a little girl? Hey,
you hit a little here, a little girl
crying down there like the lily.
That's what I wanted
to do by the end of it.
And um,
I don't know man.
I like that.
That's why I don't like going
to sports bars cause I look at,
I love talking Shit and you know,
you show up and your team gets your ass,
gets their ass kick you,
you got to take the shit.
But like it gets to a certain point where
now you're like yelling at me or in my
direction,
like I'm going to be intimidated by you
and now you making me feel like I'm some
sort of bitch and now I got to yell
shit back at you. And it just like,
I kind of left it with like a headache.
It like it wasn't
[inaudible].
I even hate like there's a,
there's a particular person down at
that bar who's a patriots fan who's,
it's just a fucking
asshole. Um, I was just of,
you guys have any stories like that.
Like he'd go to the sports bar.
The guy who like takes it too far.
Have you ever seen it actually
escalate into a fight?
Because I always want to see those guys
get punched in the face and I'm not
going to do it because a,
I don't want to get my ass kicked and be,
I don't want to, you know,
you know, you know the option
a, you get your ass kicked.
Well, just pictures of me on the ground.
You know when you get your ass kicked,
how you,
how messed up your hair gets
you breathing really hard and
you're trying not to cry. Ah,
it just always feels like the
playground is mine was up.
Just be like grass in your hair.
Remember that Shit when you got
your ass kicked in the playground,
how just alive you word afterwards,
we could just fucking feel everything
in your ears were always hot. You know,
it's just fucking weird.
Anyways. Um, the fuck am
I talking about? Oh yeah.
That's just sort of the option
now in public where it's like,
if, uh, that's, that's the situation
now when you get into a fight,
either you fight and you lose or
you win and you get sued. Dude,
I'm really sorry about
my throat this week.
I don't what the fuck's going on here?
Like,
did you guys see Ya then I talk about,
I am so fucking out of Jersey shore.
Was that last two weeks ago,
this past week.
This fucking guy starts talking
to one of the castmates all right.
And he had at a bar and he's
trying to cause a fight.
He's just begging for a fight and
the kid keeps telling, you know,
I don't want to talk to
you. Leave, leave, go away.
And if finally escalates into a fight and
the kids from the Jersey shore fucking
kid gets onto a couple
of knees, some, you know,
the classic bar fight and ends up on the
ground and the other guys get nuggies
to the back of the head,
right? He goes, I went, no,
he's ours at an east coast thing.
Those are those short little quick
punches that are just pretty much knuckle
based. It's like, oh the Bruce Lee
one inch punch without the power.
He's just sort of wrapping on
your head like it's a door. Um,
and now I evidently that kid's
getting sued. It's like for what?
Cause he won the fight. The other
kid wanted to fight. I Dunno.
I think it's fucking stupid.
And then of course his girlfriend was
really the one provoking it because the
guy was ignoring him and the girlfriend
kept talking shit. Of course she does.
Of course she talks shit
because she doesn't have to
fight him. It was hilarious.
So then when they go to square off,
the other guy's girlfriend actually
starts walking up to the Jersey shore kit
and it's just trying to, just
standing there scratching at his face.
And what's funny,
she's doing it with one hand and there
are other hand is just hanging down at
her side. She doesn't have it up
blocking that side of her head.
She doesn't need to cause he, she knows
she's not, he's not gonna hit her.
So the other girl causes the fight,
escalates into a fight and then the
other girl gets to walk up and just sorta
take swipes at this kid's face.
Then the two guys fight the fight ends,
the Jersey shore kid gets up
and then the girl, the other,
the fucking Jersey shore girls
going, oh my God, Oh my God,
the kids go and get the fuck away
from me. You caused that. And um,
at one point I got a backup here. At
one point during the fight he was going,
he's gone, honey. Stop it. Stop. Just
stop talking to the guy. And she wouldn't.
So he, he pushed her
not hard, just pushing.
Know you kind of go over a step
and a half and I swear to God,
she goes back to the house and who ends
up feeling like the, like the victim.
She does. And she starts crying and I
was sitting at Santa, my girlfriend,
you watch, you watch,
she caused this fight.
This guy just rolled around on the ground,
this guy and for all you know, he did.
The guy's like a black belt in Jujitsu
and he's going to fucking rip his ear off
or stab them or God knows what he's
rolling around on this, you know,
he actually gets punched in the fucking
face and now I sweat in the girls crying
about it. The girl who caused it is
crying and I said to my girl, I said,
you watch, he's going to
end up apologizing. And of
course he does. And she said,
they're going, you traumatize
me. Would you pushed me a
fucking, I just, you know,
I don't understand it.
I guess I'll give the guy a pass because
he's young. I was just, you know,
I was just waiting to, I traumatize you
really. You just caused the fucking fight.
And not only that, as I'm fighting the
guy, the other girls check is coming in.
Fucking hit me in the
head and you did nothing.
You know what? I lost interest in that
story halfway through it. Um, all right,
let's, let's plow through here. What the
fuck can we wrap this podcast up with?
This is actually a really short one.
Um,
and I always say I'm going to wrap this
up and then I never fucking do. Um,
all right,
why don't we end with this segment?
I'm sure I can do another 10 minutes on
this to give you at least 45 minutes for
the week. Let's end with
this. This segment. Oh Jesus.
Which is really taking
on a life of its own.
I thought it was going to die,
but it is somehow risen.
Um, okay. Here we go. And get ready for
bill is the dumbest person on the planet.
All right.
Feel for what it's worth.
I think you're fucking crazy and
irresponsible explanation. Point.
I can never say that. X, x skull
exclaim exclamation. There we go.
Exclamation point.
I just wanna let you know that there was
words that you kinda know how to say,
but you just sort of fly through them.
[inaudible] um,
what kind of person talks about God
like that? And I love this shit.
This is what they all do. You should.
And I believe deep down inside, you are,
be ashamed of yourself.
Dude.
This is what I love about these fucking
maniacs is they're so wrapped up into
what they believe that they listen to,
how much this person just keeps fucking
including other invisible people,
and then superimposing what he believes
in to what you know. He thinks.
I truly believe,
because he's so wrapped up in his own
fucking world that he can't possibly even
fathom that somebody has a difference
of opinion on this subject. So he goes,
uh, you should, and I believe deep down
inside you are, be ashamed of yourself.
Dude.
Are Your Mom and dad still alive?
What exactly does that
have to do with any,
your shtick with respect to God
is hurtful, offensive, offensive,
and despicable. Um, three things.
It always has to be three things.
It can't be hurtful and despicable
or offensive and hurtful.
It has to be hurtful,
offensive, and despicable.
Just like comedy has to come in threes.
Um,
how difficult it must be to spew
hatred and vulgarities for shock value.
Laughs, no talent in that, my friend.
That's the classic place that
people go. Um, whenever you,
whenever you,
this is the classic guy where everything
is funny until it comes around to the
subject that they take seriously
100% and no one can even joke it,
joke about it or even
question it on any level.
And then they always say that you're
just doing it for shock because they find
it shocking. It's like really my views
on women, women haven't been, you know,
that didn't offend you. All the shit that
I've said over the two fucking years,
none of that is offended you and now
all of a sudden this does anyway,
so he goes,
enjoy your success,
air quotes and all the money you are
making on the backs of hard working decent
people that understand what it means to
follow the rules and be the best they
can be without putting
other people and god down.
The rest of us are watching
and we are not laughing.
Dude, how many people are
in your bedroom as your,
do you ever group podcast listening
party every week? All right,
let's get back to that.
Oh,
evidently I am making money on the
backs of hard working decent people.
So let me get this straight
because I'm standing on a stage.
Evidently what I'm doing is not hard work.
And if people are sitting in the audience
automatically, they're all decent,
hardworking people.
And not only that,
I'm making money on the backs of them,
really do I have some sort
of comedy sweatshop like
comedy factory was sweatshop
Labor. What I do is actually
takes advantage of no one.
I stand on a stage and I,
I tell jokes and if you like what I say
you, you sit and listen and if you don't,
you'll walk out right
where, where you know,
and I love how just because
you were in the crowd,
that means you're a decent human being.
Do you know them?
The amount of fucking freaks
and scumbags that come up to me,
this is what I found at a comedy show
for the most part, decent people.
They leave after the show that I didn't
want to bug them and then they walk out
and then mania x come
up to me. You know, let,
let's do some Jaeger and they fucking
spitting in your face and shit. You know,
believe me. All right. But I know I
made fun of God. So now, uh, you know,
now all of a sudden I'm now all of this.
You want to talk about people making,
making money off of decent,
hardworking people.
Take a look at fucking organized religion.
All right, those guys don't make,
those guys are live in pretty good.
Scaring the fucking shit out of you.
Every God damn week.
All right.
And I'm entitled to an opinion and I
never was cramming my opinion down your
throat.
I wasn't okay.
You believe in what you believe
in and I 100% respect that,
but I have the right to question it.
You know,
and you shouldn't find it
shocking that I questioned it.
You should do and shouldn't you just
be what Jesus would do when Jesus just
start praying for me. Anyways, let's,
let's continue this just in case you're
interested. I was raised Catholic,
married and raised my children Catholic
and definitely have my doubts about the
whole organized religion thing.
Great. So you agree with me?
Not even sure that I believe in God. Once
again, there's another point that we,
that we agree on.
I lost my father three years ago and never
would have uttered these words in his
presence.
Neither would I.
What am I voice go up
so they know what dude,
I did it on a podcast. All right,
I'm sorry your father passed away,
but you know that has
nothing to do with me.
Do you understand what you're doing here?
Now all of a sudden you're making it
seem like I'm walking in with my Mr
microphone into the intensive care
saying there's no god, you know,
whispering into somebody's ear in a coma.
He just go into the ground.
We're all like, dear, I'm not doing that.
I'm doing a podcast and I'm
fucking around. All right.
If you want to take it seriously,
that's your problem. Okay.
And if you want to bring up your father
passing away as some way to try to guilt
me in to feeling like, I mean, you know
what I'm saying? In a hateful, hurtful,
fucking way, dude, those are all your
issues. They have nothing to do with me.
All right.
Then he goes on to say that
his dad believed that there
was something out there
responsible for all the
beauty in the world,
in our world and for our lives as human
beings. I don't even disagree with that.
I just know human beings have no idea
what it is until they fucking die,
so I'm not going to sit there and listen
to another human being who tries to
scare the shit out of me and who was
living in a fucking palace telling me that
if I become rich,
I'm not going to heaven.
I'm not out in my mind to think
that that reeks of a fucking scam.
The same way late at night when they
have those fucking gold coins that
evidently are with 50 bucks and they're
selling them for 1999 that that doesn't
reek of a scam. Somebody actually
sent me a a, an email. Of course,
I didn't save it.
Evidently it's sprayed with like a dollar,
something worth the gold. Okay,
so they're making, what is that?
A 2000% profit?
All right.
Believe it or not,
just because you're walking around talking
about religion and the afterlife and
and doing unto others,
and you're talking this great game,
it doesn't mean that you
can't be full of shit.
All right?
Okay. And I'm not saying that I'm right
about what I feel, but this is just it.
It reeks of, of, of, of a scam.
I really believe that there is some sort
of thing out there and I wouldn't be
surprised if there is
something after this.
I wouldn't be surprised if you just go
into the ground and you decay and you
give life to the next fucking thing.
I wouldn't be surprised if earth is
punishment for something that I did in,
in a different solar system.
That's another thing about religion and
forget about the dinosaurs is it doesn't
even bring up space.
Okay?
Let's say the rest is all
powerful big being. Okay. Okay.
And I'm just trying to
question this right now.
So I'm not trying to be shocking or I'm
just questioning is let's say there is
this all powerful being being that
created the everything that there is.
Okay.
The entire solar system.
Why would you do all of that and just put
people on this one planet that's like,
you created an, an uh, uh,
you built this house that has
an infinity basically amount of rooms,
bedrooms, and you just put everybody,
you're only using one room in the house.
It doesn't make any
fucking sense whatsoever.
And
one thing about Scientology for as
much shit as people give Scientology,
at least it has the brains to
incorporate outer space. You know,
I don't know if that's a really good
point, if that's really fucking stupid,
but you know, I don't fucking
know. So anyways, yeah, dude,
I wasn't trying to offend you
or anything that you fucking,
I was just trying to be funny and I'm
just fucking around and if you want to
take this shit seriously, that, that
is totally your fucking choice. Um,
you know, that's it. All right. I'm
fucking done with that. All right,
let's move on to the next person. Me, um,
no. What the fuck? Where the fuck is it?
Jesus Christ. I think I only buy like
put one of my thought. I had another one.
I'm really disorganized this week.
That's because you don't have Jesus in
your life. You don't want to have Jason,
another guy said, I love how you
pick on a, on a, on a, on a, uh, uh,
a punching bag of religion,
basically saying like,
it's very easy to make fun of Christians,
but I don't dare make fun of Muslims
because if you make fun of them, Oh Shit,
look what's going to happen.
You know?
And which I thought was fucking hilarious
because the person was sitting there
talking about how insensitive I am and
that it basically, in a round about way,
we're alluding to the fact that people
who are Muslim means that you're a,
you're a fucking, uh, uh, you
know, you're going to blow up.
Like they're all going to blow up
planes and that type of shit. You know,
I went to a wedding one time,
this girl was Pakistanian.
They actually addressed that, that what
they fucking hate it was at all, you know,
Christians thought that all of them just
wanted to walk around blowing up shit.
And, uh, and I also,
it was funny that this guy's fucking
sitting there suggesting that people just
because they're Christian, that they're
peaceful. When do you know, what is it?
Once every 18 months, some Jesus freaks
fucking kills an abortion doctor.
That's pretty much par for the course,
isn't it? Um, no, and it's, it,
it's not safe to make fun of Jesus freaks.
It really isn't.
It really fucking isn't.
And I think Bill Maher is out of his
fucking mind to say what he says and like,
or actually has balls the size of the
Grand Canyon to say what the fuck he says,
and then just walk out in Wade
into those people and just like,
I would never do that shit anyways.
And I got to admit the level with which
that people take this shit seriously.
It actually kinda creeps me out to kick
to continue talking about this shit. So,
uh, this might be the last fucking week
of it because I've definitely made my
fucking points.
And at this point we're just going to go
around in circles and I'm just going to
piss people off. So, uh, let's
move on to this last guy.
What? She brought up
some great points. Um,
all right, set a bunch of Nice
stuff. And then he said, all right,
enough with the Dick Sucking.
I was going to trick,
I was going to criticize religion,
but to describe those belief is,
is to mock them there. And you know
what dude? That's what I learned. Um,
yeah,
if you describe them,
then you start making fun of
them and then everybody gets mad.
Or as you're saying, they're just so
ridiculous. She just have to, you know.
Anyways, let's fly ahead
here. Yeah. He said,
you mentioned needing a code in the
absence of religion to live by. Um,
I'm not sure how much, um, of the,
I don't read thing as a Shtick,
but I recommend an excellent text
used in an intro to Undergrad,
an Undergrad ethics course called the
elements of moral philosophy by James.
I don't know if that's rock
hills or Rachael's, um,
everybody goes on and on about Jesus.
But Socrates who define morality
is how we ought to live.
Let a compelling life, as you
probably know. Actually, I don't,
I just know him as a party reference.
Um,
what do you fucking Socrates,
you know,
that's one of those references that
even morons can use and get away with.
And I'm sad to say I'm one
of those people. Um, he said,
I didn't know this shit.
He was found guilty of corrupting
the youth. He thought Zeus,
Venus areas, et Cetera,
smacked of bullshit.
All right? Think about that, right?
They're corrupting the youth.
Now every why Christians, Muslims and
everybody today would say that. Yeah,
that is bullshit. That those people do
not exist. Cause now we've evolved to,
there's only one God.
There's only one bank.
There's one world power. Um, and
let's see. And as punishment,
he was forced to take his own
life by drinking hemlock poison.
Once again, another death because
of organized religion. You know,
these Jesus freaks, these, these
people who are into fucking,
I even got one of the reason
why I don't make fun of, uh,
the Muslim religion is really because
I don't know anything about it.
And the reason why I make fun of
Christianity is because that's what I was
brought up. And those are
the stories that, that I,
that I hear and all I know about
Muslims is basically, uh, you know,
the couple of wars with Iraq.
So I basically don't know shit.
I just think what you,
you wrap your,
wrap your women up and bounty paper
towels and then cut their clits off.
And am I wrong?
Am I wrong on that one?
If they're not allowed to show
their fucking thongs because, uh,
you're going to get an erection and
because you were that bed sheet,
everybody's going to fucking see it. I
don't, I don't really think about it,
but I would definitely make fun of it if
I knew something about it, but I don't.
All right.
And I reserve the right to make fun of
the fucker religion that I was brought up.
And, um, so anyways,
he says Socrates was a humble man,
famously announcing all I
know is my ignorance. Um,
he sought I the one that I love people
who would take that at face value. So he,
he said he was your fucking moron.
Right there, right there. You know,
Jesus is the solution. Um, he
sought answers to questions,
whereas religion prohibits
questioning answers.
I'll fucking brilliant.
This guy is really smart.
You should do a podcast instead of
me. I'm a fucking idiot. Listened to,
he sought answers to questions,
whereas religion prohibits
questioning answers.
And if anything fucking proves that
it's the 50 emails I got this week. Ah,
I like how I'm actually asking like,
I'm questioning religion on any sort of
intelligent level. Um, I think actually,
I think I am just because I say cut
and fuck doesn't mean I'm not, uh,
bringing up some good questions.
All right. Let's finish
this for, uh, for Socrates.
The unexamined life is not worth living.
Um,
his sentiments on marriage and
nagging women are remarkably,
remarkably similar to your own,
so underrated Socrates,
overrated. Jesus. Uh,
yeah. And that's, you know,
that's, that is the one thing,
and I'm not being a dick here,
that I don't understand about people who,
like I respect
people who you know,
are raised in a religion or,
or find a religion that speaks to them
and then they decide to commit their
lives to what, and what I
don't understand is, you know,
and it brings you this piece,
right? Am I wrong there? All right,
so it brings you this piece,
but then if anybody questions
that belief that you have,
how quickly it turns violent,
like the amount of people who died
because they question these a holy people.
It is,
you don't find that fucking like
hilarious and ridiculous on any level
like this sitting there calling
the other person the devil,
because they're questioning their beliefs
and they're saying that that other
person is going to hell and then they
turn around and kill the person because
they don't believe in the holy pure way
that they live their life. I mean, I just,
I can't get behind that.
I can't get behind that the same way.
Is that the same way?
It's just because you're a red sox fan,
you can't recognize the talent of
Derek Jeter. And I gotta be like,
do full cubies who fig now he's the shit
out of fucking now. Why, why do I
continue with this shit? Um, anyways,
so that's the podcast for the week.
Uh,
this person actually goes on to
recommend a movie. Um, he says,
I heard you mentioned the departed a
few times. Um, if you haven't already,
you might want to check out state of
grace and overlook mobster flit from 1990
that was unfortunately released
around the same time as good fellows,
Goodfellas and Miller's crossing. It
has Sean Penn, Ed Harris, Burgess,
Meredith, Robin white topless. All
right. That made it a little creepy.
And Gary Oldman,
who gives an Oscar caliber performance.
All right. Yeah, if you guys haven't
seen state of grace, I've seen that. Uh,
I'm actually due to watch that
again. Um, Gary Oldman is,
you know what if you just
saw him play commissioner,
uh, Gordon in Batman and the,
the, the reserve performance that he did
and then you see him and stayed at grey,
she'll realize why that guy,
he's even though people recognize
him as an incredible actor,
he still, I think one of the most
underrated actors of all time.
He's fucking unbelievable.
And you have to see the
face Ed Harris makes,
um, without ruining the
movie. He gets betrayed.
And when he realizes that
he's betrayed the fucking,
the way he twists up his face,
ed Harris is another one. Dude,
that movie is like,
um,
the guys that are in that movie
for me are the modern day.
Like, uh, I mean, again,
this is a big statement because
you can never replace those guys,
but it was my generation's
Bronson, Lee Marvin, you
know, just the guy guy guys,
guys like you just wanted to be those
guys and they always had guns and they
never took any shit. It's just, there's
just fucking, you know, Gary Oldman, uh,
and uh, um, ed Harris,
who else do I put in that it's
a very short fucking list.
It's very hard the way.
Um,
okay.
Nowadays in movies I think to be the guy,
you know, that, that classic, you know,
women want to get with them
and guys want to be him.
And I think a lot of it is because,
okay,
back in the day, like those
being in shape, you just,
you were just in sort of regular shape
and then it was the way you carried
yourself. Kind of like what's his
face in a Ben Kingsley and sexy beast.
Do you guys ever seen that movie?
I know I brought it up a bunch of times,
but I remember he was in an inside the
actor's studio one time and they asked
him if he worked out before he played,
uh,
before we played that
character. And um, he said no,
it was all the way I held my body.
He just stood more like a wrecked and
he had like perfect posture and he just
looked like this tough as nails guy.
Even though it was Ben Kingsley and I
think there was something about those
older guys like Steve Mcqueen and
those guys that just the way they held
themselves because you look at it
and they all like Yule Brenner.
I mean all those guys,
they were like 140 pounds,
but somehow you just look at him like,
dude, I wouldn't fuck with those guys.
And then like all the star to
many of the stars nowadays,
they've got like highlights in their hair
and they got abs and they got 'em all
oiled up and shit. You look
in at my guys a fag, you know?
Yeah.
I don't know. Did Stars
back in the day? Did they?
Did they fucking shaved the chest
hair and landscape? Their eyebrows?
I think there's just something about
it, man. I Dunno. I don't fucking know.
Anyways, that's the podcast
for this week. And once again,
I'm not disrespecting your religions.
Okay?
But this is my podcast and when I bring
shit up, I fucking go off on it and I,
and I definitely go over the top.
Okay.
Saying that somebody was pet playing
the upright bass with Jesus's Juggler is
fucking hilarious because
it's over the top.
And I believe the God in
my world thinks it's funny.
He's God. Why would he be intimidated?
I, there's another thing too.
I don't understand why God
would make all this stuff. Okay.
And then just be so doe angry
all the time. Jesus Christ here.
I gone back in it again. I got a lot of
questions. Fuck you. It's my podcast.
I know.
That's why I don't understand.
Okay.
You know, I, I is it, it's
more like, you know, when you,
when you build a bookshelf and yet you
just standing back a Myra and your work
and then it falls down on the floor and
you're like God damn fucking piece of
Shit and you start blaming the
bookshelf even though you made it,
you're the one that put it up there,
you know?
Yeah.
I guess technically.
Dot. God didn't make a,
he didn't make titty bars. Guess
those are man made. But uh, you know,
the broads in Zynnyme a man or are
okay.
Wow. I'm really fucking, I was just going
to say made in his image. Isn't that,
isn't that what you guys say?
They found a dabble. Dabble.
They got the devil in him.
Um, all right. What have,
all I'm saying is because it really
gets serious to sweet people.
People really get fucking, they took
it a little too seriously. All right,
so back the fuck off. Stop taking it
so God damn seriously. And you know,
why don't you actually practice what your
preacher preaches and why don't you go
pray for me? Why don't you do that instead
of coming on here telling me, you know,
you've given me your wrath.
Isn't that one of the seven deadly sins?
You fucking maniacs.
Okay.
You just as fucked up as I am and you
don't know shit either. All right.
All right. I'm sorry. God
bless all of you. Okay.
I hope you find what works for you
and a seriously, if I'm bugging you,
don't listen to the podcast.
God knows I'm not making any money off it.
I don't give a fuck. Ah, that's it.
You guys all have a great weekend. A,
I tell you where I was
going to be this week,
but I'm worried some Jesus freak is going
to show up. So, uh, that's it. That's it.
Have a great week and a,
I'll talk to you next month.
Hopefully
down
bells.
Right?
Smooth.
It was Smith.
[inaudible].