Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Byrd
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast in,
ah,
checking in on you.
I'm just checking out how the holiday
season is fucking go and for you.
Did she get some toys for
fucking girls in boys?
That sounded really creepy.
Um, hey, what's going on?
I have been running around all day.
Podcast is a little bit late.
I was actually doing Joe Rogan's
monster podcast. Um, and uh,
we had a great time.
Talked a little bit about flying in a
helicopter earlier this week and uh,
and then he got me all sold on buying
a fucking sauna. Yeah. Joe, Joe,
Joe. Fuck. It tells you something
like, all right, this guy, you know,
he's probably read up on
it, whatever. He was like,
people who do this four times
a fucking week, you know,
live a long time or some shit.
And I'm just thinking like,
well, I'm an old dad. Oh,
I don't care.
Oh Man.
Old Dad Joe,
make me come too far away.
It's going to be me in five
years. Oh yeah, you can
job doing to cad.
Um, so I have to, uh, make
sure I take care of myself. So,
uh, Billy's got some
growing up to do. All right.
Been abusing alcohol for a while.
Now I take the bottle out,
I slept around a let them know who's boss.
Um,
and I got to fucking grow up.
You need, you need to call up.
He had to take a little bit spanky Philly,
they fucking say that all the time.
You and sneaky,
a little bit of responsibility.
Uh,
I've never in my life
understood that expression.
You need a little bit of responsibility.
They'll pick like the most immature
fucking person ever and tell them you need
some responsibility and you're
like this fucking guy. No,
this guy does not need to be in charge
of anything. He's a fucking moron.
Because they had that
whole idea of, oh, well,
once you have a kid and then you have,
you know, you're, you're gonna have to,
you know, change your ways. Yeah.
Unless you're a fucking idiot and
everything this person is doing is
demonstrating that they're a fucking
moron and you're telling them to go out
there,
procreate with somebody.
You know what you need
is no responsibility.
You need a fucking playpen
is what you need there.
Bucko my new year's resolution
is I'm going to, um,
I'm going to fix it. I'm going to fix
this little phone, a headphone Jack.
I literally sit here with my thumb
on the button like a terrorist.
You know what I mean? Like I
lift it off it, you know, my mom,
my way to fucking Evan
70 broads in my life.
I know it's a hacky joke. The more you're
married that just you just like, Oh God.
Um, anyway, um,
all beeble oh, bill burr is fucking
slowing down, man. In a good way.
You know, I'm off the
sauce. Who knows? File log,
but I'm off the fucking sauce
and I'm actually reading a book.
I swear to God. I mean, granted, it's
a sports book. Does that even count?
It's about, uh, Bob Cousy and
Bill Russell's relationship.
When I did the heard somebody over there
gave it to me believe this is where I
got it. And um, you know, one of
the things that always bothered me,
you know,
something I always got meant to get
around to was to know all the Celtics
retired numbers. And now that
I've read the book, I finally,
I think I am, I'm down.
I swear to God I'm not looking
at anything. All right.
Number one is Walter Brown.
He was the original owner of the Celtics.
Number two is red are back. The great
coach. They consider a number two,
he got number two because he's the second
most important person in the Celtics
history I guess. Cause number one is the
original owner. Then it's Dennis Johnson.
Number three, Bill Russell, number six.
Why do I, why do I need to know this?
Jo Jo white on the great basketball names?
No,
but 10 and then it's Bob Cousy at 14.
Tommy Heinsohn is 15 some guys,
Tom Sanders is 1617.
Okay.
Eighteens Dave Cowens 19
is fucking Don Nelson.
21 is Bill Sharman.
22 was Ed Mccauley 20
three's Frank Ramsey.
24, Sam Jones, 25. Casey
Jones. All right, now it's not,
now it's easy.
31 said Vic cornbread,
Maxwell 32 is Mikael 33 bird 35.
Reggie Lewis,
double zero is fucking Robert Parish.
Then there's another guy just says his
name cause he also wore the number at 18
and didn't want to retire it.
And the Dave Collins got it.
So I don't know his fucking name. So
that's not bad. That's not bad. Um,
so now my know that and
what does that get me?
Next time I get into an argument with
my wife now, but watch Walter Brown now,
but two's red are back.
Can you do this?
Oh Dad,
I'm an old dad. I said, get off
of that now I need a nap. Um,
anyways, so after I did
Joe's podcast, he's like,
he's got like did that flotation salt
tank thing in there. And I'm like,
dude, I don't know if like if I went
in that fucking thing for like an hour,
like
I always wondered what those things
will like those isolation tanks.
I mean that looks fucking wild.
They just closed that door.
And you're in there
floating in pitch black,
like you're floating through space like
Sandra Bullock in that movie. Right.
Where the other guy there was never going
to get married and then he did George
Clooney.
Right.
May just sort of floated off into space
that I could never get my shit together.
You go back to the bucket spacecraft,
I'm just going to float away that movie.
I feel like you'd feel like that,
you know,
if I ever get a role where I get
to play an astronaut, that that's,
that's to be how I'm going
to prepare for the role.
But what did you do to prepare for
a role to play an astronaut? Well,
I kept my Boston accent and I just went
to an isolation tank and just laid there
in a bathing suit. Do you
think it helped? You know,
but it gave me something to say
in this interview. Um, anyway,
so he had a sauna there, which I'm
totally sold on now. We went there,
we tried to be in there for like a fucking
half hour. He could do it. I couldn't,
I, I made like there
was eight minutes left,
10 minutes left. I made 20 minutes. It
was like 200 fucking degrees in there.
That's what he was saying. Like,
how the fuck is it? 200 degrees now.
It doesn't water boil at like
212 degrees or some shit,
a hundred degrees Celsius.
Um,
I guess those scientists can get harder
cause it's not like it because it's a
dry heat. I have no idea on all. I know. I
was just like, all right, 10 minutes left.
He goes, come on and tough
it out. I'm like, all right.
And then 10 minutes later I'm like,
how much time's left?
And he's like eight
minutes. And I'm like, fuck.
And it at like five minutes I laid down
and he's like,
all right dude.
He knew I was too stubborn so he fucking
opened the door and then I was fine.
He goes, you almost made it. It's
like, I think I did all right.
I don't think I need to go any further
than that, but uh, I felt fucking great.
I felt peaceful.
I felt calm.
Okay.
I didn't feel like yelling at anybody
or walking around being a fucking
emotional lunatic that's
just wears people out. Um,
so whatever. I'll see. They
makes little two person ones.
I want to make it fit it in my
fucking little ass garage. Yeah, no,
that would be great.
Okay.
You know, anytime you have a
disagreement with your spouse, right?
You just go into the sauna at the rule
is you go in there for half hour and then
when you come up then you talk about it.
Hey Man,
like you left your shoes in the
hall, man. Oh, I'm sorry man.
It's okay. It's not, it doesn't really,
but I didn't know why it bothered me
31 minutes ago, but it did. But that's,
you know what, you can put your shoes
wherever you want. Ah, thank you.
I appreciate that.
I don't know what the fuck I'm
talking about. So anyways, um,
I get not only do I have all my
Christmas shopping done, I got, um,
I got it all wrapped except for when I
bought my, my daughter this book, uh,
the Grinch stole Christmas. I
bought that on the road. And I just,
I forgot I had it,
I tucked it away in the drawer because
I knew if she saw it and she'd be like,
book, book, read, read. Yeah. Um,
so I just have to wrap that. Then I
think I'm done. I'm think I'm done.
And I think for once my super smart wife
hasn't figured out what anything that
I'm going to get her,
you know,
that was really covert about the
shit. Snuck it around. I just,
I brought everything into the
garage this year. Right. Sorry.
What the fuck was that?
You don't shit where you open your
mouth and you just make a fucking noise.
Did you just hear that? Sounded like
there was a ferret that was like some,
something in the back of my
throat while I continued to talk.
Sound like a little cat. Did you hit
her? You know, do you realize like bag,
if I did that back in like
the fucking 1700 state,
they'd be like drowning me thinking I was
a witch. I was like possessed or right.
A fucking tapeworm or something.
Jesus Christ.
Some of these fucking broads on,
on social media.
Thinking they're not being heard.
How do you think the the fucking
people felt back then? Well,
if you have to compare ourselves
to the Salem witch trial,
aren't you really proving our point?
That was the hedge clippers
trim in the bush there. Um,
they broke.
Anyways,
I'm plowing ahead here. Uh, by the way,
I've keep promoted this on, on Joe Rogan
to I the Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit.
It's still promoting.
That is February, Tuesday,
February 19th, 2019. Get
your ass to the fucking city.
All right, come on down. Great
benefit. Big J. Oh, Chris.
Michelle Wealth Rich Vos.
Good cipher sounds myself has going.
It's going to be a cavalcade of comedy,
but the best stand up
comedian I ever saw my life,
all proceeds go to benefit all the people
that he's taken care of, his family.
Well, you know, all that and it's
been a very successful thing.
We keep his name alive and whatnot.
Um,
okay.
All right with that.
You know what?
I actually got to watch a Bruins game the
other night by can't watch most of it.
I watch most of it. And then, uh, being
a dad comes in, you know, I saw, uh,
the first two periods of the Bruins,
four to nothing win over the Canadians.
You know, we were up two to nothing and
I missed the fourth period. Third period.
Sorry. And uh, you know, one of my friends
from Montreal comedy festival texts me,
cause you watching this game,
and I knew it was the third
period and I was like, well, I go,
I'm assuming you guys tied it up if you
fucking called me. And to his credit,
he didn't. He texted me, he, to his
credit, he didn't. The man did not.
We played fucking great.
Then I saw the highlights at last fucker,
Marshawn golden number for, they're
little big bank bull all around the horn.
Everybody it,
all those little frenchies with Dave
fucking crying into their little handcuff
chest with this silly
socks. Oh, I love it.
Going into their building,
four to nothing.
So the private plane tonight,
I have no idea, but I gotta go,
I gotta go on site for fucking supper.
I still call it supper back in the day.
That's what we call
sit down for September.
Your mother would ring the fucking dinner
bell and everybody would come running
in like cattle, right? I'll fucking
filthy for being outside there.
It was chipped beef on toast.
Uh, chicken, Alec. Kig.
You know, I don't think a
king eats like this. Um,
so let's plow ahead here. Uh,
it's Liverpool. My fucking,
my fucking adopted God damn team.
My almost fucking miss this game.
They're playing all my God. They're
playing the wolves. Jesus fucking Christ,
not the wolves. How the fuck is
that a professional franchise?
You've got some stupid Jersey with
like a w on it. We get it. You know,
you couldn't write the whole thing.
They can't afford to have the
o l v e s on there, right?
Does that he spelled or
was it w o l. F s. Wolf's.
I Dunno. They'd say everything different
over the old Oregano oil. Oregano.
You know, what else do they
say? Tomato over a Gyno.
Uh, all the spices they
say differently. What's it?
Rose Marie? No, that's not
the one with the flex time.
They see the same way.
There's another one.
There's another one that was just the
ones Basel or Rogano Basel two mottoes.
And you just want to be like, stop doing
that. You want to say that they're wrong,
but they did it first. So they were
right. Why the fuck did we switch?
We switched all the accents on everything
and I believe that was a fuck you
right to England
after we kicked their fucking red coated
asses all the way back to their island,
all the way back.
Right.
And I just think that our little rebellion
was not only are we kicking you out
of the country that you first
fucking occupied and took over.
Not only will we can send you the
genocide that you started, right.
We're gonna, we're gonna change
the accent on the English language.
Right.
Do you say, uh, automobile?
We're going to say automobile.
I don't know if we do that.
I have no idea. Um, anyways,
uh,
fuck was that
I am up. Goddamn noise is not, I
don't know if I'm going crazy or what.
I will tell you what's driving me fucking
crazy is this year I thought it was
being a smart guy. Oh, who's just to, as
a tough guy, he was a smart guy, right?
I went out and I bought a Christmas
tree like when was still November.
Okay.
You know,
so now I'm watering this thing and I got
a missed it every God damn morning to
make sure it,
it's not all brown and dead.
By the time fucking Christmas comes along,
our wreath is on the,
on the front door is already dying.
You know that my wife went all out.
You know what I mean? Like great
mothers do. She went all out,
but I got more goddamn shit. I'm running
around, you know I, I'm the water boy.
I've got a water rate. I missed it.
I'm talking to it. No, you look good.
You look good.
Now you're going to be one of the
trees that lives after Christmas.
You don't just lying to them
like a fucking dirt bag. Right?
So I didn't have a lot of time the other
day and I'm running around the fucking
kitchen table and we got this stupid
fucking potted plant that literally has a
concrete plant plant or whatever the,
the fucking house that the roots are in,
whatever you call it.
Right.
And that was on the floor because of
the Christmas decorations on the table.
And I ran around the table
and just punted that thing,
concrete fucking block with my,
my pinky toe on my left foot
and Jesus fucking Christ.
It was like Barney the dinosaur purple
within two hours and it was like a half
of my foot by foot look like I got
run over by a car. Now, you know,
obviously I did some damage,
but most of it has to be my, it,
most of it is my complexion,
you know, being uh,
a a fucking, you know, redhead,
I'm borderline like transparent.
Like I'm always getting marks on
my body and like late at night,
like I go to bed and my wife would be
like, what does that, what does that on?
Yeah. What is, you know,
fucking kilohm mark on my side.
Did you get into a fight with an
alley cat? Huh? No, I think I uh,
think I leaned up against
the refrigerator. I Dunno.
What the fuck happened.
And then when,
you know what's weird is if you hurt
yourself and you don't remember what
happened, you press down on
it and then you're like, oh,
and he takes you right back
to that moment. Oh, that's
right. That's fucking ride.
Yeah, it was, I was at the, the
fucking poster. Oh, by the way,
Jesus Christ,
I went to the post office.
I was trying to get all my
fucking gifts out and uh,
you can not fucking go there.
The only way you can fucking go
there is if you have everything done.
I went there,
I needed a box and I needed to,
and then I need the fucking, the
peanuts or whatever to put it in there.
So what I was,
whatever I was going to put in there was
going to slide around and break and I
need to tape to close the box.
It should just like,
it's just that last chopper out of Vietnam
I in and I was happy that I went down
there. I found somebody to help
me out. You know, I got the box,
I got the tape,
and then they said they had nothing to
put in there to make sure my gifts to my
nephews and nieces wouldn't fucking
slide around. And I, I just, I just,
I said, fuck it. I said,
all right, thank you.
I sent the tape down and put
the box where it belonged.
I walked out like a
gentleman while I fucking,
I went a little Tourette's
underneath God damn fucking well,
what the fuck do you have? Fucking
boxes and tape, but you don't have the,
the last inquiry,
the most important ingredient.
Well, the last piece of
the puzzle, I should say,
the box is probably the most important.
Agree. Well then you have to tape. I mean,
they work together like a great
comedy team, dare I say, right?
Like Bob hope and bing Crosby.
They,
the guys who evidently created
the fucking the buddy movie,
you know,
which has now been hijacked by all these
females and all these movies and acting
like they're breaking ground.
It's like you just doing the shit.
We already did this. Nothing
new here ladies. You know,
why don't you reinvent the buddy fucking
movie before I got to listen to your
call on each other. A bunch of fucking
heroes. What do you think about that? Hey,
uh,
this is the thing that fascinated me
because I was reading the Celtics Book and
some of the fucking teams that
they were playing, like, you know,
playing Syracuse and Rochester
stuff I had heard about before.
But um,
okay.
When they were talking,
what the fuck is this?
They were talking about playing like the,
uh,
what are now the Atlanta Hawks and I
knew that they were in Saint Louis,
but I didn't realize that they
were in Milwaukee before that.
All right, let's see here. At Atlanta
Hawks. Yeah, they were, it, this is,
this is their, their history.
They were the buffalo bisons
yeah.
Then for one season and then they moved,
or maybe a half a season.
Then they moved to the tri cities in Iowa,
which are now the quad cities,
I believe.
And they became the Tri city black hawks.
Then they may move to Milwaukee in
1951 and became the Milwaukee Hawks.
Then in 1955, they moved to St Louis
and became the Saint Louis Hawks.
And then in 1968 they moved to uh,
Atlanta and became the Atlanta Hawks.
And they'd been there for 50 years.
But they've moved five times.
And I always thought the Sacramento Kings,
which I can't remember if they were the
Cincinnati royals and then the Kansas
City kings and then the Sacramento Kings.
I couldn't remember. Hang on a second.
Let me get to this,
cause I got,
I got this fucking website here that
has all the franchises that moved,
if I can get it to work here,
please, please. Is People listening?
National Hockey League,
where the fuck is the NBA?
Oh Jesus Christ. Come on national
basketball. So she, the Tri city hawks,
Blackhawks played their home
games in Moline and rock island,
Illinois and Davenport, Iowa moved
to Milwaukee, became the hawks,
then in 55 then we'll just St Louis.
Okay.
And then the Detroit Pistons with Fort
Wayne Pistons till 1957 Rochester royals
moved to Cincinnati.
Okay.
And then where the fuck
did they go from there?
Okay.
Cause this goes year by year. So all
day became the Sacramento Kings. Yeah,
they were the raw Rochester's Seagram's.
What the fuck is that?
Yeah.
Anyways, Rob Chester pros and
they became the Rochester royals,
then they move Cincinnati royals,
Kansas City slash Almaha kings,
Kansas City Kings,
Sacramento Kings.
And then I think the Syracuse team moved
to San Diego and became the San Diego
Clippers.
Where the fuck is it?
The Syracuse nationals moved to
Philadelphia and became the 76 is, okay.
So who became the La Clippers?
The San Diego Clippers.
Oh, the buffalo Braves moved to
San Diego and became the clippers.
That's what it is. Oh No, it's the
Rochester royals. I don't know.
I'm a fucking nerd.
I love that shit.
Then I go online and see if I can find
a tri cities black hawks tee shirt.
Like they ever fucking sold one of those.
I bet it's a minor league hockey team now.
Tri City.
Come on,
come on bill. You can
write it. Black Hawks
t shirt. Here we go. Somebody makes
it, you know somebody makes it.
Mitchell and ness. Chicago
Blackhawks, Tri city,
black hawks.
There it is.
Everyone would like myself would think,
oh,
is that where the Chicago
Black Hawks first played? And
they'd be like, oh no, no,
no. That's not, that's
not the case. All dead.
MMM.
Okay.
Damn. They got the, they got the dude.
He's just see them all the fucking kid.
If they got it where and it
was like 21 fucking years old.
Similar designs. Look at this. They
got all the old ones here anyways.
Trust the process. Yeah. Boy,
I didn't want to know who
the fuck said that. Uh Oh.
There's a cool Lebron one where they make
his beard like the state of California.
Do you realize if the Lakers
don't win it this year,
this will be the first decade.
They haven't won a fucking
championship since the fucking 1960s
seventies eighties nineties two
thousands they went for decades in a row.
Celtics won 50 60 seventies eighties
okay.
Well it went for decades,
right?
It was seventies eighties
nineties 2004 Oh yeah.
No one's ever done five. No one's ever
done five. Can you see, can you tell him?
I'll fucking talked out
from Rogan's podcast.
We did like fucking two and a half hours.
I'm sitting here wondering what
the hell to talk about. I could,
I could read some advertising.
Okay.
I could read some advertising. By
the way, I'm not farting continually.
I'm just sitting in a leather chair.
I just realized
leather
chair, plush leather chair, one chair,
one chair, my little fucking podcast area
here finally, cause now we have the kid.
I can't do it the way I used to
in the fucking bedroom and shit.
Screaming and yelling. We can't
have that bill. We keep pill.
We can't have you be who you
are in your own home anymore.
Butcher box,
everybody butcher box delivers.
That's a great name for like a
fucking female wrestler. Butcher box.
You know,
or finishing move is he jumps up in the
air and it fucking puts her claim in
your face.
Yep.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and the fucking mother
of them off the holy grail for all youth
carnivores out their
heritage. Bread, pork,
the incredible, oh my
God, do I love that stuff?
The incredible quality of butcher
box means start with the co,
the commitment starting start with the
commitment to raising animals humanely
and free of antibiotics and hormones
telling me look beautiful before they
murdered. Cooked with piece of
mind knowing you're eating healthy,
high quality meat.
Each box comes with at least
eight to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individual sized meals.
Even for you size queens out there, you
can choose from five different box types.
All beef, beef and chicken,
beef and pork, mixed box,
custom box.
I feel like the mixed box
is to progressive liberal
box where custom box is more
like, you know, hardcore, right?
You know, I only want peace,
uh, in my neighborhood. Let's you,
let's you choose your own God damn cuts.
It's delicious for $20 off your first
box and a package of free bacon in every
box for the life of your subscription.
Meaning whenever you order some food,
you getting some free Bacon,
never pay for Bacon again.
Go to butcher box.com/burr
and enter Burra checkout.
That's $20 off your first
box and a package of free
bacon in every box for life,
for the life of your subscription,
by going to butcher box.com/burr
and entering bird at checkout.
Um, I got a hats off to
my wife. We had some, uh,
we had like this really mature like
get together of like, you know,
four or five different couples.
And they came over and my
wife just did it up, you know,
hired these people to cater it. They
made all this great food, you know,
the booze was flowing, everyone was
having a good time. And I sat there,
she's like, come on man, it's a holiday
party. Yeah, you have to tab one.
Drake have one jar. I said, I will. I,
Bob Start with the Ginger Ale. Right.
And I just kept putting it off, putting
it off and putting it off. Right.
And then all of a sudden it
was the end of the night,
we'd all sit in there
smoking cigars and a,
then all of a sudden the night was over
and I didn't drink. Everybody had a time.
And I've almost done it.
I only have a,
I've got a couple more holiday
parties. Oh, I got a tough one.
I got a tough one coming up with
a good friend of mine, comedian.
I'm not going to say what the fuck it
is, but he has, he has a party coming up.
Oh this can be tough and no,
it's not that gutter dweller.
Joe De Rosa. Oh Joe Rosa loves
it. Gutter loves it. Gutter.
Yeah,
I know he sees a curb.
He just sees nuzzles up to it.
Like he's laying with his own
mother, his own butter. Um,
but anyways, I always get a little bit
sad this time of the holidays, you know,
cause I know that it's almost over.
I liked this time of year,
you know where everybody just kind of
sits back cause like, you know what,
I fucking love you man fucking
PCH in my life, man. You know,
you know they got the fucking lights.
It's just, he just look around like,
why can't it be like this all the time?
Why can't work be like, all right, relax.
You know,
and everybody just chills out and just
says how much they like each other.
Why can't we do?
You'd get bored of it,
I guess after a while they
can't have like, you know,
okay.
Sort of a summer, Christmas time,
holiday, Hanukkah, Kwanza fucking thing.
You gotta wait once a once a fucking
year that it starts all over again.
January 2nd or January 3rd of this
has gotta be this company's biggest
quarter ever. Where did you
all a buckle down and not go?
You will not see your children
when you leave for work.
Y'All be sleeping when you
come home and he'll be asleep.
You'll be a stranger and you're rolling.
So his share, we could sell them. I
was wet jets we've ever saw error.
I'll tell you right now, if you
got a problem, there's door.
The Internet has made this industry
more competitive than it's ever been.
That's rob. You got to cry, Maggie.
Huh? Who else? What about you?
Greg heard you're all fucking sensitive.
Jewel fucking box of tampons
for the first fucking court.
Where did you do less last quarter?
You didn't check.
You know, can you imagine if
you had that fucking life?
Just imagine that fucking life getting
yelled at. You know, you don't have to.
That famous scene in Glengarry Glen Ross,
Alec Baldwin comes in and starts yelling
at people. I can't fucking hear myself.
God Damn it. I got to get this fixed. Um,
this would be such a
great stocking stuffer.
What an I tell fucking
Santa I wanted this. Oh,
here comes Santa Claus. Here comes
Santa Claus. He's back from radio shack.
He got you the Fucking
headphone Jack Dad shoe needed.
What does this even called? I'm gonna.
You know what? I'm a do people in,
in fucking honor of the New
Year and what I plan on doing,
which you wouldn't know from that last
little comedy skit that I did there.
And by the way, that was all written
up. I memorized all those lights. Um,
uh, you know, I'm going to try to fucking
chill out in the next fucking year,
you know what I mean? So
anyways, in honor of that,
I'm in solving problems rather
than complaining about them. I'm,
I'm going to let you
guys listen to me order,
this is the highlight of
your fucking week. I know it
is this self self involved.
I am.
You're going to listen to me order this
fucking Cock sucker God damn thing that
I need here.
What would you call this thing?
Okay.
Uh, the rotisserie. Yeah.
This is basically like the
chick and you know, a porno.
She's getting bang from behind Ed.
Uh,
she's performing the old fucking a
and how you been up front, right?
And you know someone's going
to have a bigger Dick, right?
So one of them figure the other one's
smaller. What do you call this thing?
The rotisserie.
A core Jack.
I don't fucking know a head phone.
I'm going to go with a head phone
adapter.
It's going to take me to fucking
Wikipedia. Why the fuck would it do that?
It's in my default settings.
I gotta figure out how to fucking do
headphone adapter. Oh No. Oh No, no,
no, no. That's not the one I need. Let's
see. Images. Come on. You fucking bastard.
Come on. You fucking bastard. Uh
Oh. Do I need, I just not doable.
Oh my God.
There it is.
And it's at radio shack.
Three and a half millimeter.
Male to female.
What do you call this fucking thing?
Oh my God, I know the name.
He's like a cold case file.
3.5 millimeter male to female
headphone adapter. All right,
let me go.
Let me go to fucking Amazon cause I don't
know how to do it with radio shack to
those guys deliver to do they have the
drones? I don't fucking know. All right.
Where the fuck is it?
Oh, where did it go? Oh,
you know what I did? I didn't
open a new window. Oh grandpa,
I don't understand it. Your
Internet. Oh No, I did.
Okay,
well where the fuck did
it go? Oh, there it is.
Would you like 15% off now?
Thanks. I'd like full price.
3.5 millimeter male to
female headphone adapter.
Okay,
let's see here.
3.5
okay.
Millimeter male to female
headphone adapter. Come on man. One time.
One time. Make it have and make it.
Hell. That's what the fuck that is.
Oh, look at those ones. Those ones
look like they're made on a chrome.
That's it right there.
That's it.
$7.
Can you fucking believe it?
Okay.
All this Bitch Moan and complain and
I could've had this done. You know,
you know people a lot of times in life,
you know the things that
were the most afraid of.
A lot of times they seem like
mountains in deer. Really?
You're just stepping up onto a curb.
Wait,
what do you mean $125?
What the Fuck William get the gift.
I don't want to fucking gift card.
Proceed to checkout it away from me.
Can I just, can you just walk out of
here please? Can I just fucking do that?
Place your order vamp order, place.
All this time pitching
all this tired said, done.
I just fucking did it. I did all
this fucking screaming and yelling.
You know,
I just feel like that just to be
a performer isn't enough for me.
I feel like I should be this vessel.
Who is it? Come on in. Oh,
just when Christmas couldn't
get any better. Who Sat it?
Sat my little buddy. Hey, how you doing?
Camair oh yeah. Don't mess up
my notes on that. Scripted.
It doesn't work right now.
Can I get a hug please? Hi.
Hi. Hey. Hey football.
He say hockey.
Can you say basketball?
Can you say baseball? Um, yeah.
Just don't have a knock all those
cards over. How are you guys doing?
The two most beautiful ladies in my life.
How are you?
I've been bitching about this
3.5 millimeter male to female,
a headphone Jack. And I finally got
it fixed. What did you guys do today?
We just
ingredients for Christmas dinner.
What are you gonna make?
Um, am I plugged in? Yes.
You were plugged in. Uh,
we're gonna make lamb. So I
got a rack of lamb. Oh, nice.
And I had them cut it up and we're just
going to freeze it until it's ready
because it's going to be a mad
house when we go on Christmas Eve.
Or can you say strawberry?
Can you say football?
Can you say hi?
Can't say merry Christmas.
I don't know.
She could say that. Wow, I'm here.
I know how to keep you occupied
while we're in here. All right,
well we're just doing something.
I didn't realize I hit all these debts,
that script I'm writing so I get
up. What's this? Oh, those are,
those are dad's keys.
He said Daddy's keys.
You say dad does car,
car
is getting fixed.
I hit an orange cone in my car and all
of a sudden the engine when I was on the
highway,
and this is random orange cone and I
couldn't swerve away from it or cause an
accident.
So I just drove over and went underneath
the car and I was getting off the
highway and it was,
I just heard it under the car.
Minnie mouse.
You want to go watch many mouths?
Huh? What do you say?
Oh, she does a football.
Football. What'd he say? You
say please? Now what he say?
Hey Danks please. And thanks. That's why
you're going to be a good kid. Oh. Oh,
I get a kiss. Your Mama and
Mama? Yeah, she's the best. Hey,
you're the best. You're
the best Ma. Oh my God.
Sounds about Minnie mouse.
Okay. Just don't mess.
That's you. That's you. Yes
it is. Yes it is. All right.
We've got to wrap this thing up
because I want to play with you, Kiddo.
All right.
And we're gonna Watch some football.
Football strawberries.
Yeah.
Hey, what does the dog
say? What was the duck say?
What does the cow say? Moo. Moo.
So she talks like Trump,
the biggest, uh, brain. Uh,
what does the horse say?
What is,
what does the rooster saying? Eh, Eh,
what's the, can't say, uh,
what does the sheep say?
What's the bear say?
All right. You're a smarty. Well,
you just shrug the shoulders like
that was nothing. That was like,
give me something hard. So
we go. Should we say bye bye.
Say Bye Bye Daddy.
Say I love you
again since I always say I love
you. Is Nan, Nan, Nan, Nan,
you could say it. Say I
love you. There you go.
All right.
Eventually you're going to put that
together and melt my heart even more.
All right. I love Pulte guys, but
I gotta wrap this up. Hey you guys,
thank you for listening. Have a great
week and I can't say what I usually say.
So Merry Christmas.
Enjoy the music and an extra
half hour bonus of the uh,
Thursday afternoon just before Friday.
Thank you to Joe Rogan.
Sure.
Magnolia blossom.
Don't care.
Adult to hang up. Just suck
it up.
You fucking
and your bucket.
Christmas fucking trees all be Dolby.
See,
that's the fucking song I was trying to
remember from last week and I want to
thank all the podcast
listeners for letting me know
that that was Andy Williams.
Happy holiday slash the
holiday sick season.
It's not until the second
verse where he goes,
Whoop de Doo and Hump Day dot.
Bad.
Stick up a sock,
but buck and crazy twat and you
don't see it exactly how I said it.
And then they had those fucking
women in the background. Uber Dooby,
dooby Ba boom.
You telling me you couldn't
write a fucking song back
then? I mean, Jesus Christ.
Maybe because it's so simple. It sounds
so simple that you think you could do it.
I don't know. So anyways, it is. Oh fuck.
Why did I play that?
And I want to be singing at the
whole God damn podcast again.
I don't like to repeat myself least
not on purpose. What's going on?
It's bill burr. It is the Monday
morning podcast for Monday, uh,
December 20th.
Oh my God.
Only five more days till Christmas. I
only have half. Shut up. You fucking,
yeah. All right. I'm not
even this angry week.
I'm just trying to figure out how I'm
going to situate myself on the bed.
I don't want to put my laptop in my lap.
You know what I made? Why would you,
why won't you put it in your lip?
It's called the lip dupe. Um,
this is why, because it gives off
radiation. And I liked my balls.
I think the Illuminati came
up with the laptop, you know,
and they know we're too stupid to stick
it exactly where they want us to put it
so they can find out the fucking
heard. So they go, you know,
with their evil voices,
whether we just collected laptop,
we call it didn't let up these put
it in their lap and they fucking die.
The infidels, that was
half Arab, half Italian.
So make sure I get notes from both of you.
Um,
yes it is December 20th.
I just came off of a
fabulous week out in Bray,
California and I want to
tell you guys something.
If you're ever in a situation where you
have a lot of vacation time and you just
like, fuck, where the
hell can I go? You know,
you only go around once in this world,
where can I go to vacation to summer is
not one rich people say we live in the
city and we somewhere out in the Hamptons.
I'd love to summer somewhere. Would
that be awesome? Jesus Christ.
How much fucking money do you
have to have? They have two homes.
This is where I live during the year.
And then I summer we spend a
linters down and boom Bados
doing what? Visiting the fucking money
that you're not paying tax taxes on.
You know, I don't give a fuck. I didn't
know what I'm talking about here.
I was on to something there and then I
completely lost it because I thought I
wasn't recording here. Um, oh, I know.
I was out in Bray California this
weekend and I got to tell you,
I had a miserable experience the
last couple of times that went there.
And the only reason why it was
miserable is because nobody showed up.
And Lo and behold,
this time I came out there and the
fucking place was packed all weekend and I
had one of the best
weekends of, uh, of 2010.
So I want to thank everybody
who came out to my shows, uh,
out at the Improv in Bray California.
Actually had some people
from La came out and a,
I had like 12 Mexicans,
different Mexican fans coming up saying
you have some Latino fence. Okay,
hang in there.
We will spread the word out to Ontario.
So I want to thank you guys.
Grassiness Julie word.
I know moo chose grassiness Rosetta stone.
I'm a Rio.
Um,
that's how you thank you very much. And
yellow. That's my only Spanish words.
Ay. Caramba yeah, Shit like
that, that I've seen in like
cartoons when I was a kid.
Um,
so anyways,
I don't know what the fuck to talk about
this week because uh, I am technically,
I'm on vacation.
Like Axel Foley had Beverly Hills Cop.
I'm not investigating anything.
I'm out here in La with my
Mumford fucking sweatshirt.
You know what I realized? I just
realized this podcast is going to suck.
You know why I have too much other
shit on my mind because as much as I'm
mocking people who haven't started
this shopping, I'm one of those people.
I haven't started it yet.
And it really fucked up because
I did like six weekends in a row.
So I just focused on the roadwork and
I did not deal with the fact that I
haven't done any sort of
Christmas shopping yet.
So now I have to go out there
today it's fucking raining.
I've been in this weather since I went
to Seattle right after Thanksgiving and
I'm ready to blow my fucking brains out
and went to Seattle and I also went to
San Francisco. It all those fucking
assholes would just like, oh you bring,
you bring the bed where the with you?
You know, I don't, I don't know. It was,
it was great last week.
So you know what,
considering I bought the droid phone.
Does anybody know how to shut that off?
[inaudible] every time you turn it on
my phone says that I brought the droid
incredible.
And every time I turn it on,
first of all it takes 10 minutes for it
to turn on. And then about, you know,
eight minutes in it goes drilling mud
and I don't think there's
a way to shut it off.
That's one of those
fucking advertising things.
Make It nice and loud and obnoxious.
So everyone around we'll hear it and be
like, Ooh, I want my phone to do that.
All right.
I'm still waiting for that.
Like I hope that phone does not take
over as much as I love it cause uh,
I fly too much,
you know,
and at the end of the flights when it's
okay to turn your cell phones back on,
I don't want to hear like draw, draw,
draw, draw void on the fucking plane, put,
you know, I'm going to, um,
but anyways, yeah, I haven't,
I haven't started any of my
Christmas shopping and uh,
I don't want to be that Douche just
goes out and gets the gift certificates.
You know that, you know that person, you
go out, you buy him something thoughtful.
What are they into? A, what did I hear?
A mention that they wanted
or something like that.
And you put a lot of thought and you
drive around now that isn't right.
Drive over here that isn't right. Bam. And
then you find it, they're like, ah man,
thanks a lot.
Right.
And they give you like a fucking,
yeah.
You waiting to see what they got you
right. Do you put some thought in?
Do you feel this way about me too?
And what do they do?
They hand you a gift certificate to
the fucking olive garden. You know,
it's like you fucking
asshole. How, you know,
I drove all over fucking
town and you just, you just,
and not even a good restaurant. That's
an, that's another thing too. Um,
if somebody gives you a gift certificate
to a restaurant, don't fucking go.
Don't even fucking go.
All right.
What sort of respectable restaurant
gives out gift certificates?
You know what I mean? That's, that's
just like one step above fast food.
You know what Douche bag of the week is?
Anybody who goes out and does Christmas
shop and it just gets a bunch of fucking
gift certificates. Hey you go, you fucking
figure out what you want is some money.
Why don't you just come in and take a
fucking handful of cash and throw it on
the floor,
like have some goddamn whore and watched
me crawl around on my hands and knees
picking it up. You know, like I
just gave you a bad lap dance,
but you got enough money to not bitch to
management. Hey, you'll have the really,
that's what I get is have fucking hundred.
Don't spend it all in one place.
All right,
you fucking cheap bastards.
I'm talking to you and you and you just
gotta be at least three people on this
podcast that do that shit.
You fucking tight fucks.
Right?
And then what do you do?
You gather up all your nice gifts that
people put thought into and you just,
you know, walk out of the house. You
know, you don't give a fuck, right?
Fuck it. Right. It's
just the drinking water.
We can pour the shit in there.
Well that kept me the corner office.
I swear to God,
if somebody gets me a fucking
gift certificate this weekend,
I'm going to do some of the not, this is
Christmas this weekend. Five days away.
Yeah, it'd be Saturday. I'm going to take
that fucking thing. Oh, thanks a lot.
And I'm going to slice the
juggler like James Bond level,
fucking paper cut and just watch that
blood right off the side of the fucking
neck. All right, so you
learned something about me.
You already knew I was an angry son of
a bitch, but I hate gift certificates.
I can't stand them.
I would rather get an ugly sweater
from an older relative then.
Then, then a fucking gift certificate.
That's just, you know, he did.
That's just the fucking tap out.
You know shorty,
man, it'd be really busy. Oh really? Oh,
I've been laying in a hammock all year.
You Lazy. Fuck no, you don't give a shit.
Why am I such a fucking Dick?
Somebody I knew every year would get me
a fucking gift certificate and you know,
I should have just gave it
right back to them. I never did.
I always gave him a nice gift thinking,
Nah, you're gonna, you're going to notice,
right? Nothing. Nothing.
Oh, we shit. All right. There you go.
This your first ran for the week to them.
Make you feel better. I'd like
to hear the why. Why do I have,
why don't have a podcast
where I give thanks.
I give thanks to everyone who came
out to my shows this year. You know,
I give thanks to the universe for allowing
me to fuck up enough in my personal
life to bless me with an
a new hour of material.
I've got to tell you, man, my fucking act
is right where I needed to be. And, uh,
my next Gig is until, uh, the
weekend, I believe of January 13th.
Um,
I'm going to be in Atlantic city with a,
this is the show. Jim Norton put this
thing together. It's Jim Norton, myself,
Jim Breuer, and David tell all on
one show. All right, the Miami Heat,
the Mount Rushmore, if you
will, of a, of standup,
a standup comedy. I can't see Mount
Rushmore. That'd be all time. Great.
So let's go with Miami Heat.
All right,
let's go with that. How about we say
that? So anyways, that's my next show.
So I have this weird thing
where I'm off for like a month,
but I also have to stay sharp.
So my girls all excited that I have a
month off and I'm actually doing a show
tonight
and I was trying to tell her that I,
I have to stay sharp, you
know, I got to stay on my toes.
I can't just sit around
fucking roasted chestnuts.
Does anybody do that anymore?
That anybody ever had a chestnuts?
Chestnuts roasting on an open fire,
Jack Frost nipping at your news.
There's no internet or
fucking cell phones,
so we have to talk to one another.
Um,
all right. What, you know,
something, something I mentioned,
they're actually tied into something
that somebody was talking about. Oh,
they were talking about die hard fans.
I'm talking about sports here.
Somebody said a bill,
just like the Yankees,
the Celtics purchased the last
championship with Kevin Garnett.
I love when people do half ass research.
You know,
didn't you forget a couple other
guys that we also bought? Um,
it's not, it's not even the purchasing
of Garnette that bothers me.
It's the delusion Boston's fans have
when they cheer for Garnette that
motherfucker kissed the shamrock
in the center of the court.
Like it was his homecoming,
like he was from Boston.
Like he yearned for playing for that
team and Boston's fans ate that shit up.
Totally bought into that shit.
Uh,
when in actuality it was just
another purchase for a championship.
How do you feel knowing your
fellow Bostonians got duped? Uh,
the bowl shifts fan base I see in
Boston makes me want to puke in my soup.
And it happens in a bunch of
other cities to, uh, sorry, I,
I can't read out loud and I'm also
reading this at a fucking angle.
Let's get some fucking stomach cancer
here. Put the laptop here. Uh, where was,
where was I, I you have die
hard fans for all your teens,
but they're few and far in between few
and far between service. How you say that?
Uh,
then you have just a bunch of stragglers
who suddenly come out of the woodwork
when their teams on top.
I live in New York and now in La,
in the past eight years I've
noticed an influx influx of pats,
fans and both of those cities.
All of a sudden everyone is
proud to be a patriots fan. Uh,
where were these fucks in the 90s?
Same goes for Laker fans.
Where would those assholes with
the flag on the car asked uh,
with the flag in the car?
Assholes in the 90s explained this to me,
Bill and go ahead and shit on as
many front running New Yorkers,
Los Angelenos in Miami, schmucks
all you like. Yeah. Yeah. Dude.
You're basically explaining uh, yeah,
that's how it works.
Yeah.
Where were all the Yankee
fans in the 80s exactly.
You can't say where were all the patriots
fans in the 90s because once we got
bill Parcells,
everybody jumped on board.
And then when Pete Carroll came in after
parcels fucked us that fat fuck that
fat fuck Egomaniac who never won a
championship without bill Belicheck as his
defensive coordinator. Who is you
will be to cook to do, do you go,
there'll be buy the groceries.
He says that right before our Superbowl
puts his fucking house up for sale.
What a cunt fucking were overrated bill.
Parcells if you want your uniforms
changed and you want to make it to the
playoffs, he's your guy. But if you
want to win the Super Bowl, you got,
you better have bill Bella check on
your staff. All right, yet I yeah,
you Bandwagon Fence Bandwagon fans are,
are uh,
the majority of the fan base.
There's no reason to build
stadiums as big as they are.
If they're actually talking about diehard
fans, you'd only need like a one level,
you know, you could have those old school
like high school stadiums, you know,
with a wind whip through the end
zones. Uh, yeah, absolutely. That's,
everybody is guilty of
that. And, um, basketball,
I hate to say it has followed what the,
uh,
what baseball has been doing,
where you just sort try to buy the,
buy the championship every year
and it's really a free agency.
I guess it's kind of the player's fault.
You know what it was,
it was an overcorrection.
It was before free agency,
you know, the owners were
like the owner in, um,
what does that call the perfect stallion?
What the fuck's that?
I can never mean Robert Redford movie,
the natural perfect stallion.
How the fuck did I get?
I can't remember. Shit.
I can never remember the names
of actors in movies. So I just,
whatever the first thing I think of,
I just fucking throw it out there. Uh,
the natural, yeah, the owners
were like that. They totally
fucking owns you. And um,
that's why the fucking white sox
through the world series in 1919,
that's what opened the door to that is
they were getting so underpaid and they
were scumbag pieces of shit.
Those two fucking thanks. Um,
so that free agency came around
and now there's been like a total
overcorrection.
Um,
and the players are seem to be completely
in control and they can just all pile
on one fucking team. I don't know. I
don't like it. I don't like it. Yeah.
The Celtics bought the championship.
Abso-Fucking-Lutely uh, but you know,
it's one of those deals. What are
they supposed to do? That's what the,
the Lakers were buying them too. You
know, what are we supposed to do?
Sit back and watch them by all these
fucking championships and we're not
supposed to go out and purchase one.
You know,
Coby Brian sitting out
there can't win shit.
So they buy him Shaq and Phil Jackson.
Fucking Gary Payton,
Robert Henri fucking Malone.
Who else? I don't watch hoop. Every time
I turn it on, there's another fucking guy,
the guy who beat up the crowd,
Ron, our test, that guy. What?
What, what, what the fuck are the
Celtics supposed to do? You know,
it'd be nice if they all sat down and
just said, look, this is fucking stupid.
Let's go back to the way it was. But I
just think that that's the way it is.
So anyways, yeah, they just pile on.
I think Garnette kiss the floor because
he was sick of playing in Minnesota and
he knew we finally had a chance to,
uh,
to win a championship after be in the
fucking guy for all those years out there
in Minnesota and always coming up short.
So I don't know.
I don't fucking, I don't know. I don't
know shit about basketball, but yeah,
you're basically yet diehard fans,
diehard fans hang in there. But uh,
I even think diehard fans of full of Shit,
there's a couple that will
actually sit there. Come on man.
You're going to be honest with you.
I'm a die hard fan.
Your team is going to end 14. You're
actually sitting down watching that shit.
You know, sometimes you such a die hard
fan, you can't go. You can't watch,
you know, I didn't watch the Celtics. I
went to a Celtics game the year before.
We bought all those guys
to win a championship. We
played the Toronto Raptors.
I had like court side fucking seats and
I almost fell asleep and it was just sad
looking at the parquet floor and looking
at the shamrock and just seeing it was,
it was, you know, it was hard to watch.
That doesn't mean I don't love
the Celtics, but you know,
sometimes you got to look away and
you know what, you fucking cunt,
you do the same thing. Stuck. Act
like you're all high and mighty.
You just hate the Patriots and
you're sick of seeing them.
Be honest with yourself.
All you sports fans,
who the fuck ever saw anybody in a sports
bar with the New Orleans Saints Jersey
on ever 30 years of watching football?
I never fucking saw it.
And then last year there's like a whole
gang of them going, who dat? Who Dat?
Who Dat? They going to beat
them saints. It's like,
where the fuck did you guys come from?
The sates were borderline.
They will like an expansion
franchise for like 40 years.
They couldn't even afford a
kicker with two whole feet.
They had a kicker with one and a
half fucking feet. That's, that's,
that's how fucking broke those guys were,
you know,
then they brought that football out there
with the helium in there so they could
have a feel good story.
Oh, by the way, um,
did you see how the jets,
when they got busted for cheating,
that fucking fag on the jets go with
the Patriots are doing it to that right
there is known as a pulling
a Coby when you do that shit.
That's called the shack
fucks around on his wife too.
You know when you're down at the
police dude, you don't ever do that.
All right.
When you get busted for some shit,
you go into mister blonde mode,
you shut your fucking mouth and
you'd do your God damn time.
You don't start dragging other people in.
It was so passive aggressive.
I'm not trying to get anybody
in trouble. I've just, you know,
if you just look at the tape,
I mean it's all there,
which was such a stupid, there's no
rule against lining up people there.
You can stand on the sideline,
you can all stand there doing
hand stands if you want.
That's not what he got
busted for your green cunt.
He got busted for sticking
your fucking knee out
evidently on purpose.
How wrong was,
I tried to be nice last week and I
defended that Douche and it turns out, uh,
I dunno.
I like how they tried to act like that
was his decision and his decision alone.
That guy actually, he shut that guy.
The strength and conditioning coach.
That guy a solid guy. Cause he just, he
took, he took the blame for that one.
The strength and conditioning
coach. He the only guy, he's,
he's the guy like as far as moneymakers,
he's just above a fucking cheerleader and
he's saying like, he's on the sideline.
Hey listen guys, everybody fucking
line up the private over there.
They're blaming the private, you
know, give me a fucking break.
But I think sticking his knee
out was definitely his decision.
But as far as lining up on, on, on the
side, I don't give a fuck. So I love it.
So the jets cheated and this week the
panthers had somebody get up and drills,
drill, someone coming down the sidelines.
See this is what it's all coming out.
I love it.
After all these years of people saying
the Patriots and cheaters like no one
else is doing it.
Like the Yankees weren't all taken
fucking roids [inaudible] along with the
fucking red.
Everybody cheats.
You guys watch that 30 for 30 on Smu
and how the entire southwest conference
football was played.
I hate to say it during the week of
Christmas, but there's no Santa Claus.
Everybody fucking cheats.
Everybody Cheats Booboo, booboo.
What song is that?
Remember that from fucking sesame street.
Everybody sleeps and they'd show like
turtles sleeping and you'd sit there
almost tearing up, not even knowing what
the fuck you were crying about. You know,
cause you already knew it.
You could sense it even as a six year old
that the world was going to be full of
a bunch of selfish cons. Hey,
you know something? I have
a video for you this week.
How many fucking agonizing minutes am I
into this podcast? 22 fucking minutes.
Jesus Christ.
I gotta be honest with you
people sometimes this podcast
is easy and other times
I feel like I'm shoveling.
What snow. And uh,
this is one of these times I feel
like I'm shoveling. What fucking snow?
Uh, I'm sick of talking about football. I
can't talk about it any fucking more. Uh,
thank you to a Green Bay,
Wisconsin though I do want to say thank
you for that Christmas gift for allowing
us to win that game that we
shouldn't have one yesterday.
And do you guys realize,
actually bet the Patriots after telling
you guys all given 14 and a half fucking
points,
I bought into the hype.
You know what a moron all year. I've been
saying, I hate our fucking difference.
Our defense, let's up 24 to
30 points every fucking game.
We have two good weeks in a row.
I even said last week on the podcast,
you think I'm buying into this shit.
Like we're going to win a super bowl.
You don't just play two good games in
a row and fucking wipe out 11 bad ones.
And after say an all of that,
what do I do?
I fucking bet the Patriots because
they're fucking quarterback was out.
And I'm a fan of Lsu. I don't ever
remember that guy fucking doing anything.
You know what it was that guy played
at Lsu right before started watching
college football. But my experience of
watching Lsu is they have fucking, uh,
they always have two quarterbacks,
a white dude and a black dude.
And they should, they just sorta, I
don't know what they though. They just a,
they just switch them off and it's not
the same guys every, every fucking year.
They got a new white dude, new
black dude, and they just, uh,
put the white guy in there. I
used too fucking white. Look at,
I'm taking that sec sick. The
black guy in there. Jesus Christ.
He won't stand in the pocket.
Get the white guy back in there.
I'll tell you if they could somehow
Amalga just stick those two guys together.
Add it probably wouldn't work.
I know it worked for Paul Mccartney
and Michael Jackson when they sang that
fucking song.
Was that one of the worst songs ever?
Wait a minute. Was that him who
sang? Ebony and ivory. Okay.
That was them, right. I was thinking
of Eddie Murphy and he made it.
Stevie wonder and Frank Sinatra.
That was the sketch. Yeah.
Was that one of the
worst fucking songs ever?
Ebony and a movie.
Somebody looked at the piano and just
came up with that corn ball shit.
You know what I mean? It's like, yeah,
we all want everybody to get along,
but do you have to try to make
us throw up in the process?
Okay.
Why is happy shit so nauseated?
Can anybody explain that to me during
the week of fucking Christmas, you know?
Okay.
What is it about watching like a kid
trip and fall and start crying and then
looking for his mother? What is it about
that that's so fucking funny. Okay.
You know when they get up and they're
crying so bad that they're not even making
any noise.
Yeah.
It just fucking makes me laugh.
You know,
watching my dog gets so excited
that it wants to go outside and,
and it goes to make us quick.
You know,
fucking Barry Sanders cut and its legs
front legs go up from underneath them and
I hear him hit his jaw off the floor,
gets up and fucking does that
little Harlem shake to try to,
it's just fucking funny.
I don't know what it is.
Maybe because I grew up watching
the three stooges. I don't know why,
but watching, uh, watching
people fuck up makes me smile.
What is wrong with me? I really am
destined to be alone. Um, all right,
speaking of Christmas, um, last
week I made the mistake of,
I told you I bought a different kind of
Christmas tree for the holiday season.
Whoop de Doo be Doo. Um, I dunno,
the past couple of years just
to, just to, you know, for,
for new listeners this week, you know,
I don't know what happened. I just,
I at last couple of years I went there
and I looked at these Christmas trees and
they would like,
they will like symmetrical and
there would be like, you know,
six inches a tree trunk and then they'd
have like these perfectly level branches.
I just thought they look bad ass like
that Japanese gardens sorta zen look and
shit. And I loved it and I thought
that, you know, I thought, you know,
I knew I was going to get shit,
but I thought at least a couple of
people would come out of the woodwork and
dare to break fucking tradition.
Let's read some of these, uh,
these uplifting comments here. Uh, Bill,
this guy tried to write day
yum and he spelled damn yum,
da m y u m damn yum bill.
That is Charlie Brown's tree.
Looks more like an
anorexic Lohan then thrown.
All Right, Nice Tree Dick. And
he see, this is what it's like.
You guys want to get into entertainment.
This is what you get all week.
This is pretty much the tone. Every once
in a while, a great special. I loved it.
But other than that, that tree makes
the peanuts crew look like ballers.
I would rather decorate my coat rack
then that's Skank shrub Jesus Christ.
Somebody wrote,
this is the soundtrack to that tree.
I don't get Internet in this
fucking room for some reason,
so I can't click on that. Uh,
looks like a used up toilet brush.
Uh, it looks like the tree, the tree,
the three stooges would have thrown other
picture up when you throw the lights
on it. Oh look at that. And I
liked that one. That's a twofer.
Made Fun of the fucking tree and
made fun of my bare walls. Um,
yeah. People, you got a glimpse of how I
live my life. This is why I'm debt free.
I enjoy enjoying your credit card
debt. You can't, I know how to live.
I buy a Christmas tree. I can
actually afford. All right. Uh, yeah,
you probably should have got the other
tree. What are you a fag? I like it.
I wanted a Charlie Brown tree.
I was going to buy a real tree
and cut off half the branches.
So it was like Charlie Brown tree and my
girl went out and bought one herself so
she could say it's hers and
I can't cut it up. Okay.
It's like I was kind of
like kind of on my side.
So what does that 20 against one for me?
Looks like a cell phone tower in disguise.
Jesus. I'm getting killed
here. All right. Uh,
let me see something. Everybody's
just going, Charlie Brown on me here.
What do we got? Do it. I was
generally excited to see your tree.
Where did you pick it out? What'd you
pick it out? Champ. Fucking Afghanistan.
And it actually looks like something
that would grow out of the soil in
Hiroshima. No, seriously. I'm Grad.
Glad you're going out of the ordinary with
the tree this year. Good. Good for you.
But I had no idea trees
could get hepatitis.
Merry Christmas. Oh look who's here. Nia.
Everybody is agreeing with you.
You want to come on the podcast?
Wait a second, let me, uh, let me
get your mic up here. Here you go.
Hi. Hang on, hang on, hang on.
Let me make sure you're real good.
Just talking Christmas, everybody. There
you go. Talk a little more. All right,
happy holidays. All right. Um, would
you like to hear some of these comments?
They all agree with you about the tree,
about the tree of the holiday season.
Boy, uh, maybe I should have known what
to expect when you scribed the tree,
but I didn't expect that. No offense,
but that just looks awful, man.
I have to admit that that one
hurts more than, than people who,
somebody said it looked
like a cell phone tower.
Like those ones are actually funny.
This guy that that was,
that one came from the heart.
That would really was a, well,
I'm a fucking termite and even I wouldn't
take a shit on that fucked up tree.
Jesus. Wow. Sweet tree.
Not, oh yeah. No. You know what that is?
That's like from a fucking anthrax fan
who's like fucking 48 now and has three
kids.
That's from like a Wayne's world.
Then they always used to say that not
the first time I saw not was anthrax.
That guy had it shaved into his
chest. The word, not an OT. Yeah,
the guy who then eventually shaved his
head. You know those guys who go bald,
they're always like Harry, like apes,
the guy, the guy who was on that,
that VH one show where they
had the super group. Oh, uh,
yeah, aunt. He had the long
beard. Yeah, the long beard,
but just the long beard. Yeah,
I know who you're talking about.
I forget what his name is.
That meant when I shaved my head because
I'm losing my hair and you maybe you
should fucking a girl that you loved
the shame and love it when you had this
shaved head. I say bring it back. Well,
I think nature is going to
bring it back for me, but well,
it's good to know that
you still look good.
Well he knows I can't do the fucking
Rogaine Propecia shit. I just can't. I,
I just know. I know how it works in
life. You don't get your cake and eat it.
Nature's going to get ya. You want
to keep your fucking hair. Okay.
Why don't we just fucking take
a shot to your goddamn liver.
Those people are gonna lose their livers.
You know, they're full heads of hair.
What did I walk into here?
I thought we were talking about the tree.
The anorexic tray. Yes. So if
you've done any Christmas shopping,
let's do quick little interview.
I get the people all caught up with you.
Have you? Uh, look at that tree. I think
the tree looks fucking cool as hell.
It's not the Charlie Brown tree.
You fucking asshole. Wait a minute.
The symmetrical to Charlie Brown tree
was all brown. Look, all you guys,
you have to take a picture of the
tree now that it's decorated though,
because I think there's a debate.
It looks like a fucking fucking Broadway
singer with aids because it's all
glitter and skinny. What a
lot of them died of that. Oh,
they do? They do dress flashy. You need
to stop like, well, I'm not saying that.
I agree with that.
I'm saying that that's what they would
write out for everything offensive. They,
I'm not saying I agree with it.
It's just how it is.
Fucking dirt bag.
Oh,
I saw that movie and the band played on.
Right.
I don't remember any guys friends.
I don't mind any guys driving garbage
trucks holding their other garbage truck
boyfriend rocking them slowly.
It's not only gay people who can't.
I know it's that. It's that and
truck drivers. Let's move on.
It's Christmas so I know it is.
No,
let's talk about aids and let's talk
[inaudible] I play now. Come on.
This is fucking hilarious. I never
saw me. It was a long time ago.
I know how the car did the song go?
I don't know. There was a song. Yeah.
Where are you asking me about Christmas
shopping? Wasn't it about San Francisco?
Isn't that where they basically don't
know and Harvey milk came in and then that
other guy shot him in the head
or is that a different milk milk.
Oh you want to Sean Penn. Can I
show you the most? I can't even,
I won't even show this to
cause I love you too much.
Somebody sent me a youtube video.
You guys have ever stopped
you showing me horrific pain.
This is why you don't get
affection. I try to be. I did.
I tried to give it to you and you slap it
down. Look at that. What's, what do we,
what do I got to replay?
What just happened there?
I said I'd love to show this to you
and, but it hurts you to, uh, you know,
I'd love you to whatever the fuck. Nice
thing I just said he don't even remember.
Anyway, it's two seconds ago,
but I meant it. All right.
There's a movie called Feast.
This is going to be on the [inaudible]
podcast where you guys feel free to go on
their trash. My fucking Christmas
tree. I like it. I'm sticking.
But you know what this is like,
this is like the new kid who comes to
school and you guys all pick on him and I
befriend him cause I'm stronger. I can
step outside the group. Look at me.
I'm the hero.
It's just a tree and I'll fuck you.
All right. The movie, there's
a movie called a feast. Yeah.
Have you ever heard of that movie?
Okay. I don't know what's going on.
I can't, I don't want to, oh, that's my
phone. What is your cell phone sound like?
The tornado drill from the 50.
It's
cause you know what is this? No, there's
no good ring tones. You know what? Go Go,
go get the a, you know what? I'll let my
podcast listeners decide the rink. Tom,
go grab my phone if you don't
mind. All right. All right.
And I'm going to describe this fucking
thing while while you're up. Okay.
There's this, this, this movie out there.
Feast that I have to rent.
I don't know what's going on,
but there is a woman tied down and this
beast that looks like a little person
that was a skinned alive
basically comes out of nowhere.
And
Fox,
this woman in the mouth and
finishes there. I said it,
I said it and it happened so fast.
I didn't even think that it was real.
And uh,
I dunno.
That's when I have to ask.
It's like you're not
really trying to scare me.
You're just trying to either gross
me out or make me fucking laugh.
But if you really want to get grossed out,
um,
here's another youtube video of the week.
Somebody sent one in.
I only got like two minutes into
this thing and I had to shut it off.
Human cryogenics. All right,
so if you guys, you know,
isn't that funny?
I told her to go pick up my phone.
She goes and answers it and now I
was talking to the person, you know,
what would you broads be doing if you
weren't running? You fucking yaps.
You know I, it's like I
don't understand. They just,
they just have to be talking.
All right, whatever. So human
cryogenics, red sox fans,
we're all familiar with that.
You know what I mean?
Ted Williams head,
I believe is upside down sitting on a
tuna can and they accidentally broke his
nose.
I'm talking about Ted Williams.
They froze. Do you believe in a
pick up the microphone. Oh God,
you're going to be eaten on the podcast.
You know,
I think this is good that you're on
the podcast. It's, it's, you know,
it's the holidays. It should, it
should be family here, but some people,
some people don't like my Christmas
tree to look. First of all,
the Internet is like a,
you know,
like when you hang up those
lights to track bugs, Zap them.
That's what the Internet is
for. [inaudible] you know
what I mean? They, yeah,
they just gravitate towards it.
All these miserable fucks who have all
the power in the world to change their
life and live the wonderful life that
we're living on this fucking bed without a
headboard. I've been trying, you know,
somebody trashed us because we don't have,
we don't have any pictures on the wall.
I'm trying to teach people how to live a
minimalist debt free life. First of all,
we don't need pictures on the wall.
We have a picture on the
wall that bill hates.
We have the live pictures get way
too fucking intimate but women.
But we have a picture above the
fucking bed of it. Looks like.
I thought you've talked about
this venture. You have. I
talked about it. All right,
well I already brought it up.
Yeah.
It's like every time I look
up there's another deer.
Can't see it and it's staring
right into the fucking Lens.
It's not black and white.
It's not in color. It's Sorta
in that Blair witch look.
It's kind of a Sepia town. I fucking
hate it. And you know something.
I know you hate him. Yeah. And I,
whoa. I almost fell in between seats.
We need a headboard. How much
just fell off the back of the bed.
But I'd like personally like to point
out the fact that you went out and just
bought that fucking photo. Yup, I
did. And hung it. Right. Look at that.
And you just hung it right over the bed?
Yeah. How can we didn't ask me about it?
I don't know. I just thought
it would be nice. Really.
What if I get a poster
of fucking Larry Bird?
He played for the Celtics and he used
to do this thing where he would always
wipe the sweat off the side of his feet.
So I'm going to get that.
So it looks like one of his fucking
blonde balls is going to fall out of my
shorts and I'm going to
hang that over the bed.
I don't want to see how
fucking long that lasts. Um,
I just wanted to say that we have a
mantle and there's pictures all over the
mantle of all of our fans. Those are the
pictures we have. You know what this is?
This is hilarious how innocent you are
with the Internet. What do you mean
you don't defend your position?
All you do doing now is prolonging the
arguments and now they'll do like really
do, why don't you put a picture
up of him if you have them?
Cause they just want more
material to trash you,
but they haven't even seen our apartment.
Who are they to say anything? Exactly.
I'm not, I'm just saying what
you're doing is, it's like what?
Someone trashes you fucking white.
You're legs are, I know. It's great.
I just take them out in a job interview
and I get it. So He'd go, you just agree.
Absolutely. Whatever. Yeah, I'm horrible.
I look like a puppet. Absolutely.
You're 100% and it kills it. That's what
Madonna's done. You're a fucking whore.
I know. You want to see my twat. Check
out my new book. I got it all over there.
I got a close up.
Didn't she take an a in that book?
She took a close up of her fucking hoo
ha. I don't think so. Yeah, she did.
I think she was fully nude, but there
wasn't a closeup I that wasn't that book.
No, the sex book. What book
was that? I don't know.
I don't think he was a little red wagon.
What was the last book that I
read? That book was, uh, my,
I think was my favorite work by Madonna
and I thought it was their most honest
work. You know who's standing out there
on the street looking like a fucking
prostitute. Exactly.
Exactly. She looked good.
She looked phenomenal.
She looked really good and still
banged that fucking cougar.
You know what I hate?
You know what I love is that she's
gotten all their varicose veins.
Fucking minutes stuff. I was just
going to talk about that, cause she's,
everyone always talks about her
arms are so veiny. It's so gross.
But you know what?
Madonna works out every day and that's
blood pumping through those veins.
You can see life. That's what those
veins are. It's very inspirational.
Yeah. She, you know, she's
like, she's like somebody who,
you know, she's no, you
know what she's like,
she's like Clint Eastwood in that
movie. Gran Torino. Torino. Yeah.
I'd never been named the car, the grant
and the grand jury duty year fresh.
I know that. Oh, I forget to get off
my lawn. Is that, what's the word?
I can't remember. Yeah, but then
I would say all racist Shit,
which people won't get that.
I'm making fun of the movie and I'll
think I believe it. Well that's what he,
that's what he did in the movie.
He was racist anyway around.
Oh yeah. Cause it's a Hollywood movie.
Wow. Because it's a holiday movie.
Listen. Yes. Grant Torino that, that's,
that's how she's treated like
the way he treated that car.
That's where she's treating a body. Her
body is like in fucking mint condition.
It is, you know, and all the
rest of us, what do we do?
We fucking back into a car and I'll
worry about it. Slammed into a tree.
That's how we treat our bodies.
Doesn't settle for second. Yeah.
She's out there wax in it.
Oil Balls to the wall,
not the whole fucking old
school shit this week.
So, uh, yes. I did go Christmas
shopping to answer your
dude, go Christmas shopping.
I have a little bit.
What did you get me?
I'm not telling you what the surprise
you'll find out on your shirt.
You know what sucks about being a guy is
the last time you get a good gift is I
think when you're 11, the second you
turn 12, you start becoming an adult.
Maybe he gets to Mike Electronic Shit.
You know,
you just go into that, that
phase. We get shirts and uh,
uh, organizers. This is a place
to put your wallet, Your Keys.
I actually fucking love that.
You know,
that's really unnecessary.
Perfect casting, getting trashed. Here's
the perfect pushups. Merry Christmas.
I'm fucking with you. Got me great gifts.
You have first year I was with you.
You got me the drum sticks with my,
my initials engraved in them.
That was fucking adorable as those were
great. That was cute. That was adorable.
This was when, obviously bill and I
were first, what are we doing here?
Too much of a life.
Let's get back to the podcast here.
That was when we were talking about our
social security numbers that are seven,
nine, eight, four. That
was what I thought. I
you brought it up. I'm trying to get
you to stop talking about it. Fine.
All right, let me see if I've got a
question here that you can actually answer
or you can add to. I don't think
I have anything. You know what?
This fucking podcast. Oh Shit.
Then I shut it off. I didn't,
did I please tell me I didn't. All
right, we're up to 42 minutes. Um,
so listen. Yes, I, uh,
I got an offer for a corporate
gig on the day after Christmas
and,
uh,
Eagle Rock and I was wondering
if I can go do it. No,
please. First of all, I have to
fucking lie. All right. Second of all.
No, I'm just fucking with
you. You always get mad at me.
You want to do fucking work?
You know what? This, this
whole fucking podcast just,
I just forgot I was even doing the
podcast and I'm just sitting here watching
you eat oatmeal. You have
any closing comments? I got,
I got to bring this home with some
funny here. Do you got anything?
Anything you want to say? Oh, let's
talk about how I hurt my foot.
Making fun of you fucking ex. I mean, oh
yeah. I made fun of her exercise tapes.
She,
she's in there like grunting and groaning
doing this fucking exercise tape.
And I walk in there and it said to Bob
from the biggest loser with is shredded
head. He like has like, he's,
he works out too much.
Like he actually,
you know the cuts people
want when they get abs,
he has them on either
side of his forehead.
His head is shredded,
he's in great shape.
CVDS are no fucking kids.
So she sits there and she starts telling
me how his Biz DVDs are hard and all
that. I was like, fuck that guy. I
can do that Goddamn DVD. I'll be fine.
Typical man. Right. And then what happens?
I go to stretch before I do it because
I'm 42 years old and you're like, oh,
you don't need to stretch you as this
whole at thing. And He fucking didn't.
And I ended up screwing up my foot again.
They're stretching in the beginning.
Yeah, that's bullshit. He didn't didn't
into any stretches for your back.
Nothing.
Nothing to stretch out your feet.
And then the guy has the
fucking fucking jumping.
I got Bill Walton feed at
this point. I can't do that.
God Damn Video. Bill Walton.
Bill Walton was a big fucking redhead who
smoked weed in college and hung around
John Wooden. And then all he does
is try to, like John Wooden was,
was this amazing coach who gave you all
this life advice and he's trying to be
John Wooden junior always giving out
advice, always telling those stories.
And he has this awful
fucking voice that's like,
it comes from the center of his head
and goes out as fucking broken nose.
I mean,
ugh.
Fucking redheaded Frankenstein.
Well in the midst of that workout when
there was all that stuff going on with
the back,
I was like,
why don't you stop and just kind of
do an alternate version of it and you
wouldn't do it because you're a
typical man and you have to see like,
I can do anything. You know what? I
just love that you say a typical man,
lump us all in and then give me shit
when I talk about all the broads.
You've always done that.
I always have done that and I don't have
a problem with you saying that guys are
hard headed because we are.
We're fucking morons and you guys goes,
you guys are psychos.
All right.
We're emotional but doesn't mean I don't
like you. The key buzz fucking Bandana.
What do you think about that? Oh,
t buys right from that fucking,
what's the name of that group
now was going to sound like,
how long is it going to take you
to get the name of that bill?
Never remembers the name. Crazy sexy.
Cool. Was the name of their album.
Don't go chase.
I thought they were saying
don't go Jason waterfalls.
And I didn't know what that meant. I was
like is that some sort of hip hop slang?
Who's Jason? Is that like a,
why does he like waterfall?
How to he like one fucking
you fucking get the oatmeal.
You just spit out of your mouth. Oops. Um,
now what was the name of them? TLC. Yeah,
you go and uh Oh left
die cause I his ride.
Oh Shit. What is this? Oh that's why she,
that's why she called herself left.
Done. Cause what? Cause I is right.
At least that's how she explained it.
I know what they said.
Why do you have that thing under your uh,
your left eye or so she had something
on her fucking face and she said,
cause I is right. And I
was like, Oh put a count,
you know right there or cause she's dead.
I'm not supposed to say that.
When she was alive, she probably wasn't
difficult to be in a relationship with.
Wasn't she the one who burned down
that guy's fucking house? Yes.
She didn't go to jail because she has a
vagina. She went to jail. Are you done?
Went to jail for that. How
long? I don't know. Exactly.
Internet and look it up instead of just
one of those things where you end up
being wrong. Well you ended up
being wrong and you're proven wrong,
so you just fucking gorilla your way
through it like you just said. Yeah,
that's what I'm saying. She did
go to jail bell. Look it up.
I'm not going to look.
They forced her ass to go to Rehab
because she was an alcoholic on top of it
anyway, with the, why are you saying
it like she's some sort of a victim?
She burned out so he please keep
them Mike in front of your mouth.
He didn't say that she was a victim.
I did not say that he gave her the out
cause she was an alcoholic. No, I didn't.
Yeah, you guys, you guys are always
every the whole, your whole fucking life.
You just giving excuses.
That's why you guys,
that's why you can't do as many pushups
as a guy has nothing to do with your
mothering hips.
It has to do with the fact
that you fucking get to tee
off 20 yards in front of
me and still get the gift,
the same fucking score.
What does the c stand
for and Tlc? Uh, let's,
I don't know what to the
TL stands for. Yes, you do.
Tender loving care.
Is that what it stands for?
They're the names of the girls in the
group. All right. There was chilly.
I got Chili. There's left die and then
this t boss. Hey Cow. Yeah. Got It.
There you go. Go ahead. Quiz
me on some more pop culture.
It can be a little pop coke culture
quiz here. I'll fucking, I'll bury it.
Go ahead. Do it. Ah.
Can you name all the members of now
you can't go ahead. New Edition.
Absolutely gone. Bobbi Brown, uh,
Jerome Robinson, the trails. Spreewell
and a Nipsey Russell. I was, no, he
was a manager. He was the manager.
I wish that opens the group.
No, but I know here it is.
Horrible. That's my, a humble ring.
I'll give me a fucking break. What the,
would you want to hear my one here?
My options. Give me another group.
Why don't you pick a white group
so I could actually get it?
New Kids on the block. New
Kids on the, although they
had all those gay names. Joe,
we'd Bobby Stevie,
Mikey in pooky.
Huh? Can you feel it
baby? I can feel it too.
It was Marky mark stealing the licking
the lips thing from ll cool j Marky mark
and who else?
And the funky bunch.
I remember those guys a feel it.
Feel it.
Okay.
Oh, it was horrible music. What was the
spinoff group from new edition? A bell.
Biv. Devoe. Wow. What did they say?
Huh?
I remember all that Shit.
Go ahead.
Name a song by Bobby Brown when
he was solo. My prerogative.
These are a joke. Okay. Let's see. I'm
trying to give you money, right Joey?
We didn't look at my fucking shiny shoes.
What does SWV frack?
What does SWV stand for?
Sisters with voices.
You are all on your like R and B night.
You go on. All right, let me ask you,
so, okay. What's the name
of the, the maniac and ACDC.
You can't sit still for two seconds.
He run around the schoolboy outfit.
I took you to see DC. What's his saying?
No, a great performers of all time.
He's like James Brown without rhythm.
Okay.
He never stops moving
the hardest white bull.
A work in white boy and show business.
I forget. Okay. It's a kind of beef.
Okay. Angus young. There
you go. There you go.
See what should be on the fucking
$10,000 pyramid. Give me another one.
All right. Uh, name the
original lineup of Van Halen.
Name as many members as you can.
This is the white version and Halan of
new edition. Yeah. Eddie van Halen. Bang.
David Lee Roth. Good. That's half
the group. He's got a brother.
Oh, it's one of the names. A GSP
always says Michael Van Halen.
Nope. Alex video annex and zoo G
has. Do you add George Saint Pierre?
Do it. Come on at eggs. A
Jonathan Doughnut.
Then sweep the leg doughnut then Eh.
All right. Hang on a second. What else do
we got here? Where the fuck I don't care.
Oh, the ring tones. He has the ring tones
for the week. All right. I'll give you,
I'll give you another quiz. Uh,
okay. Oh, you'll get that one.
I can't even answer that one.
I was the same name.
Name the lead singer of Duran Duran.
You'll get that Simon. Labon. Sure.
MMM. Everybody I know. I don't
find the bond. All right.
We didn't get the guy from anthrax. No,
I wouldn't get that. Alright, quiz me.
Quiz me on five movies.
Then I got to end the podcast cause
I have to go do my fucking Christmas
shopping. Five movies.
Yeah. You don't want,
I'm going to get you this year once
you don't, I'm going to get you,
I'm going to get you
away. Uh, let me think.
I'm going to get you some
workout clothes, right? Uh,
maybe like a, uh, a positive CD. Okay.
A positive CD.
One of those things.
I put it on and it sounds like weather
and it helps you sleep better. Yeah.
I'm going to get you that and then
I'm going to get you some new,
a toenail clippers. Stick that
right. You're stocking. How's that?
Mantech. All right. Go ahead, quiz me
on some movies and then I'm out. Um,
names.
Talk into the mic name.
At least five actors in the movie casino.
Five actors in the movie
casino. All right. This should
be easy. It should be easy,
but I'm not good with names. All
right. Robert De Niro. Joe Pesci. Yeah.
Frank Vincent,
uh Oh.
Sharon Stone and fucking,
uh,
the guy went to MIT.
I know about his personal life. You
had a fucking insane mullet. Uh,
James Brolin.
You got James Wright.
Was that his name? James. Dear Vanderbeek.
James Vanderbeek.
What's that?
It's a picture I know of.
What? Deer in the woods.
Oh, James wants us, right? I knew of. All
right. This is just getting boring deal.
Just pouring the listening.
Do you have anything that you want to
say before I dismiss you? Happy holidays.
Everyone. Be Good to each other. Okay.
I get your oatmeal and get
out. Get Out. That's it.
Near everybody that lovely Nia coming
on the podcast once every fucking six
weeks.
Get out of here
you go. And she's leaving.
All right, there you go.
So that's a podcast for this week.
People, I know, it kind of sucked. I know.
Some of it was Kinda nice spot. Ah,
that's it. Oh, you know something. What I,
I keep meaning to fucking talk about
on this God damn podcast is I started,
somebody sent me something,
uh,
about the fucking, what the hell
did I do to my damn computer?
Let it go.
Let go of my fucking cord.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Get Out.
Hang on a second.
People fucking court is stuck in there.
Whatever.
People keep sending me this shit about.
A one person did send me
about the Liverpool soccer
club and the premier league
and evidently these American dudes bought
it and said that they were going to
buy a buy,
a brand new stadium.
They were going to do all this
type of shit and they didn't do it.
And somebody sent me this great video
of all these English people just from
their heart's telling these American
guys to fucking sell the Goddamn team and
to fuck off.
And it was awesome.
And this is the same team that the owners
of the red sox then went in and bought
and I started looking at the premiere
league and like three or four the teams
are owned by, uh, by Americans,
specifically from the United States.
All right.
Because we're all from North
America over here. Uh, and I,
I can't believe how fucking
annoying that would be.
You don't have a bunch of English guys
came over and bought my team and said
that they were going to do a bunch
of stuff and they fucked it up.
I would be beyond pissed.
Um, so I don't know.
Sorry about that. England. I don't
know why the fuck we did that.
It's nice to know where buying something.
Consider gyp.
Japan's come over here and they,
they fucking bought up everything
over the last 20 years. Didn't they?
Don't they own our roads? You know,
what are you going to do with them?
Close them off. Do you have enough people
to do that? I don't think you do. Um,
so yeah,
send me some more information on it.
Cause I'd like to talk about the
premier league and also I'm wondering in
Ireland, is that a seven nation rugby
league or whatever the fuck it is?
Is that starting up again?
Cause I watched that last year in March
when I went over there and a rugby is
the shit and a unlike
professional football,
which they're just turning into
the biggest pussy sport ever.
Isn't it enough that we were,
that they have to wear pink for the
entire fucking month of October.
You know,
now you can't tackle people.
The amount of quarterbacks out there
that are getting like Joe Montana fucking
stats because they're drive was kept
alive because a defensive person had the
audacity to tackle someone his age.
He's just fucking be on me. And uh,
I got nothing left people.
I'm not going to lie to you.
This podcast was fucking
over before it started.
I have too much shit I have to do.
All right.
I remember the first year I did this
podcast, I actually took two weeks off.
I took two weeks off. So,
you know, whatever it was
dressed down fucking Monday.
I came in. I did what I
could. All right. That's it.
That's it for the, uh, for
the podcast for this year.
Everybody right now we got one
more for this year and next weeks.
I promise you.
I promise you it will be just as bad
as this one if not fucking worse.
Cause I'm on vacation.
I'm not required to make you laugh,
but I want to thank everybody.
Seriously.
Everybody who came out to
see my shows this year,
um, I had a great time and I actually,
oh wait. You know, I know what I'm doing.
I'm missing underrated. Overrated. How
the fuck could I do that? Underrated.
Overrated. This week real
quick. Uh, overrated.
Both the jets and the Patriots. Being a
dolphin fan, born and raised in Miami.
I'm sick.
I'm sick and tired of these two faggot
teams dominating the AFC east for the
past decade. Well, it's
really been the patriots.
It was very nice of you to throw the
jets in there. I think the jets have one.
Like what? One division in the last
fucking 10 years. Um, so I get it.
Were overrated because
your team sucks. Um, hey,
did you like how while the former Dolphin
won the game for the jets yesterday?
Have bet you enjoyed that. Huh? I
hope you get a sunburn on your ass.
You fucking cunt. All right. Underrated
the bills being a dolphin fan,
born and raised in Miami.
Like you already said,
I love the bills for always keeping the
dolphins in the hunt for the playoffs
every year, the past decade and a half.
All right. That guy was just being a dick,
so I have to respect that.
Alright. Underrated. Michael Vick.
He does sports announcer voice,
uh, Michael Vick, Michael Vick.
What are one of the things you have
to understand about Michael Vick?
Is Michael Vick the MV S P of this
season? Bob, because he's my MVP.
He's making fun of me talking about
how that's all they say. Michael via.
What can you say about Michael
Vick? Well, well, Jim, Michael
Vick, um, you know what?
I have to admit I was fucking
wrong about that guy. I was wrong,
but I was also writing.
Okay. Because the same reason
I fucking fell for it by the Patriots
playing good defense for two weeks in a
row and then actually gave
up 14 and a half points,
ignoring the fact that they only played
well for two fucking weeks in a row.
You can't say that a guy's the best dude,
the fucking lead.
Cause he lights up the
Redskins and fucking three
weeks later John Kitna lights
up the fucking Redskins.
All right. But yesterday,
what happened in that game?
I mean that was unreal.
I think he went back to old school,
Michael Vick,
he just started fucking running down the
field like a God damn water bug. But uh,
I was wrong about that guy.
Um, it's way, it's funny,
he can't say he's in,
he's in like a League of his own as
far as like what the fuck he's doing.
Cause I've never seen anybody
do that shit at his position.
And I'd say that he's going
to change the position,
but I don't know the Dilla Neb ever
been another person as talented as that
fucking guy at that position.
Um, I dunno. So anyways,
he says, uh, Bill, sorry,
you have to go through another week of
that shit of everybody saying Michael
Vick. But every time I hear them talk
about thick after a big wing, no matter,
no matter what I remember about your
rant against the announcers about the
announcer's saying his name
over and over again. Um,
I say he's still underrated because he
broke two NFL records in the last two
weeks, but still can't get
any solid respect. Ah, dude.
I think he's getting his solid respect.
The fact that they're,
they're saying that he might be the MVP
of the league and he's coming off an 18
month stint in Leavenworth
for torturing dogs to death.
You know what I mean?
I definitely,
for when someone plays the fucking race
card, I always listened to it because I,
you know,
I traveled the road and I know what
people are like having talked to them,
there's just, people are fucking,
they're awful. The fucking awful.
But this is the one time where
it's like, dude, you know,
you're tortured dogs to death.
You drowned them, your shot him.
I mean straight up, straight
across the fucking board, you know,
you can't expect people to 100% Embracia
after you do some shit like that even
though you more than
paid the fucking price.
But I'd rather be you than one of
those fucking dogs. So anyways,
he said, I say underrated because he broke
two NFL records in the last two weeks,
but still can't get any solid respect.
Honestly.
As much as I hate Tom Brady,
he is the real MVP so far.
But people are still hesitant.
I don't know who the real MVP is,
but Tom Brady's having
his best fucking year. Um,
all right, this is a good one here.
Yukon women's team, 88 win streak,
overrated.
The audacity of these media pricks to
compare the Yukon's woman's team to the
UCLA team, by the way, which
was cheating by the way,
with how they got all their prospects.
For all you people who trashed the
Patriots and act like all you're fucking
winning is because you're just
such smart fucking human beings.
I want,
I'm not going to get involved and I'm
not gonna open that fucking can of worms,
but John wouldn't,
uh,
as my buddy said yesterday was the
king of looking the other way when the
boosters got involved. Okay, let's
leave it at that. All right. Of course,
it's a major accomplishment,
but as is typical with everything,
male versus female related,
people cannot put things into
perspective when it comes to females.
The woman's Yukon teams,
88 wins is in no way,
shape or form as impressive
as the UCLA teams.
88 whims wins.
I'll put it to you like this.
I used to play little league football
and got MVP three times in a row
and co MVP once,
however,
Tom Brady has won the NFL MVP,
I think once or twice,
I have a longer MVP streak than Tom Brady,
but who's MVPs are more respectable
and impressive. That's right.
Mine. Just kidding. Of course his are, um,
all right. I get that. But,
uh, do, but you're a guy and
you could play in the NFL,
but you weren't good enough.
So that's the difference I guess.
Um, as far as, I would
say that they're the Ucla,
the Ucla of women's basketball.
How about that?
You got to say that because they are going
up against the best females out there
and they have one 88 in a row.
So I would say it like that,
but to come to put it up there
with Uclas. Yeah, the men's,
I definitely think that's bullshit.
That's just the classic, uh,
you know,
it's like them wearing pink in the NFL.
It's just did you just
appeasing them? That's all the
fuck you're doing. You know?
Then I really just compare breast
cancers to like appeasing somebody.
I really should just stop talking, but I'm
just going to keep going here. Um, yeah.
As far as sports accomplishments go,
I don't think females mean as much as
men's just because we're better at it than
you are,
you know?
And we just have better hand eye
coordination. Just generally speaking,
we're just better at, you know, the
amount of guys that if you go, hey,
think quick catch and you just throw him
a stapler, they're going to catch it.
And the amount of women who would just
take it off the face and habit, Landon,
their cleavage. It's, you can't
even compare it, you know,
let's debate that next week.
I don't think females are as good
athletes as guys are. I just don't,
I don't think they are. I don't think
that they have that killer instinct. No.
Unless they're there.
They're chemically wired like a guy
and they have as much testosterone.
I don't think it's going to be a problem.
I'm just saying this to Piss people off
so I don't have to work hard next week.
Uh, I think that's it. I'll do,
I got some, uh, youtube videos,
you know, if ever I was going
to edit a fucking podcast,
it should be fucking this one.
This one is just Jesus, whatever.
Last week's was great. This
is what I am at, but you know,
this is a let down week for me. All
right, youtube, check this one out.
This is one of the creepiest ones I've
seen. And, uh, it's called the liar card.
This is a card you can put in your phone
and for people, you know, so when you're,
you're,
if people are ducking your calls,
that will show up as
somebody else's phone call.
You can disguise your voice to sound
like a woman or a man. And uh, yeah,
I guess you could find out where they
are in case you know. I don't know what,
there's another good one.
Our Danny Woodhead,
you know the fucking Allpro for the
fucking New England patriots, right?
Danny Woodhead as Modell's employees
selling his own Reebok Jersey.
He stands in a Modell's selling his
own Jersey in New England and nobody
recognizes him.
Uh,
now the youtube and these will all
be up on the [inaudible] podcast.
A the cliff Lee signing did
not make the boss happy.
This is actually a total rip off video
of a video that a yes Canadiens fan made.
Um, or someone who hated the
Canadians a year ago. Uh,
they just took this footage of somebody
playing Hitler and a movie flipping out.
Um, just know that it is a rip
off, but it's funny, I guess. Uh,
what else do I have here? I think that's
it. Is that it? That is it. All right.
All those videos will be up there.
I apologize for the Charpie podcast.
They can't all be great hour and
five minutes. And by the way,
there's some maniac out. They're
transcribing my podcasts and Mark Marin's.
Okay.
And I think Adam Carolla's and uh,
how about a round of applause for that
fucking trooper actually sat down and was
reading,
I read like three minutes of my podcast.
The guy gets like every fucking
word. God bless Ya. You, ah,
that is it. That's the podcast for this
week. You guys all have a merry Christmas.
Happy Kwanzaa. Happy Hanukkah.
Happy fuck the holidays.
If that's how you are.
Okay.
Have a good week. Don't take any
shit that's it. And Go fuck yourself.
[inaudible].