Yeah.
Hey, what's going on as Bill Byrd
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast, and
I'm just checking in on you.
You're not going to believe
what the what I just did a,
you probably will having you listen to
this thing enough to know that I'm a
fucking moron. You're not going
to believe what I just did.
What did you do bill? Well, I just
recorded the Thursday afternoon podcast.
Right.
And I forgot my cord that I usually,
I have a routine and the second I do it,
I upload it and I've done it,
but I forgot the cord, the UCB
Chord, whatever the fuck it is.
USBC fucking public bank cord.
Yeah.
Okay.
So it took me out of my routine and I
just wanted to like robot mode and I
fucking erase the podcast.
I just did.
Why would I go there? I
was so psyched. I was done.
I just came back from Boston, dude.
I came, you know, I woke up early,
I'm still on east coast time. My
beautiful daughter, lovely wife.
I was sleeping, I paid all the fucking
bills. I got everything ready to go.
All I had to do was knock out my podcast.
It's a quarter, eight in the morning.
I'm done. My kids just getting up,
I'm ready to make everybody breakfast.
I'm crushing it.
And what do I do?
Okay.
I just hit a, and I hit a race and
you know when she had her race,
she can't stop it from a racing.
And I was like going, oh my God,
what did I just do it?
It's just it gone
over.
So now the big thing is,
is I can't compete with myself
from a half an hour ago.
All right?
I can't be looking into the past and
thinking about what I talked about.
I need to go into the fucking future.
All right?
I hope you guys all had a merry Christmas.
Okay?
Have you noticed Mary
only goes with Christmas?
Do you notice that it's happy Hanukkah.
It's happy Kwanzaa.
It's go fuck yourself and it's
merry Christmas. Isn't that weird?
Mary Hanukkah.
Merry Kwanzaa.
Marry Muhammad.
What is their Christmas?
MMM,
have a merry,
merry Mohammad.
It's the best time of the
year Buddha to to dude,
I know there won't be snow
cause we're in the Middle East.
They have any moms out there.
Do people
have I ever sounded dumber
in my life? Well, you know,
considering I just recorded a podcast
and then promptly fucking erased it
properly.
Like within fucking two minutes. That's
all I'm going to do. I'm going to bitch,
Moan and complain and whine about what
I just did rather than move on with my
life. All right, setting the
tone for 2018 once again,
we're going to look back rather
than being in the moment.
That's one of my goals for 2018
is to tell somebody who tells me to
be in the moment to shut the fuck up.
And when they say, well, why? Why
did you say, Hey, I'm in the moment.
You're annoying me in this moment.
Now that moment's gone.
I'm still talking about it. Did I
not take your advice? You can't.
Can you stop acting?
Is there anything,
you know some of the most spiritual
people have the most fucked up lives?
Are you enjoying it? Did you take it in?
Did you take a moment to fucking enjoy
dating a married guy?
The fuck out of my face?
MMM.
Anyway, sorry, sorry. Whatever.
Whatever. Well, there's four minutes.
All right. Four minutes. I just, I
just got it back. Oh, guess what?
I got some big news for you.
Um,
after a 131 days of being sober,
Oh, Gja age, oh,
Billy red face fell off the fucking wagon.
Um,
I put up a good fight right through the
holidays. I made it to December 26th.
What kind of a fucking
asshole falls off on the 26th?
I could see New Year's eve. I
could, I mean, Christmas Eve,
I could see Christmas Day.
I could see New Year's Eve,
but the 26th and the history of
people falling off the fucking wagon,
who falls off on the 26? What do
you, what are you crying about?
The fact he didn't get a fire
engine the day before for Christmas?
Um, yeah, fell off.
I'm going 131 days and very
proud of myself. I, yeah,
I can definitely have. It's definitely
in the moment. Uh, this is what happened.
Um, first of all, I had,
I had the best Christmas I've had since
I was a little kid and I still believed
that some fat stranger came
down the chimney. All right.
Uh, it was awesome. And
I was actually like a,
had a lot of stress about it because
I was flying back with my lady and my
lovely daughter and I was thinking like,
oh my,
all I've ever heard is people talking
about flying back with an infant.
It's a nightmare. Everyone,
you know? Yeah. You know,
by the end you're ready to get a
divorce and all this type of shit.
I gotta tell you something.
It was the fucking best Christmas I've
had since I was like eight years old.
When did I find out there was
Jake and the fat man was bullshit.
When did they find that
out, ma? First Grade
I find out in first grade because my
older brother found out in third grade.
He quickly told me,
and I remember I wasn't mad either. I
actually felt like an adult, like, oh wow,
man, I'm in a, I'm in on the
secret. Right. So anyways,
uh, coming back with a kid ended
up being the greatest thing ever.
It just, it takes all the pressure
off for you in your relationship.
You just come back like, hey,
we did it, we got married,
we reproduced no more questions of when,
when,
when that's over.
And then the best thing too is you come
home with a toddler and all everybody
wants to do is interact with the kids.
So nobody's asking you about your life,
nobody's giving you the third, what do
you got going on? What are you doing next?
What do you think about this?
Are you sure you're going to do that?
Was that the right move?
And next thing you know,
you're fucking boozing it up and
you're all fucking depressed. Um,
or getting into arguments or talking
politics or, I don't know what,
um,
all of that was God and I,
okay.
It was just great. I came in and
he was like, how are you doing?
Oh my God, look at your daughter. Then
that was it. There was no, you know,
I got a lot of social anxiety.
Like when I go to like
parties and that type of shit,
I was always the guy up on
the wall, you know? Okay.
It's a bunch of guys sitting around
watching a game. Then I'm in my element.
But once it becomes like the social thing,
there's no game on.
And uh, I, I don't know,
there's all this fucking weirdness going
on. Look at adults are so fucking weird.
You know,
there's all this like,
yeah,
it's just like the playground
when you were a kid,
but it becomes like adult shit.
Okay.
Like a, you know, I don't
know, competing. Right.
You know,
I dunno how much you making dreams if
you getting married or whatever the fuck
you going through. It just
becomes this, all this,
there's all these storylines
that are going on.
Yeah.
Maybe that's why my wife
has always watching those,
those reality shows I guess.
Cause all of that shit that's just
going on. You know what I mean?
Of just watching people so caught
up in bullshit that, you know,
your neighbor gets a better spatular
than you and it like affects your fucking
mood.
MMM.
So anyways, so we went back there
and, uh, just watching people,
meeting my daughter and her like,
you know,
her big thing now she knows she
just waves at everybody and uh,
she could say hi now, although
she, she's yet to say it,
she looks in the mirror and says me.
And then she also says hi and I've
yet to see her do either either or.
Although this video of her saying hi,
um,
anyways,
okay.
Everybody was, you know, flip his sheet.
She, she killed it. She killed it.
She was a little starlet.
Everybody absolutely loved her and um,
her personality is really coming out.
And uh,
I got tell you what it was really fucking
crazy is like the more her personality
develops, like the more
I love her. It's crazy.
Like every time you
think he hit the ceiling,
like I could not love this kid anymore.
There's like another level and uh,
okay.
I always hate it when I didn't have
a kid and people were going like, it,
you don't get it. You don't
get it. It's like, dude, I
can't, if it's a kid, you know,
I hate to say this, but they were right.
They were right. But having said that,
I will never tell somebody they
don't get it. Who doesn't have a kid?
That's a douchey thing to see. Now.
You don't get it yet. Okay. Yeah.
Neither did Joe. All right.
Stop acting like you're smart.
All right, there's 10 minutes.
20 more minutes to go. Um,
so, uh, I don't know. It was
just so many great things.
Uh, I got together and jammed with a
couple of my brothers. We used to play,
used to butcher hair metal tunes back
in the 80s into the early nineties.
We had not gotten together and try it.
Attempted to play music in almost 24
years. And one of my brothers, uh,
rented this place. Uh, I got to give
them a shout out. It's in Somerville,
Somerville, which was known as
Slummerville when I was a kid.
Now it's all hipstery with like cupcakes
and fucking burger joints and shit.
Um, it's like an upscale thing, right?
And, uh, this place is called the jam
spot out in Somerville. Somerville Lumber,
that's all I remember from
out there. It was, uh, uh,
the jam spot was just a beautiful
clean place. Rooms were awesome.
All the equipment was the shit.
And the guy who worked there was just a,
just a great guy. Family man actually
got a kick out of the fact that a,
we were all brothers going to go down
there and play and we hadn't been playing
together and that fucking long.
We went in there and we
butchered some songs.
Sounded all right though.
Um,
and then at the end a couple more of
my relatives came down to like doing
karaoke at the end and they sang and we
actually had the place from 12 to four
in the afternoon. I remember
thinking like two, two hours,
it's going to be more than enough.
We know like six songs from almost,
you know,
a decade and a half ago.
We're going to play for about 20 minutes
and we're just going to be staring at
each other. And, um, that's
actually not what happened.
It flew by and uh,
and what we were trying to
work on a couple songs, uh,
ACDC walk all over. You touched
too much. How would it hell,
we always had that one down.
And uh,
then one of my brothers always
play Stevie Ray Vaughan.
So we played a bunch of that stuff.
And then a few more relative showed up.
Next thing you know,
we were playing Zeplin the ocean
and uh, it was, it was just,
it was fucking awesome.
And then after that,
that's when we went out
and got a steak and a,
one of my other relatives
hadn't been drinking since June.
I had been drinking since August. So we're
like, we're going to do this. He's like,
yeah, let's do it. Fuck it. So he
orders a Johnnie Walker black and like,
come on man, we're going off the
wagon after to six and four months.
Say we got to, let's get the
blow. So we ordered the blue,
but it was a steak house. So it was around
the holidays and they were out of it.
So I forget if we've got the gold or
the platinum, but it was really good.
And my buddy stopped at
one, I had one more. And uh,
and then that was it.
We called it a night and then like two
hours later I was back in the hotel room.
I gotta be honest with you, I felt
like shit. And I was just like, wow,
I do not miss feeling like this. Um,
I don't think I like drinking anymore.
And then yesterday I went to the airport
and of course they had the American
Airlines terminal at Logan,
they have to Cisco brewery and I loved
Nantucket and I love Cisco Brewery.
So I'm like, well, I got to go in there
and get a fucking beer. So I had the,
a whale's tail Pale Ale had that nurse,
that thing that was delicious. And
then I get on the plane, I'm like, hey,
we don't have a fucking drink. And I know
I don't do it. Don't do it. Don't do it.
Right. Fortunately, uh, I
avoided that. Uh, and, um,
I think what I'm going to do is basically,
um,
I think,
okay,
I'm just going to take a few days off
as far as not drinking and then just go
back on the wagon on January
2nd I'm going to the Rose Bowl.
I got to have a couple of
cocktails when I'm there,
but I don't have to drink today. I don't
have to drink up until the rose bowl.
And I think that's just how I'm going
to boost rather than trying to go like a
whole fucking year and, you
know, so many days or whatever.
I just think I'm just going to pick
my spots. So being at the Rose Bowl,
it's a playoff game. That's a good
time to have a couple of drinks.
And then I really don't see any excuse
to have one for the rest of January. So,
or February or March,
I had a really don't see any event
coming up. Maybe a super bowl party.
I don't know.
But I think that's the way I'm going to
booze and I'll keep the weight off. Um,
I won't be a drunk dad
or whatever. And, uh,
I think that's basically the
way I'm going to do it. But, uh,
my daughter actually caught a cold,
you know, sewing people picking up,
holding her, you know, it's that time of
year was it, I guess it was inevitable.
So we were flying back and I was like,
Oh God,
six hours on the plane
with an infant with a cold,
this is going to be a nightmare.
And actually, uh, she was a trooper.
She fell asleep for like the first,
like 40 minutes and then was just up
for the rest of the flight. And uh,
she was a little bit whiny or whatever,
but anytime she would whine,
I just take it for a walk up
and down the aisle, you know,
because I don't want to bug other people
on the plane with my crying kid. And, uh,
I never resented people
if their baby was crying.
The only time it bugged me is if they
just weren't making any sort of effort to
try to entertain the kid. So, uh,
I was just walking her up
and down the aisle and uh,
cause she went over the stewardesses and
then they were holding her for a minute.
So it all worked out.
And I'm funny fucking
dad moment changing a,
uh, a diaper, you know,
on the plane, you know, in the bathroom
there. I never even noticed it.
Got a little thing that
fucking comes down.
I sterilize the whole thing with one
of the wipes the best I could. And uh,
that's a big thing.
Making sure your kid doesn't
touch anything and then
you got to wipe down their
hands and their feet and
everything when they come back out.
But a change in a fucking shit
diaper during turbulence on a plane.
I was like, all right, this is it.
I'm officially a dad. I knocked
it out, I knocked it out.
And um,
okay.
Yeah,
I got to tell you something too,
like all the things that I loved about
my lovely wife, you know, seeing one of,
okay,
seeing what an incredible
mother she is is, uh, I dunno,
that's a whole other level too.
It's a whole other level.
So I don't know what to tell you. This
is weird. I'm actually really happy.
So I don't know how know how funny
this fucking podcast is going to be,
but I had an awesome Christmas and um,
I was really at all this
stress thinking like, oh,
I'm like all I've ever heard is,
oh my God, going back to holidays,
bringing your kids and everything.
It's like as a parent you don't get
to rest and blah, blah, blah, blah,
Blah and all that. Uh, I had
a great fucking time and um,
I was thinking that we were just going
to fly back this time and then start
establishing Christmases out here by,
it's such a good time with like two days
left. I even said to me, I was like,
if you want to do this again next year,
I'll do it. Cause you know, it snowed,
it was out. It's just,
it was the shit. And um,
yeah. And my kid is awesome.
Even though she wears me out,
she'll literally wear me out and then
she'll finally go to sleep and then I
closed the door and I get this to, you
know, to lay down for a second like, ah,
and like five minutes I'll just sit
there and laugh and five minutes later I
just start thinking like,
I miss her.
I was at possible, how is that
possible? But I dunno, that's,
that's how it works. So
I'm not complaining. Um,
so anyways, uh, oh, you know,
when I could drink again
after new year's baby,
the night of the Patrice O'Neal benefit
to get that plug in there. There you go.
The Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit,
uh, entering, it's, let's see,
is this the sixth to the seventh one?
The seventh one,
right. Let's see here.
At 13, 14, 15, 16, 17,
18 is the sixth one. And I want to thank
everybody that's been buying tickets.
We're almost sold out again
this year, which is really, uh,
it's truly amazing. And, um,
I have to thank Maureen Taren
and everybody else who, uh,
gives their time every year.
Jim Norton, Collin Quinn, uh,
Dave Attell, Bobby Kelly, Dane Cook,
all of his friends that
have taken time out of their
lives. And, uh, it's just fun.
You know, it's like a high school
reunion. And then also to see like a,
okay,
you know, we always have a couple of
the young, you know, I call them kids.
I went old fucked out. But, uh, it just
see, you know, they were teenagers when,
when Patrice has stuff standing up first
started coming on TV and he actually
influenced them to be comedians.
So getting to hear those stories and get
to see the young, the young guys, the uh,
Michael Che's,
the Hannibal Bursas and see them coming
out and how funny they are and all that.
It's just, it's just
a great thing. So, uh,
I will once again tweak the link.
I'll keep tweeting it until we, uh,
sell the whole thing out.
But once again,
thank you to everybody who's been over
the years been a helping to support that,
a wonderful cause. And as always,
after we pay for the theater,
all the money goes to Patrice has loved
ones that he was supporting while he was
still alive, taking care of them. So, um,
with that,
what are we going to do now?
How are we going to talk a little sports
here? A little fucking sport. Oh Shit.
Do you know what I watched
what documentary I watched
that was only like an hour
and 20 minutes long, but it took
me six hours to watch because, uh,
my lovely daughter would not go to sleep.
I watched
this documentary called, uh, Newman.
Right.
So I was initially attracted to the
title cause I thought it was going to be
about Paul Newman, who's like one of
the coolest guys ever saw. I'm like,
I gotta watch this, see what
they're talking about. Right.
And uh, you know, what's
it going to be about?
It's going to be about racing
career is acting career or his,
uh,
his charity.
I always wondered how
involved he was with that.
I just can't see the great Paul Newman
sitting there listening to people talking
about that Balsamic
vinegarette or spaghetti sauce.
Okay.
I bet.
In the beginning he just wanted to
have a business and he's just like,
I don't want to deal with this shit.
Just not just fucking running.
Give them money. The port. Um, by the way,
did you see some fucking jerk off?
Bought his watch,
his actual watch for 17 point $8 million.
What,
what kind of a fucking asshole?
Then what do you do with it
then you put it on like, oh,
like I feel as life force, maybe
I can act now. Maybe I'm cool.
Um,
I just don't,
I don't understand that type of shit.
I Dunno.
I guess I do a little bit,
maybe it's like musical instruments.
I think it'd be cool to see a
couple of really famous instruments,
but I wouldn't want to own them.
You know,
like if you had somebody like
some famous person's guitar,
they pass away and you have that guitar
and then you're playing their music on
that with your skill level. You
know, I know the guitar is an alive,
but if it was when it started crying.
Okay.
Um, anyways, uh,
so I,
I rented this documentary called Newman
and it was about this guy who came up
with a electromagnetic
device that produced energy.
And the big thing about it was not
only was it clean energy was the device
itself,
somehow it created more energy
than it was using to run.
And I didn't know that that was a
problem because I have a horrible science
background. So, uh, just, just watch
it. See what you think. Alright.
Basically, I wasn't aware of this.
Any engine, any sorta turbine,
anything, whatever. I guess what,
even if it's used to create energy,
maybe they all are, I guess, you
know, some sort of turning forest.
I don't know what I'm in.
I'm in way over my head.
They had always day, always like you're
always in a deficit because it, it,
I guess it,
it uses more energy than it
actually fucking produce as well.
This thing that this
guy created allegedly,
like it used 10% of the energy
that it actually created,
which was fucking unheard of.
So when he went down to get a patent,
they will like what you're
doing is impossible, sir.
That sounds like witchcraft is it
basically defied the laws of physics as we
know them right now.
So they were all saying what,
you probably got some transformer
hidden somewhere on your property.
They tried to find it,
they couldn't find it.
They just refuse to believe that this guy,
what he was doing was true,
which then goes,
you know,
they wouldn't give him a pat and then it
goes into all of this conspiracy theory,
you know,
that a big oil company,
politics and all of this shit,
we're standing in the way this guy,
cause he was basically going
to put them out of business.
And um,
I gotta be honest with you,
I believed everything that I saw in it.
Uh,
and spoiler alert, cause I'm going
to continue talking about this.
You should definitely watch it.
I believe that his device worked.
I believe that the patent company
probably with pressure from the oil.
Okay.
Um, wouldn't give him a patent.
I believe he got death threats.
And then I also believed that
he was out of his fucking mind.
I believe that he had
a god complex and um,
he certainly had a temper.
Just check this disguise,
one of those fascinating people ever.
And then there's no way to
watch this for me anyways,
for me to watch this.
Yeah.
And I'm not talking about the genius side
of this guy I'm talking about is floss
the Newman dude, his, the
is flawed personality.
I couldn't help but watch that guy.
You know,
when the investors would
come around and he'd be like,
I know what you want to do.
You want to steal from me,
I'll punch you right in your
fucking face. Right. I couldn't,
and I might even exaggerate.
I couldn't help.
Okay.
When I was watching that
to not see myself going,
that looks like me. When I try
and rent a car or when I try to,
okay.
Get customer service, that's what I ended
up doing. And even though I'm right,
I become wrong because
of the way I behave.
And um, it's really fascinating. And
just one of those things where you age,
you just,
you just want it to be true.
It will be so great if there was just
a way to seamlessly have that thing
developed.
Give the Guy Newman is credit.
He makes a ton of fucking money.
You let the fucking oil companies run
the God damn thing and they keep making,
I don't give a fuck.
I'll keep paying what I pay for oil.
All right,
let's quit.
If we could pollute less and have to
liberate less people around the world
because of our fucking
dependency on this shit,
you know,
I really believed, you know, I
actually, I know you guys. Yeah.
They always say you get
your tin foil hat on.
I don't even know where
that reference comes from,
but
there seem to be this
incredible progression.
It's far is like,
uh,
in energy and in curing diseases and
then all of a sudden it just came to a
screeching fucking halt.
And it's my belief that it's because the
amount of money that is being made and
how entrenched those entities are and
how many is people's livelihoods are
attached to them that
they don't want that it's
okay.
There's just too much conflict
of interest to have it progress.
Like, uh, I dunno,
I'm one of those people that believes
that they can cure a way more diseases
than they let on. And I doctor told
me one time, a long time ago, he said,
look, there's no money in the cure.
The money is in the treatment.
And I know that's thought that human
beings would actually fucking do that.
But the way a corporation works is
kind of like the way back in the day,
the war games, the way they would
shoot off the warheads where it's like,
it took two people. Everybody's fucking
got a turn, a key. And every or,
or when they would gas somebody
or shoot somebody, you know,
and the firing squad, somebody had like
a fucking rubber bullet or an empty gun,
so everybody would fucking
do it. Uh, I dunno,
I ain't, you know, something
half by the end of that,
that didn't even make sense
to me. But I, I just, I don't,
I don't believe in people when it comes
to that doing the right fucking thing.
Well, that's to what happened. Watch the
fucking thing and decide for yourself.
I explained it so much better.
Oh,
now living in the past and
the podcast I already did. Um,
anyways, being back in Boston, you know,
something I really fucking missed was,
uh,
the Herald sports page and the globe
sports page. I was at fucking heaven
reading that sports page.
One day I sat down and they had all
the Bruins stats for this season,
all the Celtic stats,
all the patriots stats,
and then they had these giant
articles about all three teams.
There was still breaking
down the Patriots.
Buffalo bills game and rating the
quarterback, the running back,
the receivers, the offensive
line to defensive line, the
linebackers to secondary,
the special teams, the
coaching, grading them.
It's fucking phenomenal.
I'll tell you what wasn't phenomena was
watching those fucking assholes trying
to stir up some bullshit.
Right as we're going into the playoffs,
about Tom Brady in his fucking personal
trainer who gives a fuck whatever it's
personal trainers doing,
it's obviously working.
The guys ran out of digits on
one hand was Superbowl rings.
Now he's moved onto the other one.
I swear to God, the local media.
What would they be?
I tweeted that.
What the fuck would they be doing if
they weren't trying to sabotage the local
team and all you fucking cops out there
who then pile on and start commenting
and calling into these sports shows.
Anytime there's shitting on the fucking
home team like that. Like, look,
if it's deserved, it's deserved. But
if they're just trying to stir up shit,
just stop. Just stop listening. Turn the
channel. So I mean, that's what I do.
Uh,
by the way, you know what's funny
is, uh, I saw yet another, uh,
eat guy at ESPN talking
about bill Belichick's press
conferences going on like,
God, there's, there's so intimidating.
It's like what is intimidating by it?
Stop acting like you don't know exactly
what the fuck the guys do and he knows
what you're doing.
You're trying to get him to give you a
quote so you can build your story around
that and then you can exaggerate and take
all this shit out of context and give
the other team bulletin board material.
That's why he doesn't talk to you guys.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Did you see that coach for after they
beat Georgia the first time they play?
We beat dog shit out of them.
Whatever the fuck he said.
I bet that was all over their locker room.
Fucking on the ceilings above their
bed until they played him again.
And what happened?
Yeah,
Georgia bulldogs.
Hey,
they came back and paid him
riding a fucking ass man
and they came back and beat
him. That's why I built Bella. Check
doesn't do that shit. All right.
That was another thing I liked
about Newman was that this guy was,
this was a good old boy
from fucking Mississippi.
And just being out here in La and
watching all these fucking actors and
actresses just openly shitting on
anybody who lives in the middle of this
country because they have the audacity
to vote for somebody different than they
do,
you know?
And evidently because they don't live
next to an ocean that makes them a fucking
moron. Just watching what this
guy did, allegedly, you know,
Johnny Carson was from like Nebraska.
I just don't understand. I just,
I don't get people out
here and then I might say,
I shouldn't act like it's everybody,
but it's just really fucking ignorant.
Anyways, that is the podcast. All right.
And that is the last
podcast for this year.
2017 was the greatest year of
my life becoming a dad. And,
um,
I know just so many great things,
you know, happened to me this year.
So I'm going to thank all you guys.
Everybody came out to shows
and all that type of stuff.
I really want to take the time.
I never do this.
I always call you guys because
I like to think it's a daring,
but thank you guys for the
best year of my life. And um,
I hope 2018, I don't even think it
needs to be better. Just match this one.
Just be in the cruising altitude job,
the path you have to be the
presage shut up. You can't.
Um, but anyways, uh, that's it.
I'm not doing shit.
I have basically all a
fucking January off and uh,
I'm going to put together another 20
minutes to add to all the bullshit that I
have,
that sort of thing
goal. And uh, I'm going to court,
I'm going to tour a lot this year,
put it that way and I'm looking
forward to an amazing year. Alright.
Enjoy this music. And then a throwback
episode of Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast. Have a great weekend.
[inaudible] happy new year
and I'll talk to you in 2018.
[inaudible]
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the Monday
morning podcasts from Monday,
December 28,
the final Monday morning podcast for 2009.
Can you believe it?
Another decade. Has Flown by
through, this was like the most,
um,
stealth decade of all time.
And I'm going to tell you why,
just in case you're worried,
I would make such a bold fucking statement
about the Goddamn calendar and then
never give you an explanation.
I'm going to tell you why,
because every decade that I've lived in,
at least that I can remember that I lived
in the 70s everybody would discuss the
seventies one of the 70 [inaudible] like,
and then the eighties the big eighties.
Right? And then, you know,
people talking about, you know,
the 90s people would make
references on sitcoms, you know,
about the coming nineties,
right? It had a fucking name.
Every decade that I've been in
has had a name seventies the 60s,
the eighties and the nineties but
this decade had no fucking name. Ah,
the art,
the two thousands we had,
we never decided on a fucking
name. Therefore, you know,
I wasn't really paying attention.
I wasn't really paying attention
as this decade whipped by,
because it's Kinda like the
odometer went back to zero. Right.
Uh, this is getting
this, getting shaky here.
I just realized I'm really
getting into some shaky territory.
It's kind of like it went back to
two to zero, right? Except it didn't,
it was,
it was at 2000,
which actually comes back after 1999.
I'm just saying. You know what I mean?
It's like, what the fuck? What happened
to this decade, you know? I Dunno.
That was pathetic. I really sounded
like I had something to say there.
And it went absolutely fucking nowhere.
Um,
which is the theme of this podcast
every damn week. Every fucking week,
you know, for the last few weeks.
Look, give me with a gratuitous fucks.
Why am I saying fuck so
much this fucking week?
You know why I have not been on stage
since I taped my latest special.
I have been on vacation
vacation and uh,
I haven't been doing shit.
I've been stuffing my fats
face with holiday cheer and a,
I dunno what you guys have a good
Christmas. Did you have a merry Christmas?
Isn't that just put a song in your
heart to say that to somebody?
Merry Christmas. Ah, what the
fuck? Who's calling me now? Ah,
Shit. Hey, I'm doing my podcast.
Let me call you back in about 40 minutes.
Okay,
there we go.
Anyways,
merry Christmas to one and all. Um,
yeah, I got to get on stage here because,
uh,
now that I've basked in the glory
of not fucking up my special,
everything went great. Now I can
take a vacation. Now, you know,
there's this little voice in the back
of my head going, dude, you know, um,
you don't have an act right now.
Technically you really don't. So, uh,
why don't you go do some shit and
hopefully some funny shit will happen.
Um, um, speaking of which, um,
some of my girlfriends family came out
and we took them out to Venice beach out
here in California and a, if you
know about out there, you know,
there's a bunch of freaks out there,
but there's enough regular people
sort of tours that it waters it down,
but a big to beating the fact
that it was the Christmas week,
there wasn't a lot of tourists out there.
There wasn't even a lot of regulars
out there. So when we showed up,
it was pretty much wall
to wall freaks and uh,
just had a fucking great time out there.
This guy was standing in front of some
sort of fun house shit that I'd never
seen before and he was that
classic, you know, you know,
step rad have stepped right up
and he's going see the rubber man,
see the electric boy.
And then he goes and look,
look what just came in from the space
station and he reached into a bucket of
water and he pulled out
a two headed turtle.
It was one of the greatest
fucking intros to something. Yo,
look what they just look what just
came in from the space station. Right.
First of all,
I like the fact that this fucking shit
on Venice beach standing next to a crack
head has some sort of direct link
to the space station. All right.
I also like the term the space station.
Is there a space station?
I haven't seen a report on space for a
long fucking time considering NASA really
fell off. They really
fucking fell off. You know,
when I was a kid,
you know they were going to the Goddamn,
they'd been to the moon. All right.
That was like the godfather moment,
or at least they pretended to go to
the moon. I don't know what they did,
but I bought it and they would literally
feeding us Tang at school and for all
you youngsters out there,
this was,
it was powdered orange drink that
they is what the astronauts drink.
You know when they're up there and I, you
know, outer space and they don't have a,
they don't have the, I dunno what
I'm trying to say. They, they,
they can't get into any decent
fucking food or liquids.
Would you like to see what it's like
to drink a poor excuse for a raw orange
juice and be like an astronaut? And
of course you did. Of course she did.
There was actually a dream
of many kids growing up.
What would you like to be?
I'd like to be a hockey player.
I think you'd be a heel keeper.
What would you like to be? I'd like to be
a fucking astronaut. Well. That's nice.
Tim. He could you say it again without
the curse words? You little cunt.
Why do you have a fucking bowl cut?
Because it's the 70 sweetheart.
They're my dad. Grow up with malaria
and curly. Um, remember that?
Remember the seventies number?
That shit when it was still okay,
it was still acceptable for your parents
to cut your fucking hair even though
they had no beautician skills whatsoever.
My Dad cut my fucking hair
right up until sixth grade.
Sixth grade,
just laying a template for no pussy right
through fucking a right through high
school. What am I trying to say? So
there was, this guy goes, this guy,
look what just came in
from the space station.
Now obviously there's no rubber man.
There's no electric boy.
I know it's all bullshit. But you
figure if you're going to make uh, a a,
a reference to space,
you're going to pull out something that
looks like it came for fucking space.
I'm sort of rock that you found on the
beach claim. It's part of an asteroid,
maybe part of a bigger asteroid
that's headed right towards us.
Whatever you got to do. This fucking
guy pulled out a two headed turtle.
Look what just came in
from the space station.
They were up in the fucking space station.
And look what came floating by
a deformed,
uh,
fuck an amphibian that needs to be within
this atmosphere and a fucking know.
And I'm trying to say here, I just
thought it was fucking hilarious. And me,
my girlfriend and her family
laughed for like fucking 10 minutes.
You know that when someone just does
something stupid out in public and then
that just becomes like the catch phrase.
You know what I mean?
The keep on trucking moment of your
afternoon, anytime the, you know,
the conversation would die down.
Someone would just say, hey,
look what just came in from the space
station. Oh, when we would laugh,
we had a great fucking time,
bunch of freaks out there.
I saw a black guy in a yellow
fung walking on broken glass.
Now he didn't have a thong.
The other guy,
it was an American flag fung and the
other guy was dressed and as skin tight,
fucking yellow. I don't
know what it was. Um,
he was basically walking
barefoot on trash, but I got
to admit, he pulled a crowd.
I was impressed,
very impressed at the best one I saw
was I saw this dude who was wearing a
derby, which is a type of hat. I
don't if it's a bowler hat or a derby.
I don't,
one of those,
one of those like Charlie Chaplin hats
and his big Shtick to get money was he
would walk backwards in front of tourist
with his hat on and he had an empty,
uh,
like Paper Cup that you'd have cocaine.
And he was just sort of hitting it up
in the air and before it would land,
he'd hit it up with the
other hand and it would,
and would go no higher than
just the top of his hat.
And he had this look on his face
like, Eh, am I doing something?
And then there was another dude out there,
this drug addict who had his side
kick me in the ass for a buck.
He started yelling at me to do it.
And I,
I just was laughing cause I'm saying I
can't, I can't do that. I'm not, I don't,
first of all, I'm not going to kick in the
ass for a buck. I don't want, you know,
it's humiliating.
I don't want to do that too.
And then not to mention the second you
bend over, I'm going to fucking do that.
You know, you know you have a kick your
friend in the ass and you kick him.
So you want to kick him so hard that
you misjudge it and you actually hit his
ball bag from the, from the
other side. That's what I,
I envisioned myself doing it at that
point. I, I would think that, you know,
then I've got to fight a fucking drug
addict and I get hit hepatitis, whatever.
Look at me acting like a, you know,
that's what I was going to do. No,
you weren't bill. You weren't going to
do that. That's what you wanted to do.
But you didn't have
the balls to do what's,
he laughed like a little girl and
he continued on down the boardwalk.
That's what the fuck you
did. You know, you know,
speaking of a new hour of comedy,
that's something I always wanted to talk
about on stage and I always thought it
would be funny,
but I never really kind of was able to
make it funny was those fucking people
will always, you tell, tell him something
that happens, something bad to you.
And then the second they'd done
listening to it, they always go, dude,
you know what I would've done? You
know what I woulda done? Let me guess.
You would have done something that worked.
Now that you're basically in the
future and saw what the fuck happened,
asshole. Yeah, and I'd leave. I parked
my car and I go to get out of it.
All of a sudden it started
rolling down the fucking street.
I don't know what happened. I
had the thing in gear, dude.
You know what I would've done?
I would've had it an emergency.
It would have put the emergency brake
on and I were to turn the fucking tires
towards the curb.
That's what I would've done
in anticipation that the
one fucking time you didn't
put the emergency brake on,
that your car that never slipped out of
gear before was then going to slip out
of fucking gear. Shut up,
you asshole. You know,
if you had that sort of intelligence,
he wouldn't be friends with me hanging
out in this shit hole fucking bar. Right?
Well, all right then. All right. Now that
it got myself worked up into a lather,
look at me wearing my Christmas
patriots. Jersey. What a fucking nerd.
How old are you?
It looks like if she's standing with a
book bag waiting for a bus, you know,
it's just not cute anymore. Um, all
right, let's get on with the podcast.
If you're new to the podcast,
welcome, welcome. Um,
I got some news this week. Everybody. Uh,
I know I keep threatening to join
Facebook and I'm going to have to do it.
I'm going to have to do it because there's
just nobody left here on my space. Uh,
I'm a, I'm giving up. I'm pulling the
flag down and putting up the white flag.
I surrender you when Facebook you when
got damaged if it wasn't for those
meddling kids. Um, all right,
so let's get on with the podcast
and if you knew the podcast,
I try to hype my shit. This is what
I got going on. I'm on vacation.
Okay.
I just taped a new special called let
it go and it'll be out in 2010 at some
point.
If you can't wait that long,
why don't you go on iTunes or going to
my website [inaudible] dot com and go buy
my fucking DVD. Why do
I do this? All right,
so I can get a little check.
I can get my little fucking $3 or whatever
the fuck I make on those things. Um,
anyways,
my next Gig is an uh,
Seattle January 15th,
and I'm doing the Marty reamer.
Funny Fest. Martin Green was a great
guy, great radio guy up there in Seattle.
He's got this, uh, this big comedy show
that I have been trying to do for years,
and I'm going to be up there with a bunch
of other big shots like a Jeff garland
and a, and a bunch of other people. I
can't even fucking remember who else.
Me Up there with Christian
Finnegan number. I hate that.
The other white dude
in the Chappelle show.
Who would some people you want the
Chappelle show? Will you on the, uh,
the mad real world? No, I
wasn't. That was the other guy.
And then people try to argue with me.
Not that we show that we shoe.
Why would I lie? Why would I, why would I,
why would I try to knock down my
pathetic entertainment resume?
I'm all about padding it. All right,
let's get on with the podcast here. Um,
what do we got here? Let's start off with
Douche bag of the week. All right. And,
um,
my nominee for Douche bag of the week
is the NFL network for showing a fucking
game on Christmas. That was only on their
goddamn network. You know what, dude?
Fuck the fucking NFL network.
All right.
Have any guys out there actually looked
into what it takes to get a God damn
dish? First of all, if you're
renting somewhere, right?
You landlord is going to be a cunt.
If you start drilling into the side
of the building, right? You know,
a repair that's probably
going to cost him $80,
but somehow we'll take the entire
12 to $1,500 a year fucking deposit,
you know? And then also, you
know, I don't know about you guys,
but when I actually first moved out here,
I was getting the flat screen.
I was like, fuck it. She's going to
light up the card. And they're like,
would you like to get direct TV?
And I'm thinking, yeah, fuck it.
I'll get the NFL network. I can
watch the pats games. Why not?
And they wanted me to sign up for like
two or three years. Like it's a, uh,
like a cell phone company.
I don't have to do that with cable cable
right now. I could call them and say,
you know what? I'm sick of
your shit. Go Fuck Yourself.
And they'd be like [inaudible] or tearing
your Karen [inaudible]. She Ain't,
if you didn't use sign language,
fuck you.
You fucking Sunday work
in cable cont right.
And they would just shut it
off and then that would be it.
And then I could back on Monday and
be like, yeah, listen. You know,
I don't know. I was, I
was drinking. I was Ah,
I lost some money on the
games and I took it out on,
I believe her name was Samantha.
I don't know where she was
stationed and your states,
but is there any way you can turn
it back on? Absolutely. Absolutely.
There'll be a UI $80 Ra.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Restart up fee to match
the $90 cancellation fee.
You know, that's the way they
get ya. Okay. But I got mobility,
I got freedom.
I mean,
I have a feeling of control going to
sign a fucking three year contract,
you know,
the level of,
of of Douche baggery by the NFL network
to show a game on Jesus's birthday.
God's son, he sitting there trying to
think, Jesus has fucking direct TV.
I don't think he does.
You know, fucking hippie.
You think he's going to be involved in
some sort of corporate contract? Man,
I dunno. You know what I mean? Look,
I don't mind if you can show the
random Thursday game. I get it.
You're trying to get me,
you know,
you're trying to get me all right and
you have your best matchups. Okay.
And you got to ll cool j on the
fucking TV licking his lips,
telling me about all the fucking
games that I'm missing. Uh,
how many fucking tubes a chapstick
does that guy go through a year?
It doesn't make your lips
chapped if your own saliva,
if you keep them glistening
with your own saliva.
That's one of those uh,
those evidently urban sexy
moves that makes, I don't know,
white people in the suburbs just cringe.
Like really they do that.
They lick their lips and that's
like a good thing. Um, anyways,
I like how I just made all white people
in the suburbs feel the way I feel about
ll cool j licking his lips anyways, Douche
bag of the week. NFL network. All right,
you fucking assholes.
If you want to show a random Thursday game
and you know into to try to get me to,
to, to buy it. I get it. You're a
business but don't do it on Christmas.
You asshole. You know what you did. You
just made me more of an NBA fan. Okay.
Cause they had the Celtics magic and
they did their best guys out there.
They had Lebron, Kobe, Shaq. All right.
The big three up in
Boston and Dwight Howard,
who's got a bicep the size of my entire
body and has absolutely zero fucking
baseline moves. Jesus,
what's his one movie? Dunks.
You know,
if that guy would just steal one move
from fucking Kevin Mchale via a Keem
Olajuwon he would be unstoppable.
But he doesn't, he's got nothing.
He's got no turnaround jumper.
He's got nothing.
He's just got a bicep the size of a
fucking credenza. He's got two of them.
Um, anyways, seriously dude,
that's like the biggest fucking
human being I've ever seen.
So douche bag or the week is
the fucking NFL network and I'm
fucking cough. Um, I dunno, I
really want to write them a letter.
I just have to take all the fucks and
cons out of it and I think that they're
really going to give a shit,
but I'm going to go biblical on him.
You know what I mean?
Because everybody pays attention.
When someone starts saying that
you offended me religiously.
And speaking of which,
I am introducing a new
segment here on the podcast,
and this is the,
uh,
the religious segment where you can
ask questions about other religions.
You can bitch about your own religion or
you can say why it's great and why you
like it. All right? Uh, the name
of this segment is, oh Geez,
because you know, last week,
I don't even know what
the fuck I said about, oh,
I remember that guy was saying how you
were, um, how we think share a you,
you make a choice to be gay.
And then he starts, you know,
making some quotes with the Bible. And
I was just like, Oh, you fucking people,
you know, with the Bible, right?
So this guy writes in and he goes,
trash in the Bible at Christmas.
What have you gone?
Stark raving mad or something.
This guy sounds like a a
born again Christian cause
he's obviously not going to
curse here.
Have you gone stark raving mad?
I mean Jimminy cricket spill. Anyways.
Did you hit your head or something lately?
Okay. Let's see. You do
believe in God, right?
But you went to a Catholic church where
they filled your skull with guilt,
horror and hypocrisy. And then he puts
in parentheses the little boy thing. Oh,
is that what you call children?
Getting molested
grown men. Fucking children. You call
that the little boy thing. Alright. Uh,
or whatever they did to turn you off.
Okay. Understandable. Understandable.
But for crying out loud,
this, this right here,
this email is why I don't work clean
as a comedian because you have to use
expressions like for crying out loud.
Have you gone stark raving mad?
Um,
many ways for crying out loud.
What makes you think God is like that?
He's not exclamation point. I
never said he was, he's fucking,
people don't even listen to me. I'm
saying the Bible was written by people.
That's what I feel. Okay. It was with
my people a long fucking time ago.
They thought the earth was flat. Okay. A
lot of its metaphors, a lot of the shit.
I know a lot of stuff, you
know, make sense of whatever,
but it's written by people,
all right?
And I don't believe that Jesus
was the son of God, okay?
I don't believe you'll rub
Buddhist stomach. I don't
believe any of that stuff.
Okay?
All those stories are the bridge between
right now and back when we used to draw
a deer on the inside of caves,
all right?
I'm not saying there's not
a fucking higher power.
I'm not saying I don't
believe in an afterlife.
All I know is that you don't know what
the fuck is going on until you die,
all right?
So you can make you guesses.
Your guesses are, are, are, are,
you know, qualified. You know,
I'm not saying you can't make your guests
if that's what the fuck you want to go
for,
but you know,
I'm not saying you can't believe
what you want to believe.
I just don't believe in that stuff. I
just don't. Do you really believe that?
You really believe Jesus was the
son of God and he, and he just,
he had a wicker basket and he just
was pulling fish out of it and fed 800
fucking people out of this little basket
that you usually throw a fucking hot
steam and washcloth into,
you know,
and he walked on water and
then he rose from the dead.
You really believe all of that. I don't
know. Why is my voice going up so high?
You ain't
even Jesus Christ.
Um, I'm envious of that.
I remember you said that.
I, um, I dunno. I just, I
don't, I don't believe that, uh,
you know, I don't believe Noah, I
don't believe in any of those stories.
None of those stories a believable to me.
They're just not.
I could see the earth flooding
and everybody drowning.
I can see that. I can see, I can
even see a guy making a fucking boat,
or maybe people who are already on a boat.
You know?
Why didn't those people survive with Noah?
See, I can't even fuck an
answer. I don't know why.
Then you gotta fill it up with all those
animals shitting all over the place.
You've got to capture all the
animals. It's just, it's not,
it's not fucking believable on any level,
on any level. It lacks credibility.
I liked the Ted Commandments. I
love the seven deadly sins. Uh,
I like the end of the world shit,
but I don't take it that seriously.
And this is not me slapping anybody
in the face. I just, you know,
and I would think of to say this
because you have an open your,
she'll fuck Jay's is when you open your
shelf full up and you shipped him as
your one and only savior. Yeah. Why can't
I do that? Why can't I just do that?
Why do I then have to go to church and
fucking pay for somebody else's lifestyle?
Who wants to dress like James Brown's
in the fucking blues brothers? Huh?
And you guys out there
going a mega church,
you guys seen those things down the
south, down, down the south, down south.
You'd be seen. I was, I didn't know
what the fuck I'm talking about. Look
the same way, that guy standing
out there going, you know,
look what they just brought
in from the space station.
That's what preachers are doing.
And let's say that they're
giving you like life advice,
but when they just started
talking about that, uh, you
know, and then on the third day,
God created the swingset. Yeah. Gi,
it was written that children need
something to play on that would swing them
back and forth and you
have to do a flagger
brutal fucking brutal. This is really
just going to cause a shit storm.
And I hope it does. All right.
And, and, and all of this,
I'm not disrespecting your
religion or what you believe.
I just don't fucking believe it.
And I don't believe that you believe it.
That's how unbelievable it is to me. All
right. But I believe in and in something,
you know, you know that
shit where you like, yeah,
you'll walk to the phone and before you
say you'll get, just know who it is.
That kind of weird shit or
a Deja Vu. This. There's a
lot of weird shit out there,
you know?
Uh,
you forget to look and you change seven
lanes and you don't die and then you
think, wait a minute. Then I did. I just
looked back that I can't really remember.
You were in this fucking zone. I
don't know. I don't believe in ghosts.
You know?
I don't get what can it go studio other
than wake you up in the middle of the
night? I guess I can do
that. Go on beyond that,
what can they do?
You know?
That's how I got over my fear
of the dark when I was a kid.
When I would imagine that
there was a monster in there.
I got so mad at the fear.
One night I started giving the monster
the finger and it didn't kill me and I
was like,
all right,
any respectable monster's not going to
put up with that shit and would come over
here and fucking, there's no
monster is not much to the stupid.
This is actually just nature's way of
telling me it's time to go to sleep and
they're making it easy by
not having the sun there.
Did I ever tell you that time?
Uh, one of my friends was on this,
I can't say he was on a date.
You know that shit when you
went to like high school,
when you're basically drinking outside
and you just start talking to some bra
and you try to hook up with her.
All right,
so it's getting the dusk and there was
this moment, okay, right around dusk
where the sun's going down and the moon
was a, it sounds like a fucking song,
doesn't it?
The Sun was going down in the moon,
like sounds going down in the west of
the moon was kind of like, I dunno,
I guess at like two o'clock or whatever.
And this girl was go and someone's like,
Oh wow, the sun and the moon are
out at the same time. Wow. You know,
and this girl was like,
wait a day.
How can the fact San and the movie?
Yeah.
It's sad.
And at first they thought that she didn't
believe that you could see the moon
until the sun completely went down,
which I guess would be understandable.
But they quickly realized that she thought
that the sun and the moon where the
same thing and that evidently
at night,
I guess God or Jesus or Buddha would,
I don't know,
not necessarily blow this,
I guess she thought the sun was on
a dimmer and they would just sort of
gradually bring it down and uh,
I dunno. I don't fucking know.
And that's just one of those
moments where they always a kid,
you just have that first moment of,
is this thing too dumb to try and fuck,
you know,
I always had that I could
never fuck somebody. Whoa.
I really thought was stupid.
It just,
it just felt like it was a form of rape,
you know what I mean? If you just sold
like, I don't even stand, I'm a smart guy,
but you know, when someone's
just like borderline, like wow,
high school really. And
College. College. Wow. Okay.
All right. Uh, anyways, let me
read the rest of this though.
Jesus here and Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah. The kid thing.
Um, he's not a he, he does. He
doesn't, oh, this is a great line too.
He's saying that God is not mad.
I,
this is one of my favorite sentences
of all time. He's addressing, um,
the view of homosexuality.
He says,
God doesn't hate fags either.
Oh, that's good. That's good. He doesn't
hate the, he doesn't, hey, cock suckers.
God loves the faggots.
Um,
he loves everybody and that is
written in a big letters. Um,
even people that hold up
traffic, a gay guy or not, uh,
he died for everyone.
Everybody's sins so they can accept
that free gift at the seat. That's,
that's right there.
That's what I find annoying about Jesus,
is the whole guilt. He died for you. Dude,
I didn't ask you to do that idiot.
Give fucking walk on water, you know,
float off the cross. Wow. I'm really,
yeah, this is really getting
bad. But I'm just saying,
isn't that common fucking sense?
Like when you watch a karate movie in
Bruce Lee's doing all this shit and he
like, just get a gun. Why
don't they just shoot them?
All I know is if I was the son of God,
I would not sit there getting crucified
or at least I cheated a little bit.
You know,
I had sort of semi levitate,
so it looks like the nails are really
fucking ripping at me and they,
you wouldn't, you wouldn't
everybody caves under, under,
under torture. They all do. I don't, I
don't buy any of this shit. You know,
it'd be funny is if all of this stuff
that I'm saying isn't true is true.
And then like I die and
then they play Mike,
my damnation is this podcast and you know,
they just playing this podcast and God
is just sitting across from me, you know,
with his hands up. Uh, you know
that shit where you, uh, okay, you,
you don't have your hands together,
you just have the tips of your fingers
together and they're kind of spread apart
and you just sort of bouncing
them, you know, the classic, um,
what am I going to do with you?
I am in a position of authority over you.
What is your sentence going
to be? Um, anyways, we'll
fuck it. Let's see. Oh, how,
how far into hell I can dig myself.
Um,
what else does this guy say
that I don't agree with a no.
We know Jesus didn't sit
down with stationary and
write the Bible at some desk,
but it is his words. You know
why? I would love to know why.
I would love to know your proof.
Okay. I'll tell you why Jesus.
He anticipated my answer because I fuck
is it because I know you don't know it
was inspired by God.
Jesus through the certain chosen
people that physically wrote it.
Yeah,
I hear you saying bullcrap.
Why can't you curse if you in Jesus?
I don't understand
that.
You know,
you don't think when they were nailing
his fucking limbs to that piece of wood,
he wasn't going,
fuck yeah,
Ma fucker did.
Oh,
do you know my dad is your mother
fuckers? Come on. All right. All right.
Jesus Christ. I'm really fucking,
you know, this is stupid to do this,
but here we go. Let's go.
Let's go. Let's keep going. Um,
you know, something that they
never really fucked with his balls.
I always thought that was amazing.
You know, this smashing like, uh,
reads over his back, you know, and
putting thorns into his head went,
just kick them in the nuts his whole year.
Then now nuts his ball bag.
That fucking died. They,
I did it for you. Oh God. Is that
annoying? It's really annoying.
I swear to God, if Jesus at the mall
signing autographs, I walk right by it.
I'd rather meet Charles Bronson.
He was still alive, you know,
talk to him about being in Poland
and that mind. Um, anyways,
I hear you saying bullcrap,
but you are wrong.
If you're saying that I didn't say
bull crap. I said Bull Shit. Uh,
that just means you don't understand
spiritual and supernatural things. See,
that's another thing about these really
religious people is if you don't agree
with them and they can't be like, oh, you
know, this is what the fuck you think.
You know, I'm not saying what
this guy is saying is wrong.
I hope it's not coming off like that.
I'm just asking questions. You know,
how come they never
kicked him in the balls?
You think he didn't curse
when they were fucking,
when they were playing the upright bass
with his juggler or whatever fucking
horrific thing they did to him.
Um,
I actually understand spiritual things.
I don't understand supernatural things.
No, I don't. I don't believe in
ghosts and neither do you. Okay.
And just because you read a fucking book,
it doesn't mean you understand it,
right? You don't. All right. Uh,
so like so many other people,
you feel the need to stop on something
just because you don't understand it
fully, and that makes
you mad. Okay. Uh, well,
how about instead of getting mad you,
you asked Jesus himself to explain it
to you. Okay. I will hang on a second.
Jesus,
could you explain the Bible
to me cause I don't get it.
Okay. All right. So now what do I
do? This is really getting creepy.
This is, I feel like I'm about to
fucking weegee board right now. Um, I,
I can't even read the rest of this. All
right? That's probably a fucking stew.
I really should not do this podcast.
I should just fucking hit a race,
you know? All right. Let's talk about
movies. Shall We? Let's get out of this.
I saw the movie Sherlock Holmes,
uh, this week. Me and half of,
uh, the, the, the American population
all went out this Jesus
get me back. Um, yeah,
so Sherlock Holmes and uh,
this is my movie review.
This is the best way that I can put it.
It was watching Sherlock Holmes.
It was like a,
that's how he said it to my friend
or friend of mine who actually have,
who also it does not believe in Jesus.
I said it was like
Sherlock Holmes was like,
it was like the first time
you ate a fat free cookie.
Do you remember that confusion?
You just looking at the cookie being like,
you know, how can this not be good?
It's, it's a fucking cookie. You know,
how can a cookie be bad?
And that's literally what I
felt like when I was watching,
when I was watching Sherlock
Holmes. You know, I'm like,
how is it Robert Downey Jr
has given a great performance?
Fucking what's his face? Jude
law was great in it. Guy Ritchie,
I loved all his movies.
How is this not fucking good?
And I don't even know. I can't explain
it. I don't know why it wasn't good.
It just wasn't bad. It
just, it was it, I dunno,
it just, what it wasn't good. Um,
I liked how they dumbed down Sherlock
Holmes l rather than having them be just
an egg head. They, they
made him like this guy,
like they turned it into like fight club.
First of all,
it was great about the movie was that
they had elements of Jujitsu in England in
the 18 hundreds which I thought was
hilarious cause as far as I knew it came
from the fucking Gracie family.
Right.
Then they get credit or
very least Brazilian Jujitsu
and he came up with it and
like the twenties or the 30s right
now what happened? I
don't know. They did that.
They had a little bit of Zeitgeisty in
there, a little bit of fight club and uh,
and then after he beat the shit out of
people, then he would do all that Sherlock
calm shit.
And he would say all the Sherlock
Holmes is fast as like an auctioneer.
You're probably wondering how I knew that
because that thread indicates that you
were in the Middle East
and blah, blah, blah,
and they would fucking fly through
the whole thing. And uh, I don't know.
It wasn't good. I'm thinking about
seeing Avatar though, you know,
but that even that movie annoys me.
I don't like the whole, you know,
I wrote this and I had to wait till
technology caught up with it. Oh my God,
you're such a fucking visionary.
Jesus Christ
having you want enough wards,
you don't have to fucking rub
your own balls and public.
I don't think I'm ever going to book a
movie again if anybody ever listens to
this fucking podcast. All right, let's
plow ahead. Speaking of which date night,
I actually saw a preview
for it and I was like,
I'm in this motherfucker and I was so
afraid I was gonna see my big fucking head
that I actually stared down at my,
uh, the fuck was a junior mints,
Junior Mints,
the Classic Candy that you would never
buy if you actually had a choice,
but you just do at the movie theater.
They're awful.
And there's so much pepper or
whatever, spam or whatever, that mint,
I'm a fucking idiot.
It actually had the answer in the name.
There's so much mint in it
that after like three of them,
your fucking throat starts to hurt.
It's like you're eating Vick's vapor rub
covered in chocolate. Um,
anyways. All right. Uh,
I'm probably going to pay for
that. Oh, Jesus fucking segment.
But maybe that'll just be a onetime only
and I hope the fucking people who wrote
that shit and don't be a [inaudible]
about it. What would Jesus do?
He just looked down, shake his
Gregg Allman hair and be like, ohh,
golly, Gee, what are we going to
deal with this guy? Um, all right.
Last week I talked about men who
abandoned their families and um,
I mentioned obviously that I don't agree
with that and I'm sure Jesus doesn't
either. Forget about Buddha, although
Buddha was too fat to leave his family.
What's he going to do? You know,
he'd have to hit the lottery.
When you get that fat as a man, you need
some sort of, uh, it needs some power,
you know, to pull the
hot broads, you know,
a little bit of Viagra, you know,
they have liquid Viagara they,
you guys see that commercial
yet it's fucking unreal.
They show it late at night,
liquid Viagara you pour in your hand and
you literally start rubbing one out and
your dick comes up.
I was watching it and it was a
fucking unbelievable commercial.
And if you believe that you
believe in Jesus is um, all right,
I'm really being an asshole right
now and I don't mean to be all right.
I respect all religions and I'm actually
jealous that you go to bed every night
thinking that there's a real life Santa
Claus waiting to Koresh you and rub your
forehead and your brow.
Um, all right. So anyways,
I talked about guys who abandoned their
families and I was saying how, uh,
obviously I don't condone it,
but I am jealous of,
I want to feel that level of euphoria
because in order for you as a man to do
something like that,
to leave somebody who you actually
agreed legally to dedicate your life to,
and then you then had children with.
Right now I don't have any kids,
but I see the look on people's faces when
they talk about their kids. You know,
even if it's a pain in the ass and
that they really could go back,
they wouldn't have kids. There's a
look they have on their face that,
that unconditional love to
fucking walk away from that.
All right.
Like the level of misery that you
have to be in. I just, you know,
and it must've been like,
like how men della felt when he
finally got out of fucking all right.
It was a little big,
but you know what I mean?
So I was talking about it and I was
thinking like, you know, last week,
like what music would you listen to?
What is the soundtrack to fucking
leave in that? And you guys all like,
wait in, somebody said highway
to hell and another person said,
you listened to wish you were here.
I don't know what I would listen to.
Um,
I would just, it would be
just, I would just some,
any song that just made me go, like
I would just, I dunno. It's unreal.
But anyways, beyond
these fucking songs, uh,
Saudi actually had a story about it and
this is a great contribution by the way,
to the podcast.
As was the stuff about religion,
even though I was a jerk about it.
But you got an a stand.
I got to keep this shift funny. That's my
out. Um, anyways, uh, Bill, during, uh,
your last podcast you mentioned,
uh,
about fathers decided to suddenly
abandon their family. Well,
about 11 years ago when I was
stationed in South Dakota,
a guy that I work with did exactly that.
He left his wife, he left his kids,
uh, in hopes to start a new life. All
right. The story goes something like this,
settle in everybody. You're still wearing
your course, your Christmas sweaters.
All right. It was back in
1997 a what a great year, Huh?
Clinton was getting blown.
Nobody knew about it. Boy
Bands were popular. All right.
How innocent. What a great fucking
time before it all got ugly. You know,
people started liking it and nuts on fire,
trying to fucking take a plane down.
Um, anyways, uh, Mike,
this Guy Mike was assigned remote duty
for six months in Panama at this point in
Mike's life. He had about 14
years in the air force, um,
that is being tasked with rum,
remote duty playing bullshit war exercises
and being restricted to a military
lifestyle. So one day when I showed
up to work, my squadron's first shirt,
I don't know what that means.
I guess the guy in charge, um,
and a few officers hadn't had
maps laid out on the table.
I asked what was going on and
one of the sergeants replied,
we have a briefing at 15 minutes
information during that briefing,
I believe it was the base offers
officer who mentioned that Mike has been
missing since the day before the FBI
had some other military branch and some
other military branch was involved to
find Mike by Searching South Dakota,
by feet,
automobile and air with helicopters.
So my coworkers and I,
uh,
were tasked to drive about 50 miles to
some remote location in South Dakota to
post missing posters
of Mike See Attachment.
And he actually has the attachment
here. So anyways, he says, uh,
we thought he was in danger.
Uh, we were concerned for him.
He was a good guy helping people
out, um, when p when help was needed.
So I'll be telling me there was no sign
that this guy was going to do this shit.
And he said he plays bones, which
I guess is Domino's during, uh,
during lunch with us while
listening to classic rock,
he never came across as being disturbed.
But then again,
I was much younger so I might've, I
might've missed some signs. All right.
Back to the story. Uh, searching
for him a few days after the search,
someone reported they found supposedly
his lunchbox with his military id in it.
It was several miles north of where we
were stationed close to a North Dakota,
South Dakota border.
Um,
then they found his car in a
parking lot of a Canadian airport.
Shortly after finding his car,
they detained him in
Panama where he was found.
Mike left his family in exchange with
some Panamanian woman he met during his
duty there. Uh, we always wondered what
the hell he was thinking when he did this.
Supposedly he left his lunchbox
near a road with his ID,
this id in it as a decoy.
And when we drove to the car,
when he drove to the Canadian airport
to fly to, uh, he then flew to Panama.
And a,
the big joke was that he was listening
to the song by Van Halen called Panama
when he left.
So they arrested him and discharged him.
Uh,
his wife forgave him.
So evidently I guess he went back
through, you know what I love about that
story? That is the perfect fucking song.
Oh my God.
Just driving away from your family.
It would, it would, it would
reach down. He's the seed pack.
Ah, fuck. You know what? I think you
know what? I think the, the, the,
the feeling of euphoria is you guys ever
watched Ferris Bueller's Day off? Sure.
We all have. Do you know when those two
guys, the parking attendants, you know,
take the car out for the day and they
show that slow motion thing of when they
go up and over the hill and they get
that look of absolute joy with the wind
blowing through their hair.
I think that's what it feels like to
abandon a family if you're that fucking
miserable. So, uh, God bless
that woman for taking them back.
That's either a deep kind of love
or just no options whatsoever.
Um,
so there you go.
And I think that's going to
be the podcast for this week.
Let's do some classic stuff here. Some
overrated, underrated, real quick. Bill.
Overrated.
Skinny girls.
I've never understood the
appeal of super skinny girls.
They look more like little boys
than women. Plus they're a,
they usually snobby and expect
you to do all the work in bed.
They like Coby Bryant. They are jaded
and sex is more like a job for them.
Do what you hook up with coke.
They don't understand the magic
of the game anymore. Okay,
I see what you're saying. Do we talking
about Colby? Did you see Cobia? Yes.
On Christmas it down by like 20 points
and he's still draws an offensive foul.
That guy,
I'm a Celtics fan and I admit that's
the fucking best player in the league.
All right. But my big complaint
about Colby Bryan is um, uh,
Jesus Christ my fucking
alarm. Um, anyways, my uh,
my big complaint about Coby Brian,
I just want Laker fans cause
you guys watch him every night.
I'm not being a jerk, but when was
the last time you saw him take a shot?
Missed the shot and not look
over at the ref for a file?
It's almost like he's saying ref, it
didn't go in. They must have fouled me.
That's how fucking good I am. It's
annoying. But I totally respect that guy.
I love his game and he's a that whole
teams riding on his fucking coattails.
Um, alright. Underrated fat
chicks. Fat are the real deal.
They do everything they
can to please you in bed.
They're the only ones who can give you
a decent hump. They, I liked the Guy ta,
uh, taking the half court shot for
10 grand, no matter what the outcome.
They still have a smile on the face and
they're just happy to be there. Do that.
I'm telling you, some of you fucking
listeners really ought to do stand up.
Let's just, you know, do you know any
comedians could write something that good?
All right. Probably a few of
them, but it's really impressive.
I forgot to do the life advice.
Doctor Bill,
I get a blow through this and speaking,
speaking of, uh, becoming a comedian,
somebody wants some life advice
and this is a rough one. He says,
I got some shit going on in my life and
it's really starting to make me reflect
on where I'm going and what I want to
be. Okay. So I need some answers. First,
my grandfather were raised
me from the age of two,
almost died and recently had a
quadruple bypass on his heart.
No idea how long he's going to make it,
but uh,
it's definitely given me a new perspective
on life. All I think about now is, um,
what were the things that he
didn't do and always wanted to, uh,
fuck regarding things you did. I wonder
about the things he regrets not doing. Um,
I'm 29 years old.
I work as a senior manager for a
major company that builds airplanes.
I make over a hundred grand a year
and I fucking hate it. I'm in a,
this part of the world and
I'm not going to mention, uh,
I do stand up comedy almost every other
weekend at one of the comedy clubs there.
My question is this,
can I ever make a trans transition from
work to stand up performing outside of
La or New York or do you think I will
have to quit everything and move to one of
those locations also? Do you think
it's worth it? I know I'm funny.
I know I'm a good comedian. I
feel, I make like, uh, uh, wait.
I feel like making a living as a comic
would be similar to winning the lottery.
Even though I'm funny.
It's still one in a million shot that I
would ever be able to make it a career.
Thank you. Thanks for the, any advice
you have. All right dude. That's,
those are tough questions because I've
never seen your act and those are really
questions that only you can answer.
I'm not trying to cop out here.
All right. But, uh, I do know this.
If you do a job and you're miserable,
you know, I mean, we want the, if
you're making $1 million a year,
I mean a hundred grand, something
that fucking sneeze. It, uh,
I dunno dude. Um, all I can do is
tell you how I looked at it. Um,
when I went into being a comedian,
I was not making a hundred grand a year.
So it was very simple for me to
make that choice to go there.
And I never really thought about not
making it other than a couple of times,
if I was doing a college gig in the middle
of fucking nowhere and I was sitting
in a super raid and I bombed that night,
then I'd be going like,
what the fuck am I doing?
This is crazy, you know? Um,
but being able to make a living as a
comedian is not a one in a million chance.
And, uh, believe it or not,
making it as a comedian is not a
one in a million chance because a,
I'm going to go out on a limb and say,
there's not a million
standup comedians out there.
Your rods are better than that.
It might be 750,000.
Now, dude, you gotta, you gotta look,
do you go down to the club and in like,
you just, you go in there and you just
feel like this is home. You know, like,
this is where I'm supposed to be. If
that's what you feel, then I would do it.
And you don't have to live
in New York or La to, uh,
to get a career going.
Um,
AH, Jesus, I'm trying to give you an
example. I mean, there's, there's every,
every stand up, um, town has the,
the local guys who never left, who
make a living at it, you know, um,
it's just one of those things where
you want to expand your horizons after
awhile where, uh, you know,
you want to start making better
money or whatever, but, um,
I dunno dude, like if it's your dream
in life, that's what you want to do,
then I would definitely do it.
Especially because if you're at
work and you're fucking miserable,
then I would do it. And making a living
at it is not as difficult as it seems.
You know, you get a college agent, he
started booking college gigs. Granted,
you got to fly all over the
fucking country. Um, but you know,
if you want to go fucking see Sherlock
Holmes in the middle of a Tuesday,
you know,
address like a shithead and not take a
shower until seven o'clock that night,
that's one of the great things
about being a comedian. But dude,
that's a huge decision. You gotta
make that on your own. But, uh,
I would make the happy choice.
Don't choose money because you're gonna
end up like one of those Stepford wives.
You know what I mean? We've got
all this shit. Any of your fucking,
you got all this stuff but
you're miserable. So, um,
I dunno man,
that's too big.
That's too big a question for me to ask
you to answer for you without knowing
you. So I hope I helped you
out. I probably didn't help
you out at all, but uh,
it, it, it, believe me do it. It's not
as hard as you think it is. All right.
It's not fucking easy, but it, it's,
it's really not as hard as you think
it is a to make a living as a comedian.
All right, let's get
to a question bill. Hi.
My question is when you are a cup
in a couple situation, situation,
spelt with a c,
what is the protocol for who or how
you decorate your Christmas tree?
Do you do it together or
separately or in stages? You know,
one puts it in the stand, one
puts the lights, et Cetera, or uh,
do you put a not put one up or not?
Um,
all right. Uh, Christmas tree question
questions are real light this week.
Um,
now my thing is if I buy it,
you decorated and if you decorate
it, no. If you buy it, uh,
you better decorate it because I'm
not doing it. In other words, I don't,
I don't decorate Christmas trees.
That's how I do it around here.
I go out and I buy it. I stick it
in the stand. And uh, then my girl,
she goes nuts. She decorates it and
she goes, it does not look nice.
What do you think about, you didn't
say anything. No, I think it's nice.
I know that I thought, I thought you were
just going to come in and be like, wow,
look at it.
It looks beautiful.
Christmas tree fell Christmas. See, I
thought you are going to do that. Really?
What would you do if I did that?
Speak of the devil,
NATO.
Hey, I'm doing my podcast.
I'm doing it right now.
You're on it.
All right. All right. All right. Okay.
Okay. Let me call you back in two minutes.
I'm almost done. Bye Bye. He's Christ.
I'm such a space shot. I like half.
Forgot that I was doing a podcast is, hey,
just calling to let you to know that I'm
not home yet and I'm gonna be home soon
and I just want him to start talking
to you already. Um, you know,
a lot of people, a couple of people
have been emailing me saying,
I'm mean to my girlfriend. I'm not, I'm
not meeting my girlfriend. I give a shit.
It's my way of, um, protecting
what I have in this relationship.
All right? I keep it light. I
fucking break balls. Oh, by the way,
I'm doing this on a Sunday because I'm
going to the Celtics fucking clippers
tonight.
And uh,
I'm actually walked away from the
TV and last I saw was like 15,
14 cults over the jets.
Um,
I don't know if I should say,
I'm not going to say this.
You don't want you guys remind me next
week to tell you my prediction of rex.
I actually,
my prediction earlier this year of Rex
Ryan was that he was gonna break his tail
bone and a failed attempt to
hang himself at some point.
I've never seen, I have not seen
such a desperate need to be liked.
I'm telling you,
that guy is emotionally on the edge.
All right? That fucking bizarre
Christmas wishlist thing that he did.
Like, you know, I'm hosting SNL,
but I'm actually fucking a coach and east
to that guy is out of his fucking mind
and he's broken down crying
a couple times, and I've
made predictions this year,
Dad, I'm telling you, I can't tell
you who's going to win a fucking game,
but shit like that. I'm
telling you, I watched that.
Packy I'll fight and I fucking.