Hey,
what's going on is bill burn is time for
the Monday morning podcast from Monday.
Sorry for Thursday. No, it isn't.
It's not the money. My head,
it's a Thursday afternoon just before
Friday. Monday morning podcast. Dan.
Yes. Checking in on you.
I'm just checking in on you.
How you doing? What are you, what are you
done today? How did you watch the news?
Did you fill your head up with all the
fucking craziness on the news isn't a
great watch and then dose. Oh yeah.
Hey, I'm waking up. I'm feeling good.
You know what?
Let's turn on the news.
Okay.
Why would you put on the fucking
news? What are you going to see? Oh,
you're going to see an accurate
portrayal of what's going on.
Stick it out the fucking window.
I look at your neighbor. Hey,
look at him walking out to his car with
his little brown sack with his fucking
lunch in it.
Okay.
Huh? Is he saluted Hitler? You know,
it's just a,
as he got a bomb strapped around his
waist as he got a mosquito on his head
that's biting him, him. So he
has babies with little heads.
Okay.
Jesus fucking Christ the
God damn the hysteria.
Okay.
The hysteria that these news
organizations social. Yeah.
Media in all of this shit has created,
yeah. Can you just need, I'm just,
I'm fucking, while I'm walking away,
man, I'm walking away. I'm done.
I don't need to know what's going on.
I don't need to be informed. Okay.
Because walking around in a constant
state of fucking hysteria is,
I don't think that that
is being informed when,
okay.
My Real, my reality, my day
to day is I get in a car,
I drive to a building and I write
dialog for cartoon characters.
Occasionally I get to play drums.
I do stand up.
I hang out with my wife in his APP by,
right.
I hang out with my daughter and that's it,
but I put on the news and I will literally
think that there's a glacier melting
right above me that's going to drown me.
Polar bears are going to swim in and
eat meat with fucking a bomb strapped
around their fucking waste.
Everybody fucking relax,
fucking relax and all these people fucking
going on there and they just show it,
show got on TV and told Trump supporters.
I love these people that like,
you know, on these fucking news channels,
they go on and they fucking, you know,
give the other side a piece of their
mind as if the other side even sees it.
They're too busy, like watching their
own shit. And even if they see your shit,
you're not going to sway them.
I'd equate it to the,
all those years I lived in New
York City as a Boston red sox fan.
During that time I didn't have
money for the baseball package,
so I used to watch the yes network.
I always watched Yankee home games,
always home away,
whatever.
I rooted against them the
entire time I watched them.
I watched more Yankee Games from 1999
to 2007 then I watched red sox gangs.
So in theory I should have become
a Yankee fan, but I, I did not.
Yeah.
Because I was a staunch,
uh,
red freckled faced red
sox fan and that's it.
So all these people going on TV
talking about these fucking people.
Now these fucking jerk offs are
going to go up to Boston, right?
You know, 18 fucking jerk offs, you know,
I know it's more than that, but everybody,
oh my God. And then Nancy's taking
over and then they're going to,
they're gonna show the fucking footage
of Boston and busing and all of that shit
from way back in the fucking day.
Is this a perfect storm?
I racism?
Is Hitler really dead when we return it?
His body was never found.
Yeah.
According to reports,
there was an angry look and jerk off
riding around in a Mercedes Benz spotted
just last year
down in South America. Um,
I'm done with all of them.
It's absolute fucking history out that
these people are losing their fucking
minds, losing their minds,
screaming and yelling at each other.
Nobody's listening to anybody.
Everybody's acting like
the fucking sky is falling.
One fat fuck shoots off a fucking
missile and everybody loses their shit.
One missile, we do that every fucking
day. We're worried about this guy
when fucking fat guy with,
I just don't understand the level of
fucking freak out that's going on,
you know?
Okay.
It's fine. Yankees were playing
the red sox this weekend.
All right. College football's
coming up. Nfl Football,
baseball playoffs are coming.
It's all going to be fine.
All right.
I gotta tell you,
there's always been Nazi supporters and
they've kind of always have rallies,
but at the, it's not like they're
growing, you know what I mean?
Are they, I mean, I, I
gotta be honest with you.
You don't get any wider than me
and I've never gotten a flyer.
No one's ever asked me to join. I
don't walk down the street. Hey, hey.
Guten tag.
Look, I'm not saying these
aren't important issues,
but I'm just saying the level that
people are fucking freaking out.
All right? Just need to fucking
relaxed. Just fuck of a Laxman.
Okay. You can vote against
whoever you want to vote against.
Okay?
Very soon,
right?
Isn't it like midterm elections
and then there's this other shit.
You know what's going to happen. You
know what's going to happen. Okay?
This is fucking country goes way down,
way over here.
So anyways, whatever. How you doing?
How was your Thursday afternoon?
[inaudible] got good people in your life.
Jabba Sandwich today,
uh, was not delicious.
Was there a terrorist in your sandwich?
Was there a little Nazi flag on the
fucking toothpick that they stuck in your
fucking know club sandwich there?
I'm going to say there wasn't,
I'm going to go out on a limb and
I'm actually doing the Trump hand thing
right now where you put your index
finger and your thumb, your thumb. I like
it. The other three fingers stickup up.
You know what's great about it?
You really feel like you're
fucking drive and your point home.
Let's start doing that with my wife.
Okay.
I tell you right now there's going
to be cold, cold beer in the fridge.
Um,
you know what the biggest crisis in my
life is right now is I cannot fucking,
I cannot sustain
a work out or eating well
for any significant amount
of times to prevent me from
staying at the fucking weight or
gaining weight. I just can't do it.
This fucking writer's room,
you just sitting in there with all these
people you love watching them slowly
die. That's what it is. Because no
matter how few calories you eat,
you're sitting on your fucking ass for
eight to 10 hours a day and you just
can't.
You can't fucking do it.
I'm so fucking pissed at myself right now.
I'm going to have to
start doing two a days.
I'm going to work out in the morning
and I'm just going to have to like,
I don't know what to do.
I went out last night and I did a,
I did a show down at Largo,
okay.
And I stopped eating it like,
you know,
I don't know when the fuck I didn't
want to have like five o'clock.
I don't even remember what I had for
dinner. Five 30 or something like that.
Oh. Then I got down to the club and I
was hungry and I went to this vegetarian
restaurant, those fucking
things. Oh, I didn't eat meat.
Yeah, but what did you eat?
What? What was in that
fucking sauce? You know?
It's gone right to your fucking ass,
right. Your stomach. And then, um,
you know, I had one, one
whiskey, that was it.
And then I came home and
I'm fucking starving.
My wife had a little bit of Thai food
and I had that and I'm just, I'm fucked.
I'm killing my side.
I don't know. I gotta,
I gotta I don't know what
happened to by discipline. Um,
I dunno. I'm just under a lot
of fucking stress right now.
I guess that's why I'm
having this reaction to the
fucking news and everybody's
watching it and then they coming in and
then like, can you fucking believe it?
Can you fucking believe this? It's
just like, all right, Kay. You know,
it'd be great in the news that they,
if they showed the amount of fucking
people last week who didn't get in a car
and plow down a bunch of fucking people,
like a complete piece of shit,
that would be the rest of us.
And then this one fucking asshole does it.
And then everybody starts thinking,
is this what the world's going to be like?
Now? Is this going to happen?
It's this, how fucking,
I don't know how awful a fucking parrot
did that person have Jesus Christ.
You know,
I think when your kid starts putting
like the Hitler poster on the wall,
it's time to be a little more involved.
Maybe sign them up for volleyball or
something. Try to get them out there,
you know?
All right.
I Dunno what you do with that.
Is there a hotline for that one?
800.
My son's into Hitler.
A one 800 A. I keep finding two
holes poked in the pillow cases.
Um, you know what I mean?
There's unconditional love
and then there's Hitler,
right? Who's kitten home?
And then it's kind of like,
all right. You know what? Uh,
I think it's a time to ship you off to
the loony Bin and let's make a new kid.
It's time to make a new kid shot.
You know what?
You're like an old star. It's time
to golf. Which do you like Brett?
Farve when he got shipped to the fucking
jet, it's all over for you. It's over.
Okay. You can't make the pass across
the field anymore. You know what I mean?
You've lost your vision, ed, you got post
as a Hitler, it's over with Trey to you,
to the New York jets and we're bringing
in a nose. That baby, she had a baby man,
we're having a fucking,
that's what I would do.
Okay.
By the kid became a racist.
I would fucking turn my kid in and then I
would just make a new kid. That's it. I,
you know, go back to the
draft. You know what I mean?
I maybe adopt basically sign a free agent.
Okay.
You really have to have a strict no
Hitler fucking policy and your house.
You just have to have it. Um, anyways,
I saw this thing where,
uh,
people were going on to an white people
going to an@ancestry.com and we're not
pleased with some of the results.
Yeah. I mean, that's going to happen,
right?
It's going to happen.
You're going to find a couple of surprises
in there that's going to fuck up.
Fuck with your manifesto. You know,
I would love to, if he could fucking,
what the fuck did they do
with Hitler anyways? What did
he mean? Even if he lived,
he's gotta be dead by now. Right. What
was that guy born? 1890 something.
Okay.
He's so evil. Like maybe he's still
alive. Just the hate is keeping him going.
Yeah.
You know,
just picture him with like a fucking ss
walker screaming with every step trying
to get to the fucking toilet,
you know,
to take a master race shit.
Ah,
if
they only just encouraged his painting
is that it only happened then you
wouldn't have all this craziness.
Why are you still what?
They'd find something else. Anyways,
red socks up, down, up, down, up,
down against this week.
Yankees,
I think they won last night
against the mets. Soda, Red Sox,
Yankees play this weekend.
Right?
Everybody's going to have a
good time and enjoy the game.
I take me out to the ballgame.
Take me out to the crowd,
buy me some peanuts and cracker jacks,
you know,
scan your fingerprints at fucking tiger
stadium because you are a fucking dope.
Dope. Um, so anyways, I'm going
to start doing two a day workouts.
That's when I got to do it. And I just
have to, I have to fucking commit. MMM.
I'm trying to figure out this new life
that I have with this fucking writer's
room because it takes up so much,
so much of my time that, um,
you know, I have a very finite
amount of time to fucking work out.
It's still actually keep my standup act
going and all of this shit and I think
it's causing me stress. And uh,
maybe that's the fucking problem.
Maybe I'm just old. I Dunno.
I got to fight it, dude.
I can't have the fucking dad
bud. You know, we just like,
just thick it big,
fucking you stupid skinny arms coming
out the side that Mr. Potato Head,
fucking body. You know,
I can't fucking do it.
I guess also because I blew
out my shoulder, which is
finally the thing is, is,
is better now I'm going really slow and
the uh, the rotator cuff shit going on,
right? So I'm now, this
morning, I actually, for the
first time in like a year,
I had the fucking bar bell and I was
benching and I had five pounds on each
side.
That's how long and slow this processes.
And I felt like they'll just a little
something and I was going to do three sets
and I said I immediately stopped, which
is what you have to do with an injury.
So you'd have to immediately go,
you know what? Fuck this. Okay,
I'm not doing this anymore. So
anyways, let's, let's, you know, let's,
let's Google some news.
Yeah. Google cancels,
cancels domain registration
for daily stormer.
All right,
let's see what we got here.
Google has canceled all this is going
to be more hate group Shit. Okay.
Uh, Justin Bieber may been unknown. 17
year old, famous with a single picture.
Uh,
really a reporter calls out Huckabee's
claim that countless FBI employees were,
that's like reporting.
Now you just put in,
your headline is really three death foods.
You should avoid
death foods. Okay. All right, let's
just read this one. Let's see.
We say we are canceling daily stormers
registration with Google domains for
violating our terms of service. The
spokesperson told business insider, well,
where the fuck was this a while ago?
Uh,
you read Google's registration agreement,
you can read it here. Okay, go.
But one wanted service use to violence.
A source close to Google
told business insider. Um,
I dunno, I hate to do
the Cliche, but when you,
those fucking white supremacists groups,
they're just the dumbest fucking people.
Look at this fucking guy.
It's like if they went and they made
a movie about white supremacists,
guy went to the casting.
I Dunno,
I don't get people who go
down and protest the fucking,
these hate groups just let him
go down there and screaming,
yell to nobody.
Okay.
You know what I mean? Why do you go
down there and then what do you do?
You start tearing their signs down
as if they're going to be like, oh,
they tore our side down.
Now I see their fucking,
now I see their side of it.
All you're doing is reinforced it in
their head that you guys are fucking
assholes.
You should go down there.
You should bake them a little pumpkin pie,
little apple pie,
and just give him some food and just be
nice to them. That's what we should do.
That fucking guy that fatty
over there in North Korea.
You know,
Bob's trumpet golf there and smoke a cigar
with the talk about grabbing pussies.
Whatever the fuck he
wanted. The doe, you know,
steady. You'll book. We do that.
We're going to do this. All right.
Oh God.
I have to get out of this vortex here.
I just fucking Google News Boston to
hate groups. You're not welcome here.
Uh,
you're not welcome here.
We got plenty of a hate
is already here in Boston.
Know it'd be funny if other racists
and Boston were upset about the racist
coming here. They're going to take
our, Hey, go take her jobs, man.
Okay,
Doh,
we can't have a bunch of other people
coming up here dropping the fucking end
word or what are we going to do ed?
You're not wanted here. Dope.
We're not higher rent. We
got fucking plenty of them.
Um, anyways. Uh, what else? What else?
I got nothing going on,
dude.
I'm just sitting in a fucking writers
from eating Salads and somehow putting on
weight because at the end of the day, I
fuck it up. But last night I was at Largo.
I got one more show down there tonight.
Um, I worked with Joe Barton again,
Todd rex to absolute fucking bees and,
um,
they killed it last night. We're going
to be down there again tonight for a, a,
a great cause. A friend of mine, uh,
Pete common unfortunately
passed away last year. Uh,
one of the great comics that I met
on the way up and just a great guy.
So we're raising money for his kids.
So I want to thank everybody that came
down there last night and tonight raising
funds, doing something
positive, not being an isis,
not being in a hate group.
Write something positive.
Um,
honey,
when I told you I wanted you to be more
social, I should've been more specific.
That's a mom pulling up to like
a Klan rally yelling at her son
Timmy. I wish you wouldn't do
that. I really wish she wouldn't.
Could you just stop it? I mean, um,
anyways, I just can't get out of
the vortex of that. So anyways,
I'm all freckles is trying to,
uh,
invest his fucking money because
the government's taken all of it.
And I'm sitting here trying to buy the
smallest of small little properties here.
So some day when I'm in
my fucking seventies and
eighties and I don't feel like
going out on the road unless I want to.
I don't have to, you know what I mean?
I don't want to fuck, you know
what I mean? Cause you know you,
what goes up comes back down again.
And if I'd start the gentle slide back
down to doing the fucking comedy vault at
Remington's in Boston when
I'm in my eighties, um,
which unfortunately that room finally
passed away like a year or two ago,
about a year and a half
ago. The comedy vault. Okay.
Legendary rump started in 1993.
Dick Doroty how Spike Tobin,
I was on one of the first nights.
They're put together my first five
minutes write down there right next to the
fucking bag fault.
Why am I thinking of that shit?
Because right now I'm trying
to get a loan. All right.
And I have,
I should have perfect fucking credit,
but I don't because I pay off my
credit cards every fucking month.
So and they don't like that
I paid off my loans early.
They don't like that dings your credit.
They look at that like a loss. Like, Hey,
we are going to make five grand off
this loan. He paid it off twice as fast.
We only made 2,500 bucks.
We lost 2,500 bucks in this guy.
So I've given these guys every fucking
God damn piece of information they need.
I have the credit, I have the
fucking money. It's a fucking joke.
And then today they come at me.
They want two years of my,
my fucking cell phone bill.
Now I got to dig through all of my shit
to try and find that and I just want to
say to them, you can you just
tell me why you need all this? Oh,
these are the new regulations
of blood. Yes, yes. In why?
Why are these new regular,
why do these New York regulations exist?
Well,
I mean that's just something to know
exist because you guys were
irresponsible with your own country,
men's money 10 fucking years ago and you
fucking nuclear economy. I didn't do it.
I'm a responsible fucking guy.
I live within my means.
My checkbook is balanced and now I have
to jump through all these extra. Why?
Because you guys are greedy,
greedy,
fucking pieces of shit that gave
every fucking mouth breathing dope.
500 fucking thousand dollars came walking
through your back doors for good seven,
eight years in the last decade.
Okay,
now I gotta sit here digging through
shoe box is a fucking phone bills.
Okay?
You know because you're a double secret
probation cause you're a fuck up.
I love how cause they're a fuck up.
All of a sudden it reverts back to me
like now I have to pay for this since
okay,
we'll actually build this.
You the fact that they are holding
their feet to the fire like days,
you know that's a good thing for you and
your money because your money is tied
into the system. I realized that.
I just wish that when you say, hey,
why do I have to do this?
They don't hide behind a regulations.
They should say, well, because
we got so greedy 10 years ago,
the culmination of our greed
ended up with the, the fucking,
okay.
The cooking of the fucking economy and
old people thought they could retire then
had to continue working right
into their fucking grave.
That's what the fuck we
did with your money. Hence,
we need to see the last fucking two
years of your God damn phone bill. Oh,
we're taking college. Um, all right.
Let me read a couple of
advertisements here. All right.
All right.
Indochino Indochina,
Indochina,
uh,
talk about how every man looks
better in his suit. Ah, tell you,
you know what I mean? When I
look at Paul Versey, I'm like,
this guy's a fucking animal, yet you
put him in a suit. I'm like, Holy Shit.
I want to hear what dead man has to say.
He looks a lot better.
Look at him in that three piece
suit and those Jordan trees. Dude,
the Jordan's phrase with the
three piece suit, dope. Um,
Indochino is making it easy
to get perfectly tailored,
a perfectly tailored suit
at an incredible price.
You could choose from hundreds of top
quality fabrics and personalize your suit
just the way you want it,
whether it's for work, a wedding,
or another special occasion.
Indochino has suited up hundreds of
thousands of men and are now the largest
made to measure men's
wear brand in the world.
Here's how it works.
You'd drop your fucking drawers and a
little fellow comes in and he measured
from your ball bag down
your ankle. No, sorry.
Visit a showroom or shop
online@indochino.com pick your fabric.
What do you want next to your balls?
Choose your customizations from lapels,
lapels to pleats to jacket linings
in more. Submit your measurements,
place your order and wait for a robot of
your exact dimensions to arrive handing
you a suit and just a few weeks.
This week,
my listeners can get any premium 80
you think with the robots take over.
There's going to be like terrorist robot
groups or like racist ones hating on
the other ones, the older
versions. This week.
My listeners can get any premium
Indochino suit for just 379
dollars@indochino.com when entering
burpee, you are are at checkout.
That's 50% off the regular price for
a made to measure premium suit plus
shipping is free. Oh yeah. You
guys get to look like the MOOC.
You're going to look like scary.
A Mu,
the indochino.com promo code birth
for any premium suit for $379 and free
shipping and credible deal for a suit
that will fit you better than anything off
the rack ever could a loco.
It is,
but it will do me undies.
Me undies.
Your son's into fucking Hitler
due to due to me undies d
but his pants on and
watch him take his shit.
[inaudible] he's got a fucking
Adolf stash. What do you need?
Nothing rhymes. I'm fucking sorry.
Fuck. I went with Hitler and mustache
stash.
He's got a Hitler fucking stash.
You're a dope. You fucking white trash.
No one cares. You're not supreme.
You just a bunch of fucking
losers getting sunburns.
Everyone should just ignore them.
I love that whole feeling
that if you ignore them,
that that's just what exactly what
they did when they were in fucking jerk
enough. This is different.
This is different. Okay.
You don't have a you that this is
different, right? Isn't it different?
It's completely different.
It's a different scenario. This
country is on top. Germany wasn't,
you know what I mean? If this country
spiraled down in the rankings,
you know,
like what happened to the
Michigan Wolverines over
the last 20 years where they
were, they were this powerhouse fucking
program and then they just dropped out at
site, flatlined for 15 years. That's
when, that's when they can take hold.
But you know everybody and
everybody's got their fucking,
everybody's walking around with
Crocs, right? They got dead jagged,
jagged ExOne.
Everybody's got a flat screen TV.
Everybody's putting on weight like me.
It's a fucking great country. So they,
nobody hears them.
I don't think
I'm just going to shut up me undies.
Okay.
You want to look good and your
underwear and be comfortable. Right.
But that perfect balance is hard to find.
Yeah. If you're fucking mushroomed fat,
fuck. Like me. Talk about why me undies
is the best underwear you will ever own.
Feel free to improvise.
Uh,
this I just,
if you fucking want your balls
to fill nice and soft, okay.
Do you want to treat your balls right?
Basically the,
the weak point in the death star that is
the male body, which is the balls. Okay?
Cause I don't give a shit how
many fucking weights you lift,
how many fucking Kung Fu classes you
take. If you look in the other way, in a,
in a fucking,
I don't care.
A little bunny rabbit is hopping by and
its head comes up and hits you and your
ball bag.
You go and down,
get tapping out the fights over and you've
got a little bunny sitting on top of
you. And he's the new UFC
fighting out of the blue corner.
Me undies will be the most comfortable
pair of underwear you'll ever own.
Made from a sustainably sourced,
naturally soft fabric that is
three times softer than cotton.
Ultimate feel good Andries for
when you want to feel naked,
not be naked. Why? For when
you want to feel naked,
not be naked. What? That
doesn't make any sense.
Ultimate feel good undies for when you
want to feel naked. Not Be naked. Oh,
okay. Sorry. Uh, for
fellows. Hi me undies.
Diamonds.
Seen Pouches,
cradles your jewels and gives you stuff
to support it needs without feeling too
tight. Plus it gives it a nice little
outline. If you flash a light on it,
you like, ladies, here's
my junk. You know,
if you swing the other way is fellows
like a rhinestone ball
bag. Boop, boop, boop.
Uh, right now me undies has an, I just
realized my mother in Law's upstairs.
Why don't you my daughter?
I better fucking tone this down.
I just screamed like a
rhinestone ball bag. Oh Geez.
You're right now me undies has an
exclusive offer for my listeners.
Get 20% off your first pair
and free shipping there. This,
this is a no brainer to try 20% off
free shipping for 100% satisfaction
guarantee. Uh, what are you waiting for?
What are you waiting
for it to get 20% off,
free shipping and their 100% satisfaction
guaranteed and the best and the
softest underwear you will ever own.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash
bird this limited time offer.
This is a limited time offer. So
what are you waiting for? Okay.
Start wearing the best underwear
of your life. It changed my life.
Evidently it's time to get me undies.
Chain me undies changed yours.
It's time to let me on these change yours.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bird
right now. I've got to get glasses.
All right. Oh, legal zoom,
everybody. It's, it's national.
Make a will month at legal zoom and that
means it's time to take control of your
family and assets.
Preparing for your family's future
is the most important thing.
You will do this fucking
share. There's a lot of,
think about what kind of bear
you're going to drink academy under.
She going to buy. You're going to bedazzle
your fucking balls with some jewels.
But other than that,
what happens if a lightening strikes
your ball bag when you're wearing your
birth dazzle? Ryan Stone. Me
Undies, Huh? And your fin,
you die. Oh, you're nuts. A cooked
and you don't feel like a man.
You're too depressed to work. That's why
you need to make a will this month. Okay?
But it's hard. Who wants
to think that hard? Well,
legal zoom created an estate
planning kit to get you going.
Go to legalzoom.com/prepare
to get your free kit.
You'll get a ton of helpful Info,
plus legal zoom discounts.
All things you need to
stop procrastinating.
Start preparing you for
your family's future.
This is the greatest thing I ever did.
I get a will, right? So right now,
you know I didn't give a shit. I'll
fucking walk right up to an alligator.
What do you got buddy? Right? I
don't care. I'm covered. Legal Zoom.
Design a designed this kit to provide
the tools you need all in one place.
Whether a will or a trust
is right for you. I do both.
I have a will and a trust.
All right. Do not revive me.
Light me up. Do not bury me
in the ground. That's it.
Sprinkle my ashes over a dumpster.
Move on.
Um, I should actually say, just put
me in the ground. No coffin. Right?
There you go. No coffin. Just let
me fucking decompose. Naturally.
Feed the fucking soil.
You know dumb it is that we actually,
you put a box in the ground.
It's so fucking stupid.
You're dead sober.
But what if I still feel something?
Then you'd still be alive, but she dead.
You know like those people
who won't get cremated,
but they're going to sit there and wait.
Somebody's fucking drain
all the shit out of him.
Take out all your fucking Oregon's and
then fill it up with formaldehyde or
whatever the fuck they do.
Or You could just get it over with.
If you actually feel anything.
You just be like, hey,
like a fucking minute and a half and, and
then it's over. What do you die again?
Anyways,
if you have any more questions,
you can always get advice from their
network of attorneys available in all 50
states.
Since legal zoom is not a law firm,
go to legal zoom.com/prepare today.
There's no obligation,
just great resources to help you protect
everything you can get during national.
Make a will month. That's
legal, zoom.com/prepare it.
And I have to tell you something.
If you're married and you have kids,
you have to do that. There's so many
guys out there, they're just afraid of,
of thinking about their own mortality.
And I have to tell you, it's, it's a,
it's a weight off for your chest. All
right? Cause when you get to my age,
you're going to see,
unfortunately,
people dying who don't do that stuff.
And how they leave their loved ones is,
is the second tragedy. Um, you know,
so don't fucking do that to
the people you love. All right?
Being dead serious here. Dead
fucking serious. No Pun intended.
You've got to fucking do that.
You gotta take care of them.
You're going to die fucking deal with it.
All right.
And God knows if you've
got a woman in your life,
you're going to die sooner rather than
fucking later with all of the shit that
they do. They just, you know, they can't
help it. That's just what they are. They,
they give they love and they take,
that's the balance. You know,
everything that they give your kid a,
they take away from you and
then you just slowly died.
This lonely existence in a
room full of other people.
And that is the podcast for
this afternoon. I'm kidding. Um,
that's everything was fucking around
today on this podcast. But seriously,
stick your head out the window. You
know, just fucking everybody relax.
Fucking relax.
Fucking Christ. He could
see these God damn people. I
mean, the two fucking stupid.
They're, they're, they're too
fucking stupid to brush their teeth.
They're going to run a country.
Um,
and what does everything always go back
to Germany to this was like jeopardy and
the fucking 1930s. Well,
why isn't it like Russia?
Huh?
Why is it our country in the fucking 16,
17 and 18 hundreds?
It wasn't exactly a great place to
live for a lot of fucking people. Um,
oh Jesus. Now I'm doing it.
I'm talking to the fucking,
I don't know what I'm doing. Am I, am I
ranting and raving now? I have no idea.
All I know is I'm going to be in a good
mood today and I have to do two a days,
two a day. So I don't look
like a freckle doughboy here.
I worked out this morning,
you know,
I did my little half hour on the fucking
elliptical and I hate to throw the
weights around.
Now the most crucial thing is what I eat.
And when I stopped fucking eating.
All right,
so I already got it tonight.
I stopped eating at five o'clock.
I'm having a Turkey Patty with the
Tabbouleh Salad and then that's it.
And then I have to drink waters
for the rest of the fucking time.
And then to make up for my,
since last night,
I'm going to skip rope for
fucking three rounds, you know,
try to burn off some shit that way.
And uh, maybe that's what I'll do.
I'll do fucking two days. So what
I gotta do, I know what I gotta do.
I gotta fucking get out of this
writer's room. That's what I have to do.
Maybe instead of taking a lunch,
maybe I'll fucking bring an elliptical
into the office and why we pitch jokes.
I'll just be on the fucking thing.
And everybody in the writer's
room just takes a turn, you know,
or every time you pitch a joke
and it doesn't get a laugh, Yo,
10 minutes on the fucking elliptical,
you know,
our whole fucking room will
look like a, you know, the,
they look at the end of the Tour de
France. We just burned so many calories.
Like your body's like eating yourself.
Um,
they'd be going to the table reads by
episodes eight and nine being like,
you know, it's a funny
show, but Jesus Christ,
if fucking Amaziah what kind
of show we do it here. Um,
they put their heart and soul into this
fucking thing. Um, oh wait a second.
All of a sudden and getting loud in my
ears. Oh, I turned it up by accident,
brushed against him with my forearm
there. All right. Um, hey, by the way,
I got a new band that I'd been listening
to and I'm not going to remember the
fucking name of them
cause I know my phone.
So really weird name for a band.
Let me see.
I'm opening my fucking iTunes,
go to artists.
I know it begins with an a,
this is getting everybody excited.
Please say my alt J.
I downloaded this album called this
is all yours and I fucking love it.
Great album, great album to
chill out to. I listened,
I worked out to it this morning
cause it was early in the morning.
It's kind of fucking, you know, you know,
creepy and mellow and all
that type of stuff. You know,
I guess I knew I was going to get
on the fucking s scale, but um,
I had never heard of them. And Josh,
Adam Meyers from the goddamn comedy jam,
he actually, when I was
on the road, he goes, Hey,
I'm going to go see this band
tonight. Uh, all Jay. I'm like, what?
I thought it was a Typo.
It's a l t lowercase Dash,
capital j. Uh, I really
enjoyed them. And once again,
you math has a new album coming out
next month. All right, that is it.
Please listen to the music.
A little interlude here before we give
you another half hour of greatest hits
from a Thursday afternoon
podcast from a Thursday,
from a Thursday that went by on a Thursday
that you didn't even pay attention to.
All right, that's it. God bless you.
Thank you for not being a
Nazi. Uh, I'll download.
I have a good weekend. You can
sit. I'll talk to you on Monday.
Nice.
No
body.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and this is the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
August 17th,
2007 or 2009. Why can't I
have a decent date, right?
I actually,
this is the second time I started the
podcast because I always just start it and
then I go to say the date and I
realize I don't know what the date is.
So I'm sick of doing that. Like I just
did that and I fucked up the date.
I was like, I do this every time. People
are going to think it's a gimmick,
like always deliberately fucking
up to date. So I just hit stop.
I hit a race and I started over
again and I fucked up the year.
Just something wrong with my brain. You
know what it was? Cause it was the 17th.
Then my brain was thinking seven.
So then when I went to say the year,
I say I said 2007 in case you're
wondering case you're wondering.
Um, anyways, I'm actually, uh,
it's Sunday when I'm doing
this podcast because a,
if you listen to this east
coast time in the morning,
I'm on an airplane right now. And uh, I
just got a bunch of shit to do tomorrow.
So I figured, uh, I'm not doing anything
today. Why not bang out a podcast,
you know,
anybody can go out in Atlanta and hang
out with another human being. You know,
it takes a real secure fucking loser
to, uh, you know, still being his fucking
hotel bed at what the fuck time is it?
1220 in the afternoon. Ah, Jesus Christ.
I'm watching the, um,
whatever the fuck golf major,
this is the PGA.
I'm actually betting against tiger
woods kind of have this ongoing a bet.
I keep betting against tiger woods with
a another comic friend of mine who is of
African persuasion, you know, basically,
cause I've kind of not been
watching baseball lately. Uh,
I've been trying to pick up new sports
and the only way for me to get into golf
is to have stupid ass bets.
So I figure I'll bet against not only
while they bet against tiger woods,
I will bet against tiger
woods with another black dude.
And I will, uh, you know, just
to make an interesting, you know,
okay,
say dumb shit, like golf's a white
man's game. I'm betting on Ernie els.
You know what?
I actually won in the fucking masters,
I bet on Phil Mickelson and I won
that one cause he'd beat tiger woods.
And then I dunno, I got busy and I
could have one another. You know,
we bet like 25 bucks a major,
I could have won the US Open and I
also could have won the fucking, uh,
that one over there in
England and I blew those off.
And I think I'm going to lose today.
It's weird. I'm betting against tiger,
but you know, my money is, but I'm
actually rooting for him, you know?
Is that exciting now? I don't think
it is either. Anyways, let's, uh,
let's plow ahead here. I'm going to
fucking bad mood. I had a really,
I had a really bad show last night.
Now the guy had a bad show.
I went up there and I did this whole
bid on Michael Vick coming back and it
killed and everybody was having a great
time. And then at the end of my set, this,
this woman comes up to me and,
uh,
you know, like when someone's gonna win
salt, you, you know, rather than having a,
I'm going to insult you,
look on their face.
They come up and they have an ear to ear,
like Africa's Strada Grin on their face.
Okay.
You know, that's what she was
doing. And she was just going
to like, hi. Hi. How you,
yeah, yeah. That whole thing of
our Michael Vick. Yeah. Yeah.
Did you really believe that? Is that
really how you feel? Yeah, and I,
I immediately knew. I'm like, Oh
God, this is a dog lover. Here we go.
So I was just like a, okay, ma'am.
All right, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I didn't like the show. Uh,
you know the just jokes,
if you want to take them seriously,
go ahead and take them seriously.
And then she just getting, yeah,
yeah, yeah. Cause you stayed.
Me and she statements are really ignorant.
I just say,
you should know that she's
like nodding and smiling.
He stayed me through really ignorant. It's
like, first of all, why are you smiling?
You know, I, I, that was the most annoying
thing. Not that she came up to me. I mean,
he's my own God damn fault.
I fucking,
not only do I go on stage and
I say a bunch of stupid shit,
but then I stand there
like an idiot selling DVDs.
I'm opening myself to somebody coming up
to me and telling me to go fuck myself.
I don't have a problem with that.
That comes with being a fucking shithead
who sells DVDs at the end of a show.
All right,
so I totally could have avoided that.
So I'm not complaining about that.
What I'm complaining about is people
who are telling you to go fuck yourself,
but there's smiling like, is that
supposed to like mind? Fuck me.
Like I'm gonna like I'm not even going
to notice what you're saying. Yeah.
Like wow. It sounds like she's telling
me to go fuck myself, but she smiling.
Maybe I'm hearing this wrong.
And then she's like,
your statements are really ignorant and
she's nodding like, you know what I mean?
Like that bugs bunny shit. Like remember
that when he, when he would be like, no,
the other guy would be
like, yes, no, yes, no.
And at some point he would switch and go.
He would switch over his fucking argument.
Then the other guy would end up
arguing bugs bunny's argument.
That's what the fuck she was trying to do.
To me.
Your statements are really ignorant and
she's like nodding like I'm going to be
like, yes, my statements were
ignorant, so I said, lady,
so basically what you're telling me is
because I don't agree with your point of
view, that that makes me ignorant.
And then she pulls this, this thing,
she goes, I'm actually a member
of the humane society. All right.
You know,
first of all,
who the fuck breaks out credits during
an argument? You know what I mean?
She says it right and I'm a member
of the humane society, right?
Like it's supposed to be like this
dunk, dunk dog fucking moment. Oh Shit.
Are you a member of the humane society?
Good Lord.
How many years at college did
it take to get that Holy Shit?
Did you have to go through medical
school to become a member of the fucking
humane society? I actually for
half a second was like, wow,
I actually thought that she was on the
board of the humane society. First of all,
I don't even know what the
fucking humane society is.
Humane sounds like human to me,
like you're into people,
but evidently it isn't.
You're into fucking animals.
So I'm sitting here later on tonight,
I'll fucking annoyed with this lady.
This lady has, Jerry
Lewis would say, right,
I'm all fucking annoyed with this
lady thinking like a, then I'm like,
wait a minute.
She's a member of the humane society.
You know, I was a fucking member
of, uh, the fuck is that, that,
that thing now of course I can't remember.
You don't want to take it right
now is how fucked up my brain is.
I'm thinking a apocalypse now.
Amnesty International.
I know it was an a because I,
for some reason I thought there was a pa,
I was a member of Amnesty International
for like, like two, three years,
you know,
that was against torture and people
around the world and he and I became a
member.
I gave him 25.
I went on the Internet
and I gave him 25 bucks.
I have no fucking idea what
they did with the money.
I don't know if they stopped
someone from getting tortured.
I don't know if they just took that
money and they both do, you know,
a couple of them went out to a movie.
Okay,
Eh, 25 bucks, we'll go to the matinee
can, I was probably eight bucks each.
It's enough for some popcorn to
two tickets in a popcorn plant. Do,
we're not going to stop torture.
Um, so that's what I did.
So let me go on the fucking Internet.
Let me look up this, this, uh,
this humane society.
And uh,
so I went to a humane
society.org and sure enough,
this is all you have to
do to become a member.
It's $19 a month or
whatever you can afford.
So I could give these fucking people a
dollar a month and then I too could walk
around and be a total fucking cunt and
then throw out my credit that I am a
member of the humane society.
And you know what?
I'm going to fucking join
the humane society at $1.
So the next time I do
this Michael Vick bit,
when one of these fucking psycho people
comes up to me having memory of the
humane society. Oh Shit. You
know what? So Am I. Holy Shit.
I can't believe I didn't see it,
the meeting. Oh, that's right.
Neither one of us go to him.
There is no fucking meetings.
Okay.
A member of you made society,
you want to fucking,
I can't build sheet through that outlet.
She was on fucking like,
she just did the tonight show.
I'm the head of NBC.
You will never get a show on my network.
That's the way the fuck she was saying it.
God dammit.
It got worse. It got worse. So you
know me, someone's being a con to me,
no one can help cut me.
So you know,
I'm actually upset with myself
because I allowed her to make me mad.
As you can tell, considering it's
fucking 12 hours later and I'm still on,
I'm talking about it alone in my hotel
room with the drapes, pulled clothes.
This is how I always do it on the road.
Fucking sitting around like
Howard Hughes. Um, yeah.
So then she goes, uh, you know, I remember
the humane, the humane society and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah. And
I said, look, okay. You know,
I don't under why do people
take comedy seriously?
Okay.
There was a standup comedy
show I'm not doing, I'm,
I can't even begin to tell you
guys how many times am I act.
I say that I'm a moron. You guys listen
to my podcast. You know I'm a moron.
Actually.
Some people don't.
I had some guys send me this fucking email
this week on bill for the love of God.
Stop talking about banks. You
sound like a moron. Read this shit.
What do you mean read this shit that is,
goes against everything that I am.
I don't fucking read. And like, I
love how you talked about those banks.
You sounded like a moron. And what
when I talked about the other shit,
I sounded intelligent.
Okay.
It's a fucking podcast.
Just stand up back.
I don't, I don't, I'm buff. All right.
You know what? Look at, here I go again.
I'm allowing myself to get fucking
worked up this shit. So anyways,
couple more back and forth go.
And then she just realizes
that I don't give a fuck.
I said something like, well, you
know what you should do ma'am,
is what I always say when somebody just
says that they don't, uh, you know,
enjoy me and they just want
to keep telling me how much
they don't enjoy my act.
What I always say to him, I was like,
well, you know what you should do.
You should never come to one of
my shows again. That'll show me.
So then she finally realizes that I don't
give a shit about our humane society
fucking credit that she
basically purchased. You know,
it's uh,
being a member of the humane society is
less respectful than when they give some
famous person and honorary degree because
at least the celebrity didn't fucking
pay for it.
He didn't go and go to Syracuse
university.org and give $19.
So he could be like, I am an honorary
degree from fucking Syracuse University,
you know? So anyways, so that's why I
say, so let's lady. All right. You know,
you know what you should do.
You should never come to one of my
shows again and that'll show me.
And at this point,
this kind of some people around
me that it's starting to laugh.
So then this girl just,
you know,
who's a member of the humane society
because she cares so much than just,
she just starts going for my jugular.
She goes, yeah, well, you know,
smiling and nodding, right. This is creepy
fucking smile. And this whole time too,
she's got a clump of
lipstick on her upper lip.
She's one of these girls you could tell
was hot when she was in her twenties and
now she's doing the worst thing that you
can do is you're trying to hang onto it,
you know, so she looks like, you know,
one of the real housewives
of fucking Tupelo,
Mississippi or wherever the fuck she's
from. Right. And she's going, ah,
she's gone out. Yeah, yeah. Well you're
doing great, right? You're doing great.
You're here at the punchline. Hi, you're
doing great. And I'm like, yeah, you know,
show kind of seem to be selling.
Well, she goes now. Yeah,
it's great. You know? Yeah,
you are on Hbo. And now
you're here, you know,
and it's like, lady, so are you.
You're here too and you fucking
paid to come here to watch me.
What is your fucking point? And
she's like, and I didn't pay,
I didn't pay whatever. And then she'd said
something to the, she started talking,
really then she did that, that,
that, that thing, you know what,
how women have confrontations.
Like that was what they do is they
stop talking to you and then they start
talking to their friend
really loudly about you.
And she starts getting that
guy get back in cases. Shit.
The funny they was,
which she couldn't have been
more than five feet away from me.
And she's yelling at, Hey guy,
get back in pizza house yet.
And then that's when I told
her, you know, lady, you know,
I really didn't want to tell you this,
but you got a big,
he got something on your upper lip
and I didn't want to bring it up,
but now you're being a jerk. And she
goes, it's lipstick. And I dunno,
I don't even what happened that,
that point I was actually mad.
And,
um,
okay.
And I dunno, I kind of blamed the
whole evening on not drinking,
if you can fucking believe it.
You know,
cause I usually enjoy doing the road.
And now this is my third weekend that
I've done where I have not had a drop of
alcohol.
And now I finally understand why
comedians want to get off the road.
I never realized how many fucking morons
there are out here because I was drunk
and I was part of the problem.
But now, now I'm sober.
I like, I'm talking about myself like I'm
actually a fucking alcoholic. I'm not.
I'm just so fucking lonely loser.
And that's what I do.
I have a couple of beers to
talk a little shit. That's it.
Bill denial. That's the first
fucking stage of it, VJ saying, oh,
what a shot.
Jesus Christ from the French.
Oh,
you know what that was from yesterday.
Don't you fucking hate like when you
do that, when you're watching sports,
you haven't done that in a sports bar.
You looked away for a second,
he didn't realize it was a replay from a
month. Again, somebody hits a home run,
you're like, ah, fuck it.
You're like the only guy now do
that was from our last Tuesday.
They were playing the rangers and
Ah, I thought, I thought that was,
I thought that was from now you
want another case at dia? Um,
you know, I like about Vj Singh. All these
fucking douchebags nowadays they are,
they're trying to bring back that
rat pack swagger and you can't,
you can't do it all right.
And the only guy, I dunno why,
I dunno why you can't wear shirts
the way they wore shirts back then.
You can't wear that fucking little
bing Crosby hat the way they wore it.
I don't know why.
I kept no fucking idea why frank and
why Dean and Sammy and all those guys
looked so low, so fucking smooth. I have
no idea why, but I was watching this,
uh, golf the other day. I got
to admit fucking Vj Singh,
he's got a little swagger to him,
you know, plus he said that, uh,
that hateful shit against women,
you know,
which really lines up with
their generation and run
that back then once they
just like beating their women with a
mop handle every time they didn't have
their raw roast beef and mashed potatoes
ready or some shit. I Dunno what,
so anyways,
I've had a,
okay,
I'm trying to figure out why that
lady bug me so much. Last night
I, you know, she was just, I dunno, I,
I felt I was pissed at myself that I got
mad and then I was also mad at myself
die stand there like a
fucking idiot selling DVDs.
MMM.
You know, I don't know. It really
just made me want to be like,
you know what,
why don't I just go to the green room
after shows and I'll do my shows and then,
you know, whatever. I'll get
an email and you know, I dunno,
you fucking sit there dancing around
like a monkey boy for 50, 50, 55 minutes.
I don't even know. He did an hour
of that show. I can't remember.
Then they have somebody
come up to you just tuck it,
say that you're a piece of shit because
of a joke and then there are a woman so
you can't like,
you know,
you know it was funny
was she was with a guy.
So the whole time she's given me shit,
it's like I don't want to lose
so I'm giving her shit back.
But at the same time I got to keep my
eye on the dude and also like not go too
far because then I got like a
physical confrontation with the dude,
which I don't want to
have in 41 years old.
Last time I had a fight 35 that was
when my brother and our red roof fan.
That's an entirely different story.
And that doesn't count either because
your brother's going to stop at some point
cause he has to answer to your dad. You
know, I, I can't even fucking remember.
Right. I ain't no tough guy. I tell
jokes. Right. So I don't want to get it.
So this guy, you know, it's funny,
the entire time the guy had his back to
me and he was trying to get the woman
out of the club and I'm,
that's the exact kind of guy who goes out
with a woman like that and vice versa.
If it's a loud mouth Douche bag guy,
they always have a little mousy girl
because nobody who actually would speak
their mind would ever tolerate dating
somebody like that man, a woman,
they would be like, are you out of your
mind? Are you out of your mind right now?
You know, it's a joke. It's
guys telling jokes or whatever.
You made your point now you just
gonna stand here screaming. I Dunno.
I Dunno. It was a fucked up
night. Then I had the next show.
I'm on stage and I'm doing my act and
I'm having a great time. And you know,
I told the story about the woman I called
direct contact and I felt like I got
that out and everything was going great.
Then all of a sudden this, uh, this, this,
uh,
this lady just walks up to the stage.
I'm in the middle of my act.
She's like, hey you, can you,
can you say happy birthday?
And my friend Heather
and I was like,
lady,
could you act like maybe I'm fucking in
the middle of doing a show at some point.
I know it was just, it was a fuck. It
was a weird, it was just a weird night.
And then after that, then I went
over to the club to 90 next door
as I always end up doing.
And this time,
this is the first time I went in there
and I wasn't drinking and I realized how
fucked up that place was. It was
just, dude came up to me, right?
And this whole week I've really been
having a difficult time understanding some
of these, uh, who, people
who live outside of Atlanta,
they're fucking accents this,
uh,
I'm standing there talking to a couple
of people from the club and this guy just
comes up to me. He's like,
we'll, I'm like, what? He's like,
will he stick sticking his hand down?
And, um, I thought he was saying like,
will you like, he was to sentence
like, will you stop standing there?
Will you buy me a drink? I don't know
what the fuck he was going to say.
Evidently he was saying his name,
he was introducing himself.
His name was William,
but he's got will,
will, and I was like, what? I right,
but this is one of those bars.
Everybody's,
every other person seemed like they were
on fucking coke. And, uh, I don't know.
This is just petering out. I
don't know. I'm just fucking,
I've had enough and I usually do Thursday
through Saturday and something fucked
up happening this weekend when I'm
doing Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
And somebody asked me this
question last week, like, uh,
asked me if Sunday was a
depressing day on the road. Um,
I don't know if you listened to my
past podcasts. I think I answered that.
Yes it is. Sunday is the fucking
worst. You know, two shows,
Friday, three shows, Saturday,
you know the big peak and you want
to fucking leave and then you,
you got to hang around the entire fucking
day to do one more 50 minutes set.
And then you've got to fly in on Monday,
which is the fucking worst. You know,
I like flying on Sundays, you
know, flying across the country,
everybody's still asleep.
They go into church, you know,
they're waking up from a hangover
finishing that last slice at Domino's.
I don't know what they're doing,
but they're not on the road driving.
So when I land at the airport,
I just grabbed my shit at,
jump in a cab and I'm fucking
back at my place. You know,
you fly back on a Monday, the ups trucks,
the Fedex guys are out there, right?
Fucking homeless people laying in the
streets. It's just fucking horrific.
So anyways,
I had such a great week too.
I had a great week.
You know,
one of the people listening to
my podcast works over at Cap,
the capitol records place and they
invited me over there to go on a tour,
which I did this past week. And I got to
tell you, it was a, it is the, was the,
the greatest tour of anything
I've ever taken ever.
Do you remember Geraldo Rivera when
he did al Capone's vault and everybody
thought it was going to be the
greatest fucking thing ever.
Remember how great you thought it was.
Gonna be like,
what the fuck is going to be in that safe?
And you'll like this no way.
This is going to suck.
And it just didn't live up to it.
Whatever your expectations of that,
where this was 20 times
that it was unbelievable.
The guy basically explained
it. Uh, and I'm saying the guy,
cause I don't use people's names on this,
he was basically explaining that the
capital records building is basically a
functioning museum,
meaning that there's a bunch of shit that
they're still using that really should
be in a museum.
I walked into the room where Frank
Sinatra sang all those songs.
Luck be a lady, Dean Martin, all them,
they had nat king Cole's piano and
they had this little metal chair.
They're like, yeah, that's Frank
Sinatra's chair. And I'm looking
at it and I'm like,
that's not fucking Frank Sinatra's chair
that looks like it should be in an ips
class.
That was like one of those science room
classes and later on in the tour he was
showing all these black and white photos.
Cause I guess back in the day the
Capitol records label had their own
photographer and they took all these
fucking pictures. And by the way,
frank and dean never
looked bad at any moment.
They want picture of Dean Martin eaten
a bowl of soup and he looked like a
fucking million bucks.
But anyways,
then you look at the photos
and there's that fucking chair.
Okay.
They had a microphone over there
that said Frank. Okay. Oh yeah,
that's Frank Sinatra's microphone.
And then they just use it.
Yeah.
You know,
I gotta just fight.
Absolutely fucking blew me
everything in that I can't even like,
they had like the masters of like
a, the band, you know that group.
Like they just had them laying,
not like laying in the corner.
They were going to be doing
something with them. And it does,
I fucking actually got to hold it in
my hand. A master. It was, it was,
I don't know if you're a music geek,
that is the,
that it was the place to go and not
to mention later on that afternoon,
one of my favorite drummers of all time,
Steve Jordan was recording with a,
some huge artists and they
actually, you know what sucked was,
they had already recorded his drum shit.
So he was going to be doing, I get some,
some percussion shit and all I
wanted to see was his kit set up in,
in the, uh, in the studio.
That's all I wanted to see.
But I fucking missed it by a day.
But other than than that,
then I got to go on top of the building,
you know,
like I was fucking dice clay and
Ford Fairline unbelievable view.
It was, it was the greatest fucking thing
I've ever done. Um, and I know what,
and if I was more articulate, I could
explain how awesome it was. So, uh,
I want to thank everyone over at capitol
records for being so fucking cool.
That was a greatest tour of
anything I've ever taken. And, uh,
if you ever want to come to one of
my shows, if you bring 40 friends,
I will still hook you up. That's how
great that tour was. So there we go.
Look at me. I'm bringing it
around to something positive.
Have the fucking Twat from the
humane society. I'll wait a minute.
I can donate by phone.
You want to hear me do this?
Let's see how easy it is to fucking
join the humane society of America.
You think they answer on Sunday?
Do they make their people work on Sunday?
That's not very humane.
Is it? Three, nine,
three, nine. All right,
let's see if we can do this.
I'll wait. I'm gonna have to
give my credit card number over.
And you guys can't hear this.
What? Oh wait the same, the number
has been changed or disconnected.
Oh fuck you. Computer woman.
I'm joining the humane society.
I cannot fucking wait for the next dog
lover to come up to me taking that joke.
Seriously. I'm, I'm a member
of the humane society. So Am I.
I have your credit too,
ma'am.
And I got it in the time that it
takes to write a check. So stand down.
All right.
And why don't you blot your fucking
lips before you walk out of the fucking
house.
I'm good,
Phil Mickelson that I,
you know,
I'll give you what else you got
to love about Phil Mickelson.
That guy always goes for the pin.
You have an order set shit.
He just doesn't give a fuck. And
then he for Putts, the guys on into,
and then he four putts.
So anyways, let me,
let's get to the podcast questions
this week by phone is vibrating. Um,
you know,
it's weird.
I have not drank and so long and I still
feel hung over cause I stayed up till
four in the morning last night. I couldn't
go to sleep. I was so fucking pissed.
All right, here we go. Let's get to some
of the stuff. Okay. Uh, youtube videos.
If you would like a laugh this week for
some reason, I only have one of them.
I don't know why. I know I got
more. I don't know. I get busy.
I fly around sometimes I fuck up. This
is actually a cool video watch. Ah, it's,
it's snuffbox boyfriends scenes, s n, u f,
F snuffbox boyfriends scenes.
And uh,
I think you'll enjoy that.
I got a couple other ones,
but people will kind of sending me stuff
that I just feel like that just classic,
um, youtube videos. Like who hasn't
seen that woman who, you know,
she stomps the grapes,
you know,
she's having that competition and
then she falls out of the thing.
Ow. Ow. Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
You know,
cause you've got the wind knocked out
of her and I know that sounds like I'm,
I'm doing a fucked up impression,
but that's exactly what she sounds like.
And if you don't believe me
a, let's, let's fucking bring
up that video right now.
Shall We?
Let's see.
A stomp stomping grapes.
Let's see if that'll work. Did that
just fucking work? Of course it didn't.
I really don't like typing with one hand
stomping grapes and I'm telling you,
it's literally,
Oh,
oh,
here we go. Here we go. This
is how she does it. Yeah.
Oh, right here. This buckets
are filled with grace.
Just fall off the fucking
thing. Shut up. Shut up.
All right.
He has a go.
Second time. Here we go.
So what's the dude? Sorry,
I'm trying to fast forward to this.
Shut up.
Why can't you fast forward these videos?
Better an hour. It won't fucking play.
God dammit.
You know what am I gonna have to
start this podcast over again?
This is so fucking horrific.
Go play.
There we go. There we
go out. You know what?
Go Fuck yourself a plate later on when
the damn thing's going to load up.
All right.
You don't.
I feel like right now I feel
like one of those news guys who,
I just threw it to the field and then
the story's not there and I got to stand
there smiling and I'm like, oh, okay.
Now there's nothing on the
teleprompter for me to read,
so I feel like a fucking moron. All
right, let's go to Asheville. Hey Bill,
I want to be a standup.
My friends say that I am funny.
I wrote down about five minutes of Shit
I thought was funny and I did a little
stand up back to my brother.
He laughed and said it was great.
I have dangerously low self
esteem in myself and the fact,
uh,
that I don't usually like to laugh at
myself when I'm writing jokes by myself.
I usually laugh at a joke.
I tell when I say it in front of people
and I realized how crazy it sounded.
I live in a small town so there's
not really any standup clubs.
There is a place called the coffee
connection, which has an open mic there.
I am a little nervous to go because I
don't want to bomb and completely destroy
my confidence.
I have to actually become a comedian.
I'm not afraid to talk in front of people.
I just don't want to fuck up in
front of other people. But, um,
here is where a bigger problem
comes in and my high school,
they have a talent show around
the end of the school year.
If I got up there and did shit
and didn't make anybody laugh,
everyone that didn't know me at the school
would think I'm some dusty cunt that
just was up there for the
attention. I think. Uh,
I would just use the classic,
I was just fucking around.
I wasn't even serious line,
but inside I would still feel like shit.
Do you have any advice that
could help me? Yes, I do.
Okay.
All right.
First of all,
having low self esteem and
couldn't sort of hating yourself.
You have the foundation for
becoming a comedian. Um,
you got to give yourself permission
to suck and you got to give yourself
permission to grow in the beginning,
which means you have to go out and you
have to perform in front of people that
you don't know the last fucking
thing that you want to do.
Okay.
Not knowing how to do stand up would be
to go on in front of your entire high
school. I mean that,
you know what maybe at that takes Dat,
right?
Did the fact that you're
even considering doing that,
you have way more balls than
I ever had at your age. Okay.
See already fucking ahead of me.
And not to mention that you're still in
high school and you're already starting
it. So I didn't start doing
standup till I was 23, almost 24.
So you're way ahead of the game.
There's no fucking reason to put yourself
into that situation unless you feel
confident. You know, if you
feel confident, you feel
like you're going to destroy,
who knows? You might bang one of them
fucking cheerleaders there. But uh,
but then that would probably boost your
self confidence and it'd be like, well,
maybe I'm not a Douche and then you just
get some regular job and you'd never
get into show business. Um, but I digress.
Now you've got to give
you got to you something.
I did stand up and for the first year I
didn't tell and none of my friends even
knew I was doing it.
I think one of them knew and
nobody saw me for the first year,
I wouldn't let anybody cut my,
my family knew that I was doing it and
I would not let any of them come out to
see me do it. And um, I didn't let my,
my parents first saw me.
I started in March of 1992 and my parents
first came out to see me in March of
1993 and I've always been
blown away by comedians.
Um,
they'll go there first time ever on
stage and they invite everyone from their
office to come down the place where
they work to watch them do stand up.
And I'm just like,
dude,
do you realize what it's going to be like
if you fucking bomb and you have to go
to work the next day I made, why
would you set yourself up? I mean,
it's just, I dunno. So what I
would do, my advice to you is,
is first of all,
don't worry about having a low confidence
or low self esteem or whatever the
hell it is. You don't have
to worry about that. You'll,
your confidence will build as you do it,
but what you have to do is just,
you just go out and go do open mikes.
You'll,
you'll get in the click of other open
miker is you'll make some friends and then
you become like this little platoon,
you know,
and it's like you against the world.
Okay.
And everybody's going to bomb all every,
all year open micro friends are
going to bomb. You're going to bomb.
You're all going to fucking do it.
It sucks.
But it's the best stories
you'll ever tell in your life.
And later on in your career, you're
going to look back and tell some stories.
I mean, I'll tell you, you know,
it would be a hell of a fucking story is
if you went up in front of your entire
fucking high school and
you ate your balls. I mean,
that's some shit like later on
in your career, if you, you know,
if he was starring in a movie and you
needed a panel story to tell on Letterman
or fucking Conan, I mean, that
would be a hell of a one to tell.
So that's,
I mean it's hard for me to tell you what
to do as far as whether you should do
that high school show and not
all I can go is with with my gut.
The fact I got like scared reading your
email thinking just putting myself in
your position of like just picturing
myself at 1718 if I ever went on in front
of my high school and tried to tell jokes,
I mean I probably,
they would have been a bucket of blood
of above me and would have poured down on
me just like that movie Carrie
would have been bad. You know,
I got to met halfway through that.
I wouldn't, I just thought like,
what if I killed the,
you know,
say you're like a junkie. He just
keep fucking chasing it. All right,
so don't worry about it man.
Just fucking have fun. Go Out,
sign up for some open mics and just do
it in bars with his show and football
games and no one's looking at you and
you just learn, get tough that way.
That's what I would do, you know? And
if you want to do the high school show,
by all means fucking go forward.
Personally, I wouldn't do it but that,
but I'm coming from a place of fear.
So you know, if you got the balls,
go ahead and do it. But if you do
it, I want to hear the results,
so please email me back. All right.
But other than that, don't worry about,
you know,
second guessing your material and all
that stuff and thinking stuff sucks.
That's just a part of it in the beginning.
Okay.
If you think you're awesome
when you first start out,
you usually end up being a hack, you
know, and you're out there, you know,
what's the deal with Michael Jackson?
I'm fucking great. All right.
I hope that helped you out. Okay. All
right. Any, uh, next question, Bill. Um,
I want to ask you about how you felt
about parents taking their kids on planes.
Recently I had a flight to Denver back
from Los Angeles. Not a long flight,
but I was absolutely exhausted and
looking forward to the two hours of not
talking to people and hoping to maybe
catch a nap. I had no such luck.
A young couple with their two year old
Brat set behind me and proceeded to let
their kid kicked the back of my seat
and scream repeatedly. It was awful.
I don't blame the kid. Two year old
kids, they stay, kick and scream.
That's what they do.
But the kids' parents did nothing to
control the child other than saying you
shouldn't do that. But it really
pissed me off was that we were at,
when we were landing, they were asking
their child what he wanted for dinner,
and this is written in capital letters,
so you fucking kidding me.
Two year olds don't get options.
12 year olds don't get options.
20 year olds don't get fucking options
if they're living in your house and
you're paying for everything.
As we were getting off the plane,
I was hoping these people would have
the decency to apologize for their kid
kicking the back of my seat,
but of course they didn't.
I thought about telling these people
that they ought to both get a,
they ought to both get fixed because
they were absolute assholes and all they
were doing was raising another absolute
asshole and adding one more to the
fucking population.
Um,
but I kept my mouth shut because people
like that see nothing wrong with their
behaviors. So what's the fucking
point anyway? Have you ever,
have you ever experienced, had an
experienced slice like this? Um,
did you think about saying something? Did
you actually say something? All right.
Uh, great question. I
gotta be honest with you.
When I'm on the plane and
the kid starts crying,
I don't know why I can't explain it, but
it makes me laugh and it makes me laugh.
Watching other people get fucking
annoyed because, uh, I don't know.
Somewhere along the line I just sort
of let go of that. It's like, look,
these people, they have kids just like
you said, they can't control them. Um,
and that's it.
But I will tell you this,
if you have a kid and
it's in the fucking thing,
cause it two year old, it's not a
person yet. It's a fucking thing.
The fucking thing is kicking the back
of the seat of the person in front of me
in front of you. You have to do
something about that. All right?
They got a little short little
fucking legs at that point.
All you gotta do is just scoot him
back and they won't be able to,
they won't be able to, to, to
kick the back of the seat. Now,
I might be fucking ignorant here because
never had a little two year old thing.
And I might be over simplifying this
because I really have sympathy for,
uh, for, for people in that
situation. I mean, I don't what,
what are you supposed to do?
I mean, in a perfect world,
you could just knock the kid out, but
you wouldn't want to do that. It's a kid.
You can't punch a kid. I mean, you can,
but then you'd have to talk to somebody
from the fucking humane society a wow.
And you know what the fuck I'm saying?
You know what I mean? Perfect world.
You could just tie into the seat.
They wouldn't move,
but you'd psychologically damaged with
them. Um, you know, damage the kid,
then you've got to live with them for
at least another 16 years before he
fucking moves on to
community college. So, um,
have I ever said anything? No, I
have never said anything. I wouldn't,
I would never say something
like, you know, you know to,
do you understand that I also
like when the plane's landing,
you know like when your ears
a pop and like little kids,
they don't know what to do.
They don't know what to do.
But I've definitely given some people
some not even like what the fuck I give
him that look like really?
You just kind of let the kids sit there.
And this is another thing too,
if your kid is freaking out,
if you're just making a fucking effort,
even if you can't stop the
kid from freaking the fuck
out, just make an effort.
This is weird. I'm gradually agreeing
with this person more and more.
Just make a fucking effort.
That's all.
When people are just sitting there
and letting the kid cry. I mean,
I don't know if they're
doing an experiment because
I've heard like if you pick
a baby up every time it
cries, then it learns. Okay,
all I have to do is cry and
then I get this comfort. Um,
if you're trying to retrain them,
I dunno if you've got to retrain them.
Could you do it at home?
I think they should sit date kids. There
you go. Yeah, I just said that, you know,
just coming in with the fucking had one
of those fucking world war two psycho
doctors just come in with an old fashioned
needle and you just drug them up.
Or maybe they could have like
a fucking a glassed in area.
Do you guys ever have that?
Like the crying Roman church,
you'd put your kid's way in the back
and they just be behind glass, you know,
so they wouldn't interrupt the pre
scaring the living shit out of you that
you're going to be going to health.
Maybe they should have that
done by the luggage. Um,
anyways, uh, so no, I've
never said anything. Yes, I've
wanted to say some things,
but um, you know, by the end of it,
you know when you're actually
going to say something,
the flight's over anyways and uh, I
had some part of flying, isn't it?
Some kids screaming
anyways. All right. Um,
what I'm in moving on to the next
part of the podcast. Oh wait,
is this video loaded up yet?
Remember my impression? Oh, oh, oh,
okay.
Here we go.
Wow.
See,
I told you I hosed up.
You know what that was?
That's the first time she ever
got the wind knocked out of her,
so she didn't know what to do. That's
what I sounded like when I was five.
The first time that happened to me.
And the first thing you learn is when you
get the wind knocked out of view is to
shut the fuck up. Because every,
anyone, if you try to talk,
when you get the wind knocked out of you,
that's what the fuck you sound like.
So you learned afterwards, once you
get your breath back, you're like, wow,
it really sounded like a fucking
idiot. It's not, it's good. You know,
you just fucking,
can anybody explain that phenomenon?
What is that and why?
No matter how hard you're
trying to breathe in,
does your breath keep exhaling
or just pushing out? You know,
it's like when you, when you, uh,
he's like, you have an a dry heave,
but you're not puking, you know,
just for those of you like a hell.
I dated a girl one time,
she was like 27 years old.
She'd never had the wind knocked
out of her in her life. Um,
which I thought was one of the most
adorable things I'd ever heard. Yeah.
It was like she was living under glass
or something. But anyways, uh, why is,
you know, how many fucking times
that happened? Me As a kid,
that was like what we did. Me and
my, I, you know, had four brothers.
That's what we did as a kid.
That's what you did.
And your brother wasn't paying attention.
You didn't have to do it hard.
That was just great.
He just give him a fucking rap
right in the stomach and the kid
fucking this. So, um,
does all the wind literally
go out and why can't you just,
why can't you just breathe in?
Why am I acting like you
guys are fucking doctors?
Why this isn't just a bunch of truckers.
Just forget it. Don't even, you know what,
I want somebody to attempt,
you know what half the people who are
going to fucking answer this question are
going to do exactly what I'm going to
do at the end of this fucking podcast,
which is just look it up and then give
me the Wikipedia reason. All right,
here we go. Here's some questions
for the week. Um, Bill, um,
on a different not that's
what someone just wrote.
I think they wanted to
say no on a different not,
I was wondering what did you think
of the song Baba O'reilly by the WHO?
I recently started listening to rock
music and I thought that this song was
incredible. Is it? Or I am or am I
just some dumb fuck no, you're not.
You're a young kid and you're discovering
the WHO and they are the shit. Um,
I would get who's next? I would get a
lie that leads start with that. Just,
just surf the Internet. They got
some great shit. Um, Dear Bill Ha.
How much drinking do you
typically do during the week?
You're out on the road all of the time
working places that serve booze and it
seems like it would be tempting to
drink pretty often out of bored,
boredom and loneliness. I think
I already, to answer this,
at least I could see myself doing
that if I were traveling. Comedian.
Is it tough to avoid being a
lush? I, yeah, it Kinda is.
You basically become an alcoholic out of,
uh,
like proximity, you know, it's just there.
It's one of those deals where, you know,
I don't know if you were in a
bar four nights a fucking week,
I would think the odds of you drinking
would, would go up exponentially. Yes.
I just said that. So yeah,
it is, it is hard to not, uh,
to not drink. I already answered
this shit, you know, I dunno,
but I gotta tell you it's fucking
boring as hell to be out here. It this,
this not drinking is
actually put me on edge.
Okay.
MMM. I mean, you should,
the way I've lived this
week out here on the road,
if I live my entire life like this,
I could run for president
and I wouldn't have to hire.
I wouldn't need any hush money.
Okay.
I've worked out the first day I went
to the grocery store, I bought food.
I got a little fridge here.
I've been eating healthy.
I went to the gym every single day.
I even brought my little
practice drum pad thing with me.
Okay.
Fucking around learning some rudiments.
I wrote jokes.
Okay. I looked at some internet
porn. All right. Right there. That,
that would fucking loser.
Governatorial fucking race gubernatorial
or wherever the fuck they say it.
But you know.
Yeah.
That's the last thing. If I could just
cut out the fucking internet porn,
mmm.
I would be completely bored.
That's, you know, I got to tell you,
that's what I am right now. I am sober
right now and I am not feeling this,
this unbelievable fucking high of like,
wow,
I can't believe all this shit I'm,
I was missing.
All I'm thinking right now is I can't
believe how fucking long the day is,
you know. Thank God I stayed up
until four in the morning last night,
so I didn't wake up until 11.
You know,
if they end up feeling like a loser
because now it's already fucking one.
I Dunno. I think I'm done.
Everybody. If I don't drink,
I don't think I can do the road anymore
and I don't think I'm going to be
fucking selling DVDs after my show. I
just, I'm not fucking doing this anymore.
I'm not going to be stoned fucking sober
and just seeing a mirror image of what
a fucking Moron I've been all these
years. All right. Overrated. Underrated.
Um, I didn't, I don't know that
I actually got any of this week,
so I actually throw in a couple of
mine. I probably got someone I just, Oh,
it's tough.
During the weeks I traveled to try to
save all these fucking emails between my
blackberry and this, this uh,
computer here. So a overrated,
I say expensive jeans. I
remember when, you know,
if you had a pair of Levi's, you were
cool. You were in the club, right?
And what would they, 30 40 bucks and
then people all of a sudden diesel jeans,
there was the first expensive jeans.
I remember in this,
this girl is talking me into buying them
and they were like 180 bucks did it,
60 bucks. This is, you know, this
is like eight years or seven,
eight years ago I remember like $180 for
a pair of fucking genes is ridiculous.
I could buy four or five pairs
of Levi's and she says like, no,
but you'll see the quality's better.
They last longer and you
know what they don't,
I think they look a little better.
I think nice jeans look better.
Like at this point then
like, you know, this is not,
I mean I think we can all agree there's
nothing worse than gap jeans, you know,
and they have like that sort of not quite
stonewashed look to them, but you know,
they just look,
you just look broke.
I noticed a lot of white dudes and like
they're at their thirties and forties
will be wearing those and they'll
have like a button down sort of like,
I'm going to go see Jimmy Buffet shirt
on and they'll tuck it into that and then
they'll have a pair of dirty white all
white Seinfeld sneakers on and it is just
like, wow, dude,
you are fucking married
with children because uh,
that is,
if ever there was the anti pussy,
that is the anti everything that is
just the asexual outfit that you could
possibly be wearing. So I've been one of
these guys who gets sucked into buying,
you know, more of these expensive jeans
and these fucking things they wear out.
They wear out. Just like,
you know, you don't want to,
you want to make your jeans last,
you've got to buy like fucking five
pairs and you've got to revolve them.
That's how you make them last. But
if you're wearing them, you know,
every two to three days, like I do like
a fucking, I'll tell you in Austin,
most filthiest motherfuckers
out there are musicians.
I can't believe I forgot to
tell this story, right? Uh,
last week when I was flying back
from Providence, Rhode Island,
I decided to upgrade to first class.
I just said, fuck it. You know,
I'll deal with the,
the fucking credit card bill,
who's one of those deals where I just
didn't want to fly and I'm so sick of
fucking flying. And they were like, Hey,
do you want to upgrade to first class?
And I was like, of course
I do. And they go, well,
we're just going to put our virgin
island fucking airline Dick in your ass.
And I was like, you know what? I
don't give a Shit Gad and raped me.
I want to fucking sit in a lazy boy. The
entire fucking ride across the country.
So that's what I do.
So I'm sitting down and on the plane
comes to skinny dude with his big titty
girlfriend and,
and they're like,
is there any way you could switch seats
with that? So we could sit together?
And I was like, apps a fucking
locally, if I was in coach right now,
give you a dirty look and give me,
give you some sort of bullshit.
I'm superstitious. I'm not changing my
seat. Fuck you and you'll love affair.
But I was in first class, so now
I'm affable. Absolutely. Absolutely.
So I walked over and I sat in my seat
and they were fucking sitting there.
And the first thing is dirty ass musician
does. He's got these flip flops on,
right? And His fucking toes,
it looks like, you know,
now I know why people wash Jesus's feet.
That's all I can fucking tell you. Okay?
This fucking guy, he looked like
he looked like a bird of prey.
That's the only way to describe his
fucking toenails and everything.
And he did the most disgusting fucking
thing I've ever seen a human being do.
Halfway through the flight,
this motherfucker gets up to use the
bathroom on the airplane and I'm going to
say that airport airplane bathrooms are
some of the dirtiest fucking bathrooms
ever,
just from turbulence alone.
And the fact that it's so fucking cramp,
this dirty motherfucker got up in his
bare feet and just walked into the
bathroom in his fucking bare feet.
I couldn't believe it. I, I, I
was just a, does this, no fuck,
there's no fucking way.
There is no fucking, and he
just walked right in there.
I mean, he should've got a
tetanus shot when he came out.
I couldn't fucking believe it. How filthy
is that? And you know what kills me?
Women love fucking love.
Musicians absolutely love them.
CanNot get on their knees quick enough
to jump down into their crab infested
pubes and stick that fucking
read in their mouth. You know,
could give a fuck, could give a fuck about
comedians. What a, what a women doing.
FDN The comedy show,
they come up and they'd say,
you're a loser for the place
you're fucking working in.
And then talk about what a piece
of shit you are really loudly,
which brings me to my underrated,
underrated for the week.
Learning how to play an instrument.
Unbelievably underrated, you know,
cause he's really stick with it.
You can get in a band
and I even if you suck,
you're going to get some pussy and
a, and if not, it's, it's just,
it's so much better than reading and
it's better than, you know, you read,
what are you doing? You
know, you're getting smarter.
So what are you making the person's
day next to you better you're not,
but you actually learn how to play guitar.
You can play drums or something like
that. I Dunno. I just think it's,
I think it's a great fucking
thing. Um, you know what?
I'm actually excited because I actually,
you know,
I told you guys about this Les Paul
Guitar and by the way, God rest his soul.
You know, Les Paul died this
week and I'm really bummed.
I never got a chance to see that guy.
That guy was still playing shows
every Monday night in New York City.
And when I was back in New
York for the month of June,
I actually tried to go see the guy.
And um,
unfortunately the night I was open
where I could go see him, he was a,
he wasn't performing that night, so I
didn't get a chance to see him. And, uh,
I'm really sad about it
because, um, I dunno,
that guy is legendary.
I mean, I'm trying to see who I would
put that guy up with. I mean, he,
he's right up there with, for
me anyways, all the inventors,
I'm so stupid. She says Christ, but you're
gonna put them up there with Einstein,
the light bulb, because the guy
fucking did some with a guitar.
You know what I'm going to, and my world
is important. If you guys, if you're not,
if you're not into a, if you don't play
an instrument or anything like that, just,
just Google images for a,
a Gibson Les Paul,
and just look at how beautiful that is.
It's literally,
it's literally a fucking work of art.
And even if I didn't attempt to play
guitar, I think I would still own one.
Rather than going out
and buying a painting,
I would actually buy a Les Paul because
that's how fucking beautiful they are.
But anyways,
I'm actually learning how to play guitar.
And a last week I discovered drop d
tuning and it might've been the greatest
sound I think I've ever produced
as a human being on that Les Paul.
It just fucking sounded
unbelievable. And, uh,
I can't wait to get back to my
apartment to take out that guitar,
to not read, to not watch TV and be
informed on what's going on in the world.
So I can continue to sound like a moron
on this podcast so some people can
continue to take me seriously and
tell me how fucking dumb I am,
even though that is my point of view.
What am I talking about? All right,
let's wrap up with this.
Now. You know, we have to do,
we actually have to hype some of my
shit. Okay. And by we, I mean me,
I need to get better at this
type of stuff. All right.
And this is what I am going to be hyping
for the rest of the biggest date that I
have on the horizon for me,
believe it or not,
is my Improv Gig in
Ontario, California. Okay.
I live in Los Angeles and I'm not able
to perform out in the La area because I
have not shown to the
clubs that I am a draw.
You know, it's, it's a weird one.
I gotta I gotta get on the, the,
the Latino radio stations out
there so I can get, you know,
a significant portion of the population
to at least kind of know who the hell I
am. Because, you know, I don't want to
get on a fucking plane every other week.
I just don't want to do it.
Um, I just don't want Ai.
Every once in a while I would
like to fucking, you know,
just be able to get in a car and drive
like I did when I lived on the east coast.
I drive down to Philly,
I drive up to Boston.
I take the fucking train down
to DC, you know. So anyways,
I have this Gig at the Improv in Ontario,
California.
It's a from September 17th through the
20th for the love of God can you and 58
of your closest friends buy some
tickets and come out to that show.
I never begged people to come out
to my shelf. Maybe I do, but I,
I don't grovel right now.
I'm groveling for the love of God.
Please show up to that show so I can
somehow just have one weekend during the
year when I don't have to fucking,
you know,
just be sitting there in
row 33 kv changing please.
This is a very full flight olive.
The overhead space is going to be used up.
So if you have, when you're
smaller, smaller containers,
if you could just put it underneath your
seat and please don't put your jackets
in the overhead compartments. This is
a very full flight and you know what?
Everybody fucking blows it off and they're
sticking lunchboxes and for length,
fucking full length fucking
coats as the ladies say in that.
So just once or flying Tang
is four hours in 58 minutes.
Um, I would just, you know,
every once in a while we'd like to not
have to fucking listen to that so I could
just perform in a, in California.
So for the love of God,
could you southern California people,
I know you got a lot of options for the
love of God. Can you come out to my show?
Thank you. All right, other
dates I have in September,
I'm going to be in Philadelphia,
the city of brotherly love.
Do you guys beat the Braves last night?
I know that shit was going on. Um,
what do we got here?
A helium comedy club.
I'm going to be there from September 10th
through the 12th and I got a big date
coming up in the Improv, Addison, Texas,
September 24th through the 26th possibly
the 27th because I think I'm hanging
around on Monday night because the
cowboys got a football game and my life is
awesome and I'm going to go to the fucking
game and I'm going to look at those
fucking blonde,
big titted fucking Dallas whores
with their Mary Kay cosmetics.
You know who likes those bronze? Is that
guy from the playboy, the playboy. Ya,
but the fuck's his name
there. Hugh Hefner. You know,
he's really into that Tex Mex snap text
mess. The fucking Texarkana, Oklahoma,
that big round pie face fucking bleach,
blonde looking girl. You know, you
know those girls I'm talking about,
hey you, how are you doing? How
y'all doing? Those fucking girls.
Do you guys watch that show? That show
when he had those three girlfriends,
I only thought one of them was hot. The
other two were kind of a mess. You know,
the athletic one, she was fucking
smoke and that girl was hot.
And those other two girls, I had
absolutely no use for him. You know,
just cause you dye your hair blonde and
you're in shape doesn't mean you're good
looking. Um, all right.
I know I got a lot of fucking nerve
balding redhead fucking throwing down like
that. All right, let's, let's
fucking get on with it. All right.
That's the podcast for this week that I
did on a Sunday and I will be uploading
this thing,
um,
as I always do right around midnight just
to make sure that I never post them on
a Sunday because if I posted it on a
Sunday then it would be a very special
Monday morning podcast. And this one
isn't special. This was sorta me bitching,
which is sort of the standard. So anyways,
I hope you guys all have a great week.
Once again, thanks to a everybody
over at capitol records.
Let me take a tour of that
building. I had an I, you know,
one of the greatest things I've ever
gotten to do all seriousness and um,
please come out to my shows.
Uh,
the next show I have coming
up is in Stockholm, Sweden.
So if anybody overseas is listening
to this, if you live in Copenhagen,
Denmark, evidently you can get in your
car and drive to fucking Sweden now.
Huh?
Or at least I just discovered you.
Could you go over that bridge then to
the islands and into the fucking tunnel.
So why don't you come on over
and watch me talk. My Shit.
That is all the data's October, August
29th when I'm doing all right. I'm done.
When you guys have a good week, take
it easy. We have taken to the streets.
We are dancing. No
black. Walt's bad there.
Picture
black and white
sticks
stones.
That made me smaller sports,
that code
because nobody is,
we are waiting on a towel.
Sorry
Paris.
We have taken to the streets.
We are advancing a black walls there.
Paris
[inaudible].