Hey, what's going on? Is Bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon?
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast. Dan.
Ah,
just checking in on you. Ah, March 29th.
Oh my God, this Bob this almost. Oh
Ma.
Did you have a good month?
Well that's good. Um,
I just have so much stuff to talk about.
I don't even know where to begin.
First of all,
last night I watched the
first hour and a half of that,
the zen of Garry Shandling,
the Judd Apatow documentary on
the great genius Gary Shandling.
And I'm, I got to tell you a jug. Did
that Guy Proud? It's unbelievable.
You have to see it. A comedian buddy
of mine told me, he goes through it.
Have you seen this thing yet?
You got to see it.
Thank God he told me about it and I
went and I recorded this God damn thing,
you know, and I'm telling you right
now, you got to see him. All right.
I told you last week
you have to watch Barry.
If you sat down and you watch
berry storing Bill Hader, uh,
Henry Winkler and all those
guys, uh, you know, I was right.
Okay.
When are you going to learn to trust?
When I tell you something on HBO
is going to be good. Um, anyways,
I was watching that documentary
and [inaudible] I guess
Gary Shandling just kept
diaries his whole life.
It was basically his entire life and
he was writing all this stuff and
overcoming fear and trying to
get better as a comedian and a,
it was like Erie watching,
like how much I related to it because
I never kept a diary. I tried one time,
I was just too walled off emotionally.
I remember I wrote like one line,
my name's bill,
I'm 28.
I'm a standup comedian and
that's as far as I can.
Got It.
And then I think I threw that book out
so it's biodegrading somewhere because
it's made out of paper. Um, but anyways,
I used to always,
why would write down on cocktail napkins.
Okay,
dad. Right. Commit to everything.
Be Positive. I actually
used that thing, you know,
in the Catholic Church, I can't remember
the part of the mass, what you do,
the sign of the cross on your forehead,
your mouth and then over your heart,
which means you know God in your mind
and your mouth and in your heart or
something. So, but I used it as like
a positive side rather than, you know,
God's only son died on this thing that
I'm now fucking drawing on my face.
I actually, I use it as like a positive
side, like no negative thoughts.
Um, I don't know why I thought I'd
put a positive side of what my mouth,
so much of the Shit I say is
fucking curmudgeony at best.
But it was just more just
committing to everything. And um,
cause when we first moved down to
New York, it was intimidating thing.
And uh, I get on my heels and
then I wouldn't have a set,
then I'd have to wait like another five,
six days before I get stage time again.
Just fucking hating myself for going
up there and acted like a little.
Um, although you're not supposed to say
that now, right. That's not progressive,
you know, why are you saying that you're
acting like a little girl. Okay. Okay.
I was acting like a,
somebody who's gender neutral.
Why can't you just say that she was
scared without insulting the opposite sex?
Well, I don't know. I guess, you know,
I guess I think I said something I
need to work on there. Are you happy?
Yeah. Okay. Kay, can you shave your legs?
Um,
AH, fuck. I had fun last night on
stage, man. I went up when I was just,
I'm sick a bunch of shit in
my act and I was just like,
I'm not talking about any of that shit.
And I just meandered,
meandered is the key word there. But I
had a good time. I apologize to the crowd,
but I, you know what units? It was
a fucking Wednesday. All right.
Is a workday. Um, but anyways,
it's a wonderful week.
It's a wonderful week in Los Angeles.
Nothing's on fire. No
one got me too, dude.
Evidently they got all the crepes.
Um,
all right. Oh, I got to promote
here. Par still rough and rowdy.
If you've missed the last few podcasts,
first of all,
it's one of the great paper
views you're ever going to watch.
It's just regular people
that enjoy fighting.
They want to get on TV and they are
willing to fight each other. Okay.
It's like, I don't know, I don't
even know how to describe it. It's a,
it's a juggernaut and it's like 15,
16 bucks and a,
I'm going to be at the next one and I
will be ringside announcing even though I,
I bet I know what jab is.
I know to hook his overhand right.
I know what a straight right is to
cause I watched the documentary, uh,
leap Ba Yay. I watched that a long
time ago. But other than than that,
I'm just going to be making fun of Shit
like I always do and hopefully one of
those regular people won't try to beat
the crap out of me afterwards. Um,
I dunno. I'm so fucking
excited for it. And uh,
that's going to be on
April 13th. Okay. You guys,
I'm telling you, I'm,
I'm, I'm, I'm telling you.
Got To fucking see you gotta see the Sh,
you know, you don't have to, you know,
if you want to miss out and then not
know what anybody's talking about.
Come Monday when you standing
around the fucking water cooler.
Um, and uh, this is the last
promo thing I have to do.
Um,
we've added some shows.
If you want an updated list of the
shows to see possibly come and see my
ignorance live, uh, go
to [inaudible] dot com.
Dot Events for an updated list of shows.
I hate to end promos in the beginning
of the podcast because it just kills my
fucking flow, you know, now I
just feel like, and m, you know,
like I'm sitting in a fucking waiting
room. I don't feel funny anymore.
I don't know who I am. Um,
oh, here's one for you.
The theme of this podcast,
this half hour is late to the party.
All right?
And, um, which is really
a theme to my life.
Okay. I was late for everything. You know,
I stayed back in first
grade. Boom. Right there.
I was just a year behind my
whole fucking life. All right.
I wasn't late getting my driver's license.
I got that thing immediately.
The day I was eligible.
I did the old right there.
Fred took it on a stick shift too.
It's one of the main,
that's probably the only manly
thing I've ever done in my life.
I had no choice. That's all
we had in our, in our family.
We always had stick shifts. Um,
cause they were fucking cheap.
Um,
so it was more fun.
You felt you would drive in the fucking
car instead of just getting it some go
cart down though. I hate
automatic transmission. You know,
there's only a few left out there.
I think the, uh, the Volkswagen Gti,
there's one or two BMWs is probably a
Porsche. That's something interesting.
There is something that I could look up.
How many standards?
Standard dreads,
mission cars left in pro duction.
All right.
The disappearing stick shift.
Less than 3% of cars sold in the
u s still have a stick shift.
All right.
2017 cars that still offer
a manual transmission.
Let's see what we got here.
Well, we have is slow Internet
by the way. My buddy called me
up and you know, I have a deli,
miss this amazing Celtics road trip
where they went for now coming in there,
the walking wounded, everybody's out
in, all the young kids is stepping up.
And last night they played
the Utah Jazz and I guess, uh,
was it Jaylen Brown?
I'm a said Jalen rose hit a three pointed
a when I heard Jason Tatum stepped up,
uh, I'm just, I'm missing it. I'm missing,
but I have to miss it. I got the kid,
I got the kids. So I, uh,
if you guys want to know what's going on
with the new episodes of muppet babies,
I'm on. I'm on that. All right.
Gonzo Baby Gonzo had some little chicks
and in the beginning of the episode,
Foz Little Fozzie bear is,
is doing is bad jokes.
And he went to open his mouth
and it sounded like a fart noise.
And somebody goes, hey, you should say,
excuse me. And I was like, Holy Shit.
Is this going to be about passing gas
and how you handle that in a public forum
like this really progressive compared to
the shit that I saw as a kid. You know,
it was just the alphabet.
They didn't deal with bodily functions,
but that wasn't the point.
Fonzie goes,
I didn't make that noise and they looked
up when they saw that there was all
these geese were flying south for the
fucking winner. So then God's, Oh,
got all fucking afraid. There's
chickens. We're going to fly south in.
Selfishly, even though chickens
don't fly south south for the winter,
they're doing it for survival.
But selfishly Gonzo is so fucking needy.
He tries to, you know, keep hiding the
chicken so that the mother, it's weird.
It's like they're all little
fucking puppet animals and
then there's like a real
person that kind of takes care of
them and bring some lunch and shit.
It's like this sort of like,
I don't know what's going on there.
Some sort of muppet beastiality
that this woman had.
All of these kids, I have
no idea of, you know,
when evidently fucked a frog and a bear
and all kinds of ship it, I don't know.
One of them is hers a pig.
So anyways,
I'll fucking episode this. God
Damn, I don't know what he is.
He's like a a vulture.
Maybe I'm a two can,
I don't know what he is.
He's trying to hide these fucking
chickens. And then the end, uh, the mom,
you know, the, uh, the
puppet groupie there,
she comes out and she says like,
listen,
you'd get dumb little fuck chickens
do not fly south for the winter.
They're going to be in the coop.
They going to be fine.
And then Gonzo is all happy.
And what upset me was that the
chickens didn't get mad at him.
In the end, they should have
been like, wait a minute.
So like for your own selfish needs,
we would have fucking starved to
death just because you're, you're,
you're so fucking codependent.
And then of course he would try to
talk his way out of it being like,
well I mean it doesn't really make a
difference cause you don't fly south
anyways. If he says, yeah, yeah, but
you didn't know that digit Gonzo,
you didn't know that
and you will fucking content.
What the fuck are we going to stay
outside in the fucking snow? You can't,
you crooked beaked comment and then
God's Ob like I always knew you thought I
was less than other people.
Right.
And then he would make it about his
fucking nose. See that's why he can't,
you got to stay on topic because I just
fucked up the argument for the chickens.
Don't make fun of his beak. You keep
it on, on, on topic. I should say.
He keeps it on fucking topic about the
fact that you're a codependent cycle and
you had information that you knew that
as far as you knew it was pertinent to my
own fucking survival.
And you kept that to yourself.
Didn't you get a little cunt sell?
That's the shit that I've been watching.
Um, I know the [inaudible] they were
doing well and what are, let's see,
what have they been doing? They lost
in a shootout to Columbus five, four.
They lost it over time to one to St
Louis to there's two points. We go,
we beat Dallas is four points for
that week. Four of a possible six.
I'd say that's a good week.
And then this week we beat Minnesota.
And over time that's two points.
Now we lost in a shootout to win a pig.
Uh,
so we've got three out of
four points cruising along.
Okay.
Now we've got a couple of home games
against the Florida teach the Tampa Bay
lightning and the new
fucking, uh, broad street,
the Southbridge speech bullies and the
Florida panthers with the most fighting
fucking major in the league.
I mean,
I think they, I think they're almost
going to have 30 fights this year. I mean,
those people are out of control.
Okay.
That was fucking assholes. They all wrote
it. They all ruined the Goddamn game.
Those fucking constant watch.
Olympic hockey, not even them.
I can't even blame them.
It's just people that aren't
content with being millionaires.
They want to be billionaires
and now they have to fucking,
let's just level it out.
Let's mainstream it up.
Let's alienate our core fucking fan base
and try to get all these fucking
douchebags that watched the Kardashians to
fucking watch rivalry, rivalry
Wednesdays, which they're not going to do.
All right. And the theme,
this is good. Everyone.
Did you guys write in and tell
me how, uh, you know, let me,
you're late to the party stories. I
got married late. I had a kid late.
I started standup late. I stayed
back in school. I got laid lake.
Yeah, I fucking, I'd go to
summer school. I was just always,
everybody everyday everybody was
always like turning the corner.
I was always like,
where'd for B?
MMM.
I become progressive late.
Okay.
My ideas of, of, of, of of everything
else is like from fucking 20 years ago.
So here's another thing that I am,
I am 30 fucking years late.
I am so late to the party on this
band that they're actually doing their
farewell tour and half the people
aren't even in the band anymore.
Two out of the fears, two
original members. So yeah.
MMM.
Doing the goddamn comedy jam and all of
that and like trying to do, you know,
pat terror and learn these,
these double bass drum songs.
Uh, now I, and then, uh, my Trump teacher,
Dave took me to go see miss sugar.
All of a sudden that whole
world opened up to me.
So now I'm backtracking to all of this
shit that I vaguely remember my younger
brothers, they were into it go
and you got to hear this shit.
And I was listening to
a ribose has it stone
just like a,
Oh,
okay.
Just a cow.
Oh,
you know, you're singing along. Six is
say, say that's a good fucking song.
I was listening to that shit.
And uh,
when Metallica and all these other bands
came out, it was so fucking fast. I,
I just, my ear couldn't
catch up with it. And uh,
now I'm going back 30 years fucking late.
I,
so guess what album I
fight downloaded yesterday?
Slayer south of heaven.
I was watching,
I don't know how, I just was watching
blink trying to learn, you know,
all this double bass shit and I
was just on this youtube thing.
And then eventually if you're going to
do that shit eventually you're gonna to
run into Dave Lombardo and slayer. So
it was like, I got to fucking see that.
I got why I watched this mini documentary.
I guess it's a new
documentary coming out on 'em.
So I watched this older
one from like 2004 and um,
I've always tried to get into the band
and it was just always, it was just,
was beyond what my year is.
Understood.
So I heard that song south,
they haven't, and that's it.
I'm done.
So I love that album.
And I guess that was an album they play,
made a conscious effort to play little
slower than they did on the previous
album. That's the one that
has like angel of death.
And I listened to that one a little bit
and I was like, the south, they haven't,
I'm going to fucking, I got to,
I can't go from like, you know,
listening to poison and Bon Jovi and
all the shit that I listened to two
immediately going to that level
of speed, you know, that's like,
that's like when his sober person after
20 years decides to start partying again
and they pick up where they left off,
you're going to have a
fucking heart attack.
So I have to kind of ease my way
into it and this fucking album,
which I guess you know
more on fans of musical,
not fresh, it's not fast enough. Like
saying like that doesn't even make sense.
It's like,
is it a good fucking song?
So I have just been listening to south
of Heaven and whatever the song is after
it because they do that thing where
it just sort of blends into it and a,
it's fucking hilarious.
I'm going to be 50 in June and I'm
finally listening to slayer and up driving
down the street,
pulling up to red lights.
I got it. I fucking love it. So, uh,
late to the party on that went 30 years
late and I know I'm going to listen to
this fucking album a million times and
then I'm going to get a angel of death.
And I remember a long time ago
I had that, uh, I had the, the,
the Iowa album. Uh, what's
the name of the band there?
Jesus Christ with Joey Jordan said,
and all those guys. A seven Jake Day.
Thanks five ball.
The fuck is in now.
Jesus Christ. Don't say that. I almost
said no. They way they way the mass.
They were the eyes. Watch.
Ah, fuck it. What am asshole.
You know what I mean? Listen,
I know who the big four hours anthrax,
anthrax, slayer, Megadeath. Metallica.
I at least know that. Okay.
I'm an I'm new to this. Please.
Please be gentle when you trash me
on social media for not knowing,
uh, shit. Thrash.
I wear masks.
Let's see what this comes up with.
Why can't I know the name of the
drummer but not the name of the band?
What the fuck does that say about me?
Huh? Oh, speaking of which, I did the,
I did the goddamn comedy jam.
Um,
okay. So now they're showing me slipknot.
Fuck. That's right. That's right. Okay.
It's funny, the first thing he came up,
why these 11 bands wear masks?
I Dunno. Cause this smart,
they want to have a life
after the show's over.
Well that's the best thing ever.
Like that bucket had it's fucking genius.
He gets to fucking go around the world
and guns and roses and all these awesome
beds. And then the second he doesn't
feel like being that guy anymore.
He just takes the bucket off his head
and the mass goes away. You know,
probably puts it up in
a man bun or something.
Looks is [inaudible] God is possible.
It just fucking walks away.
Like what's his face at the end
of the usual suspects, you know,
straightens out his foot and just
walks right through the crowd.
No one has any fucking idea. Um, anyway,
so I did the goddamn comedy jam.
Uh,
thanks to everybody. You know,
I played the, uh, I played, uh,
was it Pantera cowboys from Hell
and uh,
I thought I had it down. I thought I
knew what I was doing. I got out there,
my Vinnie Paul Costume,
I actually,
I almost said Postmates did it.
I fucking, uh, Instagram did,
I grabbed it, Yolo, my young again,
um,
the costume that I wore and uh,
that was probably the best part of
the performance was the costumes.
Look an asshole, you know Vince,
you know he's a Husky fellow, right?
So I had like a pillow or a throw pillow
underneath this does fucking shirt and
like a fucking asshole.
When I sat down behind the drums,
like I didn't take it off.
I sat there,
so it was like a had a kid or something
sitting on my lap and this snare was a
little lower than I was used to.
So I fucking got through the song.
I think I fucked up every single Phil
and I got that in my already suck at
drums.
Why would you add to difficulty with a
pillow and your fucking chest and this
thing up? You know why?
Because it's the comedy camp,
there has to be some sort of comedy.
So I just love my double bass playing.
It's the whole fucking thing
sucks. So then the closer was, um,
was a def Leppard pour some sugar on me,
which was a song that
I absolutely fucking,
and not necessarily because it was a bad,
it's a pop song for what it is.
It's a great fucking song.
But he is a reason why I hated it was
because in 1988 my buddy got that fucking
tape.
Okay.
And all he did was listen to that
fucking song. Like why don't,
can we listen to animal? Can listen to
hysteria at no, no. He just kept fucking,
I remember a time he didn't
really know the lyrics,
but anytime I would get to pour some sugar
on me, he'd be like pumping his fist.
So was doing the song right
and thank Christ we got out of the middle
part where there's all that busy bass
drum shit then, ah ha
or that, oh shit. Right.
We got to all of that,
that whole breakdown thing.
And then we're right in the end.
And I go to hit the bass drum and
no sound comes out of the bass drum.
And I'm like,
what the fuck?
And I looked down and my bass drum Beta
had fallen off right in the middle of
the folk and song. So fortunately
had the double pedal. So I just,
I just played the, the left one for the
rest of the song. Nobody really noticed,
um, until they got to the end of the
song. And I had to do all my, my songs,
fillers and I had nothing. Oh, it's
Paul Forsee. Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the podcast.
Mr. Paul Versey.
Paul, can you hear me? Hey Dude,
I'm doing, I'm doing my podcasts.
Let me call you back. I'll
be done in about 15. I see.
Um, you know, so that, that
all of that shit happened.
So I had such fucking high
hopes. I'm like, I'm going
to fucking murder this song.
And I did in a, in a bad
way. I butchered it. Um,
but my standup set,
the thing that actually do for a living
was actually really fun and it was fun
to go out there. I wasn't really
being Vinnie Paul, I was just acting,
I was just speaking in a southern accent
and I was talking positively about Ar
fifteens
which is such a fun thing to do,
um,
in Hollywood is to dress like a cowboy
and then say why you love Ar 15.
So I mean, why, why wouldn't a, why
wouldn't you do that? All right.
So anyways, late to the
party, got into parent terror,
could have seen them live. My younger
brothers were going to go see them.
I was like, yeah, you know, and yeah,
I think I'm okay. I think Mr Right.
And I, I didn't go see them. Uh, you know,
just, I don't know when the, when
the fuck did the 1990 they came out,
we're talking, okay, I'm literally
30. I'm 30 years behind. The fucking
30 is late.
Wherever the party was.
Like the fucking building
doesn't even exist anymore.
That's how fucking late am all right.
Continuing continuing with the late to
the party fucking theme here. All right.
I finally watched the first
moto GP race and Qatar.
Is that how you say it? And I
got to tell you something. Okay?
For those of you not into with
debt is a professional, uh,
motorcycle racing at its highest level.
It's the formula one of motorcycle racing.
And I have to tell you
something right now.
I don't know why I have to tell you that.
I'm going to tell you something.
I should just fucking, you
know, cause I watched friends,
Mcdermott. Dharmic, right?
I'm going to say something,
right?
I'm going to say something
that fucking sport.
Okay.
Completely fucking sold on it.
I am a big fan of Andre de Vizios.
So who drives to Ducati and
Italian? Right? I just fucking,
I like loved the way rides.
I know Mark Marquez is like the
fucking Derek Jeter or this sports.
So whenever I get into a new sport,
you know, it's like Lewis Hamilton.
I'm not going to come.
And do you know, Oh,
this is my first year of watching
Formula One, my favorite drivers,
Lewis Hamilton. The guy will
fuck it always wins. Um,
so I can't be a mark. I like Mark
Marcus. I'm going to say I'm not a fan,
but it's just,
I can't be like some bandwagon guys.
So de Vizios so it was a guy watched last
year. I was just like, I like this guy.
He's always, you know, he's
always up there and you know,
on the podium or whatever,
he's calming.
I liked him and I liked a Yo hand Zarko
I just liked his bike and he was always
up there and he seemed like he didn't
have as good a bike is other people and he
was somehow fucking with those guys.
So I watched the first.
MMM.
I watched the first race and uh,
I had missed all the qualifying and I
see yo head Zarko has pole position.
I was like, Holy Shit. Last
year his whole story was like,
this guy is like right there,
but shit just kept happening. Um,
and he didn't quite get over the hump
and here is the first race of the year.
That guy's got the pole position. So
I watched the race. And by the way,
if you think this is a big time
commitment, it's like 22, 23 fucking lap.
She can watch the whole race
in 40 minutes. There's no
pit stops. And by the way,
it's people racing on motorcycles
going over 200 miles an hour.
Now they're going to say kilometers.
So it's simple math.
Every 80 kilometers is 50 miles an hour.
Okay?
So a lot of times they go and
like, you know, 240 kilometers,
that means they're going
to about 150 miles an hour.
And then on the straightaways, when they
go by, all the fans to start finish line,
they will get up over 300 320
when they get the 320 they go,
they're going 200 fucking miles an hour
on a motorcycle and there's someone
right on their ass and they have a big
fucking turn that they
have to slow down for.
And the big fucking movies who has the
balls to break last usually comes out of
the turn the fastest. However, if you
go wait, if you brake too fucking late,
you might go to widen,
the guy will cut under neath IA or you
could go flying off your bike and die.
All right. Now, if that's not enough
excitement for you, that I don't know.
I don't know what to tell you.
So anyway,
so I'm watching this race and your Zarko
in the lead for the whole fucking race
and, and they keep talking about his
front tire because he's averaging like,
I don't, I don't know what they're, his
average was like one 50, 150 kilometers,
uh, which would be what? Oh, Jesus. Bill,
that's like a little over a hundred
miles an hour is what he was average.
And that's, you know, with all the turns
slowing down and all of that Shit, right?
Um, I'm sitting there watching this
fucking guy and I'm like, Holy Shit.
Is this guy going to go wire to wire?
And when, and they keep talking.
This was something I need people
who are into this, this, uh,
into racing to explain to me,
they just kept talking about your
hands Arccos front tire and saying it's
eventually it's going to wear down and
he's going to have a fucking problem.
And before it happened to him and
happened to Valentino Rossi and all of a
sudden, like he was in second place and
all of a sudden on one lap he got, um,
he got passed by like two people. But
then it's like he made this adjustment,
which is why he's evidently the
one of the greats of all time.
And he was able to come back and still
make the podium and come in third place.
But when it happened at Zarko,
he just,
he got passed by two people
at the same fucking time.
You went from first place the whole race
down to not even being on the fucking
podium.
And then he ended up finishing eighth.
And why doesn't he have the same
fucking tires as the other guys?
How come?
How come his tires are wearing down
faster than other people?
What the fuck does this Zarko guy
have to do to get the best shit?
Yeah,
I know. I'm probably fucking this up.
So anyways, a Da Vinci also, right?
He was like in ninth
place starting the race.
So I was kind of keeping an eye on him,
you know,
like what's his face when I was
watching the Formula One when uh,
Valtteri Botox started way in the back
because of the gear shift penalty, uh,
changing out the gearbox fucking
a penalty gear shift penalty,
the gearbox penalty and um,
I just watched him slowly moving his way
up through the field and then the last
two laps of the race.
Okay. He's in first place.
Mark Mark has is in second
place and last year.
This is like the Brady
fucking Peyton manning.
This is star back for stabler Elway
verse Montana. This is just like,
okay,
this is Jordan verse Dominic
Week Wilkins Dunkin Content,
one of the great chaebol in First Russell,
whatever the fuck you want to call it.
And these guys were fucking riding
like maniacs for the last two laps.
Marquez is right on Davinci.
Oh,
so his ass and he just knew it
wasn't easy going to pass him.
It's when is he going to pass him?
Because he did this all fucking
last year and it drove me nuts,
which is why I became a de bitsy also fan.
You gotta gotta root for the underdog,
right? So there's like fucking two or
three corners left and they're like,
I don't think mark has his close enough.
And all of a sudden he
braked later than Divisio so,
and he was right on his ass and the
next fucking corner he fucking goes
underneath divisio. So in past them, and
I didn't even realize I was that into it,
I was in the living room and
I would just went like, Nah,
my wife comes running it.
What's the matter?
She thought there was something
wrong with that kid. So he does,
he goes dives underneath the vizios.
So at this point,
you know they're going like 90 fucking
miles an hour in a turn with their knee,
like a, like an eighth of an
inch off the fucking ground.
And he ducks underneath them.
But he was going so fast,
he went a little wide and then divisio
so went underneath him and then it was
just a fucking flat out race on
a straightaway. Just pinning it
all the way to the fucking finish line
into vizios. So wins it. It was just an,
it's everything that's missing in Formula
One as far as like, I love Formula One,
I'm going to continue to watch it,
but I just fucking hate water. It's,
it's just a race to the first corner and
whoever's in the first corner is going
to be driving and clean air
and everything. Everybody
is so equally matched.
No one's going to be able to pass him and
then you just have to wait for someone
to fuck up in the pits.
Like that's the exciting passing.
It's just like in this guy,
get out of the pits before that
second place guy comes around again.
Um, I dunno, but if you're,
if you're missing passing and Formula One,
uh,
I would suggest jumping sports. You
can watch him both. I mean it's, they,
it's not that much that you're committing
to 40 races a year. On a 365 days.
I mean, he can take them, you can watch
them whenever you want to. So, uh,
I am 100% sold on this fucking sport
and I've actually going to be taking a
vacation coming up when I'm celebrating
my 50th birthday and I just realized I'm
going to be in the vicinity of that
race and Spain and I'm trying to talk my
wife into going with me. That's my, uh,
and I'll just be like,
come on honey.
It's my 50th birthday and she's such a
sweetheart. I think she's going to do it.
By the way, a honorary mentioned
to a cow crutch low, uh,
coming in fourth place and riding a
great race and having one of the great
fucking names of all time, cal crutch
Lowe is such a fucking cool name.
It doesn't even sound like, it sounds
like an alias. Like if I was a cop,
I wouldn't believe him if I
cut some underage drinking.
All right, give me an age.
Which name? Uh, count crutch low.
All right. Get up against the wall.
He'd go downtown. I swear to God
it's my real name. Um, anyways,
all I got to go a little read here.
I got to do little re,
I get the little read here.
Uh,
and then get off my fucking
day cause I got another show.
I'm coming up where I'm
going to be playing drums.
I've got to make sure I tighten down the
fucking bass drum beater before I play.
I'm doin a Dean del Rey's.
It's is uh,
what was it, 52nd birthday. And uh,
I played drums on his
50th birthday is great.
He has a whole standup show and then
after that he came out for his 50th
birthday with a live band.
He sang the entire AC DC
highway to hell album.
So for his 52nd, he's going
to be singing the, uh,
the entire, uh, power age album.
So I'm playing a couple
of songs off of that,
so I got to make sure
I have that shit down.
And I'm also gonna make sure that the
bass drum beater is fucking tightened out.
Um, but whatever. And once again,
trying to learn those songs that I've
been learning I and really be able to play
him a whole new, already had a love, uh,
Phil Rudd. But Jesus Christ,
I mean, he's just, he just,
it's perfect what that
guy's plays is perfect. Uh,
but this can be a bunch of,
you know,
big musicians there cause dean came up
in the, in that world and music world,
so he knows all of these guys.
Um,
I think there's a flyer somewhere
out there I missed. I think that I,
but actually I believe it's already
fucking sold out. But, um, that's my day.
I'm going to go fucking play drums.
Huh?
I don't know why all you
guys don't become comedians.
You get to be a fucking kid
for the rest of your life. Um,
actually it's not that easy.
After 20 years of
sitting there going like,
did I make the biggest mistake of my life?
Then all of a sudden the clouds part,
you know,
unless you have a look,
unless you have a look and then he gets
scooped up early and they chew you up,
spit you out. All right. Oh look
who's here though. Tell me undies.
D
He's, I got nothing to fucking say,
dude. Dude. Dude, do me undies.
Biondi zip your balls. Feel
like they're rubbing on. Hey,
put on a pair up against your nuts.
They'll feel real good.
You won't give a fuck.
Cause me undies has the best under wear
and they'll feel nice up against you.
A pubic hair. Oh yeah. All
right. Mandy's everybody.
You've heard me talk about
me undies and you know what?
That I am a big believer
and their products,
they're the perfect
balance of comfortable fit.
Every month they have new and exciting
prints and they arrive at your door in a
fun bag. Talk about why me
undies, other best underwear.
Uh, I liked that my balls don't
fall out of them. You know,
if that's been a problem with like
tidy whities, you know what I mean?
They got the little pee hole there and a,
just the way it's situated, if you know,
if your balls are fucking, you know, I
dunno. Just sorta really relaxed that day.
All of a sudden. Yeah, got an
issue, you know what I mean? Oh,
does that work me undies core
copy running wired bill. Why they,
why do they have the title me undies
uses Lynn Zig Lenzing Lenzing.
It sounds like a metal band that never
made it. Did you remember that band?
The lending.
They had a couple of good songs.
Lenzing my girl modal, modal and their
underwear. It's sustainably sourced.
Naturally soft fire,
but that starts with beechwood trees
and ends with the most amazing fabric
you've ever experienced.
I have to find a making
of Lenzing micro modal,
modal. How do you start with trees and
then end up with something that can be up
against your body.
You know,
even if they polished it down like I
don't think I would want to have like
guitar grade wood up against my nuts,
but for several,
I don't know how they do it anyways. The
results have been downright dreamy man.
Me undies has a great offer
for my listeners for any
first time purchasers when
you purchase any me undies,
you get 20% off and free shipping.
Me undies is so sure you'll love
their Rhonda where they offer a 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
If you don't fucking love your first pair,
you get a full refund.
This is a no brainer.
Get 20% off a pair of the most comfortable
undies you will ever put on to get
your 20% off your first pair.
Free Shipping.
100% satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bird.
That's me undies, m e U, N D. I e. S m, e,
u. N d. I e.
S me on dies.com/bar.
I slowed that down cause I realized,
you know people have brains like mine.
That would have been too fast.
How do you spell it?
Helix. Everybody. How? Uh,
there's nobody on the planet
like you know, you're special.
So why would you buy a mattress
built for everyone else? Well,
what about your doppelganger?
Maybe you could go fucking have a sleep
over at his house working with the
world's leading sleep experts.
Those sleep experts. Can you get
laid tonight? What do you do?
Big Boy. Uh, I'm asleep. Expert.
Oh, I love sleeping. Well,
why don't you come over here and sleep
on this Dick. Sorry. He looks sleepy.
Developed a mattress that, oh Jesus,
what's Today's sensitive people is he,
it seemed once he just
advocating drugging people.
MMM.
Helix sweep developed a mattress that
customized that's customized to your
specific height, weight,
and sleep preferences.
So you can have the best sleep of
your life at an unbelievable price.
Here's how it works. Go to helix,
sleep.com. Fill out there two minutes,
sleep quiz, and they'll design your
custom mattress. What do you dream about?
Um,
they even customize each side for your,
for you and your partner.
In 2018 he looks sleep has
taken customized sleep to
the next level with the
Helix Helix pillow.
The all new pillows are fully
so you can achieve perfect comfort.
How are they adjustable?
Is really a little motor in there.
Would that be up against your head?
How would that be comfortable regardless
of sleep position of body type.
Helic sleep has thousands
of five star reviews. Well,
how many one star reviews do you have?
You're just going to talk
about the good times.
Plus you get a hundred nights
to try them up. Go to helix,
sleep.com/bird right now and you get
up to $125 towards your mattress order.
That's helix sleep.com/burr for
up to $125 off your mattress.
Order Hallux.
sleep.com/ [inaudible] spelled spelled h.
E. L. I. X. Was there a band called that
Alex Band? Was it helix? Maybe.
That's why I always fucked that up.
Were they the guys who were like,
give me an r o c k and what?
She got rock and what are we going to do?
Rock you.
It was like if cheerleaders
made a heavy metal song,
that's the spirit rebel
against your parents. Sorry,
my Internet's not working. All right,
that is the podcast. Have a great weekend.
You fucking cunts.
I'm going to be at the Brady.
The top gray dod said best the Brady
Theater and Tulsa Oklahoma with led Debbie
talks,
Dean del Rey,
and then we're going down to San Antonio
for two shows and I for the life of me,
couldn't figure out why it was like 500
fucking bucks at night for a hotel in
San Antonio.
I'm like,
what do they have some new hipster area
or something and they making cupcakes
and riding bicycles. Why is
everything so expensive? Well,
it turns out that the night I'm there,
so it's the final weekend,
so I bet a lot of you are thinking like,
oh,
bill came in town to go to those games
and I had no idea that games were there
and I'm just paying five times what
I normally would have paid for 'em.
Yeah,
for a hotel room. You don't, I just
realize whatever happened to five,
four club Faffel Club,
motherfucker
did. They dumped me. You know what?
I am so sick of being,
I feel like I'm that podcast that like
advertisers go to right before they meet
their soul mate podcast.
You know what I mean?
You know that chick who's always the
fucking bridesmaid, never a bride.
That's what I'm starting to feel.
I just don't feel that people
understand what the fuck it is.
A just cause I joked doesn't mean people
take it seriously in the God damn copy.
It makes them listen to it
rather than fast forward to it.
It's so fucking simple. Why can't you
Madison Avenue conch figured that out.
Maybe they're going to be
advertising my podcast next week.
I probably should check with my
producer before I say that.
But you know what even did
all right. That's it. Okay.
Here's a little bit of music and then um,
I don't know.
I guess the fucking we'll play in some
half hour greatest hits. You know what?
I'm actually, I'm going to tell my
guy to fucking put a slayer south.
They haven't.
Alright,
go fuck yourselves
Monday.
Have you guys seen this youtube video?
My name is John Dacre.
You got to watch this thing.
I apologize cause it's going to be in
your fucking head for the rest of the time
he's singing. He's singing a
moray and he can't remember how to
more
rare.
They can't stop watching this
guy, this guy, I swear to God,
I think it's his first TV Gig.
Somebody was sick,
I think they said at the beginning. So
this guy fills in and if you look at him,
he's literally having an
out of body experience.
So it's so funny to me because I can
relate to this person because the first
time I did stand up I felt
like I was watching myself.
I've fucked everything up and this guy,
just the way he says his name,
it's almost the just,
he says like,
my name is John [inaudible].
Okay.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's like he was outside,
so I think that might be my favorite
part of the video is the one this fucking
guy. Just the way he says his own name. He
didn't say, my name is John [inaudible].
He goes,
my name is John Dacre.
I did it right the first time
I, and I just fucked it up. Hey,
you got to hear this.
You got this fucking guy.
He says he's singing all these
Jesus songs. Hang on. Hang on.
My name is John Dick,
or
my name's John Take.
It's like he's watching life,
like he already died
and then he came back and he just got to,
okay.
Like he, first time we ever realize
my name. My name is John Taker.
That's my fucking name.
And this is my life and I'm on TV
and I'm going to sing this song.
Yeah.
This is what I did with my life. And as
you look at the guy fucking poor bastard,
oh my God, listen to
them sing. Hallelujah.
Oh Damn.
But for the grace of God,
this fucking guy would be the most
interesting interview ever. Just like,
yeah,
he's one of the most fascinating
people I've ever seen. Like what the,
what is going on in between those fucking
ears right now? I think if they could,
if you could make a show
about his fucking thoughts,
you know all these fucking movies. Oh,
it's, yeah. You know, they show the movie,
but it's done in reverse. And then they
tried to fucking flip you out. Nothing.
Not that pink Floyd could ever fucking
right can match what's going on in this
guy's head. Highly
recommended. All right. Yeah.
Okay.
What's going on? It's built and is this
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
March 29th,
2010 72 degrees out.
Her little sort of jealous.
How the hell are you?
How's it going?
I know I've been getting a ton of emails
do it. It's still not up on iTunes.
I don't know what's going on.
All right.
All I know is I just keep
recording these fucking things.
Having faith that we'll finally
get these fucking things up there.
I know we're going to,
and I'm going to go out on a limb
and say this is definitely the week
everything's going to be up there,
but until then I'm going to whore
myself out and tell you that the Monday
morning podcast starring me,
myself and I is only a exclusively on
billboard.com that's the only place she
can get it. See what I did.
I'm like a drug dealer.
I gave you a couple of free samples.
Actually I didn't.
I gave it two and a half fucking years
of free samples and then I fucking pulled
it.
Oh,
you guys are all feed in for it and I'm
going to get you to my fucking website,
right.
I'll get a bunch of hits on my website,
then I'll start selling advertising for
like tampons or something and I'll make
a fortune. Get a midget in a hawker. Hang
on. I have to sneeze. Where's The sun?
Where's this something? Come
on, give me some sun. There
it is. There it is. Nothing.
I hate that. When you feel it, it's
like fucking blue balls for, you know,
so I thought it was gonna fucking
sneezer nothing. All right.
Anyways, it's Monday, March 29th.
I have not watched one 2nd of
March madness and is always,
it's the best fucking sporting event of
the year. And I don't know what happened.
I was over in a fro and uh,
I was over in Europe, so, uh,
you know, I wasn't there at the
beginning, so I missed the whole thing.
I watched Kentucky lose yesterday and
I can admit I can't really look at John
Calipari the way I used to have to, what's
his face verbally bitch slapped him.
Um,
that angry white haired guy from Indiana
who then went to Texas and now he just
talks about games.
The fuck's his name.
I actually went to a game when I was
out there when he was still locked down.
What the fuck is his name?
I keep thinking white to his hair.
Jesus Christ. He's one of the great
coaches of all time. Come on bill.
You've been going to lumosity.com.
Okay.
Focus. Let it go. Just don't care about
it. I don't give a fuck now I care.
My brain can tell. I care. So it's just
hiding it. Just mocking me. Come on work.
Bobby Knight. There we go. I to think
of him throwing the chair. Uh, yeah,
he called you give key, actually called
John Calipari out on some kind of decent,
he said, you know, every fucking program
that this guy has been a part of,
has had some sort of problem with the
NCAA and then he jets out of town,
you know, continuing to build his
resume. And he really trashed him.
Now I'm not saying what he said was right,
but Calipari all he came back
with was a respect glovie night.
I think he's a great coach. And he
didn't that you didn't address anything.
You know, somebody told me
I killed a hooker and they
were a friend of mine and I
respected them. I would address the
killing of the hooker at some point. Uh,
in my innocence of it before
I, you know, after, you know,
after I said how much I respected
the guy. Right. You know,
I went to a game one time out there in
Indiana with Bobby Knight was still there
and he was, you know, Indiana
started to lose. It was a year.
Michigan State won the championship.
I think it was the year
2000 already 10 years ago.
And I went to this fucking
game and I remember I bought
a student ticket and, uh,
you know, showed up at that point
I was well into my thirties.
And the guy's looking at
me like, really? You know,
what do you want the fucking 12 year plan?
That's when he got to come with the
fucking Luther vibe from a 48 hour.
I've been busy,
none of that shit.
When he pulls up to the toll
booth of the parking garage thing,
and the guy's like this tickets like
four years old. Yeah, I big busy.
That was the vibe. Me, I just gave the guy
that's like, come on man. Come on. Really?
It's me. So he let me in and I
went in there and I remember, uh,
watching Bobby Knight and it was a
fucking great arena. And there he was,
the legend, right? I was up
in the nosebleeds, but, uh,
Indiana started losing and he started,
he walked out on the court and was
yelling at the, the point guard,
bringing it up to court. Like his, his
whole fucking head was just, you know,
with just with every fucking
mother fucking like is like a,
like a rooster with Tourette's. Right.
Just, just fucking unbelievable.
And I remember I got so Goddamn
mad watching him do that.
I was just,
I was,
I wanted that kid just to take the ball
and just fire it right into his fucking
screaming face.
Five,
I have a son and he allows himself
to get fucking yelled at like that.
You know what I mean?
You fucking retard control.
You've got damn emotions. All right. You
want to fucking blow up a little bit.
Blow up.
But this guy had completely lost his shit.
Yeah. Do you ever see Marvin
Hagler when he fought Tommy Hearns,
remember when he was punching him in the
head and Tommy's fucking head would go
back and his Jheri curl all the
shit from it would fly out. Instead,
he was doing that with his head to
himself, except instead of going back,
he was going forward every time
he was making a point to this kid.
It was like Ben Kingsley and sexy
beast make me look like a right cunt.
You're fucker Darren to fucking,
ah,
he's leading with this head fucking
right cross white to is fucking,
I fucking hate people like that.
Remind me of one of my relatives.
Um,
well I just really revisited that
anger, didn't I? Um, so anyways,
I was actually going to do this
podcast last night at, uh, at,
at 12 midnight now that I've been over
to Europe and I found out how many people
listen to my podcast over there. And you
know what? I'm starting to have a little,
uh, you know, responsibility for
those people. Like, you know,
I now know that England and Ireland
are seven hours ahead of me.
So if I did it at midnight Monday
nights, if I posted it then, I mean,
Sunday nights, you know, they're rolling
into work a couple hours later, you know,
and I know what you're thinking down
there in Australia. Ooh, what about us?
We're fucking 14 hours ahead.
Go fuck yourselves. All right,
the fuck. Do you want me to do it
on Thursdays every week? You know,
why don't you be happy?
Why don't you guys just focus on the
fact that you guys don't get respect for
living on the largest
island in the fucking world.
You know, Disney's should've made a
cartoon about you guys, Not Madagascar,
Huh?
What was that about?
So sick of those fucking cartoons about
animals that know about global warming
and then they teach human beings a lesson.
You know,
do you realize that like 98% and I just
grabbed that stat right out of my reach
right in and pulled it out. 98% of fucking
animals, including the goddamn insects.
There's an insect, an animal.
I know what ain't human. Um,
98% of those mother fuckers are murderers
every day,
every fucking day.
When they want to go out and get something
to eat, they have to commit a murder.
You know, they got to set
a trap. They got to ambush.
They never do with fucking face to face.
You ever seen a fucking animal, you know,
be a gentlemen,
come up and slap another fucking beast
with his glove and say, I challenge you.
I challenge you. To a
meal off. I want to eat,
you know, these pieces. Shit.
Fucking animals. What about
me? I don't kill anybody.
I go and eat an animal that's already
been murdered. I am accomplice to murder.
That's what the fuck I am. Um,
I did I get on that subject.
What was I talking about? It's
talking about Bobby Knight. Oh,
some of those stupid fucking animal
movies at Disney's always making,
trying to make me cry.
You know,
as they have some polar bears slide
known as belly into a coke can,
the same fucking thing that would
just be eating me alive. Um,
if you had to get mauled by an animal,
if you had to get eaten by an animal,
which one would you pick?
I picked the biggest fucker ever.
I want that shit to be over.
Cause I remember when that gay dude with
the Evil Knievel onesy the Joan Jett
fucking leotard. Remember those two
guys out there? Six Free Android.
Roid,
Siegfried and Roy.
Remember those two twinkle toes out there,
dance around with all those fucking,
you know, whatever they had. They,
they're cats. They were doing cats
the musical for real. What if we,
you thrill cats?
I think he's spectacular.
We just skip around and
I'll bleach my hair.
And then you put shoe fallacy in
yours. Yeah. Will Rub it's pools.
Um, actually that's bullshit because the
musical cats came out after fucking, uh,
the, the, the fucking,
those two guys. Gay,
evil Knievel and uh, and gay. Uh,
what was the other one?
What did he look like? A,
who's the other guy at night at the
Roxbury? Not will Pharrel. Oh, Jesus.
My memory is just shot Catan.
That's what it looks like.
If they ever,
if they ever make the movie of that,
I would cast a Catan Kriska Tan as the
one who gets his neck chopped and then I
would have to go with the guy who
played Bo Duke and the rob. Uh,
Nah, he's too fucking all at this
point. Who's got hair like that?
God knows I don't, even if you're fucking
bleached it, I don't get enough left.
Hang on a second.
Who the fuck would I pick?
Okay,
well, whatever there, there's your
project for the week. But anyways,
my point is when he grabbed the,
the, the gay Chris Catan, dude,
it was just over. It wasn't like, Oh
my God, I'm getting new. Buy An island,
an island, a fucking lion.
Jesus. It wasn't that.
It was just crapped his fucking throat.
And that was,
if he went to chomp and that was
it. That was it. It was fucking off.
I know, Bill, we saw it. We
saw it on fucking Hollywood.
Aina aided a bitch or whatever
the fuck that, that's stupid.
He Hollywood bowl shows he Hollywood
fucking stories about celebrities and
addition all this dirt about them.
Did you ever notice that none of
their close friends are on it?
It's because it's all bullshit.
You know,
they do like the willy aims story
and they have like his fucking made
talking all sorts of shit about him.
There's grant. Good Eve say anything? No.
Does the kid who played Nicholas
Bradford, does he say some shit? No.
None of them say anything. It's always
like, you know, some fucking PA.
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking.
I was talking about animals.
Let's rewind this for a second.
Yeah, those stupid fucking, Oh,
if you've got to get killed by an
animal. That's what I'm saying. I want,
I want to get fucking killed by
something like that. A big cat or a bear.
You know there's something about an
alligator though. I just, I don't like it.
I don't like that they have fucking
them. They're mean about it. You know,
they just did, they grab your leg and
then they do that fucking barrel roll.
You know, it's like, can't you just
fucking shot my leg off? Can't you just,
just nice clean Ginsu it and you
know, it was a major writer. We there,
I'll fucking bleed out
in like five seconds.
Do you really got out Joe
Theismann me to the 10th power.
You guys ever seen that clip?
Non Sports fans.
If you want to see something that'll
just make you lose your lunch for all you
broads out there trying
to lose some weight.
If you just had a piece of cake right now,
go on youtube and look up Joe
Theismann breaks leg or Joe Theismann,
uh, who landed on him. Lawrence
Taylor. Remember that Shit. It's,
it's a,
it's a two for one break.
Compound fracture I believe is what is
what is called the Tibia and the fibula.
Uh, yeah, I think that's what it is.
Look at me full of fucking pulling
another thing. I'd have my age.
Um, all right, so this is the deal. It's
Monday morning out here in Los Angeles.
She probably wondering, hey bill,
you know what, what does that,
what does a struggling actor,
moderately successful comedian
do on a Monday morning? Well,
I'll tell you right now.
I had a fucking audition and I,
I prepared my little actor
hard out for it and uh,
it was one of the roles I've always
wanted to play. All right. Um,
there's a few scenes that I want
that I want to do as an actor.
A lot of actors want to win an Oscar.
Of course I do. But who's kidding? No.
You know, one of my Jane Staple
Horn said somebody's name.
I don't know. Fuck, that is a triple horn.
I don't know what the fuck I'm trying
to say here. Look who's getting to,
it would be 42 years old in June.
Okay.
If I can just stand near somebody who won
a fucking Oscar, I'm going to be happy.
All right? So anyways, um, um,
and you know what I'm doing? I'm,
I'm adjusting my dream.
Okay?
Rather than going on Oprah now and
having her ask me how I became so fucking
brilliant. Now all I want to
do, I want to have that scene.
I want to play a snitch.
That's what I want to do.
And I want to have somebody
chase me down a fucking alley.
I don't give a fuck if it's the cops
are the guys I snitched on and I want to
come to the end of the alley. I want that
chain link fence. You know, you grab it,
you're trying to climb up it and you think
you're gonna to make it and then they
grab you by your cheap leather coat.
They pull you off it and kicked
the shit out of you. I want that.
I want to do the interrogation scene.
You know, when I'm sitting there,
then they're doing the good cop,
bad cop. I've already been the cop.
I did that on Chappelle show.
I want to be the guy getting interrogated.
And then the last thing is I want to get
my fucking head blown off in a movie.
So today and I have the perfect head,
my big fucking kitchen TV set head,
my Sean Penn forehead. I mean this,
it's just begging to be fucking blown
off in a movie. I'm dying for that scene,
right? And I had an audition today to, uh,
to play a guy who gets fucking shot in
the head. In the end. I was psyched.
I was feeling good. I worked a
whole fucking thing out, right?
So I go down to the
audition and I show up,
I'm at the address and I'm looking at
somebody's house. I'm like, what the fuck?
This is somebody God damn house.
This doesn't seem right.
So I rechecked the address and then I
saw a couple of people walking in holding
this sides. Um, so I was like,
all right, fuck it. Not Sides.
For those of you not in the business,
they didn't walk in with like
mashed potatoes and stuffing.
It's fucking sides of basically
the part of the script.
The couple of scenes that they give you.
Um,
so I go walking in there and I walk in
and all I see is two Asian guys in suits.
And I'm like, all right, this is weird
because basically what happens when you,
when you audition for a role,
they kind of know what they want.
Every once in a while they
do that all ethnicities.
But basically I walk in there and there's
a bunch of howdy duty looking guys.
You know, Donny, most is in there.
Fucking resent me, you know,
cause my red hair hasn't
turned yellow yet.
Now it's not all
redheads, which, you know,
it's a bunch of fucking white dudes
about my age, you know. And um,
this time I'll walk in,
it's two Asian dudes,
one with the shaved head and one
with fucking Chow, young fat hair.
And they're both sitting
there. I'm like, what the fuck?
I must be coming in at the tail end of,
we're trying to find the Asian dude.
And I walk in and I sign in and as
right as I sign in to say I'm there,
the casting person came.
I was like, Oh my God,
I tried to call and I was like,
oh fuck.
I tried to cut shiny email.
Basically they, they,
I dunno, I dunno if they'd cast it.
They gave it to somebody famous or what?
But they basically tried to call me to say
that, uh, they were rewriting the role.
I love when somebody says that I
tried to call really what happened. I,
I dunno, I, I dialed it, but I
couldn't pick up the, I tried,
I couldn't
just be honest.
It was a late night fucking
decision, you know, and I had,
I was one of the first guys coming out
of the shoots. No big deal. Whatever.
I'm already showered,
looking good today.
It was still would been sleeping
like a bump. So, uh, yeah,
my day started a little fucked up. When
are you going to do whatever, whatever.
I'm 16, 17 minutes into this podcast,
I got a little bowl of grapes here.
Um, and people, let me tell
you something. I am severely,
severely off the wagon.
All right.
I stumbled in last night and,
uh,
all I had was two beers.
I don't know what the fuck happened.
I was like stumbling and I,
you know, got out of my car,
which I probably shouldn't
have been driving. I two
beers in an hour and a half.
So I mean I think I'm not drunk.
Right?
Your body gets rid of a one drink an hour.
Isn't that what it is?
All I know is I have this fucking little
zip up, right? My little fucking, uh,
you know, I don't know what
it is. It's like a fun,
I think it has the English flag
on it and it's white. It's weird.
It looks like really American
because it's red, white and blue.
It's a fucking cool look and zip up.
It makes me look maybe two and a half
years younger than I am and I'm vain.
So I wear it.
So I stumble out of my car and I brush
up against the hinge of the garage and I
have, and then I was like, fuck. And
I looked down and I have this Greece,
at least it was brand new, so it was
kind of green looking and I ruined it.
And I just sat there and I remembered
what this recovered alcoholic told me when
I wasn't drinking. I was like,
Yeah Dude, I'm done with drinking.
And he looked at me and he said, yeah
man. He goes, nothing good comes from it.
And I was like, once again, this
guy's right when you're younger,
good stuff comes from it. You get laid,
you get charged with date rape later,
but you know in the moment it's
good. Um, no. You know what I mean?
Loosens people up.
You don't know how to talk to a luck.
Be a lady two nights.
Let me get you drunk and less uptight.
Gonna stick my finger in your
fucking who? Hoss, Sweetie.
What are you want it or
not? Not doing it. I don't,
I'm not advocating rape here. I just felt
like singing. So let me have a grape.
Maybe that'll take me down here.
Oh God, isn't that delicious?
It was the last time you
bought some grapes and actually
finished them. You know,
I'm actually trying to, cause
I, when I came back from Europe,
I throw out a hellacious amount of food.
How much do you think?
A starving kid ways,
because when I walked out, I felt like I
had like six of them in my garbage bag.
That's how much food I threw out.
Some of them would jars,
you know, wasn't all food. Some of
it was the containers. But you know,
a lot of it's made out of cardboard at
this point. I throw out a lot of food.
That's what I'm trying to tell
you. So I'm really, I'm try,
I bought some food this week and
I'm trying to eat all of it up.
I'm trying to be a less wasteful American.
I was speaking to that Shit fucked.
And I look up,
I was on youtube the other day and they
had these German motherfuckers and they
would, they would, they were trying
out the new um, um, dodge challenger,
the fucking XJS that's a Jaguar,
whatever the fuck you call it. The,
the Hemi one versus the
Shelby Mustang versus
Dodge Viper.
And their whole thing was they just kept
relating the cars to eating fast food
in a big cheeseburger. They will
basically saying, these are American cars,
Americans are fat fucks.
And, uh, I got to admit,
man, we earned it. We did earn
it. But you know, we don't do,
we don't test out a Porsche and Audi
and a BMW with some sort of Nazi theme
underneath it. You know, I'm fucking
really getting tired of this man.
Everybody's taken shots at the good
old USA. So you know, you got to do,
I've got a new segment called
let's get smart America.
I wish it had some sort of production on
this where I could just have a fucking
silly ass song.
What are you going to do this week as
it a fucking American to make yourself a
little less fat,
a little less dumb,
a little less something else.
Cause the magic number is three.
Say I'm too fucking stupid to
come up with three examples.
What are you going to do? I got to tell
you, these motherfuckers over in England,
man,
are not in good shape and they
weren't in good shape and fucking in,
uh, Scotland either. Ireland,
they were all right. You know,
it's like they're not fat,
but they just like,
they look like out of shape.
Seventh graders,
like there's not a lot of weightlifting
over there. Like I just saw arms.
You don't like straight arms like Dilbert.
I'm not saying they're all like that.
So fucking old gets your blood up over
there. Right. You know what I'm saying?
Put it this way. My girlfriend
saw somebody over and um, in,
uh,
we were the fuck where I think we were
in Scotland and she saw somebody and this
kid looked like he was in his early
twenties, his face. But his body was just,
she just looked at me and she just goes,
his body is unacceptable.
And it wasn't even that he was
fucking ridiculously honest shape.
It's just that not only those
fucking guys over mushy,
they were the tightest fucking shirts
ever. I'm not saying I'm in shape.
I got a nice little fucking pooch going
right now that I need to try to work
down.
But I have the decency,
the common fucking decency for my
fellow man to wear a button down.
You know,
give yourself a little space,
let it hang off your man tits a little
bit so we don't have to see, you know,
these fucking guys over in Europe,
it's like they want you to know exactly
how many pounds overweight they were.
It was disgusting. You
know, and appreciate it.
A little courtesy out of my fellow
man. That's all I'm saying. Okay,
you got you gotta be honest with yourself.
All right.
What kind of shape? My mind wife
beater shape am I and t shirt shape?
Am I in fucking buttoned down shape?
Do I need to put on a Hoodie?
You know, sport coach
shape. Remember that Shit.
I used to have a regular job. Why am
I walking around? I think I'm excited.
This is one of the exciting
moments of the podcast for me.
Look at me pacing back and forth as if
I'm fucking coming up with some brilliant
shit here.
I remember when I had a regular job,
he used to work in a warehouse
unloading trucks. You know,
it's not curing cancer,
but it served a purpose and a,
I remember once a year they would have,
they'd have the company cookout and all
these fucking suits that you thought
were in shape, dude, they would show up
with their fucking tee shirts on. Wow.
Wow.
You know,
I'm talking like a fucking big slice of
cake just hanging off each side of him.
I remember it made me feel good too
because they will make him more money than
me.
You know?
And when you do that, you just fucking
good your wedding in that category.
So I'm glad that you're losing in
this one. Did that go anywhere?
However another grape. God Damn
it. These things are tart. So
here we go. I'm trying to become
a better speller, everybody,
and I'm sick of being a
fucking moron in that category.
So I figured I'd give you a
spelling tests this week. All right?
You don't have to play along. You
know, what am I going to tell him?
He can keep fucking rambling for another
40 minutes. You can tell at this point,
I don't have shit to talk about this week.
I just emptied my brain on Thursday.
It takes a week for it to fill up.
It's like a just jerked off
and you want another load.
I don't have one inmate got a
fucking empty chamber this week.
All right, you guys sitting at your
desk, this would be even better. This,
you know what's great about this, if I
actually add this to the podcast, right?
Teach it fucking 10 words every week,
okay?
We all learn together.
This is the great thing,
cause if you're listening to it at work,
you shouldn't be doing that.
You know it and I know it looked down
at in shame right now at your desk.
Now don't fuck that.
He shouldn't have any shame.
Did you dream about your job then?
There's no fucking shamed fucking off. Um,
the great part about this part of the
podcast is you're actually going to start
writing and people going to
be thinking, Oh wow, okay.
Sandy's over there taking notes
on something important. You know,
who fucks off and writes at the same
time. Um, all right, so here we go.
Here's 10 words that I think,
uh,
I don't think anything about them.
These are just words I fucking found
that I could, I couldn't spell.
Catalysts is the first word.
What it is.
Yelled at into the Mike Catalyst
is your first word. All right,
let's see how fucking dumb you are.
We need,
we need to gauge how
fucking stupid you are
to have a jumping off point. All
right. Catalyst is your first word.
Can you use it in a sentence?
Uh, I don't think I can. Um,
this spelling test was the catalyst
to expose how fucking stupid I am.
Catalyst
is a fucked up one.
We all eat them. Cantaloupe. A,
what'd you look at that fucking
cantaloupe? I, you know,
I just realized I could never do this.
I could never be a teacher. Chloroform,
okay.
Hey, you know what? If you
don't shut the fuck up,
I'm going to take a chloroform reg and uh,
put it over your face there.
Chloroform.
God,
this is like designed to make you smarter
and it's really exposing how dumb I am
is a tough one.
A penitentiary.
Don't go to the penitentiary. You might
get fucked in the ass penitentiary.
Uh,
you know I love about this podcast is,
even though I have no idea
whether this is the, you know, I,
there's no way to hear
feedback or anything.
I know this is bombing and I don't give
a shit. I don't know. You know what?
I don't even know how many I've done.
I'm going to fucking do all ten one, two,
three. I did three, three c words
and I'm not, I would say cunt,
but it's too easy. Uh, let's go
with another one was another one.
Aesthetics. There's a great one.
Here's a great one. Aesthetics.
Using a sentence. Bill, come
on. You dummy. Jesus Christ.
Look at these aesthetics.
And you know, it's funny, I know how
to spell all these words now, but I,
I can't use them in a sentence. It's
just really a fucking moron. All right,
let's go.
Infrastructure.
Okay.
You know, I'm sick of this
infrastructure. It's really, uh,
it's really unnecessary infrastructure.
Now I can use that in a sentence.
The infrastructure of the
company was a exquisite, Oh,
Jesus Christ. Geez. Oh
Gee, what else we got?
How many, how many words is that?
One, two, three. That's four.
Okay.
There is a tough one.
Succinct. Think I did that last
succinct.
What?
Somebody who stutters brushes
his teeth in a succinct,
can I just do five?
Can I bail on this?
Are you guys enjoying
how fucking horrific,
this is a pertinent,
what does that six, I want to
say that six part in it. Um,
you know what,
if this is pertinent information,
that's the only time anybody ever uses
that word is when they're describing
information.
Okay?
If I had access to the pertinent,
pertinent information,
I wouldn't have to deal with this
infrastructure at this cantaloupe colored
company.
Okay?
Pardon it. Fuck you. You don't even know
how to spell it. You can't smell it.
Spell it. You can't fucking
be laughing at me right now.
Okay.
All right. Here's a fun. The, Oh,
these ones are all the ones that have
psycho at the beginning of him. Uh,
here's one. Uh, negotiate.
You know,
you guys want more money in your cubicles.
You're going to have to negotiate.
Oh,
negotiate was that age.
I'm even getting bored with this. Uh, this
is a hell of a dilemma. Huh? Go ahead.
Spell that one dilemma.
Okay.
I didn't realize this was going to bomb
bomb and now I'm in a fucking dilemma.
Okay.
Dilemma. And what's the
last one here? A silhouette.
Yeah.
Hey, when I see you silhouette
up against the mood,
it makes me want to
fucking baggy silhouette.
Ah, all right. There you go. Let's
just spelling tests for the week.
Do you have any desire to get better
at to shit. Am I super imposing?
That's what I do. I can spell all those
fucking words. Huh? Are you impressed?
You shouldn't be. Um, here's
another new segment bills,
embarrassing moments from
the previous week's podcast.
This is actually from two weeks ago. I
actually re listened to these when I, uh,
when I upload them,
it takes a moment for me to upload all
of these fucking things that no one can
hear unless you go to bill bird.com.
Um,
[inaudible] um,
and I listened to them and I listen,
I hear all the dumb shit that
I say and the stuff that I,
I mispronounce like I was trying to say
exclamation point a couple of weeks ago,
exclamation point as an exclaim.
And I actually said explanation point.
Like it was explaining it
to me in a very excited way.
Jesus Christ, this is fucking
awful. You know what this is?
You know what this is like, this is
like your second day back at the gym.
That's what this podcast feels like. You
know, the first day he like, fuck this.
You know,
when you go nuts and then the next day
you wake up and you're all sore and then
he just fucking dragon asked.
That's what this podcast is just
dragon fucking dragging my freckle das.
I don't have a freckle das,
by the way.
That would mean that I stunned
bades in the nude. Um, all right,
last week I was talking
about how our Avocados,
that whole bullshit where
they're, uh, they're too, oh wait,
that's for the wrong part of the podcast
with a fuck. Is that information?
Jesus Christ. Bill. You know what,
why, why do you even try? Oh,
I fucked up. I will be, I can
just tell you the gist of it.
The reason why Avocados costs more
when you go to get a Burrito was a,
evidently there was some damage done to
the crop a couple of years ago or some
bullshit.
So there was a shortage of them.
Thus they were more expensive.
And as always,
the corporate cons pass the
expense on to the regular people.
And this is what happens.
Then they had more fucking avocado,
so it wasn't a fucking problem anymore.
But they will like, well, wait a minute,
people are already paying more for
Avocados. Ain't never fucking complained.
So they just kept them at the same price.
So now you pay extra,
which means means when
it's time to change,
what it means is that
they're going to fucking,
they're going to do that
with every kind of food now,
cause we're not bitching
about, uh, our bacon.
I've got a breakfast sandwich and they
said Bacon was extra. So you know what,
that's my little rebellion.
Fuck you all right.
I'm not paying extra for my
Avocados from my guacamole.
You fucking cunt. You fucking corporate
cons. How big is your God damn.
Y'All gotta be all right. Let me, let me,
I'm, you know, I'm going to wrap this up.
You guys are getting a
mini podcast this week.
I'm not going to sit here and be
treated this way on my podcast.
When I sit here fucking bomb and
like this, I got a reputation. Um,
last week I have saying I
didn't understand the difference
between Great Britain.
The United Kingdom is England,
the country is England and Scotland.
Two separate countries are, they're the
same fucking thing. It was all confusing.
So a, this guy says, hey bill, I'm from
England. So answer your question might uh,
England is a country. Cause you said on
your podcast, England wasn't a country,
but is it you meant to write,
but it is. What do you,
if you're questioning yourself, sir,
what the fuck am I supposed to do?
Scotland is a country, Wales is
a country. I didn't know that.
I thought maybe Scotland was a country,
but I didn't think Wales was a country.
Ireland is a bit different because it's
split into two countries to spelled t oh
there's one of your smart
fucking Europeans there.
Everybody see that if we
learn how to spell America,
we can start making fun of them again.
We at least we can have a a
basis to make fun of them. Um,
anyways,
uh,
continuing Ireland is a bit different
because it's split into two countries.
Northern Ireland,
the Capitol is Belfast and the
Republic of Ireland capital is Dublin.
Both completely separate countries.
Countries spelled country apostrophe s
okay.
Yeah.
See this let's all they do over there.
They watch fucking soccer
and eat fish and chips.
They don't want to fucking spell either.
United Kingdom and this is what the United
Kingdom is. It's a England, Scotland,
Wales and Northern Ireland. Great
Britain. Great Britain is England,
Scotland and Wales.
Reason being is Ireland is an island.
Hence why Northern Ireland
and the Republican Ireland
are just known as Ireland.
That doesn't make any sense.
England is in Ireland or whatever.
Fucking do the United Kingdom is an
island island. I don't understand that.
How come fucking,
uh,
Australia is not an eye is not considered
an island surrounded on all sides by
water.
Okay?
You know what the fuck.
South America is an island at this
point with the Panama Canal, isn't it?
And why does it, it
floated away. Um, anyways.
Anyways, this podcast sucks.
I'm sorry. What did, what
the fuck do you want from me?
All right. I'm fucking Neil O'Donnell
this week. I've got nothing for you.
I started doing this spelling tests and
all these fucking nerds came out of the
goddamn woodwork. This guy goes, Bill,
here's an interesting piece of trivia.
Facetious is the only word in the English
language that has every vowel in order.
A E. I. O. U. Isn't that interesting? Is
that what I did with the spelling tests?
Maybe this is why I never
learned out of fucking spell,
because that's the kind of
people that you attract.
Here's an interesting
tidbit of information.
Okay?
Do you know that on the the fucking,
they started talking about
some moon off of Saturn
that instead of fucking air, it's
the, their atmosphere as methane gas.
And I got to sit and I sit there and
nod like, wow, you know, and I'm like,
and he's sitting there thinking,
I'm nodding because I'm so fucking
interested and I'm really trying to do the
math in my head.
Trying to figure out when was the
last fucking time this guy got laid?
There's another great stereotype.
If you're some fucking smart nerd,
that means you don't get late in life.
That's bullshit.
It's only in fucking high
school, you know? I Dunno,
is it, I don't even know if it's
fucking true. I just figure, you know,
when you get smart,
if you're really smart and you're good
at business and that type of shit,
you go out and make money and the second
you make money, what's going to happen?
A bunch of fucking cancer going
to come out of the woodwork.
Who wouldn't have fucked you back in a
day because she couldn't throw a ball
through a fucking hoop.
You know?
That's what that twats wanted to vacuum
up when they were in high school.
Okay,
the,
now all of a sudden look at you,
you invented a fucking
Hula hoop or whatever.
The hell you did and now
they want to bang. Yeah.
Okay.
Right. Isn't that how it
works? Anything? I am flailing.
Okay.
I'm walking around.
Why do I feel like I have
to make it 50 minutes bill,
if you don't have anything to say,
fucking bail. Ah, let me hike this. Um,
the m m p m m podcast.com is the fan page,
the official fan page, the
only one that I sponsor, www,
the [inaudible] podcast.com. So the
only one that I, that I did well,
who's kidding who?
It's the only fucking one there is,
but it's the only one that I sponsor.
I'm trying to make it sound more official.
Um, but anyway, so I think there's
at the podcast for this week,
I'm literally laying on my back right
now just staring at the ceiling wondering
where it all went wrong. Do I have
anything left to talk about? Oh,
I got something to foist.
Somebody sent me an email. Let me,
let me just reach for this fucking Straw.
At this point,
somebody sent me an email and it
said overrated in the subject line.
And then I opened it and it said the
Beatles and then underneath that he wrote,
yeah, I said it. Let me tell
you something right now. What?
Like how much I fucking
hate people who go, yeah,
I said it.
You know like this shocking you.
Like they're going after some
sort of fucking, you know, taboo.
If you're ever in a comedy club. All
right. And there's a comedian on,
on stage and they, they're
allowed one. Yeah, I said it.
If they do any more than that.
Yeah.
You have my blessing to start
throwing shit at them. I hate that.
That fucking false
dangerous fucking horse shit.
Fucking bitches d to get a job.
What am I said Shit.
You guys can't handle the truth.
Yeah,
we keep fucking going. Yeah, I said it.
What? I said it, but it's like, dude,
nobody in the crowd is going. Who
said that? Did you say that? Yeah,
I said it. You know what I mean? Like,
like they're being led out and
fucking let out and fucking handcuffs.
What will people realize that
nothing is shocking. You know?
Look at the fucking Catholic Church.
Look what the fuck they're doing.
You know what is more shocking than the
fact that they fucking look the other
way? Cause I understand why they look
the other way. Cause it's so much fun.
Good money involved.
And you know,
to get to the top of any sort of pyramid,
you have to be an ass kissing cunt.
That's basically what it is.
Unless you created it,
unless you created
whatever pyramid there is.
And at that point you want
your ass kissed. So whenever
there's money involved,
they don't give a shit.
I you,
what is the most shocking thing about
all of that is that people continue to go
to the the Catholic church.
Get anybody out there explained
to me how they separate that.
How do you separate that?
How do you still go to the Catholic
Church knowing that they had 16,000 cases?
Those are just the ones that came forward.
16 fucking thousand.
That's the population of a small town.
16,000 fucking rape of children.
And you still go and you
give them fucking money.
What do you think they're
going to use that money for?
Lawyers to get these fucking guys off.
You know,
I dunno. Why don't Ya Jesus
Christ. Why, why, why,
why do you go down that fucking
road? All right. You know what?
I'm really off my fucking game. Okay.
Peyton manning threw an interception,
the final fucking drive of the Superbowl.
This is my,
this is my fucking Peyton manning
Superbowl game right here. Cause this,
this podcast was it
disjointed cluster fuck.
And I really have nothing that I really
think I was going to come here and I was,
I had a little information
about Avocados and uh,
what is the United Kingdom?
And I was somehow going to be able
to fucking talk for 50 minutes.
Do you realize like when you guys,
you,
all you have to understand is the
level of fucking ego that it takes.
That I can look at three different things
and think that I could run my fucking
mouth for 50 minutes. It's not,
this is even the podcast anymore.
This is my confession scene that I didn't
get to do because they're retooling
it. All right? You broke me down.
It's fucking over. You got me.
I have nothing left.
I bought the box set of the wire
just looking at mom around my room,
trying to come up with something.
My voice gets weaker
and I watched the first fucking season
and that's a fucking great TV show,
but I'm not going to be
one of those guys who goes,
this is the greatest TV show ever.
It's fucking good.
It's a really good show. I
like it. I like it a lot.
Did I gave a spelling test that I really
do that I give a spelling test on the
fucking podcast. All right.
You know what? I'm going to,
I'm going to bow out gracefully
right now. Okay. If you want, I add,
I added a date. Here we go. Let me,
let me actually use this podcast.
What I really want to use it for,
my ulterior motive here is the height.
My God damn dates. I got some
new dates out there. Everybody.
Let's go to the official
website of Bill Burr.
He's doing officially one of
the worst podcasts ever. Um,
this week in Los Angeles,
April 3rd at the Gibson MP
theater. Um, I'm doing the,
uh,
Kevin and being a cancer
show show for cancer.
Hey, let's get rid of the
cancer. Everybody. I believe
that's the name of it.
It's a fucking benefit for cancer.
Uh,
I'm going to get the punchline in
Atlanta, April 8th, ninth and 10th,
and I'm hanging around the 11th.
I have tickets for the finals,
not the finals to final day of the
masters. Me and another buddy of mine.
I'm going down there cause we knew tiger
woods would cause what's going to play?
We fucking knew it. Okay.
Who's kidding? Who? You know,
he's sick of bang in that broad.
That's why he fucked around on her.
It was her fault. She stopped him. You
know, she wasn't washing the dishes.
She didn't make sandwiches
for him anymore.
She started taking tiger for granted and
tiger was sitting there and his billion
dollar lazy boy. And he's like,
is this bitch taken tiger woods?
The greatest fucking Golfer of all time?
Okay,
actually, is it Jack
Nicklaus? Jack Nicklaus is,
but she's taken me for granted. Fuck
this. I'm going to go fuck a whore.
That's the one thing that I hated about
that story is how they just never blamed
her for his fucking around
because it was clearly her fault.
Okay.
And if you're wondering why
I'm coming up with that,
I'm just using the, you
know, it's speak eight.
I'm saying it because of my
respect for females, you know,
because I respect you guys so much
that I'm actually using your train of
thought.
When you look at,
when you see a woman get caught
cheating and you always view,
always blame the guy.
What is funny because he
wasn't paying attention to her.
It's probably because he was doing this
is probably because he was doing that
whether shoe's on the other one,
but you know, they never say it's cause
she wanted to go out and get some Dick.
No, never. Because of that's cause
it's something the guy was doing.
He left his shoes in the fucking kitchen
after she'd fucking mop the floor.
So therefore she had to go to the fucking
Luxor and collapse on somebody else's
cock. Right. It's her fault.
Okay.
You know where the fuck does she get
off getting mad at fucking tiger woods.
Do you even have a fucking job woman?
What is your job to go around
gold dog fucking Tannin.
What do you got to dope?
I love these fucking twats who are
married to some unbelievably rich person.
Okay?
They have kids with them and they don't
have a fucking job and they still get
help. Still got to have some
fucking, you know nanny.
It's like, do you want to fucking
do anything? I Tony, that's,
that's the guy's fault.
If you marry a fucking woman who
you're making so much goddamn money,
all right that they don't even have a
fucking job and they still need help.
You need help with doing nothing.
Okay,
I'm raising kids.
What the fuck my mother
did that and had a job.
You Lazy Twat get off the Goddamn Sofa.
That's what I would do.
I take a right across my knee and pull
off her fucking Gucci flip flop and I
fucking paddle or right butt cheek until
she admitted how fucking wrong she was.
What do think about that? Maybe that's
why I'm not a billionaire, you know,
cause that's how I do it. John. I'm
Razzi would take a picture of it.
I do that at paddle. A little fucking
right. Fannie is, I had grapes
or, and then when they question
me, I just, we fucked you.
The God Damn Golfer in the world.
Okay,
thanks to me. Yes. Sunday's aren't boring.
Come here. Come over here. I'll fucking
sign you camera for you. All right.
Take the film out. Yeah. There's no film
anymore. It's fucking digital. Right?
Okay.
I Dunno. I want somebody who embrace
being a piece of shit. That's what I want.
That's what I got to say there.
Tiger Woods wife is a lazy fucking Twat.
All right.
And that's why he cheated on her.
And I'm going to tell you this right now.
The reason why he's playing the
masters is because they need the money.
Yeah.
All right. This guy is at work since
November and I know what you're thinking.
Oh God. Well he's a
fucking billionaire. Yeah.
And he's living the lifestyle of a
billionaire. Do you think he wants to?
Of course he does. And he's got
to keep that fucking whore happy,
you know?
Do you think she cool? Do you think
paid for all the fucking window?
She smashed with that golf club,
right?
I like how he denied that shit in
that attack way. Uh, with a golf club.
Rarely your windows exploded and then you
drove into a tree where you fucking on
mushrooms. Did you think you
could drive into that little?
Not In the center of the trunk.
Tiger me a fucking break.
What are you sticking up for?
You know why?
Because he married her the fucking
idiot. No, he's got this contract.
You can't get out. He's, he's looking
to lose all the a fucking idiot.
Okay.
I hope. I hope she listens
to this. I don't even know
our God damn name. You know?
I don't know your name sweetheart, because
you never did anything with your life.
You know, it was the last time
you even fucking, you ever,
even when it's swim meet.
What about the preschool level?
When kids are just happy,
they can even fucking stand up.
Did you even win a ribbon?
What have you ever done
besides suck the Dick
suck the Dick.
It was the greatest golfer of the last 50
fucking years other than Jack Nicklaus.
You know that's your big
accomplishment in life. Oh your heart.
Let me ask the fellows that question.
Let me ask you this.
What have you or shacking up
with fucking Oprah like Stedman.
Do you think he gives a fuck
if she fucks around on him?
Going to chase him down or
down the street with a ladle?
Some other fucking utensil. Cause
you know Oprah be eaten, right?
You think he flipped it? I wouldn't give
a shit gun. Fuck whoever you want. Oprah.
I don't give a shit.
Okay.
Can I have another car?
That'd be awesome.
What are you doing today?
Nothing. Doing nothing.
Playing fucking Xbox. That pitch is
doing what everybody wants to do.
Absolutely fucking nothing.
No. Wait. Why don't we work.
We work so we can, we can have one
zillions of what that bitch has.
She has the nerve to get mad at this
guy because he's out there banging some
fucking
okay.
Cause he's tired of her fucking lazy ass.
The fuck is wrong with people. Why
not the one window? What I said it?
Let's say, yeah, she's fucking lazy.
Okay.
Anytime you see a guy fucking around
on his woman, I'm telling you,
part of it is because he's a dog.
The other part is because these
women are so fucking, well,
they'll just lazy
to,
it's like they're not even human.
They're just slothful.
Okay.
Do you know they just sit on religious,
just fucking laying around.
Get off your ass is all you.
You want us to stop fucking around you?
Get off your fucking lazy ass is
what are you think about? Dead.
All right. That's 49 minutes.
Here we go. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
I'll fucking women out there. Somebody
had to go down, so we had to get hurt.
You know, I had nothing. I was
flailing. I was on the fucking ropes.
What'd you want from me?
All right.
49 minutes and 31 seconds. I have another
fucking, uh, oh, I didn't finish hyper.
My gigs let me finish hyper my
gigs. Um, I just added a date.
I'm going to be in a Cincinnati Zia,
Newport, Kentucky. Uh, I'm going
to be at the funny bone. All right?
So why don't you all you fucking rednecks,
get her done and come down to
the fucking club. All right.
Now I know I'm not going to be standing
there and overalls with a fucking piece
of shit
hanging out of my teeth going,
you're trying to shoot a
fucking thing and your gun.
That's crazy. And a fucker can't
Kirk or tier one a hard one.
I know.
I'm not going to be knowing that.
Why don't you broaden your
fucking horizons? All right,
God damn pig fuckers. When are you guys
going to come into the 21st century?
Um,
where am I going to be after?
Um, oh, I'm going to be
at the, uh, the Wilbur,
the Wilbur Theater in Boston.
Jody's going to be at the fucking Wilbur.
I'm at.
We actually added a date on May 6th,
and for some reason it's not up on my
site. May 6th and May 7th, May 8th,
and it'll be at the Taj Mahal in
beautiful downtown Atlantic city.
And when I think a glamour,
I think of Jersey. Um,
I'm going to shit on every fucking place.
Then I'm playing [inaudible] Jersey shore
scumbags going to come down there with
your fucking track suits.
Huh?
Oh look in like some grease
stuff. Fucking $6 million, man.
You're not impressing me.
Chicks with your big fucking
Olympic sized Jody Watley.
Who bearings. I know that's not
real gold. Just like you're Tan.
It's fucking fake. Come on down. Uh,
what else do I got a,
I got a Gig in a,
in Los Angeles at the Hollywood improv.
All right,
well how do I shit on this? I
live here. Come on. You phony.
Fuck ads all been done.
How about some fucking Mexican show up?
You know, Jesus Christ,
you're 80% of the population.
You figure you could send a fucking crew
to come down there and represent your
people. Starting to think you guys
don't like me. What did I ever say?
Bad about Mexico? Nothing. And you know
why it's cause I haven't read about it yet
and that's it. Then I'll be a Carolines
in June. I'm going to be in Montreal,
Canada, you know, I love that.
That's like the minor league for Paris.
That's what that shit is. You know,
all those silly little French guys going
up there acting like they don't speak
English, you know, with
their pointy noses. You know,
they all get that Wayne Gretzky face and
their little feathered mullets like Ron
do gay, you know, I'm going
to be coming up there.
You know what sucks is every time I do
Montreal, it's never during hockey season.
So I, I haven't been to their new,
their new place sucks. Anyways,
I actually went to the
old forum in March of 89.
You can fucking look this up too because
I remember they played the Minnesota
north stars.
I was at that game and uh,
and I had a good time and that's the
podcast for this week. Everybody,
you see that we had a spelling test.
I talked about Avocados and I went
off on the broads for like 10 minutes.
There's your podcast
for this fucking week.
I'm really hoping that we get everything
ironed out. I'm sick of saying this.
I don't know what the fucking problem is.
All right, but I'm the talent. All right.
I'm not on the computer side.
Okay?
Okay. That's not up to me. I don't call
the place. All right. I got a headset on.
I just fucking execute them. All
right. I'm responsible for all
field shit,
not this behind the scenes stuff.
So send all your complaints
to a bill burrs web guy,
www.doperswebguy.com
back slash what the fuck?
All capitals.
All right.