Hey, what's going on?
Hey. Oh, what's going on?
It's, it's bill berm then this
is the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Ah,
just checking in on you.
Just check all I'm eating
my balls do to, to, to,
to do on a damn stage Bob.
Oh, freckles is paying the fucking
price. He's paying the price.
Every comedian that has a
special coming up, you know,
in the next couple of weeks,
whenever the fuck they're putting it out.
I believe the rumor I heard a rumor.
Bananarama oh yeah. When are they
going to get back together? Huh?
Fuck.
Every year that goes by,
everybody was talking about when's guns
and roses going to get back together.
When's axl and slash going to,
but what about Banana Rama?
Okay,
I hear a room and they were getting back
together for a summer. Fucking tall.
Um, I'm paying the price.
Every God damn. Oh look,
a job are paid.
Uh,
who have a special coming out is that
you just go on stage and you have,
you know, you got nothing.
You got one little fucking,
you got one little pea shooter and then
you've got a slingshot and a fucking
whatever,
two months earlier you had a Howard sir,
have a fucking act and it's
the weirdest fucking thing.
Just imagine if a whatever,
if you're an athlete or something like
every couple of years he had to relearn
that, all the mechanics, but you just
couldn't hit the jump shot anymore.
He had to fucking, ah, that
that shot was in my repertoire.
Now I've got to relearn how
to fucking do this in a sense,
but in a different way.
I've got to do it and then I got to shoot
it with my left hand now because they
already saw me do it with my right hand.
And then the more you fucking do it,
the more hours you put
out. Right. Then you go,
when I got to bounce
it off my fucking head,
cause you know you can't keep doing the
same shit or everybody's there more or
they say, dude, that reminds
me of this day, your day.
Oh no other guy with this person. Right.
You just got to fucking deal with that.
So last night, you know, and of course
they have to go on after Ian Edwards,
I a n Edwards who's won like lack guy.
All he has is a level fucking
material just up. They're murdering.
And uh,
I went up there with my look book,
but the total basic fucking horse shit,
I was in a really fucking dark place.
It's funny to be in a dark place and then
like, you know, mentally just like, uh,
and then to be talking about the
shit that I was talking about and um,
yeah,
I dunno, but I, I got to plow
through this shit as far as like, uh,
I got to get past my anger and I'm telling
you this fucking exercise that I did
that I'm really starting
to think my shoulders.
How fuck do you put your shoulders up?
Remember that bit I used to do,
I think I was stuck in
a defensive posture,
like shell shocked,
you know what I mean?
There's only so many times you can get
slapped in the back of the head by bigger
kids before your shoulders
are just naturally up.
Like you're already beginning to block
whatever's coming at you fucking head.
And I think I was kind of
stuck in that and um, you know,
I was talking to some people about
that and it was like, well, you know,
there's physical ailments and then
there's the emotional fucking trauma of
what's going on with your life.
And there's certain people
that think they're related.
I don't know if you guys
are into that Hippie,
but you look up to stuff,
you know,
this is like one of these things
when you go to look this up,
you completely leave the
medical profession in the
United States of America.
Like you start like the doctors slowly
start wearing less and less shoes as you
start to go further east with your, your,
you're looking for medical solutions.
You know, if you're looking for a
medical solution in the United States of,
of the Americas,
it's going to be a guy in wingtip
shoes with fucking dark socks,
you know, fully clothed being
like, okay, yeah, you got a,
your rotator cuff is taped up though.
We need to go in and operate
and take the Metal Carlo,
all the fucking MCL and all,
they're going to give you this
straight fucking how the body works.
We've done an MRI. This is what the
fuck is going on with your body.
But then as you start to go,
you know,
you start to step away from that shit
that the pharmaceutical companies and all
that,
not saying it's all bad,
not saying it's all Ben was the
last time we had a plague. You know,
for as much as the pharmaceutical
companies allegedly
allegedly created a heroin
epidemic in this country by handing
out opiates like Flintstone vitamins to
fucking adults. Uh, you
know, there's also, you know,
because nobody's walking around with
scurvy, so that's something, right?
I guess no one really walked
around with scurvy bill.
He had to be on a fucking
boat, lost at sea, you know,
with no wind in your sails and
iron maiden singing right the car.
Um, so, uh, yeah,
but the further you go down that rabbit
hole, like, uh, the, the fucking,
the longer the hair gets,
then there's like, you know,
more loose fitting clothes,
then it becomes sandals.
And then just sort of the more,
you know me and even then we should,
I can,
I can like this and then I get
all fucking uncomfortable. Um,
I'll look up some stuff.
Let me hit pause her and I'm going to
look up some shit about like the memories.
Let me, let me see what this fucking
doctor looks like. Our of perfect,
perfect fucking perfect.
So I looked up memories held in,
in the meeting that came up was in body.
So of course Wikipedia has something
that's just going to be like, you know,
the old right there, Fred. So the
first thing I scrolled down too,
that was not Wikipedia was tiny Buddha.
All right.
And I swear to God,
it says how to release the painful
memories and emotions stored in your body,
uh, by Jennifer Sterling. Of course, now
they're going to let a woman do something,
right. They're not going to
let her in the wing tip world.
So the picture you see is some
Antonio Banderas looking guy with the,
uh, I call it the gay cut tee
shirt. You know, you know the,
you know the v Neck t shirt
that the fucking gay guys were,
cause they're all fucking in crazy shape.
You know what I mean?
It's not the dad bod cut.
It's the gay male fucking cut where they
have chess cleavage because they have
0% body fat.
So the guys dressed white on white
with the gay cut t and yoga pants,
no fucking shoes. And he's
on the beach, not a half.
He looks like fucking a good look.
And Tom Hanks in castaway,
if he didn't give a fuck that he
was cast away, cast away. Yeah.
And he didn't need to talk to a soccer
ball because he was so fucking centered
and he breathed his way through.
How the fuck did he become a castaway?
I can't even remember.
Okay.
It must've been his ship sank, right?
What was he flying with? Amelia Earhart.
I Dunno.
Was it one of those Tarantino movies
where he kind of fucks with history?
All right.
The cure for pain is in the pain,
says somebody named Rumi and then it says,
free download,
Buddha desktop wallpaper.
That kind of kills it.
You know when you have a good Jesus
or Buddha or Mohammed like wallpaper,
you know what I mean? Kind of cheeses it
up a little bit. Then you think, okay,
it's all right. Let me read
it. My Best Yoga voice,
your body keeps a physical
memory of all your experiences.
You have lots of memory stored in your
brain that you can recount at any given
moment, even called names. Faces. Yeah,
get out of my fucking brain works what
you're fucking sandwich smelled like,
but over time these memories fade or
change as time passes as and we mature.
However, even when the memory
begins to fade from your rang,
get to the fucking point.
It lives in your body,
in the form of a physical
sensation and behavior patterns.
The body doesn't forget now, Jesus,
what's your body from Hell's kitchen?
And I was for fucking 20 years ago.
You fucking piece of shit.
Your brains all forgiving
like, hey man, like you know,
not going to lie. I didn't enjoy it
when it happened, but you know, God,
I mean just the sunny day, just
go out and enjoy it. All right.
The events of our lives leave
physical imprints in our bodies,
especially when we experience trauma care.
I okay.
Stress and all this shit that
caused the body to fight, flee,
or freeze in order to cope. This is what
I'm saying. I think I was all fucking,
I was in a a,
you know,
after you take a couple of fucking right
left to their head, you just Kinda,
you just walk around. I
just thought I, you know,
I have like fucking 40 years ago,
whatever the fuck I was in high school
40 years ago
was I 18 now. That was 30 years ago.
30 years ago. It was fuck at 18.
Yeah, I'm a, you knew
that phone was gonna ring.
Who is this? Who the hell is this?
I should have put it on pause.
Who is this?
Hello?
Hello.
Yeah,
for Fuck Sake.
Can you believe someone would
pocket down me during my podcast?
You know what's funny is I don't
even know who the fuck that was.
I have no idea who the fuck that was.
They have no idea who the fuck I am. I,
that's what's always fascinated
me about when you just fucking,
you just dial a wrong number.
I've said this before, right?
You dial a number and somebody says hello
and you're like, yeah. Hey, is a is is,
is frank there? And they're
like, whoa. And you're like,
and they're like, oh, I'm sorry.
They're like,
I'm sorry you have the wrong number.
Now I get wrong numbers.
Everybody gets wrong numbers.
Here's my question to you.
Do you think you've ever
accidentally called somebody famous?
You know what I mean? Like
you just fucking, uh, I dunno.
You just dial the wrong number and like,
Bill Clinton picked up or fuck it Obama.
Oh,
throw a Republican in there. George
Bush. Hey, she's Daddy, right?
He fucking picks up and you and he has
to go through the same shit is you like
is frank there? And he said,
[inaudible] know frank e F, g, H.
I love them. Then they'd read
the fucking number. T like,
you don't know what your number
is. It says plop. No it isn't.
That's why there's no frank here.
Anyways,
let me continue one. All right, well fuck
all this shit. How do I get it out of me?
Because my body, it never forgets.
It's like fucking Niamh. Listen,
if you punch me in the fucking
head, seventh grade, um,
wait a minute.
I love that they finally give Jamie
Foxx the fucking Liam Neeson Merle.
He has a movie coming out where
it's one of those movies like,
you fuck with my family. I'm gonna fucking
kill you. It's about time. You know,
they ran out a young white guys to give
that to and then they just kept going
over and like, Liam Neeson me, let me
know that guys. Like, what is it? Like 83,
then he play like fucking Obi
wan Kenobi or some shit. Um,
all right. The first tool to
put your emotional toolkit,
the first tool to put in your
emotional toolkit, and this is why,
this is why I've never been
able to get through this shit
because I was getting no,
because I'm fucked up.
But when I start to go down this road
of doctors who don't wear shoes like it
said, okay, the pictures
that they have, okay?
It says how to set New Year's goals
you'll actually enjoy pursuing and it's a
stick figure sitting on a rainbow staring
up at the sun with a big goofy smile
on its face. And uh, I
don't know about you guys,
but where I came from,
that sort of happiness was not allowed.
You basically were not allowed to be
happy and it was shamed. Fuck off.
Oh No, wait, why am I letting that
react? I, why am I reacting to that?
I have the power. I could,
you know it's funny,
right before I started this I was thinking
I should go into the settings and I
should just turn it off and I didn't.
So I created this situation.
Not a dead Steve Jobs.
Huh?
I guess I could get upset with Steve Jobs
with how fucking many times that thing
rings before it goes to voicemail.
But then I imagined that I could actually
go into settings and I could determine
that. I just don't have the patients.
All right. The first tool. Okay guys,
your first tool to put in
your emotional toolkit.
This is the type of class I would go
to with Nia and she would just feel me
either starting to get mad or just
laughing at the thing as she being the
fucking angel that she is. An open
fucking channel would be like, okay, get,
what is the first emotional tool?
It's cause she's a woman.
She gets to fucking do that. Being
like, oh my God, let's get some smores.
They get to be like that.
We're not, you know,
you don't have a fucking bottle opener.
You've gotta use your teeth, you know,
and said stupid Guy Shit.
And then if you don't know how to fucking
do that thing where you bring your
beer up to the counter
and fucking slam it down,
you know you're somehow less of a man.
Um,
I like how I'm putting all of my issues
onto you guys. All right, let's say we go,
okay.
The first tool to put into your
emotional toolbox nonjudgment ah,
fuck. I mean, there goes
my standup career. I mean,
my entire fucking life is judging people.
All right?
When you feel emotionally triggered
and tempted to turn to food or other
addictive behaviors for comfort, I'm
not f well, I'm, maybe I am a drunk.
Try not to judge the reaction. Our
bodies are programmed to seek pleasure,
not discomfort.
So it's natural to try and find something
to soothe the pain and make yourself
feel better.
The need to suture yourself with food.
I'm not a fat fuck or other means.
Doesn't make you a bad person.
It makes you human. Oh
God, this is so gross.
The second tool permission, the third
tool release. I can't even read this.
The fourth tool.
Forgiveness. Finally time.
Oh my God,
I'm going to the wrong website.
Jennifer sterling is an
emotional eating coach.
Well, what the fuck is this?
Have met the wrong website.
She helps women to stop eating their
feelings and released the physical and
mental emotional weight that keeps
them from feeling the absolute best.
Download the cravings decoder guide and
uncovering the hidden hidden emotional
meeting behind your food cravings.
I don't know.
I don't want to be a
fucking negative person,
but doesn't that sound a fucker generic?
I was craving a peanut butter and jelly
sandwich. Okay. What that means is this.
All right, where do you
store your emotions? Where
do you store your emotions?
So right now,
this person has a phd.
So imagine there they're going
to be wearing more clothes.
They don't even have a picture,
okay?
It may surprise you then. Motions are
not the sole product of your brain,
but our [inaudible]
might be surprised you.
This isn't gonna say the same shit as the
last website and these emotions can be
triggered through your body
work, meditation, breathing,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
Use one half. All right. You
know, evidently I'm never
going to get cured cause I,
I can't get through this
shit. Well certainly not
while doing a fucking podcast.
You Moron. Why did you just call
yourself a more on there? Is that,
is that really what you thought or is
that what people told you when you were
younger?
That's the type of shit where you just
want to grab the person by their ankles
and drag them out of their chair
and they just walk out of the room.
You know me from that session,
uh,
Jesus Christ, I'm up against it, dude.
This is what it's like to become a parent.
You just suddenly become hyper aware
of how unqualified you are and what a
fucking moron.
You weren't like someone's gonna be
looking at me like I have questions. Hey,
I'm like, we talked to my
kid like, Hey, join the club.
You think any of this shit makes
sense to me? At least you're a kid.
And you can have the comfort of, of,
of, it's okay that you don't know shit.
Where do you get to be my age? And
you don't have an excuse, you know?
And there's that fucking, uh, uh,
whatever the fuck isn't the
Micheal Ray Richardson, Tyson,
Sicily to whatever the fucking name is.
Quiet Leaf Tyson.
I forget what his name is. You
get like fucking the, the, the,
the guy who looks like the,
the cop on the black cop on Barney Miller,
who fucking knows about black holes
in the universe and is a fine wine
connoisseur.
MMM.
You know, that's the kind of person
you need is a debt. That guy,
that guy's got fucking answers. You know,
I was reading a thing on him. I'm fine.
I got it. I can never remember
this guy's fucking name.
Last name is Tyson de Grasse Tyson.
Tyson scientist. Tyson
sites. We'll go with that.
Mike Tyson's foot worth Neil degrasse
Tyson. This is why he's the shit,
because that only is the unbelievably
intelligent and he knows that we came from
trees or some shit, whatever the fuck
he was saying. You know, thank God.
I don't do heavy drugs. When I
watched that guy show, alright,
he also was talking about how he's into
wine and he was talking about how when
you, you had whatever, you
finish a bottle of wine,
you fill it up with water or you go to,
you know, and you're pouring it out.
It does that Glub Glub glub thing.
He was just going,
what'd you do is you just turn
the bottle as you turn the bottle,
it causes a swirling effect. And uh, uh,
basically because it's swirling down,
then there's that hole in the middle,
lets the air go in. So as, as the, uh,
liquids coming out in the
air can freely flow in
to take up the space that the liquid
once had. And it just flows right out.
Plus it looks,
it looks fucking cool as you do it.
So the next time you pour a big fucking
glass of wine for some real housewife,
you know,
gets,
you can't wait to hold her botox
face in your hands. You know,
you don't want to fuck it up by Glub glub
glub in it into a giant glass because
it might go all over a fucking dress
that she's going to wear once, you know,
they look, you know, that's what
I get out of Neil degrasse Tyson.
I watch that show and I'm
like, God damn it. You know,
as much as this guy just told me where
we came from in the universe millions of
years ago or whatever, thousands, I don't
know. You're going to go back to Jesus.
That was only what, a couple
thousand years ago. Um,
as much as he's teaching me about that,
he's also on the side showing
me how to bang a real housewife.
Um,
anyways,
so I've continued to uh,
get rid of shit and I'm,
I'm still in my office.
That's how much shit I had had two
closets and everything in my room and I've
fucking,
I've gotten rid of everything and I might
even do another pass cause I have to
tell you, I fucking walk in
there now and I'm relaxed.
I had no idea that when you walk
in and there's a ton of shit,
uh, the level of stress that was
bringing me up, fucking relaxed.
And like there's my drum kit, there's
my guitar, there's where I keep my pens,
you know, get it out of here and
anything that's coming in the house,
get it the fuck out it. So then yesterday,
of course, you know, you know, women are,
you know, you know, you know, they are,
I mean, if, if, if they're not fucking,
you know, watching a real housewife show,
if they're not eating something there,
they're on Amazon buying something.
They just, they, they, they,
they fucking consume
shit. So, um, you know,
it's spend the holidays. So we've had a
bunch of boxes, people sending US stuff,
we're sending them shit
and it by my front door,
every day there's these fucking boxes.
Okay.
So what I always do is I
take our fucking address.
Often I put it through the paper,
right?
Then I cut the boxes up and then I take
them over this fucking place that, uh,
you know, one of those mailboxes separate
places, you know. And I say, Hey,
go is some free fucking boxes.
They take it now.
I don't know if they throw
it out like goodwill,
but I feel like I made the fucking effort,
you know,
but I can't fucking keep the God damn
door clean and I cut up like fucking 20
these God damn boxes, you know? Did
you went to, you have a fucking baby.
Everybody sends your shit. Everybody's
sending your shared socks, shoes, swings,
follow this shit. And
it's just like, you know,
I just love the amount of socks
that they send you. It's like,
it's not gonna be able to walk for like
the first fucking, I dunno, six months.
What does it need socks for?
We didn't get me a hang glider.
I mean just that doesn't
even make any fucking sense.
I know you get the baby's
got to keep its feet war,
but does it have to have one pair
of socks for every fucking day,
but six month life, you
know, and then what?
You got all these little socks,
it's going to grow out of him and like
fucking Ted's out used to see what level
of a con would you have to be to
look at the cutest thing ever.
A little baby socks and, and it still
makes you upset. See what I'm saying?
Oh, tell your freckles needs
some help here. Um, all right,
let's get to some of the, uh, let's
get to some of the announcements. Oh,
by the way, everybody, I keep
forgetting to promote this, uh,
the Patrice O'neil comedy
benefit, the fifth annual, well,
uh, Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit. I
still have a nice photo on the wall.
Somebody did his great painting of him,
the perfect size and all that that I will
never get rid of. Now having said that,
I don't need any more. Um, all
right. Patrice O'Neal comedy benefit.
This is the fifth annual one at the
New York City Center. All right,
we're going to post the link and all
of that. There's a, it's a 2000 seater.
We got a couple of hundred
seats left. Yeah. And um,
it's a great way to
start your year. And, um,
it's one of my favorite shows of the year.
Um,
just get to see all of the,
uh,
just all my friends and now it's becoming
like newer guys that were influenced
by Patrice and they come and
they talk about, you know,
the amazing comic that he was. And, uh,
I got to tell you that will never not be
in the back of my head cause I love the
guy to death. But it's also like
whenever someone will come up to me and,
and give me a high compliment,
you know,
as far as where I am in the comedy
world right now is a standup comedian.
I always think that's,
cause Patrice isn't here right now and
Mitch Hedberg and Geraldo and all these
other monsters that we lost. So, uh,
this is an incredible
benefit. And it, uh, you know,
through the money that we've raised,
his mother's been able to get a
condominium and she's living great.
She doesn't have to worry about
anything, you know, you know,
the only thing,
you know,
and that's am I really a belief of mine
that when somebody passes and their
family members are,
you know,
the only thing they should have
to deal with is the grief of it,
which unfortunately you
never totally get passed,
but they shouldn't also have to
deal with all this other stuff,
which is why we continue
to do the benefit.
Because I always hated
when I was coming up,
when there was an unexpected death and
the person had a family and all of that
type of shit. You know, it's like you
do one benefit and it's like, okay,
here's your bag, a loop, you know,
trying to make this last for the next
20, 30, 40, 50 fucking years. Um,
I dunno. So that's why we continue
to do it. Plus it keeps the,
the memory of him alive and all of his
comedy out there. Uh, that is the hope.
Anyways. Okay. Now I want
it to the advertising,
the Black tux.com.
All right.
Looking great for a wedding or a special
event has never been easier with black
Tux dotcom
with high quality rental
suits and Tuxedos.
Why is this itchy
delivered to your doorstep?
The Black Tux is giving guys
a new to rent and get this.
The Black Tux offers free home triathlons.
Try Ons so you can see the fit and feel
the quality of your suit months before
your event through these fucking
companies. Man, this is like,
you're not going to have to
leave your house anymore.
You can get food sent to
your house. Wine, Cindy,
a house and a fucking Tuxedo.
You know,
and God knows horrors have always been
willing to come to your fucking as you
eat it right there.
This is the list is the final.
This is a final piece of the puzzle
like you putting together a championship
team. All you were missing was the
fucking Tuxedo. You go to blue apron,
he gets you fucking food,
right?
You go to fucking loot crate to get
your t shirt that you're going to wear
underneath all the bullshit. You go to
fucking something and me undies, right?
To get your sexy Greg Louganis sign,
right?
And then you got the fucking Roger Roger
Moore, right Sean Connery Tux. I know.
You know, how do you do this? It's the
best part is just done completely online.
No trips to the Tux. Tuxedo shop
required. The Black Tux start doll.
That's the worst.
When you go to the Tuxedo shop,
there's always that guy who's been
there for like forever and he's got dead
fucking tape measure
around his fucking neck.
Whatever the fuck you call that thing.
You know the,
you know those people don't clean their
ears to the point that everything just
turns black in there.
It looks like somebody lit a firecracker
off in both their fucking ears. Sorry.
The Black tux.com lets you create your
look or choose from tons of styles,
selected outfits starting at just $95.
These suits have a modern fit and are
made from the Italian fine Italian wool.
The highest quality on the rental market.
You're going to buy a fucking wool suit.
Okay.
And if you have any questions or issues,
their expert. Yeah. Why is this itchy?
It's gotta be some new kind of wool,
like mad at a modal or something.
And if you have any questions or issues,
their expert customer care has
your back every step of the way.
After ordering your suit will
arrive 14 days before your event.
Why don't I pay attention to Camas?
Yeah.
After ordering comma,
your suit will arrive 14
days before your event.
That's a full two weeks to try it
on and make sure everything fits.
If anything is less than perfect,
the black Tux will send you a
free replacement right away.
When your event's over,
just drop your rental back in the mail.
Shipping is free both ways.
How easy is that to get started now?
Visit the black tux.com/bur bur and
experience a new way to rent the black
tux.com/burr.
Alright.
Thethe Oh see,
so fuck you man.
Alright.
Siso is the place for comedy.
They won't tell you how amazing they are,
but I will.
Thethe though is amazing the though I
just feel like you know it wasn't my
fault. Anybody says, see, so this is,
I don't know if they don't take
responsibility for their actions, but CSO,
anybody does that is,
it's going to be see some amazing content.
See that it's comedy for
nerds by comedy nerds,
CSOS spelled s e s o Sierra,
Echo,
Echo Sierra Oscar is the new ad free
streaming service bringing you are
hilarious original series,
handpicked classics,
weeks of Standup specials and
more bingeable comedy anytime,
anywhere. CSO, every episode of SNL.
Mm.
Including new episodes the day after
they air the tonight show starring Jimmy
Fallon,
late night with Seth fucking my,
the day after it airs. And even, uh,
they even have classics like
30 rocks, 30 Rock, sorry.
Parks and recreation
and saved by the bell.
30 rocks as a documentary
on crack cocaine. Sorry.
Even British comedies like the
original office with Ricky Gervais'.
He's got a,
uh,
the entire money python catalog,
the it crowd and Steve
Coogan as Alan Partridge, uh,
discover the big names in comedy and
watched the icons before they made it big
like Louis C k when he had hair.
Ah, there was no reason to do that,
you know, ah, fuck you. Like the
original you when you had a life. Um,
Chelsea Peretti Amy fucking shoe.
Okay.
Bo Burnham and so many more critically
acclaimed originals and exclusive content
like harmonquest quest created by
comedian Dan Harmon, and funny as hell,
a variety show featuring such comedians
as Jim Jefferies and Hannibal Burress.
If you're serious about comedy,
you've got to try CSO streaming anytime,
anywhere on any virtual devices. It
mirrors this add way too. Fucking long.
CSO is ad free,
just three 99 per month.
That's less than what you paid for a
latte or an artist and cold brew coffee
you're holding right now.
You beard con.
And right now my listeners can
try CSO for free for two months.
When you use the Promo Code Burdett,
check it out.
Shows you can't get anywhere else from
critically acclaimed original series to
all 40 plus years of SNL. That's
why I'm getting it right there. See,
so was the only original play.
The only place that offers every episode,
every made and new episodes
the day after the air.
Just go to [inaudible] dot com right now
to sign up for two months for free with
the Promo Code [inaudible] at checkout.
That's [inaudible] dot com
Promo code birth. Check it out.
You can do it for fucking free.
Oh look who's here are our old friends.
But
Mandy's,
Andy's Biondi
doctors who don't wear shoes.
[inaudible] too.
Mandy's me,
Andy Reiki Jervais
strengths, bro. When he fucking house,
the Golden Globes are always balls feel.
Nobody knows.
But if he had on me undies,
his voice would even be higher
when he made fucking milk.
Fan of fucking Mel Gibson. Oh
yeah. All right. Me undies.
Picture a world where putting on a new
pair of underwear isn't just fresh.
That's fucking gross.
You know what I mean?
As opposed to what Dale balls hanging
in the things you're stepping into a
better day. Think about underwear.
It's the first thing you put on.
Last thing you take off.
Unless you Matthew mcconaughey,
why would you settle for anything less
than the best feeling underwear on the
planet? Uh, please include all of the
falling point. I always include them.
If you write it, I will read it.
If you build it, they will come.
Me undies focuses solely on producing the
most comfortable underwear you've ever
experienced. It's just what is going on
with other people's underwear. It, it's,
it's a tack in my Frat, Colby my
undies for my friends at me on these.
We're not friends.
I never met these fucking people sent
me a few pairs of while back and now I
can't imagine wearing anything
else. Of course I can't. Okay.
I'm a very fluid person. All right. If I
don't have me undies or whereby my hands,
these, oh my fruit of the loom
cease, uh, it's really easy. Uh,
it's really makes each day that much
better for the price of two cocktails.
Mian he's full dwell, you
know, thing to cocktails,
home pores we talking
about at a fucking bar.
Beyond these will deliver your new pair
of favorite underwear right to your
doorstep.
Better Day guarantee you try them on
if they're not the most comfortable,
best feeling fucking
underwear you've ever had.
There were a fund you and let you
keep your first pair for free.
Included in the price.
It's the sweet touch of modal,
a special fabric made with the best
in class raw materials that are
scientifically proven to be
three times softer than cotton,
scientifically proven by what the
scientists that you hired that are on your
payroll. Maybe it's only two
and a half times. Who knows?
I'll let my balls to be the judge of that.
Your Uber Cozy underwear undies are
sold exclusively on me on these website.
While you're on. Enjoy free
shipping in the U S and
Canada. Uh, for a limited time,
everyone in my audience gets 20%
off. Uh, they're not crate alors,
uh, oil makeup for women too. Uh,
but you have to go to our special URL,
[inaudible] dot com slash burr with the
[inaudible]. He's better day guarantee.
You have nothing to lose. So don't
wait any longer. Go to me undies.
Dotcom slash burner right now,
20% off your order.
That's [inaudible] dot com slash burr
no longer will your balls fall out the
side of your underwear with this snug fit.
And if they do B and e's will,
I don't know what they'll do, but all I
know is it's going to be the sweetest,
softest ball roll to
the left or the right,
depending on where your junk is that you
ever felt in your life before it starts.
It's free, fall down to your
fucking kneecap. Um, all
right. That was disgusting.
It was disgusting.
It wasn't socially redeemable and I don't
think anybody became a better person
listening to it. Um, all right, so
is that the podcast? That is the podcast.
Um, now when I get off the podcast,
I'm going to go look at these
barefoot doctors. You know,
I can't fucking believe they, you know,
the misrepresentative, that fucking site,
you know, they have some guys sitting
there, right with the gay cut tee shirt.
And I'm sitting there thinking like,
all right is going to be
for angry Fuckos like me.
And it's for a bunch of women who, uh,
every time, uh, their boyfriend says, hey,
you know, I don't feel like getting
a, going to see that movie tonight.
I'd rather stay in.
And they go,
oh they go when they eat a fucking
death by chocolate fucking thing.
I Dunno. I don't even want to complain
about anymore. I really don't.
I'm just freaking out
cause I got a kid coming.
I would just like the kid to show up
already so I can get on with that part of
my life. I suppose this is what,
this is literally what it's like.
Sometimes this reminds me obviously too
much emotionally heightened state than
this,
but I always remember when I would be
standing the side of the stage and it was
just a fucking brutal crowd and I knew
that they were going to scream and yell
the entire fucking show and it was just
going to be 45 minutes of pure fucking
hell. I always remembered just the
worst part was not going out there.
It was waiting the second I got out there,
I didn't give a shit because it's
just like every second I'm out here
is one less is I am a second
closer to this fucking being over.
It's like doing cardio,
getting on the fucking thing and doing
it is not a fucking problem. It's,
it's the stretching beforehand,
you know,
putting on the workout clothes,
dragging your ass over to the machine.
The second you get on the thing,
I'm in literally 30 seconds into it.
You listen to your tones,
you having a good fucking time.
Everything is fucking great. It's, it's
the getting, it's the getting there,
at least for me.
And you know what?
I think that that's something
that we can all relate to, is it,
I don't fucking know. Anyways, uh,
I started to watch the Celtics
last night against Utah. Uh,
I got to watch that one cause I
think the Bruins a plan today and uh,
I'm trying to do this.
I'm going to watch every Bruins and
every Celtic game that I possibly can.
It's fun.
I got to tell you something I never
realized because I haven't watched it so
long.
When you watch NBA hoop,
it's so easy to start to get to know your
team because they got a starting five.
You know what I mean? Patriot's, you got
11 guys on offense. 11 guys on defense.
Basketball has five five starters.
Their play,
they start both ways. Offensive
Defense, run down the fucking court.
Now you're on defense,
you know,
I guess the Bruins just to have a
starting line and then they're starting to
defensemen. That's five. And then they got
a goalie. But thing about what, how many,
you know, I don't know how many
fucking players are on a hockey team.
How fucked up is that?
All these years of watch and I don't feel
like football is like 41 42 people you
know of which if you know like 10 of
them, you kind of know your fucking team.
What do you guys think?
I'm going to say there's like 25 guys.
Well let's see this for fucking lines.
Four lines.
Three guys in a line.
That's 12 you've got two goaltenders
that's 14 and then you've got like what?
Eight defensemen? Something
like that. Six to eight. Yeah.
I'm going to say about 25 and then you
got like the guys who don't get in the
game, you know with the, with the WHO's
hockey stuff doesn't smell it off.
At least their, their practice
stuff probably smells. I'm sure.
How many players on a hockey tea?
I'm gonna say 25.
Yeah.
Uh,
under the NHL rules,
each team is allowed to have up to 18
players with additional two goalkeepers
for a total of 20. That's
it. Well, there's really no,
excuse me not knowing I was only 20
players. Right. That's when you're on a,
on a crazy level of a sports fan is if
you can name all fucking 20 players on
your hockey team and all what
11 guys on the basketball team.
Just for the simple fact that they fucking
overlap, I would say. And by the way,
my, my wife taped off the sports jeopardy
set. We're hosted by Dan Patrick.
But judging by some of the questions, it
was a little dated, but uh, I was like,
finally a jeopardy.
I'm going to do well on it.
And I still got my fucking ass kicked
because it was, it was fucking hard shit.
Like who is he like they had like,
uh,
yeah,
uh, bankrupt teams, teams that went
bankrupt yet to know the owner's name.
If you know the owner's name,
it's like you're watching fucking
sports talk radio and all of that shit.
Give me a fucking break. Wait,
what? What's wrong with you? Yeah.
I'll tell you right now our specialty
fucking coach, you get to that level.
You know what? I'm just babbling here.
I don't have fucking time to do this.
All I was doing was checking in on you
and that, that's, that's the podcast.
Have a great weekend yet conch and
um, no, no, no, no. Why am I, why?
You know what? Why do I say that?
You know why I fucking say that?
Because of defensive. If I actually
said something nice to you, I'll be, ah,
what are you a fucking show up date,
right? Then my shoulders start coming up.
I hope you guys have a wonderful
rest of your week. I can't do this.
I can't fucking do is have a great
weekend. You fucking cuts. All right.
Can I see that in the most
loving way possible? All right.
Did that make you uncomfortable? Good.
Welcome to my fucking world and a here.
Let's do a little bit of music and
then afterwards we'll play some, uh,
some clips from a podcast
scarred by Thursday.
Then we'll just want to fucking half
maybe on Monday. Who knows? Alright,
go fuck yourself.
So talk to your mother.
Hey, what's going on? Uh, Bill
Bar and this is the money. Hey,
morning podcast, the first one for 2009.
So I want to take some time to waste.
So I tried to, I tried to,
I tried to come out nice.
I tried to start it by being a, I can't
do it. I just can't say something nice.
Why can't I just start my podcast to be
like, hey, happy new year everybody. Hi.
Hope you had a nice Christmas. You
know, even though I feel that I,
I can't get myself to say it.
I have to market,
I have to say happy new year.
And it's silly voice, you
know, I can't just be like,
hey, happy, happy. I can't
even do it. Happy New Year,
you know,
that doesn't sound happy or sad or angry.
It just sounds like I'm
reading it off the cue cards.
We tried to give it the
feeling it deserves. Hey,
let me try again. Uh, oh. Oh, I got
a phone call. Hang on one second.
Hang on. Hang on one
second. Hello. Hey Dan.
What's going on man? Uh, uh, I'm actually,
I'm finishing up a podcast. Can I, can I
call you right back in like, uh, oh, I do.
I do buy, yeah. Okay.
That's the fucking tax man.
So it's the goddamn tax man. It'd
be fucking year, I think. Hey,
I actually got ahead a little bit and
then what did they do to come out?
And they just fucking,
why I make the perfect amount of
fucking money in this country.
You know what I mean?
I'm not rich enough to fucking afford
somebody to tell the IRS to go fuck
themselves and I'm not broke. So, um,
I'm the fucking, you know what I am? And
when you watch the discovery channel,
you know that that fucking a
gazelle that's walking with a limp.
That's what I am.
The fucking lines.
Their ears perked up and they try to
separate me from the fucking hurt.
That's who I am on the tax man comes
around. Some God damn fucking assholes.
All right. Sorry. You know potholes
all up and down my fucking street.
You know what I mean?
Why don't I pay you when I just go
down a fucking home depot and buy some
Goddamn tar and I'll fell. Can you buy
car at home depot? I'm sure you can,
but God knows there's nobody
there to help you find it. Huh?
50,000 fucking square foot store with
200 foot ceilings and they got like three
people with aprons walking around.
You ask him any question they
don't know where the fuck
fucking bitch shut up. Just
go hang yourself with your
right. But no, don't need,
you're not, you're not the problem. You're
not the problem. You get a poor worker.
Sorry about that. Do you know what they
actually did get those automated? Uh,
they got those automated cashiers out
here at the grocery store and you know,
I get out and there's a whole
bunch of people just lining up,
lining up doubt.
The corporations fire other Americans.
I swear to God,
if you're one of my podcast members and
you go to the grocery store and you can,
you stand in that automated line,
I want you to delete yourself
as one of my friends. Okay?
I have a zero fucking
tolerance for that shit. It's,
it's unbelievable how stupid people are
and I love how they have like the one
employee where his job is literally
to stand there and teach you how to
basically do his job so
that they can then fire you.
And I know what the corporation
is going to do. They had,
it's going to help cut costs on
food. Really. You got eight people,
they're making $8 an hour.
That's 64 bucks an hour.
You've got a thousand people in
here buying cornflakes. What?
What do I save half a cent on my
fruity pebbles? You fucking cunts.
That was the first concert
of 2009 right there.
People stand in line,
help keep a fellow American at work.
Huh?
Blah blah blah blah blah blah, blah,
blah. Do it. I'm not even joking.
Don't do that.
Don't do that shit.
These fucking parking structures
with their pay stations.
Now I have to be the parking attendant.
I don't work here. I got to be for free.
I got to do this for fucking free and
put another guy out of work who now is
walking around trying to find a job.
Find a job for all I know he's
going to start writing jokes.
You know don't do that shit. Don't, don't.
Okay. You know me? Yes.
Actually you don't know me.
You think you know me cause he
listened to me every Monday,
but I'm telling something about myself.
I don't give a fuck what you do.
This is the one time where I'm going
to get up on my goddamn soapbox. Okay.
Which is really difficult for me because
I've got a big head and my equilibrium
starts to fuck with me when
I stand up on soap boxes,
which is why I don't preach, but I'm going
to preach on this one. Do not do that.
Go to the grocery store.
Stand in line. Okay,
let that mother of three
keep her job. Okay. Or that,
that fucking convicted drunk driver who
was fine to put his life back together
again.
Let them keep their jobs.
Do not stand in and learn how to do it.
You're going to do their job for fucking
free and it's not quicker and in the
future you're going to have,
she didn't have to fucking stand there.
And you know what happens when you need
a price check on a fucking cantaloupe.
You have to go do it.
I don't,
I just fucking blows my mind.
We're already pumping our
guests around gas people.
When's it going to stop? Huh?
Okay. I had a hell of a week.
All right. Actually, you know what?
I want to know how you guys feel about
that stuff. Am I, am I, you know,
do you feel like I have a really good
point there because I feel I do all my,
you know,
if I was living in the 18 hundreds would
I be the guy going stop churning butter?
No. Keep churning butter.
Don't let them do this for no,
but that's not even the fair example
because it's not like there was maybe that
has a bunch of butter charters.
If they could somehow come up with
automated buttered butter churning.
You know what? I really paid my pay
to myself into a corner with that,
that reference, I really had
nothing. They're all right,
but I still think I made a
good point there. All right,
let's talk about my week.
I had a fucking insane week and,
um,
I went to the rose bowl with
a fellow comedian and uh,
I'm not gonna name his name. Usually
I'll do that. Maybe it gives somebody,
you know, bump up their
friends or that type of stuff,
which I'd love to do for this guy,
but not behavior was so,
uh,
colorful.
That's the word I'll use that you know,
just in case, you know what I mean?
I'm old school.
I don't name names.
When I started talking about a
semi crimes that I committed,
not really committing, well I guess
being drunk in public is a crime bill.
Why don't you shut the fuck up and get to
the story and we'll, I'll be the judge.
Fine, fine. Look you guys with all the
tension beginning of 2009 you know,
so you guys be more relaxed this year.
You know things going to be
fat and 2009 may the love bit,
they gonna Rhyme, you know, just
make it rhyme and then, then, then,
then I'm supposed to feel good.
You know,
and I'm not supposed to
notice that last year it was,
things are going to be great in 2008 and
now you've, you've knocked it down, outs,
things. It'll be fine things. It'd
be great man. I think he'd be fine.
No,
don't freak out in 2010 Ooh.
Did they combine this with Canada in 2011
why am I fucking checking myself out at
a grocery store and I'm not getting paid
for it? Okay, so my name is,
I go to the rose bowl with a a comedian.
We're just going to call him Joe.
All right.
Cause that's the classic alias name.
When you don't want to get somebody
in trouble, you just call him Joe.
But the ironic thing is this
guy's name is actually gel.
So me and Joe,
we go to the a fellow comedian and now
you can try to figure out who the fuck he
is and it's not fisco. Um, we
go to the Rose Bowl and, uh,
we had great intentions. Okay. And
let me paint a picture for you. Okay.
When you go to the rose bowl,
it's one of the great
tailgating experiences you'll
ever have. First of all,
you're going to the rose bowl.
Okay?
The granddaddy of them all home have a
bunch of Superbowls Superbowls with fully
that, that Super Bowl, uh,
if you see that famous Lynn Swann
catch that wasn't made there,
I actually realized that was made
at Temple University, wasn't it?
I don't fucking know.
There's been a oh nine,
although the Jackie Slater one where
he dropped the ball, that's right.
That that cowboy Steelers won
the greatest fucking, I dunno,
clash of two powerhouse
teams I ever saw was the, uh,
I dunno, whatever. They played
a bunch of fucking things there.
And I don't have any information front
of me and I'm really killing the momentum
of the story. So anyway, so
we go there, right. And uh,
you get right behind the Rosebowl is
what I'm assuming is an 18 hole golf
course.
Cause God knows that's how big it felt
at the end of the game when I was two
shit faced and we couldn't find the
car and we walked for four hours.
But that, that I'm getting ahead of
myself. You know what I'm foreshadowing,
I'm doing what all great movies.
Do you know what I mean?
You go see a movie whenever they
show movie about a guy who dies,
everybody knows he's going to die. So
they show them, died in the beginning,
and then the next thing is they go back
to his childhood. You know what I mean?
Except they never do that
with the Elvis movie.
Cause then they'd have to start the movie
with some fat fuck dying on a toilet
and no one wants to do that.
I'll just,
but it was that my pancreas plop.
Um, anyways, so Jesus Christ,
let's get some momentum here.
So we fucking, we go to this tailgate.
All right. And this is the deal.
Basically, there's just two
of us and amongst us, we
have four hamburger patties,
two bags of chips, hamburger
buns, 12 pack of Bud Light,
12 pack of Budweiser,
and a Clint Eastwood canteen,
size of fucking crown royal,
and to Cuban cigars that I
snuck back from fucking Canada.
So we're ready to go. I got my
sunblock, we load it up into the Prius,
which is, uh, which was just fucking
hilarious. You know, everybody,
everybody tries to outman people
at the, uh, at the tailgates,
people coming up there with, they
have their fucking, you know,
for two or pickups with the lift kits,
you know,
their generators, skydive fucking
satellite dish in a flat screen TV.
You know, I came there with a
little Hibachi, but whatever.
We had the big thing of crown royal,
so people and Cuban cigars.
So no one fucked with us, right?
So we're having a great time.
All of a sudden this lady comes
walking by and she's like, Hey,
do you want to buy a little ticket
holder for your ticket? I'm like,
absolutely sweetheart, 10 bucks a
whack. Let me get, let me get that.
Two Times they had baby, you know,
you got a cigar in your mouth,
you start getting a little swagger,
some reason when your leg
starts rocking back and forth,
like you've got to sing it like
you're going to sing an Elvis song.
I was failing it and the great thing was
I didn't give a fuck about either team
USC, all Penn State. I was just
happy to fucking be there, you know?
But I quickly realized most
people were for the Trojans.
So automatically I'm a con second cons
of the year. I'm like, you know what,
I'm going to root for the,
I'm a roof a Penn state because this
gives me way more chance to annoy people.
Plus I, I've never liked USC and uh, most
of it has to do with back in the day,
I used to be a Notre Dame fan before
Lou Holtz. What? They're holier,
holier than thou. We don't do steroids.
Shut the fuck up. Yes you do. Alright.
I had acne when I was fucking a teenager.
Right? But it wasn't all over my back.
And I also couldn't pick up a
house. Okay, so you fucking,
people are doing steroids anyways.
And also I always hated
the Trojans fight song.
They play it every three seconds bad,
you know, they came like half a yard.
And it also reminds me of Fleetwood Mac
who I never liked. So fuck the Trojans,
right? So anyways, so we're sitting there
and we'd drink and party and would eat.
We eat burgers and a,
then we break up the crown royal after
we had polished off a good half a case
between the two of us.
It's probably nine 30 in the morning.
And we just started
pounding this crown royal,
which is going down like fucking Koolaid.
I was really impressed with my ability,
or at least the, the makers of crown
royal. That is some smooth shit. So,
uh,
so basically we start walking towards
the stadium and the alcohol slowing
through me and that's when I go into the,
my transformation.
I don't know what happens
to me at sporting events,
but instantly I just become the loud guy.
I feel like I'm,
I'm doing a comedy show.
I want to make the people around me
laugh and I also want to irritate as many
fucking people as I can.
So I start walking in there
and I quickly notice, um,
well I know I went to go buy a program,
I'm trying to put this all back
together cause I was pretty drunk. I go,
just to give you an idea of,
of the mood that I was in,
I get to about a hundred
yards from the stadium.
This lady's selling programs
and she's like, yeah,
I get you probe the ad pack America gets
a Parker Hanson. Like I fuck it. I want,
I want a souvenir. So I'll walk up and
Mike, how much are they? She's like,
10 bucks, my car, I find,
so this other guy comes walking up
because how much for the programs?
And The lady's like 10 bucks,
right? And the guy starts bitching.
Be Kidding me, right? So I'm standing
there, I got a Cuban cigar, I go,
you know what, let me get another one,
two times. Let me get two of those.
All right, one for you over there.
And the guy's like, really? I go, Hey,
I go take a look at me. They
know, you know you're looking at,
you're looking at a big shot.
Take a good look. There's not a,
there's not a lot of us left. I swear
to God, I said that and I was so drunk.
I was only half joking.
Like I knew I was being an asshole,
but like I was only half.
I had a fucking Cuban cigar. Go
Fuck Yourself. I'm a big shot.
Let's get a program
for this fag over here.
Who's bitching about 10 pool still
Roseville and bitches about a $10 fucking
program.
You know what I mean?
He should have been de pants and he
should had his tickets removed right there
and sent right back to wherever the fuck
he keep key came from, sent to an apple.
Bee's watch the game there.
All right.
Kind of fucking behaviors that is the
granddaddy of them all take you fucking
money out and play the Goddamn game. All
right. So anyway, saw him Hammock, right.
And we're fucking, we're walking.
And uh, I don't know what happened.
We got into the stadium,
everything was cool.
And then they have this weird
sort of like they funnel you in,
cause it's a really old
stadium. It's like, you know,
it's like trying to go through the
Lincoln tunnel like five o'clock at night.
It's a pain in the ass.
So I'm standing there,
I'm getting frustrated
because it's getting close
to kickoff and I hate missing
kickoff. So I'm getting pissed. And
I noticed that the Penn state fans,
they got this chant where one of them, I
don't know where it just yells, we are.
And then all the Penn
state fans go Penn state.
And then the dude yells again we are and
they'll go Penn state and they say it
like five times and then the end, the
guy who starts to chant goes thank you.
And then everybody screams Yo,
well cub.
And I immediately noticed that it annoyed
the shit out of all these USC fence.
You know,
cause they kind of felt like it was a
home game cause they were out there.
So next thing you know, I don't
even think it. Next thing you know,
coming out of my mouth, I'm
going, well I'm not here.
I'm not from Penn state. I don't know
Shit, right? But I just start going, we,
everybody starts going Penn state,
Penn state,
and I'm like, thank you. And
they're like, Yo, welcome. I'm like,
this is fucking awesome.
I can do this the whole game and annoy
the shit out of people around me. So
like it took us 20 minutes,
20 minutes to get through the tunnel
and I swear to God, I was like,
perfect timing light.
As we got through the tunnel,
this check is finishing singing the
national anthem as we just take in the
Roseville on a sunny California day,
everybody's wearing their Trojan colors.
Everybody's wearing that Penn state.
There's pawpaws people are going
fucking nuts. And this lady's like,
and no home of the brave.
And what is,
she finished a fucking stealth bomber.
Flies right over the God damn
top. I'm shift, right? It's
like a fucking acid trip.
I almost passed out. Right? So now,
you know, we've got end zone seats,
you know, evidently I'm not a big shot
and we'll wait at the top of the stadium,
which is a really rough thing to
negotiate when you're a redhead drinking
whiskey in the sun,
right?
We get all the way up to like row whatever
fucking triple f and you know it's an
old stadium. Okay. And you know, back in
the day, like you were tall if you will,
like five foot six when the stadium
was built. And now you know,
with fucking growth hormones and
all the preservatives in the food,
we basically outgrown the stadium's,
not to mention the cheesecake factories
that have these fucking people go to
every other day.
So I'm trying to walk a tight rope down.
I'm really acting this out
of my bedroom by the way.
This is how into the
stories I get to tell.
So I'm literally walking a fucking tight
rope trying to get down to my seat and
I just become that guy.
I fell, I didn't fall.
I sorta like,
like [inaudible].
It was like almost like I was on a show.
I was the only guy in a ship that was
in a fucking perfect storm and all of a
sudden the whole thing just
lifted to the right side.
And I landed on this like 55 year old
lady back then like land like I was doing.
I was on one foot and I,
I put a nice forearm,
oh I'll Samuelson in front of the
net fucking action right on a pack.
And I was so drunk it took me,
I swear to God that at least 28 seconds
to get offer in the entire time I am
apologizing with my fucking cigar whiskey
breaths just gone Psi Phi and I just,
I couldn't get off it cause I,
the only way to get off of was to put all
my weight on my forum and use her as a
banister to push me back up because
nobody's fucking helping me cause I'm
obviously the drunk guy.
You don't want to touch me.
So 28 seconds to trying to figure out if
I have the quad strength to pull myself
up without pushing off the
back of this old lady's neck.
I finally just say fuck it
and just drive my, the Meta,
my forearm right between her
shoulder blades and I get up,
I apologize profusely and I don't
know what Joe is doing at this point.
He was fucking probably just
standing there watching the game.
But basically we finally get to our seats.
It was unreal.
I didn't know what, we got to
our seats and I, we turn around,
we faced the game to watch the game and
next thing you know this lady is just
screaming at us.
She's like that screaming
and she's yelling,
you can't smoke in here. And I'm like,
what the fuck is she talking about?
Because I put my my cigar out.
I'm going to tell you to do the
fucking Cuban is sweet too, man.
I smoked that thing all the
way down like a Goddamn Roach.
It's like burning my fucking fingers
and she's yelling, stop smoking.
I'm like the fuck she talking about
do I smell like a cigar? And I turned,
I looked,
I looked to my right and Joe is standing
there with the fucking Cuban cigars
still lit and his mouth. I don't know
how the fuck you got a past security.
I think it's, cause we had
our tickets, those tickets,
things I bought arrived on neck. I don't
know if he had it down by his side,
but he's sitting at chomp on, on
it like fucking Archie bunker. So
you know, in defense of me, if she just
turned around and she had just said,
hey guys, um, you know that, you
know, I don't know if you know,
but there's no smoking in here.
Yeah, I would have been, you know,
I'm a happy drunk. I swear to God,
I'm angry when I'm sober, but I sorta,
I'm a happy drunk. I just would have
been like, Hey, aside bought that,
we didn't know. Oh, what do you for you?
I see. All right, good luck. Bye. Ha Ha,
whatever. I would've kept it at that,
but she fucking was yelling at us.
So I don't like being yelled at.
And I like being,
I like fucking with people and I'm
shit faced and Joe is of the same ilk.
And then that's when it all started.
She just based, she's like, Hey, she
goes, there's no smoking in here.
And then immediately I just go
and I just go. I'm just like, Hey,
said.
So she goes to California,
I had a smoke and doors were
like, we're outside. And she goes,
you're not allowed to smoke here.
And I go, you're not my mother.
This isn't our section. This is in
your section. Turn around. Right.
I just kept being an asshole.
And then finally she goes,
I'm going to call security. And
I'm like, call column. She goes,
I've got to call him. I go, go ahead
and call him. And then in my head,
my brain is going, Bill, shut up, shut up.
You're going to get,
we're 90 seconds into the game,
you're going to get kicked out.
And I just couldn't stop myself.
I just kept saying
column, column, and then,
then she made some sort of comment,
I think about the size of Joe's knows,
and then he said, hey, he goes,
you need to lose a hundred pounds
to talk to me, bitch. He said,
the guy to the left of us turns
around and he's like, Hey,
I got my kid, I got my kid
here, what do you cursive?
And then Joe goes, well then don't
bring them to a fucking football.
So now I'm doing that last, you
know that laugh. We're like,
your mouth is wide open but
there's no air coming in or out.
I'm having the time of my life
and then the fucking guy goes,
he goes, I'm going to call security.
And then I'm just, then at once again,
I'm going, God, I'm going to
call it God and call up call.
I was just calling that bluff because
we were so fucking jam packed and I knew
they weren't going to walk
down there and go do that.
So that lady makes
another fucking comment.
At which point Joe makes another comment
about her weight and then she just
turns down and it's like mark and yells
down to a husband and next thing you
know this fucking dude comes running over
and he starts screaming at us as he's
screaming at us. This spray is coming
out of his mouth all over his wife.
So it was easy. I had a fucking,
Nah, I was just going, sir, sir,
you're spitting on your wife and once
you know, I hope it was pathetic.
He was like 53 but like,
and I'm 40 and I'm thinking like that.
I'm not too old to fight this guy.
You know, it was just, Oh God,
I'm front pieces together. And so when we
all sit down, right? So then we sit down.
I think Joe had put out the cigar.
Maybe it was just holding it down.
I don't know what was going on.
But now by this time we'd
already missed the kickoff.
The Trojan's get the ball and I think
this is the basically the one good play
Penn state made all day. They Trojans
their first play. I think offense,
they handed off the ball and they tried
to do like some sort of sweep the Penn
state defense strung out and just stuck
this guy either for no gain or for like
lots of one yard.
And then Joe go,
I forgot to mention is
a good six foot four,
just a huge guy just starts screaming
like an inch from the back of the Lady's
head who's a Trojan Fan. He just
starts screaming life, not the head.
Not that,
not that I can't believe
like her hair wasn't,
he was yelling so loud as she,
I know.
She turned around and she'd had that shift
of noxious. That's just, it was, it was,
it was great.
It was fucking great.
And then basically what would
have for the rest of the game,
shit would calm down and then we would,
we would,
I don't know,
we would mumble something about her and
then she would fucking yell down to her
husband and that he'd come
over threatening to kick
our ass and we would just
laugh at them. And then, I dunno,
I just realized I was so drunk.
I can't even remember the rest. I
remember it was the very end of the game,
uh,
somebody Joe us,
somebody said something about the score
and then the lady in front of us goes,
yeah, I'm surprised you can
count that high. I go, yeah,
why don't you try counting calories?
Right. Something real me like that.
And then once again, she's like
mark. And then at this point,
half the crowd and left
because it was such a blow out.
This too comes over and he
starts fucking screaming at me.
It doesn't scream at Joe
because Joe six foot four,
he yells at me cause I'm fucking barely
five 10 and I'm a fucking redhead. Right?
Even with the shaved head,
I still look like fucking howdy doody.
So he starts yelling at me
and he keeps telling me, yeah,
I'm going to fire you down on the field.
That's why he kept saying,
he kept telling me he's going to grab me
and fire me down on the fucking field.
And I was just, you know, and
I was just being an asshole.
That did do it. I'm gonna fight. Are
you said that you already said that.
You already said you already said
it. You fucking cunt. All right,
if you're going to do it,
you would have and you didn't see you're
not so sit down and shut the fuck up.
Which is funny.
Cause by the end of the game,
everyone in the stands somehow
liked us and hated those people.
I mean path of it was cause they
were assholes. The other half was,
they couldn't hear the shift that we
will mumble him at this dude's wife
Poo. I know at this point he might
have a little bit of sympathy for it,
but I mean I'm telling
you she was, she was, uh,
she was an asshole and she's the
one who made it personal first.
She made the comment
about Joe's knows she, uh,
oh she was doing real hacky lines too.
She's told me I was ugly.
She goes and I always can lose
weight, you know, which, uh,
I believe I saw during the second
season of def jam and um, you know,
and I thought,
well we will come in with was a lot more
clever and if it was a battle of the
bands in a standup situation,
I think we want. So, uh,
basically what ended up happening,
I know this is a long ass fucking story.
I don't even have time for questions
this week, but long story short,
we ended up walking out. Um, I want,
I believe that somehow the lady in front
of us to who was being a jerk had a
bunch of these dark streaks on the
back of a shirt towards the end of it.
I don't know what it was and almost
look like a ashes from a cigar.
But um, I know that that didn't happen
because there's no smoking in there.
But anyways, we go to leave
and we're basically so drunk.
I don't know, man. It took
us like fucking nine hours,
literally took us 50
minutes to find our car.
I think it was calmer for being such
assholes in, in, in, in the stadium.
And I don't, I don't know who
the fuck set up the parking lot,
the things out there.
But they basically,
the way they do the sections on this golf
course is they have like balloons that
they just have numbers, number
one, number two, number three.
But they're not lit up.
So you can't really seem at night.
So you walk out of the stadium
drunk and you look up and you see,
I saw the number to where we were,
where we were parked and, but you know,
you've got to follow the path because
you can't walk through the sand traps and
shit like that.
So you look down for half a second,
then you look up and it's like a big
fucking oak tree in front of you and now
you don't know where you are.
It's like the end of the shining without
the shrubs. It's a fucking golf course,
right?
So,
and you're far enough away from the
stadium where you can't get your bearings.
And we just wandering around and around
and around and it's getting to the point
like, you know, like hypothermia is
becoming an issue because it's a desert.
It starts getting cold,
was shit faced and we just can find a car.
It was like the Blair witch.
We kept coming back to the same goddamn
ladies' teas, whatever the fuck we were.
And then I lost all confidence in
my ability to find the damn car.
So I started following Joe,
who is convinced,
even though we both know where
we're parked in section two,
we went from section three to section 40,
section five,
and he keeps telling me to go in that
direction because for some reason he
thinks numerically it's going
to go three, four, five to,
I dunno, it took us an hour to
find the fucking car. And uh,
at that point I started sobering up and
I started thinking about our behavior
and I was starting to thinking like,
and I kinda kinda feeling an asshole.
Yeah.
You know,
I shouldn't say I shouldn't taken the
higher ground even though they'd throw was
a content, you know? And he was just
like, what are you talking about?
What are you talking
about? You, she was a con.
We treated her like one
and a half and that's it.
It's quite a lot about that guy.
He just,
he just breaks it down to
the simplest fucking point.
Hey Buddy, I got my kid here. What don't
take your kid to a fucking football game,
which you know, I know that's
harsh, especially if you have kids,
but think about it.
Think about it.
Why would you bring your kid to his
professional, so to sporting event?
Not only that,
that the guy with the kid is
being hypocritical because
he was me before he had
a kid. All right? He was having the
time of his fucking life and what now?
Because he has a kid now all
of a sudden I'm supposed to,
I'm supposed to fucking act my age.
You know,
it's like the fucking
baby boom generation.
They Bang so much the fucking in the
mud Woodstock that by the time I come
around there's herpes and aids and all
this shit and then these, you know,
and then they come around with their
don't do drugs where a condom shit after
they had the time of their fucking lives.
I'm so glad all of them and getting
that whole generation is getting hip
replacements now with their fucking cause.
They all had that fucking Olivia Newton
John High impact aerobics tape that they
did try and to stay in shape and
it's the one good fucking thing.
Consider I got to fuck with the God
damn trash bag around my dick my entire
career. Right. The very least,
I at least knew to stretch
before you lifted weights.
And I also dangers of high impact
aerobics. Okay. When I did my aerobics,
I definitely was rocking the leg warmers,
but I did not let my feet
leave the ground. Okay.
So anyways, so that's
my rose bowl story. Um,
it's a fucking law when I know that, but
I think it had some nice moments. But um,
yeah. But getting back to that, what do
you guys think about that stuff? You know,
sporting events are not for children.
Okay.
And I know they always try to talk
about the good old days of sports.
The good ole days of sports is bullshit.
Okay.
When I was a kid, first football game
I went to, I was fucking terrified.
I was terrified.
It was not a place for kids.
It was a place for adults who hadn't
achieved what they thought they were going
achieve in life to get their
fucking anger and frustration out.
People with in loveless
marriages, you know, people,
you know,
people who could tell they were going to
get laid off the next week or maybe the
rd got laid off and they just wanted to
get it out. Okay. And they, you know,
they've now turned going to a fucking
football game into like you're standing in
line with a bunch of people waiting
to get their kids, you know,
photo taken with Santa Claus.
You know,
and even if you go further back than
my childhood, which was seventies,
early eighties,
um,
you go back to the 1950s
they talk about that. Oh,
the good old days is sports or what
do you mean? What, what, when, uh,
when they finally let a black guy
playing baseball and they said,
we'll fucking black cat on the field and
all that racist shit that was going on.
Can you imagine the shit
that was getting yelled in?
The stands when Billy crystal was going
down to la to go down and go and watch
the mic boy, Oh boy, I've got myself a
hot dog and assessed Barilla. You know,
they always tell us stories about how
great it was back then. It wasn't,
it wasn't great. They were
way more racist, way more
ignorant, way more sexist.
And people went to the games and
they saw Johnny Unitas. Okay,
so now for some reason,
now it's my turn to be an asshole and be
a drunk and have a good time and all of
a sudden I have to take everything down
a level, you know, not now. Now it's,
it's Chuckie cheese time. It isn't.
And I know you guys are saying,
well that's because you don't have a
kid right now. No, fuck that. Fuck that.
I wouldn't bring my kid to the game.
Or if I brought to give to the game,
I would prepare him. I prepare them, you
know, this is what's going to happen.
Okay, you might see a fight, you know,
hey dad might even get in one. No, I'm
not. I never took it to that level.
But you know what I mean?
I think, uh, I dunno,
it just felt guilty.
I am for my,
my behavior that they actually pulled
up a quote from George Orwell who,
uh,
granted this is from Wikipedia,
which the other day I looked up something
that I knew something about and was
completely inaccurate.
But this is according to
Wikipedia, George Orwell said,
serious sport has nothing to do
with fairplay. It's a bound up.
It's bound up with hatred,
jealousy,
boastfulness disregard of all
rules and sadistic pleasures,
pleasures in witnessing violence.
In other words,
it's war minus the shooting. Exactly. Now,
why the fuck would you bring a
child to that? And not only that,
when was George Orwell alive
a long fucking time ago?
I don't know when he was alive. When did
you write? 1984 he didn't write it in 83.
I know that he wouldn't like the 30.
Stinney I'm just saying. And See,
that's how he described sports
back then. So guys, like, you know,
these Billy crystal guys were always do
those little heartwarming stories about,
uh,
you know,
their baseball cards and going down to
the baseball stadium and acting like it
was this fucking, you know, this
time that was lost, you know,
George Orwell right there,
according to Wikipedia,
the guy proved my point.
I'm a moron,
but I did have a good time and I'm
gonna tell you like this right now,
if you ever get a chance in your
life to smoke a Cuban cigar,
definitely do it all right.
Because I'm not even a big smoker.
And I could tell how fucking amazing
that cigar was because I've drank fine
wines and I can't tell the difference,
you know?
And it took me a long time to be
comfortable with myself. You know,
when you go through the whole long
process of spinning the big red wine glass
around, I see red up on wine
to try to learn. So I, I,
you know about it.
So I wouldn't feel so fucking stupid when
they bring a nice bottle of wine over
and I'm like, you know, this tastes like
the shit I used to drink in high school.
You know, I learned
that, you know, red wine.
The reason why it's in a bigger glass
because I'm about the oxygen and you want
it to breathe more and how to,
you know,
move it around the fucking table and
then you shove your fucking nose all the
way in it and yet put it in.
You switch it all around your mouth.
I got all the moves down and
I'm like swallowed up Mike. Yes.
This tastes like every other fucking
red wine I've ever had. That's not true.
I can tell the difference between like,
you know,
a Cabernet or low or something like that.
But like I can't tell like the
difference between a 1499 bottle and a,
a $60 bottle and uh,
you know,
I guess I'm trying to say
with this podcast, I'm not
that culture. Okay. All right.
Well, so why don't you guys chime
in with that. Okay. Like, well,
do you think David,
they should have a kids section.
Should they just have a Chucky
cheese section? It's not my fault.
You're knocked her up and you can't
go to a game and have a good time now.
You know, you want to be getting drunk
with me. See what I just did there.
That's how I made myself write, made this
guy who can't even defend himself, uh,
actually be secretly agreeing
with me. That's how I do it. Um,
did I mentioned I have a
rat problem. Um, I have, uh,
I have a really nice apartment, but
the garage I have is a glorified shack.
Like if they ever decide to do the
Hatfields and McCoys TV series,
they could shoot it on location
in my garage. Okay. Is a
rotting out hunk of shit.
And even though the door comes down, um,
the hole and the back of the garage, he,
granted you couldn't
drive my car out of it,
but a fucking rat could crawl into it on
a rainy night and then crawl up into my
engine and sleep.
This mother Fucker,
I took my car down to get it service
and they took out the air conditioner
filter and it was rat shit in there
and I got to for everybody going,
Oh God is good. So you
know, being a man, I'm like,
okay, operation kill the
fucking rat is now in motion.
And I sat there and I thought,
how can I kill this motherfucker?
And basically what I did was I went to um,
a smaller hardware cause fuck home
depot in there, eight people in aprons,
um,
and I bought $114 worth of those rat glue
traps and I got a couple of really big
cardboard boxes and then I took some duct
tape because when you don't know what
the fuck you're doing,
duct tape is always a solution.
And I duct taped 28 of
these motherfuckers,
I think over 30, I think I lost count
how many I did on all these boxes,
two big boxes,
side by fucking side.
And I split them underneath my
car. Okay, you want to get dry?
Why don't you try to get,
try and get by that now?
I don't know cause rats are intelligent.
I don't know if what I have in my garage
right now is the star wars plan that
Ronald Reagan always dreamed of.
I don't know if I have the red version
of that or if I have the Maginot line,
you know, national line. Anybody, any
man you want to read up on that one.
That's one of the classic
military blunders of all time.
Basically Germany invaded
France in world war one.
It was trench warfare, ton, ton of loss
of life. They came in, they got invaded,
they got overrun and all that,
blah blah, blah, blah blah shit.
So they wanted to make sure they would
never happen again because they were
worried about Germany, you
know, and why wouldn't you Ben?
So they decided to build like this
is called the Maginot line and it was
permanent trenches with these,
these fucking basically built in.
I don't live like an anti,
it wasn't anti aircraft.
That was the problem that killed him. It
was fucking, uh, like machine gun nest,
like permanent all the way around. And
they spent all this fucking money on it.
And what's hilarious is by the time
they went to war with Germany again,
they had perfected the aircraft and they
basically just flew right up and over
all the fucking trenches.
You don't drop bombs on him and shit.
And they once again took over fucking
France. And I'm so, I don't know.
I don't know if the rat laughed
at it, brought in the, you know,
a couple of friends over
to shit inside of my car,
but I'm going to kill that fucker.
And all you animal lovers can go fuck
yourselves because I'm not losing a
$23,000 automobile to a fucking road.
All right,
I'm going to show him why I live inside.
All right.
And I don't have to shit on an air
conditioner filter filter. Okay,
let's get the podcast questions,
Shelly people.
Um, I'll let you guys know how
it goes if I kill the rat or not.
All right. Podcast question number
one. Bill since you're a patriots fan,
I got to ask you, what's your honest
opinion on the Tuck rule game? Uh,
I'm a raider fan and I think that was
hands down the biggest bullshit call and
the history of sports.
And still to this day I carry it with me.
The fact that the eight ne charges
made the playoffs over the 11 and five
patriots made me happy inside.
And while I respect Tom Brady
is one of the great all time.
Qbs if he snapped his leg in three places,
places I'd be a happy man.
Okay. Um, for those of you
who aren't big sports fans,
the Tuck rule was basically is
basically a rule where the quarterback,
if he goes,
I basically goes into the passing motion,
doesn't throw the ball and if
he brings it back to his chest,
if somebody whacks the ball out,
then it's a considered an
incomplete pass or something.
I really should have looked up the
tuck rule and um, and you know,
basically the Raiders slap the ball
out of Brady's hand. They fell on it.
They had thought they won the game because
it was a fumble. And then the, the,
they brought out this the top rule,
which nobody had ever heard of,
including probably Tom Brady.
Um,
when he wants to know what
is my feeling on that? Um,
I don't feel it was a big relax,
let me finish.
I don't feel it was the biggest
bullshit call in the history of sports.
I think it's the biggest bullshit
rule in the history of sports.
That's the thing. They made the right
call. The rule needed to be changed.
I think it's a bullshit rule. I think
that that should have been a fumble.
It is a fumble. He didn't talk and he
was going to throw it and he didn't.
And then he pulled in, he
got slapped. It is a fumble,
but that's what it should be.
But because of the Tuck rule,
it was actually the right call.
But it's a bullshit rule and
I'm big enough to admit that.
But the reality is,
you know,
why that happened to you and why you
carry that with you. Oh, poor baby.
You've had to carry that since.
What, 2001 Aww. Poor baby.
You know what I had to carry for almost
20 years was that roughing the passer
call. You're probably too
young to remember this,
but we basically beat the fucking Raiders
in 1976 we had you guys beating sugar
bay. Hamilton is coming in against Ken
Stabler. He jumps in the air. Once again,
I'm acting this out.
He jumps in the air as stabler
is going to release the ball.
He's in the fucking air.
The ball is released.
He slams into Ken Stabler and they call
roughing the passer like he was supposed
to change mid air. Now, I don't
know if you guys know this shit,
but back then roughing the
passer was not a yardage penalty.
They basically put the ball where they
were trying to complete it and it was the
end of the game and they threw
a fucking 50 yard hail Mary.
They called roughing the passer,
so they gave him the ball.
Now it's not on the 50 they put it on
like the fucking three yard line and the
Raiders went in to go score that.
My friend was the biggest bullshit call
of all time because that was a complete
wrong interpretation of the rule.
Do you understand the difference?
The top rule is a bullshit rule
that was interpreted correctly.
So the guy made the correct call.
He did make the correct call,
but I feel for you because
that was a bullshit that was a,
it's a bullshit rule and the
Raiders should have won that game.
But that was paid back because the
Patriots should have beat you in 1976 but
because a lot of you rate
of fans are a lot younger,
you don't remember it or maybe
you don't want to remember it,
but I carried that from
1976 to 2001 all right,
so that was 15 years. All
right, youngster, you're
only seven years in the yard.
Bullshit. So I have no
sympathy for you. Okay. Sorry.
I get heated when it comes to sports and
he said something that was the next one.
What's your, what's your opinion
on the field goal guy? You know,
every bunch of guys.
I don't want to fucking read this one.
I only went too long and that when I
get get tickets and some other people,
I don't mind field goal kickers by the
my, sorry. I still got my old laptop.
I'm trying to not hit this
button too much. All right, Bill.
Um, I want your can be
comedic opinion on something.
I was talking to a coworker of mine
about a girl that I had been seeing. Oh,
I love this question. This is a great
story. Everybody just settle in,
settle in and turn this, turn this down.
Turn this down because I think this has,
does this have the word continent? A
mature. Okay, here we go. All right, Bill,
I want your comedic opinion on something.
I was talking to a coworker of mine
about a girl that I had been seeing that
I've been kind of seeing.
I was telling him that one thing I
really like about her is how he wrote the
song, how her, how good
her smell, her hair smells.
Um, well there's Twat of a girl
that works with me, overheard us,
and decided to chime in by
saying shit like she wants,
she wants to meet the girl who would go
out with a guy like me and how she would
actually be nervous to be alone with me.
All right.
I know my reading out loud skills suck.
So let me just sort of paraphrase
what happens. This guy's at work,
he's kind of seeing this girl and he
says to a friend of his gay, you know,
seeing this girl, you know, I really
love him. Her hair smells really great.
That's all we have in the
send instant conversation.
And then this other girl who's not even
in the conversation as a guide, let,
I'd let them meet the girl out like you,
you know,
I'd be nervous to be alone with
you. Right? Completely uncalled for.
And he goes,
et cetera.
So now we recently found out that that
girl who chimed in just had an abortion
like a week and a half ago.
Jesus brought, I brushed her off.
I saw I brushed her off,
but the bitch didn't stop.
She continued on by asking,
Ugh, another female worker,
if she'd be nervous to be alone with me,
which my response was,
why don't you ask, why don't
we ask someone what it's
like to be alone with you.
Oh, wait a minute. That's
right. You killed it. Wow.
Wow. Wow. Dude. You said that at work.
Wow. Okay. Okay. And he basically says,
which shocked half of the people at
work and made the other half crack up
laughing. She called me an
insensitive asshole. Yeah. Okay.
But I could care less. To
me. She was asking for it.
It's not like she was just sitting there
minding her own business and I walked
up and said, what's new fetus
killer? What do you think bill?
Was I out of line or was it a kick ass?
Come back.
Okay. Let me wrap my fucking
head around this. Um,
all right. First of all, it
was an unbelievable come back.
It was a game set and match come back.
You know,
it was literally,
you know,
I dunno, she didn't even
bring a knife to a gunfight.
She was sitting there with a water
pistol and you took out a machete and you
fucking chopped her head off and I dunno,
held it up for everyone to
see and then you swung her,
her fucking head around by the ponytail
and threw it across the offices.
Basically what you did. Um, well
what do you think was I Adeline?
Yeah,
I'm going to have to say yes because
I totally understand why you went there.
Like why you wanted to hurt her back
because what she was saying to you was
fucked up,
but she was fucked up on like level two
and then you went right to the penthouse
level. You know what I mean? I might
even say level two, she was a good,
she was a good a third of the
way up the building. Okay.
I don't know why I'm using a building
as an analogy, but I'm too deep now.
I have to go with this.
But you,
you went right to the penthouse suite and
you kicked her ass right off of it and
you didn't even do it on the side.
You know where they have that,
that canopy thing with a bellman stance.
We're in a three stooges mover.
You'd somehow live,
you kicked her out the backside of the
building right down into the fucking
alley with as a rat waiting to
crawl up into my fucking car. Um,
yeah. What I would, what, I don't
know how old you are, but yeah,
you kind of went,
well you didn't have to go where you,
what you have to do as you get older,
both men and women as psychologically,
you have to realize where they're
coming from and you have to understand,
especially knowing that she had just
had an abortion dude, which is fucking,
is, is, that's brutal for a
guy to go through. You know,
if you have any sort of a conscious,
forget about a woman who's actually
carrying it, you know what I'm saying?
And so the reason why she's saying that
she obviously is having difficulty with
her own relationships and it's so fucking
insecure that to hear someone around
her actually maybe making some sort of
connection and be happy in that area of
her life is fucking with her so much that
it wasn't enough just to say the mean
shit to you.
She starts walking around the office like
trying to get people to like reinforce
her statement and to sort
of cock block you. And, um,
I understand why,
why you did that,
you know, you know, and you
gotta understand why you
went to that level. Okay.
You went literally to that level
that had nothing to do with her.
That adds some shit to do
the baggage you are bringing.
I don't know what house you sound
like you came from a household like my
household where, uh, you know,
somebody makes fun of your
shirt and you're like, yeah,
at least my fucking uncle is in bed.
You know, you know, you just admit,
you immediately go way beyond
what was just said to you. So,
uh, was it out of line?
Definitely. Adeline. Dude,
you shouldn't say shit like that at work.
I don't want you to lose your job,
but you know, I'm not gonna lie
to you. It was fucking hilarious.
And not to mention who to
fall after my rose bowl story.
Who the fuck am I to say anybody was on
the line? I'm thinking, you know what,
I'm and this is like your story.
Know I'm trying to break it down.
How you ended up there is where
I'm at as a human being right now,
I'm still doing the what's
new fetus killer lines.
But I'm trying not to do that. You
know, it's funny on a comedy stage,
but it's,
it's not funny at the Rose Bowl.
All right? But dude, I got,
I gotta give you, you know,
I gotta give you a fucking over the phone
high five on that one. That was just,
wow. Why don't we ask someone who's been
with alone with you? Oh, wait a minute.
That's right.
You killed it.
There's no way people burst out laughing.
That's one of those things.
If you've found it funny,
you made that, you know,
you raise your eyebrows up like
holy shit and you gotta walk away.
You know what I mean?
Somehow there has to be a corner within
10 yards for you to walk around so you
can let that laugh go. God Damn it.
That's, it was brutal. But that was funny.
Come on, women. You've got
to laugh. You've got to know.
That's funny. I know. I know.
It's brutal for, come
on. That was funny. Okay.
Uh, where are we going? Where
are we going? All right,
Milena. Sports questions.
All of a sudden people are really liking
the sports. Okay, another question. Bill.
What happened to our beloved teams? This
is a Boston person. Do the Patriots,
try and keep Matt Cassel
knowing Tom Brady is rehabbing.
His Rehab is slightly behind.
Uh,
do the jets offer back the second round?
They gain from spygate back for the
pets. Oh man, you gone real detail.
I have no idea what's
happened to our beloved.
The patients had an unbelievable season
and what I love about it is everyone was
questioning bill. Bill
Parcell, Bill Parcells,
Bill Belicheck because of
the spy gate thing. And uh,
you know,
look at this year after winning with
the six round pick three Superbowls,
seventh round draft pick, he goes 11
and five and almost once a division,
I think he's proven himself as a fucking
coach. And uh, people always be like, oh,
fucking spygate. But they got nothing.
They don't have an argument. And a,
the reason why I said bill Parcells is
because I really think that that guy is
overrated. You know, I think he's
really good at making a team good,
but he can't get them over the top.
And he throws temper tantrums when he
doesn't get his way. And he totally,
he's like the Larry Brown of football,
you know,
he's only won two super bowls,
86 and [inaudible] 90.
And who was his fucking defensive
coordinator? Bill Belicheck. All right.
He got to the Superbowl
again with the Patriots.
Who was his defensive coordinator?
Bill Belicheck. Right.
You see bill Bellacheck has gone on.
It's won three Superbowls parcels has one,
nothing, one, nothing. He
changed the colors of the team.
He definitely gets a winning tradition
going on there, but he doesn't win.
So I'd rather have Bella check you in
order to realize he's a great coach.
I'm just still pissed that he'd,
he announced that he was leaving our team
a week before we were going to play a
Superbowl for his own selfish reasons.
I really annoyed me. All right.
Question number was even on four.
Okay. For those of you not into sports,
here we go. Here's the non
sports stories. Uh, Bill,
when you do an appearance on a
big show like Letterman or Conan,
what's the protocol for
meeting the other guests?
Does the show hooked that up automatically
or the guests isolated from each
other and the dressing
room and green rooms? Uh,
the reason I ask is NBC just
recently had a replay of your cone,
an episode that you appeared on with
Keira Knightley was the headliner.
I assume one of the perks and doing the
show is getting to check out a famous
chicken person, right? Um, no you don't.
You are on a entirely different
floor than the actual famous people.
You're just the comedian. So I don't
know what it's like to do panel.
I've never done panel.
That's kind of one of my goals here for
2009 maybe I can do pony a panel on one
of the later,
later shows like Carson Daly and I
just have to have something to hype.
Maybe I can do that then I'd love to
do that. But I've only been a comedian.
So basically, you know, you're
on kind of on your own floor.
Um, on Letterman you're aren't, you
have like your own Florida yourself,
which is cool and kind of creepy.
And then on Conan, you're,
when I did call in and you know what,
I def you definitely more,
I don't know where they put the famous
people because I'm not near them.
But I did walk out and after
Chuck Norris did his sketch,
I made sure when he walked by
me, I shook his hand, you know,
thinking like that hand ship Bruce
Lee's hand, you know what I mean?
Or at least blocked his fucking kick or
some shit and whatever movie that was a,
but no, no, you don't get to
meet those people. Some, some
people are cool. You know,
I remember once the first time we did
Conan, Mary Tyler Moore walked by,
looked into my room,
smiled and said hello. Um,
you know, I think a lot of times
people are sitting back there thinking,
what stories am I going to tell you?
Get your head together and you already
have your crew of people, you know,
people who book you and
that type of stuff. And um,
cause personally before I go out and
do my set, like literally, you know,
once the show starts after the first
segment, I kind of send, you know,
all my people out of the room so I can
kind of just basically remember what my
opening joke is. So
they go, all right, um,
question numbers or whatever we're on.
I have these numbered wrong
for some reason, says three,
even though oil and it's like five.
Uh,
I have a question about
your storytelling ability.
When you told the story about
getting the hot dog from pinks,
it was not only hilarious,
but I felt like I was there.
I suck at being able to replay
the funny shit that happens to me,
my family is and friends.
Does your story ability come naturally
or is it something that you've worked on?
How do you put together a good story?
Um,
I'm actually not the greatest storyteller.
I digress a lot and I'm trying to get
to get to the meat of it a lot better.
Um, but yeah, just kind of comes
from telling a lot of stories,
but uh, but don't beat
yourself up man. You know,
there's a lot of people
who can't tell a story,
but it's more like they are the
story, you know what I mean? Like,
um,
I dunno,
I got a good friend of mine who he does
the funniest shit ever and he as you on
the ground, he does shit
offstage. I wouldn't do onstage.
And he has you on the ground laughing,
but he read, tells the story. It.
It doesn't sound like anything funny
happened, but like in the moment,
he's like the funniest guy
ever. Like a, it's weird. Like,
I don't know how I told
that Rosebowl story.
I was just trying not to get
the other dude in trouble,
but the other dude kind of was the story.
Joe was fucking hilarious.
Um, I dunno. And then afterwards I'm,
I'm telling the story. I'm the story guy.
I tell the fucking story, but I'm
not the fucking story. All right.
I'm just a sad little man we
telling shit that I didn't do. Okay.
Question number six.
Um,
all right. Hey, what's the
word? Uh, Oh, you know what?
I got this one totally wrong.
The, I, if someone asked me the other day,
a couple of weeks back about what I
think about the Chicago Blackhawks,
I was only mildly paying attention to
them. I didn't realize how good they were,
the sheer, and I started
watching them. Um,
I think that they're going to go maybe
a couple rounds into the playoffs this
year. And, um, I'll see.
You asked me why the flux or the Bruins
get rid of the Thornton and I, you know,
was saying why, you know, they kind
of blamed our shortcomings on him,
but I forgot that we got,
we got Phil Kessel in that trade.
So we did get something sort of a
trying to correct something there.
All right,
let me try to get to the
rest of these. All right. Uh,
here's the new year's
resolutions. People, I know.
This is getting long new
year's resolutions. Um, I
never, yeah, you know what,
why do I hate my shit? This we can go be
at the Improv and Tampa, go to Improv,
the number two.com for all the information
where you can click right on my
homepage. Please come out to
see me at the Improv in Tampa.
I got a whole new hour is shit.
And um, yeah, come on man.
Can't be just listening to
me for free and my podcast.
I know it's a tough economy,
but for the Christ sake,
come out and fucking support me. All
right, New Year's resolutions. Um,
all right. Fill a lot of people who were
against him. Here's a guy I have. No,
I never understood the logic of new
year's resolutions that's turning 64 other
days a year when one can decide to
do something better for themselves.
Perhaps it's another marketing
scheme for capitalists.
Bloodsuckers I'm hoping that we will make
another hoping that we'll make another
irrational decisions. It's not
really a, it's more of a statement.
I kind of agree with that. Um, I
absolutely hate new years resolutions.
People trick themselves into believing
that the best time to make changes and
start things is at the
beginning of the year.
I don't make New Year's resolutions
because they are an unnecessary.
I start every new year off with what I
refer to as my three golden rules. One,
laugh my ass off.
Every chance I get
to after I have done what I can,
I walk away from those things that
I cannot fix or resolve. And three,
I surround myself with people,
places and things I love most
and support who I am as a person,
Jesus Christ and somebody
who's healthy. Huh? Um,
all right. What are, where we
go in here, where are we going?
Let's wrap this fucking thing up
with a quick overrated, underrated.
And I'm actually going to pitch it because
you guys have been doing such a great
job here. Um, I'm going to say
overrated is the movie 300.
Um, that's, it's just
that it's laugh out loud.
Awful.
The second time you see it,
the first time you see it
visually it's really interesting,
but it's just the stupidest fucking
thing ever. It's the complete meathead,
what it means to be a man. And you
know, the, the, the kid, you know,
it was crying for his mother and they
fucking stick them in a loin cloth out in
the wilderness.
It's snowing out.
He's walking around in his bare feet and
he kills some sort of hybrid wolf slash
alien with a stick. And I'm
supposed to believe that. And,
and you know,
and then they had the fight club moment
where he murders another fucking half
naked,
six year old with this kid who's spout
Taj and they kick them down that fucking
man hole. And that one guy does the,
the beautiful backflip as he goes it,
it's fucking gay. All right. And
they take on an army of 20,000.
You know what I mean?
You know what that movie is.
That's the fantasy every man has after
he pussies out and a bunch of women som
pussy out in like a bar
fight or something like that.
And then when you're driving home and you
start dreaming of the man you wish you
were and how you looked and
fucking, you know, mood lighting,
fuck that movie movie sucks.
It really sucks. Okay.
I think half those apps were painted on
once I saw that Janet Jackson does that,
you know, that you can actually do some
shadowing there on the stomach. Okay.
Um, if somebody is, say some
old rate on rate overrated,
I losing your virginity. Uh, but God,
but God SEC's rules when you
figure it out later in life. Also,
my guitar playing to my friends
is underrated. Uh, Bill Burr,
the funniest men alive and chicken
wings are also under underrated.
The greatest food ever. Chicken
wings are great when you're younger,
but once your stomach is so full of
grease, when you're in the middle ages,
you can't eat them anymore.
So enjoy underrated jerky.
It's a good source of protein, low in
fat and it's tasty. Great snack. Yeah.
But you've got to go to a
truck stop to get it. And uh,
there's always the danger of being raped
there, man or a woman, um, underrated,
uh,
being in familiar enough company to talk
some serious shit and do some serious
ball busting.
There's nothing worse than going out
with some people you kind of know,
but you don't know enough
to know their limits.
So you can't mix it up verbally with
my friends at bars watching a game,
it's great knowing I don't
need to censor myself,
but with my girlfriend in general
quite insists on couples nights,
it feels like I'm eating with my
grandparents. It's all smallest talk,
no substance. And I'm constantly censoring
myself. It's a psychological prison.
Exactly.
I'd have to agree with you on that one.
Totally would have to agree with you that,
uh,
less couple of things.
I think that's basically it.
That's the podcast for this week. I hope
you enjoyed my long ass fucking stories.
Happy new year to everybody.
I hope you guys have a great new year
and I hope you can stick with you new
year's resolutions. Personally,
I've been doing what I always do,
getting myself in shape the first half
of the year before I completely get back
out of shape and nose dive with some
Christmas cookies at the end of the year.
That's what I do. But you know,
bikini season is coming up.
Um, yeah. You know, I did.
I actually bought that P90x thing that
they have late at night and I got to
admit, dude, it's the fucking shit.
Once you get past the guy hosting it,
you know, I don't know if I already
talked about this. He's, he's kind of a,
if you're doing a sketch about a personal
trainer and you imitated this guy,
they think that what you were doing
wasn't realistic. He gives, oh yeah.
P90X you know, talks about how he does
a nice shoes or almost as cool as mine.
Okay, let's drop down
and do some crunches. Um,
but after awhile you get to
see that he's just, you know,
he's just a big insecure guy.
You know,
I think I talked about
this right halfway through.
He admits that his dad through a
couple of no hitters, you know,
and you're like this, the pain. Right. And
you never lived up to him athletically.
Decia now you joined a gym.
At the very least,
you're trying to be in better shape than
your old man cause she just want to hug.
Did that make any sense? It
probably did. That's the podcast.
Thank you for listening.
And um, and uh, that's it.
I don't know how to end it.
I never know how to fucking end it.
Go see me at Tampa. Go see me
in Tampa at the fuck. And uh,
the Improv and Tampa,
cause I'll be in Tampa,
in Florida at Tampa. Okay. And
also be at the Improv and Houston.
And I'm also coming back
Boston, my triumphant return
to Boston, Massachusetts.
And uh, all my dates are up, my website,
[inaudible] dot com and all the
information, all the links, all that shit.
And for those of you who are wondering
what happened to my date at the Trump Taj
Mahal, the Atlantic city, whatever
the fuck I was going to be, um,
I'm going to get a date up there. We had
to reschedule it. Alright. That is it.
God bless all. Yes. And uh,
fucking don't go to the automated
lines at grocery stores. All right.
Ooh.