Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and ah,
Ooh, ee, just checking in. All
mother bugging you, Lou. Um,
uh, what's going on? I'm in the middle
of this, this acting job. Ovi He,
so I got to do this before they
picked me up in the sad van.
The Sad van that takes you to set
for the excitement. That's the rules.
If you're going to have that much fun
pretending to be somebody else, right?
Winning bar fights and all the
shit you get to do as an actor,
all the shit you can't do in real life.
Um,
then yeah,
they got to pick you up in a sad van.
The van is basically a bare bones,
usually all white with the gray
violin to just completely like,
you know, four wheels powertrain.
This will get you there.
I call it the said Finn.
I don't know why. Um, but that
is the one thing about it.
Great thing about acting is you get to
do all this shit that you don't get to do
in real life.
You know,
which is what's kind of cracking me
up lately about action movies is how,
um, I don't know when exactly the
action hero genre started, but I,
I came up in the eighties, so
you know, you had Stallone, Yay.
Add Schwartzenegger you had John
Claude van and then you had,
um, Steven Seagal in each
year. They try to, you know,
Chuck Norris in each year.
They just tried to fucking,
Chuck Norris actually walked the line from
like action hero in Karate Guy, right?
He was somewhere between
like Bruce Lee and,
and uh, I don't know what, it's
a fucking chuck Norris, I guess.
Sorry, my brain is fried. We've been
walking at work and long hours here. Um,
but anyways, those movies kind of
already started off ridiculous. You know,
we'd have 40 guys with machine
guns and a guy would just fucking,
there's one movie where I
think it's Schwartzenegger,
there's like 20 guys with machine guns
shooting at them and there's all these
potted plants and he just runs and
kind of puts his hand up, you know,
to guard his face from all
the, uh, thousands of bullets
that are coming at them.
And somehow they miss him.
He runs across this fucking foyer.
I mean,
they just kept getting more
and more ridiculous, you know,
all the way up to like a
Steven Seagal. Well, he would,
she would barely be moving and just
beat the shit out of an entire bar.
I love when they would throw a punch at
his face and he would just sort of lean
and just actually watch the
fiscal passed his face. Um,
so now just when you think that, you know,
and the dialogue was always really bad.
So then what they did, you know what? No,
they all went away because
they just got so ridiculous.
They kind of just start making action
movies for a long fucking time.
I think they did anyways.
Um,
I guess the born identities and
those were action movies, whatever.
All I know is that now they
got the lady starring in a,
and m for some reason,
like I think just because people were
so educated to how fucking stupid they
were, they actually finally decided to
start writing decent dialogue, you know,
as opposed to all this shit.
They gave a Stallone to be a go
for a ride or what's his face?
Schwartzenegger would rip off a steam
pipe and throw it through someone's chest
and then be like, let off some steam.
I mean, it was literally that bad.
Don't wake my friend, he's
dead tired, this really bad.
Um, then they started actually
writing scripts and a, I guess, yeah,
I'd like the Bourne identity.
And then you had the, uh,
the other guy lock stock and for fucking,
who's a wants this.
And so now they've got the ladies are
doing them and they're actually writing
good scripts.
But you know,
it is kind of funny to watch a woman
like beating the shit out of two fucking
400 pound guys. I mean, doesn't it
get to the point where it's like,
I don't give a fuck how much karate,
you know, like I could just sit on you.
Cause that's the latest one.
The latest ones like atomic blonde and uh,
they just got off take out of,
pick smaller guys because it immediately
takes me out of the movie like cheese,
what the fuck's come on.
Really. You know what I mean?
It's bad ass.
As those women are in the UFC,
they still fight other
women because you know,
and there's still weight classes
because at the end of the day,
if you're tall enough and your fat enough,
you can eat a lot of those punches.
Then you just, you just
smother him. Remember that?
Like when you're old brother,
your older brother would sit on your
chest and you be getting claustrophobic Ma
like that. They could just do that to
you and they would, they would win the,
I gotta keep my voicemail. Um, yeah, they
would just win the fucking fight. So, um,
I'm not trying to be a party pooper here.
I'm going to go see atomic blonde,
but it is getting to, it's a
common, you know what it is.
It's a combination of those kinds of
movies and then all those feminists tee
shirts that I saw this week, that's
really starting to fucking annoy me.
It's like,
do they think they're dumb enough that
they're going to get into my fucking head
with this shit? You know, I told you
guys about that t shirt. I saw it, right?
This woman was walking around with
this t shirt. It said, um, uh,
what is it said a,
a a little boy.
I got a strong woman's scares a
little boy, but excites a man.
Like what kind of guy would fall for
that page one horseshit psychology.
Like I'm going to be, or I want to be,
I want to be considered a strong band.
It's like,
Hey lady,
how about you say something
fucking impressive that I
already talked about this
already on Monday. I can't
remember. Anyways. Yeah.
So why don't you fucking say
something impressive, you know,
instead of having your tee
shirt and warm up the crowd.
MMM.
I can't remember if I told
you guys this already,
but I wanted to make a t shirt that says
a real woman isn't afraid to make her
man a sandwich every once in
a while just to get the looks.
See that right there, ladies. That's
exactly what we're talking about.
What are you smiling about?
Nia. You liked that one
in the same ole song again? Huh?
He's in the same as long. Yeah.
My singing.
What's same old song again?
Yes.
What is my same old song?
Nia,
you're saying, well, Song
you say move women do is have in savings
and never feeling he's still singing
that same old. No, I don't know.
That's what I'm saying. Old Man.
That's not what I'm saying.
Prehistoric cave man.
Have you evolved at all in the time we've
been together or are you just singing
the same old song? Oh, if you'd let me
finish, I heard everything that you said.
All right. I heard you.
So drastic tee shirt.
Isn't a tee shirt a little ridiculous. I
mean, if I had the male version of like,
you know, a real woman would blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, a little,
your take on it is actually very funny,
but it's still,
what were you talking about? You
were talking about how, oh the,
the women in the action films
like beating up like big guys,
but you're willing to suspend your
disbelief that vin diesel can drive a car
through. Not One but two or three
buildings. In fact. No worries. No,
I'm not going to be fine. No,
I'm not. And be like, Whoa,
that was quite a ride or whatever it
is that he said. No, it's stupid. No,
it's absolutely stupid.
They drive from one building
to another fish tail before.
Now it's completely stupid. I
don't want shows movies. Right.
So I'm just saying it
was all action films.
You got to suspend your
disbelief a little bit.
Daniel Craig can't beat up
like 20 guys at one time. No.
Been to the movie he does.
No.
Yeah, but here's the
thing. What they did was,
what they did was they'd stay started
in the 80s and it was immediately
ridiculous.
And the dialogue was horrific.
So then what they did was they started
to may have better dialogue and they
actually have the guys get hurt
a little bit with like, you know,
fucking Bruce Willis had his bloody foot
on the glass and his wife beater just
kept getting dirty or dirty or,
so they tried to make them real.
But I'm just saying when I was
watching that atomic blood,
she's like beating the shit out of
these two guys to like 260 pounds each.
So skies. Yeah. Once they get their
paws on you, I don't give a f if you,
if somebody outweighs you by a hundred
pounds, once they get the hands on,
he is fucking over when
there's two of them,
but it's a movie, so we go
with it. Right. I know, but
it just gets too, there is a certain
level, like me, there's a bunch of them.
Like I never used to watch the Bourne
identity just because the way they would
edit it, I went to one of them, I swear
to God on which set of seizure. Yeah.
The editing was like, uh, uh,
that was that, that one that uh,
woody Harrelson did. Uh, the murderers
of the boyfriend, girlfriend, murderers,
natural born killers. Yeah. The way that
was edited, it just, it was just like,
you know, this is fucking,
I can't, I can't watch this.
Right. The quick cuts. Yeah,
but that's what you're talking about.
You so bombarded with images.
I get it slowly edits down please.
Right? Yeah. There was one,
Matt Damon was like fighting a guy inside
a bathroom and like his elbow would go
back. They follow that it through the
wall and then back to the guy's head.
It's like Jesus fucking Christ. You know,
if these NFL running backs are like,
can't even move until Tuesday.
The level of fighting that this guy
would do on just like every six hours.
Oh my God. Wait, did you see that video?
Speaking of NFL running backs of the ex
NFL player who ran through that plate
glass, that glass door and his wife
thinks he's suffering from some, like,
you know, post traumatic stress in
his brain, it's called something CTE.
Did you see that video? He know,
but I'm trying not to laugh.
He of literary sprints through a glass
or when he doesn't remember doing it.
Don't love it.
It is definitely sad,
but that is fucking hilarious that he's
just like walking into a dental office
and all of a sudden he just,
he is 60 49 boots. Blue,
sad. I'm just fucking,
how can run through it?
No, that should there it's
ruining their brains. Like,
isn't that like what are they going to do?
What are they going to do with,
did he spike his wallet after
he went through the window?
No, because it fell down after
he crashed through the glass.
As long as he just walked in with his
wife and all of a sudden he just fucking
mid conversation.
He was talking to police or
something about something.
Maybe he was having some sort of episode
and then he just took off and he ran
right through this. Like Glassdoor. I got
a grocery store. Is he black or white?
Black.
All right. He's talking to the cops. Yeah.
There's probably some shit from his
childhood. You can't blame the NFL.
I thought the cops don't
treat you guys well.
He ran,
he ran through a glass door and
he doesn't remember doing it.
So his wife was like, I
think he's got, you know,
his brain is all fucked
up from playing football.
So where are they going to do about that?
Can they put more padding
in the helmet or like how,
no, cause what happened, what it
is is your brain sits and fluid.
So it's going to take some fucking like
crazy brainiac to have like something
that somehow keeps your brain stationary.
The helmet fucking moves,
but your head doesn't see,
your brain doesn't smash
against it. I mean, personally,
if I was Oj Simpson's lawyer back
in 1994 that's what I would've said.
I would've said, oh, Jay suffers from CTE.
He had been watching the cooking channel
or this Ginsu knife commercial and he
just got a little confused. Right. Well,
whatever you would of Ron Goldman looked
like Vince Ferragamo and he never liked
the ramps. I mean, that's the best I
could've come up with. Sure, sure. Well,
it's a comedy podcast. If
he brings something up, what
am I supposed to do? No,
I'm laughing on the inside.
It's an inner cry Bitch.
Yeah. Did you see that?
You want to see, okay,
now if we're going to just talk about
horrible fucking things, did you see that,
that fear,
that carnival out there and I'm
in Ohio with somebody one on one,
like one of those tilt a world rides in
the fucking thing snapped and all these
poor people went flying through the year.
One person died.
This little girl was laying on the ground.
It's one of the most horrific
things I've ever seen.
And then like investigators are looking
in to see what the problem is. It's like,
you know what the fucking problem is? They
don't maintain those things. I used to,
uh, I used to go to that a, I don't
want to, I don't get in trouble here.
Uh,
it rhymes with seven
and a homophobic slur.
No,
no.
I should say I'm going to do one,
six homophobic slurs
a lot. You don't know that one. You
used to go to a what? Where you weigh,
what is it? What is a was
the country wave. Yeah.
Oh yes, yes. So I went there and
so I went there,
seven banners,
banners for seven brothers.
Why can't you say where it was you
think they're going to like not want to?
I mean it happened.
I was at the one that rhymes with a
ring wield massive two sets and um,
I got, uh, I was, I was on
the roller coaster right.
And we got off it and the time it took
us to stand in line and the ride next to
us, we lined up, you know, line
moved twice. We just heard Bam.
And the rollercoaster that was ending
the ride did not stop and rear ended the
ride in front of it.
And this woman broke her cheekbone.
Do you remember the time we went to
that other one that rhymes with the six
homophobic slurs out in
a new war Z and we were,
we were in that, that superman
roller coaster and we, we got like,
we were waiting to get off it and then
it would move and then we was stuck in
those. Yeah, it was really horrific.
How many minutes? 30 minutes. No,
it wasn't 30 he was probably like four
minutes. Five minutes, 30 minutes.
It might've been like 10 but I was
sitting there and I felt you starting to
freak out and I was like,
well,
if I wanted to I could wiggle my way out
of this and the second I couldn't move.
All of a sudden I started feeling
shortness of breath and I was like,
hold it together.
Bill holds it together.
I believe we actually went to that place.
I assume that was my idea.
I don't think you would ever suggest
going to a theme park as a date.
It didn't you weren't you?
The one that taught me that macaroni and
cheese is not a main dish. Yes, I was.
I'm, I'm this weird
combination of, you know,
professional white collars in white trash.
Oh yeah.
We weren't good with money. That was
a period we were not good at money,
so we used to have a tray and
macaroni cheese with toast. Yeah,
that's fun. Male. That's fucking
delicious. The craft frozen.
You just throw it in there. God, how
dare you. White people go the anime,
macaroni and cheese. It's
pasta. It's from Italians,
so you can only take 50% of the credit.
Italians would be offended that
you use Kraft macaroni and cheese.
Wait a minute at do they
make macaroni and cheese?
That's not their thing yet is macaroni
and cheese. That's one of the,
you meet an Italian.
That's one of the first things
that they say when they meet him.
Now he wants a go wrong.
Maybe it's big ship,
but beef on toast.
Now remember when you get Alec King?
I made fun of me because
I was like making a jet.
We went out to dinner the other night and
I was sort of like lovingly doing this
kind of like know your worth and now it
was because, because we were in, okay.
First of all, when I'm on my podcast
and I'm just being silly now,
if you did what you did in little
Italy the other night in the,
in this apartment, I would have
laughed. We were sitting there, right?
I took near to where we
got this restaurant. When
I first met my lovely wife,
I took her to like 10 years ago. Right.
So I'm trying like all day going, yeah.
Saying let's whatever it saint, let's
fucking go there. She's like, Ooh,
I want to go to the stone
cold creamery and fucking uh,
what's that other stupid burger place that
everybody eats? Like it's crack. What?
Shake shack. Shake shack. Like this day
I want to go to shake shack over this.
Anyway, whatever. Just tell the story.
We'd go and she wanted to go to some
shiny place and I wanted to go to the
fucking old school home style. You know,
you order like chicken parm is Sean.
It's like, is that it does that,
uh, how long did you hammer this?
That this is only one chicken breast.
This is like nine chicken breasts.
And then you fucking plow your way
through it. You wish you didn't need it,
but it was delicious. So we go there and
they're playing all this Italian music,
right? They got Dana on
where the moon hits your eye,
like a big pizza applied
at so more the Nia does,
you know that thing that you
know in Hollywood movies,
one of the Italian like something when
he puts his thumb between his index and
his middle finger brings them
together with both hands,
like going back and forth, back and
forth like that. So good a pizza sauce.
So the songs on and Nia starts doing that
at the table, sticking her bottom lip.
Other key,
you'll book a little book,
but like in a fun wags and bouncing
lot of the music they were playing.
I had to do that, Dah, Dah, Dah,
Dah. And I was like, you know,
I was just doing the whole,
and I said,
what if we were up in Harlem and
some soulful restaurant? Okay.
And they started playing some fucking
RB or whatever the fuck you guys are
listening to.
And I started to doing a bad version of
some break dance and shit sticking my
bottom lip out.
You'd be like,
if you don't stop fucking doing that and
you're sitting there with a white man,
Nia Huh? What do you think when you think
would happen? I was saying just show,
hey,
it was out of respect.
You though was culturally insensitive
of me to do that. I didn't give a shit.
I thought it was funny,
but I didn't need the waiters.
We still hadn't gotten all of our foods
so I didn't need you fucking with our
food less.
Then they had the whole rack of glasses
and stuff like right by the window.
Like right behind me. We
were sitting, I mean come on.
Can I ask you a question if I took you
to Chinatown was delicious though by the
way. Delicious. Delish delish
now if I took it again,
delete if I took you to Chinatown.
Okay.
And they were playing the, you
know what it did that, that, that,
that that day we went in because
apparently that's offensive. Okay.
We started playing high. Yo, Yo, Yo,
Yo, Yo, Yo, Yo know if you were a,
if they started playing some company,
was Kung Fu fighting, would you,
what would you, what would you
be doing? I go start doing,
everybody was calm and it will
be offensive be yeah, right.
I mean, I don't know. I
wasn't, I really wasn't not,
I'm not trying to be
political correct guy.
I'm just trying to get people
not to spit in my food.
That's all I'm trying to do it.
It wasn't like talking to the waiter like
a by then bring me some fucking Vinnie
Gabon. Ooh. Like I was trying to that
shit. Like I was on the fucking Sopranos.
I wasn't doing that. All right.
I mean, your, your point is made.
My point is not about
being culturally sensitive.
It's about Kevin people not
fuck with your food. Okay.
You want to do that on your own,
your own time.
You want to go on and get a Bagel
and be like, oh, a VA with a lady,
you're going to get an everything
Bagel like you never had before,
if you know what I mean.
There. I mean everything.
Is that a Matzoh ball there?
Um,
anyways, uh, you got
to wrap this up, right?
I don't have to wrap it up cause I don't,
I like that.
I've only been doing 20 minutes.
Oh,
I got to read some are I got to read some,
uh,
advertising advertising some time,
but I know I'm not supposed to
because why aren't you supposed to?
Because they want you
to read the advertise.
No one's no one's paying for me to read
it. They want you to read it. Yeah.
Everybody knows that. Why don't
you have to bring that up? I know,
but I'm just saying I want
some weird woman thing trying
to mind. Fuck me to get,
yes, that's it. You to put
it on a tee shirt. Yep.
[inaudible] Yup.
It's a great one. That chief, hold on me.
The other night we were laying in bed
and all the lights were out and we both
tired and there's a lamp like across
the room sitting there. She's like,
how do you turn that lamp off?
And I'm like,
I dunno Nia. You get up, you
walk over and you turn it off.
I'll show you. How dumb do you think
I am? I am dumb. I'm not that dumb
paint here. Go take some karate classes
and beat up all my tall friends.
I want to see that. The
Black Tux, everybody.
Um, see you see this, and again, this
is another progression for your people.
What are you talking about?
He used to just back in the day,
he's just be the white Tux. No,
no. This isn't one of those things.
Let's see how you can get through
this. This the reed. Okay.
Nice and slow so you don't mess up.
You can make fun of me all you want,
but you married me.
You've hitched your wagon to this
wasn't listening to what you listen to,
what you hitched your wagon
to the Black Tux. You know,
there's only so many opportunities
in life to wear a Tuxedo at Saks,
at tux.
So when your big day or special event
rolls around or you'd have to go to court,
you've got to go to court. That's a good
move. Show up in a Tuxedo you were on.
It may approach the
bench with my cumber Bun.
So when your big day or special
event rolls around this summer, look,
just as great as you feel
with suits from the black Tux.
Dotcom with high quality rental suits and
Tuxedos delivered to your doorsteps of
delivered to your doorstep. Sorry.
That was all in capital letters.
The Black Tux gives you a new way to rent.
Okay.
Why do you keep putting
the emphasis on the, Oh,
cause I always watched football and
they go the Ohio State University. Okay.
All only the capital letter once and I'll
yell at the capital level noise, right?
Plus what? They're Craig home. Try on's.
You get to saying the fit and feel the
quality of your suits months before your
event and the best part is
it's completely done online.
What fucking coke had wrote this
shit. Now this is the best word. No,
that's the best word. All right. The
Black Tux stock. The Black tux.com
lets you create your look or choose
from tons of stylistics stylist,
stylist selected outfits. Do this really
only like three days. It's the black one,
the white one and the
gray one suits like these.
Usually retail for $1,200 really?
But at the black Tux they start
at just $95. Why does this itch?
If you have any questions or issues,
their expert customer care team as
your back every step of the way,
no pun intended.
After ordering your suit,
after ordering your suit will
arrive 14 days before your event.
If anything is less than perfect,
the black Tux will send you a
free replacement right away. Uh,
when your event's over,
just drop your rental back in the mail.
Jesus in the mail,
you're gonna fold it.
How many times you full debt to
get in that through a little slump,
people is going to stop it.
Then
send it back and or walking intention.
The smelly socks. All wadded up.
Chicken Marsala stains
all over dose. What else,
Amy? I guess what?
Shipping is free both ways.
How easy is that stand out at your event
for the right reasons with the black
Tux call to action to get
$20 off your purchase,
visit the black tux.com/bar.
That's the black Tux dotcom slash
bar for $20 off your purchase.
All right, legal zoom, everybody. Okay,
come on in. Zoom, zoom, zoom.
A zoom. Do remember that's
shown ya come on. And Zuma.
Zuma, Zuma zone, kid show
comma, gave it a try.
We're gonna show you just why
we're gonna teach you to fly. Hi,
come on in. Zoom, come on. And legal zoom.
All right,
legal zoom sometimes how my time is here,
that means it's time for family vacations,
sunscreen and we'll have a qs.
Uh, but the most important thing to do
this summer is prepare for your family's
future with an estate plan
from legal zoom. Exactly.
But if the Hibachi blows
up in your face there,
and next thing you know somebody
doesn't have a flatter, sorry,
national make a will month is right
around the corner and that's the perfect
time to make sure you're prepared
for the future. How do you,
who do you have to pay off to
have them must be about you.
You know when they're like,
today is national pancake day.
Somebody lobbies for that. And how
relieved of those senators, you know,
usually there's some sort of pill.
It's literally going to fucking kill
children in some godforsaken place.
This is this next bill's about pancakes.
And for once people with red ties and
blue ties can all get along because who
doesn't like pancakes? Um, it helps
to know what your options are.
Legal Zoom, zoom, zoom, a
zoom that is not a law firm,
but their network of independent attorneys
available in 50 states can work with
you to make sure you're
getting the right estate plan,
whether that includes a
will or living trust. Uh,
they'll provide specific advice to,
to address the needs of your family.
Plus during national make a
will month, month, Mug, Mug,
legal zoom, zoom, zoom miles,
little pulling, a bunch zooms,
pulling a bunch of helpful resources
together all in one place to make it a
little easier to ensure your family and
assets are protected. Call to action.
Keep listening.
We'll have more information in
August and to find out more now,
check out legal zoom.com for special
offers that are coming your way.
If you're a fan,
if you have a family,
whether you're still with them or you
abandoned them or you own anything you
care about, you won't want to miss
out. In the meantime, save more money.
Wait, save more by entering
bar at checkout at legal,
zoom.com legal zoom.com. All right,
mercifully we're through that.
How about the Red Sox? They finally
want to have to drop in four in a row.
They lost the last two.
The angels,
they lost the first two to Seattle before
they finally beat the fucking Bareness
and the Yankees starting to surge the
only end game and a half out, you know,
which is crazy because there's
only like 50 games left.
Uh, how much time have I done here? I
got to get going. Cause this sad van.
Yeah. You familiar with the sad
van that takes you to the set?
You know it's even past.
Yeah, the 15 passenger. Yeah.
All White Gray, vinyl. You
know what about it? I know,
I always find it depressing. Why? I always
liked, I always liked the union guy.
That set. Yeah, I know.
But they could, you know,
could they couldn't get like the fucking,
the cloth seats,
everything. She's, you could literally,
you could beat the shit out of the inside
of the, of everything. Plastic. Yeah.
Excited to go to your sex and
the city remake goods. You Doing?
Yeah, I'm playing, but it's
an all male version. No,
I'm playing Cynthia Nixon and she
trends she got, she's transgender.
She always, she always
related male. And uh,
so somewhere during the best
actress on this, you know,
it's great if you transition
from, oh no, wait a second.
If you transitioned from woman
to a man, yes. All right.
Can you go ball dead?
Maybe like if they start giving
you a male hormones, I don't know.
If you get the good hormones, can you be
like, listen, I want the fucking who's,
who's got the great full head of hair,
who's got the Kennedys always had
great heads of hair, right? Yeah.
Like he'd get the Kennedy Cheat Hormone.
Can they do that yet? That's not an
marina I'm willing to step into. I'm not,
I'm not willing to step into
that conversation cause I don't,
I don't know anything about why because
I'm not saying they can't join the coast
guard. Well, Trump did. I know.
That's what I'm saying. The joke.
Okay, sorry. Um, isn't that
a good thing though? No.
Who the fuck cares? I wish
she banned redhead. Some going
to war. I'd be like, Whoa,
my man. Both of you again. Hey,
could you vote for me now that I don't
have to pay taxes, how about that?
Oh good.
I don't have to go down to
some godforsaken bootcamp
and get screamed at by some
fucking guy whose mom never hugged
him. I get it. Where I'm from,
livestock into homosexuals are
from, I understand sir. Wow.
Look at all the extra stripes you
have on your shirt versus mine.
Why in God's name would
I want to go do that
to get a free pair of 10 bullets?
I would definitely be that guy.
If I was in the military,
who at the end of my hitch,
whatever the terminology would be,
I would definitely be the guy
who takes apart his weapon in,
starts to mail it home,
bolt by bolt.
That's why I didn't join.
I would do some dumb shit like that.
I try to figure out how to take apart
a grenade so I could be the hit at the,
at the 4th of July party. Um, alright,
what do we got here at 29 minutes
and 54 seconds. All right.
I'm contractually obligated to do
30 seconds. I mean 30 minutes. Um,
so, all right. Whose contract?
I have a contract with the people
and the people's King. Yes.
I have a people's contract.
I told them back in 2007 that I was
going to make podcasting great again.
Hey, I want you to think about how much
money you think Obama's make it tonight.
What's he gonna say? Oh
Dude, he's got his keys.
Got a tour that's bigger than Kevin
Hart. Actually, I don't think he is.
I think Kevin's still make it more, he
has a $69 million toward, he's still
giving Rah Rah speeches to corporations,
you know,
thousand points of light.
He's getting his bribe money near him.
And what's his wife's name? Penelope.
How'd the area, her name is Michelle.
Michelle. I know she tweeted so much.
I should have known what
her name was. Don't ever
disrespect Michelle Obama. Yeah.
Why do they try to act like the wife of
the guy who was actually doing the job?
And so God damn important.
No, I don't understand that.
All around the world. Same. So,
Huh? Who's Martha
Steward? Dayton. I Dunno.
What the fuck he does was nice to have
you heard Stedman say something on
Twitter, Huh? I'm
telling you those ladies,
they got their bitches in line.
I'm just fucking around. Hey Nia, do you
want to make fun of my hat before we go?
Oh my God. Okay, so let me do that. Let me
get, no, no, I'm going to go back story.
Bill fucking bought
a Sassy Midwestern mom,
New York tourist hat,
and it's the most ridiculously I.
Can I please take a picture
of you in it and tweet it?
Yes. This is what happened. Um,
as bald as Charlie Brown, actually, he
says at one curly cute thing and, uh,
the sun was out tomorrow,
the sun was out and I just,
it was just fucking a Hot New York
day and I didn't have my hat because I
fucking worked out with my Nike
hat and I needed one because, uh,
I actually used to think you have,
I'm so pacing.
If I got a little bit of Sun that
would be good. But it's bad. Yes,
it's bad cause you come in and yeah,
I come in red and they're like,
what the fuck do we do with this?
Uh,
so I had to put a hat on so I didn't
fuck up my Cynthia Nixon acts acting gig
here. And uh, so you know,
all they have this time of year is they
just have all these New York City had
some down in the village.
So I was in a bind and they didn't
have a mirror and I bought it.
And it's like literally, you know
those, you know those shirts. Jay Leno,
where's with the gene?
Gene gets like, yeah,
it denim, it's a denim hat. It's in
a mat. Oh, New York City hat. It,
it's the kind of had that a white
Midwestern mom would wear. Be like, Ooh,
I gotta I gotta I got a hat from, from
New York City, let kids, I got a hat,
like a baseball hat. Like you guys have.
Like, that's exactly what this is. That is
the woman on set was making fun of it. I
said, how awful it was this. And she goes,
it's pretty awful. I go look at this
cool t shirt. My wife bought me.
I go and I just ruined it with his hat.
And she goes pretty much like she was
giving me no day. Like she wasn't,
there was no out. Nothing. All right,
well I'll through the MLM podcast will
tweet out a picture of my awful hat.
Um, all right, fuck hoes
enjoy the music. Uh,
transitioning into a,
some,
an extra 30 minutes here of a greatest
hits from a Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday. Monday
morning podcasts from a
Thursday afternoon. That one
bye but is no longer here,
but they'll never be forgotten.
Fun
to give it a nine.
The Shah
Ooze Harley started carefully from
becoming something that then
stay.
Hey, you know what people wanted me
to talk about Jay z and salon. Oh,
the elevator fight. Uh, whatever the
hell are fucking name. That's her name.
I'm sick of Jay z wearing that.
Roger Moore Tuxedo. We get it.
You're fucking cool enough already. It's
Tom Ford. Oh, is that what that is? Yeah.
I don't fucking know. I always forget
at this point. Jay Z so famous.
You forget he's from Brooklyn and he
fucking grew up in a street corner.
It can still beat the shit out of you.
You know, although him with his shirt off,
you know, I dunno. He's definitely
a businessman either. Yeah,
exactly.
He's fine dining.
He's eating like steak and wine and
like what songs? He is not keen.
90 exits. I can tell you this doesn't
need to do all. He's got the gift of Gab.
He doesn't need to do all it doesn't,
it doesn't. You know what, I've,
I've had enough arguments that people,
God bless him and his Roger Moore Tuxedo.
Did you talk the elevator fight?
Have you cut? I'll talk about it.
Oh, I'll talk about
it. Write down all day.
I thought Jay Z,
regardless of whatever the fuck he said
that set her off showed unbelievable
restraint. Okay. Getting kicked
by a woman in high heels.
Shoes. I've been there. Okay.
That five fucking hurts.
And he kept taking it to the hands
and there was a moment at one,
I only watched it once. There was a time,
like one of the last times she hit him,
she even flinched cause she was like,
yeah,
at this point he decided deserve to get
punched in the face. You see her flinch,
she's spit at him. That was
what, it was really awful.
That's what I forgot to do
to that driver this morning.
That would have been clowning bitch,
move. I never do that. No, no, no.
But you know, their family has
problems like anybody else's family.
I feel like if anything,
it just, you know,
it just goes to show you
that you shouldn't feel bad
when you know your uncles
or whatever, start screaming at
each other over thanksgiving.
That is funny though,
when you really think about how
many people are tour judging them.
Actually there's footage that exists
somewhere of their family fighting in an
elevator. It's just they're
not famous and nobody cares.
It just gets taped over.
I feel like a lot of,
there are a lot more like physical
fights that happen in families between
siblings and stuff that most people
wouldn't want to admit. You know? So I, I,
I really don't think it's that big of a
deal. I was watching it like salons stop.
No, he definitely said something fucked
up because Beyonce did do anything. She,
she was, she was standing at with
her sister. She was probably like,
well that's what happens when you
say x, Y, and z. That was her vibe.
Uh, yeah. So, but I, it's not that big
of a deal. I don't feel like, you know.
No, that's kind of a big no, that's
a tough, that's that's it's over.
Their relationship is fucking
over and if money wasn't involved,
whose relationship? Jay Z's
and the fucking large, yeah,
those side kick there. She's
not, yeah, she is. Come on.
She's frank. Frank Stallone. No, no.
She has a really good album and I love
her music and she has great style. No,
she thought was famous as Beyonce
obviously and all these dumb ass Internet
people on Twitter like I've never
even heard of her until knows.
You should be thankful she got
any classes. This is my theory.
Don't know music beyond what's on
your top 40 radio station. Hey,
play in the morning while
you're going to work.
Doesn't mean that this
person isn't talented. No,
I just get annoyed with that is
first of vegans down the music level.
This is the deal.
The only way she can make it as if she's
in the same group is Beyonce because
that's the way it fucking works.
There's no way.
Never in the history of two people in
the same family trying to be as solo
artists. Have they ever
made it? They always,
you gotta beat together the
Everly brothers, the Jackson five,
the Osmonds.
And then what happens is somebody breaks
out of it and then the rest of them go
back to the dinner table going, I have an
album out to whenever. He's like, yeah,
we don't care. I know I'm
your mother. I don't care.
Michael is special.
Donny and Marie are the best.
They're younger than you. They're shooter
than you. And Jesus likes them better.
And that's what happens and you're fucked.
So the only move she had was
when Beyonce was on the way up.
She should have been a Destiny's child.
Look at me,
look at me on the other side of the
fence. Just calling off groups here. Well,
she was, well, she in
that group, she was like,
I thought it was Kim Coles and a
that chick from, uh, from uh, uh,
one of the roller skates.
Tootie, wasn't she? That
it is his name and black
people now? Yeah. Um, no,
she was like a backup dancer. She went
on tour with them when she was younger.
She had an album when she was younger.
She got pregnant.
She moved up to like I was
Oklahoma as a backup dancer.
I was remember that Ac DC,
that ACDC video.
Who made who when I had all the Angus is
up there. I always was one of the Angus.
She also, she also, I didn't really
people I didn't know. I wish I did. Hey,
she also wrote quite a few of Beyonce
songs and like call wrote some of destiny
tryouts on too, so you know she's, she's
got other talents, things you know,
she doesn't need to be as famous
like that chick and I say,
hey,
when did Barry no,
that's what's going on. Her
name is Linda. No it isn't.
It is it called Jessica?
It's not, you know I'm right.
I don't know what her name is.
Four non blondes lead singer Linda Perry
recently married to Sarah Gilbert from
Roseanne. Did you know that you
could play Darlene? They're,
they're married. The last
time I saw her, Linda Perry,
not the last time like I see her,
but I saw her blonde chick.
Isn't she like fuck,
she's got to be my age probably.
What's she going around with that little
girl for? What are you talking about?
Sarah Gilbert is older than I am.
I saw the show the other day.
She's like 12th that's
cause she looks great.
Like I was watching the fucking TV show
bombing all over the place.
Ooh.
Yeah.
Wow.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr
and it is the Monday morning podcast.
Monday,
July 27th,
two south 2009 2000 2009 and uh,
uh, the year of the current on, if
I can never remember what year it
is and the Chinese knew it's the,
is it the year of the pig? I think
it is the year of the pig, isn't it?
I saw a thing the other night where you
know that those shows where they have
people,
they flip houses,
they buy some dilapidated hunk of ship
from some old lady who just died when she
fucking passed out face first and her
fucking dog food because it got damn
bankers killed a formal referral. One
K. Right. Do All people have 401ks?
Did they have that back in the day when
they went by in war bonds. I'm like,
dog sleeping over there. Look
at her. Fucking adorable. Um,
anyways, um, yeah, I was watching
this thing. We know what they flipped.
I hate those shows where they
flip the houses because uh,
you just see people getting
completely fucked over.
You get a couple of shitheads,
they don't even know what they're doing.
And then they go in there and they,
uh, they go to Grossman's or, uh,
what's some awful hardware store?
Home Depot.
They go down there and they buy a bunch
of cheap tiles and then everybody walks
in like, oh my God, it's beautiful.
Look, look at the tile work.
And it was like done by this fucking
accountant. You know, I hate to,
they know this old house. Like it's,
that guy gave a shit about the house.
Now they'd say they should just, they
just showing people getting fucked over.
I can't stand that when people walk in
and then they think that the place looks
amazing because they changed the brown
paint to read and that opens the room up
or whatever.
Fucking mind trick they used and it's
still the exact same piece of shit house.
And these guys sell it to these fucking
morons for an extra 40 grand when all
they had to do was buy a bucket of paint.
You know?
You know what that reminds me of?
I hate those commercials now where they're
trying to make it seem like fast food
is at the level of a five star restaurant
and they get these white trash fucking
idiots, and they just see a
tablecloth and some cloth napkin.
And then they bring in some pizza
hut and they're eating their pasta.
Have you seen that commercial?
And that girl was like, oh
my God, it's so decadent.
Who the fuck uses that word when
they're talking about pasta?
It's decorated. You know? It's like,
did you just want to use that word?
You dumb fuck. And then they come
in and they're like, oh, it's pizza.
It's pizza. Oh my God. Again, I believe
that I eat dead. She and every week,
you know, always tasted like shit, but now
these fucking cloth napkins. Oh my God,
he's so fucking jaggedy. And they're
breeding and they're breathing.
They're not using condoms and
they're eating pasta. I mean, how,
you know, the, and I like how, um,
all these other fucking fast food
places are acting like they into,
they invented these mini burgers.
You know what I mean?
Like white castle doesn't exist.
I'm really waiting for white castle to
sue a jack in the box or write any one of
these other places. These, these guys
who come up and they call him sliders.
And evidently it's,
it's not as fattening because
rather than eating one burger,
they take a burger and they
cut it into three little ones.
But because of their little,
even though you're eating the exact
same amount of fucking Burger, you know,
somehow it's, it's, it's less
fattening. I Dunno. Yeah. I mean,
it's so much what I just said is, you
know, obviously just not even research,
but you know, I, I, you
know, I just eat, I,
that fucking lady using the word
decadent just really annoys me.
You know what annoys me even more?
I can't even give you a fuck a definition
for it. What does it, extravagant.
Is that what it means or is that Latin
for, oh my God, I can't believe this.
Shitty pasta tastes much better
with cloth. Napkin says that.
What the fuck it means? You know what?
I'm going to look it up right now.
I'm looking up right now because I'm gonna
set you guys up with what this, this,
this week is going to be all about.
This is going to be,
there's a lot of information,
not information this week. Um,
that's going to become an a,
how the fuck you spelled decadent.
D. E. C. Deca a, another.
A deca. No. D C. A dent.
Deka Dent.
Oh, Jesus Christ. I
wasn't even close. Was it
d e c? A. D. E. N. T. Wow.
Fuck. I got it. Holy Shit. All right.
Decadence. Let's go to Wikipedia.
God knows they're fucking
credible. Um, decadence. Kimra.
For to a personal trait or to the
state of society or a segment of it.
Use to describe a person's lifestyle.
MMM.
It describes the fuck happened.
Just it a goddamn computer.
Users grab a person's lifestyle.
It describes a lack of moral and
intellectual discipline. Well,
there's a fucking left turn. Oh, no
way. Yeah. Wait a second now. That's,
I guess gotta be right. Nice. Am I going
to question these people? I'm a moron.
Bill. Why don't you just read it and shut
the fuck up. Alright, I will. All right.
Used to describe a person's lifestyle.
It describes a lack of moral and
intellectual discipline or in the Oxford
Dictionary,
a luxurious self indulgence.
Okay.
You, you know who the fuck describes
pasta is a luxurious self indulgent,
you know some,
you know who does some stupid white
trash conduits fuckin macaroni and cheese
six days a week and all of a sudden you
bring her a little fucking CD and he,
you know, she can't, she can't
believe it. Oh my God, it's the deck.
And she was actually,
that was an insecure comment.
They probably had an extra couple of
forks there and she started to panic.
You know what I mean?
Just like Jodie foster when she's talking
to that dude and silence of the lambs
and he can tell us that she, she grew up
dirt poor because of her shoes. Right.
You know, that's all the end of that
commercial needed was somebody saying,
I can smell your cunt. That would have
been, that would have been all right.
You know, I'm really being
crude right now and I apologize,
especially after last week,
that video they told all you guys to see.
I got a lot of,
I've got a lot of feedback about that
one about what a ignorant moron I am and
I'll be reading those a little bit later.
Look at me foreshadowing here.
He liked that. Like I'm on a God
damn radio station. Um, all right,
let's get to some mom.
If you're new to this podcast,
I do one of these every week and this
is basically what it is. All right.
If you think it's going to get better,
like I'm building to something, I'm not,
this is pretty much,
I'm going to flat line the whole week
and I feel like I have internal hiccups
right now. You know those hiccups where
you start to hiccup but then you don't?
Huh?
Am I doing an eighties bit again?
What's the deal with internal here goes,
um,
great.
It's like a fork.
Doesn't know where to go.
Oh God, I'd love to fucking do standup
in the 80s. It was so much easier,
wasn't it?
One week you're an accountant,
the next minute you're on comic strip
live wearing the same blazer that you wore
when you were doing somebody's taxes,
except you just fucking pull the sleeves
up and everything was funny back then.
All right. Uh, let's get onto some shit
here. Uh, Bill, just for your information,
the guy, the wrap you were
trying to talk about last neat,
nice week is it's pronounced,
I still can't say it's Quali.
I never heard anybody say it to Lib.
Quali coyly and I'm fucking
notice name is quietly,
I mean I listen to someone's rap,
you know, I like about the guy,
he doesn't say his fucking name every
three seconds and the one time when I need
somebody to do it, he doesn't do it.
And I still don't know how to say it.
Sky Spelled the qua. How'd
he say? Is that choir?
Quasi right.
That's how you said so
quiet quietly to Lib.
Quali ah, this is fucking pathetic one.
Want to do alright. You know. Alright,
plowing ahead here. Um, here's one that
somebody actually was going to have, uh,
for another segment, but this
seemed more like a ask bill. Uh,
here's two things I'd love to hear
your opinion on drugs and double dates.
Um, yes, this guy wants to
hear my opinions on double
dates in this. Actually,
I think this is more of an ask
bill kind of question. So he says,
long story short, I met the
hottest chick ever at a club. Dude.
I met Ohad is fucking chick
ever and names fucking Stacy.
Um, I get a number one.
Read this all like,
come a fucking knasis's back in the day
and Kenmore square doors go down and
fucking nasty. This is with our
fucking z cavalry. Ricci's dude,
fucking go down there,
get a couple of rule fees.
Drop him in a fucking Zima dude.
Fucking cock sucker. All
right, long story short,
me and the hottest chick ever ran a
club. I get her number, we talk, we,
I ask her out, she changes it.
Okay. Ask her out. And then,
then she changes it to a
double date with her sister.
So I go out on this double day to
an extremely expensive restaurant.
I'm 22 in college broke.
I drop $140 on her. Uh, the,
the sister wouldn't let me out of her
sight and all I got was one small kiss
later on. I did not even get a kiss good
night because the sister was watching.
All right,
dude.
Now you really shouldn't be asking
my opinion on double dating.
What this is really about is
how did you as a young man,
22, I'm going to cut you some slack
here. End Up in that situation. Okay?
Don't walk away from this. Just go in
like, you know what you wanted to do.
Overrated. Underrated, overrated. Fucking,
you know, double date and it's sucks.
Now you should have right there,
dude.
You went when she tried to turn
it into a double date right there.
You just have to be, Nah, I don't
want to do that. And she'll be like,
why don't you want to do that?
And you just feel,
I don't like going on double dates.
Why not?
Because one person ends
up not having a good time,
and it's usually the other con that
you bring. You can clean this up, this
no. You know what I mean? You
get your ski. Just just say
it. I swear to God that's,
you know when you're 22 you
don't realize the power of no.
All right.
It actually seems like maybe you have
some shit going on because at 22 most guys
don't know how to talk to women.
So all women here is yes, yes, yes.
Especially if they're hot.
They just keep fucking agreeing with them.
So if you say no, all of a sudden it's,
it's, it's kind of different. I mean,
you could fuck it up, but
at the end of the day, dude,
you didn't get laid and you're
out of 150 bucks. All right?
Think about that moment when she said,
let's turn.
You were going to turn this into a double
date. What did your internal voice say?
Oh Great. Or did it say, fuck,
this is going to suck.
This is going to suck.
I'm not going to be able to get along
with this girl. Uh, you know Joe Pesci,
I'm trying to fucking
bang this broad over here.
You know it's not going to go good.
So right there you just got to watch.
You just got to say no. I don't want to
do a double date. And she'll say why?
And just say, cause I'm 22.
What am I potsy we unhappy days.
We going to go to inspiration point.
You want to go out on a date with me?
I don't Ya.
At that point you bring a little anger
into it and he kind of just show the side
of your head and you don't really
look at her. That'll get you.
That'll get you a second tape. All
right. That was fucking brutal.
It was bad advice. I'm
trying to tell you, dude,
just don't fucking go on a double
date. All right. They suck.
You knew they suck.
You knew before you even went on it,
you knew what was going to suck.
And if you're broke,
don't take a girl someplace where
you got to drop 140 bucks. You know,
what did she do to deserve $140 meal?
What?
Cause she's hot like that some sort of
accomplishment. She was born that way.
You know what you did is you basically
took probably a nice girl and you just
added another layer to the foundation
of her just being an incredibly stuck up
human being who doesn't have, who doesn't
have to develop a personality. You know,
look at me making all these judgments.
But I think it's true.
Just because you're hot doesn't
mean you deserve $140 meal.
If you're broke,
dude,
be honest with yourself with that
chick was like a seven. You know,
you'd probably take it a pizza hut
for some fucking decadent pasta.
So I don't know.
Did I help you there?
I got to stop doing these podcasts on
Sunday cause I'm fucking jet lag from
flying back to wherever
the fuck I came from.
I was actually working in Denver this
weekend. I was at the comedy works.
So I should take some time here to uh,
uh,
thank everyone who came out to see me.
The turnout in Denver was ridiculous
and I actually flew in a day early and I
got to do five minutes out at red rocks.
And um,
if you're not from Denver and you're not
a fan of you to just go on youtube and
just Google red rocks,
it's fucking,
it's one of the most amazing venues is
basically an outdoor venue built into the
side of a mountain and that youtube
video. Speaking of that. Yeah,
that's why I was trying
to say that youtube video,
I don't know what the fuck was called.
Unforgettable fire. I don't know.
What was it about? What was it about?
What, what is you to sing about?
They sing about breaking up with girls.
Martin Luther King,
and then they went through
their irony stage, didn't they?
Where are you?
Where the big glasses and he just ain't
just acted like everything was fucking
surreal. I don't know. Whatever it is.
There's a video that they did way back
in the day and he marches around like a f
with a, with a fucking flag.
Like he's in a, I don't know,
like they're doing something. He playing
like this military be get dead, dead,
dead, dead, dead, dead, dead,
dead, dead. And he comes my,
I say an old fucking David spade
bit. He starts chatting. No War.
There you go. It's that video.
Yeah. No, but we got it.
It's not like they're a
small fucking indie band.
We knew 10 minutes ago when you started
describing it. All right. All right.
Sometimes they get a
little carried away. I, uh,
just reminds me of something.
Can I have a falling out with somebody?
Like two months ago, you ever
have somebody, a friend of yours,
just say something so fucking stupid that
you don't want me to get angry and you
just, you just have that moment like, wow,
I can't be friends with this person
anymore because they were fucking moron.
No, you don't. What happens? Somebody,
somebody does happen to me twice.
One time somebody said, uh, they were
talking about secretary at that horse
and they were talking about all the
whole, all the racist, the horse one in,
in the end they went,
what? An athlete. And uh,
I don't know if that was it. I just
could never look at them the same way.
What an athlete. You know, I, I don't,
I just do. I have, you need to fucking
go off on that. Do I need to explore?
Can you tell him actually scrolling down,
I'm trying to find something else.
Somebody wrote a fucking question about
that. This whole fucking podcasts,
it's just falling apart. This
is what you get. You know what?
Maybe if I started
charging for these things,
I take them a little more seriously
and we wouldn't have these long lulls.
My dog's fast asleep from
my monotone voice is no,
there's no passion in this.
What am I doing here with the fuck is it?
Oh, you know what? Fuck this podcast. Am
I going to start over? I'm going to start,
you know, I want to plow through. I
can't, I can't start off with this is it.
I got one take.
This is like live television here.
I'm just going to read everything in front
of me. How about that? All right. Uh,
Bill's listen to your podcast
on July 20th you said, uh, the,
that the youtube video.
Tough talk in college.
Girl was a must see a search forward. Oh
yeah. That people kind of took it down.
People took that one down.
Um, and if you didn't see it,
that people keep putting it back up.
So just check every couple of days.
Just look up search, tough
talk and college girl, t,
U F F and it's talking with the GE
even though I don't pronounce my gs.
Um, anyways, uh, here's one for ups.
My girlfriend and I were at the grocery
store last night and all that they had
opened where those self checkouts,
this is the first time I was putting that
situation because they usually always
have at least one real lane open.
Anyways,
the place was fucking swamped and going
to a real person to pay for the shit
wasn't even an option. Uh, there
were three fucking employees.
It was just three fucking
employees as standing there.
I went up to the three fucks
and I asked him if, uh,
if they would open a real lane and they
just told me that they were too short
staffed, um, fucking
horse shit. This guy says,
he said, I thought to myself, uh, where
is bill burr when you need them both do,
what would I do other than just sit there
and curse under my breath neck next to
some fucking candy like you did fucking
bullshit. That's fucking bullshit.
Um, so I got in line and I rang up
my own shit, like a little pitch. Uh,
I had no other option.
What would you done in that situation?
I would have done exactly what you did.
I would have been hostile
towards the three people there.
I would have cursed under my breath and
then I probably just would've fucking,
you know,
depending on how much I needed to shit,
if I really didn't need this stuff,
what I,
what I would've done a what I would like
to, you know what I'm doing right now?
I'm doing that shit.
You know,
we're after something goes down
and the guy tells you the story,
then there's always that Douche bag. He
goes, dude, you know what I would've done?
You know what I would've done? Now that
I have all the fucking information. Um,
you know what you could do in
the future is just say, oh,
well then we are going to come back during
the day when you have some people and
then just leave your food
there and let them put it back.
You know, dude, I told you this was going
to fucking happen. They're understaffed.
They're understaffed on purpose.
That's phase two.
Phase one was just to have like five or
six fucking registers and give you three
others. So all the fucking sheep look over
the curiosity factor, what's going on.
And then you had the other cashiers over
there teaching them how to fucking use
it. Now they've gotten beyond that.
Now they're going into phase two.
Okay? Phase two of the experiment.
What happens if there's no,
if there are no cashier people,
how will the herd handle this?
When should we do it? Well,
we can't do it during the day.
This fucking old people and their
little motorcars riding around.
Let's do it later on at night.
Let's see how the drunk crowd handles it.
Even if they don't like it, they won't
fucking remember. At the very least.
They won't send any angry letters.
I'm telling you,
this is how the whole
fucking thing is going to go.
And somebody actually asked me in this,
uh,
this week asked me, they were curious
as to what I thought about ATS.
Um,
yeah,
I'm not against technology is
if it makes my life like easier,
like ATM at banks before,
I don't know if you guys remember this,
shipped it back in the day when there was
no a tms, you know, Friday, five o'clock.
If you didn't grab the cash you needed
for the weekend, you were fucked.
You couldn't get to you.
My IC,
they will be open for like 20
minutes on a Saturday. But uh, yeah,
that was just be that, that their
expression, the guys work in banker hours.
He used to be open like nine to five.
You can never even get
your fucking money out.
So what I like about the ATM as at
least I have access to my money.
I don't mind that. And a lot of times
it is easier to just throw it in there.
So I don't give a fuck,
you know,
that one doesn't bug me and I understand
the technology does replace some jobs.
The reason why I can't stand this latest
brand of automated shit is it's not an
advancement.
It doesn't make it easier.
I just go up and do exactly what the
cashier did and the bag person did,
except I'm doing it for free. Now. If
I walked up to the cashier machine,
the automated thing and magically the
fucking thing figured out what I owed and
then suddenly it was all in a bag,
I wouldn't give a shit. All right.
I Dunno.
People just hear what they want to hear.
Like you make one comment about something.
It's God who like technology,
he's against penicillin. No I'm not.
I'm not at vent gets advancement.
I'm against fuck overs and those automated
things in the grocery store and at
the, at the parking garage, the
automated park or fuck overs.
Yeah.
It doesn't make it quicker. It actually
makes it longer and a lot of instances.
And, uh, I'm just working for free.
I'm working for free and I
don't fucking like it. Okay.
And that's the last time I'm fucking
explaining it and I don't need any,
you douchebags glue. They, we ain't got
money origins. Dod Janie Wedge Quicker.
You're a moron. Just fucking work
for free. All right, here we go.
Um, what are we going on to a, somebody
sent me an email, said, hey bill,
I just want to thank you. Thanks a
bunch for teaching me about tinnitus.
That ringing in the ear stuff I was
talking about. I just turned 21.
I had that shit as long as I can remember.
Didn't know what it was a thought.
It was just me,
um,
for anyone that has the problem and
not sure what to do when I was younger,
I used, uh, I left the TV on, that was
a bad idea. After that I played, uh,
mostly chill music,
um,
and my music collection and a 70
minute album or something like that.
And now I just sorta put a fan on low
speed and it keeps the ringing away.
For those of you who don't have
tonight is what he's saying is,
is you put some sort of smaller,
quieter noise in the background that
drowns out the ringing in your ear and uh,
actually do what you really should do is
go see a doctor is what you're supposed
to do.
And um,
okay.
Okay.
I Dunno. Um, that's,
I think the case is of Tinnitus is
going to go way up just because of like
iPods. And when you go to clubs, how
loud they play that fucking music. Um,
actually,
you know,
I actually bring ear plugs everywhere I
go because I have such fucked up ears,
at least I try to remember.
But basically how it works is anything
up to about 60 or 65 decibels,
you're pretty much cool.
And you can listen.
Your ear can handle like are right
around 60 decibels that say, ah,
that's like how I'm talking right now.
Regular conversation and you
don't do any damage to your ears.
Your ears can listen to it for, you know,
all day and you don't do any damage.
But what happens,
I forget how the math works,
but every time you move up 10 decibels,
like 60 to 70 the timeframe that your
ears can listen to that level of noise
without doing permanent damage
goes down really quickly.
And I know some worry where when you start
getting around 80 that starts getting
dangerous and anything above 90 um,
I mean I think like 90 listening
to something at 90 minutes.
Don't quote me on this. I forget. I used,
I used to have this chart and only
shit I tried to find on the Internet,
but I couldn't.
But anything around 90 decibels.
Yeah,
after like 15 minutes.
And you can easily with an iPod go up to
about a buck 10 15 minutes of listening
to music.
You do permanent damage to your hearing.
And I know that sounds fucked up. It's
just incremental. And you can't tell,
I forget,
I read all this shit.
There's little hairs in there and when
you blow it out yet the things get
knocked down and then they slowly stand
back up again and after a while they
just don't get back up again.
You just fucking like a boxer.
They just lay in there and you go
into clubs, man. And they have,
they have those that fucking music
up to like a buck 15, a buck 20.
If he noticed the bouncers who worked
there always heavier plugs for the most
part. Um, I dunno, I suffer from
tinnitus. You don't want it.
It's horrific. But um, if you have it,
you should definitely go see a doctor.
And I would always have earplugs
on you just in case you know,
you're hanging out,
hey, check out this bar.
And you'd go in there and I don't know
why they play the music that fucking loud.
I can tell if the, I guess if there's
a Dj and there's dance of what I said,
when you just walk into a bar and you
haven't a couple of beers and he got to
scream, I can't fucking stand that.
I don't know. Maybe because I'm,
maybe because I'm old. Who knows? All
right, let's move on to the next section.
You know, I'm just, I'm just
reading shit this week. All right.
I don't know why I forget what this is,
but this section is named the
accidental racist. All right.
Uh, Hey, bill,
I just downloaded a bunch
of your uninformed shows
on mini mini Nova and just
began listening to the first one,
a show from February 10th,
2007 I stopped at three minutes in to
write you to thank you for delivering
already the accidental racism to the
Asian guy. Oh, that's why this name,
this I'm in the elevator story.
It kind of reminded me of
a sending [inaudible] funny
thing that happened to me.
All right.
Just to get you guys caught up,
I was going up with them in
the elevator at the old, uh,
XM building evidently on February 10th,
2007 and it was me and Joe
de Rosa who do the show.
And there was this Asian guy in the
elevator and I can't remember what,
but he seemed confused and uh, he was, I,
I sometimes,
I didn't know what floor he was on.
Somehow I made the assumption that he was
delivering food and I conveyed that to
him and I was, yeah. Said something
like, Oh, what are you delivering food?
And he just put his head down and he goes,
I work here.
And I felt like such a fucking asshole.
But he just looked,
he looked disheveled and he was dressed
down and we did the show on a Saturday,
so he wasn't dressed like he was going
to work. It was just one of those things.
Uh, if I could find the guy,
I would apologize to them.
But you know what I mean?
There are a lot of Asian
guys delivering food in, uh,
in New York, you know, so,
and they're always going up elevators
and they always have that look of like,
what fucking floor am I going to?
I don't know the guy, I don't know.
I don't what happened when we got an arc
with his girlfriend. It's how I read it.
So anyways, I felt like an
asshole and I apologize. Uh,
you know,
for some reason he's listening to this
podcast and be funny if he actually was a
listener of my podcast and didn't realize
that was me and now realizes it's me
and now I've lost another listener.
Um, anyway, so this guy gets,
has a story just like it. Um,
so when he says anyways, um,
my junior year in college I was looking
for a roommate because some previous
people I had lined up dropped
out on me in the last minute.
A girl I was friends with put me in
touch with the guy she was friends with
because, uh, he was
looking for a place to,
despite both of us having this girl's a
mutual friend, we never met each other.
Uh, we set everything up over the phone
and came to terms we could both live with
without ever even meeting in person.
Um,
thus the first time we would meet was
at the place we would both be living in
Jesus. Dude, you're really
taking a risk there. Um,
there are some things about me that are
vital pieces of information in order for
this story to make sense. First
of all, I'm black. However,
due to the tone and the pitch of my voice,
my usage of correct grammar,
most of the time, um, you know, do it. If
I said that I would really be in trouble.
But you can trash your own people.
Okay. So everything's good. Um,
he said I was an English major, but
I'm not an asshole about it, I promise.
Correct Grammar,
use correct grammar most of the time and
the semi racist nature of most people.
Uh, many people have told me that I sound
white or could be mistaken for a white
person over the phone. I'm going to
address that point a little bit later.
All right, so getting back to the story.
When I talked to this kid over the phone,
we found out, uh, we had both gone to
the same high school for a year. Again,
despite that this, we
didn't know each other. Um,
the fact that this school was
mostly white combined with the,
the sounds of his voice,
I thought he was white in my mind.
Um,
which set up this awesome situation.
I figured he was guessing I was white for
the same reason I was guessing. He was,
I was really looking forward to seeing
this white kid squirm when he pulled up
and realize that was black.
Of course,
a black kid pulled up to the house
looking for me and it was uh,
my prospective roommate.
I remember seeing a little bit of surprise
look on his face and I said to him,
he thought I was white, didn't you? And
then of course my computer craps out. Uh,
he smiled and admitted he did. Uh, I told
him that I thought he was white as well.
We both ended up having a great laugh
about it and became pretty good friends
afterwards. Um, anyways, thanks for
the podcast. Okay, let me, let me,
uh, let me get back to that. Um, the
semi racist nature of most people.
Many people have told me that I sound
white or could be mistaken for a white
person over the phone for the life of me.
I don't know why that
is considered racist.
Okay.
I don't know if you've noticed,
but like white people kind
of talk in a certain way.
I mean if you watch def def jam, we just
talk in one way. But like, you know,
there, there is, you know, if,
I mean if I was on here and
all of a sudden I was like, Yo,
you know what I'm doing more fucking
podcast is shit. He'd be like,
why is bill trying to talk like he's
some black dude from the ghetto?
Wouldn't you? Would that be
racist or you know, there's,
there's nothing wrong with a,
what the fuck am I trying to say here?
If you just say somebody sounds white,
you're not,
you're not saying they're a a moron.
Right. Am I a fucking idiot here? I
don't understand why I was saying,
you know over the phone. Yeah. He
sounded like a black guy or hey,
you sounded white over the phone.
Is it,
does it go back to that correct grammar
thing that the black person then assumes
like, Oh, why? Because I didn't say
mother fucker every five seconds.
I know I do a brutal fucking impression,
but is that why it is, that's actually
an interesting question to say.
Is this a great fucking podcast
through my, my stupidity.
You guys learned shit
unless you already know it.
Your role in your fucking
eyes at that place. And you
have to, if that's the case,
go fuck yourself. All right. And then
this guy also ends this email. He says,
uh, what did he say here?
Anyways, thanks to the podcast,
they're awesome.
And as a New York Yankees Fan,
I want to thank the red sox for
keeping first place warm for us.
Good luck with David.
I can't hit anymore.
Now that steroids are
banned or teas and Jason,
we had to trade one of the best right
handed hitters of all time for this
nonthreatening white Gabe Bay
for the rest of the summer.
You know, you got a lot of balls as
a Yankee fan bringing up steroids.
Okay,
half your fucking team got busted.
Do I really need to go through
the names? A Rod, Sheffield, GMB,
Clemens Pettitte.
You're a fucking $200 million
team and you're on steroids. Okay.
At least our steroid guys. A
fucking winning championships.
Your bunch of cunts.
No, I'm sorry. You want it 99
and 2000 with your steroid guys.
You know, I, I love how he Yankee fans are
talking to you got to $200 million team
[inaudible] you're barely
playing 600 baseball. You know,
that's like having a fucking
Lamborghini and you're psyched.
It's going 70 miles an hour.
You guys should be playing like seven
20 ball with all those fucking guys you
have.
And you know what the funny thing is,
you still don't have a bullpen so
you're not gonna win shit this year.
It's a joke. You know what? You guys
do like a super group, you know,
why don't you just sign fucking Ted
Nugent to play. So play center field,
you know, hey, we're just
$122 million team that could,
that's the best thing about Manny Ramirez
going out to La is that it knocked our
payroll way the fuck down.
Now we're down to like 122 million.
We're actually number four this year.
People were behind the Yankees,
the mets and uh,
who was at the cubs or the Dodgers?
I fuck him and have to Dodgers. Who
the fuck was it? Maybe the cubs.
I don't know who it is.
All I know is we're number,
we're like 80 million less and this
guy's all excited cause they're two,
three games ahead of us even though you're
oh and eight against the red sox and
he got swept by the angels.
What are y'all excited?
Cause your feast and on the royals
and the rangers and all that Shit.
And Jason Bay is a great fucking
baseball player and uh, he's done,
been doing a great job for us and we've
barely missed Manny. I hate to say it,
I love the guy. And uh,
just for the record,
he didn't do steroids till he got to La.
You know,
dude,
when did he get caught?
He didn't got caught when he was
in Boston that whole fucking time.
All of a sudden he comes out to la,
he starts running with the wrong crowd,
you know, happens to the best of them
when they come out here. Look at rape,
the River Phoenix, he came
out here, he did some roids.
He fucking never got up again.
Cute little actor.
He was all right, here we
go. Here's another thing.
I don't know why I'm reading this,
but I'm just going to read a dude.
I can't believe you didn't notice
that she, okay, wait a minute.
Wait. Okay. Here we go. Wait a minute.
All right. What am I doing here? All
right, this is, this is the response.
One of the responses I got from
that leg sweep video last week.
And if you're new to my podcast,
there's a video up on Youtube,
I guess it got taken down where a,
this, this guy hits on this girl.
She doesn't, you know, she's not
having it. So he gives a shit.
She gives him the finger,
he calls her a bitch.
She throws a drink in his face
and he goes up. You think he, you,
he's going to blast her in the face and
he just gives a leg or her a fucking leg
sweep that uh,
it should have been done in Mandalay
Bay in Las Vegas was fucking tremendous.
All right, here we go. So, uh, this,
this woman wrote me, she goes, uh, Bill,
I can't believe he didn't notice that
she was visited with violent behavior
first. This is the girl in the video.
Um, cause I was sitting there and saying,
I thought the video was funny because
the girl threw the drink in his face and
even though he should never hit a woman,
I just think that's outrageous in life
to think that you can throw a drink in
somebody's face.
I just know if I did it within two
seconds I would be on the ground getting
fucking pummeled and uh,
I dunno.
There was just something funny
about it. So anyways, she goes,
I can't believe he didn't notice that
she was visited with violent behavior
first. Watch it again and you'll
see him violently poke at her.
All right. First of all, how
fucking hilarious is that violently.
Have you ever heard that expression
in your life? Violently poked.
There's no such thing as being violently
poked. All right. It's called stab.
That's, you know, that's fine. I actually,
my gym teacher used to violently poked
me in the chest to fucking cock sucker.
Um, he did and he gave her, he
gave her a little fucking poke.
He get one time to her fucking shoulder.
That was it.
He was just trying to ignore her.
But anyway, she says, by the way,
it's not very complimentary to a grown
woman to be shown that he has a crush on
her by punching her. He didn't
punch, he didn't punch her.
Anyway,
she goes,
I can't believe you're not allowing
her to do the only thing she can toss a
drink Adam,
since she can't beat him up,
do you honestly believe that her
throwing the drink equals his, um,
kick slash knocked to her on the
skull? Shame on you, you bastard.
So I wrote her back. I said, I
knew this would spark some debate.
I respect your point of view on it.
So here's mine violently poked 41 years
on this planet and I have never heard
someone being violently poked.
Um,
she threw the drink in his face because
he called her a bitch and then she goes
that cause she goes,
that's right. I am a bitch.
And then the drink his throne and throw
in the drink in his face was not the
only thing she could've done.
She could have walked away.
She could have talked to whoever
was in charge at the pool.
She could have talked to some of the guys
who were over there, um, by her friends.
There were a bunch of things she could
have done, but she lost her. Cool. Um,
and if you're going to define the action
by the guy in the video as violently
poking her,
then you could also address,
couldn't you also address
the racial undertones of her
giving the man the finger
and stating,
do you understand this and English?
The reason why the video is so funny
is because the unexpected happened.
He actually treated her the same way.
He would have treated a man
that threw a drink in his face.
So the reason men find the video funny,
I think is because the amount of times
women get physical with us and there's
nothing we can do except get punched,
slap,
or have a drink thrown in our face because
we're never going to hit a woman and
they know it.
I had a girl try to punch me in the
face and a bar and as I'm trying,
as carefully as possible to defend
against getting punched in the face,
basically I'm turning my back and cover
it up. Or is this girl wailed away?
The bouncer comes flying over.
And what do you think?
Who Do you think they
grabbed and tossed out? Um,
I was in an argument with the
female, but, so what people argue,
but because of the way things are,
she can take it to a physical level
while I have to try and defend myself
without getting physical with her at all,
only to be dragged out by the neck. Uh,
you know, if they tossed her out
too, I would have been fine with it.
But because she's a female, she gets
to throw punches, have me kicked out,
and she gets to stay in the bar while
they continue to serve or more drinks.
So to go back to the video, um, that is
the world. This warm woman is living in.
I'm a girl.
I can do this and nothing will happen.
I could throw a full drink at someone's
face and nothing will happen. Well,
guess what?
Something did the exact thing,
same thing that would have happened to me.
And then I go on to say,
actually I would have been fucking punched
repeatedly in the face and the dude's
friends probably would have jumped into.
And you know what the reaction from the
others people at the pool would have
been? Well, you threw a drink at his
face. What did you think was gonna Happen?
And then I guess my excuse would have
been, but he poked me violently. Um,
anyways, I've never hit a woman. I
don't advocate it, uh, that gain.
The video is an animal and I wouldn't
want any woman I cared about to ever date
him.
But the leg,
the fucking leg sweep was genius
and undeniably funny to me.
I'm just going to read you all of
these back and forth. So then she goes,
you have no idea what women have
women have to put up with. All right,
this is where I guess I'm a moron.
These guys take such personal
offense when they're turned down,
he should have walked away.
I will not tolerate being touched
by a stranger in that way,
and it is really a really
vulnerable feeling as a woman.
It makes us angry and fearful of men.
Besides you didn't hear the things
he was saying. Guys like that.
Parentheses in hip hop style clothing
are the sleaziest of scumbags licking
their lips. Nasty. Who's
hitting on you? Ll Cool j.
Why don't you fucking go to
a nicer place anyways, uh,
as for the argument you had in the bar,
you didn't specify.
Now she's talking to me. This
is classic line. Here she goes.
As for the argument you had
with that woman in the bar,
you didn't specify what it was about,
what it was about.
And if you are yelling in her face,
as you know, you probably were.
Dot Dot, dot. More violent
behavior. He see that.
Let's stop right here. This is what
I love about this type of shit.
Anytime there's a group of people
bitching about their situation.
Nine Times out of 10
when they're bitching,
they ended up doing the exact same thing
to the person that they're bitching at,
that they don't want done to them.
Look how you assume that
immediately I'm getting hit.
I'm not hitting her back.
I'm getting hit and you're blaming me.
I'm surprised you didn't ask me
what I was wearing. Was I asking for
anyways, you want to hear the story,
sweetheart? This, this is basically,
this is why this girl was
punching me in the bar. All right,
we're going back here about 10 years.
I'm standing up now.
I'm going to tell this story. My
dog's looking at me. What's up?
[inaudible] how you doing? Huh? You're
a female. You can defend yourself.
You fucking psycho. Um, this,
this is what happened. I was in,
I was in a bar and I was
with somebody in mind.
This group of girls is next to us.
We're hitting on them. You know,
we'll make jokes with joking around. You
know, he tried to get women to laugh.
That's what the fuck you have
to do. Women. I know you don't,
you don't understand that because you
don't have to make somebody want to fuck
you. Okay. The same way,
I don't know what it's like to have to
carry a fucking living thing inside of me
for nine months. I understand. We
all have our advantages, so whatever,
I'm not trying to be a Douche
here, but this is basically, it's,
so we're trying to,
we know we're joking around or whatever.
I had a couple of drinks,
they had a couple of drinks and
one of them was dressed like,
she looked like Rhoda on Mary Tyler Moore.
All right.
So at one point that girl goes up and uh,
she goes to go to the bathroom.
So I say to a friend and go,
Jesus Christ was she,
she a big fan of Mary Tyler Moore or what?
Right.
Made a joke about what she was wearing.
So another 20 minutes goes by,
those girls Kinda peeled off, you know,
we weren't really talking to them anymore.
We were, uh, well maybe we kind of
were, I don't know what was going on.
Sort of that type of shit. You're
talking to a girl for a couple seconds,
then it's not working out.
So I went back,
I was talking to my friend and I guess
when the girl came back from the,
from the bathroom,
her friend told her what I said.
So unbeknownst to me,
so I'm sitting there talking to my buddy.
Then all of a sudden they just hear
this, this, this woman yelling,
hey bitch, hey bitch. Right.
So I look over and she's looking
at me. She's going, hey bitch.
And I'm, and I'm, I'm trying to
process cause I, you know, typical may,
I said some shit. I don't even remember
what the fuck I said. And then she goes,
you know, you're going to talk shit
about me when I'm not around. And then I,
then I kind of was right
as I'm putting it together.
Then she stood up and she fucking put
her hand over. You ever see like a,
you ever see like a,
a center in the NBA how they fight or
they can't throw fake fucking throw
punches like that. They're trying to
fucking throw somebody out at second base.
That's what she did.
She winds up and she's about ready
to come down on the top of my head.
So you know, because she wound up,
I mean if he fucking threw a jab,
she would have fucking
blasted me right in the face.
And I got to admit that
would've been fucking hilarious.
But because she went up and over,
I was able to get my arm
up in time and I saw it.
I sorta like cut her wrist. So now I
instantly, I recognize the situation.
I'm like,
oh fuck,
okay this girl is not going to stop and
I don't want to get hit in the face.
I can't squeeze her risk too hard.
All this shit's going through my head
and I know, even though I can't see it,
I know the bounces are on their way
over and I know what the fuck's going to
happen.
So all I'm doing is holding her wrist
as she's fucking client at my side.
I'm sort of turned to the side and of
course my buddies aren't doing anything.
This sort of just looking at this point
cause it happened so fast and I'm going,
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. I was going, hey, hey,
hey, I can't even, what I was saying,
I was just, this just too much
shit was going on. I, I couldn't,
I couldn't formulate anything
to say to get this girl to stop,
but she just kept fucking bitch.
You fucking bitch.
It was like punching me in the side and
then the fucking bounce has come over
and they fucking grabbed me.
Of course, because I'm the guy.
I just blew my mind. I, I'm fucking,
I almost have my back turned to this girl
with my hand up and she's wailing away
and they immediately go to me
and I get fucking tossed out,
you know? So let me ask
you this. In her world,
was she justified for taking
it to a physical level?
Because I fucking made fun of her outfit.
You know,
that's was my point about that video.
I don't think that you should hit a woman.
Really. The reality of that video that
I, that I watched, they're on youtube,
is that they're both assholes
and they're both stubborn.
And what happened there is what you saw
when you get two stubborn people who
want to get the last word
in. Okay. He had on her,
she tells him to go fuck himself.
Not saying she literally said that,
but she basically says no. So he couldn't
handle it. So he probably, he starts it,
I'll go, I'll give you
that. He starts it. Okay.
And he wants to get the last word
in so she can't let them. Right.
He should have walked away,
but he did. That's you know,
right in the beginning he didn't,
so he gives her shit.
Then she should have walked away.
Realized he was a psycho. She'd had,
she fucking gives them the finger
than he should have walked away,
but he doesn't, he pokes
her. She should've walked
away then, but she doesn't,
she fucking throws a drink at his face.
He should have fucking walked away.
He doesn't, he fucking goes
up and he likes sweeps her.
It's just one of those deals,
two fucking assholes who probably should
be breeding and make a little fucking
asshole kid. And then we'll have
another dog. The bounty hunter. Huh?
You see how that math works out. So
anyways, um, I, you know, I don't know.
Sometimes I feel like I'm saying shit
and people don't get what the fuck I'm
talking about. I'm not saying that
you should go around hitting a woman.
I'm just saying, you know,
guy, she never hit women,
but women shouldn't take advantage
of that by doing outrageous shit.
Like throwing a drink in somebody's face
that is fucking outrageous behavior.
And be honest.
As a female,
if another female walked up to you
and threw a drink in your face,
what would you do? Huh? What would you
do? Would you just go out with mature?
Do you feel better about yourself?
Is sprite is dripping down the
fucking your bangs, whatever. Fucking
you got that Rachel Bob Haircut
from friends. Ah, look at me,
look at me with that
fucking check reference. Um,
whatever it gives a fuck. Anyways.
All right, here's, here's some videos.
So I actually was, I nominated that
video for a video of the year and a,
so people sent me some other videos
and I'm really upset at myself because
somebody sent me a great video of these
two bullies attack in this guy with his
girlfriend and his,
the guy's girlfriend jumps in and she
fucking blast this guy in the face in the
end. It's a fucking awesome video. Um,
so I really need that video so I
can balance it out, Sarah. You know,
so I don't just have videos of guys
knock and women down because, uh,
that's not what I'm trying to do here.
You know what I mean?
This is supposed to be a fun
thing for everybody. And, uh,
all right, so here you go. Here's
some nominees. Uh, somebody, uh,
ONA fan said a east freely was in,
uh,
was on the show this week celebrating
Jim Norton's birthday. Um,
and he recommended a video
called Winnebago man.
I watched it and it's fucking hilarious.
Um, Google how to spell when a,
when a bag. I'm just going to tell you
what the name of the videos are. Uh,
there's another one,
a guy with gun confronts skateboarder,
and there's another one that
says, uh, this is the last one.
And I deliberately put this one last
because this is more in the vein of last
week's video. It says, guy gets
revenge on girlfriend for headache.
This one's really more silly
and I'm actually jealous
of like how perfectly this
guy's prank works out. It's just,
it's, it really is a work of art. And,
uh, most females won't like it, but it's,
you know, no one gets hurt in this one.
Okay? Nobody's head
hits concrete. Um, yeah,
that's it. Okay. And if
you're sick of those kinds of
videos, there's one on there.
Have a little fucking golden
retriever. Puppy howling. All right.
Go Google that one. Okay. That'll
make you fucking smile. All right,
I'm going to have to wind this. Jesus
Christ. 47 fucking minutes. All right,
let me wind this up real quick.
We're talking about grenades again,
people the subject that just won't die.
Uh,
anyways, uh, Bill, I missed the last
couple of podcasts. This is from a marine,
so we can all hang out here,
right?
47 minutes and let's support the troops
and listen to the last few minutes of
the podcast here. I missed the last
few podcasts, but there was, um,
there was a lot about the military.
You seem to be interested in the military,
Bubba, bubba. Oh,
and I was a marine for four years
and did my tour in the sandbox.
Parentheses,
Iraq.
Go on Wikipedia and type
in operation Phantom fury.
Those are my credentials.
That kid you talked about on
six 29 was kind of a joke.
I can tell by what he says.
So he's basically saying the other are
there other military person who gave me
my grenade information is uh,
you know,
I guess working in a mess hall. Look at
me trying to start some shit. Look at me.
Huh? Hey Guy from uh, June 29th,
you're going to take that shit.
He's saying you don't know about grenades.
So anyways,
he says fragrance aids have
a kill radius of five meters.
A casualty is 15 meters casualty.
I guess that's, you know,
shrapnel. Okay. Marines define,
definitely use frags when necessary.
They use flash bangs when doing raids.
If you're using a flash bang and
entering a room and you shoot blindly
everywhere,
it is totally contrary.
It's a total contradiction to what
you're doing in the first place.
Trying not to kill everyone in the room.
If there's bad guys in there,
you frag the fucks, I guess that
she throw the grenade in there.
And if you throw in one,
you might as well throw in five grenades.
Aren't that lethal? Well they
are, but it just kinda depends.
Two guys and another company
tossed grenades into the,
into our house from different directions
only to have the grenades roll across
the house, cross paths and in front
of the other marine respectively.
Jesus Christ. I think I saw
this on the three stooges. Uh,
they both dove away and Eileen and only
received a minor shrapnel to the legs.
Uh, more of something to laugh
about more than anything. All right,
so there's your grenade information.
Here we go with earplugs.
Getting back to the Tinnitus
Shit. Um, went in some nasty shit.
Basically when you're in battle,
you have one ear plug in and one out,
uh, due to the sound
resistance created by plugs,
it only allows you to hear a certain
range of noise, take one out,
and it allows you to hear the larger
range of noise even after you can barely
hear out of one year. Dude, that's
fucking insane. That's what I did. And,
and it always worked.
So basically you sacrifice one year.
Did you switch off every other
battle? You know, or did you just say,
fuck my left ear?
Um,
I guess you need to do that because
what if you have the ear plugs in and
somebody's sneaking up behind
you? Good God, thank God.
Thank God I didn't have to do
that. God bless Ya. Anyways,
a machine gun next to an unprotected
ear isn't that bad at all.
Loud is explosions loud as airstrikes.
Loud rockets loud is standing next to a
tank and an ally and not having an ear
plugs that concussion river reverberates
and reckless Shay's along the walls and
the of the buildings. Um, I know
because it happened to me when,
and my ears started to leak clear fluid,
presumably,
presumably from perforated eardrums.
The sound was beyond sound.
That's one of the greatest
sentences I've ever read.
As far as like fucking description. The
sound was beyond sound. It was an impact.
It felt like I was hit with a two by
four across my entire body all at once.
My face and my balls hurt.
Jesus Christ. That's from sound,
I guess. I don't fucking know.
Just shut up and read a bill.
All right. Um, I had my one,
I had my wind knocked out.
Basically I was,
I was almost even with the barrel of them,
of the main tank gun
and the fucking tankers,
fucking guys in a tank never gave us a
signal that they were going to shoot. Um,
that's what it can because of
a concussion blast feels like,
and it gets worse the closer you get
and the bigger the explosion is throwing
some shrapnel and you get the idea.
Jesus Christ,
who this is better than the fucking
history channel. I'm really enjoying this.
All right. Um, and you talked
about the stress of battle.
There was one dude who was about to get
out of an Aa v big armored vehicle and
he went blind,
I guess he's saying from the stress.
And then he writes, just went blind.
He regained his sight a few days later,
but right before he got out, he
literally had to turn around and say, ah,
I can't fucking see Jesus Christ.
Um, as for a funny story, Oh,
you know what, that reminds me.
How have you guys seen that
movie? Uh, the fuck was that.
I was going to tell you to
watch that last week. It was a,
it was an animated movie about war.
The fuck was it called? I just rented
it. Waltz with waltz with Bashir.
You guys see that? I def,
I highly recommend that.
That's about a guy who went to war.
And when he came back,
he couldn't fucking remember anything.
So then he goes around and he talks
to his former army buddies, you know,
that's the whole hook.
A guy who can't remember,
goes around and talks to
those who can't forget.
It's pretty fucking pretty fucking
amazing. So anyways, let me continue here.
Um, and as far as for a funny story, um,
in war the stories are all fucked up.
It's all fucked up humor when you're
over there like really sadistic fucked up
shit. Even the nicest evangelist
stick person or a Mormon, uh,
we'll have the same humor over there.
Personally,
I found it hilarious when insurgents
were so drugged up they would literally
step out of an alley in front of a
tank about 50 feet away and just start
shooting an AK 47 at the thing.
The machine gun on the tank would slowly
point towards the dude and just shred
them. That's funny when
you're over there. Wow.
This is like time life books presents
the Iraq war as it's going on.
So let me ask you this.
You saying the dude,
so like hopped up on drugs like are a
lot of the insurgents over there on drugs
and why are they on drugs? Cause they're
scared from the stress of the battle.
I mean I can't,
I can't imagine that anyway.
It's probably the best story that normal
people can relate to was when we first
took over a centrally located
compound within the city of Fallujah,
um, referred to above his operation
Phantom fury. Dude, you were in Fallujah.
Holy Shit. All right, this is a great
story by the way. So hang in there guys.
I know this is long. Um, this was the
third day of the assault on the city.
Obviously after three days a bunch of
dudes are going to have to take a shit at
some point. So we had to dig
some trenches, the trenches.
We're in the middle of a large courtyard
about the size of a football field and
instead of just standing over the
trench like a dog and squatting to shit,
we knew we had to find something
to assist us when we dropped guts.
Good Lord. Okay. I mean, fuck
it. We're going to have to,
if we're going to get popped while
taking a shit, we better be comfortable.
We started searching around and inside
some of the side buildings we found some
chairs and some wooden boxes.
We cut holes in them and position them
over the trenches. Um, the area wasn't,
uh,
what the military would deem as a,
would not consider a secure at the time.
But after eating the instant
dehydrated shit meals called Mrs,
which constipate you,
uh,
you having constant op
operations for three days,
we hadn't had a satisfying shit for three
days after the new shitters were set
up.
Guys were a little apprehensive to go out
there as there were still RPGs mortars
and gunfires directed
towards our compound.
You have to understand that marines and
the marine corps, all right, this is,
this is Kinda, this is him
saying this shit, not me.
You have to understand that the
marines in the Marine Corps, uh,
like are retarded.
Many individuals are very,
actually are very intelligent
within the marines,
but the Marine Corps just makes you
into a retard and therefore the policies
within the marine corps
are retarded as well.
The only thing the marine corps
doesn't fuck up his combat,
this retardation is why most
people realist less with
the Marine Corps than any
other branch. Well, you have
to expand on that. So anyways,
so being the real retarded
marines we were, we said, fuck it.
A bunch of US strolled out and took
off our kavlaars, our helmets and flax,
bulletproof vests,
as well as our blouses shirts.
Within two minutes there were 10 or 12
marine sitting in the middle of a bay, uh,
middle of this field,
bear his bones courtyard the size of a
football field with only t shirts and
trousers at the ankles,
smoking butts, chewing, dip,
joking around like we
had a fucking Applebee's.
While there were explosions and gunfire
going off 150 meters away. Jesus Christ,
it was Robert Duvall, a fucking
surfing in the background. Actually.
He didn't surf. He was on the beach.
Anyways. Um, as we were sitting there,
a few civilian reporters poke their heads
out of the compound and went back in.
They were looking to see in the proverbial
coast to see if the proverbial coast
was clear to the armored vehicle
they were using for transport.
So basically there was a
bunch of reporters poking
their heads out trying to get
over to their fucking armored transport.
Mind you.
This was the typical type of vehicle
with the type of armor that our unit
couldn't get at the time because ours
kept getting fucked up and it was too much
of a monetary drain to give us the proper
protection because our B vehicles will
get blown up every couple of weeks are
in paraphrasing cause this is really
fucking long. Um, these business,
these people had no business
being there and they knew it.
This was evidenced by the fact that
they continue to poke their heads out of
doorways several more times.
Apparently they got the carrot
carriage up because all at once,
the group of about 10 people
who look like my seventh grade,
a gym class started making their way
to the armor armored vehicle in there.
Gay Little Blue Helmets, invest that
read press in big bold white letters.
They were visibly nervous
jogging mechanically and
looking spastic Lee in every
direction as if they would somehow be
able to change their fate. Infants,
if an insurgent decided to lean out a
window and opened fire at them as they
jogged along,
we sat there half naked from the
bottom down and stared at them in utter
amusement.
After a few seconds of silence,
someone shitting next to
me screamed and comment.
It was like a kick to the fucking
nuts. Uh, something snapped.
The reporters absolutely lost their shit.
It was one of the most beautiful examples
of Darwinism in action that I have
ever witnessed.
The strongest and fastest males threw
themselves into the truck first,
not far behind where
they're smaller males.
They were then followed by the most
attractive females who were pulled almost
instantly into the, into the truck. Um,
in last where the wingman,
wingman grenades helped in only by their,
their own large legs.
I don't get that last sentence. Uh, after
they realized that they were actually,
there was no actually incoming
really butchering this, sorry,
I'm seeing double at this point.
Uh,
after they realize that there
actually was no incoming, they slowly,
she grossly turned to look over at us
as we were sitting there with our balls
flapping in the wind dirty as fuck
while pushing out three days worth of
compacted tar and having no business
being happy in any way whatsoever.
But we were absolutely
all dying with laughter.
We continue laughing as they drove by
and we sat there smiling and waving at
them wildly like what people do
when a cruise ship leaves port.
They stared at us and
complete bewilderment and
just simply started shaking
their heads in a way a parent does when
a small child gets a pair of new clothes
covered in spaghetti and meat sauce.
But we weren't kids and we definitely
weren't dirty from eating spaghetti.
Fucking classic.
Dude,
that's a great story and I
apologize for butchering that thing.
I suck at reading out loud. Um, anyways,
this podcast has to be over a
fucking hour at this point. Yeah,
it just turned an hour.
All right.
Has been a really long podcast
with a lot of information. Um,
this has been the encyclopedia Britannica
version of the Monday morning podcast.
You guys all have a good week.
I hope you enjoyed the stories.
Forgive me for my awful reading
and uh, oh, let me hype a
couple of gigs. I got coming up.
I'm going to be at providence at
the comedy connection in Providence,
Rhode Island in August and the next week
I will be at the punchline in Atlanta,
Georgia. And after that,
the final day, August 29th,
I'm going to be in
Stockholm, Sweden. So, uh,
who the fuck is going to go
to that nobody from Sweden
listen to this shit. So that's it. That's
the Monday morning podcasts you want.
If you want to know the exact
dates, please go to my website. Uh,
it's bill@billbird.com. B U R R in,
please sign up for my mailing list.
Um, cause I'm really starting
to lose my faith in my space.
There's just nobody left on there. Like
nobody fucking emails me anymore. So, um,
and I don't want to join Facebook
and I don't want to tweet.
So I think I'm just going to basically
maybe phase out my myspace page and I'm
going to just start doing shit
on my, uh, my website. Mainly.
That's the plan. All right.
You guys all have a great week.
[inaudible] [inaudible].