Hey, how are you? It's bill
burr on a Thursday afternoon and
yeah,
I'm just checking in on your
hair on a Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast just before
Friday just to see how your week's going.
Quick little 30 minute, you know, just
opening the door, sticking my head in.
See now you're doing everything okay.
Everything okay over there and your
cubicle. Maybe you drive home. Huh?
You got your hands 10 and two on the
fucking wheel like you supposed to.
Driving like a fucking nervous Nelly.
Who is,
have you ever been comfortable in a car
when someone who had their hands 10 and
two on the fucking wheel or whatever,
nine and three whatever you supposed
to do and now six 30 and fucking 1123
whatever the latest thing is.
New Studies have shown about the way the
collarbone, Rachel's the shelter. Well,
the most affective lane and all of the
Stanley. I was actually at nine 20 say,
shut the fuck up, right? We sit
a zillion dollars on that study.
You know not to get going about that.
Fucking James Worthy again,
fucking driving off the road. They're
female, James Worthy, right? So, uh,
anyways, I'm out here. I am in a, I'm in
Portland, Oregon. I'm going to say, well,
have you ever been fucking comfortable?
Have you ever been fucking comfortable
with so much sitting there with you when
you're riding in a car? All that
says is I am brand new at driving,
or I am lost,
or I am currently being abducted
and being forced to drive this car.
That's what having your hands get fucking
tenant to system me as a passenger by
see somebody up there, you know,
they fucking lean to the, you know,
leaning on the door,
even if it's unlocked,
I don't give a shit that drive like two
fingers. I'm like, all right, this person,
he or she, you know, they got this.
I see somebody fucking, you know,
tended to when then you start moving your
head towards the windshield, forget it.
It's fucking over. Um, that's
like, is that a media, you know,
I just have one of the greatest
cab drivers I've ever had.
Now being up here in Portland,
Oregon at the beginning of my, uh,
my tour here as fu, basically Oregon, um,
California.
Um,
it's mostly California and
Oregon, by the way. Not Oregon.
All right? They don't like that
up here. They don't like that.
They don't like deodorant,
right?
They don't like not dressing like you're
on little house on the prairie is all
kinds of things that they
don't like up here, but they,
they liked their food fresh.
They like to keep it weird or
whatever the hell they doing up here.
If they're keeping it weird with a fucking
Chase Manhattan Bank right downtown.
Oh, they're keeping it weird out here
in Portland. Is that a men's warehouse?
God, it, this place is weird.
Corporations will always eat your way in.
I swear to God,
everybody joined a fucking cult and left
civilization within fucking 20 minutes.
These corporate clients would figure it
out and they'd figured out how to get a
fucking a cult look at best buy
in there. They disguise it, right?
They make this sign, the color, a corn
and grass sprinkled little fucking,
you know, sprays out like Pachulia Isam,
Shit. They'd figure out how to do it.
But anyways, they had this
great, uh, cab driver, um,
and the way from the airport over to
the hotel, you know, he's talking,
he had a thick accent.
So I asked him where he was from and he
was Armenian and he was from Russia. So,
uh, I always, you know, anybody
could speak a different language. Um,
I'm fascinated by,
so I just start talking to the guy and
somehow we started talking about cursing
and our own languages and this
guy was fucking hilarious.
Like he was talking to him, he said, he's
like, oh shit, it's more, it's more like,
I said, how do you say, go fuck
yourself. He goes, what does the,
it's not like you say, go fuck
yourself, and he was a good America.
It's all about fuck fucking and
everything. You know, fuck you. Fuck you,
go fuck yourself.
What the fuck is that?
He was saying all that shit where
he says in Russia it's more like,
do I sound like Yakov Smirnoff in an Asha?
Um,
it's more, um, like they act,
they don't say go fuck yourself.
They say go sit on deck.
Which I like, that sounds very
rushing. Go sit on Dick. I must break.
You have to sit on Dick. Right? Then
they have another one a instead of say,
what the fuck is that? Their translation
is, what kind of deck is this?
Like basically, you know,
I know I'm getting fucked.
What's going down here? And they don't,
they don't call anybody a motherfucker or,
and they don't say, go fuck your
mother. They will say fuck his mother.
But it basically means it's
not like saying, you know,
somebody goes and has sex with his mother.
What it really means is fuck his mother
for doing such a horrible job raising
this fucking asshole that
we all have to deal with,
which I think is actually a little more
intellectual then have fuck your mother.
You know, like imagine somebody
banging your mom. I mean,
that's definitely disgusting.
But to say, fuck his mother,
like because she did such a horrific job,
you know,
fuck your mother for raising you.
It's such a horrible way, that net,
we're now having this conversation
or you're doing this to me.
I thought that was one of my
favorites that I've heard. Uh,
that was one of my
favorites. Um, so anyways,
I am up here and he had all these
fucking, he was fascinating like, well,
just to listen to him talking
like he grew up in Russia,
so he's not into the whole
democracy thing. Like he,
I was like, well, do you think what to
free over here? And he was like, yeah,
I can't do his accent.
He basically said we were too free and
that there's fucking chaos over here.
And he started, he goes the other day
and he's here in Portland. He goes,
they see this,
this man 28 years old and he's dressed
like a five year old child and the 1920s,
you know,
he's like,
this man is not a leader of this man's
not a head of a household. And I'm dying,
laughing, going, I'm going, you
mean hipsters? And he's like, yeah.
And he was just saying how the kid was,
was not fit to run anything to run the
country to be in a business or when it
was the one of the funniest fucking
takes. I've heard on hipsters, you know,
not saying it was right,
but just his perception of it.
And he said that coming from where
he came from, he likes having a king.
You know that someone has the balls.
Jesus do you know,
to lead people. And he
actually liked George W. Bush.
She said he wasn't the smartest guys,
but he had balls. He was like, fuck you,
I'm doing this. Which I couldn't argue.
I was not a fan of George W. Bush,
but I always had to respect the fact
that that guy did not give a shit.
He's not on. Now we're going
to do it. Getting there. We
can fight tear. It's like,
dude, you really don't, uh, I don't know.
You don't really have an exit strategy.
I don't give a fuck. I'm fucking
going in there. Right. Um,
okay.
But anyways,
this guy was actually into a having a
king and all of that type of shit and that
it just, I don't know, fucking
blew my mind listening to that.
I've never heard anybody saying,
you know what, we're to free.
It's really weird and I
don't want to do that.
I probably shouldn't have said that.
He was,
it was actually Armenian living in Russia.
I don't want to fucking get
everybody all going again.
You know about the whole
fucking USA Russia thing.
Did that end than the and already
or does it start back up again?
I don't fucking know. All I know is I'm
important Portland, Oregon, and I'm,
you know, this morning I had a hole,
I had a screw up with my itinerary.
I thought I was going to lax
at like fucking, you know,
one o'clock in the afternoon and it
turned out I was flying out of Burbank at
nine 30.
I discovered this.
It's 757 in the morning about ready to
do the Thursday afternoon podcast here.
And uh,
okay.
So I fucking,
that's why I don't have a microphone
cause I threw all my podcast shit and I
forgot to put the microphone in.
So I apologize for the bad quality.
I'm going to try to
stop off at a good task.
Okay.
And buy one. If I can find a local mom
and pop music store, I would do that.
I just tried to find one within walking
distance and it was close for good,
it said so. But anyways, so, um,
even with that driving over to Burbank
and fucking rushing through the airport
and everything, I'm beyond excited to, uh,
to go on this tour and it made me
Amy site, you know, then I, you know,
if you have a shit day and you're
still excited to go to work, you, you,
you're doing the right job I think.
Anyways, but, um, so anyways,
what the fuck am I rambling?
A buff.
Okay.
I Dunno.
I'm a
okay.
What the fuck is with my brain tape? My
brain is all over the place. What they,
I want to talk about Donald Trump.
There we go.
I don't have my list in front of you and
you've got a couple of subjects to keep
me rolling here.
Um,
did you guys see Donald Trump
talking about how that he wanted to,
when he's going to run for a run for
office here, president, the United States.
How fucking stupid was that announcement?
The way he drew it out like
everyone was going to be excited.
So I am announcing
my candidacy
for the president of the United States
or mistake. We got it Donald. We got it.
We got it. Okay, we understand. All right,
you're going to be running
like this is like a good thing.
I've seen guys like
this run my entire life,
these guys who were just like,
oh I got a ton of fucking money and I'm
just going to go in there and it's like,
no dude, you're going to get
the shit kicked out of you.
You're going to get the shit kicked out
of you because you're going to be going
up a venture,
a bunch of guys Smiley's that are already
bought and paid for and those are the
guys that are going to get in.
But just listening to him talk,
like he went on the O'Reilly factor
and Bill O'reilly's going like,
how are you going to stop isis?
Which of course is always the
big question in this country.
How are we going to stop isis?
Fuck these people that you know are
fucking with our food supply right here in
the United States. Fuck these people that
are, you know, want a private taze wider.
Yeah.
Those guys aren't that big a threat.
Let's go after these clients
all the way over here, right.
That are bankrupting us. So anyways,
sorry for the politics. So right.
This is just my own ignorant
point of view. All right.
And I finally found someone
of some dumber than me,
which is fucking Donald Trump.
So they ask him was, he goes,
so how are you going to get him? He goes,
I would hit them so hard. It would egos.
I would find the right general,
I would find my patent or Eisenhower
and I would hit them so hard.
It would make your head spin. Right. He
just sounds like somebody at a bar. Like,
I hope he hangs in there long enough or
get a good six months side of this shit.
Right? And they, so bill
O'Reilly's going like,
so you're going to send in ground troops
and he, is that what you're telling me?
And Donald Goes, I'm not going
to tell you what I'm going to do.
I got to keep it a secret.
Right. Which I'm like, Eh,
it wasn't a bad answer and
that he, O'Reilly keeps
pressing him. He goes, so eat.
So you're going to, but some point you'd
have to send in ground troops, right?
You will be sending in ground troops
and it finally just caves. He goes, no,
I wouldn't. And then a writer was
like, well, what would you do? He goes,
I bombed the hell out of him.
I got to tell you something.
Once again,
Donald Trump has proven that you have
to be literally out of your fucking mind
to either want to be president,
run for president,
anything at all for him to just
so just casually, just Sam,
I'm going to bomb the hell out of them.
You know?
I would think that that would be like,
even if you knew that that's
what she had to do, that,
that that's a hell of a fucking
thing to have to say. You know,
cause you know,
not all of those bombs are going to
land on the people you're trying to hit
someone we're going to land on some
mother feeding a baby in the end that's
going to be on your conscience
for the rest of your fucking life,
even if it was the right thing to fucking
do. So you, you try to like, I dunno,
I guess choose your words more carefully
or maybe it's refreshing that he just
had bombed the hell out of him.
You know,
he should literally just been stuff on
a sandwich in his fucking mouth as he's
taught, not Fucko. I kick the shit out of
him. I didn't really know fucking balls,
just speaking in like, just
total generality. I mean,
he sounded like he was doing a podcast.
He didn't, you know, he sounded like me.
MMM.
I Dunno. But you know, he did all
right in the hair plug department.
Remember when he was doing that?
Psycho fucking flock of sea gulls comb
over that he was doing that thing has
disappeared. Let's give it up to
the people who make hair plugs.
They're really doing a hell of a job.
You know, they started off horrifically
mmm.
Or whatever. The hair transplant. I
think Elton John got like the first one.
He's been wearing wigs ever since. Like
his top of his head looked like Bobby.
Yours. Nice. By the time they
were done with it. And um,
so now you said the where that
little pageboy haircut. Yeah.
For the rest of the time,
you know, poor fella,
all he wanted was hair.
You know,
now he's got to have that little
little fucking, yeah, we're gone.
Just goes a little stubby fucking
fingers trying to reach those keys.
Got a little fat,
you know.
So a lot to feel bad about when you
look it out. John, poor guy, you know,
they're a little too much coke,
right?
One on one on MTV unplugged,
a little coked up in a very
unfortunate fucking a running suit.
Why am I talking about him? Oh,
let's get back to Donald Trump case.
So the 90s right.
Then they went with the fucking ant leg.
Once you remember though at the insect
like ones where you just couldn't stop
looking at it, it was literally
like sewn into your fucking head.
People used to call it doll hair.
MMM.
And now they've gotten to the
point where they just sort of,
they sort of sprinkle it in.
I think they take it off the back,
the vacuum mount out of the back and then
they put it on a tray and then like a
fairy comes by and just takes the tray
and skips around your head going Chareau
la La. And they drop it in and
it looks very natural evidently.
But then what happens is,
is those ones I guess can survive whatever
hell is going on beneath the scalp.
But the other ones that weren't
built for it, they still fall out.
So then you got it. You got to think
you've got to get receipted again.
I Dunno,
I'm still holding out for
the fucking pill until then.
I'm going to keep buzzing my head.
That'd be fucking hilarious.
It's like eight years.
They come out with a pill,
right to cure baldness and
all of a sudden guys like me,
we come back from for the fucking Mr
Clean look to come back looking like we're
in the bgs.
Right.
Ah,
that'd be fucking hilarious.
I would actually be willing
to take the risk on that one,
which is really fucked up cause you
know that it would do some sort of
unbelievable damage to your liver. There's
no, there's no fucking way. I mean,
you fucker with Mother Nature,
aren't you? I mean you can't.
That's the fucked up thing about plastic
surgery and everything is your really,
your, your face, your
hairline becomes a lie.
You know, if you're young enough,
especially, you know what I mean?
And people looking at you like,
and they are attracted to who you aren't.
You don't what I mean?
Like what if it's the nose that just gets
the person go and then that's not your
real nose. Then you bang and
you have a kid. You're like,
what the fuck happened to that kid's nose?
Did you cheat on me?
Hey [inaudible] your fucking whore.
And then she takes out a fucking
high school year book was like, no,
this is what I really look like.
You know?
And every time your kid starts walking
towards you, what? That's crooked nose.
You can be thinking like fucking
bitch lied to me, you know,
which will affect your child rearing.
One of the weirdest fucking words
ever. It's just, I don't know.
Was that before they realize
that pedophiles existed,
that somebody came up with a, what's a
good word for raising your child? I Dunno.
Rearing. Um, anyways. Oh,
in the world of Sports,
Sports, Sports, sports, sport,
congratulations to the
Chicago Blackhawks and the,
uh,
golden state or Sacramento is,
I call them golden state
warriors on their championships.
A opposite things. There. One
was a so called dynasty, which
it isn't, which it isn't.
All right. And then the other was the, uh,
a team that hadn't won in like a 37 years.
Is that what they said?
I should know this
Celtics one in 74 and 76.
So the warriors one in 75, 40
fucking years. 41 seasons maybe.
Is that what it, is that how it works
out? I don't fucking know. Um, oh,
basketballs hard. By the
way. 74 was the Celtics.
75 was a warrior is 76 was a Celtics.
77 was Portland.
78 was the bullets.
79 was Seattle supersonics
with the young Dennis Johnson.
Rest his soul. 1980 was the
Lakers. 81 was the Celtics. 82
it was the Lakers.
83 was the 70 sixers.
84 was the Celtics.
85 was the Lakers. All that when killed
when Kareem sank that Skyhawk any,
any fucking,
you know,
he did that double fist thing as he was
running down the court and they were
going to beat the Celtics and there and
they were going to drink champagne in
the Boston garden, which had never been
done. Uh Oh my God, that was brutal.
86 was a Celtics.
87 80 it was the Lakers ain't no weight.
87 was Lakers.
Then it went back to back and then Detroit
went back to back and then it was the
Michael Jordan shelf for three
years and then Houston for two.
Then Jordan for three and then the
spurs and I think fucking Lakers,
one three. I don't fucking remember.
Anyways, sorry. Got sidetracked there.
By the way, Black Hawks, you don't
have a fucking dynasty. Okay.
How much more lax or are we going
to get with the term dynasty?
When I was a kid, when I was a lad,
when I had a full eto, orange hair,
um, a dynasty was winning three
in a row. The early seventies.
Oakland ace was a dynasty,
the late seventies,
Montreal Canadians,
the early eighties
islanders was a dynasty.
All right. I'm trying to
think. Nobody is ever,
but the Steelers when in four and six
years, that was considered a dynasty too.
So I dunno then I'm remember when the
Patriots won that we won three and four
years and people will go,
well,
it's a dynasty because of the
salary cap and the boob tube.
And I still didn't buy into that,
but,
and so then three and four years became
a dynasty when you had to win three in a
row or four at a six to now,
just three and four.
And now 10 years after that.
Now if you win three and six years,
you're considered a dynasty,
which is so fucking stupid.
All right?
And I'll tell you why,
because the kings have one two times.
So they want to,
when the Black Hawks have three,
I mean the dynasty is you have 1:00 AM
all three years in a row and everybody
else has got a fucking goose egg.
That's how I look at it.
All right? I'm just a freckled old
man here though. I still believe that.
I'm not trying to take anything
away from the Blackhawks,
what they've done with the free agency
and all that, you know, without a doubt.
It's fucking amazing.
And I love the Blackhawks,
even though they fucking crushed me.
If he'd couple of years ago when they
beat the Bruins. All right? But you know,
come on, three and six fucking
years. Why don't you just, what?
When we get to the point of, hey, you're
one three, that's a fucking dynasty.
It isn't not a dynasty.
All right?
You got something going
on called you got to,
you got a horrible case of
the every others. All right?
You want it in 2010 on Oh yeah.
Every others is the giants.
Baseball giants. They wanted 10 12
and 14 isn't that what they did?
Yeah, they got a horrible case
of the every others. All right.
Which can only be cured by when in fucking
three in a row and shutting jackasses
like me. Right. The fuck up.
All right. But I don't think,
I don't think three and
six years as a dynasty,
even with free agency and all of
that fucking horse shit. I don't,
I think he got to win.
You got to win three in a row or we'll
give you the asterix three and four years.
Or if he won four and six years, like
the Steelers, I'll give it to you,
but three and six years when someone
else want to like now what happens if the
fucking kings when it next year
and then they want three, right.
And then is it overlapping dynasties
that occurred at the same fucking time?
You see what I'm saying?
This is like that movie faceoff well
you don't know who's nick cage and who's
John Travolta at that point.
You can't have that. All right.
And who else want during that time?
The fucking Bro. That's right.
The Boston Bruins won a Stanley Cup.
You know what I love about
them winning the Stanley Cup?
Is everyone in Boston just about except
for newborn babies knows what it's feel.
Feels like. Dab your team, win
a Stanley Cup in. Meanwhile,
up in Montreal,
despite all of this success,
there's an entire generation and a half
has no fucking idea what that's like and
that I swear to God
makes me smile every day.
Um, I'm fucking with you. Montreal.
He a bunch of sensitive conch.
All right.
I like your language and I'm
going to learn how to fucking,
I'm gonna go and do a lingo. Maybe I'll
fuck with that over the next couple,
a couple of hours before my show up
here in Portland, Oregon. Jesus. Bill,
can you tell us a little bit more
about your tour? Well, I would love to,
after I read out loud with these,
with the following message,
this fucking Internet would work.
Here we go. All right. All right.
Right out of the bat. This sounds
fucking creepy to me. Video Doorbell.
Uh, we'll insert dinging
sound. What does that mean?
I was supposed to fucking insert ding.
Dongs. All right, let's do it again. Uh,
I can do this. Here we go. Doorbell.
Yeah.
Sound.
This is like Donald Trump announcing
he's running for president doorbell.
Sound effect. Did you meet
doorbell? All one word.
Of course I did.
I'll see if I can do this correctly.
All right. Hey everybody. Video Doorbell.
Let's do that again. Oh, I'm at and all
kinds of layers to the podcast here.
Hang on a second. It's got a
fucking, uh, it's gotta reload here.
Hey everybody. I'd like to take a
little bit of time to talk about, yeah,
video doorbell. What is really
odd? I was the shit video doorbell.
This is the sound of a package
being delivered or friends
coming over for dinner.
But it's also the sound of summing plants.
Someone planning to rob you blind.
Jesus Christ.
I took a left turn then it over 90,
95% of home breakins happened
during the day and I write the way.
Is it, what's going on here? Oh,
I think I'm stuck in one of those youtube
loops where they just keep playing the
fucking the doorbell. Well, I
think it works with the copy.
I'm going to keep it anyways,
and burglars always almost always
start by ringing the doorbell to see if
someone's home before
pillaging your possessions.
I guess that's a fancier doorbell.
Yeah.
I like this
music too with ring video doorbell.
You can see and talk to anyone
from anywhere in the world
using your smartphone. Hi,
I'm bill per, what's happening?
It's just a DJ party.
MMM,
okay.
I think we're having a fire alert here.
Back to the copy rings.
Advanced motion detection alerts you,
even if someone doesn't ring the doorbell,
it's like a caller id for your home.
You know,
millions of people suffer every year
and they don't have a video doorbell.
Please share a personal story how this
could help you or someone you love. Hey,
will you share a pocket person's story?
You content isn't enough.
I'm reading your copy. I
don't know anybody who has a
video of fucking doorbells.
How does that work for you? Then
she's story. You look at another one,
I'm sorry.
It's sealing.
Ring takes minutes and it works with
either your current wiring built in
rechargeable battery.
Put your mind at ease and
protect your home and your Perry.
Keep with the video doorbell Time magazine
named one of the top 10 gadgets of
2014 Sheridan Kilmore porpoises cause
then eventually you'd have to throw out
the wires and they will
end up in the ocean.
The right now my listeners get the
ring video doorbell for only $174.
That's $25 off the normal price. Still
kind of expensive though. You know,
door fucking house comes with
the doorbell already attached.
He's still making payments.
Anyways,
go to ring.com/burnout protect your
home and at peace of mind with ring.
Go to ring.com/square for $25 off.
Once again,
that's [inaudible] dot com slash
oh and it fades out the music,
Jesus Christ. That could be a DJ,
but a fucking mouse had on
me and see what happens.
I'll tell you what will happen, Huh?
Bunch of drugs will be taken. Um,
how much can I freak out
people that one of those rapes,
if you just had the DJ and he's clean,
all this mellow shit,
then all of a sudden out of nowhere I
just started coming out with a mouse head
screaming Khan to over and over again.
Okay.
I would love to have an
overhead shot of that, you know,
maybe using one of those drones and just
watching them all scatter like fucking
roaches all across the desert.
Stepping on side.
Winders um,
anyways,
what else did I want to
talk about? Oh, an ant,
ant man, Bam, Bam, Bam, Bam, Bam.
I got my truck back.
Yeah,
I got my fucking truck back. Sorry.
Sorry for the big intro there. Um,
my truck a,
I had some fucking issues with it and
I finally just decided to have him pull
the engine and Redo the whole fucking
thing. It runs on unleaded gas.
I don't have to do any additive anymore
and it's running a fucking like a
bastard. You in Boston there, it's
running fucking strong as shit.
And um, we ordered the air
conditioning and the power steering.
It's going to be my fucking daily
driver because right now I don't know if
you've ever fucking tried to turn the
wheel when there's no power steering,
you do that.
And like a fucking 83 toilets herself,
which is the last one I ever drove
that didn't have power steering. Um,
that's a bitch.
This fucking f 100.
I'm literally out of breath and when I
try to parallel park and then the anxiety,
you have somebody behind me,
it takes like fucking,
I swear to God it takes me like seven
minutes to park the fucking thing. So, um,
I was going to be one of those
purists where I was like,
I'm going to keep it the way it was when
it rolled off the assembly line in 1968
and then I just realized like, you know
what? It was meant to be on a farm.
It's now in Los Angeles. Okay.
I already added, um, you know,
put some disc brakes on the front.
I am a guide and make this thing safe.
I fucking love it though,
man.
I got to tell you the
suspension that was fucked up.
You go over a bump on that thing, you
know, it's like, it just starts rocking.
And you know, if you don't have your seat
belt on, you literally hit your head.
And I was talking to,
um,
the guy worked on my truck about possibly
putting in an updated suspension and
he was saying, well, I'd have to lower
it like two or three inches. And I, I,
I fucking hate that man. I don't like
those trucks that are lower down, man. I,
I like, I like it that it rides up
a little high. Um, so I'm willing,
I only have three gears on in any way.
So how fast am I going to be driving?
So I think, um, I think
I'm done messing with it,
but, uh, I got a couple more
things I have to get done on it.
I don't have my direction most right now,
but once I get the power steering
and then the air conditioning,
I think gold daddy is going to move on
to trying to find a 65 galaxy that's a,
got a straight body and everything
else is fucked up on it. And, uh,
and I'm actually going to get that
thing with automatic transmission.
I was thinking about
having a, a, a stick in it.
I've always liked driving a standard.
I just think it's cool man.
You feel like you're driving
the fucking car, you know?
Okay.
I Dunno. I'm just sad, grumpy go. I'm
not dumb. Just like grumpy old man.
Like now the cars are
going to drive themselves.
It's like why the fuck would you want
to do that? And then you know what?
You don't,
what's going to happen?
Everybody's going to be on their
fucking iPhones and reading and stuff.
And Are you going to see going down the
street is people hanging their heads out
of these cars in the drive to they're
not driving puking out decide cause
everybody's car sick.
That'll be the next thing that
somebody will sell for 1995.
It will be like these fucking,
you know,
one size fits all curtains that you
can fucking wrap all the way around the
inside your car so you can read while
it's driving and not get sick or fucking
jerk off of our have sex with somebody.
Right. What the fuck do you
care? You know what I mean?
You know what's funny about that is the,
the liability that the automakers
will somehow get off of themselves.
It'll somehow still be your fucking fault.
And the insurance companies still won't
pay you when the car that was supposed
to drive by itself just stops working.
Dude.
How many times a week does your,
does your laptop crash?
How good are these computers are going
to be that I'm just going to just get in
this fucking thing that has no
conductor, no pilot, no nothing.
I'm just sitting in this fucking thing.
The cars going 40 miles an hour and
so's my brain in my skull physics.
It's going as fast as the car and
when the car smashes into the tree,
that's what my brain does to the
front of my skull and goes back again.
And then what happens? Huh? What
happens? Like a good neighbor?
I go fuck yourself. That's what, that's
what the insurance covers companies
will do. Um, I'm not into
that at all, man. I am into,
my phone is ringing here.
The fuck is this. Well,
I don't know who that is because you don't
have a phone. No Id. I don't pick up.
Um, I'm actually bullshit and
I'll pick it up after this. Uh,
what's this podcast is
over. So anyways, um,
I'm so fucking excited to
do this guide down tour.
I'm going to so many cities
that have never been to before.
I've been to Portland
before a bunch of times.
Actually back in the day I
used to work Harvey's um,
comedy club and a, and the last
time I was here I worked helium.
Um, I did a bunch of colleges up
here before he used to do cuse bay,
like every other year I
would go down there, um,
and after I do Portland and I just,
I just blow all the way through fucking
California and all these places.
I never been to Sacramento. I've been
there before. I'm there on the 19th,
and I go to Reno,
which had been there before.
I'm going to go to bizarre
guitar and gunshop. Um,
and then I'm back to California
and I play Santa Rosa.
Never been there doing two shows there.
And according to the people,
that's the last place George
Carlin performed at before.
Unfortunately he passed away. Well I'm
doing one show, sorry, one show that um,
on June 21st, so that's going
to be a, an unbelievable night.
Then on the 20 seconds I'm in San Jose.
Then when Fresno never been to
Fresno at the Warners theater though,
I said the warriors theater, I was like
that, that's a cool fucking name. Uh,
then I'm in Bakersfield. Never
been there. I've driven through it.
He stopped and got gas,
never fucking hung out there.
And then I'm in a Highland
California on the 25th for two shows,
Denim in Vegas at the Mirage.
And then I'm in Tucson.
I mean it's just going to be a fucking
awesome talk at a really bad ass poster.
Once again, kind of making
fun of the drought out here.
I too actually retweeted
a copy of it. Um, and,
um,
I'm just really looking forward to this,
getting this fucking hour up to speed so
I can murder with it, you know, cause, uh,
this time last year I, I taped, uh,
I'm sorry you feel that way. So Marty,
uh,
the clock is ticking.
Sometime next year I will
tape another special and um,
it's what I plan on doing for
the rest of my career because a,
I don't know why I still love
doing this shit 23 years in.
I should not be excited to be
going to Fresno and Bakersfield,
but I am because I've traveled enough to
know that I'm going to meet some people
out there and they're going
to tell me some places to eat,
like people make fun of
Reno and then you go there.
And that bizarre guitar and gunshot
thing just fucking blew me away.
And that's only one thing that I saw
there. And then I drove over to the,
what's that fucking lakes
that's over there? You know,
where Michael Coler Corleone
had frayed a whacked,
I went over there and got a great burger.
Was it Lake Tahoe?
Um, I'm really fascinated with
that part of the country and, um,
I know that I said I was going to do
Eureka in and end up falling through,
but I'm definitely going to come back up.
I might even just come up for the day
and fly my lovely wife up. And um,
then I was thinking and drive him back
down, checking out the redwood forest,
going to maybe wine country is some
shit like that. Um, but uh, you know,
it's a beautiful state.
Fortunately there's not a lot
of water out here, but uh,
you know, who knows, it
might fall into the ocean.
One day I might be on the road and I
won't die with the state and I can tell
people when I got older,
I remember I tore down whole stack
and kids will sit there wide eyed is,
I described places like Fresno
and San Jose, Sacramento, right.
Taking all of them for granted.
I could tell him that I went there,
I went there and I went
to the FDF fucking uh, uh,
what is that fucking Mexican restaurant
at a Mcdonald's zones. You know,
they got the burrito bowls,
so was trying to pick something mainstream
and not do the usual Wendy's and
Mcdonald's.
I Love Mcdonald's is now freaking out.
If they're actually using
real meat. It's like, really,
what the fuck were you using before?
They'll never answer that question. Um,
all right. This was the Thursday
afternoon podcast just before Monday,
just before Friday. Sorry,
the judge [inaudible] podcast.
I want to thank all you
guys for listening. Um,
there's gonna be another 30 minutes here.
It's some throwbacks to some classic
Horse Shit that I talked way back in the
day. Um, thank you to everybody before
even do this tour. Everybody who shows up,
um, I can't fucking wait and I'm, and
I'm working with Joe Barton. Nick,
I never did a bus tour
with Joe Voir. Nick, um,
one of my favorite
people on stage and off.
We're going to have a
great time and a hey,
as weak as we roll through
your cities and stuff,
let us know some cool places
to get dinner or lunch,
a good place to go grab a drink
or something. Um, or whatever.
If you've got something weird that we
got to go see, like I know in Tucson,
Arizona, I want to visit
that, that, that, uh,
airplane graveyard that they have.
I got a fucking hit that,
um,
I want to see some crazy shit like that.
I don't want to go to some fucking malls
or Cineplex horseshit that I can do in
my own town. So tell me something
unique, something fucking weird.
If you know a bartender with the fucked
up by or a weird way of clearing his
throat, just something
unique about where you live,
please let us know and we'll try to hit
as many as we can. All right. That's it.
Have a great weekend. And uh, that's it.
Yeah. Have a good weekend. Your constant,
let's see.
I'll get some advice.
Somebody wants a bill.
My girlfriend looks like a
centerfold. Good for you. She's blind.
She has a beautiful face,
a tiny waist and giant cans.
I have outdone myself. What, what the
fuck, man, don't sell yourself short.
Maybe you're, maybe you're a,
you're a stud. So he says, however,
having a girlfriend of such caliber,
as you might imagine,
comes with its share of problems.
Ooh, Jesus. Here we go. Like,
uh, like your good self.
I battle my battle,
keeping my temper under control at
times and particularly struggle when my
girlfriend and I go out in
public together. In short,
the amount of male attention she
gets is ridiculous and at times it's
infuriating.
Have you ever found you found yourself
out with a girl and notice that every man
within a three mile radius from the
sweaty 22 year old walking boner to the
porky,
sexually frustrated father of three is
blatantly staring at her tits in her ass?
Um, I've always been of the opinion
that if a girl is obviously with a guy,
whether you know him or not,
it's a gentleman's code not to
have a staring contest with their,
with her, with their ring piece.
I don't know what that means.
What does that look into her pussy? I have
no idea. This guys from Australia. Um,
if a girl there's alone
or with girlfriends, sure.
Objectify the shit out of her.
But I think if a girl is holding hands
with their boyfriend and you make it
obvious that your helmet is pressing
against the inside of your front Zipper,
then you're a cunt. Um, nothing
serious has happened yet,
but the weather is getting warmer.
The outfits are getting smaller and I'm
concerned I'm going to wind up with,
I'm going to wind up with some perverts
blood and quite possibly come on my
hands all for now. Um, all right.
All right. This is a tricky
situation, sir. You know,
it's a very tricky situation.
You know,
there's a price you pay for everything.
All right? You're the one who,
who has the center fold fucking
girlfriend with a great ass,
nice set of fucking tits and
a, you just, you just have to,
okay,
this, this, this is, this
is how I look at this shit.
As long as you're,
a woman isn't going around trying to
get attention if she's just fucking
standing there and she's so goddamn
stunning that men are looking at her,
but you know, she's not, oh,
I dropped my lipstick and then slowly
bending over at the waist while looking
over her shoulder. Um,
if she's doing that,
I can tell you right now a banger
another couple of times and then fucking
dumper because she's going to be an
absolute fucking nightmare. And a,
you don't need that in your life. Okay.
But if she's just a stunning league,
gorgeous woman, um, you,
that kind of comes with it.
And,
uh,
if you lose your fucking temper
and you start acting like a maniac,
that's a great way to eventually
annoy the shit out of her.
And because she can't help
it. Like I said, if she's
not trying to get attention,
she can't help it, that
she's gorgeous. And, uh,
if you then,
it's in this weird way,
you're giving her shit for being herself,
which is not fun for anybody,
and then you're going to have a problem.
So.
Okay.
Um, I don't know how to it. You
know what it's like. It's like a,
it's like when I whore myself out at
the end of my shows and I sell DVDs.
All right?
I don't have to do that,
but I choose to do it and I'm
standing as a choice. I fucking made.
And then I stand there and what's
going to happen? I answered this. Yeah.
This is one of these podcasts questions.
All right.
Eventually somebody is going to come up
and they're going to fucking insult me.
He's telling me they didn't
like my act. Tell me. Uh,
they didn't think I was as funny as
when he saw me on TV and I can't get mad
because it's my fucking fault for
standing there like an asshole.
Just, you know, I, I put myself on the
Dunkin stool and I got to admit, sir, if,
if you're, if this, if your girl
is the way that you describe her,
you just have to accept that it's,
it's par for the course and, uh,
just give yourself a little halftime
speech before you go out. You know,
I'm not going to lose my shit. Um, but
if it is overt,
uh,
that has to be a way that you can fucking
address it without pissing her off,
without you. And you also don't want
to get into a fucking fight. Um,
I dunno. Just say, hey buddy, can,
can you limit it to like, you know,
five second shifts of staring
at her tea and I can't say tits.
Okay.
I don't know what you do too. That's,
that's a rough one. That's a rough run.
The man that takes me back to being a,
okay.
Jesus Christ. I was like 21
years old. I went on this,
I went out on a date with this girl who
was well out of my fucking league just
because I didn't have the confidence to
fucking be with her, you know, I mean, um,
beautiful girl.
And I went out with her and I noticed
she just kept looking around the
restaurant to see who was looking at her.
And I remembered it annoyed
the shit out of me, but I,
I didn't have any experience
with beautiful women, so I
just sort of accepted it.
And, um, but I never went out with her
again. It just, it drove it. I, it,
I tapped out somewhere
through the fucking dinner.
Even back then I was an angry
son of a bitch. I was like,
let me get this straight.
I'm buying you fucking dinner and
you're looking around to see who's Elsa
staring at your tits.
Um, yeah, you're a cunt.
Good looking cunt. But uh, nonetheless,
someday those looks are going to be gone
and I'm just going to be left with the
cunt.
You know who's going to be a psycho cunt
because you're an attention whore and
when the attention goes away,
you're going to be like some celebrity
who fell off the fucking math,
fucked his bitch. Fuck this. You know?
And that was the end.
[inaudible]
Shit.
That's probably cases fucking
all
right.
Question out there about, you know,
things that happen within society,
especially,
this is something that I think a lot of
white people need because not because
we're more racist than anybody else,
we just get just the,
the consequences of us fucking up is so
much harsher than other people because,
you know, we are the gold
standard when it comes to racist.
We are in the driver's seat right now.
We have been in the driver's seat
for awhile, basically beating that.
If we are ignorant ass holes, it has way
more effect than when other people are.
You know, back in the day
when other people were running
shit. That's the thing.
Whoever's on top, if you
thinking ignorant, uh, that's
what, that's why, you know,
if you're on top and you're
thinking ignorant shit,
you have to be called on it because,
uh,
just cause he cause the effect that
you can have. You know what I mean?
Okay.
Like if somebody from Bangladesh fucking
hates me, that's such a stupid example.
Okay. That, that's not a race of people.
I don't even know what Bangladesh's
and I gotta be honest with you.
I don't even know if
that's a city or a country.
Bangladesh have ever seen
that on the prices, right?
Yeah.
I want to showcase showdown with selling
yet a Bangladesh and some white trash
person like myself to sit with a
confused look on their face. Like yeah,
I don't know where that is.
Is that where the terrorists are?
I don't want to go there. Whatever,
like a Filipino people fucking hate me.
That doesn't affect my life.
It doesn't,
I'm not going to go and
do a job interview at,
at Walmart is not run by Filipinos.
So you know what I mean?
You know, not saying there's anything
wrong with Filipinos. All right. See,
we'll see what I have to do with
there's white person. They'll say,
I'm saying I do bad about
Filipino because we clear hair. I,
I've never had issues.
I've got to have a valve of Catherine.
I'll fucking all that shit. You got to go
to the Jerry Lewis voice there lady. Um,
so yeah, people have
questions. So here we go.
And I think all racist should shy men.
The questions that you have,
if you have feelings about a different
race of people and you just think about,
you're thinking something funny, there's
nothing malicious, but is this offensive?
Is it racist? This is, this
is the new topic. Okay.
And if you feel that I answered these
questions like the ignorant white man that
I am, uh, call me out on it. I'm
here. So here we go. This first one,
Bill,
is it racist to call Indians,
Dibble Dab.
And I'm talking about the Asian ones,
not native Americans,
I'm guessing by Dib and Dab as
you mean Dubai Dhabi or Dubai.
October to move it the,
but you're saying like that debit Dabu um,
is it racist? Probably,
but it's fucking funny.
So that knocks it down a little bit.
This is what I feel that makes
something like racist. It's like,
like the reason why,
uh,
that one isn't as offensive
is because we haven't,
we never enslaved them. That's the
reason why white and black should,
is so sensitive is because of
the shift that we did to him.
But we haven't really fuck
with those people. You know?
So if the black version of that was,
is it,
is it offensive to black people?
Hey man, mother fucker or whatever.
Yes.
That would be offensive if you did some
sort of mocking of the way they spoke.
Yes.
That would be,
that would be offensive if some CEO was
giving a speech and I was driving, uh,
actually I was having someone else drive
my town car and we drove by a group of
a y'all mother fuckers and uh,
they proceeded to walk towards the gas.
You'd have to apologize. So I guess, yeah,
I guess technically Duma
Dabo like that would be,
that would be offensive. Is it racist? Um,
this is what I, I really, I really,
it's hard for me to say because it had,
it's what's in your heart, you
know, cause I make fuck I really,
I make fun of, of everybody, you know,
I mean, I play a game out here, uh,
when someone is make, let me ask you, I've
got a question for you. Is this racist?
I have a game out here when I ride around
with Nia and she does not approve of
this to keep her in the clear,
she does not approve this.
When somebody makes a more ronic
move in front of me, you know,
driving, you know, just makes
a fucking horrific move.
I play a game called old or Asian
and you have to guess why cause I'm going
to pass the person cause I got to see
what they look like. You know, whenever
somebody does something fucked up,
some committees do a
great joke about that.
You just want to see what the fuck they
look like. Right. Uh, that's the game.
Older Asian. So as I speed up my little
hybrid to try to pull parallel to them,
I always say, what do you say, Nia?
What are you going with all the regime?
What do you got? Older Asian. She goes,
I'm not playing this game. That's mean.
And then I was going, I'm going to
go with the old and then I pull up,
oh it's fucking Asian, you know? Or
Oh I nailed it. It was an old guy.
So, um, is that racist?
I'm sure it's offensive,
but within the context of my own car,
you know,
I'm not yelling at anybody
and I got to admit, you know,
there's a lot of truth in
the fucking game, not Jesus.
I'm going to have to apologize next week
on the podcast. So I would say that, uh,
uh, Indian people, why don't you
chime in? I would say that, yeah,
that they would find that they
would find that offensive. Um,
is it racist? Let me see if I
can use it in a sentence here.
Hey, uh, you know, I called up
customer service, said, uh, you know,
one of those blue bird dog was answered
and tried to tell me that his name was
Steve and act like he was in Kentucky.
But I,
I know that he was actually an India,
cause what he talked,
he was going Dubak Dabo
Woods, how can I help you? Um,
is it racist?
Probably.
You know what, something bad has to
happen between white culture and uh, or,
or western culture in Indians.
So, you know what I mean?
It's like a, it's like you're
playing a team and there's no rivalry
like patriots versus jets.
This year was like a whites and blacks.
It was bad. It was a
lot of hate, you know,
but like patriots verse,
like the Fucking Lions,
you know? Yeah. And there's gotta be
some shit targets. It's knocked out,
but it still hurts if somebody
says something mean. I don't,
I really don't. What the fuck
I'm talking about? All right,
let's move to the next one.
The next one on the new controversial
topic on the Monday morning podcast.
Is it racist? All right, here we go. Um,
Bill, I had an interesting experience
today apparently involving me as a racist.
I was walking with two of my coworkers
who are both black. Oh, Jesus. Here we go.
Um,
we were going to go get some lunch.
One of my coworkers who are
most of friends with, uh,
did a little high five fist bump shuffle
with one of the female sex security
guards at the front desk.
Knowing both of them and how
they interact with one another.
I kind of made a passing
comment to the tune of, man,
you guys in your handshakes
while obviously laughing,
laughing while obviously laughing at
just how choreographed it was in more or
less picturing them in
a studio or something,
working out the logistics to get the
fucking handshake. Perfect. Anyways,
we all laughed and moved on and
we got our lunch. All right,
so nothing wrong yet.
So you're cool with these people.
You made a joke and everybody laughed.
No problems,
no problems so far. Um, however,
after coming back through,
secure back through security,
I noticed the security guard stopped
me and Kinda had a scowl on her face.
I thought she was mad at me for something,
but it turned out she was mad at this
other lady who was black because she
overheard my comment and was telling,
uh,
that security guard that she couldn't
believe I had the nerve to say something
like that. And I should be ashamed
also to the point where she could,
um,
almost to the point where she could
actually go complain to the human resource
people because she was offended,
um,
et cetera without even considering that.
Maybe just maybe I was talking about the
security guard and my coworker and not
all black people now.
It being corporate America in all I'm
sure rather than even face the pos
possibility of any bad press,
they'd rather just sweep me out the
door and completely ruined my re any
reputation I may or may not hold at the
company just to save their own assets.
I feel I did nothing wrong and they had
no intentions of ever doing anything
wrong.
Anything wrong,
I'm not going to go on and on about
how I kiss black babies and trying to
rehabilitate inner city
schools because I don't,
but I'm certainly not some corn fed rebel
flag waving ignorant product of what
might be incest.
I guess my question is do we really have
to walk on eggshells when we are just
making casual conversation that just
any that just any cunt can pick apart,
select the context that they might think
it is in and then start crying foul.
Basically.
I would have liked to call that woman
a cunt and told her to go fuck herself.
But let's just say I was already
kind of worried about my job.
All right, let's see. Um,
yeah, I think this is,
this is the classic one where
you were fucking around.
The other two people knew
you were fucking around,
but they're one person decides to get
offended and then you have to go on TV and
apologize.
Which personally I think is the wrong
move because when you apologize now it's
like you're, you're admitting that you
meant it in a bad way. I mean the apology,
I would do that and say, look, you know,
I'm sorry that you didn't
understand that I was joking,
but I'm not going to sit here
and apologize like I have any,
any sort of ill will come in way,
you know,
but I, but just to avoid
the problem in the future,
uh,
white people do not use the
expression you guys or you people
when talking about black people, that's
just it. It's just not going to, you're,
you're setting yourself up for
someone to get offended. And, um,
there's a weird sort of a push
pull going on with that whole, uh,
you guys and you people thing where,
um,
with somebody white says that
there becomes this concern of,
um, that you're separating.
You're separating like, yeah,
you know,
you people over there with how you
live your lives and where over here,
black people have that weird relationship
with white people where they're like,
you know, can you stop stealing our
fucking music and our culture? And,
but then like, if something,
you know, hey, let's pave
the streets, you know, well,
make sure you do it in our neighborhood.
We're all in this together, right.
All of us together.
You know what I mean?
So that's that weird sort of fucking
push pull thing going on. So yeah,
just avoid, uh, avoid the whole fucking,
um, yeah, you fucked up.
You didn't fuck up, but you,
you left yourself open for a
sucker punched by saying you guys,
you know, uh, I guess that
that's what it is. I don't
know. That's, that's, that's my,
I basically a white guy telling
a white guy how he fucked up.
So black people feel listening
to this think, uh, please,
please help me out here.
Did I basically get it right?
Is that essentially it?
And I know most people wouldn't get
offended at all. Right? So there you go.
That's the new, that's the new topic.
Is it racist? And I would love to hear,
um, some honest comments from a non
white people about their thoughts.
You know, the fucked up ones too. Okay.
Cause I've watched enough spike Lee movies
to think that evidently it's just us,
but I've hung around enough people from
different races to realize, oh yeah,
everybody's like,
[inaudible] so.