Hey, what's going on? Is Bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon?
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Ah,
ah.
Just checking in on you.
I'm just checking in on you.
Doodah Doodah how's your
fucking Cuba coal old odot.day.
Um, what's going on? Happy Thursday.
Everybody here. Almost there.
I'll tell you that this weekend.
Just cannot come soon enough. Oh,
fucking suck it up,
Mary.
They're paying you to do you do a
fucking job. Go ahead and do it.
What are you gonna do this weekend?
It's going to make you less of a fucking
Goddamn wet diaper to be around next week.
This weekend can't come soon enough.
Oh yeah.
Who you're hanging out with that you got
to dump all your fucking problems on.
Sorry, you wouldn't know
it, but I'm in a great mood.
I'm in a fucking great mood.
Um,
tomorrow morning I'm
taking it early flight.
I'm flying out to a casino in Maryland
doing a one or two shows out there.
I'm not sure.
I don't know what,
just point me at the stage and I will
go out there and do my little fucking
dance. But a red sox finally won last
night. What did I do? Did I call it
or did I not call it?
All of these guys?
I don't know why you guys continue
to watch ESPN when the Monday morning
podcasts and the Thursday
afternoon just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast exists.
Okay.
Why do you put on that? Okay, Jay.
Okay. They're professionals. Okay.
They went to broadcasting school.
Okay.
They pay attention to sports way
more than I do. Having said that,
yeah.
According to my ego,
nobody reads the sports
tea leaves better than me.
Of course it isn't true,
but the one thing I am right about
is all these people that flip out
during the regular season about God,
he records and all that shit.
All the fucking wins. The Red
Sox half, we've seen this before.
We saw the Seattle mariners do it.
They want 120 something games
came home with no fucking,
they came home with their
pockets turned inside out
and I'll tell you right now,
there was all,
there were a lot of lumberjacks and
Seattle crying on Monday. All right.
No, I know that. I have a well earned
reputation as being a bit of a combustion.
Okay.
A bit of a fucking wet blanket.
A bit of a freckle. Alright,
guilty on all counts.
But I'll tell you one thing,
I'm right above other than my
misogynistic opinions about women,
I,
I am right about the regular season.
Okay?
And I'm here to tell all of you,
okay?
To fucking stand down
with this screaming and
yelling every fucking sport,
Kate fucking relax.
What you want to do is you take all
the stats of all the fucking 90% of the
teams or whatever sport you're watching,
sometimes only 40% if
you're watching hockey,
the amount of fucking teams that
are not going to win the playoffs.
You take all of those fucking stats.
All right?
As the rock used to say,
you turned them up sideways,
the seventh straight up candy.
Yes.
Cause they don't mean shit because
you're not going to see those people come
flop in October.
So what did I sing when I jumped on
the Red Sox bandwagon six hours ago?
I said we got the Indians twice.
We got the Houston Astros and we got
the Yankees to more fucking times. Okay.
Now if we lay waste to those teams,
I can get excited.
But even then the playoffs
at diff Joe Bucks there,
there's more cameras. Everybody's watched.
All right? People get a little tight.
You never know what the fuck can happen.
So anyways,
I've been telling you guys and
yes I am pat myself on the back.
I told you everybody's sleeping
on the Indians and Terry Francona.
Now what happens?
What does Terry do?
He comes right out in the
first two fucking games.
He makes us look like a 500
ball club handled us with east.
That's two wins. Two more. And
you just took a series. All right.
I know we got Chris sale and
I know we got price. Okay,
that's only going to get us to there.
All right.
And I think Terry Francona is the best
manager in fucking baseball and then
never, evidently they got this Guy
Brad hand or some shit closer. I,
it was no fun. I know his last
name. His hand. All right,
very impressive. Lights out. I know
we won last night and everything,
but I'm just saying, you know, but that's
what they do over there. The ESPNs,
the Fox sports,
they are in the business of saying the
sky is falling or sending something to
the fucking moon. They sent it to
the bone and when the sky falls,
they have the balls to say what happens,
what happened? Rather than being like,
wow, we will, we will fucking wrong again.
All they do is hype shit up
over there. They did. I mean,
how many fucking times have they,
how do you compare the DD dd
2018 red sox to the 96 bowls?
MMM.
Okay.
And it's always the 96 bolts.
By the way.
Everybody ignores the 1983 Philadelphia,
70 sixers.
Okay. One of the most underrated
teams of all fucking time. Um,
anyways, I was very relieved
that we got a win last night. Uh,
I'm going to try to
watch the game tonight.
MMM.
And it will be split with
them. But, uh, I, I mean,
I love our, and all our players
and all that shit, but I,
every time I see Terry Francona,
basically she's the best, you know?
I don't know what happens. You
just ever, you're just like,
familiarity breeds contempt. Is that
what is, how do you say that word?
Familiarity. Familiar. Familiarity.
Okay.
Hang on a second.
That's one of those ones.
You start the word and then
you get halfway through
and you're like, oh my God,
I'm not going to make it.
And you have like,
you're talking to three people
to save time at the party.
You just see all of them
just ever so slightly.
You see their faces drop and they
realize how dumb the person they are that
they're talking to her. Sorry.
Famille year air or a T.
I didn't even spell it right. All right.
How do you say this? Okay, everybody,
here we go. You Ready? Whoops.
Hang on. Hang on. Hang on.
Familiarity.
No. Familiarity. Familiarity. Yeah.
Garrity.
Yeah.
Familiarity. Dude. You know what it is.
You just feel familiarity of the ballpark.
He ain't fucking scared
when he gets sick on a,
on a and he knows all
the nooks and crannies.
I said it right.
Yeah,
yeah. Already. Yeah. Familiarity.
Okay.
You don't look, you don't believe
me. Listen to the fucking robot.
White Guy in my computer.
Familiarity C,
go fuck yourself. Give
me a bud light kit. Um,
watching my waistline for the end of
the summer, speaking of which, oh,
and then the Red Sox,
uh,
they had some fucking little a is the
English would say a little cheeky fucking
tweet there. I didn't like it. You know,
we apologize to our fans for, uh, our,
our lengthy losing streak.
Why would you do that?
You know,
this is what you got to ask yourself.
What would bill Bellacheck do? All right.
Just lob that over the
net. Hey, fucking cheat.
I know you guys would say that I cut
the sleeves off his sweater and fucking
blind a child to get an ice cream
cone quicker. You're all jealous. Um,
but funny. Um, anyways, uh, yeah.
Why would you give
bulletin board material?
Why would you motivate any other
fucking team? You know, that's just,
I think that's a stupid move.
Uh,
and that's what happens when you go on
Twitter and they probably read all these
red sox fans. Freaking
the fuck out. You know,
if they got 50,000 tweets,
I bet 30,000 were sent by Dan Shaughnessy.
Oh, I always get to make fun
of him. Um, there's this,
the 1978 season I'll over.
Are they going to chant 2013 at us?
Um,
anyways, tonight, tonight. Big, big,
big fucking match of who's on the for
the Indians. I have no idea. But uh,
the Indians are my team.
If the red sox don't make it this year,
I'd like to see them get one,
even though I'm going to have
to watch people in the stands,
have those stupid Cleveland
shirts that say defend the land.
Uh,
I just fuck getting,
I think that might be the
worst one. Okay. Yankees sing.
Why MCA during the seventh inning
stretch? If think that's bad, right?
Dirt that Eh,
all these fucking fat Harry
fucking Brooklyn cuts, right?
You'd take dad's bed and then you
go up to Boston and this, what is,
what is it swaying Caroline?
The thing is,
is you got to have like
a song for dumb people.
Yeah.
You know, like if you just
hum the melody of why MCA,
it's a Buddhist monk would probably tell
you that some sort of scent thing where
you just have a complete inability to
have any sort of thought in your head.
You know,
like,
think about your future while you go
a duck.
That's it.
It's over.
MMM.
And then the temple of it,
young men walking down the fucking street,
cause you can't dance. Right. Just
white guys walking around in a square,
you know,
is it's a girlfriend,
looks over his shoulder at the
black guy in the background.
MMM.
Anyways. And you just think it can't get
any bad worse than that, you know? I mean,
that's pretty bad because
it's, it's Douche behavior
combined with music. I mean,
that's usually takes the cake,
but defend the land,
the land.
What land? Cleveland. He'd be the
one you guys all fucking abandoned.
It's a fucking ghost town.
Drive in from your fucking
plush neighborhood.
All those fucking rich out there
in greater Cleveland, you know,
in their gated communities,
sitting out there reading their broths
in their fucking 14 carat big green eggs,
you know, then they come downtown
like the fucking Paul Revere.
I'm going to defend the land and go to
a game for three hours and then quickly
retreat back to my cul de sac,
the Lexis fucking riding mower.
The amount of money in greater
Cleveland is just insane, by the way.
I have no idea what greater
Cleveland is like. Uh,
but anyway, is it, is it
that much difficult to be
greater than Cleveland? Ah,
see what I did there. Sorry.
Anyways, having said that,
uh,
I love the idiots.
My Dad was a big Indians fan growing up.
MMM.
Indians at tigers where there's two
teams as he moved around a lot there. Uh,
so anyways,
I'll speaking to that late last night.
MMM.
I somehow, you know, and went
down this, this fucking, you
know, what do you call it?
The rabbit hole on Youtube.
And I ended up watching this youtube
video about every quarterback the Detroit
lions have ever had, you know, and uh,
they've had a lot of fucking quarterbacks.
Not a lot of offensive lineman,
but they have had a lot
of fucking quarterbacks.
MMM.
Fascinating. Fascinating franchise.
Allegedly, it's the curse of Bobby Lane.
It isn't. It isn't. It's
not. Okay. You know,
to say that you're cursed is just you
just passing the buck. It's like, no,
we don't know what the fuck
we're doing and we need help.
It's not the curse of Bobby Lane.
What?
Cause he left a little disgruntled.
Yeah, you get rid of me.
You're never going to win again.
And then some old lady I heard,
he shed fat 50 years and that's how it
starts that Dan Shaughnessy writes a book
about it. It makes a bunch of money off
the misery. That's what it should be.
His next book,
the curse of Bombay,
Bobby Lane would come into the
game fucking half in the bag.
He need hair of the dog after fucking
the second quarter going in halftime,
not listen to the coach, slap his fucking
wife around. Then he'd go out and he'd,
he'd have a fourth quarter
comeback, you know. Um,
and anyways, that's the way they told
the story. But I remember Greg Landry,
Eric Hippel,
I remember Joey Harrington his whole
fucking career just running for his life.
You know, that's what's amazing. You know,
when you see like some of these
people that are called bus like the,
this ship, this should be
like a consideration for the
fucking team you went to.
You know what I mean?
Like if Jimmy Johnson did not
come into the fucking Dallas cowboys
organization and make that Herschel Walker
trade, how long would have Troy
Aikman lasted in the league?
The amount of hits that that guy
took me the first couple of seasons,
he guy was on his back. You can only
take those hits for so long. Now.
I'm not saying Joey. Eric did his
Fuckin Troy Aikman I'm just saying,
remember way back in the day when
John Elway, the Baltimore Colts,
drafted him and he was,
you know, and he was like,
I'm not going to that fucking franchise.
And they go, what are you talking about?
He got ready to play baseball, I'll go
fucking play baseball for the Yankees.
You know,
because you guys don't know
what the fuck you're doing.
And I have one shot at this and
then they traded him to the Broncos.
Koby Bryant did the same thing
drafted by the Charlotte Hornets.
Say like I'm a fucking plane out there.
I actually think it is
like an for basketball.
It's bullshit for baseball
would be bullshit.
It wasn't like non contact sports for
the most part compared to like, you know,
football, football. I
get, it's like, dude,
I'm literally going to be drinking out
of fucking Straw by the time I'm 30 if I
play for you guys. Alright, you
don't have an offensive coordinator,
you have no offensive line. And I'm just
going to get like, I'm going to be like,
you know the guy, he waves his hand for
a fair catch and just get stuck. Now,
you know,
something with the new rules of tackling.
Now maybe I think that you
can go to these franchises.
You don't have to pull an Elway.
Um,
yeah. Cause I think it's that you
can't lead when you're fucking,
you can't lead with your head.
Where do you go to tackle?
I'm trying to picture how, how do
you do that? That can, can you,
you can hit with your shoulder though,
right?
But there's no way to hit with your
shoulder with our leading with your head
unless you just sorta like a,
it just come jump and buy like a
pogo stick and just sort of like,
it's like slam dancing.
Maybe they should do that.
I think what they should do is they
should have a giant velcro belt around.
All of them right in the ball becomes
velcro and you just stick it on the person
and the person can't run that.
You bounced down the fucking field like
a pogo stick and then everybody else
hops after you and tries to bump into you,
but you're not allowed to slap the ball
the way the way a rod did when he ran
down to first base. I don't know.
I'm just trying to fix the game.
You know who the fuck knows?
I know it's all about concussion
protocol and all that.
I think they should just have NFL players
just sign a release being like, yeah,
basically. Um, you're going to
take about 30 years off life.
Okay. But in the three and a half
years you play in this league, okay,
you're going to have a,
you're going to get more pussy.
You going to drive more God damn cars and
have more fucking bling than you could
ever dream of. All right? So
joy, joy. Well, last, okay,
just sign here and you
can lead with your head.
Maybe that's what they have to do.
I Dunno.
Maybe the NFL implodes and then the
WNB takes over. I mean, who knows?
There's a good story for ESPN. Is
that what's going to happen? Um,
anyways, let me read a little
bit of advertising here. Um,
then I'm gonna talk about, uh, dog. Cleo.
Cleo is back in town.
I'm going to go take her for a walk after
I upload this fucker. A butcher box.
Everybody. Oh my goodness. Oh my
goodness. Are you a kind of war?
Dia Love,
impeccable cuts of fucking
butchered meat the way I do.
I literally read this.
This is disgusting.
I literally read this in my mouth waters.
That's how much I enjoy it. Plus also,
I'm on this fucking, this diet, you know,
and this week is like the
vegetarian diet. You know, I, I, I,
I had like a quarter of a chicken breast
at some point, you know what I mean?
An animal has to die so I
can live. I mean, it's just,
it's just how I am, you know?
Um, anyways, I just wish they
didn't treat the animals like shit,
which is why I like this one.
You know, these guys, they, they,
they treat them night. They pet them, they
rub their bellies before they kill him.
You know what I mean? I
mean, if you were going,
if you are on death row when she want
that, you know, nice head rub, foot rub,
you know, work out the kinks in
your back for they flip the switch.
All right.
Butcher box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chickens and
the greatest thing ever.
Heritage bread,
pork,
the Cuban cigar of pork.
Okay.
Uh,
the incredible quality of butcher box
meets starts with the commitment to
raising animals humanely and free of
antibiotics and hormones before we kill
them. Each box comes with at
least nine to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24
individuals sized meals.
You can choose from five different
box types. I disliked it.
You can order a couple boxes of those
and you're ready for the apocalypse.
Just freeze those bad boys and everybody
else is going to be all starving out
there eating dandelions
in fucking flossing their
teeth with the flag in their
mailbox.
And you're going to be coming out
there with just full of fucking protein
throwing elbows and knees, Huh? Um,
you can choose from five different
box types. All beef, beef and chicken,
beef it and it makes box for
are you progressive people?
Custom box lets you choose
your own cuts. Oh, this is for,
this is for the fucking chef right here.
Antibiotic and hormone free.
We already said this.
Butcher box believes in a healthier
food system where everyone has access to
meets the way nature intended.
Free of antibiotics and hormones.
Humanely raised on an open
pasture before we killed them.
Shots fired at the company,
the artist formerly known as Monsanto,
Monsanto,
um,
butcher box carefully curates
the finest selection than cuts.
It makes it a breeze to
customize your own delivery,
build your own box to get exactly
what you and your family love.
Choose your delivery frequency
with customizable subscriptions.
Receipts Are Available on recipes,
receipts,
recipes are available on the butcher box,
websites and videos.
I literally thought like,
is this meat like tax deductible and
videos are available to follow along on
butcher box youtube channel? Yeah. They
wanted me to say my personal experience,
I told you I had the,
the heritage bread pork was the
best pork chop I've ever won.
One of the top three I've ever had and
I've had five unbelievable once by five
star chefs. It was just an entirely
different level. It's like,
did you ever just like,
you have to have a tomato at a grocery
store and then someone has a garden and
they bring that over and you're like,
this is what the fuck it's supposed
to taste like. It's unreal.
It's like our food has a mute
button that's been pushed,
so every once in a while
when you get the real shit,
you know,
she's so fucking weird that if you know,
if you went back to the 18 hundreds
how much better food would it tasted,
but then all the other shit
you could have died of,
you know?
Then you could fast forward all that shit.
They died of an hour.
Foods all fucked up, which is
causing more shit that you die from.
I'll tell you people, it's a
quagmire. All right. Legal Zoom fact.
Most Americans don't have
a, well, not this guy.
My affairs are in order.
20 years ago,
that wasn't a shocking statement.
You had to find a trustworthy attorney
and pay them by the hour to draft your
will,
but these days there's no excuse.
Legal Zoom has made it
easy to create your own.
That's why more than a million people
have used legal zoom for their estate
planning needs. It's an, it's national.
Make a will month@legalzoom.com so now
it's your turn to take control of your
family and assets with an estate plan.
It starts with the will or living trust.
I can tell you this,
a lot of guys don't do it because you
don't want to contemplate your own
mortality. I gotta tell you, I was
one of those guys. I got a will.
I got everything all done and uh,
it was like a load off of my fucking
chest. You'll feel great afterwards.
You know,
unless you're married the wrong person.
And then they immediately start
to poison your food. I mean,
there's always something. There's
always a fly in the ointment anyways.
Don't know which one's right for you.
No problem.
Legal sims network of
independent attorneys will
advise you on what's best for
you and your family. Plus,
legal zoom is not a law firm,
so you're not have to pay hourly rates.
Make things a lot easier on
your family when you're gone.
Checkout legal zooms,
last will and living trust estate plans.
Now during national,
make a will month@legalzoom.com yeah,
you don't want to fucking die and then
have your loved one's worrying about how
they're going to pay for their fucking
fruit loops or corn flakes or maybe
you're a fan of the Czech family.
Rice checks, corn checks, we checks.
Right?
And for special savings,
be sure to enter code burr in
the referral box at checkout.
That's code birth for special savings
only@legalzoom.com where life meets legal.
Then you have to hunt your own
funeral because you sell urine.
An unsettled spirit.
Okay.
And then you just going to be screaming.
I'm sorry, like you're in ghosts, but,
but you know what? Peace not there,
so no one's going to be able to see.
All right,
he's get a fucking wheel. Okay. Oh Dude,
dude, dude. Beyond days beyond the,
she died with Datto weld to do,
to do brds.
Brds now nobody can fucking chill.
They got no money.
Now they're sucking dick out
on the street doing it quick.
They do what they do because
they need to eat some checks.
Thanks for fucking us over dad. You're
really screwed. US. All right me undies.
You've heard me obsess over my me undies.
You've heard me talk about how they
are three times softer than cotton.
While you've heard me read about it and
come with fun new prints each month,
but I got evidently I got a big scoop
that evidently I'm so excited to share
with y'all.
Me undies just gave their
membership a massive upgrade.
I just pictured them like there's some
sort of shelf they have in the front of
the underwear now that
just lifts your junk.
There's your massive upgrade
of foot rest for your balls.
All those dirty old whole written
disgusting underwear you've hung onto.
It's time to throw all that out and
give your top drawer the refresher it
deserves.
Each month's BMDS we'll release a new
exclusive print that only members can get.
These can be collaborations with artists,
brands or other unique designs you
are going to definitely want to have.
Members were also pay less for everything
on me undies website with special
member pricing. That means if
you want a second pair of undies,
a Bralette or lounge pants,
you'll pay less than anyone else.
The membership comes with no strings
attached. You can switch styles,
skip the month or cancel any time. Uh,
you're going to love these Sundays.
They're the softest underwear you'll
ever put on and they come with fun prints
that can match with socks or a bralette.
Uh,
they come with 100% satisfaction
guarantee. If you don't love him,
just send them back grouse,
uh, for a full refund.
Me undies has a great offer for my
listeners. For any first time purchases,
when you purchase any me undies,
you get 15% off and free shipping.
That's a no brainer.
Get 50% off a pair of the most
comfortable undies you will ever put on.
Lastly, but not leastly.
He looks everybody.
There's nobody on the planet like you.
You're so unique.
The sounds you make when you sleep,
the high pitched way that you fart.
So why would you buy a generic
mattress built for everyone else?
Next, please mention all the talking
points below. Okay. Hallux Helix.
Sleep matches your body to the perfect
mattress so you get the best sleep of
your life. They developed, they've
developed nine different mattresses
tailored to specific body types in
sleep preferences. That's amazing.
There's nobody on the planet like you,
the seven and a half billion people and
they've made nine different mattress
types and they think they covered all
the basis. Well, I would say that Hallux,
he is talking a lot of shit here.
I think they're pretty confident that
God damn product just go to huge.
That looks sleek.com/spur take
their two minutes sleep quiz.
You sleep in the nude and they'll match
you to, to a mattress that perfect.
That's perfect for you.
Contouring to your body to provide
unprecedented comfort and better sleep.
36% of Helix Helix sleep customers report
better sleep after switching to their
customized mattress
from helic sleep helix.
Right now he likes,
right now they're offering up
to $125 off all mattress orders.
Whether you're a side sleeper,
hot sleeper,
like a plush or affirm bed,
they've got the mattress
that will fit just right. Uh,
anybody who likes up fucking
plush mattress, is it just
they're not motivated?
You know? Whoa. I like a plush mattress.
Get up to $125 off.
He looks like [inaudible] dot com slash
[inaudible] that's helix sleep.com/pro
for $125 off your mattress order.
Hi heavily sleep.com/
[inaudible] all right,
let's wrap it up. Boop,
boop. Wrap it up. All right,
Billy botox is getting in shape.
It's right.
I'm going to get some injections in my
face. I'm going to have my teeth bleached,
my tongue scraped it.
Uh,
you know the wind have that
candle stuck in my ear.
We fucking melt out all the wax or some
shit. Now I'm not doing any of that.
I'm just trying to get, I'm trying to
get my abs. I got a four pack right now.
My stomach reminds me of the
old fucking wine. I mean,
that old bottle and James
Belly right here. Um,
it's abs sick. It's Ab five and six.
Those are the tough ones. You know,
even seven and eight aren't that bad.
Like the fat just goes right to five
and six. It just fucking sits there.
You know what I mean? Like,
you know, whenever you, you're,
you pour some liquid into a measuring cup,
no matter how much you
try and dump it out,
there's always that little bit that
fucking gathers in the bottom and then you
try and fucking snapping it down.
He did is always going to be a little bit
left him. That's what ab five and six.
So like in my fucking world,
um, I'm doing all right though.
I look really good with the
shirt on right now, you know,
but if I take my shirt off
it's still put it back on. Um,
so I think I need to do a little more
cardio or something like that. Uh,
you know what I want to
buy, I don't know, Rogan is,
has been talking up this fucking
cardio machine. I got to check it out.
I got to go next time I do his
podcast or write in the area.
I ran into him the other night and I was,
I was,
he was going on and on about how fucking
unbelievable this thing and how it was
tiring him out. So I figure if it tires
Joe out, it's borderline going to kill me.
Um, but I remember way
back in the day, um,
there was a gym and
they had this thing called Jacob's ladder,
which was just per picture.
You are a fireman and there was a ladder
that reached up to the top of a fucking
skyscraper. Right? And that's
what it was like. It was like,
you're on all fours and,
or like a 45 degree angle and just
climbing this fucking never ending.
It just keeps going and going and going.
You know,
it's like a treadmill on a 45 degree
angle. They, they didn't, they did.
It's like you're fucking crawl 10 miles
away from the gym and then you're like,
fuck, now how do I get back to my
car? You know, it just, you know,
it goes in a circle using your
own weight or some shit like that.
And I remember I got on that fucking
thing. And with if then three minutes,
it felt like my heart was in my
throat and I had done an eight ball.
MMM.
So I'm considering getting one of those.
I might buy one of those or
I'm going to check out the Joe Rogan
was could Josie, Josie always like,
he's always sees one of those guys.
He's always looking around the corner.
So he's always,
he knows what the next shit is.
And I feel like he's had that thing long
enough that if that he's already past
the, Oh, wait a minute, this thing
sucks. He was still raving about it.
So whatever the fuck he got, I'm going
to, I'm going to try to get, you know,
and then maybe I'll have a spinning heel
kick at the death level that he does.
Um, anyways, my dogs back in town.
MMM.
I'm going to go take her for a walk.
I fucking miss that dog so much, man.
I'm having an ally.
Uh,
it's just the best,
but I still get to see her like once
every six weeks and she's out here for six
days. So every day I'd been
taking around like a fucking hike.
She goes nuts when she sees me.
I got crazy when I see her.
It's always a little sad when I
give it back, you know? But, uh,
I think she's kind of used to
it at this point. You know,
I think human beings take
it harder than, than, uh,
the fucking dogs too.
But anyways.
MMM.
Okay. Let's, let's look a little bit
of world news. Let's see what's going,
let's check in on the
world. Everybody, uh,
Trump under fire for claim of large
scale killing of white farmers in South
Africa.
Um,
is there any doubt that this guy is just
a straight up fucking racist at this
point?
It's amazing how long he kind of hid that.
Like you had no idea when he
was just sort of this funny,
famous for being famous guy.
Um,
but the things that he chooses to focus
on, not saying that this isn't happening.
Okay.
White farmers getting killed
in South Africa, but, you know,
white people are killing a lot of other
people from different races for quite a
while. Uh, actually right now.
Oh I'm sorry.
We thought you were a terrorist.
Will you just a family go into the market?
Sorry about that.
We've been doing that for 15 fucking
years. I mean it's, you know,
I'm not saying what's going on in half.
I've even about it is right.
But it's just like that like,
I dunno when you can see like you know
when this like neo Nazis and you can kind
of see their argument to why,
you know,
it's kind of six of one
half dozen of the other
and the fact that fucking politicians
on both sides are such pieces of fucking
shit that they will,
they will sit there and they will just,
they will tow the fucking company line.
Okay.
Because they're grossly under fucking
paid and it's all about getting reelected.
So someday you can write three books while
you're still in office and then buy a
$10 million house.
That's basically what it is.
A UK outlines plan to
avert chaos of a no deal.
Brexit, when the fuck is this thing going
to go down? I thought they were leaving.
This is like the longest break up ever.
What is a no deal?
Brexit.
So they leave the European Union and
then they don't know what the fuck they
going to do.
All right,
so there's showing a picture
of a bunch of tractor trailers.
Okay.
All right. Make a difference in today's
world. Support independent journalism.
Subscribe for a dollar a week.
Oh,
can I read what you wrote first?
How do I know you're independent?
This is New York times.com.
You're not fucking independent.
If mainstream, uh, London,
the British government issued its
first contingency plans on Thursday for
leaving the European Union without an
agreement seeking to prepare the public
for possible disruption without spreading
alarm that could undermine support for
the entire undertaking.
The government an agreement for what
citizens of other countries that are
living in London with some sort of work
visa. How you're going to
trade with the rest of it. Oh,
this is looking like a shit show.
Yeah.
The government emphasized that it hoped
and expected to hammer out a deal with
the European Union.
But in a series of technical documents,
it warned that without an agreement,
importers and exporters could face
significant new bureaucratic hurdles that
credit or debit card payments in
continental Europe could cost more.
And the British citizens living in the
block could lose access to banking and
pension service. I'm going
to call this right now. Uh,
England or Great Britain leaving
the European Union is either going to be
the greatest or the worst fucking move
ever. I mean, it's a great
move on some level, I guess.
Do you get out of the world banks
and you get to go back? They'd wait.
Are they are,
I can't even know if they're on the
euro and they still in the pound.
Were they on the road? Did they go back
to the pound? I can't fucking remember.
But that's going to be that this is
either gonna fucking make other countries
want to do it or they're going to be like,
thank God I didn't do that.
This is not going to be where.
You know what I mean? You know,
there's pros and cons. It's going to be
great or a shit show. One of the, uh,
I just went ESPN on that, uh, US,
China impose fresh round of tariffs as
escalating trade wars shows no sign of
ending. Why can't, why, what are we doing?
Why can't we just fucking get along
with people, you know? Hello China.
How are you? Is this how you want to
run your country? Well, God bless you.
This is how we run our country. You
know, you want some apples? I mean,
how fucking hard is that?
I know,
I just oversimplified it
anyways. Um, oh, lastly,
but not leastly. Uh, I did, uh,
an episode of Conan O'brien last night
to hype my show at Madison Square Garden.
November 7th.
I'll be there with Joe Bart,
Nick and the pride of Trenton,
New Jersey,
Paul Versey on November 7th.
I'm very excited about
that. And a, as always,
I had the best time on,
uh,
on Kone ease him and Andy,
they're the best current sets you up.
And then if you get in trouble,
Andy Saves,
you actually joked with Andy
when I left. I said, you know,
I think you only need to save me one time,
maybe twice.
I think he jumped in twice.
So my idea of a perfect game on
Conan is Andy never has to save me.
He's always two to five
times every segment. But um,
I had a great time. I actually got
there a little bit early and, um,
I got to go check out the drum kit,
which was,
was fucking bad SDW kit.
So I sat down and actually played
them for a couple of minutes and uh,
I don't know what that is.
That always like makes me more
relaxed before I go out. And,
uh, that do was show, I don't know why.
Maybe cause I'm a fucking lunatic.
I have no idea.
So I actually got to sit down at James
Worworth's kit. Um, sounded amazing.
I was like, you sure he's not going
to get pissed if I sit days. Hey Dad,
that's fine.
Um,
okay.
But, uh, anyways, I had a great time on
it. If you'd like to see some clips, uh,
maybe we'll, I'll post some links
or something like that to it.
I had a great time.
As always.
I'm so thank you to everybody
over at Kona for helped me, uh,
promote Madison Square
Garden November 7th. Uh,
please get you tickets so I'm not standing
there in a big empty arena. All right,
that's the podcast here for a Thursday.
Have a great weekend.
You [inaudible] enjoy this,
um, music interlude here,
musical interlude before we,
uh,
play some classic hits from a Thursday
podcast from earlier in the year of
fucking 10 years ago. I have no idea
how it works. All right, I'll see you.
[inaudible]
wait, let's get back to Vegas out here.
I, uh, had a great time last night.
I did a surprise,
not so surprised.
Guest spot at,
uh,
on the fucking,
what the fuck? The, uh, the all
the all end tour. Sorry guys.
You can you tell I've been drinking
again. Drinking again. Oh, baby.
I'm drinking again. I went 73 fucking
days with that, without the booze
and uh,
Versie Bart,
nick in law had all came in
Saturday night after, um,
my second show over here at the Mirage.
And,
uh, I came back to my room
and I was waiting for them.
They were on their way up. Kevin
Shay opened for me. All right.
So all,
all the fucking maniacs.
We're out here and I'm sitting there
with the lovely Nia and she's going,
I'm tired. I'm like, I'm
tired too. I swear to God, if
these guys weren't in town,
I would just go to bed.
And they showed up.
We had a couple of drinks and had
some cigars sitting on the table.
And I go to my wife, hey, you
know, like, let's just, we're
just going to go outside,
smoked a cigar. I'll be back in a couple
hours or whatever. And that was like,
I don't know what that was. That was
probably just a little bit after midnight.
And I don't, you know, I started
drinking and I just became that guy,
that guy who just wants to keep
going and does not want to go home.
And a bargaining was joking,
said what we did was basically they could
have shot a commercial for Las Vegas
is what we did. Um, I
hate to say it. We did.
And we just did old school Vegas shit
that was not old school when I first
started coming to Vegas.
But I've been out here for 15 years and
like the new school's going to that Dj
Shit. So I didn't know what
the fuck we did. We somehow,
I think we ended up over the Venetian
and uh,
we were already smoking cigars. I don't
really even remember. I was just pounding.
Okay,
well where are we? I played
roulette somewhere and I made money.
Then I cashed out.
Then we went over to the v Venetian.
I remember playing craps.
Yeah,
throwing the dice.
I just kept going,
hey,
I started yelling and everybody's saying
I'm throwing numbers over here. Right.
And I just started throwing it.
I did what I always did.
I bet the 68 in the past bar, I should
have bet the point I hit the point twice.
I'd through like fucking, I
dunno, 1215 numbers in a row,
you know,
I was bullshit
man. I had like five bucks on each fucking
thing or whatever I made and I made a
couple hundred bucks cause I was
too drunk to realize like, Bill,
you know what you're feeling it.
Why not throw down a little bit more?
But I didn't this many people
on the other end of the table.
Okay,
well going. Hey, you're built bar
your throat die. I go, that's right.
They're buttoned down.
Throw throwing numbers.
Let's talk at Shit.
Oh is that what a hell of a time tip and
people doing what you're supposed to do?
Laughing my ass off. I made
money. I went back over,
cashed out. I had like fucking
three, $100 bills in my pocket.
I have to starting off with my old
Hartford. So I guess it was up 200 bucks.
Now all of a sudden this shady dude
comes up to us who had this weird little
sodas, zipper scar in his nose and
he's handing us a fucking flyer.
Oh wait,
somewhere in there,
I met these two agent chicks and I
talked them back into their dreams.
I can't answer that. Um, just
one girl, she was an accountant.
She wanted to be in fashion. And I
was like, so go do that. She's like,
do you really think I carrot Mike?
Yeah.
You totally can just keep your day job
and just start working on the fashion
thing and then eventually fashion
thing will surpass your other thing.
She was like, you're so awesome.
And all I'm thinking in my head is,
this is why that fucking guy,
okay
was able to buy where the Houston Rockets
used to play and go in there and talk
about Jesus. What the fuck is that
guy's name? You know that guy, you know?
Oh, what is his fucking name?
He's got this squinty eyes.
He closes his eyes and he sits there.
You know,
Jesus wants you to have a popsicle.
He wants you it,
all they gotta do is just tell people
what they, what they want to hear.
And I was totally sincere.
Okay.
When I told this woman
to go follow her dreams,
but I didn't really give her
any sort of concrete plan.
All I did was just tell
her that she could do it.
Yeah.
And it made him feel good. So I did do
a good thing, but you know something I,
if the bottom falls out,
uh, of standup comedy,
that's what I'm gonna I'm going to
turn into a motivational speaker.
I would absolutely crush it because I
already know how to make people laugh.
And then rather than being a negative
content, I would totally turn it.
I would finally take off like,
you know,
you don't want Spiderman wears that
black suit and he can't control it.
And he starts acting like a con,
you know,
starts talking shit to women and
spraying web web juice in their face.
Then he goes back to the classic
red and blue and then he's like, oh,
I'm sorry about that sweetie.
Let me get that. Uh Oh shit.
I didn't finish that fucking story.
So this guy with a Goddamn zipper
stark scar on his fucking nose,
he convinces us to go to a titty bar,
which really wasn't difficult.
And next thing you know,
we're in this fucking
titty bar. And are these women
were really God damn aggressive.
Like the second you sat down, one of
them sat in your lap and I was like,
it was really, I'd be honest with
you, it's fucking suffocating.
Okay.
I actually, it's kind of like, Hey,
can you fucking let me
just get my bearings here
before you put, quit trying to shake your
tits. They're fake. They're not moving.
All right. What do you do
next? Shake your elbow.
MMM.
So anyways,
we're in this fucking place
and uh, I dunno. I mean,
we're all guys, we don't give
a fuck. Next thing you know,
it's like six o'clock in the
goddamn morning, six something.
We came walking out,
it was broad daylight and
I'm sitting there like,
the only thing I can relate it to
was when I was playing up in Alaska,
when,
uh,
when it was that one of those times
a year where it had like 22 hours of
sunlight and you were inside
the club and you drink it.
And it's about two in the morning.
Like, all right guys, I'm tired.
I'm going to bed.
And then you would walk outside.
You'd open the door into broad daylight
and immediately give body's clock,
you would wake up, he said at two
in the afternoon, two, two at night.
It seemed like two in the afternoon
is the only way I could describe it.
And I walked out and uh,
all I heard was Kevin Chaise.
Maniacal fucking laugh at
like how light it was out. Um,
so that was my,
basically,
that was my first night out here
and I gotta be honest with you,
I'm still recovering from it.
And that was two goddamn days ago.
Last night after a show, I was just like,
I sat down and I got something to eat.
I had one Budweiser and then I went to
bed and I was fucking psyched to come
back and go to bed. So that goes
back to what I was talking about.
So I have to dress maturely.
All right now,
like I was ever a guy walking
around in a tank top. I didn't,
I didn't have any fucking a pigment,
you know, but I gotta tell you,
you go down on the pool. Some people, I
don't know if they just have, they just,
they can't see it or if they just don't
give a fuck some of the shit that people
wear it down,
but by had got damn pool.
I mean
it's just like, can you put that all
of that shit away? Can you put it away?
Half the people at the pool,
it should be wearing like one of those
bathing suits from the roaring twenties
you know where it was basically it
was kind of a mechanic suit like that.
Fonzie used to wear that one z zip up,
except you would cut the sleeves
off and you would cut the legs off.
That's what guys would wear.
And women wear the same thing and they'd
have a little frilly thing going around
the outside. Now it's unreal, man.
Oh Jesus. And my generation, oof,
it's, it's ugly. The tramp stamps,
the Barb wire tattoo around your arm.
It's just a,
it's not a good fuck.
Good luck.
It's just not a good
[inaudible]
going on. It's Belper and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
August 23rd, 2010. How they hell are you,
what's going on? I just got
back from Portland, Oregon.
I'm actually taping this a Sunday night
cause I got a bunch of bullshit I have
to do tomorrow.
MMM.
I Dunno what the fuck I just got back
from Portland and I hate doing these
things Sunday night because I'm
still like jet lagged. I'm out of it.
So, uh, this is gonna be a rough
one and I'm plowing through this.
Even if it fucking sucks,
I'm not stopping it and rerecording it
like I did last week because that ended
up getting me in trouble.
That's how I started talking about
that doctor Laura Shit last week.
And I got to say for the first time,
maybe the second time ever,
I'm nominating myself as Douche bag of
the week because last week I actually
supported Dr Laura because I had no
fucking idea who she was. And uh,
you know, I was having a rough time
doing the podcast. I needed some fodder.
Somebody send me an email.
What do you think about this?
And I watched like a ten second clip of
evidently a five minute clip and I just
thought she was imitating
something, something she saw
on def jam. So I was like,
well, she's quoting it, she's
not calling anybody that word,
but the ban and all that bullshit.
And then Jay's Zola, Jesus,
the fucking emails came in
from a, I evidently, uh, for
my 14 podcasts listeners,
every will be like six of
them are African American. Um,
and uh,
yeah,
they read me the riot act in different
stages and dark got admit they were
fucking right. Cause I didn't,
I, you know, something,
my uninformed logic is usually funny that
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking
about and I go off on shit and I realized
that our race probably isn't one that
you should probably do that on. I
didn't know that. She was like, uh,
like rush Limbaugh with a cunt.
I had no idea. I just, you know,
I don't know the fuck she was that she
was some soccer mom with a podcast,
you know, and she was like all the crazy
kids out there. Fucking blob applied.
No idea. Sorry. Fucking eggs
on my face. Um, but you know,
it's funny, one guy got so
into fucking trashing me. Wait,
before I close this email,
here's something I got from a former
marine talking about that clapping for uh,
the troops going through the
airport. He goes, as a former marine,
nothing was a bigger joke than seeing
those support, the support, the troops,
stickers talk about an empty
gesture and is even lamer.
I've always fucking thought those bumper
stickers was stupid. Support the troops.
She just slowly,
you go buy that for a buck slapping on
the back of your truck or car and then he
just drive away. Well, I did my
part. Do you support the troops?
Have you looked at my bumper
sticker will. All right then. Um,
yeah, that's fucking lame. And he said,
and clapping is even lamer. He said,
you're on the right track. Sending
over drinks to veterans who got back.
But think bigger. How about a
program called head for heroes?
That's right.
Every,
every service member returning from
whatever fucked up Third World Shit hole
we're engaged in at the time gets met at
the airport by some gorgeous whore and
blown in a specially designated area.
That would be a great way of
showing the country's gratitude.
You know what, I think if he can bail
the bankers out, give him $1 trillion,
I think it's, you can get a couple
of fucking who is, you know,
forget about the girls who have a
fucking uniform fetish. Um, but anyways,
uh, yeah, so I got, I
got fucking trashed. Um,
I took a little heat off of Mel Gibson.
I bet that he caught a couple of
less a fucking hate mails last week.
So I apologize. I don't know who she is.
I'm not gonna Apologize For my stupidity,
but in the future when it's
something, you know, race related,
I will try to be a little more
informed. All right, well,
I got to find this fucking email. This
guy fucking trashed me, you know, he said,
uh, let's see. He goes,
it starts off good.
Just trashing me, which I totally
get. He goes, just like in your bit,
you did about the Jimmy,
the Greek thing.
It's best for white people to just
leave it alone. Dr. Laura May be old,
but she's aware enough to
know what happens to white
people when they say the n
word or bring up racial supremacy
theories. See that's the part of the tape
watch
showed up late to that rally.
You know,
by the time I showed up they had
already put the cross out. You know,
everybody's hoods. They took
them off. It was a hot day.
I didn't know what I was walking into. It
thought it was like a fucking, you know,
Aa meeting or something. You know, we're
all over by the table. I haven't, don't,
it's my fault. I came
in late. Um, so anyways,
he said the porting comes out.
So I'm surprised you defended
Dr Laura in this case.
They asked where I got a lot of them.
Surprise you. Defend it or can we,
cause I watched eight seconds
of the tape cause I'm Maura. Um,
I don't understand why there's any
debate about racial inequality,
why any debate about racial inequality
always comes down to comedians and def
comedy jam. I don't think it does,
but evidently a in your world,
maybe it does. Um, I've heard
this argument before, well,
black comedians say this and that
about white people and say the n word,
why can I, is it fair for minority
Comedians, but put up into and all basic,
all that's all that shit. Uh, I'm
trying to get to this part here.
So then he was talking about this
documentary where some comic was saying,
you know, making a joke. This is actually
a good joke where white people like,
why can't I say the n word?
Uh,
okay.
And then the dude was like,
Oh, it was Chris Rock. Well,
why do you even want to say it? Right.
Great. Fucking joke. Totally makes sense.
Uh, then the punchline is, I've sailed
the world. I've fucked Raquel Welch.
If I could just say the n word,
my life would be complete. Uh,
then this dude writes after that,
he goes,
I think that it bothers white people
because you're not used to being told that
you can't do something.
Why people used to be able to
do and say anything they wanted.
Now there's all these rules.
Isn't that fucking that,
that part of the email, that's where it
just went off the fucking rails for me.
You know what I mean? It's like I
totally get it. She's a fucking idiot.
I didn't realize it cause I watched
that short little clip, you know,
I shouldn't have support that shit.
And, and you're offended by that,
which I totally get. And then
in the end, you make some dumb,
general generalization about white
people. See, we're all the same.
We're fucking morons.
Jesus Christ.
I've sailed the world. Fuck walk Calwell
see that parts of the joke, but this,
here's what he writes bothers white
people that you're not being used to told,
being told that you can't
do something. Oh yeah, yeah.
We just run around doing whatever the
fuck we want to do. It's great. Ah,
Jesus Christ.
That's,
that's one of the great stereotypes
is that we're all Kennedy's living on
fucking Martha's vineyard
rather than fucking
okay.
You know,
the majority of white people aren't
the majority of white people sitting in
cubicles, not living their dream,
drowning in a sea of fucking debt,
trying to get health insurance. Isn't
that the majority of fucking white people?
Evidently not. Evidently according
to this guy, why people have yachts
sailing the world, all 300
million of us, you know,
do you just see it during that, the Gulf
War, uh, the Gulf spill there, you know,
that was one of the biggest problem.
All those white people,
all the 300 million white people with our
fucking yachts, just sailing around. Oh,
it's so awesome to be white.
You can just walk. You do it,
say whatever you want to do.
It's fucking incredible. Um,
that's an argument I've, I've
gotten it to, uh, with the, um,
I think every fucking,
yeah.
Female comics, black comics,
every fight, they just go, yeah,
it's easy for you all. You
gotta do show up, man. Oh yeah.
That's all it is.
I don't even audition.
I just lay here and they
call me up and I'm like, why?
Why did you give me that part then?
Cause you're white. Here you go.
You don't have to work
for shit. Uh, you know,
that's that class. You know, that's that
fucking double standard right there. Okay,
now we're opening a whole
nother can of worms.
Let's talk race for the next
couple of weeks. People,
this oughta bring out a lot of ugliness.
That's that classic fucking like,
that's one of those statements like you,
if you flip that thing,
what you just said there,
that generalization that you made of
white people that basically what we just
sit around and they do.
People just give a shit and we can
do whatever the fuck we want to do.
You're basically going to
define us by the Illuminati.
Um,
if you flip that around,
it's somebody white says that about
another race of people than there were in
like a Mel Gibson situation. All right,
now I'm opening this up for discussion.
I'm not opening this up for
fucking rednecks to come
on here and be like, yeah,
that's why the fuck I'm talking about.
I'm not saying it like that,
but what I'm saying,
you know what,
this is what I've learned traveling
the fucking Globe and by the globe,
I mean I went to two other continents
and went to Australia and Europe.
I did all my research with just white
people. All right? And uh, yeah,
I think pretty much people
are people. We're all the
same. You know, there's a few,
like very small percentage of people on
this planet are genuinely good people
and everybody else is pretty much full
of shit and everybody looks at everybody
else and they think they got it
easier. And all you gotta do is, yeah,
you got to do is this,
I got to work twice as hard at this guy
and this guy does this. And you know,
no one wants to know
what I've learned. Well, you probably
don't to know because I'm a fucking moron.
But for what it's worth,
this is what I've learned in
life is that life isn't fair.
It's really fucking difficult.
But if you bust your ass,
you're going to make it on whatever
level you're going to fucking make it.
You surround yourself with positive
people and you don't fucking quit.
Somebody kicks you in the fucking chest,
you get back up again,
you don't walk right into his foot.
You go around finding
different fucking avenue,
or maybe you build your own avenue, you
do whatever you're going to fucking do.
And everybody's got different
starting positions and all that shit.
And it isn't fucking fair and there's
nothing you can fucking do about it. But,
uh,
you know,
and there's some people who don't get
stuff because of who they are because
they're there. So the data,
they're fat and that they're,
they're fucking in an
Asian guy with one leg.
Okay. And he can't work at a God damn
fucking place where you get a fake Tan,
you know? Yeah. That shit definitely
fucking exist. But you know,
what are you going to do?
You know? But you know what?
I think most people don't make it because
they're fucking pussies and they just
tap out. You know? And I'm
talking about fucking wipe.
I'm actually talking mostly white people,
cause that's what I know, you know?
And I got, I got people, people I know,
they just fucking quit and they've got
all these fucking excuses why they can't
fucking do it. And it's
like, no, you, you quit,
you got punched once in the face and then
you just fucking laid down and I going
to fucking blame everybody else. Right.
Does that make any fucking sense?
I'm trying to say something positive here.
Trying to be balanced where
it's like, I know, you know,
like female comics, they're always
fucking complaining. You know,
I can't tell you the amount
of fucking times I would,
I would be auditioning for festivals and
the industry becoming up to me going,
we need funny women.
Where are the funny women?
And then they would pick a fucking
woman just cause they needed one.
Not because they were one of
the funnier fucking people.
I'm not saying that female comics
aren't funny, but I'm just saying there,
there are examples. You know what?
You guys can all go fuck yourself.
I'm a balding redhead trying to get
into movies. All right? You know,
cry me a fucking river. I
don't give a shit. All right?
But I was wrong about the
doctor Laura think okay.
When I start a fucking group crying
about how there's no fucking redheaded
action heroes out there. You know,
Jesus Christ. What's that fucking movie?
That's the number one
movie in the country.
They got 58 fucking action stars in there.
One of them can't be a redhead.
Couldn't have called up David Caruso to
show his pasty white ass walking up to
Arnold Schwartzenegger. Ah,
who gives a fuck? All right,
so there you go. That was,
that was my, that was my roundabout
apology. Uh, now, seriously,
I really felt bad about that.
Felt like an ignorant ass at rather than
just immediately come on and apologize.
I left it up there for the week,
so I'd get my nice pounding from everybody
and uh, yeah. You know what I mean?
I fuck around and said a lot of
fucked up shit, but I, you know,
I'm trying to start your week off right.
I'm not trying to Piss you off,
although there's probably a lot of women
out there who would fucking disagree,
but you know, it's a comedy. You
know, people, people get hurt.
That's how it fucking works.
This is the worst apology ever,
but it's coming from the heart.
All rights. Go Fuck Yourself.
That's how we got to end it.
All right. I grew up in no hugs,
so if I'm trying to be fucking nice,
it has to end with go fuck yourself.
Um, speaking of go fuck yourself.
Um, I just got back from
Portland, Oregon and I had a great
time up at the a helium comedy club,
the grand opening helium
comedy club and Portland,
Oregon is a city that I
have not worked in, um,
in 10 years because there was no comedy
club for a guy in my situation to come
in there and work. Uh, I, I did work,
there was a local club there, but it
wasn't really a comedy club. It was,
but it wasn't like the club on it.
This is basically what he would do.
He would paper the room,
which is a, the showbiz term.
He would just just call people up and I
talk about this last week I came fucking
remember he would just call
people up and just say, you know,
or have this whole team of telemarketers
call up people and tell them that they
want a comedy show.
And he would just call enough people
where he would fill up his room every
fucking night of the week from
Tuesday through Sunday. And uh,
everybody caddied got in for free and
then all he did was fucking just throw
food and drinks down their
fucking throats. And that's
how he makes his million.
But meanwhile,
the comedian stands on stage in front
of a bunch of fucking drunk overeaten
jackasses who could give a fuck about
the show and had to go up there on a
Tuesday night with a goddamn
whipping a chair, two shows, Friday,
three shows Saturday the guy
when he wouldn't even let
you talk to the waitstaff,
you think if you put a
comedian through that bullshit,
they can at least try to get fucking leg,
you know,
try to get a little bit of action.
He fucking cock block young
like nine different levels.
It's a fucking horrific gig
is what I'm telling you.
And then the second you got a
TV credit and you said, hey,
can I have an extra quarter?
The next time I fly across the country.
And then the guide, he just wouldn't
return your phone call. So he basically,
other than up and coming guys would
just be booking horrific talent.
So Portland has been really starved
for any sort of national headliners.
So now there's a new club out there and
I was really excited to be the first guy
to come to town and uh,
and have, uh, you know,
work the comedy club.
And I had no idea how bad that other
club was until I talked to some of the
younger comics. This guy told him,
he walked in there to do with spotty,
moved up from, uh, from host to feature.
And that club owner guy calls
him and he's like, look,
I make $1 million a
year just selling food.
That's what he said.
When you get on stage,
no f bombs that just reads them the
fucking riot act. It's, it was horrible.
It's great business model.
He's made his money,
but it's fucking horrible for
the development of Comedians.
He's just sitting on their fucking chest
and their dicks. He's not even let them
get fucking lay. What did I, you know,
just asshole fucking asshole.
Um,
so it's great that there's a new comedy
club out there and that the, you know,
there's another place for these comics
to work and that they can actually see
national headlines.
Cause that was a fucking big thrill for
me when I was back in Boston. So, uh,
so if you live in the Portland area,
you know, if you're a lumberjack,
climbed down out of the fucking tree
and come on down and do a helium comedy
club. It's a great club. And uh,
he's got C's. Who's he got next week?
He's got a Jimmy Pardot.
Yeah.
Is who he's got Jimmy Pardot a
right. Is that what it is? What?
I think there was one
other person, um, oh,
Reggie watts.
Reggie rots on Wednesday and then Jimmy
Pardot from the never not funny podcast.
Jesus Christ. I'm losing my goddamn
memory. I knew there was somebody else.
So go check out those
shows next week and uh,
support a comedy club. That actual books.
Somebody who's funny and on television.
All right, low plowing ahead here. Um,
what's the next thing on the docket? I
really have, I don't have shit this week.
Do I? One of my 17 minutes
in. That's not bad.
You gonna fucking tap out
at 40 minutes yet. You know,
you guys don't go home early every once
in awhile and just fake a fucking injury
at work. Try to pretend like a
forklift drove over you some shit.
You know what I really wanted to do was
I wanted to look that five hour energy
here on the Internet,
five hour energy.
Now this is how I do my research now.
Five hour energy I think is a liquid
cocaine and I think it really fucks with
you. I think it's bad. So, um,
rather than just look up five
hour energy consumer reports,
I'm going to search five
hour energy unhealthy. See,
and this is how most people do research.
They already have their mind made up
and then they just read shit that agrees
with them.
Yeah.
You know, according to a fuck
face.com um, I'm exactly right.
Side effects to five hour energy drink
shots. Are they unhealthily unhealthy?
Let's read this one. This is the first
one that came up. Side effects of 500 to,
okay.
I was at lunch today and my friend was
trying to get someone to drink five hour
energy caffeine shot.
So I,
I opened it and smelled it and
said I'd give it a shot anyways,
I think he's supposed
to mix them in a drink,
but I straight chage that chugged
it and almost gagged from the taste.
After I swallowed it, it took me like
50 minutes to get that horrible taste.
Uh, out of my mouth. I tried
eating food, chewing gum, drinking,
but the tastes stayed in my
mouth for like 40 minutes.
Okay.
I felt sick every time I
thought about the taste.
I think the taste bothered me so
much. Uh, Jesus, why you do research?
Are you going to get to the part?
We had the heart attack so
I can feel like I'm right.
Yeah,
take the taste bothered me so
much caffeine. But anyways,
I'm shy. So after the tastes
and the sickness wore off,
I was feeling great all day and I felt
probably the happiest I have all school
year because all my subtle tendencies
wore off and I acted more outgoing and
funny like I do around friends.
They just turn this dude
into a fucking coke head.
That's classic reason why people
do drugs. Helps me loosen up, man.
I could talk to the chicks.
Um,
there's nothing on here.
Are you shitting me?
Oh,
gives a fuck.
Okay.
I just, you know, why don't
you get eight hours sleep?
Why don't you do want to just start
that? You know, I had somebody else,
another mother call in a or call in or
write in going back to that fucking that
shit I said about stay at home moms and
once again they were doing, she was,
she was saying, I totally agree with you.
I understand. You're absolutely right.
They have no right to be come saying
it's the most difficult job ever.
And then she wrote three paragraphs about
how difficult it is to be a mother and
to be worrying up in having
the responsibility of
another life. And it's like,
I like, I don't, I get it. I know I don't
totally get it cause I don't have a kid.
But you know
enough already.
Yeah.
All right. Like that other listeners
said, you chose to be a mother.
You know you're acting like a,
all of a sudden you've got
like a fucking terminal disease
and all you're doing is bringing up
the bad shit. What about when you have,
you have a bad day and you
come home and that kid with,
you know all that innocent just looks at
you and just thinks you're bigger than
life. What about that? Doesn't
that, that, that you know?
Yeah.
Wash away some of the spittle
on your shoulder blade.
I don't fucking know.
You know, it's funny,
actually ironic was I just watching 60
minutes and they have one of those guys
on the fucking BP oil rig and I
said when they jumped off of it,
it was the equivalent of jumping off
a three story fucking brownstone.
Evidently it's the equivalent of
jumping off a 10 story fucking building.
That's what they did.
That was their choice standing there
in the middle of the Goddamn Ocean.
Either I burn up. All right, jump into
the fucking oily water without, oh,
it was brutal.
Okay, so while you mom stand the
fuck down, stop giving me shit.
I was just fucking joking around.
I'm just gonna have to end up
apologizing to everybody here. You know,
I had somebody writing to
me today from a New Zealand.
It's podcast is really going to be random.
Somebody wrote it from a New Zealand.
I was thinking about this topic that from
people and all these random countries
who listened to this podcast.
I'm going to start nominating who I think
the coolest person from your country
is. And with new New Zealand,
I think it's a no brainer.
It's Phil Rudd.
You don't get any cooler than that guy.
He's played the exact same drum beat for
fucking 35 years and he's such a tough
bastard that no one has the balls
to tell him to switch it up.
You don't feel like, how about boom chuck,
boom, check, check. Yet. How about that
fucking guy? The whole fucking,
the whole goddamn album.
I think he just goes in there.
Right?
And he just starts fucking playing
that beat and then they just,
they just play the whole song.
The whole fucking album worth of socks.
Yeah.
And then when they're done, they
just, they just start yelling, fell,
fail. It's over. We're done.
Yeah. We made another album
and he's just like, oh, all right. Yeah.
It's just starts breaking down his kit.
Oh Geez. I got nothing. I
really riffing about Phil Rudd.
There was some of the worst
beat box and you're ever going to fucking
here. Um Oh, here we go. You know what?
I got to read this right here.
Now I got something.
This will take up a good three fucking
minutes. You know what? I liked it.
This podcast is this difficult. Now
you guys can relate to me. You know,
you sitting there and your Goddamn
cubicles on a fucking Monday,
unless you're white, of course
you're out on your yacht. You know,
chat it up with a Kennedy.
Hey, when's the stock market going
to crash again? Give me the heads up.
Don't tell the Puerto Ricans.
That's what it's like.
That's exactly what it's like.
Okay.
There's not white people
work in farms,
slaves to corporations.
No, not at all. Not at all. All you
do you, you don't have to get up.
You don't have to get up.
I spent nine years in bed just because
I was white and they just fucking
hilarious.
I made more money then than when I worked.
That's how great it is to be white.
It's so fucking easy and thank
God for people who aren't white,
who've never been white to tell
me what it's like to be white.
It's fucking awesome.
Let me tell you something about being
white white guy is how good it is.
Oh yeah.
What do you reincarnated was
your name frank and another life.
Um, is that a white guy name? I don't
fucking know. All right. So anyway,
so I've pissed off a bunch of
people and uh, I just want to,
I just want to try to redeem myself
and show you that it's not all bad. I,
that's not all bad. You know, I do inspire
some people. Uh, here's one for you.
Milk white thighs is the name of this.
This email,
somebody sent me a, it
said bill. A few things. A,
the last five years I've been
six feet tall, 240 pounds.
I print trying to work out with
no results and no willpower.
I usually lose five pounds,
give up and sit in each shit.
However, you talked on the podcast a few
weeks ago about Bill Clinton and Al Gore
sloshing around the White House.
I believe I said sashaying around the
White House with their milky white hips.
Um, I was in a quiet room with
about 15 people and blurted,
blurt, laughed out loud, laughed
loudly, blurt laughed loudly.
That's really worded strangely. You
burst out laughing. There we go.
Ever since then. How will
be sitting, watching TV,
looking at my treadmill
and I will say to myself,
slosh your ass up there and work off those
milky white hips or something to that
effect. It makes me laugh every time
and realize how pathetic I've been.
It's been about three weeks.
If this every day and 45
minutes on the treadmill,
I'm down to 208 pounds.
Well,
on my way to my goal of
a hub of a buck 80. Also,
I'm a dude and my name is Lindsey.
I know you don't have a
lot of female listeners,
so if you ever feel like you need a
quote or just a woman's approval on
something, you do, feel free
to use my name and just say,
yeah, this chick Lindsay,
I know this chick Lindsay who digs it.
Uh,
I'm more than willing to compromise my
sexuality for the furthering of your
career.
Um,
I would buy five of anything, Bill burrs
endorsing. All right, there you go.
There's a good email. Congratulations.
You're down to 208. Keep going.
And, uh, I'm glad. You know,
I'm glad I just didn't bring all
negativity to the podcast this past week.
I felt fucking horrible about that even
though I've been kind of a cunt again
this week. That's what I do. You
know, you came back, didn't you?
You know, I don't know any better.
I'm just a white guy laying in bed.
I can't remember the last time
I've had disappointment in my life.
It just doesn't happen. Just
doesn't happen, you know? You know,
sometimes the sale on my schooner
will break and I'm just like,
oh Jesus Christ. And then I call the
government and I say, can you, uh,
can you send me another one? They're like,
white and what color are you? I said,
why they guy? There you
go. Right on the way.
You know, I agree with the first half of
the email. This guy I'm making fun of,
but I would love to send this guy
my fucking taxes. I really would.
These mother fuckers,
what a lot of people don't realize is
that rich people feel there's enough rich
people and they got all kinds of fucking,
they take a fucking pipe,
Tia.
God damn knees every fucking quarter.
They make sure they can only be,
they can only be a certain number or
a fucking rich people unless you just
invent some shit like,
uh, I dunno. I Dunno what
if you come up with the technology
for the fucking iPod then even then,
I mean they'll just, they'll just,
hi. Yon Is like a scientist, right?
I'm really getting to know over my
fucking head here. You know what I mean?
Do you come up with Facebook? If you
reinvent that? I think that's the way,
now that you can actually become fucking
rich, but I'll tell you right now,
it's not fucking telling jokes.
Fucking assholes.
Goddamn fucking quarter.
I gotta I gotta. Oh Gee. I
am my man to get into it.
I'm not going to fucking get it. Just
give me some me so fucking mad your time.
I think I'm getting
ahead. Look at me. Yeah,
I'm getting the hey a fucking sit down.
That's what they do every quarter.
You sit the fuck down. You stay
right where you're at. Hey,
sit right where you're at.
It's what it is. Anybody else?
This isn't even a color thing. Anybody
else in the fucking middle class you go,
it's fucking rich pricks
fucking less goddamn eight years and then
making a ton of fucking money and then
all of a sudden the shit hits the
fan and they run out of the God damn
restaurant. Leave everybody
else with the fucking check.
Fucking unbelievable.
My ever going to get that fucking car.
I'll tell you.
And I got off the plane today and somebody
had the dodge challenger in the all
white, like the vanishing point guys ever
see that movie with that Dude Kowalski.
He's got an all white charger.
So they did this tribute to,
it's all fucking white and the guy
had these fucking rims on it and uh,
okay.
I just sat there drooling at it. My
girl's looking at me like, she's like,
Jesus Christ, you were obsessed
with that car. It's like, yeah,
you know I am. Okay. Well,
you know, I'm standing here.
You just got off the plane. You
could say hello to me, you know?
Oh, you know what that reminds me of. I
fucking went to go to this pizza place.
I really try to do fun things. When I
was in Portland, tried to be healthy.
I went for a fucking hike. I was
sticking with my smoothies, you know,
dropping pounds here and uh,
okay.
Anyway, somebody tells me that in, in
Portland, they have this fucking room.
They got this pizza parlor where they
had the best God damn pizza and all the
fucking northwest.
So this guy has like this homemade God
damn doe and he only makes so much of it
every day. And when he's done making
the dough, he's done making pizza.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right. So
I'm like, you know, well shit,
I got to try this pizza. So I go on the
Internet, I look up, I see where it is.
It's right on Hawthorne Street.
Okay.
Like 45th and Hawthorne, 46 and Hawthorne,
something like that. Right. So I'm like,
alright, I gotta go check this
fucking thing out. So I allow,
I get myself an hour and a half before
the show to get there to get a God damn
pizza. Right? It's a fucking pizza. Okay.
So I call up just something told
me to cut just to call this place.
And uh, I call up the, it rings like 11,
12 fucking times and nobody
picks up. So I'm like, Eh,
you know what, the probably busy, no big
deal. I got an a, I'm, I'll get there.
We're an hour and a half before,
right? I get a goddamn cab.
I'm driving over there. Cab driver
goes, oh, just to let you know,
this guy's kind of like the
pizza Nazis, like, like the,
like the fucking a soup Nazi on Seinfeld.
So I show up and I walk in. Lo
and behold, the place is packed,
but I see this little two top gets up,
waitresses cleaning off the table.
She walks away.
So I go over and I sit down
getting ready to order the pizza.
I'm checking out what people are ordering
of getting excited is what I'm trying
to tell you. And then the waitress
comes over, she's like, um,
were you over in the waiting room next
door or did you just like walk in here
and sit down? And I was like, um, I
just came in and sat down. She goes,
yeah, I'm, you have to like sign in, um,
next door and all those people,
everything's,
everything's a question you'd
have to like sign in next door.
And I'm like, oh, all right. I go, well,
how long is the wait? She's like, wow,
I can't really like say it's, you
know, it's kind of busy at that point.
It's like a quarter of it go, well, I
got to show at eight to quarter to seven.
Am I going to have time to order a
pizza and eat it? She's like, yeah,
now,
now and um,
and then that's when my blood starts
fucking boiling because I realized what I
just walked into.
You know what I walked into?
I walked into the pizza version of
pink's hot dogs out here in fucking La,
the pizza version of
magnolia bakery in new city,
all that fucking place.
We get the hot dogs in Chicago,
you know,
hour and 15 minutes to make a
fucking pizza. You can't do that.
Sky's sitting here acting like,
you know,
like he's making some sort of gourmet
food out. I'll tell you right now,
that's my overrated for the fucking week.
Standing in line at any restaurant.
These, you know, the, the, the
breakfast place in your neighborhood.
You girlfriend's like,
oh my God,
the stuffed French toast is to die for
and you stand there and fucking line,
never worth it. It's never
worth the hype. Okay?
If you learn anything from this podcast
other than I'm an ignorant asshole,
don't ever stand in line for
fucking food. Okay? And less some,
there's a natural disaster.
The places flooded and this dis
scooping out fucking pea soup.
You know when you're putting
it into your baseball hat,
then you'll stand in line. Soup
kitchen. You stand in life,
but don't stand outside these fucking
places. It's stupid. It's never worth it.
You know, fancy restaurants. You
don't stand outside. You call up,
you make a fucking reservation.
But I'm not standing out there
like I'm waiting to fucking,
did they even make God damn sense.
You know what I mean?
It's fucking people in New
York. They stand outside for
90 minutes for a cupcake,
for fucking cupcake.
It's gone in three seconds.
You know it's going to Piss me off.
Is some people in Portland. Okay.
They're actually going to figure out
what pizza parlor I'm talking about and
then they're going to tile. Tell me,
dude, it's totally fucking worth it.
These low self esteem Douche bags
who just allow themselves to get totally
treated like absolute fucking shit for
pizza. Yeah. Sorry,
I can't make you a pizza
within an hour and 15 minutes.
We know what fuck you
and your fucking pizza.
What are you think about that and
your number one goddamn rating.
I got a pizza hut.
Eat their fucking slop.
You have to kill him. He is that. I
know. I'm going to have to go back.
I have to try it.
People hyped it so much.
That's what I'm really
mad about is as I know.
As much as I just fucking
talked about that shit.
I'm going to have to go back
there and go get it and for all.
You guys wander and yelled at
Magnolia. It's, it's a great cupcake,
but it's not that great.
It's not that great to have to stand there
and listen to that awful conversation.
Now if people driving by looking
at you trying to figure it out,
what are they standing in line for?
You know,
is the president,
they're doing a book signing.
Is there a porn star there? I was going
to blow you at the front of the line.
Can I raise the stakes for something
funny within the last seven minutes?
All right. Fuck this. Fuck
this podcast. Here we go.
Why don't I nominate some youtube
videos for the week? Everyone. Um,
I have a ton of them and I'm going to
make the bold rex Ryan statement that I
think pretty goddamn soon if not already.
The MLM podcast.com is going to have the
best fucking youtube video collection
of youtube videos.
Okay.
All right. I mean cause you
guys are on the cutting edge.
A lot of these videos that you guys
send me, they only got like, you know,
10,000 to 40,000 fucking hit.
Some of them have like a hundred
thousand or so like that.
And even a few with a million. But if
they're really funny, I don't give a shit,
but I think that we're on the
cutting edge of some shit.
Like here's two that I found that
have, you know, only, you know,
in the tens of thousands of hits. So
I'm assuming you haven't seen them. Uh,
look up a prank of the century.
This woman puts on a mask and scares the
shit out of this other woman and it's,
you gotta watch it. It's fucking
great. And then piss off.
Pissed off. Cat freaks
out. Look up that one.
Um, and we got a lot of people,
you guys like violence shit.
I'm trying to categorize
them now. Um, and by the way,
the man podcast is the official fan
page or the Monday morning podcast.
If you don't wanna have to,
you know,
it's a pain in the ass to go on youtube
and try to find six different videos,
right? Typing it in and all
that shit. You're going to
get caught. You're at work,
you're not supposed to be doing it.
But if he just subtly type in the MLM,
podcast.com and nobody's fucking looking,
all of them are going to be right there.
And you can watch one after another,
you know, or we can make it
last the whole fucking day.
You can even drink that five hour fucking
energy and just start screaming at
your screen if you want. It's
all up to you. Um, so anyways,
uh, he has a couple of, for you fight
fans out here. I will start slow,
look up a choke slam.
Um,
I hope that's the name
of the fucking video.
Just this referee roughing a
fight and this it's choke slam.
Look it up. All right. Uh,
his kind of a cute one says little
girl boxer. It's actually a boy.
His name's pretty boy. Bam, Bam. And
you got to look at this fucking kid.
This kid would kick the shit.
Just imagine this kid fighting
another fifth grader. Um,
and this is the most insane one.
Boston Street fight guy with bat does
damage Boston Street fight guy with bat as
in baseball. Bat does damage. Um,
what else do we got?
Some ridiculous is something ridiculous.
Swollen in south Philly.
It's a guy walking around like he's got
a fucking hard on having conversations
with people. Sort of an old
bit. I've seen it done before,
but this guy does a great um,
wrestling fans.
We've got two for you.
A mature man on Coke and uh,
ultimate warriors. Confession
is absolutely fucking brilliant.
You got to look at that one. And uh, Oh,
more violence office worker goes insane.
Second Angle.
Evidently there's some new
footage. Uh, what else?
Oh, this is a great one. Look up the
turtle man. This one might be my favorite.
This guy's missing all his front teeth.
And when you find out how
he's missing his teeth,
it's just one of the great stories
that he'd, he'd just alludes to it.
It's fucking awesome.
It's just this redneck who just
fucking catches turtles and a,
I swear to God,
I would pay admission to sit on the
side of the pond and just watch this guy
catching turtles. It's fucking hilarious.
And I actually getting the covers,
we were talking about the
worst covers of all time.
Here's a great one of the
best covers I've ever seen,
just as far as being creative.
Look up a stairway to heaven,
the beatniks and that's all
one word, B, e, a. T. N. I x.
It's fucking cool as hell.
It's really fucking cool.
They do stairway to heaven the way the
Beatles would do it. It's really fucking,
I dunno, it's really creative. Um,
and speaking of movies,
here's one for you is, uh,
I got in this conversation
with somebody on the Internet.
They sent me an email and they were
talking about how, uh, you know,
they're not married yet,
so they're kind of hanging out with
people who are younger than them,
so they get a little bummed out when
they make references to movies that
nobody's seen before. So, uh, he started
showing him some of the classics,
like the dirty dozen and that type
of shit. And he asked me, you know,
what are some of the great fucking
movies, uh, I should recommend.
What then led it to like music
and that type of shit. And, uh,
here's a new topic for you. Is
it? Do you guys have like songs?
You must have these, these fucking
songs that the second you hear them,
you can't hear the song without thinking
of the movie. You know what I mean?
Of course you do. Here I'll, I'll give
you a classic fucking example and uh,
I think even the broads will know
this one. Did I get rid of it?
I had it all fucking cute up.
I really am the worst.
Can I ever do this?
This is why I started off in fucking
radio and then my career quickly ended
because I would do the whole beginning.
You're listening to 6:40 AM
WACB a broadcast service.
The fucking whatever the fuck I
used to say. Hang on a second.
Let me get to youtube. God dammit, Bill.
Yeah.
And now there's a lull. See what happens.
You know what a play the other one. Well,
no, I can't do that at the end and
ability to do that shit. All right,
let me set the mic down. Hang
on a second. All right. Do you,
why don't you act like you're
working for once. All right,
now I'm yelling at you cause I fucked up.
What the hell's the name of that
fucking Saba. Oh, something.
Something. Something.
Something air. It is. I got it.
Hang on. Hang on. Hang on.
Yeah.
Ah, you fucking can't come on. Come up.
Should I edit this out?
You know what this is
like is when you fucking,
someone just told you what their name
is and then somebody you know comes
walking in and you go to introduce and
you have no fucking idea who they are.
Okay.
That's how I'm speaking
right now. All right. What,
what movie does this remind you of?
Instantly.
Come on. You know what?
You know the movie, right?
I know most of you know even the
broads. We'll get it. Come on,
I'll wait for the breakdown.
I'll wait for the breakdown of it.
Where the hell is it?
What did it hell was it?
I had this whole fucking thing queued up.
This part right here.
You don't remember this.
I even did the sound effects.
Remember that reservoir dogs,
when he cuts the fucking dude's ear off.
Okay.
I used to love that God damn song and
I couldn't listen to it for 10 years
because every time I fucking heard it,
I just thought about Marvin Nash
getting his Goddamn ear cut off.
Ah, stop. Stop yelling at him.
Fucking what?
What a great piece of acting
by both of those guys.
Whoever played Marvin Nash and uh,
Mr Blonde. I can never remember
people's fucking names.
Okay.
Uh, we'll call him Vince Gilligan.
I don't know his fucking name now.
How did I fuck that?
I forget his name.
Okay.
You know most guys to play a psycho
would act like a fucking psycho.
How they think a psycho supposed to act.
You know it just how fucking Cami was.
You know, that's what's really fucking
scary. Somebody cutting your ear off,
going with neck like a fucking maniac.
You almost start laughing
halfway through it. Like,
is this guy mocking being crazy? But
it's the calmness with which he does it.
Here's another one for you.
These are really easy for like guy movie,
so I need some more, more suggestions.
I'm actually going to disguise this one.
I downloaded this song because of the
movie and I didn't realize that this
fucking Irish dude babbles telling some
fucking story for 20 minutes before they
get to the part that I
actually recognized. Uh,
let's see if you can guess this
one. Here we go. What movie
goes to
the test with Joyce,
right? You're like, what the fuck is this?
I didn't want to get blood on the floor.
Yup.
Hello.
Audio tion.
That's a Donovan singing a Atlantis.
That was from a,
the Billy bad scene.
When they start kicking the shit.
Fuck it Billy bet.
Is there anything better than that fucking
camera when they're doing that point
in up at Robert De Niro's character?
Jimmy just fucking kicking him.
Rick flair. Couldn't do fake kicks
better than Robert Dinero. You know,
he just sitting there kicking him.
See,
this was bad.
Billy batts was a made guy with
some real grease ball shit.
We did what we wanted.
We were wise guys. Right?
What's the last one I got here? So I want,
I, I, I, you know, as usual, you know,
whenever people ask these questions,
I can't end up, I can't remember him.
MMM.
Let's see.
Here's one for you.
This is actually an interesting
one that's really fucking obscure.
This is one from a movie that
the dude ended up selling.
This is from cool hand Luke.
All right.
For those of you have seen cool hand Luke,
if you haven't seen cool hand Luke,
you got to fucking watch that movie.
All right.
And basically the guy who did
the score, uh, wrote this song.
There's a scene where they
have to tar this road and uh,
Paul Newman's character,
you know,
rather than just sitting there being like,
this is a miserable fucking job.
He gets them all amped up that it's
supposed to take all fucking day,
but he gets these guys so fucking
amped up. They just, they just fucking,
they just,
it's like they took five hour energy
and before they just flying down the
fucking road and they're all laughing,
having a great fucking time.
And they finished the road and they
actually have an afternoon off. Right.
So it was like Paul Newman's way
of saying fuck you to the, to the,
to the, to the screws. Is that what they
call them back then to the, to the guards.
Right. So they had to
have this music. So they,
this guy wrote this score for this scene.
Uh,
but the problem was it
was perfect for the movie,
but the problem was years later he sold
it or I don't know how far along he sold
it and it got played so much in this
other shit that it actually kind of fucks
up the movie. This is, this is the score.
This is going to be for some older
people to actually understand this is the
music that they had for the tea.
It's called tar sequence. When they,
when they tar the road
and they ended up selling,
the guy ended up selling the song
for something else. Here it is.
Just listen to this shit.
Ah,
you suck. God dammit. Fuck the, see,
this is why I got out of range.
I used to do shit like that on the air.
There will be the worst break ever.
I am the fucking worst.
I what a great intro. I gave
that song. All right. Here we go
for and the road totally makes sense.
Wow.
All right.
[inaudible]
good evening and welcome to the six news.
It was a four car accident.
The motherfuckers sold it to
every six o'clock news station.
This was the classic,
if you fucking old like me,
anytime the fucking news came on,
this is the fucking song that they played.
This is back when the,
when they actually had fucking journalists
telling you what the corporations
wanted you to know.
Good evening. I'm Jake Johansen.
When I say, Gee, I'm a Jew.
I was, that's how fucked up my brain is.
I was trying to think, uh, Chet Curtis.
I was like, well, I can't say I can't
say Chet. That's an actual fucking name.
I don't name names. So then
I'll go, I'll go with Jake.
And then for some reason I don't,
it just got crossed up and they said,
Jake Johann's I gave Jake,
Joe answered a fucking shout out the best
God Damn Comedians the last fucking 20
years for my money. So anyways, yeah,
it's called out of the tar sequence.
So that one actually doesn't remind
me of the, the, the, the fuck.
That's a reverse one.
I actually watched the movie and I'm
getting into that scene and then I think
there's like all of a sudden I'm
going to start listening to the news.
So Jesus Christ,
that was,
that was probably the worst debut
of any segment. But you knew,
you got to admit you were
definitely into it, right?
I know you guys have suggestions.
Can you help me out? All right.
I'm fucking burned out
with this fucking podcast.
I'm trying to get ready to do other
shit and I'm just, you know, look at me.
I'm fucking supporting Nazis now cause
that what I'm doing is that I'll fucking
tired. I am doctor Laura. If you're
not a bad birthday book and Moron.
All right, here's one for you. You know
what? I'm going to actually do one.
I'm going to do one here for it to try
to make peace after my doctor Laura a
Dr Laura comments, here we go. Uh,
wait a minute. Wait a minute. I got
to get a secretary for this shit.
All right. Where the fuck are we?
Yeah, I fucking hate you tube.
I don't want you douchebags doing the
fucking thing. I want the actual guy.
Everybody doing a fucking remix.
Wait, hang on. Hang in there.
There it is. [inaudible] we go. Alright.
Now this one's mainly going to be
for, uh, the people that I offended
last week. Last week,
uh, with the fuck is it?
Come on now. All right, here we go.
Here we go. This isn't going to remind,
this isn't going to remind you of a movie.
This is going to remind you of a TV
show. What? What show was this? Hang on.
This is the last one.
Come on. Wait a minute.
You fucking cunt.
Okay.
I did. I didn't hit pause. Did I? Hang on.
All right. This is going to remind
you of a TV show. What TV show.
Okay.
I somehow missed that when that came
out. That is a, that's the Carlton Dance.
I think I was too old for that one. I
kind of tapped out with sitcoms after, uh,
after why happy days.
And I wanted the cheers.
I started Busan and actually
believed cheers, you know,
I believe that,
you know,
there was a bar like that and you come
in and just being an alcoholic was like
funny and fulfilling.
I guess there was the sadness.
He completely avoided his wife,
Vera, and they never showed her. Um,
anyways, you know what? I think that's
going to be the podcast for the week.
I have to, I got a tap out
here, man. This, this, uh,
this trying to do one on the road the
day after I come off the road is really
difficult. But, uh,
fortunately thanks to been
going well that I'm really busy.
So I guess that is a good fucking thing.
But you know,
you get used to this comedian lifestyle.
Well,
you just get to fucking hang out
on a Monday. Now I actually, uh,
I have shit to do,
which is annoying.
It's not why I started being a comedian.
I started to be a comedian,
so I would not have shit to do,
you know,
wouldn't have a boss tell fucking jokes,
talk about my Dick in all 50 states
and whatnot. Believe it or not.
People, my neck stand up date
isn't until September 9th, uh,
at the comedy works in Denver, Colorado.
Let's blow through some date shall we,
by the way,
my tickets from my big theater show,
my big theater tour that I'm doing,
um,
are on sale now. And uh, I don't have
the fucking link. Do I? Where is it?
Oh, you got to live nation.com, um,
slash bill burr tickets or he just got
a billboard.com. You just click on any,
any of the dates here. I'm going to be
a, before the theater's tour starts.
I mean also going to be at
xannies comedy club in Nashville,
Tennessee on our September 23rd,
24th and 25th.
One of, uh, one of my favorite clubs to
play as is the comedy works in Denver.
September 10th. Well, we've
got this September 10th,
11th, I have September 9th,
10th and the 11th. There we go.
That's what I'm working there. Um,
and then starts to theater shit.
I'm going to be at the egg in Albany,
New York.
All you people in upstate New York.
We're always say come to upstate New York,
man. What the fuck? I'm going to be there.
I'm going to be at the egg in Albany,
New York.
And then the following day I'm going
to be at the center for the arts,
Buffalo, New York. Um, so I'm
finally coming to buffalo.
I'm actually hitting up a bunch of
towns that I haven't been to in fucking
forever. Uh, another city, a city.
I've never done standup in a full set.
I've done a guest set,
but I've never gotten a gig out there.
I'm going to be at the
pantageous Pantages Pan,
an ageless, whatever the fuck
it is, theater in Minneapolis,
Minnesota on October 22nd.
And then the following day I'm going
to be at the Vic Theater in Chicago,
Illinois on, um, October 23rd.
And uh, any other ones? I
got another theater date.
On November 19th I met the
listener auditorium, Washington,
D C and a,
the last theater I have is
the more theater in Seattle,
Washington on November 27th.
Uh,
you can go on to bill bird.com and just
click on the links in the lower left hand
corner and you can check out
all that bullshit. And, uh,
hopefully you'll come out to the
shows. We'll see how it goes. Um,
for those of you wondering if I'm just
going to try to do theaters exclusively,
um, no, I am not. I'm always going to
be doing the clubs. The clubs are like,
the gym keeps you in shape, you
come in, you do five, six shows,
and then every once in a while like,
uh, like Buffalo, I don't know,
they don't really have like a
big time comedy club out there.
No disrespect to anybody out there.
So while you just come in,
you try to do with theater. Same
thing with Albany, you know,
you start going to those really smaller
fucking towns or smaller comedy markets.
And then that's just when, you know,
the local comedy club is just nay nay,
you know, like knee slappers, you know.
Um, God damn it, you're funny.
Who's ready to laugh? You know, they
just got awful fucking names and uh,
yeah. And they try to make
you stay in a comedy condo.
So that's why I always
avoided those things.
And I tried to stay in the
bigger markets where that could,
they actually put me in a hotel. I'm
like, you, I like my comforts. So,
uh, that's, that's the big,
uh, my big tour coming up.
And there's also a date there I missed in
Columbus, Ohio. That's a club date. Uh,
November 12th, 13th, and 14th. And
the fucking, you know what kills me,
it's how quick that's all gonna go by and
another year is going to go by as well
as, you know, by the end of that tour, um,
football season will be three quarters
over. How fucking sad is that?
At least the regular season.
Uh, who do you like by the way?
Anybody?
Anybody for some predictions.
How about we try to do some predictions
and whoever comes to fucking closest
gets a, an audit, grab an autograft DVD of
my brand new DVD.
Let it go.
Because by then it'll be the end of
the season and I'll fucking sent, Nah,
I'm not going to do that then
you won't fucking buy it. Right.
I need to get you to buy it. Goddammit.
I suck at marketing. Anyways.
That's a podcast for this week
was very disjointed. I, you know,
they can't all be gold. You
know, even Peyton manning,
he throws an interception every once in
a while and the file drive of a fucking
Superbowl doesn't he? Well, doesn't,
he actually saw what's his face. Uh,
drew Brees finally getting some props.
He came in there with John Gruden,
you know, John Green's got that
unbelievable intensity that,
that vein down the middle of his forehead.
That's one of my favorite
announcers out there are color men,
whatever the hell that guy's
doing that guys to shit.
This is not the better than an
ex football player. And this is,
this is provided that they
have broadcasting skills.
Somebody that played the game,
coached the game and that type of shit.
And then you get the classic
like broadcaster, like, uh,
like an Al Michaels or something like
that to call the game. And then, uh,
then you got your crew.
Thank you bill.
Thank you for breaking that down
is if we didn't fucking notice,
why don't you just admit bill,
that you just babbling at this point to
somehow try and make it to 'em up to 57
minutes. That qualifies. I
can tap out at this point.
I don't you guys leave sometimes
three minutes before five.
So what did we learn this week?
We learned that even on major topics
like race bill really doesn't do his
research. Uh, we learned
that I yet at y. Uh,
then I got some fat guy with the milky
white ties to laugh at himself and he's
lost 40 pounds. So I'm not
totally a bad guy. And uh,
I guess from the troops come back,
send them a drink or get, get him,
get him a blow job or shut your
face. And evidently they, they,
they feel the same way of that support.
The troop bumper stickers is,
I do you like I'm taking one marine,
his point of view and just saying that
that's everybody's well that's what the
fuck I do. That's what I
do, support the troops.
I always thought it was ridiculous.
So out of those bumper stickers that said,
I support the troops, it's like,
well, why wouldn't you? What do you,
what are you rooting
for? The, the other team.
So fucking obvious. I support the
troops. Ice Cream tastes good.
Okay.
I like babies.
You know what?
He's gonna have all kinds
of obvious bumper stickers
on the back of your fucking
car. I saw a guy had a
big heart on, on his,
on his side of his house.
It said love our troops.
It just really gave me the creeps.
And every time I see it,
I want to fucking rip it down.
You know, I, this other guy,
ray wrote me an angry fucking email all
about the politics about setting the
troops over there, you
know? And it's just like,
like he was fucking dropping
all this knowledge man,
about what's really going on
with the war man. You know,
like I don't realize,
like I don't realize that shit.
I also realized that those guys don't
determined where the fuck they go.
All right? So I'm just trying not to be a
Dick, you know, pick up in a dick enough,
haven't I?
I've gotta be honest with you.
I have no idea what I said
for the last 11 minutes,
but all I know is I recorded it
and you're listening to it. Okay.
So who's worse make you guys just
shaking your heads right now.
He's really losing his mind. Well,
maybe I am. Um, that's it. So I got to,
I got like two,
three weeks off on be hanging out.
Could be gone doing a lot of
spots down the comedy store.
If you're in Los Angeles,
going to be working out my shit.
If you want to come down there,
watch me bomb. Lean on the mic.
Stand and stare at that. All weather
carpet is, I work out my bits,
uh, pop in down the comedy store and
that's it. Thanks. Everybody wrote in,
uh, that is it. I'll talk
to you guys next week.
Yeah.