Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday, Monday
morning podcast. And Ah,
just checking in on you.
Hey Bill, what the fuck?
Why are you checking in on us? So
fucking late this week, dude. Ah,
what'd you have a fucking hernia?
Is that what happened? What did you,
did you get hit by a car? Uh, no. I, I,
it's been the most difficult podcasts
I've ever had to record you guys.
I need a startup for my
emotions. Um, honestly,
honestly, uh, uh, I don't
know what happened. I fucking,
I got real busy and then I recorded the
podcast and for some reason there was no
audio. I can't figure out what
the fuck I did to my Miksa. Oh,
I did something. All freckles did
something. So this is my second attempt.
The last attempt was,
believe it or not,
I believe it was on
Thursday hours on Wednesday.
I swear to God the dog ate my homework.
That's literally what I'm telling you in
a podcasting way. Um, so I'm back to a,
one of my original mixers here.
Thank God I didn't throw it out.
Thank God I'm a bit of
a pack rat you guys. No,
actually I didn't want to throw it out
because I was going to give it away to
somebody. What I wanted to do. That
was the thing I was going to be like.
Do you mind?
You realize the amount of times a semi
known comics said the word cunt into this
mixer, mixer, mixer.
And I thought it'd be worth something
to somebody that they would take it. Um,
but I never got around to doing that.
And thank God I had a backup mixer. Ah,
that's the level that
I'm bawling at right now.
You got to mix it, buddy. I
got a mixer and a backup mixer.
What the fuck do you got? You know,
if they still had MTV cribs right now,
I would be on it would lifestyles
of the rich and famous.
They have one and a half mixes.
Um,
all right, it's Saturday,
Saturday. All right.
And Moe freckles has been,
uh,
alcohol free for nine miserable
fucking weeks. It's actually, you know,
something, I'm at the point
now, I don't even give a shit.
I don't think I think about
it occasionally, but now
when I think about it,
I think, but why would I
go back to that? Huh? Oh,
Billy booze face sitting back enjoying
himself after a long day of hard work of
performing words that other people wrote.
Do you guys realize,
realize how hard it is to be an actor
sometimes to just show up and say things
that people already said
for you on a piece of paper.
Um, that's one of the reasons
why this week's a little crazy.
So I got a little acting gig
over the next, uh, week or so,
and a mon general hospital. Um, no,
and I'm not allowed to say everything.
You're not allowed to say now because
you've got all these fucking cops.
Everybody tries to figure out what
you're on and then they start,
I don't know what they do.
And then somehow they know what
you're doing before you even shoot it.
That's like the level of technology.
Okay.
If you actually say what you're acting
on and somebody's listening to you on a
podcast has a drone with
one of those Gopros,
somehow they will know what senior doing,
but the next day before you are,
before you do
okay,
speak in a drones.
Do you know that the next level of Uber,
the next level of lift,
the next level of fucking
is early to fucking,
there's only two of them
either take Lyft or waste.
It's like back in the day when there
was VHS or Beta and everybody chose VHS.
So think about that. The next time you're
going to get in a car with a stranger.
Huh?
Um, there's a bunch of weird movies
coming out now that I don't understand.
You know, this is a fucking
documentary right now in, in, in, uh,
in Sundance.
It's,
I can't, but I glanced at it quickly.
I think it said it was four hours long.
It can't be four hours long.
It's a documentary about two now
adults who said when they were kids,
they allegedly got molested by Michael
Jackson. Now I gotta ask you this,
why the fuck would I want
to sit down and watch that?
I'm going to sit there with a bucket of
popcorn and some fucking junior mints.
Alright, let me hear the worst
story that can happen to a kid.
You know, you know, some people
say, oh, they just do it for my,
I don't know what the fuck happened.
I wasn't there, but let's, you know,
true or untrue.
I don't want to listen to those stories.
What kind of a fucking person
wants to fucking sit down?
You go to the movies, you know
you're going to get something to eat
and you're sitting there at the cow.
Oh, what do you feel like indulging in?
Before we listened to this horror?
MMM.
I don't know. But when I go back to,
I think when I saw Schindler's list,
I believe I was eating popcorn.
I mean that this certain movies,
they should not,
you should not be sitting there
stuffing your face with food, right?
We now have a documentary about the
genocide in Rwanda and out of respect for
the victims than you fat Americans will
be allowed to eat over the next two
hours. Aw, everybody fucking groans.
Hashtag hypoglycemic. Um, anyways,
so they, they uh, getting
back to the drones,
the next level of Uber is that they're
actually going to have, I swear to God,
like unmanned
drones,
I guess none of them really mad right now
that you can get into like a life size
one,
like a human size one.
Okay.
And you get in this fucking thing
and you fly over the traffic
like
a,
like I do when I fly one of the Helio
type copters and I have to tell you this,
you are out of your fucking mind.
If you remember with Lasik eye
surgery when that first came out,
do you remember that? And that'd be a
couple of fucking people go, oh my God,
I can see it to the future. But like
one out of every 15, we'd be like, Mike,
what did you, I'll never see again. Yeah.
There's going to be the first week
of Lasik eye surgery version of that.
Okay?
I want to know how in the fuck the FAA
is going to fucking sign off on that one.
You know,
God damn well there's,
it was a glitch that hatch just blue.
You're going to have the Gus Grissom
fucking, something's going to happen.
You know it's bad enough that you're going
to have the person up there careening
down or falling down to their death.
You're going to be sitting there
fucking watching NFL Bup, bup, bup,
but a bad app in a fucking hipster.
It's going to fall through your
goddamned ceiling. Tight jeans and all.
Okay?
You know,
Hitler youth fucking fade with the A,
I know how to make shoes by by hand.
Beard that he thought he's going to have
is going to come fallen right through
your fucking ceiling.
I don't know. You know, you know,
you'd think if fucking people like Elon
Musk or trying to figure out a way to
drill through the God damn earth and
now they're going to have unmanned,
unmanned people, unmanned
people, unmanned devices,
flying people around up there. You
take it. Some people at some point,
Jesus Christ,
the kid speak,
somebody would addressed the
fucking population problem.
Okay.
Signs. You have too many people. Uh,
we're going to have unmanned drones flying
people over densely populated areas.
Hey everybody, you have cell
phones, you have laptops.
How many times?
What?
What's the longest they've consistently
worked before you had to refresh it
or shut it down or restart it or
take it over to the apple store.
So one of the geniuses get,
be like, oh, oh, I find the,
I found the problem.
Yeah.
People in aviation, you can't
hit a refresh button. Okay. Yeah.
They refresh. They refreshed by hosing
off wherever the fuck you crash landed.
Let's refresh this scorched earth.
Um,
and then it will be like,
well shit,
they installed like horror struck today
when to hipsters from several lake.
We're trying to get from silver lake out
to Santa Monica to go to a craft beer
tasting fucking festival, whatever
the, whatever the fuck it is they do
to go to a pocket watch convention yet.
And then love followed through
some fucking, you know,
yeah.
Not paid in a month.
Air traffic controllers.
Fucking a irony struck today.
Um,
I dunno audio,
you're out of your fucking mind and I
also got to think it's going to be at
least 300 bucks per trip.
That'll become some elite thing.
And then there'll be like, you know,
we have to have affordable on man.
Droned why you saying unmanned bill?
You know why?
Because man learned how to fly not women.
And I'm sure when Hollywood
does the fucking next bio
pic of Orville and Wilbur,
it will be like, well, why
can't it be Orval in Wilma?
And they'll make one of them a woman
and they'll make some sort of backstory
that one of them actually identified as
female just so they don't get yelled at
on Twitter.
Okay.
Or Villain Wilma.
We're very proud of this,
that the real story of fucking Devil's
island, whatever the fuck they call,
wherever they,
they actually,
where they learned how to fly is
like some devil's something or other.
Okay.
No, I'm sure there's some Jesus fucking
group out there. Jesus Freak Group.
We'll just talk. Okay. That's why you pay
you right now. Let's swap. Flight is evil.
Ain't you ever read the story of Icarus
flew too close to the sun and his and
his winged is wing base caught on fire
and he went all the way back down to
earth and he continued to fall to earth
through the earth into the pits and the
flames of hail.
Yeah.
Um, I dunno what I'm talking
about and I don't give a shit.
I'm just contractually obligated here
to give you guys some sort of an effort
for 30 minutes. Okay. That's what
you get. Not to me. Oh, by the way,
speaking of efforts
Sunday, tomorrow, Sunday,
okay.
Whatever. Fucked. January
27 2019 this is the,
this is the soft open of a sports
world without football for the next six
months.
This is the one,
okay.
Yeah. Gift. Giphy can, you know, God
bless ESPN. God Bless Fox sports the way,
the way they're going to be.
Keep yammering on on Sunday
as if something sports wise
is actually happening in
football.
What?
Down here at the trade and
Kevin Rob Grad Caskey is,
is touching his left hand
to his right fucking clique.
Rob,
you find it harder to reach to the right
one with your left hand or the left one
with your right hand?
I'm sorry rob.
Gronkowski he's not answering
questions right now. I mean,
who the fuck is going to sit
around and watch that? All right.
They used to at least
have the goddamn pro bowl.
Okay.
They had something going on.
Um, but that's it. People.
There's only one more week of NFL
football and there's only two teams left.
All right,
one left.
So you have to ask yourself,
who are you inviting to
your Superbowl party?
Huh?
Are you going to have the balls
to fucking only invite sports fans?
I guess if your team isn't in it, why
do you give a shit? Why not be social?
You know what I mean?
Why not have a bunch of people
come over who don't give a fuck?
They're just there for the Burgers,
the Doritos, the fucking hot dogs,
the stupid dips, that fucking thing that
somebody made that nobody really likes.
But they bring it every
year and everybody's got to
take at least one fucking
bite out of the thing and be like,
ah,
it's even fucking better than last year.
I think. I'm thinking, I'm toying
with the idea of having people over.
It's going to be a select few.
All right.
And they will come in in unmanned drones
and hopefully not fall through the
fucking roof of my house.
That's what I'm hoping.
That's what I'm hoping happens.
Now,
why the fuck is this? This seems like
the sound is down low on this one.
At she says, Christ, who
knows who the fuck knows?
I just want to thank all the brave men
and women who make the mixers out there
who are fighting for my freedom and
defending this country against terrorism.
How's that dude? How much longer is
this government shutdown? Gonna lie.
This is like the most
fucking petty God damn like.
And I don't understand too why if
the government shuts down, okay.
Uh, air traffic controllers and
people like that. They don't get paid,
but politicians continue
to get fucking paid. I bet.
I'll tell. I'll go out
on a limb here. I'll bet.
Because there was some sort of
legislation that a fucking politician paid
somebody to come up with and they all
fucking agreed and they all agreed to be,
I guess we will continue to get
paid those fucking filthy counts.
I still don't understand how somebody
could actually be a Democrat or Republican
when you watch behavior like this
feed actually just fucking sit there,
you know? I mean I don't know when I'm
going to sit here and I'm going to,
but I'm going to do now is do
what every fucking cunt does,
which is I'm going to state the
obvious without a solution, you know,
and act like I am above you. All right.
That's what I mean. I do that in general.
Just part of being a former
part of getting on stage,
part of being back and waiting for your
name to be called and feeling that rush
of excitement that can only be describe
to someone else who was taking the stage.
Um,
you know, when you speak into
a microphone, there's this,
you just feel like you know things.
All right?
And I apologize to all of you poor people
out there who never in your life where
you know the thrill of not reading
and simply turning on a device,
speaking into a microphone,
recording yourself. You know,
I felt bad for you. You know,
I respect all of you. You know,
you put your pants on one leg at a time.
You know Joe Sixpack Shuggie you get
through at least four beers before you
physically abused the woman in your life.
You know the regular joes out
their lunch pail, Larry, right?
Ham Hock Harry,
you know,
fucking Capri Sun,
Sandra Capri Sun. Where the fuck that I
pulled that out of that. I don't know.
I never, I never got into those
fucking juice is back in the day.
I'll add fucking weird shit.
People used to eight.
What were those things during lunchtime
30 fucking years ago in the cafeteria
I'd go to, it would literally be what
they call it, fruit rollups. Okay.
You said this shit, fruit roll ups
and I swear to God it looked like wax.
These people would just fucking just
be, I don't know what it was. It was,
it was some sort of fruit and fused
flavor with like a pound of sugar.
And then, uh, I dunno,
earwax from fucking workers in a
third world plant or some shit.
I don't know what it wasn't. Kids would
sit there and eat. I mean, you know what?
Nobody died. Nobody died. And, and,
and the world was actually was in
a lot of ways, was a better place.
I'm not saying we were as progressive
as we are today.
Some would argue overly progressive.
And when I say some,
I would say a lot of the
voices in my head would say,
I think we're going a little too
far with this shit. You know?
Okay,
well you start giving
actors shit for acting.
Okay.
Why are you pretending to be
something that you're not a,
because it's acting that that
is what acting is. Okay. If you,
if you take an acting job and you
just act what you already are,
that's not really acting,
which is why so many people have done
a decent job be and what they are on
sprayed and then everybody thinks
they can act. Oh, I can act.
Okay.
Acted z Z.
Remember when that chick from hall,
that crazy drug addicted chick from whole
played the crazy drug addicted chicken,
that fucking bitch,
she was unbelievable as it crate
that crazy drug addicted chick.
I couldn't leave out. Well, she
played a crazy drug addicted check,
let's say in every crazy drug addicted
woman can then go on screen and there is
a certain level of fucking towel,
but k,
but don't put yourself on the
same level that my left foot guy,
okay.
Guy Walks around acting like Abe Lincoln
for a fucking year before he's actually
a Blinken.
Okay.
Then you're going to just come in and
play heightened version of yourself.
What am I doing right now?
I am describing my acting career.
Um, anyways, how much time
is that? Oh Jesus Christ.
It's like fucking,
you know what's hilarious?
It's like five 50 in the morning
and I got up to go to the gym,
I got to, I got the acting
Gig also happens today. I
just have a later call time.
So I was like, I'm going to get up and
go to the gym. All right. Cause I'm uh,
trying to get myself back in shape here.
Right? So I remember the old gym song,
I go to the gym every day.
It's just become pop me life.
And if you don't want to be a fatty,
you go to the gym every day.
You can't have big body. I called them
every day. So I don't go every day.
I take one day off.
Right.
I figure even if the Lord needed to take
one day off when he was creating the
universe as I'm sculpting
this
flower covered colored body.
Okay.
Do you know how you know something?
All of these minorities out there
with their pigment bitch moaning and
complaining. I asked you this
as a privileged white male,
do you understand how difficult it
is to get shredded when you were as
transparent is me.
Okay.
I could be in just as good
as shape as some Hawaiian.
Okay.
But because I am so pasty,
the world is never going to know it.
And do you understand how difficult it
is for me when I walk out into the world
it's like, Hey, I have a couple of
abs too. You just can't see them.
[inaudible]
I want to get that Janet Jackson stomach
makeup where you just said, you know,
get one of those people that you know
when you almost have abs and they just
spray paint them in.
I want to do that.
Right.
And then I'm going to do,
put on a half shirt and do my
dance cover of miss you much.
I miss you man.
Oh miss you much.
I really miss you much.
Um,
I remember I had a crush on her
when she was on different strokes.
I didn't like her when she was on
uh,
good times.
You know what I mean?
And not because she was younger
with baby fat and you know,
cause we're basically the same age.
Uh, it was because she was broke. Okay.
And I'm not, I'm not trying
to get with some, yeah,
she was living in the projects then I
liked her better when she was, you know,
on different strokes,
you know,
interacting with super rich white people
then then me as a little white kid
could relate like,
all right,
oh now the world dove move
to the beat of just one drum.
What might you may not be right for some.
Um,
all right.
That was inadvertently
one of the funnier things that
I've said on this podcast,
but I'm sure someone will take it in
the wrong way. What are you saying?
You can't fall in love with
someone because they live
in the projects, projects,
projects. That's exactly what I'm
saying. That is how privileged I am.
You know, if women can go into these
fucking single buys, these meat markets,
and one of their first questions they
ask you when you run into them is what do
you do for a living?
You know,
how much fucking cake are you putting on
the table? They're swinging Dick. Why?
Why can't I choose?
Why can't I choose my TV crushes?
Huh?
That's how I was. I was an elitist
with my TV crutches. Crushes,
you know,
fuck all those bitches on the Waltons.
But I would fuck anybody on Falcon
crest and cloning though, man.
Now they'll world doe boom to the beat.
Just one drove a bunch of rich white
people throwing each other in the pool in
evening gowns.
I've never seen that one.
Is that when Joan Crawford in Morgan
Fairchild had their infamous cat fight,
you know?
Yeah.
That I think gets reenacted on floats
during the gay pride parade in every city.
Isn't that what they,
isn't that required that you have
to have one stereotypical thing.
All right. Gay People, gay men, let's,
let's do what straight
people think we're into,
which let's appease them so we can try
to be a little more mainstream this year.
Oh Man. That different strokes on when,
when it gets in your fucking head,
you just can't get it out,
you know? But it's enjoyable.
Everybody's dead.
Except the due to played Willis.
That's kind of sad. A guess. I died next.
I think I'm the same age as Willis Willis.
Drummer booboo boo.
What is covered? He's on the
only one left alive. Yes, he is.
Yeah, that's a, you know something.
That's what I do when I watch me TV.
I try to see like, who's
the only guy left? Oh,
that's a great fucking trivia thing.
Okay.
Name TV shows where there's only
one series regular is still alive.
Different strokes. The
Beverly hillbillies. Wait,
[inaudible] the fucking, uh, the dude,
you know, that's how you, right now,
that's how that shows you right now.
How hard show businesses. You know
what I mean? Because in the real world,
women outlive the men.
All right?
But this business is so fucking difficult
that
I would say that doesn't make any
sense. Does it? Well, let's see. Well,
the one chick overdosed
and then the housekeeper,
she was like 93 when they started
shooting that she fucking crushed it.
She had a great act in career. You don't,
she had two shows that made syndication.
She was on a,
she was on, uh, the facts of life.
You take the good, you take the bad,
you take them both in there. You
have the facts of life, you know.
Do you know why that
song was at that tempo?
Because when you really just slow that
down, that doesn't make any sense.
You take the good,
you take the bed,
you take a both and there you have the
facts of life. It's like, wait, what?
That doesn't mean anything.
Okay, but you speed it up,
take the goods to take the bed.
You take a boat and there you had
the facts of life. Oh, that's catchy.
I don't feel like thinking
the facts of life. Um,
I know what you thinking. Hey
Bill, you're wife is black.
We ended today on that show.
No, I was not. I like Joe.
Joe The mechanic. I liked her riding
the dirt bike, the fucking tomboy.
I like Blair at first. You
know, at first I like Blair,
but there was just something
so fucking wholesome about her.
After awhile I was just
like, yeah, Jesus Christ.
Can you imagine the fucking look?
She be given me a weekend to this.
You like how I'm entertaining the fact
that a young freckled me could actually
dated Blair from um
Oh is that fucking show. I just said
it. The facts of life. All right.
I don't have anything to talk about.
Something to tell you about my TV crushes.
All right. Back in the day. MMM.
I would occasionally watch Charlie's
angels because even back then I was so
sexist
that I couldn't get over the
fact that I was watching these,
these women all made up
running down the alleys,
tackling these fucking guys
into trash cans. You know,
having said that, I obviously
liked Farrah Fawcett, right?
But I was a Kate Jackson Fan. Okay.
She was sort of the first Demi Moore,
I feel,
you know,
the fucking Brunette with
the smokey fucking voice.
And then the best was when she was
on the rookies. Bad Outta Butoh too,
about that ad ad ad, ad, ad, ad ad.
You know what I would love to
have on the fucking podcast?
I would love to have the trumpet player
from the 1970s who fucking just got in
with whatever studio and played
half of those themes, songs, dude,
if you were in a fucking horn section,
okay.
Living in La in the 70s.
Right. And you just,
you just fucking,
and then they had all those cop shows
you were working every fucking week.
You in that Bongo player,
the Bongo player was just crushed every
time you fucking chased the suspect down
a fucking alley. They always were playing
the congress of the bongos. Right.
And then whenever they had the theme
song for the show is the fucking horn
section. Uh, but um, uh, [inaudible]
uh, [inaudible] uh, trumpets. Yeah.
Dead Dead
fucking horn players crushing it.
Yeah.
Walking around with polyester shirts
with unbuttoned dowdy in Naval Yaggie
Medallian your little coke spode right.
Don't go to bed with a price on your head.
No,
don't do it. Um, all right, bill,
what are your predictions for
the Super Bowl? You know me,
I never think my team's going
to win. Okay. I hope they win,
but I'll tell you right now,
they're going to have their hands full.
Love these rabbis of Los Angeles that
I already make fun of those fucking,
those 30 something douchebags who
in the rams jerseys who were crying,
they were getting all
emotional and they're fucking
girlfriends were comforting
them. When the rams beat
the states, it's like,
what the fuck are you create such a
typical Foti fucking La Douche bag.
It's like the rams had
been back for three years.
They left in the 80s you're
fucking 30 years old.
You don't remember these fucking people.
Oh my God.
God had been waiting for is I
was trying to fix and now I'm 49
okay, now the world dope. Move
to the beat of just one drum.
Your team, Jess moved back.
Stop with the crocodile tears.
That's the wrong expression.
Stop with the a phony fucking tears.
Those were actors.
That's what they weren't in the
NFL of course has to show them,
look how happy we make people
and now let's take a veteran out of the
crowd and charged the marines money for
it lays gel. When Alibaba, a round
of applause for this hair, all that.
We're now charging the military a fee
for a cupbearer shall act a like way
support.
Let's bring out the American
flag everybody and horror
out people's patriotism
so we can make more money.
Let's settle this class action
suit with former players.
That comes down to about $38 per player.
Um, oh Geez, I'm getting
cynical. 29 minutes a,
we made another one. You know what? I
got to read a little advertising here.
Um,
I can be broken my own mother fucker.
That's how I, I, I justify my crush,
my elitist crush on Janet Jackson.
All right,
here we go. He looks
everybody. Alex. Hey man,
you ever wake up in the
morning with a raging out? No.
You have a wake up in the morning
with regrets of what you'd done.
Okay.
Do you know what I did this morning?
I woke up this morning.
I had a dream that one of my
relatives was on a boat that sank
with like 200 fucking people
and they were all missing.
And somehow I was in the
ocean but still in my house.
And I found my loved one and they
picked her up and she was face down.
And when I turned her over,
she started crying and was
coughing and she was still alive.
And I came in,
okay.
And I think I talked shit, I talked to
the other rescuers, I said, beat that.
And then I realized she was
still alive and I started crying.
And then I really just started wailing,
crying.
Okay.
And I walked by my mother and
she just went, Jay says, Bill,
like I was crying too much.
I don't even get supported by drapes.
I'm replaying the terrible decisions you
made the previous night over and over
and over, the kicking, the sweating,
the yelling or whatever else you did to
piss everyone off to piss everyone in
the bedroom off. Well, guess what, Bud?
Depending deciding to sleep on a
shitty mattress is your choice.
I like how these people try to write
this dialogue like the way I talk.
So now I have to take my head away from
the microphone and read literally what
they wrote. But bill, buying
a mattress is so high.
Where would I ever begin?
Well, you're in luck buddy.
A lot of buds and buddy here. It's written
by Jeff Spicoli. What's your problem?
Bird. Because Helix, helix sleep. Um,
the mattress I've been yelling at you to
buy for almost two years will challenge
your life.
Just go to helix,
sleep.com/burr take their two minutes
sleep quiz and they'll match you to the
perfect mattress.
It's like Tinder for finding a mattress.
All the fun with none of the
next morning regrets in misery.
And right now you can get up
to $125 off your mattress.
Order on helic sleep.
He looks.com/burr.
They have a 100 night trial,
grouse free shipping and won't
send you creepy texts the next day.
That helix sleep.com/burr for
up to $125 off your mattress.
They let you try that.
You got a hundred night free trial,
uh, uh, uh,
it doesn't feel right and we
all went out bag in my broad,
it just doesn't feel right in my cock,
you know.
Well what kind of balls do you have?
I got those medium size ones,
but for some reason they weigh down my
ball sack is if it's not a quality ball
sack, you know, like I feel like
if I had a quality ball sack,
the weight of my balls,
they wouldn't be mid thigh.
It actually makes me know,
do they end plastic surgery?
Am I going to see one of the
male Kardashians down there and
get a ball talk,
a ball sack Tuck,
you know,
do you have a wrinkly ball sack?
That is so 2018,
come on down and get botox,
Gabby a balls, botox.
Just listen to what
these women have to say.
I never used to lick my husband's balls,
but now that it's so smooth and not Harry,
I'm down there every night
taint. Um, all right.
That was my nod to David
Cross and Bob Odenkirk.
One of the hardest I've ever
laughed in a sketch show
is when they did that fucking sketchy
about the guy with the giant Tate in the
porn industry and how they were,
it was, it was not that sketch.
I didn't even hear that sketch.
It's the way they went into that sketch
where they had like a Batman style fight.
I can't really remember what
happened, but like, you know,
they were doing the freeze frame on the,
on the, on the punches, they go pow bef,
you know, slam. And then the last one,
this dude looked like he kicked the guy
in the balls and it just said taint.
And I was fucking screaming,
laughing because Tate
was in the white world,
a very not known reference at that point,
if I remember correctly, that came
out of the African American community,
you know,
taint pussy tape balls.
It's the taint. Right.
And that was new to white
people and I was not ready for,
I think Patrice told me that
one and I wasn't ready, uh,
for that to be coming out of that
show. And I was screaming, laughing,
and my lady at the time who was Caucasian,
she didn't know what I was laughing at,
but I was left.
You know when somebody laughs so hard,
even if you don't get it,
you start laughing. That's basically
what happened. And you know what
just happened there? You just listened
to 34 minutes of my bullshit. I gotcha.
Again, motherfuckers. All
right. That's the podcast. Have
a great weekend. You can't,
there's got to be a little music
Telenor,
Lou here,
and then you're going to listen to
another 30 minutes of a greatest hits
Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast
possibly released on Saturday.
They made a [inaudible] came out
10 years ago, eight years ago,
or fucking eight minutes ago. I don't
know. I don't pick them. All right,
I'll see you on [inaudible]
Monday
morning. What's going
on? It's built birth.
It's the Monday morning
podcast for Monday,
January 24th,
2011 how the hell are you? How are
you doing? Did you have a good week?
Was the world nice to, yeah. Uh,
this is a big day for me. Everybody.
This is my 100th day.
And when I said I was knocking off the
booze because I was starting to have a
big bloated face, I was like, fuck
this. I gotta I gotta you know,
gotta get on the treadmill.
I got a knock off the booze and I was
trying to beat my previous record of going
75 days and this time I said, fuck it.
I'm going for an even hundred. And uh,
the goal has been a chief JF JF Javed.
Um,
I'm site,
I did it and a,
tonight I'm going to the Bruins la kings
game down at this stable feda the most
unfriendly fan fucking play
she'll ever go to. The haves,
the really haves and the have nots.
I broken it down for you before you got
all the corporate seats down low sit
next, Diane Cannon, Jack Nicholson
and fucking sissy space sick.
Whoever the fuck else is down there,
all those Douche bags sitting there
with their fucking faces yanked back.
You know, by the way, how long has
Jack Nicholson had going bald for?
It's just fucking unbelievable how
long it took for that guy to go bald.
He lost one hair a day since 1972
so do you have any notice
that there's certain people,
it just takes for fucking ever,
unless they seamlessly went into
a toupee pay, but he's bald. No,
but you know, being someone
who's balding myself, you know,
I pay attention to that type
of shit and I pay pet tension.
All these motherfuckers,
I see the receding hairline and all of
a sudden it's not there. The next movie,
and I was like,
day you go look at that guy.
He went out and he got himself sort of a
scalped in a user friendly way and then
they reseeded the front. I going
out like that. My goal in life,
I want to look like Clint Howard.
Okay.
Woo. It's not going to end good for
me. Uh, yes. I went a hundred days.
100 days.
100 days and yes,
and I don't know,
I'm afraid I'm scared every one.
I'm afraid to start drinking
again because I noticed that I,
I just pick up where I left off.
Like I really learned about addiction
during these last hundred days.
I realized how much shit I was,
uh, you know, not addicted to,
to a level that it was like, you
know, I was coming home and slap it.
My girl around,
you know,
getting on all fours growling at my dog
is I peed on the Stereo and then the
next morning, like I didn't do what
he did. I don't remember that. Oh,
well maybe I wouldn't drink if
you weren't such a coat. You,
I wasn't doing stuff like that.
I was just out having a good fucking time.
I like beer the way I
like cake and cookies.
There's really no reason.
There's no reason to have cake or cookies.
It says no nourishment
that your body needs.
You don't need that much fucking sugar.
But a, I like it. I like the fucking rush,
you know, is sitting
there feeling gloomy, Eh,
I hate myself.
What am I doing?
Remember when I was young and I'd just
go out and play Frisbee and it was fun,
man. It was simple, right? You get older,
you got all this debt, he got all his
bullshit. Everybody's fucking nagging you.
You get the blues, see, go out, you get a
slice of cake, right? Feeling like shit.
Six bites of cake lady. You're
like, dude, I am fucking awesome.
Right? You got that sugar rush going.
So that's what I realized. I am a,
I have a number of addictions.
I am addicted to sugar.
Not In like a, you know,
I need an intervention,
but like I fucking crave it.
But if I lay off it for four days,
when if I don't eat any
sweets for four fucking days,
when I look at a doughnut or a
piece of cake, it's like laughable.
Like why the fuck would you eat that?
Look at it yet, that, that at, at, at,
at that data,
it doesn't even look like real food.
You know when you're off, when you're
fucking, when you've kicked sugar,
when you look at a glazed doughnut,
just sitting there all fucking sweaty.
It just let, it looks horrible. It's
like, why would you do that to you?
So you know,
you look at all the frosting on a cake,
you make that face like he just
sucked on a lemon like Jesus Christ.
Enough already and a fucking cunt
downstairs just slammed the door cause I'm
being too loud. I don't care. Douchebag.
I fucking love old people,
but I hate that motherfucker downstairs.
I fucking hate that guy.
Hate that.
He's got that classic old person's
smell. He does it. He has a unique smell.
You know what he saw? He
smells like a, like a fucking,
if you lit a wet dog on
fire, okay, if you did that,
that's what he smells like.
Fucking miserable motherfucker.
This goddamn Docker's the original
Docker's fucking army navy store shop and
douchebag. Fucking miserable.
Cont giving me the stink eye.
Every time I walk up the fucking walk
can't stand the guy fucking hate them
there. I hate him. I don't give a shit
right. I die. I'll fucking, you know,
I'll argue that one in the afterlife.
I'll sit right there.
You know you drank it drove.
Yes, I did. Guilty as charged.
He treated a lot of women
like shit. You're absolutely
right. Guilty as charged.
And you had, you had a poor opinion
about the old man downstairs. Well,
let me tell you something. Jesus,
you try living above that cunt.
Go Talk to your dad. He made them, oh
my God. Shut up. You fucking hippie.
Oh Gee. Um, so anyways,
so tonight I am going to, um, I'm
going to go watch the best of the,
of the, of, of the four sports,
the four major sports hockey is the
best goddamn sport out there. All right?
And uh, I know a lot of you won't
realize that because you never played it.
You never went to a game, hence you
don't know what you're talking about.
You know, it'd be like me making fun
of line dancing. I've never done it.
You know,
I've never gone out and bought a pair of
wrangler jeans that were fucking $8 and
nine sizes too small for me.
So they cupped my fucking bowls and
got out there and stuck my hands in my
pockets and did this little
fucking, that little, oh my God,
that fucking line dancing.
Can there be a mass suicide
amongst line dancers?
Could that just fucking happen in the
middle of one of your fucking corn ball.
Stupid ass fucking sell country music.
It's country music is, I don't even know
what it's for. It's for like pod people.
There's absolutely no soul in it.
What's so it there? Is it all right?
They're angry.
Redneck listening to this,
punching the dashboard or your
Chevy s 10 all right. There isn't.
It fucking sucks.
And that line dancing.
We sit there with your fucking thumbs
in your book and pockets and you do that
little fuck I'm doing, I'm, I'm actually,
I'm in Dallas, Texas this week, so let's,
let's go for big air in this one. We
do that then you're fucking, I wish,
I wish this was a vodcast,
which I'm not doing by the way.
So stop fucking asking me.
The great thing about this thing is
you can listen to it while you're doing
other shit.
Right?
Are you or are you not doing other
shit right now? Well, all right then.
Are you or are you not pretending
to be working right now?
Looking at spreadsheets, right?
You want to fucking plane?
Huh?
What are your choices for food?
Aren't you doing that as you listen to
this when they quit your fucking pitching?
All right. So anyways, they do that
stupid thing where they banned,
they're fucking nice and the,
and I can't even think of the fucking
music by Ana [inaudible] the Gig, the Gig.
You right. There's none
of the music goes. And um,
and they do that little thing where they
just one of their, one of their feet,
right? The right foot,
we'll say the right foot.
It's just pivoting on the heel and the
toes of face forward and then to the side
and then back to the front.
Ah.
Then they do that little thing where
they bring their fucking foot up and they
spanked the bottom of their foot.
All of them.
You know what kills me about those
people is they actually think that Jesus
loves them. I got news for you. Rednecks.
Jesus is looking the other way.
He's embarrassed.
He's combing his fucking
hair into his face.
When he watches you people line dance.
He is looking that chicken the ring.
Um, yeah. So speaking of
which I'm going to be,
I completely forgot what the fuck
I was talking about. I know. Yeah.
I'm going to go into
the hockey game tonight.
La Kings verse the Boston Bruins,
the La Kings,
which who actually have a
really good team. I liked that.
I liked that Dude Simmons.
He's fucking fast as
health and a cold baton,
um, border. It's the
greatest fucking game.
And I've actually been playing
a hockey recently. Ice Hockey,
the real fucking deal. And I'm excited.
Guess what? I learned how to do this week,
42 years of age, not
married, no kids. I learned,
finally learned how to stop on both sides.
Okay.
But you know what's funny? I have, I
have to go buy some more hockey stuff.
You know, it's funny, out here in La,
I have to drive all the way down to like
Orange County just to find someplace,
stuff that we'll sell hockey
stuff. Uh, but I have to,
even though I suck at this sport,
I just,
I'm just an old man and like
it takes about four days.
That's how deep the bruises are.
After I'm done falling on the ice
and like four days after I play,
I look like I've been beaten
with a fucking bamboo cane.
I had a brutal one when I was in fucking
Atlantic city last weekend doing the
Miami Heat tour of comedy.
Um, by the way, um,
the Atlantic city was so successful.
I just got an email today for an offer
up in a fox woods for April 30th.
So I will let you know
as soon as I find out.
I might actually have an update right now.
Wouldn't that be amazing right here on
the fly as you listened to the Monday
morning po? Fuck, let's just keep
the flow of this podcast going.
I think this was good.
I think it's what it's going to.
It's going to be a good one. We're almost
11 minutes in. Things are going well.
For some reason. The voice seems
way too loud on this thing.
What's going on with
this anyways, uh, yeah,
so I fell on my fucking right ass,
cheek and hip last time he played
before Atlantic city. And, uh,
it's one of those deals I
kept pushing on it going,
I can't believe that didn't bruise.
It's, it hurts when I touch it.
When I push my thumb into my little
fucking right. Buttcheek it hurts. Right.
And then like four days later,
I'm in Atlantic city and I'm showering
and I looked out and it looked like
somebody threw a can of grape soda.
Yeah.
Uh, so I will be getting
all, all of the hockey stuff,
which I really didn't want to do because,
um,
I don't want to put it out there that I
think I know how to play hockey because
I don't, I just enjoy it. It's
fucking fun. It's a fast game.
The only equipment I wear is I wear a
helmet for my big fucking head and I wear
the full cage in the front because, uh,
I don't need any hockey scars, you know,
with the sticks and all that shit. Why
would I do that to myself? You know,
like I'm going to win a cup. I need
to sacrifice. Oh, speaking of which,
I should probably wear a cup
too, right? No lifting. Um,
hang on a second. We're
going to the inbox. Did I get
anything? Did I get anything?
Nothing. You motherfucker.
So anyways, yeah, so this,
so tonight actually tech,
technically I can start boozing.
This is the 100th day, but I gotta be
honest with you, I'm not going to do it.
I think I'm going to try to see
how long I can go with this.
I'm going to wait until there is,
there is a specific event where
boozing makes sense and uh,
then I'm going to knock it off. Then I'm
going to boost, make people, what am I,
what am I going to do?
Honestly,
I might never going to have a
beer for the rest of my life.
I don't know how those people in Aa do it.
That's like,
I have a weird sort of like
respect for people in Aa.
And I also have a,
uh,
a disdain for them because,
I went to a couple of Aa
meetings, uh, not by choice. Um,
the judge told me I had to go,
that's part of your sentence.
Um, and I went there and
uh, I didn't like it.
I kind of liked it. I liked sort
of the room, but kind of like, uh,
the only aspect of church that I like,
I like going to church because it reminds
me not to be a complete piece of shit.
But other than that, all that stuff
about hippies walking on water,
talking to bushes, it just
sounds like an acid trip. And uh,
it just, it's just stupid and
there's always a fucking leper.
How many fucking lepers were there
back then Jesus Christ get tell me you
wouldn't have a fucking giant stick
back in the day. Just for the lepers,
you know,
ugh.
Jesus Christ had fucking
smash them. Right? And if you
get the fuck away from me,
he fucking leper.
What would Jesus do?
He has the ability to cure
himself. I don't. All right.
Don't you think that that maybe that's
why he was such a good shit because he's
the son of God. He knows he's going to
heaven course he's doing the right thing.
It's so fucking easy to be a good shit
when you can walk on water and touch
something and it gets cured. Of course
he's going up and shaking your head,
your fucking freak. Get away from
me. I can't do that. You're a leper.
Fuck off Dow.
Go cry to the son of God.
Um,
so anyways,
yeah. So I would go to these, these,
these meetings, these meetings and uh,
you know,
yeah,
I dunno. I, I believe in addiction.
And then other times I just think,
I don't think all of those people addicts,
I think some of them,
they're just weak. I can't stop
myself. It's like you don't have
like your brain tells you arm to move
and pick up something and put it to your
lips.
Right.
Did you guys like alcoholics?
You guys become like such an alcoholic,
like the bottles actually talking to you.
I had a fucking buy into that shit.
You know,
God damn fucking pussy alcoholics.
All right,
go drink a case of beer. I understand
it. Puke it up. All right. And then take,
you know, a week or two off.
You don't do it every night.
You know, actually, I'm full of Shit. I,
I 100% believe in that addiction thing
and I actually believe a, I actually now,
I now understand after watching
the biggest loser every season,
I now realize yeah it is.
It is an addiction.
Because every one of those people has
some sort of psychological reason as to
why they do it. But wait
a minute, I'm not fat,
but I'm out of my fucking mind.
Yeah,
yeah. So fuck him. Yeah. Right. All
right. Sorry. I had to work that out.
Fuck those fat fucks.
Hey fuck them.
I get sad and then I eat 24 cakes.
Well,
how come nobody gets
sad and they do sit ups.
What's the deal?
Actually some people do that and that's
one of the last shows they'll do a Jim
addictions.
You know,
they'll do something like that cause I
think they're out of boring jobs to try
and make exciting.
Have you seen that?
They actually have a show out there
right now about people mining for gold,
you know, I mean mining for
gold, obviously they still do it,
but it's like big business now.
They have these sophisticated machines
that cut the tops off of mountains and
then they grind them down like you did
with your number two pencil and second
grade trying to get down to the array,
right.
Okay.
But nobody with a big bushy beard is
squatting down like a Chinese gambler next
to a fucking river with the God damn
dinner plate trying to find gold.
But Lo and behold,
they found 10 douchebags who are doing it.
And they decided to make it a show and
they decided to fucking have what film
these guys arguing each other and play
this something dangerous is happening.
Music underneath it. And I'm sick of it.
All right? Fuck minors. Fuck people who,
uh,
make cakes for a living did fuck
those God damn crab fishermen.
You know, nobody is making
you go on that Goddamn boat.
Fucking idiots going out.
They have risking your lives.
Have a flounder. You know,
just say what you do
out loud for a living.
Just say it out loud a couple of times
to yourself. I go on a fucking tugboat.
Okay. And I, I, I risked my life
to get a, to get king crabs. So rich
people have something crunchy to eat.
Go Fuck Yourself, JP Morgan, you
want crab? Go get it yourself.
What are your fucking options? Actually,
you know some, I'll make it fun.
I actually respect those guys
cause I have a tremendous,
tremendous fear of the ocean.
A huge fear of people who go
out and swim in the ocean.
You're out of your fucking minds.
I know I've said this before in
the podcast, but you know what?
I'm going to say it again. I
don't give a shit. I'm edgy.
I'm crazy. They should make a show about
me and my podcast and the dangers of it,
you know, then me and Neil
will have fake arguments. Um,
you know, we'll have shit like plugs
or something will go wrong. You know,
I don't know. I don't have what
we're with my Olympic SLS, ted. Oh,
I thought you were going to have it.
Then they'll cut to me. You know?
So I went to go do the podcast
and I couldn't find the Olympics.
Ellos 10
ditto.
I mean, I, I gotta get this
podcast done by Monday,
or I don't know what the fuck's
going to happen. If you notice that,
like I think the,
at Orange County choppers,
they basically created the template
for all those reality shows.
And now everybody does that shit.
The exact same thing that would happen
on that fucking motorcycle show,
uh, with where the sun would be like,
eh. And then we had a problem. The, uh,
the carburetor didn't fit
for the carburetor, wasn't
here. And then the bar, like,
then the dad comes,
shit,
Yo, what's going on? The
carburetor isn't here.
Then he gets on their show. Mike,
he's fucking scary. Well, no, could,
how fucking jacked is
the dad on that show?
He could please my entire family to
death if he got excited enough. Um,
so now they do that shit. Like it makes
sense on the chocolate for Shell, right?
Bunch of mechanics. They're, yeah,
they're wearing their greasy Dickies.
They got butt cracks hanging out death.
They're going to yell and
scream at each other. Right.
But the fucking idiots making cakes.
So we get a job.
Uh,
we have to make a cake for the firehouse.
And I decided to do a cake that
was shaped like a fire hydrant.
I wanted to do a fire hydrant motif with
the little a Dalmatian know peeing on
the fire hydrant.
But Michael was like,
I don't think that we should bring urine
into something that's going to be in
your mouth. They was typical Michael
just shitting on my creative process.
Oh, kill yourself. Nobody cares. Nobody
cares about you and your fucking cakes.
And I like cakes. Yeah. Do you guys didn't
know that about me? Did you? Let's see.
How will you at 20 minutes in here,
20 minutes into the podcast.
Um,
should I do it?
Should I do it?
I'm going to be a class act here.
My condolences to the Chicago bears
fans and the fans in New York jets.
Uh, the true fans, the true sports
fans, the ones that don't talk shit.
The ones who are cool.
The ones who, you know,
you can actually have a conversation
about football with my condolences.
Go out to you. Uh, believe me as a fan
of Boston teams for my entire life.
I know what it feels like to be that
fucking clothes and they get kicked in the
seeds against some my condolences.
Congratulations to the Steelers
and the Green Bay packers.
And uh,
I would like to open this dialogue.
This is something that bugs
me about a NFL football is,
is this,
I don't get why in every
other fucking major sport.
They count championships from
100 years ago. Like, well,
let's look at the red sox.
They won the championship and like 1908
or something. When they had crazy legs,
Magee was playing fucking third base with
his giant Ebeneezer fucking mustache.
They count those,
the red socks count five world series
titles that we went from 1918 and before
fucking Montreal Canadians.
They Count Stanley cups that they
won during that time too. All right.
The Yankees,
they count all their pre depression
era during the depression or whatever.
That's right when they started,
when they count all of those,
the fucking Celtics
count this from the 60s.
The fucking Lakers count
their championships,
their first two or three,
it wasn't even the NBA.
Those are BB eight championships. Their
first four out of five championships.
We're one before the 24 second shot
clock even existed when you could win a
basketball game like 17
to 12 they count those.
So my question for spots
for sports fans is this,
why don't they count Nfl Championships?
Why do they only count Superbowls?
Because when you just count Superbowls,
the Pittsburgh Steelers are the Yankees
that Canadians are the Celtics of
football.
But as bullshit,
it's fucking bullshit because the Greenbay
packers have won like 12 or 13 NFL
titles and Superbowls.
They won three super bowls in like
another eight or nine NFL titles that for
some reason they don't count.
The Pittsburgh Steelers were in the NFL
when Green Bay was winning all those
titles. So they had a shot
at winning them. You know,
it's as much as I give
the Canadian shit going,
I you dominated a 16 league,
which isn't really true.
They were going tit for tat with the maple
leafs until 60 but the Bruins were in
that original six.
So we should have dominated and we didn't.
So that's why I shut the fuck up
when it comes to that conversation.
So can anybody out there tell me
why don't they count NFL titles
like I, I don't, I don't get that.
I don't get it. That would be,
if you didn't count that in baseball,
you would have missed out on Babe Ruth,
Mickey Mantle, Joe Dimaggio, none
of that. None of that would count.
Bill Russell wouldn't count. It's
fucked up. I think it's bullshit.
And I think it's, I think the,
I like, I want to go to what?
Like I love sports history.
I want to go to an eagles game and I want
to see 1960 NFL champions and I'm not
giving an eagles fan shit. I'm just,
they should have that up there.
The Cleveland browns won it and like,
uh,
I don't like 63 or 64 with Jim Brown.
The bears won one with Mike. Uh,
Mike Ditka and uh, what's his face?
They're a Dick Butkus
right. They want it. Uh,
the Green Bay packers won a few.
Then the cults with Johnny Unitas,
you know the ones that they won the
greatest game ever fucking plague.
Yankee stadium giants first, the colts,
1958 the overtime fucking victory, right?
They don't count any of that shit.
It's,
it's disrespectful to
the athletes that played.
Those were the best of the best,
at least white guys
for, for most of those
years. But seriously,
there was only one professional league.
So the talent pool was even greater than,
and they don't, they don't count it.
And I think it's fucking bullshit.
And I'm hoping that somebody talks
about that considering you have the most
successful teams since the Super Bowl
era and then you have playing the most
successful team in NFL history.
They have one in every era except for
the seventies and eighties I guess they
didn't want a championship
and the 2008 but they,
but they've been competitive or whatever,
you know, I dunno. Speaking of which,
you know, do you guys realize
that right now Brett Farve
is getting sued some of this shit.
This is how fucked up
the world is right now.
Brett Farve is getting sued by the,
uh, by two [inaudible]
because he tried to get, uh,
some sort of sexual favors
afterwards and they're, they're,
they're suing for that.
Okay.
Do you understand that? Well, let
me say that just one more time.
Brett Farve is getting sued
by a [inaudible] tumor.
Susis does that how you said my sue says,
um,
mousses um,
tomosynthesis for,
for asking basically to, to, uh, you know,
to bang them at the end of it,
they're suing him.
Okay.
Could
you fuck a believer? I just,
it's just fucking bus that will,
you know what that's like?
That's like me showing a comedy
club because I got heckled.
It comes with the job.
There is not any machine,
any female Masoud out there
that listens to this podcast.
Are you honestly going to tell me that,
that you've been rubbing guys bags and
their legs and the chest and all that and
you've, no one has ever asked you for
a fucking hand job at the end of it.
It fucking comes with the territory.
That's like being a cop and suing
the city cause you got shot at all.
Right.
You fucking put hot oil all over a guy's
body and you rub everything but their
dick. I mean, give me a fucking break.
You goddamn cock tease is, yeah.
People are going to ask you to rub
one out. Okay. And if you had a shred,
a fucking decency, you'd do it. You'd
complete the Goddamn job. All right?
Because you're sign says
full body massage. All right,
last I saw my dick is still part of my
body. All right. You know what, they'll,
you know what Miss Susan is a like,
they like the fucking quarterback
who can't get it done, you know,
just always comes up a little bit short.
They should fucking interview
them afterwards. So, you know,
like what happened in there?
Uh, you know, and I just didn't,
just didn't get it done. You
know, it's like right there.
All I do is just reach out and
grab it. And I just, uh, you know,
we didn't want it. We didn't want
it as much as they wanted it. Um,
that's just like, just, that's such
a classic, uh, piggyback lawsuit.
It's like once that first stupid whore,
um,
you know,
gave Brett Farve Shit,
this is very interesting that
I've noticed about horse.
Once one comes out of the woodwork,
then all of a sudden 20 come
out of the woodwork, you know,
and then they always try to paint it as
well. We were too scared. We were scared.
Fuck you.
You were you trying to make money and
you're trying to build on the momentum of
the other case. That's the female
version of pulling a train on somebody.
You know, the guy version is,
you know, you and 80 of friends,
bang the same girl. The
female version is, you know,
you're a fucking whore and you're just
waiting for a whore to sue a guy that you
fucking banked and then you fucking, you,
you draft in right behind their lawsuit.
Okay? Like one of those fucking fairies
that rides in that bike race out there.
And uh,
in uh,
in France that just piss
some people off actions.
You realize that the level of cardio
that you need to compete in that sport is
10 times that of a
professional hockey player.
That's when you know you're watching a
sport that no one gives a shit about.
When you have to really start
bringing up like science,
they did a study,
the heart rate of the highlight
player of go fuck yourself.
Why don't you take that highlight
thing? It just fucking cup. You're nuts.
You're taint and your asshole
and carry yourself outta here.
Why don't you do that?
Did that make sense?
Is that what they do with
the highlight sticks?
Okay.
Or is it shaped that way?
It's sort of a, a, you know,
a user friendly bike seats that
you can rock up and down on.
You know what? I think it's time to
read some questions for this week.
I'm going to say I've, I've exhausted
all improv skills at this point. Oh,
first thing I want to tell you guys,
can you guys do me a huge favor
if you're on Facebook? Um,
there's some douchebag
pretending to be me on Facebook.
It just don't add the guy.
He has a Celtics logo. I
don't know what he's doing.
He's not doing anything malicious.
He's just pretending to be me and
it's really weirding me out. Um,
I mean, I don't know what
he thinks he's good. I mean,
I can't get laid off of Facebook
so I don't know what this,
well maybe he's got better at
typing game than I do, you know,
but I just don't want that shit to be
added to my file down there in Houston,
you know? All right. There's a
lot of question out there about,
you know, things that happen within
society specially, you know, this,
this is something that I think a lot of
white people need because not because
we're more racist than anybody else,
we just get just the,
the consequences of us fucking up is so
much harsher than other people because,
uh, you know, we, we are the gold
standard when it comes to racism.
Yeah.
We are in the driver's seat right now.
We have been in the driver's
seat for awhile. Basically.
Meaning that if we are ignorant assholes,
it,
it has way more effect than
when other people are, you know,
back in the day when other people
will run shit, that's the thing.
Whoever's on top, if you're
thinking ignorant, uh, that's
what, that's why, you know,
if you're on top and you're
thinking ignorant shit,
you have to be called on it because,
uh,
just cause he cause the effect that
you can have. You know what I mean?
Okay.
Like if somebody from Bangladesh fucking
hates me, that's such a stupid example.
Okay.
That,
that's not a race of people.
I don't even know where Bangladesh's
and I gotta be honest with you.
I don't even know if
that's a city or a country.
Bangladesh have ever seen
that on the prices, right?
Yeah.
I want to showcase showdown where selling
yet a Bangladesh and some white trash
person like myself.
So sit with a confused look on their face.
Like I don't know where that is.
Is that where the terrorists are?
I don't want to go there, whatever,
like a Filipino people fucking hate me.
That doesn't affect my life.
It doesn't,
I'm not going to go and do a
job interview at, at, you know,
Walmart is not run by Filipinos.
You know what I mean? You know,
not saying there's anything wrong
with Filipinos. Alright. See,
we'll see what I have to
do with those white person.
Let's say I'm saying I do bad Filipino
cause we clear here later on, I,
I've never had issues. I go have a lab of
Catherine. Well, fucking all that shit.
You got to go to the Jerry Lewis
voice there lady. Um, so yeah,
people have questions.
So here we go.
And I think all races to chime
in the questions that you have,
if you have feelings about a different
race of people and you just think about
your thinking, something funny, there's
nothing malicious, but is this offensive?
Is it racist? This is, this
is the new topic. Okay.
And if you feel that I answered these
questions like the ignorant white man that
I am, uh, call me out on it. I'm here.
So here we go. This first one, uh,
Bill,
is it racist to call Indians?
Dibble dabbles.
And I'm talking about the Asian ones,
not native Americans. Um, I'm
guessing by Dib and DAB was,
you mean Duba Dabu though.
But the movement, the bud,
you're saying like that debit Dabu um,
is it racist?
Probably,
but it's fucking funny.
So that knocks it down a little bit.
This is what I feel that makes
something like racist. It's like,
like the reason why,
uh,
that one isn't as offensive
is because we haven't,
we never enslaved them.
That's the reason why white and black
shit is so sensitive is because of the
shit that we did to him. But we haven't
really fuck with those people, you know?
So if the black version
of that was, is it,
is it offensive to black people?
Hey man, mother fucker or whatever.
Yes.
That would be offensive if you did some
sort of mocking of the way they spoke.
Yes.
That would be,
that would be offensive if some CEO was
giving a speech and I was driving a,
actually I was having someone else drive
my town car and we drove by a group of
a young mother fuckers and uh,
they proceeded to walk forwards again,
you'd have to apologize. So I guess, yeah,
I guess technically Duma
Dapa like that would be,
that would be offensive. Is it racist? Um,
this is what I, I really, I really,
it's hard for me to say because it had,
it's what's in your heart, you
know, cause I make fuck I really,
I make fun of, of everybody, you know,
I mean I play a game out here. Uh,
when someone is make, let me ask you, I've
got a question for you. Is this racist?
I have a game out here when I ride around
with Nia and she does not approve of
this to keep her in the clear.
She does not approve this.
When somebody makes a more ronic
move in front of me, you know,
driving, you know, just makes
a fucking horrific move.
I play a game called old or Asian
and you have to guess when,
cause I'm going to pass the person
cause I got to see what they look like.
You know, whenever somebody
does something fucked up,
some comedians do a great joke about,
you just want to see what the fuck they
look like. Right. Uh, that's the game.
Older Asian. So as I speed up my little
hybrid to try to pull parallel to them,
I always say, what he's saying to you,
what are you going with all the ration?
What'd he got? Older Asian. She goes,
I'm not playing this game. That's mean,
and then I was gone, I'm going to
go with old and then I pull up, oh,
it's fucking Asian, you know, or Oh, I
nailed it. It was an old guy. So, um,
is that racist?
I'm sure it's offensive,
but within the context of my own car,
you know,
I'm not yelling at anybody
and I got to admit, you know,
there's a lot of truth in the
fucking game. Yeah. Jesus,
I'm gonna have to apologize next week on
the podcast. So I would say that, uh, uh,
Indian people, why don't you
chime in? I would say that, yeah.
That they would find that they
would find that offensive. Um,
is it racist?
Okay,
let me see if I can use it
in a sentence here. Hey, uh,
you know, I called up customer
service and, uh, you know,
one of those Buba dog was answered and
tried to tell me that his name was Steve
and act like he was in Kentucky.
But I,
I know that he was actually an India,
cause what he talked to,
he was going [inaudible]
woods, how can I help you? Um,
is it racist?
Probably.
You know what, something bad has to
happen between white culture and, uh, or,
or western culture in Indians.
So, you know what I mean?
It's like a, it's like you're playing
a team and there's no rivalry.
Like patriots verse jets this
year was like a whites and blacks.
It was bad. It was a
lot of hate, you know,
but like patriots verse,
like the Fucking Lions,
you know? Yeah. There's to be some
shit targets. It's knocked out,
but it still hurts if somebody
says something mean. I don't,
I really don't. What the fuck
I'm talking about? All right,
let's move to the next one.
The next one on the new controversial
topic on the Monday morning podcast.
Is it racist? All right, here we go. Um,
Bill, I had an interesting experience
today apparently involving me as a racist.
I was walking with two of my coworkers
who are both black Oji. Here we go.
Um,
we were going to go get some lunch.
One of my coworkers who are
most of friends with, uh,
did a little high five fist bump shuffle
with one of the female sex security
guards at the front desk.
Knowing both of them and how
they interact with one another.
I kind of made a in passing
comment to the tune of man,
you guys in your handshakes
while obviously laughing,
laughing while obviously
laughing at just choreographed.
It was in more or less picturing
them in a studio or something.
Working out the logistics to get the
fucking handshake. Perfect. Anyways,
we all laughed and moved on and
we got our lunch. All right,
so nothing wrong yet.
So you're cool with these people.
You made a joke and everybody laughed.
No problems,
no problems so far. Um, however,
after coming back through secure,
uh,
back through security,
I noticed the security guard stopped
me and Kinda had a scowl on her face.
I thought she was mad at me for something,
but it turned out she was mad at this
other lady who was black because she
overheard my comment and was telling,
uh,
that security guard that she couldn't
believe I had the nerve to say something
like that and I should be ashamed
all to the point where she could,
um,
almost to the point where she could
actually go complain to the human resource
people because she was
offended, um, et Cetera,
without even considering that.
Maybe just maybe I was talking about the
security guard and my coworker and not
all black people now.
It being corporate America in all I'm
sure rather than even face the pos
possibility of any bad press,
they'd rather just sweep me out the
door and completely ruined my re any
reputation I may or may not hold at the
company just to save their own asses.
I feel I did nothing wrong and they had
no intentions of ever doing anything
wrong.
Anything wrong.
I'm not going to go on and on about
how I kiss black babies and trying to
rehabilitate inner city
schools because I don't,
but I'm certainly not some corn fed rebel
flag waving ignorant product of what
might be incest.
I guess my question is do we really have
to walk on eggshells when we are just
making casual conversation that just
any that just any cunt can pick apart,
select the context that they might think
it is in and then start crying foul.
Basically.
I would have liked to call that woman
a cunt and told her to go fuck herself,
but let's just say I was already
kind of worried about my job.
All right. See, um, yeah, I think this is,
this is the classic one where you were
fucking around the other two people knew
you were fucking round,
but then one person decides to get
offended and then you have to go on TV and
apologize.
Which personally I think is the wrong
move because when you apologize now it's
like you're, you're admitting
that you meant it in a bad
way. I mean, the apology,
I would do that say, look, you know,
I'm sorry that you didn't
understand that I was joking,
but I'm not going to sit here
and apologize like I have any,
any sort of ill will come in your way,
you know,
but I, but just to avoid
the problem in the future,
uh,
white people do not use the
expression you guys or you people
when talking about black people, that's
just it. It's just not going to, you're,
you're setting yourself up for
someone to get offended. And, um,
there's a weird sort of a push
pull going on with that whole, uh,
you guys and you people think where,
um,
with somebody white says that
there becomes this concern of,
um, that you're separating.
You're separating like, yeah,
you know, you people over there with how
you live your lives and where over here,
black people have that weird relationship
with white people where they're like,
you know, can you stop stealing our
fucking music and our culture? Uh,
but then like, if something,
you know, hey, let's pay
the streets, you know, well,
make sure you do it in our neighborhood.
We're all in this together, right.
All of us together.
You know what I mean?
So it's that weird sort of fucking
push pull thing going on. So yeah,
just avoid, uh, avoid the whole fucking,
um, yeah, you fucked up.
You didn't fuck up, but you,
you left yourself open for a
sucker punch by saying you guys,
you know, uh, that's, I guess that, that's
what it is. I don't know. That's, that's,
that's my, I basically a white guy
telling a white guy how he fucked up.
So black people feel listening
to this. Think, uh, please,
please help me out here.
Did I basically get it right?
Is that essentially at,
and I know most people wouldn't
get offended. Uh, but that,
that's one of those things like that
girl getting offended and then you got to
worry that you're going to lose your job.
It's like those fucking piggy back
horse who massage guys for a living.
Okay.
You know, some of those
myths, sutures date,
they'll actually come to your house and
give you a full body rubbed down with
oil.
Okay.
And then have the fucking nerve to get
upset that you tried to get a hand job at
the end of it. You know,
give me a fucking break.
Why don't you fucking pursues broads man
the fuck up and start rubbing one out?
Is it that God damn hard,
no pun intended.
Is it that fucking difficult
to just fucking,
you know, it's like your
revenue motorcycle. That's it.
That's all you gotta do. Up and down,
up and down with that dead fucking oil.
You in and out. You want that
house on the hill, sweetheart?
There's a price to pay.
All right?
And when a quarterback who owns
every fucking record, good and bad,
and the Goddamn universe asked
you to rub one out, God damn it.
You fucking rub one out.
Okay,
well maybe you don't blog in this
business sister. That's right.
Stare at your fucking manicured toes.
Pedicured whatever the fuck
you supposed to say. Um,
Jesus Christ mean spirited. All right,
so there you go. That's the new,
that's the new topic. Is it
racist? And I would to hear,
um, some honest comments from a non
white people about their thoughts.
You know the fucked up ones too. Okay.
Cause I've watched enough spike Lee movies
to think that evidently it's just us.
But I've hung around enough people from
different races to realize, oh yeah,
everybody's like this. Everybody
has their little fucked up thoughts.
You guys ever see that Broadway
play, they got that song. Everybody,
everyone's a little bit racist.
What does that the alphabet city one,
whenever the fuck it's called actually
enjoyed that actually went to a Broadway
musical and there was puppets in it
and I had a great time. How about that?
What does that say about me? Um,
all right, let's get on with advice.
Advice for this week.
All right, advice. Spill.
Let me set this one up for you cause it
gets a little complicated over there. Um,
I went to a New Year's Eve party with
my best friend of 13 years. Oh Jesus.
Oh by the way,
this guy uses so many fucking names.
I'm just going to use the names. All
right. I know I don't name names,
but fuck this guy.
There's like 15 fucking names and
then he goes back to the first name,
back to the seventh name. So fuck it. I'm
naming names. All right, so here we go.
I'm suspending that role much like
they suspended the salary cap and NFL
football this year. Same Way.
All right. All right, Bill.
I went to a New Year's Eve party
with my best friend of 13 years mark.
I got really drunk and hooked up
with my friend John's ex girlfriend,
Anna.
John and Anna had dated for two years.
John broke up with Anna back in September
rather harshly and immediately started
banging other girls. Anna and
I also work together. Oh Gee.
And we've become good friends. Here we
go. So hooking up seemed inevitable.
Our friends have even joked about it.
Hey,
if you guys like fucked each other yet,
you guys want to get wings.
Um,
anyway,
I had been dating this
girl Sarah since October.
We never got too serious and we kind of
agreed to take a break when she left to
go to London for spring semester.
Mark's girlfriend who happened to be
a cunt is best friends with Sarah.
All right. Are you like
me? Are you already lost?
Are there too many fucking names here?
Let's go back to the beginning.
Mark and I got really drunk.
I went to a newsy part
of my best friend mark.
I got really drunk and
hooked up with okay. Marks.
His friend John has the ex girlfriend.
All right.
It was like a fucking mini series they
had to show you clips from last week. Um,
so anyways, he's taking some cut named
Sarah. They agreed to take a break
and the girl you taking a break with
his best friends with your friend's
girlfriend mark. Okay, I got it.
All right. I'm up to speed here.
So at this party and an eye,
this is John's ex and,
and I get pretty drunk
and start making up.
None of our friends were
there except for mark.
Mark saw it and got upset you
fucking pussy and just had to leave.
Oh my God.
Really?
Like some 15 year old girl.
Exactly.
Anna and I went to her place
and proceeded to do some stuff.
We didn't bang that night, but oral sex
and whatnot was traded and we passed out.
We both agreed that nobody
needed to know what happened.
I went to Mark's house later,
New Year's day and said nothing
happened with Anna and I,
[inaudible] and I, and by
the way, we just made out.
I figured that was enough for him to know,
not to tell anyone,
especially his fucking girlfriend.
Neither of US brought it up for the next
four days and it seemed like everything
was fine.
A couple of days passed out of nowhere.
Mk asked me if I was going to tell
John that Anna and I made out.
I was sort of taken aback
as you should have been
sorta taken aback by the question,
but I told him I hadn't planned on it.
He said he wouldn't tell John if I
didn't because he didn't want to be a bad
friend. All right, good man.
I told him that it wasn't a big deal
that we just made out and he was being a
huge bitch.
That was a bad move on your part.
Even though he was being a huge bitch.
He shouldn't have said that. All right.
Because he's acting like a fucking chick
right here and hell has no fury like a
woman scorned and you just scored that
fucking bitch man right there. All right,
so you can guess what the
fuck this is going. Okay.
And then asked him if he
told his girlfriend about it
and of course he said yes.
When I asked him why the fuck he did that,
he said,
because I needed to know if I
should tell John Jesus Christ.
I proceeded to column a bitch.
Good man and let them know how much
of a bitch move it was to tell his
girlfriend. Especially since he acted
like everything was fine for four days.
Yeah, this guy is beyond a pussy. This
is the kind of guy who like, you know,
does he like Bake Brownies?
See One of those guys who like doesn't
mind going shopping with his fucking
girlfriend. Yeah. That's funny
that I just said that. I actually,
I'll bake brownies in a fucking second.
I'm such a fucking hypocrite. All right,
let's, let's finish this. All right.
Nobody needed to know about what happened
and now he told his girlfriend, Sarah,
uh Oh, this isn't my fault. Once
again, he fucked up to sentence.
Nobody needs to know about what happened
and now he told his girlfriend Sara
would definitely find out.
I knew Sarah wouldn't care about me.
Drunkenly hooking up with Anna, but it's
still something she didn't need to know.
Oh, Sarah is the fucking
Twat and went to Europe.
Somehow I was able to leave mocks house
without beating the shit out of him.
I called John who was spending winter
break in El Paso and told them what's,
what happened.
He said he didn't really give a shit and
agreed it was fucked up for mark to say
anyone, anything to anyone,
especially as girlfriend.
When I told mark he could have asked
anyone else about whether or not his bitch
ass should tell John what happened.
He said he asked his girlfriend so he
could get a serious opinion as if being
told to keep your fucking mouth shut.
You little girl from either one of you,
either one of our tenants.
So close guy friends wouldn't have
been a serious enough opinion anyways,
I just needed your validation of how
much of a bitch mark was about the whole
thing.
Also,
Anna and I decided to start
sneaking around and are
banging each other. No harm,
no foul.
Feel free to add on to the story of,
I mean you read any podcast.
Yeah, Dude. Yeah, that's, yeah,
that guy right there at that guy. You
need to cut out of the loop. Okay.
That is, um, that's it. You,
you forfeited your fucking guy card.
It's over.
You can't be trusted. You think
like a woman, which is fine.
There's nothing wrong with
thinking like a woman,
but just go hang out with a
bunch of women now what a fucking
do the amount of shit that has
gone down that I have fucking,
I am so buried in me that
I don't even remember it.
The amount of fucking shit
is ridiculous and I don't even bring it
up when it's me and just the other dude
who did the, the dirty shit.
I'll fucking bury it in a second.
I know exactly how to do it.
When I meet your fucking wife or
your girlfriend. I'll fuck yeah,
fucking look you right in the eye. Hey
Sweetie, how are you? You look great.
You've been going to the gym. That's
fantastic. I'll tell you your guy.
He's such a sweetheart.
God Damn it.
The other day there was a cat stuck
in a tree. He's the first guy up.
He didn't even wait for a letter.
A just started climbing
up there when a swell guy,
even if it's a dick,
even if it's a fucking Dick,
what I'll then do is I'll
just avoid his girlfriend,
but I'm not fucking bringing up dude.
That guy really needs to go get
his fucking tubes tied. What a fag.
All right.
Youtube,
youtube videos of the week. You tobe. Um,
all right.
This one is fucking absolutely insane.
And if this was made by white people,
this would actually be considered racist
on some level, but it was actually made,
I don't know if it's Japanese, Chinese
people, whatever the name of the video is,
how to poop.
And it is an animated cartoon
teaching children how to uh,
go poopy in the toilet.
And it is fucking insane.
It's fucking insane.
It's great.
If you really have a problem in your life
that is just weighing on you and it's
sucking the out of you and you just need
to clear every thought from your brain,
please watch how to poop.
Just go to the [inaudible] podcast.com
we've got all these videos, this,
that's the official fence side of
the Monday morning podcast. Uh,
just please go and watch this thing.
It's fucking awesome. We got really good,
I got three really good youtube
videos this week. The next one is, uh,
this guy made a federal reserve
music video that you have to see.
It's a, he's doing basically
a song parody of the police's,
a song. Every breath you
take, it's fucking great.
The guy actually has a really good voice.
This is fucking funny as hell.
Now the great one. And
then the last one is, uh,
it's just a highlight video of Jim Brown
and there's so many fans that say Jim
Brown is overrated and he
couldn't play in today's NFL.
You just look at this highlight reel,
the balance and the power
that this guy has is,
it's unfucking. He, he's like
running sideways half the
time or running backwards,
just plowing over people. The
combination of balance of power is like,
it's,
it's foreshadowing to Earl Campbell,
Earl Campbell's the only guy I've
seen with like runs like this.
And for everyone who thinks Jim
Brown couldn't play, now you're,
you're 100% wrong and I know
what you're going to do.
Are you going to look at how tall he
was and how much he weighed and say he
would get crushed in today's NFL?
That's the wrong way to look at it.
If you took Jim Brown and you
put him in the modern era,
which you have to do is also give them
all the modern trade, uh, nutrition,
all the modern sports
science and all of that.
So he would look like today's NFL
football with his, with his skills,
his God given strength and balance.
And he would fucking tear up the
goddamn league. Go Fuck Yourself.
I don't want to hear another argument.
I'm sick of people bringing
up fucking guys from,
from nowadays where they're taking
fucking horse, tranquil tranquilizers.
You could tell he would have dominated
in 1950 I would have dominated in 1950
somebody 50 years from now
could dominate the NFL.
Right fucking now beget
it's called advancement.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Morons. Alright. Overrated.
Underrated for this week.
Overrated.
Every minority and woman in commercials
playing the straight man to the dumb
white guy. I'm not racist or
misogynistic in the least bit,
but enough is enough. Uh,
dude, that's fucking hilarious.
And that's another thing that uh,
that's not minorities a women's fault.
That's because of all the fucked up
shit white people have done and we don't
want to get sued.
That's why they're doing it.
Not because they're trying to be
sensitive to other sexes or other races.
They just make the white guy be the
stooge it all these fucking commercials
cause they don't want to get sued. But
yeah, it's starting to get annoying.
There's always like the black guy
shaking his head as the fucking white guy
slamming himself in the face
with like a fucking rake.
That's not the way you do it. Um,
that was actually a, a man woman one,
remember that one with a woman's sit
there at the computer and that their
husband is outside fucking, he's
got to go. There's a beehive,
any stake taking like a broom handle and
he's shoving it up the fucking beehive.
And then he gets stung and she's
sitting there rolling her eyes like, ah,
my husband, he's a fucking retard. Uh,
and they do that between men and
women and race and the fucking, uh,
the white dude always has to be the moron.
But I mean, you know, it is what it is,
but you know, you should be happy
white person who wrote that,
that they had that. That's the
way they balance it out. You know,
you're still winning, so quit
your fucking crying. All right.
Also overrated in real life and not what
I see on TV is the female carpenter or
construction worker I get,
I get that you've got to make up and
try harder for all the bullshit you deal
with. For Fuck's sake. Crack
a smile for once in your life.
I really don't know what
he's bitching about.
Their female construction workers
don't smile enough. Um, alright.
Underrated the PJ's Eddie Murphy was
brilliant and the claymation was the shit
back in the day.
Why the fuck don't,
why the fuck that show isn't on
DVD is a crime to all comedy.
One of the few shows that is actually
better with closed caption on a number two
real musicians.
Anybody remember these people that
naturally play actually play their
instruments and none of
that fucking auto tuners,
sampling machine and turntables,
all of those are not fucking instruments.
Um, well I mean, you know,
I've actually come to a place where I can,
I can understand the brilliance
of being able to take pieces of,
so I think the way that the Beastie
boys did it on Paul's Boutique where you
took like 10 or 12 different samples,
looped them together and
created a new song. I mean,
there is there that is a
talent, you know, turntables,
that's just, I don't get that shit. That's
just, I don't, I don't understand that.
Um, I'm too fucking old to get that
and I don't get, I don't get mashups.
I bitched about that before.
Mashups are the emperor's
new clothes of music.
Okay. All you have to do is pick
two songs that are the same temple.
Okay.
Same beats per minute.
Then the lyrics will
fit on that other one.
Then all you have to do is just one that
where the lyrics fit the mood of the,
the new music you're putting it over.
That's not that fucking difficult.
If he got sad sorta music,
pick another sad fucking song and just
stick that music under those sad lyrics.
As long as the tempo was the same.
Yeah, it's going to work out.
Dude. He took jingle bells and blended
it with Santa Claus is coming to town.
MMM.
What else do we got?
A road trip.
Road trips with your fucking bug
buddies never gets old. That's,
that's absolutely true. That's why the
hangover was such a great fucking movie.
A real lemonade.
Not that coke and Pepsi package garbage
but real shit with fucking pulp and
flavor. I like this guy. This
guy's into old shit. You know.
A pen and paper,
not this fucking laptop horse shit.
I don't remember my laptop ever crash and
I've actually said that. Um, all right,
that's it. That's the podcast
for this week. Everybody.
I hope you had a great
week. Um, and once again,
good forward to the uh,
the Steelers Greenbay
championships and do me a favor,
bring up all Green Bay's NFL titles.
I would really like to try to start an
underground debate about that because I
want them to start counting NFL titles
and I want to see NFL franchises fly
those NFL championship
flags. You want it, you know,
I didn't think the AFL one should fly
those flags. It's part of the history.
If you're a fucking nerd like me,
I like that type of shit.
I'm actually reading a book
right now called the greatest
game by Richard Bailey.
Uh,
somebody gave me this book and uh,
it's actually about
the Bucky Dent Red Sox,
that one one day play off game.
And you know,
that's a great thing about the red
sox finally winning a world series and
they're wedding.
Another one.
I can actually sit back and
read this book and it is a,
okay.
It's a fucking great read to great read.
I recommend it. All right. That's it.
That's a podcast for this week.
Everybody have a great week.
I'm at the Improv and Addison,
Addison, Texas this week. And,
um,
okay.
What else do I got coming up? Let's go
on my website. Uh, hang on one second.
Come on guys. Hagen that don't shut it
off just yet. Don't shut it off just yet.
All right. Um, then I'm going to be at
the count Basie theater in Red Bank,
New Jersey on February 18th,
and I'm going to be at the new
okay.
Of Jesus Christ to Tarrytown
musical on the 17th of February,
Miami beach. We have a new theater.
Um, they had me booked in another one,
but they had already booked another
act there, so they had to switch it up.
I'm actually going to be at the new World
Symphony Theater, uh, on 17th Street,
Miami Beach, Florida, or
the, the 4th of March,
the tower theater in Philadelphia.
Look,
I got a bunch of new dates on the website,
tower theater in Philadelphia
on April 9th. And,
um,
this is the last one here.
I'm going to be at the paps. Fuck
Jesus Christ, the linkedin work.
I would be at the, you know, I was having
such a great podcast too. On April 22nd,
I'm going to be at the PAPP's
theater in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Um,
and right off the bat,
I just want to tell you,
I'm blown away about how many
tickets sold the first day. Uh,
Milwaukee was one of those cities where
I was like, you know, I dunno. I Dunno.
I Dunno if I'm gonna sell tickets
there. You know, it's not like New York.
It's not Chicago, it's not La, you know,
so it's not one of those kinds of cities,
but I don't, it doesn't strike me
as a gator dad kind of city either.
It's one of those middle ground once.
So I don't know where the
fuck I'm going to fit in it.
So I want to thank everybody in Wisconsin
who went out and bought tickets.
MMM.
Especially, Oh, you know what?
Somebody sent me a fucking email if I
can just from Escanaba Michigan saying
they were coming all the way down
because they remembered back in the day.
I played a college up there and the upper
peninsula of Michigan and they said,
um,
I went up in front of 17 people in
a cafeteria and evidently I killed.
So the fact that actually put
on a show in front of 17 people,
see how it see all that new comedians.
If you're listening to this podcast,
those fucking shows matter.
Years later,
they'll actually show up if you give
him hell in front of 11 people doing a
nooner or the upper peninsula, Michigan.
I actually fucking remember that Gig.
I did a couple of gigs up there though.
That's an amazing group of
people who live up there.
I like how they embrace winter.
They really have no choice,
but they actually get real fucking a
snow storms. You know where you come out,
you open your door,
you know,
and you get buried by like
nine feet of fucking snow.
You walking down the street on your
snow shoes and you're stepping over like
frozen elk, right? You know, and
they just stay. Just stay. Embrace it
as opposed to all the pussies down here.
Every time there's four
inch is a fucking snore.
Every god damn fatty is running down
to the fucking supermarket like they're
going to starve to death.
I just want one news guy.
During all that insanity,
we're going to get six to eight inches.
It's like,
do you realize six to eight inches of
snow it that would barely reach the
average person's up to their cath and
considering you can last about 35 days
without food as long he had, as
long as you have water. Okay?
And Snow is water. Stick it in your
mouth. See what happens. All right,
you've gotta be fucking fine.
All right, so sit tight.
Okay.
All right. Their sport. That's
what I wanted to say. I want to,
I want them to just fucking sit there
and watch the weatherman losing his
fucking mind.
All excited that he's the focus this
week on the God damn fucking newscast,
right? Well that night of the newscast
and then when they go back to the anchor,
who's fucking the co-anchor cause
he's the god Damn Alpha male.
I want them to dress down that
fucking that goddamn a weatherman.
Four inches of snow. Jesus Christ.
I could stick my dick in that.
You could still see the shaft. The fuck
are you talking about? Go Fuck Yourself.
All right, that's it. That's a park
cast for this week. You guys have a
great weekend. Yeah, go fuck yourselves.
Don't take any shit.