Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
his time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast data.
Just checking in on you.
Ah,
just checking in on your week.
How's it go?
One hour you're slogging
your way through another one,
settling in to 2017 as it had been.
Everything that you expected so far,
are you still going to the gym?
Have you have or are you sticking with
your, I'm not going to take the bait,
you know, with your, your,
whatever the fuck you're
dating, whatever you're rent to,
whatever you have led into
your fucking apartment.
Be it a flat, a one bedroom
of fucking a studio. I mean,
or a fucking maybe got a little house,
you know?
Do you know that's one of the
top reasons people get a house.
It's because they fall in love with
somebody and the only way to keep it going
is there has to be another room
for you to walk into. You know,
there has to be a door that you
could walk through and close. See,
you just can't see the person. Even if he
can hear him. You just need that space.
That's what it is,
which really shows you what con's
super rich people are considering.
They have a fucking mansion,
you know, and it's still not,
it's still not enough
room for them to get away.
They get divorced left and
right. You know, or this is,
they go into another room.
Right. And, but there's
always somebody in there,
somebody's Dustin off of
vase or some shit. See,
you can't just have that alone time to
just go in there and just sort of yell,
whisper. Right. You can't do it.
Um, I wonder if your spouse ever
saw or your boyfriend, girlfriend,
whatever the fucking issue were to
ever saw a highlight reel of the shit
that you said when you got into your car
after a fucking disagreement.
Um,
it would either be the funniest shit
I think with me and my wife would be
fucking hilarious. Uh, I think her shit
about me, we hilarious. Mine wouldn't be,
you know, you know, cause I'm angry
because I'm the guy. Cause what?
Cause we're always raw, you know,
according to those doctor Phil shows,
we don't have a fucking leg
to stand on. Um, anyways,
speaking of which, you
know what? I got to admit,
I actually watched three
days in a row of whale. Oh,
for Jan and I missed it last night.
And uh, I was actually upset.
I think I'm actually gonna put
that on my DVR to record the show.
There's just something so
mindlessly fun about that show.
He just sit there and you try to
yell the letters with them. Hey,
there's t um,
okay.
And jeopardy.
I'm telling you right now,
I'm so sick of people thinking that
people in jeopardy of fucking smart,
those people are nerds. Okay.
The book smart. No, nobody.
I've never seen one person on that show
look like they have any sort of a vision.
Okay, you give him a fucking book.
Yeah, they're going to read it in a day.
They're going to retain 80% of the
information and then some day, you know,
at a cocktail party or a game show,
they're going to puke it up
when you fucking go, Hey,
what's the capitol of fucking Tanzania?
That's even a country.
They'll fucking tell you what it
is and what the state bird is.
You know what I mean? They end the day,
know some shit about classical music.
They all his fucking trivial.
It's trivial shit to be honest with you.
It's just shit. You know,
the only purpose for no one,
like 90% of the shit that they have on
that show, if you really think about it,
it just, it doesn't help
you in your life, you know,
depending on what you're looking to do.
I mean,
if you want to make like a
zillion dollars, it's like no one,
all that shit does not help
you. Like, wow, this guy knows,
or this woman knows a lot of
shit. Yeah, but what, what do,
what do you know about
you fucking baroque music?
You know,
you go to crossword puzzles,
I'm telling you,
you got to have a different kind of smart,
you got to have Donald Trump intelligence.
Okay?
And what you need to learn how to do
is you have to learn how to mobilize
morons.
You know,
and I'm not saying just because you
voted for Donald Trump, you're Maura,
but you know what I mean?
I'm talking about,
yeah,
I'm talking about the kinds of people
that would be excited if like Mayweather
fought Conor McGregor,
you know,
not seeing that for what
the fuck it's going to be,
which is basically about 12 people
vacuuming $100 a zillion people's pockets.
Why would you want to see that?
It's like that is a lose lose,
right? If they have that fight and
it's, it's going to be boxing only,
it's going to, it's over. If it's,
if it's going to be MMA rules,
Mayweather's going to lose.
It's going to be over in two seconds.
It's the stupidest fucking thing.
You know what it goes back to?
It goes back like that fight.
We'll, we'll, if that happens,
will be no different than when fucking
Bobby Riggs played tennis against Billie
Jean King.
At least he was a fucking tennis player.
You know,
I would say it'd be more like when
Muhammad Ali fought Lowel Zaida
that's not fair. Somebody compared to
a Muhammad Ali fought like the best,
you know, uh, Japanese
wrestlers in like 1976 now,
I'm assuming it was actually real
wrestling and not like the fake shit where
they still fucking break their necks. But
you know what I mean? The predetermined,
um, is it, was it Bobby Riggs? I
think that that was the guy's name.
The guy played bill fight a fight.
I mean,
fucking played tennis against
Billy Jean King. You know,
it was so fucking pathetic about that
is that was considered a big victory for
women that the best tennis female tennis
player in her fucking prime beat like a
fucking 57 year old former champion
is the thing though. He was winning
games. He actually didn't do that bad.
And then years later there
was stuff that came out,
said he was a degenerate gambler
and that he possibly, you know,
could have placed a bet on Billie Jean
King made it look good for a minute and
then fucking, I dunno
what someone is. Yeah,
buddy of mine was talking about that.
See the,
you know Dana Way off from both 25
million bucks. Of course he did.
Of course he did because he's going to
find 50 million fucking idiots to give
him a hundred bucks.
Um,
anyways. Yeah. What would you, you know,
would you want to see a baker get involved
in a, a cooking contest with, okay,
we're going to smoke meat today.
We've got a champion guy fucking,
and he's won every smoking the meat
comp I can contest. He's going against.
The Gal makes cupcakes.
They're both in the kitchen.
They're both making food.
But I guess the other guys outside,
you know what I mean? It's
just two completely different
fucking fix. All right.
Um, anyways, and that's
what Donald Trump did.
Donald Trump was able to fucking do that.
He got enough of them together.
And that's what you need to do. All
right. And I'll tell you right now,
I haven't yet to see a contestant on
jeopardy who can even remotely get the
mouth breathers.
They key to get the fucking heard moving
towards whatever cliff you'd want them
to fucking topple over. They
don't have it. You know,
just sitting there going like, uh,
you know, I'll take a, I dunno,
I'll take ancient Indian
construction for $700.
Uh, this structure was, uh, well,
one of the most popular for lack of a
plan was there in the 60. [inaudible].
What is a wigwam?
Uh,
let me get door hinges
from Switzerland Circa of,
uh,
Jesus crisis 32nd birthday for 200.
You're not going to fucking get anywhere
or maybe I'm just insecure when I watch
it. All right, let's go. Let's get, maybe
we're getting to the real shit here,
by the way. I have a Boston Detroit
came on in the fucking background.
You know what's hilarious as they just
showed a skyline and I think I saw the
casino I played right across
the fucking way, you know,
we had just into Canada.
You know,
um, Jesus Christ, the Bruins
play in the island is holy shit.
What a shit show that was.
That was one of the worst games I've seen
them play in a long, long fucking time.
Got smoked four to nothing and now much
of the Redwings and all of a sudden they
come out, they're ready to play.
And you got to ask yourself,
where is this night in and night?
Um,
I honestly didn't know.
They tearing down Joe Louis Arena.
They're saying this is the last
Bruins regular season game ever, um,
against, uh, against the Redwings here
at Joe Louis Arena. That's I, you know,
and I got a chance to go to that one. I
went to a, believe it or not, I went to a,
uh, red wings Penguin's game in, uh,
I don't know how many years ago.
And I quickly learned that you have to
sit back in that stadium if you fucking
lean forward and everyone
behind you has to lean forward.
It's like there was all these fucking
rules, but because I'm a considerate con,
I was able to figure it out by halfway,
you know,
halfway through the first period,
with people screaming at me from
behind and I was like, all right,
I get this shit,
I get it.
But it's just one of these
fucked up arenas where you
can't even stand up if you
stand up and applaud the play.
Half your head is blocking the TV
screen of whatever the TV camera.
Um, but anyways, I want to say this,
this'll be the third. This is the
second one they're going to get rid of.
And then the next one will be their third.
They played,
it was at Olympia or something like that,
which I have no recollection of really.
I don't think.
I think the first time I remember watching
the fucking Redwings was the early
eighties and I think in the late
seventies they get rid of that one.
Oh see this is some, this right
here. This is some shit on jeopardy.
I'll take a arenas,
former arenas that sports
franchises played in.
What is county stadium? Excellent.
What does that get you in life?
You know,
when it gets you a kit,
you sitting in your fucking pajamas doing
a God damn podcast Thursday morning,
that's where it gets you. Um, so
anyways, I haven't been doing shit,
no kid yet. So you know,
we're coming right up on going
full term. So I think, uh,
you know, we're going to have to induce
or something like that. But either way,
most likely, you know, barring
some sort of like a miracle,
I should be dead next week. I think
it finally goes down that all right.
And then my whole perspective changes.
What are you guys going to do if I really,
you know, there's some people have
kids, they don't fucking change it all.
And then there's other people that have
kids they change, which I think is shit,
right? But what do you guys do if I
just fuck if I go off the fucking rails,
you know, I stopped Carson, I stopped
saying, can't, you know what I mean?
I find God,
I reevaluate everything.
That fucking remotely makes me funny.
Nothing,
nothing for a third time.
Not Robs of all your humor,
like finding your savior,
you know what I mean? All of a
sudden you give a shit about people,
you know,
you have empathy.
You put yourself in other
people's position. Yeah.
Okay.
Which is also known as empathy.
Now I've seen it. I've seen it in the
past. I've seen, I've just seen too,
I've seen musicians, I've seen Comedians,
I've seen all of that. They find God.
They get away from, what the fuck got
you. Got You to the God damn dance.
All right. It ain't happening
with me. I'm calling it right now.
What do you think? I'm, you think I'm
going to start reading? I will read what?
I become a dead. You know, I'm going to
read these kids' books. Whichever Deli.
I don't even, I don't even get, I guess
that Caterpillar One's a classic book.
I never saw.
I never saw that one when I was a kid.
I liked to make way for ducklings.
I like where the wild things are.
Okay.
Um, and that was it. And that
was the two books. I liked it.
And then other than that,
I liked fucking football cards
and not doing my homework.
That's what I enjoyed. Hey Dad, what did
you enjoy most about your childhood? Uh,
blowing off the assignment and the
challenge of pretending that I did it.
Uh, the next day in class, that's
what I remember joining the most.
I like drawing on desks.
Uh, getting in trouble,
going down to the principal's office
with a friend was always fun by yourself,
was a lonely experience, you know, sitting
on that bench waiting to go in there.
William, come on in it for a second. Uh,
Ms, uh, [inaudible] as Sarah said
to you at tech and they do it,
I'll let shit you just,
you just standing there going like,
why are you talking to me?
Like I can actually plead my case and
you're going to be on my fucking say, oh,
I didn't look at it that way ever.
Evidently the teacher was wrong.
Just give me the fucking detention.
You fucking cunt.
You know, it's funny, when I really
looked back, my, uh, the principal,
vice principal and my school, he's a
gavel leash to dole out the punishment.
He used to dress like the geek squad
guys who upon seeing a hidden figures
dressed like he worked at NASA,
you know,
I don't fucking know. Anyways,
what am I talking about here?
Let's plow ahead all we got some
football this weekend yet that worded,
you know what,
one of the,
one of the dangerous things to do when
you're watching NFL playoffs is not to
realize while you're watching it,
that the NFL season is almost over you.
So fucking excited that it's the playoffs.
Who's going to win?
I said this, I said, dad,
dude, I called it. I got,
I fucking put my kids' college
education on the Pittsburgh Steelers.
What the point?
Fuck it.
Okay.
42, Detroit. I mean,
42 Bruins. God dammit.
We needed to get that next one out in the
second period. Uh, you know, you know,
I swear to God with
fucking hockey nowadays,
the second they got rid of the red line,
there's no lead that's safe.
Back in the day you went up three goals.
The fucking game was over.
There was going to be like a fucking bench
clearing brawl because the other team
knew that they weren't going to
win. Right. So they sell high. Well,
if we're not going to beat you will
beat the shit out of you. And that,
that was hockey. That was the
hockey that I remembered. Um,
yeah.
Now you go up three to nothing
and it's, you know, for candidate,
you can go up three to nothing
and you go into the third period,
you can still be going into overtime.
So it was three, nothing Bruins.
Then three to one, then four
to one, and now it's 42.
Okay.
Yeah. Jesus Christ. Anyways,
um, you know something,
I've been meditating so much,
uh,
I just been consistently not by lot that
actually losing my shit now feels weird.
It just felt weird to scream. Fucking
cut there. I wasn't really mad.
It was just upset. One of
those two things. The same
thing, Bill. You know what,
go fuck yourself. Uh, anyways.
Anyway.
Yeah.
So you're watching the NFL playoffs and
you forget because you're so fucking
excited that it's the playoffs and you're
going to get to see somebody, you know,
the best teams play each other.
Next thing you know,
it's the super bowl and he gets you.
He gets your first taste of
no fucking football. When, uh,
there's that break between the,
for whatever fucking reason between the,
uh,
the NFC and AFC gene games,
championship games, and the Super Bowl,
you get that first Sunday that comes by,
you know,
back in the day they used to give
you the pro bowl ego Fuckos right?
Um,
is 22 people not really trying and that
was your first hand of, Oh wait a minute,
they're going to play the fucking super
bowl and then I have to sit here for
another six months with
no fucking football.
So what I'm saying is try to enjoy it.
There's only three football
games left in the year. You know,
I'm not trying to ram actually raining
on the fucking parade here, but uh,
that's something I always forget.
And then all of a sudden the Superbowl's
over and then, then, you know,
you're not even thinking,
wow,
I can't believe this team beat that team
or this team loss, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
And then next Sunday comes along and
you're sitting there on your front porch
waiting for your absentee father
that show up in the eight common,
he's not coming to the end of the summer.
You got to grow six inches and he finally
going to show up. Hey, what's up sport?
How you've been on a fuck.
Have you been, um, anyways,
let me read a little bit of
advertising here for this week. Um,
as it rained again last night,
rain,
rain pretty much all night
long, which is great, man.
We're just getting a ton of
fucking rain out here. And uh,
but I don't subscribe to that fucking
lunacy that the drought is over.
Yeah. In, in the, in the, in the near
future it is. Put it in the fucking net.
You can't, uh, you come here,
come the Goddamn read books.
You can feel it.
I tell you right now,
the next goal is the most important goal.
It's cake.
It's difference between five to two or 43.
Give a one team hope putting
the gave away. All right, let's,
let's read a little bit advertising here.
Oh,
[inaudible] Miyan d play
enough fucking red wings.
But Dude, dude, my Mondays,
Mondays losing them would be a sin.
Meaning not as a right man.
Fuck them with their red and white UNIS.
I don't like that. They're called
hockey town. It's a bad nickname.
And you shouldn't give one to your
fucking self. That's up to your friends.
Oh yeah. Why would you give yourself
a nickname? Cause you're reduced bag.
Why the do the two
hockey town?
It's a town that likes hockey.
Me undies.
Everybody this Valentine's Day give a
gift that they can unwrap again and again.
Matching underwear for me
on these Valentine's Day is
near and it's go time for
thoughtful gift counting beyond.
He says you covered with
limited edition matching,
matching pairs of undies
for you and yours. Okay. I
mean you are giving one day,
all my family members were going to walk
around like the fucking the Waltons. Ah,
has Valentine's Day. Got You stumped.
Okay. No it doesn't. I don't celebrate it.
I go out the next night when food costs,
what the fuck it should cost and the,
and the restaurants aren't
jam packed with people.
Forget the cliches and give
a gift that looks great,
feels great and will make everyone happy.
Me undies.
Fancy dinners and chocolates last
at night. Flowers last a week.
Shots fired this year.
Give the gift of looking great.
Feeling great every day with the
world's most comfortable underwear.
Heads up Valentine's Day,
February 14th if you haven't noticed
that every fucking year, your life,
don't panic. Get you a hat on and show
some love with me undies matching undies,
please include all of the following
points during your read. I read all the,
she fucking write it.
I'll read it.
Me undies or the perfect gift for
you and your Valentine this holiday.
They're unbelievably so oft and
come and limited edition prints. Oh,
so don't wear them.
These things could be worth money someday.
You know somebody's comment and 20
years is going to want to want to buy.
Some fucking never
opened before me undies.
You know like those stupid action
figures that grown fucking men.
You know,
they want to get the Millennium Falcon
still in the box and then they're going
to buy it and keep it in the box. Like
that's, that's their retirement plan.
That's how bad the bankers
have fucked over this country.
Hey, by the way, considering the
Federal Reserve is not a, uh,
it's private corporation.
Here's my question. Where
does the money, where do the,
what is your tax dollars go?
Your federal income tax dollars.
It goes to the Federal Reserve. What
do they spend that money on? I get it.
I get at a fucking state level that that's
allegedly going to go to fucking fix
and pothole. Let me get back to me on
me. Undies knows that your special,
someone deserves a special fabric,
which is why their underwear is
made exclusively out of modal,
modal of fabric with a touch
three times softer than cotton.
Beyond has a special limited
edition Valentine's undies,
which means you and your
Valentine's can match and yeah,
it's as cute as it sounds. Jesus
Christ. Yeah, that's great. Dress.
You dress your wife in the same underwear
as you and then go to make a move of
fucking weird. Is that
going to be, you know,
just wear the same boxers you have on,
gives a whole meeting to go fuck yourself,
doesn't it? And if for some reason you
and me undies aren't a perfect match,
they'll give you your money back
and let you keep the first pair.
There's no refund on a bad fancy dinner.
They offer free shipping.
And for a limited time, listeners to this
station get 20% off their first order,
but you have to go to [inaudible]
dot com slash bar with me undies.
Better Day guarantee you have nothing
to lose. So don't wait any longer.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash bird
right now for your 20 for 20% off your
first order. All right. You know what I
mean? Where the fuck does that money go
in the end? If you're at the top
of the fucking Federal Reserve,
why would you pay taxes?
What do you,
what are you going to fucking
investigate yourself? Do you know any,
any money made past 11 million?
All right.
Say you're really fucking successful.
You come up with some sort of APP,
you know, you were smart
enough not to go on shark tank,
so they didn't buy it off you
for fucking $30. You know,
you retain the money. You
like that Facebook guy, right?
That little fucking cunt.
You know,
we stole the idea from all his fucking
Harvard people for probably, I don't know,
they're making money in oil in Iraq
now. You know, all his Harvard people,
you know, if they don't, if they don't
end up like being comedy writers,
they just kind of go around the world
doing horrible things, don't they?
Isn't that what all Ivy League people
do? You know, they start managing,
affirm that fucking cuts down the Amazon.
Oh, this is just sour grapes from someone
who couldn't even go to a community
college. Um, what was I
saying? Yeah. Like wait,
what do they use that money for?
If the Federal Reserve is in
fact a private corporation,
you give them the fucking money.
Where the fuck does it go? So our,
I was going to say, so after any
money you make after $11 million,
that money you already paid taxes on
that you then should just be able to give
the a kids nice. You just sit around
getting a drug habit. You know, if you,
if you make over 11 million bucks,
if you give it to them,
you then have your kids have to
pay 45% tax to the fucking IRS,
which means any sort of sizable fortune.
Okay.
The IRS gets 45% of that.
Every fucking sizable afforded a
Rod Kevin Durant under 90 million,
you know, provided, you know,
they don't blow their money,
which is something to be said too.
This is what you should do.
You should just go out and
blow your fucking cash,
but don't fucking blow it on stuff.
Just go around a regular
people and give it to them.
There's gotta be a way to turn it around.
You can't do that.
You can't give them out free this, that
kind of money. Actually. Maybe you could
then they get these psycho.
Fuck you. Oh, nice. Safe. Nice.
It it didn't save it.
Four or three. Ah, Jesus Christ.
Oh, you know how much of the
red wing fans and join this,
cause you know the fucking
outcome of this game, aren't you?
Okay.
Are we really going to blow
it three nothing to lead in
the first fucking period.
Is that what we're going
to do? Oh, that's great.
Everybody can fucking go behind
the net goal for the puck.
That looks like me playing pickup
hockey and I am a puck. Chase a jackass.
I have not played hockey and like,
well over a year.
I didn't play one slash two year.
I get hockey stuff.
Just sit in my God damn bag I
was supposed to play last week.
Yeah, it was just fucking eight.
Anyways, movement watches everybody.
Oh, it's going to say, yeah,
if he gave every, if every,
if every fucking say
that Facebook can right.
Just kind of gives away his
money just to regular people.
What would be great about that is that,
uh,
the first thing I would immediately do
is I would invest in whatever companies
make four wheelers,
right?
Jacuzzis jet skis.
Like the average fucking guy
who wins the lottery. I mean,
that's what they're going to buy.
You're going to get a Jacuzzi,
you're going to get a jet ski and you're
going to get a four wheeler. All right?
Then what else are they gonna do?
They're going to have that and know
what the fuck by George Foreman Grill.
I have no idea,
but the three out of four of those you'll
hit and the stock market, all right?
Then you get all these cards out there,
okay? They're not going to have to work,
which means they're going to be drunk
and they're going to get on these four
wheelers. They're going to tip over
and they're going to crush their,
their ribs will crush their,
their,
their vitals and the population
will start to go doubt.
Maybe.
Maybe that's what it is.
Maybe that's how the Illuminati
plants to thin out the herd. Um,
MVMT watches everybody movement watches
the company started the company started
by two broke college kids.
I don't understand how you started
fucking company if you're broke,
but we're flat broke. Let's
start making watches, um,
that wanted to wear stylists,
watches but couldn't afford them.
So they started their own watch company.
How is this like how you started?
Okay.
Built a following lunch to the podcast.
You've,
okay.
They have the weirdest copy.
I guess I'm supposed to like,
this is how is this like how you
started built a following launched into
podcast, youtube, radio, et cetera. Hey,
I'm not here to ask answer questions.
I'm just here to read. Read
your shit. Who would watch it?
Started it just start at just 95 bucks
at it to start mint department store.
You're looking at four to
500 bucks movement figured
out that by selling online
they were able to cut up,
cut out the middleman and retail markup,
providing the best possible price.
Classic design,
quality construction
and styled minimalism.
Over 500,000 watches
sold and 160 countries.
Get 50% off today with free shipping
and free returns by going to movement
watches.com/bar. This watch
has a really clean design. Uh,
you'll be getting compliments
everywhere you go.
Now is the time to step up your
watch gang. Go to movement,
watches.com/burr and join
the mother fucking movement.
Um, all right, we got two more.
I always give you guys a break from
listening to me. Read out loud, okay?
It's not an enjoyable
thing. All right? Plus,
if I drag out this
podcast a little longer,
maybe you can listen to my fucking
Bruins Lewis. Come on yet. All right,
here we go. Bring it over the Blue Line.
And what are we going to Dell? Yay.
Take taken away. You
know, it's really hard.
Even if you know the names
of the players on your teams,
hockey move so fucking fast to sit here
and try to announce what is going on and
then to try to know all
these God damn names. I mean,
I don't even know what countries,
half of these fucking people come from.
All I know is they have like the,
uh, you know, whatever they are,
wheel of fortune is over there.
I don't think anybody's buying any vials.
And I think, you know, over here
we're always like, give me an s,
let me see a t over there. It's
like, give me an h gimme a z,
like their fucking name.
Like the first,
like the first three letters would be
like c, h Z. It's like I'm supposed to,
I'm supposed to read that. Yeah. Bill,
you are disposed to have what it a
name like yours, bill or fucking Larry.
Excuse them for having a culture.
Um,
I don't give a shit that this,
that there's foreigners in this,
in the national hockey league that
was starting in Canada, you know,
the Goddamn league was started by
foreigners. Okay. And you know,
being a Trump supporter,
I never thought the NHL should have been
allowed to come into the United States
of America. Come on back in. Um,
yeah, I don't think that they should have
been allowed to come in here. You know,
and I hope when Donald Trump is a,
is done making that wall
between here and Mexico,
he then makes one between here and uh,
Canada.
So these God damn foreigners can stop
coming down here on their skates.
Entertaining mouth breathers like
myself cause I've had it, you know,
that should be me out there on the
ice. They took my job frame. Bridge.
Everyone are your walls empty?
Is Your Life Empty?
Do you look at your walls?
It wish you had something to look at.
Do you have a bunch of photos lying
around? A lot of questions here.
around or art at rolled up and your closet
just waiting for you to put it in a
nice frame and hang on your walls?
Let me tell you something right now.
You do not have art rolled up
in your closet. What? That's,
that's called a poster.
I got a Picasso rolled up at my fucking
closet. Now is your chance to get I,
I really had to pause to try to come up
with somebody. A Van Gogh oh two for two.
Now is your chance to get them framed up,
framed in,
up@framebridgedotcomgotoframebridge.com
choose your frame,
not Cambridge frame
bridge. Choose your frame,
uh,
let their design has helped you choose.
Upload Your Photo and you
computer upload to you.
Upload your photo from your
computer directly from Instagram.
Preview your photo online in the frame
you choose can upload your photo or art.
Slash. Poster. No worries.
You can mail it in for free.
Instead of the hundreds
you pay at a framing store,
their prices start at 39 bucks
and all the shipping is free.
Plus my listeners will get 15% off their
first order at [inaudible] dot com when
they use my code. Burr frame bridge
uses premium real wood moldings,
acid free mat board, and for our
good, the mat board is acid free.
Thank God.
I'll take our acid free Matt boards
for 600 they're acrylic glazing.
We'll never shatter and protects
your piece from harmful UV rays.
The expert team at frame bridge.
We'll custom frame your item in days,
not weeks or months,
and deliver your friend finished piece
directly to your door. Ready to hang.
Frame Bridge offers a happiness guarantee.
Their team gives each item personal
care and attention because meeting your
expectations is as important as
meeting their own. Get started today.
Framing your photos are our go to
frame bridge.com and use the Promo code
[inaudible]. You'll save an additional 50%
off your first order. Just go to frame,
bridge.com Promo Code Burp.
I mean,
seriously, people. Where does the
money go? All right. Simply safe.
This is the last one.
Simply faith, don't you?
Everybody want to be simply faith.
It sounds like a bad band,
doesn't it?
One of those bands that cares about
issues at where the red or brown simply
safe. Just a heads up. Simply safe. Home
security is massive. New Year's Eve.
New Year's sale ends this Sunday.
Uh,
if you haven't seen it this deal already,
I check it out right now.
You can get $200 off simply states.
Defender package.
I like that.
It just does tender package.
Their most popular security system of
2016 this alarm is everything you need for
comprehensive home
protection with simply safe.
Any burglar who attacks your home gets
bombarded by an arsenal of security
census and an ear splitting siren.
And with 24 seven monitoring
help is never far off.
Simply safe calls,
police the minute you need them.
There's no longterm contract, no hidden
fees and no installation costs though.
Wait,
these simply safe defender systems have
been flying off the shelves and with the
sale ending this Sunday.
Uh
Okay.
I can't parentheses or it's hard
to guarantee they'll stay in stock.
Go to simply safe
xxx.com to get your $200.
I'm about to say burr.
I Dunno, I dunno what the fuck a website
is. I have no fucking idea. Simply safe,
everybody simply safe.
Everybody figured out for yourself.
I would tell you by about the time I
bought a safe like 10 fucking years ago,
you know.
Okay.
I bought a safe cause I had like, you
know, moved out and all that shit. Well,
shit moved out and moved out for 10
years and somebody hit me all fucking
paranoid. You know that if I lost
my birth certificate, my passport,
you know,
by done my first standup special and
I had the original like whatever the,
the master copy of it and
basically if that thing was gone,
I was afraid I was
fucked. Oh No. Break away.
They scored
four to four.
It was three to nothing. Then it was
three to one, then it was four to one,
then was 42 then it was 43
then it was four to four.
These fucking constant scored three goals.
We haven't scored anything.
How does, how does this
even happen? Oh yeah.
Our defenseman falls down. Yeah,
that'll do it. I got to tell you kids,
one of the big things you want to
void when you're playing team hockey,
it's the fucking,
we just fell down.
Ah, that's all right. That's
all right. All right. Anyways,
so I get this. I just got
this little fucking, you
know, it wasn't even that bad.
The fucking safe was like the
size of like a kitchen fridge.
I mean one of those little ones.
So you know what I mean?
One of those ones that you can
also use as like a nightstand.
So one of the things about getting a safe
is she don't want anybody to know that
you have it, you know, or a kind
of defeats the fucking purpose.
So these assholes come
okay
to fucking deliver the safe.
And I'm living on a second floor walk.
Okay.
It's what I'm in New York City, right?
I live in a second floor walkup,
which is great. So, um, you know, oh,
we just fuck it's gone.
Adam McQuaid.
Five to four.
Okay.
This game is shaping up.
Did anybody see that?
Penguins fucking capitals game
eight to seven. Here we go.
The fuck is going. They didn't even play
in goal. He had a clean look at that too.
Oh, it tipped and then it bounced
between his fucking balls.
The old five hall there. Anyways,
so I'm living in New York City.
I got a second floor fucking walk up.
So I have these guys deliver it. Right.
And like I said, the thing is you
want nobody know that you have it.
Not only do you want
to have a fucking safe,
but you don't want anybody to know that
you have it because immediately you get
is safe.
People think you have bars of gold
worth half a million of whack in there.
We're just gonna fucking busted your
apartment and find a fucking, you know,
my birth certificate and
the fucking, you know, the,
the master to my first standup special.
So the dude shows up.
Now the thing about a
fucking safe is not only,
there's two things about a safe one,
you know,
once someone to be able to crack the safe,
pick the lock or whatever and
get in there. And number two,
you don't want it to be like,
you don't want someone to be able to
just be able to pick it up and leave with
it. So then they can go to their
house and take a fucking blow torch.
So it's gotta be really
fucking heavy. It's gotta be
hard to break into. And then,
you know, depending on
the thickness, you know,
it can survive a fire for
a specified amount of time.
So I get this basic fucking safe, you
know, I don't wait a couple, I don't know,
a couple of hundred pounds.
I don't know when it weighed.
And this fucking guy shows up with this.
I never seen this thing before.
It was an elected, an
electronic two wheeler. Okay.
And I lived in this old building to flow,
walk up.
He shows up like Saturday morning,
everybody's asleep in every step.
He press a button and it would
lift the safe up and then he,
I don't know.
And then the wheels would go up to the
next thing and it was the loudest fucking
noise ever. Every state. And we got here.
Yeah,
he did two flights of stairs and
everybody's open in their apartments,
looking out,
seeing the safe and then looking at me
and see me standing there with my fucking
door open.
Like nothing to see here.
Everybody just buying a
safe from my bars of gold.
I fucking was so convinced that my
apart what was going to get broken into.
Um, and then what was funny
when I went to move out,
I just had friends helped me move
out and we didn't have that thing.
So then I just had to leave the safe.
I just left to safe and gave
the person the combination.
And that's what happens to all safes.
Like wherever they get delivered to his,
where they fucking stay,
uh,
there never moved than haven't booked
because they're too fucking heavy and you
just, you just gotta say fuck it.
You leave him now leave it. Yeah. Um,
anyways, is that the podcast
for this week? I have no idea.
My wife's gonna kill me.
I screaming about every goal and a fucking
imitating somebody bringing us safe
up two flights of stairs. Excuse me.
I just belched that's that, you know,
something that's not a, that's not a
formula for a happy, for a happy marriage.
Anyways, that is a Thursday
afternoon, just before Friday.
Monday morning podcasts.
I know what you want to, you want to
hear my predictions, don't ya? Um,
my prediction for Patriots Steelers. Ah,
I don't have a good feeling about it.
You know, I thought we looked
like shit against the Texans.
So I'm doing what every
Patriot fan is doing.
I'm hoping that that was
our one bad playoff game.
Like you can do that in the playoffs.
So yeah,
you can do it if there's no JJ watts
and a, you got a rookie quarterback,
you know, I guess she can get away
with a bad fucking game. But, uh,
I was not impressed with our
offensive line last week.
And the Pittsburgh Steelers always have
a fucking great defense. So, you know,
big Ben, the Steelers
at due to beat us, man,
they haven't beat us in a big
game in a long time. But, uh,
I'm going to go with my hat and I'm going
to say the patriots are going to eat
out.
They're going to eke out a victory
at home and a Gillette stadium.
Yeah.
You know, that's, that's what I'm
open. I'm hoping we go up early.
That's what I'm hoping.
I don't want to see us try to play catch
up against those guys. Uh, alright.
And then what else we got?
We got the Falcons and we get
the Green Bay packers and uh,
am I going to disrespect the falcons
two weeks in a row? You know,
so I don't even know where this game is.
I'm going to pick a,
you know, something. If the
Falcons win, this would be Matt.
Ryan's like fucking finally
getting the respect he deserves.
Yeah.
Then he got an Aaron fucking Rogers.
Okay.
Is it in Green Bay? I, if it's in Green
Bay, I got to go with the packers.
I Dunno, they beat Seattle, but what
the fuck? Seattle was hurt. You know,
if they're the fucking up by
whoever the fuck it was came in,
they're stepping on their quarterback's
foot. Gave him two points.
Let's see what we got here. This
is, this is how every gambler,
most gamblers makes their decisions
before they put their kids college tuition
down. This is right here is literally
the level of research that they'll do.
Where is that Gig? Is that in
Green Bay? It's in Georgia.
Ah,
okay.
This gets more interesting.
Wait a minute. Point spread.
Okay.
It's got a good spread.
What do you got here?
What do you got here at Green
Bay packers versus betting odds?
Just give me the fucking odds.
Falcons packers.
Why won't they do that? How can we, if
you say, what does this mean in German?
It just comes right up.
If he asked for the fucking,
okay.
They asked for the fucking odds.
I gotta Click on somebody's site.
That's so they get,
they get credit for uh,
for eyeballs and this
site, right. You know,
this is such, this is why I hate the
fucking Internet sometimes. You Know Ali?
Okay, right there, right there.
Green Bay packers at death.
That was minus five and a half.
Shut up.
I don't even know what I'm doing.
And you want me to hit pause?
I'm not going to torture you guys
with this. Hold on a sec. All right.
Since the falcons open as five
and a half point favorites,
the total was 59.5 59 and
a half earlier in the week.
That's the over under according
to the sports book. All right.
I don't know shit about
either one of these teams.
Okay.
Oh, I tell you. Got To take the package
with the points. If you're betting,
you know what I mean? You're gonna
get Aaron Rodgers fucking six points,
almost six points.
Um,
fuck. I don't know shit. I'm going to say,
yeah,
do I do it?
Do I take a chance on the new guy?
There's a new quarterback in
town and he's failing. Good.
That was the theme to Alice. If you
guys ever watched that fucking show,
uh yeah. Fuck. I gotta go
Green Bay. Green Bay goes in,
breaks that fucking hearts,
you know. That's what I say.
They're going to go in there and
somehow they're going to get it done.
That's what I fucking, you know what?
I'm going to go with the tried and true.
I'm going to go Aaron Rodgers and
the Green Bay packers. There you go.
You heard it hear first from a standup
comedian who hasn't watched a lot of
football the last couple of years. All
right, so take your hard earned cash.
You know, put it on Aaron Rodgers.
Get yourself fired. A half points,
said a that doesn't work out.
Uh, you know, that's what
you get full listening to.
A stand up comedian. Go fuck yourselves.
Have a great weekend. You constant.
I'll talk to
you on Monday.
Hey everybody, what's going on? It's
still, it is the Monday morning podcast.
I believe it's January, January
19th. Martin Luther King Day.
Happy Martin Luther
King Day. Everybody. Um,
yeah, Obama's getting in this
week. I don't know if you noticed,
spent a lot of parties.
I gotta be honest with you.
I couldn't watch any of it and I heard
some reports of what was going to be
going on and I just got
like those embarrassing, uh,
you know,
I just heard that they were taking white
artists and black artists and putting
them together and uh,
you know,
that old tired thing like this
is kind of a scary thing or are,
you know,
now if they were having a white artists
and a black artists get together and
then beat the shit out of a
banker, then I would be like, okay,
now we're a,
we're getting somewhere.
But if you just going to put
James Taylor with fucking I,
you know, and then they're going to do
a folk that then turns into a rap of,
uh,
knowing the Carolina in my mind,
whatever the fuck it is.
You know what's funny?
I just sang the melody with
the wrong words. No, in my
mind, I'm going to Carolina.
I still fucking roller blade.
Um, [inaudible] James Taylor's
really into rollerblading.
I bet you didn't know that. Well,
listen, if you're new to my page,
let me get right off. Let me just
get right off on the right foot here.
This is going to be a rough one. I'm,
let me get off to the, on the right foot.
You know what? It's early and I
have to work out and I was like,
I gotta get this fucking thing out of
the way that sounds approaching this
podcast this week. I have to get
this thing out of the fucking way.
And I don't know about you guys,
but whenever I approach something like
I have to get this out of the way,
something suffers and it's usually the
quality. Okay. So I want all of you guys,
wherever you're at, to just lower
your fucking expectations, okay?
Because I am on,
let's get this out of the way.
Mowed this week.
All right,
button going hardcore with my workout.
Just had 98 proteins doing
this new fucking diet, man.
It's just fucking ridiculous.
It's ridiculous. But it's
working. It's working.
But I know in the back of my head,
eventually you're going to
get to where you want bill,
and then you're got to go off the Diet
and then you gotta to fucking get,
you know, get a big Charlie Brown head
again. That's what's going to happen. Um,
but anyways,
the news page,
I'll do one of those diets where you
like weigh your food. Three nights,
it's a chicken dance answer. The primers
on cheese and ten eight egg whites,
which is a whole fucking Carden.
I swear to God. By the end of it,
you just want to Puke, but somehow
you lose weight. It's all like a,
it's like chemistry. Is that what it's
like bill? Is it really like chemistry?
Have you ever taken a chemistry
class? A why? No. No, I haven't.
Then how would you know? It's
like chemistry. You don't,
all right. That's what I'm doing.
Heckle in myself this week. Um, yeah.
You know something.
I'm already kind of a no bill.
Stick with what the fuck you wanted to.
Let's, let's have some sort of beginning,
middle and end to this
thing. All right. Okay.
Let's start with the basics.
If you new to my page,
I do one of these every single week.
I do it every single Monday.
People send me in questions and I
answered them to the best of my ability.
People send in their list of stuff that
they feel is underrated, overrated.
And lately much to my
pleasure is that the word?
I don't know.
Two full of protein.
I need some carbs to be able to pull
up the right fucking word here. Um,
I really enjoyed the fact that a lot of
people are weighing in on a lot of the
stuff that I'm talking about. Like, um,
and also introducing new
subjects because uh, you know,
I don't want to be doing the same shit.
You know,
it'd be doing this podcast 20
years from now and just being like,
oh,
battery power,
um,
underrated. Fucking, uh,
Gabe Kaplan's come back.
All right.
That was overrated.
Underrated in the year 2029 when
gay clamp with Kaplan will be 96.
Um, I saw him on the world series
of poker and wow, you know,
this had fucking aging thing where some
people try to prevent it and that's when
you get in trouble. You got to go with
it. You've got to use a Kido, you know,
you just, you just go with
it, you know, you know,
you know fucking Oh, by the way,
I also saw blazing saddles recently and
uh, two things I want to say is Gavi,
Johnson is the best fucking laugh.
I got in about three months,
absolutely dying, laughing.
And if anybody can explain to me why the
actor who played Gabby Johnson made the
choice to start swinging his arms,
it's,
it's fucking genius.
And Gene Wilder has the most horrific
powdered wig comb over I have ever seen in
my life. What was that
bowling movie that, uh,
Bill Murray was in and they had
those really bad comb overs.
He puts them to shame. What the fuck
was the name of that movie? Candle?
Big 10.
The fuck was that movie called Gardner
Ball had something to do with Boeing.
I don't know these people right now
screaming at that dashboards in the car,
like they know the right answer. Like
you're going to get a star or something.
The fuck was the name of that
movie. All right. Anyways, um,
yeah, so I do one of these, every single
week is such a fucking mess. And uh,
I also hype shit that I have coming up.
Like these are my three big dates
that I have coming up this week.
I am at the Improv in Houston and a
surprisingly I've been getting a lot of
emails because I didn't draw a shit
last time. I was their mom, frogger.
And um,
you can go to Improv too.
Dot Com for tickets or you can just
click on the link right on my, uh,
run on my homepage,
which I imagine probably still says
that I'm going to be a Tampa this week,
which isn't true.
I just haven't changed it.
Really need to get a fucking assistant
that's on my list of shit to do. Um,
and February 6th,
I'm going to be at the
Wilbur Theater in Boston,
Massachusetts.
And then on the seventh,
I'm going to be out in chickopee Chicopee,
Massachusetts.
Um,
and then a couple of weekends after that,
I am going to be making my
debut appearance in Ogden, Utah.
So all you Mormons,
you know,
fucking come on down to the Goddamn show.
Why don't you,
when you're 18 wives come down to
the show and sit there and judge me.
You know, I'll tell
you, you know something.
I don't know anything about Mormons
other than Steve Young as a Mormon.
That's the only thing I know about him.
And you guys have a lot of wives and uh,
for some reason, when I think
about you, I think about the Amish,
which I know isn't true. I
know it's not fair. I actually,
there's a college out there
a long time ago and uh,
it was really weird,
like all the kids out there,
how like for pepper press they were,
this is out in front of sell tickets
in Utah by basically attacking the main
religion out there. That's real smart
though. No, it was just really weird.
I felt like I was in the footloose, you
know, people weren't allowed to dance.
They weren't allowed to fuck.
Anyways, let's get on with this.
This podcast is starting to lose momentum.
I can feel it.
I'm like fucking Steve Austin and the
beginning of $6 million man, you know,
she's breaking up. She's
breaking up. I can't hold it.
Steve Austin astronaut,
a man barely alive.
We can put on a new foot.
All right. Um, here's something that
somebody said to me recently. Um,
and this whole thing is judged because
basically I drive a Prius, which,
you know, driving a Prius yet
people really fucking judge you.
Like I pulled up in front of this,
uh,
just try to get an extra key made
from my apartment and I get up,
go and get out of my car.
And I was like,
pull up as these two douche bags with
green, green peace sweatshirts on.
And they immediately eyeball me, you
know, and I'm like, Oh God, right.
And I get out of the car and the girl
goes, I swear to God, she's like,
hey, their Prius driver. So I go,
he there chick with a green
peace sweatshirt, you know,
really what the country tone
in my voice as if to say,
I don't care about whales. Do you
know, maybe I'm just a tight fuck.
Who doesn't want to pay for gas?
Do you ever think about that?
But that doesn't stop her. She just
keeps coming at me. He has time.
He has hands. I go, no, no I
don't. She's like, you know,
he takes a second and I walked around
the corner and I want you to this key
place to get my, you know, my
key done. And uh, you know,
God does the key in to second.
I come walking back out,
I mean literally within the first,
the same two minutes of this woman
talking to me and I clearly didn't want to
talk to her and she sees me again and
she's still coming at me and she said some
shit like, come on, you know it's
your Prius driver. Just sign up.
It's easy peasy. What? She
said it's easy fucking Pz,
which made me want to go buy a bus and
take the muffler off of it. You know,
it's easy peasy. Goes to come on
and you drive a Prius. I'm like,
how do you even know this is mine? You
don't even know what's mine. You know,
fucking Twat hid away from me.
I don't know why. You know,
I really, I like animals. You know,
I really like animals and I enjoy
doing things to the environment,
but I don't like fucking people thinking
they know shit about them even though
she did in a way she did.
But just because I drive a Prius,
it doesn't mean I'm going to talk to
you and your stupid sweatshirt and,
and you know, sign up on your clipboard.
I don't want to fucking do that,
you know,
because if I do at some point I got to
listen to you use words like easy peasy.
It's where I'm like this fucking type a
psycho environmentalist and I just don't
get along with those
Bergen stock. It is. Ah,
I'm just getting annoyed now. Just
fucking talking. Hey tree is driver.
The thing I really want to say,
I'm just not going to say it because
it's just going to be to me. All right,
let's get on with it. So
anyway, so I drive it for you.
So this guy sends me something
about global warming.
I don't know where he says bill.
It's a,
it's about 10 degrees in New York City
now. And since you drive a Toyota Prius,
I'm going to assume that you at
least believe somewhat in global,
global warming. And honestly with
you being a great cynical comic,
that shocks me. Okay. I like
how we just did that. How he,
uh, was patting me on the back
as he backhanded me in the face.
And honestly with you being
a great comic, wow, there's,
there goes my self esteem
that shocks me black.
Um, I hate when people fucking do that
when they give you a nice compliment.
So you know, thinking like lean,
you're going to come around it.
Their opinion like I'm some little
fucking dog and I just rolled over and now
you're going to give me a fucking
snack. All right. And honestly,
you being a great comic, that shocks
me. You have common sense enough, Jesus,
he's just throwing out
the compliments here.
It's almost like he wants
to change my opinion.
You have common sense enough to realize
things like self checkout lines being
the beginning phases of teaching us how
to do the job for free yet exclamation
point.
You don't spell any bullshit whatsoever
on listening to a guy like Al Gore
basically predicting some shit that he
claims is going to happen 50 years from
now.
Now you know what?
I love how at the beginning of this he
realized that he doesn't know my opinions
on global warming and he says,
I'm going to assume that you
at least somewhat belief.
And now two sentences later,
I totally fucking believe in
it until he can trash Al Gore.
Anyways, he says, my logic,
my logic just tells me that if anyone's
going to tell me that they know what the
world is going to be like a 2060, they're
full of shit. Nobody knows that shit.
Same as nobody knows what's going
to happen to you when you die. Um,
blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. On and on and on.
And he trashed this basically a my
really gonna read out loud this long.
Okay, let me just try to blow
through this. Some 27 now.
I vividly vividly recall plenty of people
20 years ago guaranteeing flying cars
by the year 2000. Really?
I don't remember that. Um,
20 years ago,
you're seven years old,
they will probably just fucking with you
once they still telling you that effect.
Fuck came down the chimney
and gave you the toys. Um,
I vividly remember that
when I was in the sandbox,
somebody saying that there
was going to be flying.
Did you go to a private school or all
your little friends running around in
sport coats?
Um,
and the closest thing we have to occur
that car instead of a close to we have
that car is instead of running on
gasoline, it runs on less gasoline and,
um, and a battery and is 85%
plastic. All right. First,
before we get into all of this shit,
one of my pet peeves about people who
argue against global warming is when it's
10 degrees out in January,
you know, January,
a winter month when it's supposed
to be fucking 10 degrees out,
you know, the big, you know, all of a
sudden it's, it's actually winter weather.
And then they're just like, well, I
just, that proves that. I mean it's,
it's fucking 10 degrees in January.
There you go.
So it was fucking 10 degrees in October,
you know, for a bunch of days in a
row for a bunch of years in a row.
And polar ice caps weren't fucking mouth.
The top of the world wasn't melting and
grizzly bears weren't mating with polar
bears,
you know,
then I would maybe believe your little
point about one day in January being
fucking 10 degrees or maybe a cold
spell and it's called the winner. Dude.
All right, you want to talk
about vividly remembering.
I remember vividly riding
on my bicycle back when,
uh,
when kids delivered papers before they
scared the shit out of us that everyone
was a fucking pedophile.
And before they printed billions of
dollars more with no gold behind it.
So now adults have to do that job.
They were fucking kid like me riding
around in that bicycle and it was so cold
out.
You fucking nostril stuck together and
they used to give you those ski masks and
your breadth would condensate or
whatever the fucking word was.
And then you had hocked
up against your nose.
I've definitely remember my brother
coming home, his hands were so cold.
He turned on hot water in the sink and
stuck them in there and they immediately
all cracked and became bloody.
And I laughed my ass off at Adam.
I vividly remember that. It's called
the fucking winter. All right,
so don't send me a fucking email about a
couple of days in January where it's 10
degrees out and you think
that that fucking disproves
would not look it. I don't,
I don't, I don't even how
to get in this fucking shit.
The reason why we don't have fucking
flying cars right now, I mean,
think about that. 6 billion people
all having cars that fly around.
How the fuck are you going to have roads?
You know what I mean?
And the reason why you have Prius's that
run half on gasoline and a little bit
on electricity is cause it. That's
all bullshit. It's a fucking scam.
All right? It's a better scan than
the car that they have out now,
but it's a fucking scam
because you're dealing with,
you're dealing with that robber baron
blue blood money that has been running
shit for 150 fucking years, and
they're not just going to go, oh,
they're the fucking cop of
the world's melting. Well,
let's do something about that.
They're going to incrementally
slide their way into something,
they're going to do the
least amount that's required.
A hybrid is a complete fucking scam
other than the emissions, you know,
the admissions are a lot better.
That's the big thing.
But as far as the gas mileage
and all that shit, it's bullshit.
You basically get 45 miles a gallon
if you're gliding down the street.
But that's true with all cars.
But the mere fact that corporations
are actually giving in now and um,
at the very least I love what they do
is they basically paint their packages
green and then psychologically like
there's a gas station, I think it's BP.
All of a sudden they went to like
green and yellow now and it's subtly,
I'm supposed to have to be thinking
about ethanol or some shit. Like wow,
grasses grade carness yellow gas is good,
it's stupid.
The whole is Jackie,
what you're dealing with dude is a ton of
politics in there. So to sit there and,
and look at it and you know, blast the
guy like Al Gore. Yeah. Al Gore, you know,
the guy, you know in defense of him
has always been into the environment.
One of his things when he was in office
was he tried to get the Supercar,
a car that got a hundred miles a gallon
and they just dragged their feet.
The big three dragged their feet and as a,
you know,
we're putting it together and
there's a finite amount of time.
Someone's in office,
he was in office for eight years.
They just dragged their feet for eight
years and he was out and then they
shelved it. That's all. That's all
that bullshit. But Al Gore, yeah,
he's using it to try to get
himself back in the ring. You know,
he's like a comedian, you know,
his show got canceled and now he's,
he's doing infomercials.
He's got to get his face out there so
we can still make speeches and make some
money so we can pay the fucking
bankers. But Dude, you know,
you really should do a little more
research into a global warming other than
it's 10 degrees out in January.
That's all I'm going to say.
And to sit there, and obviously I'm
by no means a fucking scientist,
but you know,
I do know that you can't have 6 billion
of any species on this planet,
especially human beings who,
unlike animals, we're the
only ones, as my brother says,
we're the only species on the planet
that alters the environment rather than
adapting to it.
You know what I mean?
You could have 6 billion deer and
that would fuck up a lot of shit,
but not to the level that we're fucking
it up because they don't make, you know,
nuclear weapons and deal with the
waste and plastic and all that shit.
So I dunno dude. I mean, if I, I mean,
I don't know what to tell you,
dude.
I'm not here to try to convince
you that global warming,
that 6 billion people on the planet
are going to have an effect on it.
You know, we're like the Gypsy
moth caterpillar for right now,
just eating everything in
her fucking path and uh,
none of this shit that
they're doing hybrids,
any of that shit is going to fucking
help anything until they literally get on
TV. And they start telling people
to stop having children. Um,
well that's uplifting bill.
I mean,
I don't understand what
people are fucking doing.
Have you seen that IBM car shul or all of
a sudden, you know, they're acting like,
you know, they're talking
about how in uh, oh,
this is Joe to Rosa just called me
and I missed the fucking call. Um,
this IBM commercial,
they sitting there talking about how
like in Sweden or something that, uh,
they installed a automated toll booths
and that decreased gridlock by 20%.
And then in the end, this
girl's like, I'm an IBM or,
and that's what I'm working
on. It's like, really? Well,
why don't you work on a digital poster
that tells people to stop fucking busted
nuts in their girlfriends? I think
that that would help gridlock by, uh,
a hundred percent kept clashing.
Not 100%, but you know what I mean?
Some point I can't wait.
I hope I live long enough to see that.
I really want to see that argument
where they somehow finesse in,
you have to stop having
kids because there's,
there's no, there's no farmland. There's
nothing left, you know what I'm saying?
And then just all the Jesus freaks
going while the bottle said,
go for food is multiply.
Lord said it.
He said it really, it wasn't a
bunch of people just writing it. No,
he said it.
He said it.
And then he had a kid and a kid was in
some woman who was never impregnated and
he walked on water to cure a leper and
he does a lot of Jews even though he was
one. Oh my God. Hopefully
you know something.
I really am as cynical bastard tried.
Definitely.
I still believe in a higher power though.
But like I gotta admit I'm
lost because I don't know what,
I can't go to any of these, uh, you know,
from the Catholic Church to Scientology.
I just can't, you know, I can't fucking,
I dunno.
Do you have a look at a picture yourself
from five years ago when you just think,
you know,
I was so much better a person then how
do I get back to being that person?
That's where I am in my life right
now. You know, I'm trying to do,
trying to do some better. I don't know
what the fuck I'm talking about this week.
All right, let's, let's, let's, let's move
on here before I do my, I tell you guys,
I'm doing that teen 90 x system for
fucking 40 year old douche bags like me.
It's actually great.
It's a great system and I'm just killing
time right now as I tried to get to the
next point. Okay, here we go.
Uh, how to link to my podcast.
This is something else I should
have done upfront. Um, you log in,
you log into Google with an
account. Yes, I am reading this.
Um,
go to google.com/reader/view click on add
as added at a subscription on the left
hand side of the page. Oh my God.
And then paste this in the box.
I can't read that. That's
like too much. All right.
Evidently I can't tell you how
to link to my podcast. All right,
let's move on to the next fucking issue.
I really loving how this is becoming
like the morons meet the press,
my podcasts,
we're discussing issues like that last
guy who I just screamed that he basically
has no more information on
global warming than I do.
He just has his gut opinion
that says it's bullshit.
And I watched the discovery channel
and I saw a brown and white bear,
this grizzly polar bear that they called
the piddly there because they're now
meeting and fucking, and how do I know
it exists? Because some redneck shot,
that's what happens.
I don't know what the fuck it was all
shot in the face and now I'm standing next
to it. And then I went and
I found a scientist. Do you
know what the fuck this is?
Whatever it is, I killed. All right.
The checkout line argument is still
continuing. All right? Some people, uh,
I don't know if you're new to my podcast,
I'm in front of bloat from my explanation.
Um,
and a lot of people love had been arguing
with me that the automated checkouts,
um, where they make the customer
work as a cashier for free.
There's somehow telling me that this is
progress and they are equating it with
great inventions of the past.
I kinda got into it with some
guy on the Internet where he was,
I can't find the email
because I'm disorganized. He
brought up some sort of um,
some sort of machine like a hundred or
so 150 years ago that came out and the
textile mills that would obviously
do the work of like 10 20 people.
So this one guy started revolt going,
this is all going to put us out of work.
And Him and his friends came in and they
attack the machines and all that type
of shit and he tried to equate
that with the cashier thing.
And I'm not saying that I am against
inventions straight across the board just
because they put people out of work.
Like to me that's not the same example
because it's not like they came out with
a new cashier machine that does the
work of 10 cashiers while I just fucking
stand there.
They just came up with a
new cashier machine that now
I have to operate and then
I have to bag my own groceries.
That's not progress.
That's making me do the fucking job.
And actually to his credit, he goes,
you know what?
Fair enough.
You are right on that because I'm not
against them coming up with a machine that
does the work at 10 textile mill workers.
I'm really not against that.
And uh, because at no point does it then
require me to go down to the factory in,
so my own fucking shirt, that
is my point. But despite that,
people still have opinions that they
like them. Here we go. Here's one. Um,
what a fuck is it? God dammit, I can't
find it. It was a great one. Hold on,
hold on, hold on, hold on.
Just keep yourselves
busy. Um, all right. You,
you actually just fell into underrated.
That's why I couldn't find it. Um,
somebody will,
you know what's underrated?
Those self service tills
at the grocery store,
I'm going to assume you
don't understand what it is,
what it's like to not want to talk to
someone about the effectiveness of the
Maxi pad you're buying or if some hair
conditioner really works, et Cetera.
There is always a fucking conversation
and it's always fucking annoying.
I feel bad that maybe someone might be
out of a job because I don't like making
a name conversation
with other human beings.
But Sundays being able to get in and
out without speaking to anyone is all I
really want. Uh, you know,
I have mixed emotions on that one cause
I understand not wanting to get into an
annoying conversation like that fucking
Douche bag with their green peace
sweatshirt,
you know,
pay Prius driver. I
understand that. But um,
I would rather have an an a personally,
I'd rather have an annoying conversation
then know that I helped to put another
foot on the yacht of some corporate
fucking Douche bag because I just put
another person out of,
out of work who's probably already
eating macaroni and cheese nine times a
fucking week anyways.
Um, all right. What else?
Some other people, like some
people agree, some people don't.
I think we've beaten this thing to death,
you know,
I don't know what to tell
you guys. I just fuck it.
I'll just get you, keep having kids. Keep,
keep going with the computers, you know,
line up for the microchip in your head.
It's all going to be good. It's all great.
It's all fucking great. Everything's
great, everything's wonderful.
Global warming doesn't exist.
It's all awesome.
Go see that new movie that that fucking
crooked nose guy is in with Jennifer
Aniston about the dogs.
You know,
take your fucking kids there who are
going to add to the mess. You know,
an SUV when they turned 16 Jesus Christ,
I am on my soapbox is fucking week.
I really need to shut the fuck up. Let's
move on to the questions. All right.
Whenever I get this
way, by the way, people,
I'm really not this
passionate about the subjects.
That means I have other shit going on in
my life that's causing me stress and I
have an inability to focus on the
thing that's causing me stress.
So I rant about other stuff and annoyed
the shit out of people. All right.
Question number one. Hey, I
think you'll like this one.
That's how somebody just started it out
and then for some reason I didn't erase
that part. Um, there's a forward,
oh, this is more of a story.
And then I guess a question.
All right.
This is a four way intersection that
I drive through on my way to work.
A lot of people keep getting
into car accidents there.
Well for about a month I could tell they
were installing a traffic lights, um,
because they had tons of poles and wires
and construction workers where they are
all the time.
Or when they finish installing the new
traffic lights with the Green Arrows
alliance, allowing people to
turn and not get into accidents.
They also installed cameras
looking in every direction.
Am I crazy to be really bugged by that?
I live in a small area about 30,000
people and they definitely could've told
local residents with a letter that they'd
be putting in cameras or something.
If they can't afford a cop
to watch the intersection,
then they shouldn't have cameras there.
Right. People will slow down for a comp,
but nobody cares about a camera. It's
not like they, it's not like that.
We'll stop bad driving. It
doesn't, it doesn't even end there.
They put even more cameras towards the
downtown area, so when I drive into work,
I could be photographed or tape
twice in a span of seven miles.
Would this bug you too? Would you do
anything about it too? Awesome questions?
Yes, that would bug me.
Would I do anything about it?
I probably do what I do on this podcast.
I'd sit in the bed and bitch about
it and not join a group that would
effectively try to make a change because
they judge me because I drive a Prius.
Yeah, it does bug me. It does
bug me. I think it's bullshit.
I bugged me on two levels.
It's a way for them to just,
I guess,
nail every single person who sorta sorta
ran a red light and just give everybody
a ticket so they can have even more money,
you know,
to, to just fucking give away to some
Douche bag that they're going to pay eight
bucks for a ham for. You know what I mean?
I really can't explain anything today.
What is wrong with me?
You know what I'm saying?
If I that's like some boss hog shit
that's like putting down the fake fire
hydrant. Um, yeah.
I really find it disturbing that in the
future I'm going to have absolutely no
privacy. I mean, it's not like they're
going to watch every second of footage,
but just to know that at no point am I,
you know,
can I just like being my alone,
that's what freaks me out about the
future and going to let shit I was talking
about last week while I was on,
you know,
watching 60 minutes and they're in the
beginning stages of having computers have
the ability to read someone's mind.
I mean,
think about that shit.
They're already putting microchips in,
people at the upper corporate level.
They'll love computers to be able to read
your mind and there'll be able to film
you every way you go. You know, it's like,
that's to me is a,
that's like all those science
fiction fucking movies. Um,
I dunno what I do anything about it. I, I,
you know, the movie version of me would,
and I would turn into a Ellen, uh, Erin
Brockovich or whatever fucking name is,
but uh, yeah. You know what would make
me feel good? I'm one of those people,
I don't start shit. I, I, I don't
do anything. I don't join two.
I joined shit too. I don't know. If it was
a movement, I would definitely join it.
I just hate how protesting has been.
It's turned into like a cliche thing.
Like if I actually went to a protest
and I had a sign and I was chanting
something that rhymes with four, you know,
it always has to rhyme with four, one,
two, three, four wheel
Duggan more. No, no,
no, no, no, no. Not a whore. Right.
It always has to rhyme with four.
Why is it, you know why that is is
because musically, all our, all our,
all our music is in four,
four time.
That's like common time and we
just kind of go with that rhythm
like in the Far East like
they play in like I dunno
like that Vinnie Kali Uta time,
like fucking 17 eight or whatever the
fuck it is and they can all sit there and
bounce and they have the patience to
wait for the person to count up to 17 and
with their crazy language they have words
that Ryan was 1717 you're fucking in
the hummus team or
whatever the fuck the fuck.
I don't know. Question number
two. Here we go. Hey Bill.
Was there ever a crossover period in your
career where you were still working a
day job but getting
successful as a comedian?
Did anyone ever recognize you at your
day job sparking a Mickey Rourke temper
Tantrum at which deli displays
if anybody, if any, did you body
slam? Dude, what the fuck happened?
The rest of that sentence.
Did anyone ever recognize you at work?
Sparking and Mickey Work?
Temper tantrum.
And then this is the rest of his sentence.
At which Deli displays,
if any, did you body
slowed? Okay. Oh I know of.
There was no comma in there.
It should have been at,
at which deli displays comma if any.
I Dunno.
I Dunno what they should be a comma in
there cause I can't figure out what the
fuck that means. That I have a
body slam someone at a deli. Um,
does anyone ever recognize
me at my day job? Uh,
no.
I,
I want to say maybe once
and I was thrilled because
I never got recognized and I
felt like somebody,
you know,
which I think is very poignant
on Martin Luther King Day.
I am somebody I did five minutes
at the comedy Ville comedy vault.
I used to go up and Dick Doherty's,
comedy volt and Remington.
And uh, it's actually one of the things
I like to do when I go back to Boston.
I'm not working, I go back to that
club cause it's still fucking exist.
So I put my first five minutes
together on Boylston street. Um,
yeah. So no, no one ever recognized
me. You basically, you have to be,
um,
you have to be on TV for a long
time to start getting recognized.
Um, you know, it's weird, like
you'd think if you did stand up on like
a Conan O'brien the next day you walked
down the street,
if millions of people watching a bunch of
people would recognize you, they don't,
uh,
they don't.
So you have to be,
you gotta be super famous and then,
or at least famous,
and then you have to fall off and then
have to get a day job and then they
recognize you.
It's weird.
People recognize you on
the back backside of fame,
you know. And speaking of which, you know,
being 40 years of age,
um,
I did what you're the responsible
person supposed to do.
You know,
the May I fucking,
when I actually got my God damn prostate
checked and uh, got to tell you, dude,
do you want to talk about the,
that's the other side of fame
that people don't bring up.
I was really happy that I have a low
level because when people look at same and
they just think like, you know, court
side seats to fucking the Lakers,
you fucking a supermodel,
they don't think that you still
have to get your prostate checked
and you don't have the ability to walk
into the office as an an anonymous,
an anonymous person, you know, thank
God this guy wasn't a comedy fan. So
my prostate is fine by the way.
You know,
psychologically I don't know how I
am after that. It was just fucking,
it's horrific.
And I gotta tell you something when
they tell you there's nothing wrong with
your prostate, you really have
mixed emotions at that point.
Cause you site that you're not
going to die of ass cancer.
But on the other side does immediately
a jolt of anger where you like. So it's,
so that means you really didn't
fucking have to do that then did you?
I don't know.
I just came to peace with the fact
that his job is just fucking horrific.
Said for me. It's just a
fucking horrible eight seconds.
And then I can just,
you know,
turn on the radio at full volume and
drive away and try to kill the thoughts of
horror.
Where is he has to then just because
he has to just do that all day long.
Uh,
you know something.
I think the fact that I just
talked about this on my podcast,
I'm now emotionally fucking dealing
with the fact that another man put his
finger on my ass and he's just fucking,
you know,
and it's done very professionally.
It's not like he's whispering in your ear
like, you know, like this, it's not that,
oh my God,
I got to go to therapy.
I still fucking horrible.
I let another man do that.
And there was nothing wrong with me.
You know,
Jesus Christ,
Jesus Christ.
I think this is the end of the podcast.
I really,
I really don't know how to process that.
And you know, you know,
it's funny, as you know,
in five years they're going to have a
way to do it where they don't have to do
that. You know what I mean? Like,
I just did the ass version of
electroshock fucking treatment.
That is what they should do. They should
put like a fucking Arrow in your mouth.
You know, I don't think I'm going to
be able to stop talking about this.
It's just fucking horrific.
Fucking horrific.
Um, okay, let's grit the teeth and
let's move on to question number three.
Who, wow. Wow.
All right. Yeah. What the fuck? All right.
What if that's all a scam?
Forget about global warming.
Oh my God. Question number three.
Come on bill. You can do it.
You can do it.
Hey Bill,
do you ever think of how ironic it is
that Hitler didn't have blonde hair and
blue eyes?
Um,
no. No I didn't. I've heard that argument.
I find it more weird that he was just
a complete fucking spats and people
followed him. I mean, he had
the classic spazz haircut,
you know, that's shorts stuff on
the side and it's all long on top.
I mean that, I mean, if there's
any kids listening to this shit,
it's like if you really want to just
up the chances of you getting fucking
slapped in the back of the head,
buzz the back of the size of the ahead
and then leave it long on top and mean
it's classic in naked head
is just sitting there,
which is just going to make a football
player want to slap you with those three
fingers right in the back of your head
so he can watch your colic flap around on
your forehead. Um, again, you know,
I've heard that before.
I've heard people talk about how
Kettler didn't even fit into his, uh,
his, um, his view of,
of, of the perfect race.
I think it was like a self hate.
He was like a chick who was born or
Brunette and always wanted to be a blonde.
You know,
he just sort of bought into what he was
like a self hating Brunette that somehow
convinced people to kill
like 10 million people. Um,
you know,
and I like to say that we've moved beyond
that and in our society and you know,
judging by people's reactions to fucking
microchips and being filmed every five
seconds and being like, well, you know,
if you're not doing anything wrong,
I really think that there's another
Hitler and our future. Um, all right,
bill number five. Hey
Bill, what's the, uh,
worst slash most embarrassing
thing you've ever done to get laid?
For me it was watching ballet.
Um,
all right, let's see here.
The worst thing I ever did,
I'll tell you the last most lost I've
ever gotten in a relationship was I dated
a girl who sang in a
band and I was about 20,
21 years old and she was like 30,
31.
And uh, she's saying in this
band that was called, uh,
I don't know what it was called.
Fuck was the name of the band.
God, I'm so old now. What's a, what's a,
what's a male? It was something
in the girls was a guy's name,
like Mike and Mike and the girls.
And it was basically,
they did like cover songs and
there was three, three hotties,
you know, like the Andrews sisters
and they would sing fucking, you know,
awful Bryan Adams songs and
CNC music factory. Shit.
This is how long ago it was. And then
the dude would be playing the keyboard.
And I sat in the audience with a
Michael and the girls sweatshirt
that was written in three
different levels of pastel.
You understand?
Like it was like the Miami Vice Aqua blue,
the hot pink and some
other awful pastel color.
You know what it look like?
It looked like Demi Moore eye shadow
and that famous eighties picture of her
where she has her hair all crimped,
whatever the fuck that was.
You know what girls used to do that and
their hair used to look like a staircase
descending down to the
[inaudible]. Um, yeah.
And I sat in the audience and I
remember sitting outside myself going,
how the fuck do I get out of this?
How do I get out of this? This is not,
uh, I was just psyched to be getting late.
You know, I was definitely a late bloomer
and I was banging on this hot broad,
who's like 10 years old.
I mean it's sang in a band and you know,
that was all my Dick just going
like, yeah, keep blowing me,
I'll load a sweatshirt.
And then I was actually in public
by myself sitting in the crowd.
And uh, that's one of those
things where it was almost like,
you know when you were in first grade
and your mother gives, your mother,
gives you the shirt your grandmother
bought you and you're kind of thinking you
back of the head.
You kind of haven't thoughts like,
does this shirt like fucking gay? Is
it, I don't know. You just, you know,
and then you watch a cartoon and then
you go to school and then all this,
the second you get on the bus, it's
just like everyone just starts, dude,
what's with your shirt at? Then it
starts and then you like, oh my God,
this is going to be the longest fucking
day of my life. And everybody just,
I mean,
you lose like half your friends that day
and you contemplate kissing your pants
so you can just fucking get out of school
or are claiming you have chicken pox
or anything just to get the fuck out of
it. That was the adult version of that.
And uh,
I remember I walked out of the
place where they had the Gig and I,
and I went into a bar.
I was trying to reclaim my manhood,
but I still had that
fucking sweatshirt on.
I think I took it off and I turned it
inside out and I just drank at this bar
for the rest of their show. And
then I walked back, hammered and I,
I think I turned it back in. And you
know, I hate that part of my life.
I really do. I don't even want to
bring it up on, I resent that question.
What a fucking Douche.
Like now I just, I dunno,
it's all part of the learning process.
People.
This is a really fucking
becoming a dark podcast.
I'm just admitting to horrible things
that have happened to me. All right.
Um,
index,
anal rape and an awful fucking sweatshirt.
All right,
question number six, Bill. Hey, what's
the worst slash most embarrassing thing?
Oh, I've already read that one. I'm
so fucked up right now. Emotionally.
I just reread that question. Wait
a second. Oh, I have it down twice.
So that wasn't me.
All right,
let's move on to underrated,
underrated, overrated. This is really,
I like the awkward pauses at this
point is I'm trying to fucking
mentally deal with what the
fuck happened to me last week.
I really didn't emotionally
even deal with that
big deal. It's a medical
procedure. You did the smart thing.
I know I did the smart thing, but did
it, I have to go through that process.
All right, Bill. Um, my friend and I have
a couple of ideas for you. Uh, all right.
Overrated.
Crown Royal Crown Royal is overrated.
Okay. I can't agree with you on
that one. I think it's fun tickets,
tremendous underrated.
Woodford reserve.
Basil Hayden, four roses, single barrel.
These obviously whiskeys were from
Kentucky and a little biased. Oh,
well fuck it. All right. Now
I have to try those. You know,
there's a bar in downtown la called
the seven grand. It's a whiskey bar.
They have all kinds of, uh, I'm
going to try that four roses,
single barrel and actually
sounds good. Um, overrated.
All the damn spitting in pornos.
What the fuck?
Spitting and a-holes
spitting in Vijay Ga's,
spitting on the pain.
I,
when did hawking a Lougie becomes
sexy. Yeah, that is pretty disgusting.
I've actually sworn myself off of porno.
Um,
I was a big fan of, uh, this one website,
which I'm not going to name just because
I feel like a crack dealer because it's
a free porno site and I don't want to
put the name of it out there and get
somebody else hooked.
And, uh, I just, you know,
I just decided I wasn't going to go on
there anymore because I was finding shit
that used to turn me on. I
found it to be boring, you know,
and then you start progressively
moving towards sicker and sicker,
crazier shit. And I'm just
like, I can't fucking do that.
So I know I've mentioned on
a number of times that, uh,
I've been trying to fucking
stop doing that. You know,
you know something, I, I really,
I really think that that shifts,
it's just not good.
It's just not good for you.
You ever think about how fucked
up that is? That you can just,
you know,
think of something that you want to see
and you can go on the Internet and you
can just find it. And how, back
in the day when you were a,
you know, little house
on the prairie, I mean,
all he ain't just had was your
imagination. I'm not saying he,
people didn't lay in the fields,
lay down in the barley and take down their
trousers and a a but, whoa, whoa. What,
what could you possibly
could people even comprehend?
You know, some of the shit that people
have come up with at this point,
I don't think you could.
There's no way that you could think of
some of the shit that they have on there.
If like musically you're just that
Jimmy cracked corn and I don't care.
Actually, that's not true.
They had Beethoven, they had
classical music, but still,
you know, I dunno. Like I said,
I just looked at a picture of myself like
from four or five years ago and I was
just like, you know, I was a
lot better person back then.
So, uh, you know, this
is actually been a very,
a very sad melancholy fucking podcast
and uh, yeah, that's it. I'm
going to end on that. No,
because I have to emotionally
deal with the fact that a, yeah,
I got to deal with that shift
at whatever's in medical
as a medical procedure.
It doesn't count, right. Fuck.
Anyways, so I'm going to hit the
Improv in Houston this weekend.
I want to be extra funny because
I want to be burying that, uh,
that procedure deep in my psyche.
And I probably won't be talking about
it on stage just because every comedian
over 40 who's had that procedure then
goes on stage and talks about it.
It's all stared in there.
Uh, I got the bug in Pega on,
in my ass is hanging out.
You know who, who goes to school
to become that guy, if any.
That there's your homework for the week.
If anybody can come up with a
new standup comedy angle on,
I had to get my prostate checked.
Um,
I'll give you a free DVD.
I will literally fucking mail it to
your fucking house and I'm not joking.
All right. If you can somehow
come up with a new angle,
that's actually a no, you don't, I'm
not going to put any parameters on it.
They can go clean. You can
go dirty, you can go clever.
You can even be a guitar act if
you want to write a song about it.
I don't give a fuck if you can somehow
come up with something. You know,
you got a couple of days to this offer
expires Thursday afternoon because by
then I'm going to be on my
way over to the club in, uh,
in Houston, Texas. Oh, speaking of
which, you know what, I fucking, uh,
you, one of the things I like going about
to Houston as they got a mall out there
that actually has a skating rink in the
mall and it's the funniest thing ever.
You can actually go ice skating right
near the food court as you watch. In fact,
Fox eating orange chicken
and you're burning calories.
And a actually when
skating out here recently,
I just hate going to the gym people.
That's basically it sound like
I can burn calories doing that.
So I go out to Burbank,
it's like 80 fucking degrees out and
I go onto a skating rink out there.
It's the worst fucking ice
I've ever on it in my life.
It's like the cracks in the ice.
I mean it's, it's unbelievable.
It's like Tiger Marcel Dion skated on
this fucking ice back when the kings wore
the colors of royalty.
And um,
I get over there and there's literally
like 15 other people out there and uh,
I have a question for, uh, people who are
Asian, not Indian people who are like,
you know, Chinese, Japanese,
Korean or whatever. Like,
I'm really interested
in your culture that,
you know, it seems to
me that like, I dunno,
I just never see you guys get
angry. You know, I'm sitting there,
there was like five Asian dudes and
they suck to get skating and they,
and they just kept falling
down like really hard.
Like they be getting going fast and they
would fucking roof really hit the ice
hard.
And every time they would get up smiling
with like this self deprecating when I
go, I was still bad. Look on
their face and my, you know,
and everybody else in that group or
just sort of laugh and I just was
fascinated.
I mean it's like I never saw maybe like
an American version of an Asian person.
You'll see, you'll see one of them go like
fuck if they'd like stubbed their toe.
But these like dudes are like whacking
the heads and shit and they just kept
smiling. And I'm not gonna lie to
you. I was laughing my ass off.
But then after a while it just became
bizarre. And then I felt bad about myself.
Like,
what's wrong with me as a human being
that I can't laugh off the little things
in life, but you know to me
once you fall for the 15th time,
that's not a little thing anymore.
That's like a major God damn problem.
Then you should,
you know mine's be that Stephen
King Book were there was,
there was the music guy
and those I got dammit,
I didn't close my fucking refrigerator.
I hate when I do that.
It's refrigerated.
Such a piece of fucking shit.
Don't you know your frigerator
you supposed to have to
hold the door open and if
you don't hold the door open,
it's supposed to do this. Listen,
it's supposed to close but not mine.
Mine just stays open.
Cut the shit and to global
warming right there.
I want to go to the fucking energy.
I just wasted anyways. What the hell.
I was talking about Asian people fallen
on the ice and not in a, not, not caring.
I don't know.
It's just been a really weird podcast and
I don't even know how I feel about it,
but um, anyways, that's it. I'm done.
I have to go work out. All right. You
guys were a very patient with this one.
Please keep the, uh, the questions
and everything like that coming in.
Please let me get the momentum going here.
Please come out and see me
at the Improv and Houston,
please come out to that show.
Please.
I'm begging people because
every time I go there, you know,
didn't like nobody shows up.
And I know I said that about
Tampa and people showed up.
I don't know if cause I
have a new special out,
things are finally going to change, but,
uh, please, for the love of God, show up.
Bring 15 fucking people,
you know, just, you know,
I wrote a new hour. I'm literally begging
you. Okay. Just for the love of God,
I had a really rough week. I did violated.
Okay. I've seen confusing things.
I've seen a group of people fall on
the ice and not get mad about it.
And I left my refrigerator door open.
Okay. And that's it. All right, that it
come see me in Boston and in
Utah and that's it. Right?
See Martin Luther King Day.
Everybody
[inaudible]
yeah.
Uh.