Yeah.
Hey, what's going on is bill burrs
time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Ah,
just checking in on you.
I'm checking in on you about
Du du Du du check in on you.
Okay.
Far called mad has said,
Ooh
cares if your nose is fucking Ryan.
Get some fucking clean x
and have some fun and sorry.
I am so sick of being sick.
Just when the fuck is this going to end.
I woke up Bodu Luda I had a fucking
coffin fit at like four in the morning and
uh, you know, I was upstairs up and
vanished upstairs. You know what I mean?
Like back in the day when people had like
tuberculosis after the slum Lord stuck
them in some damp, dark fucking
apartment for years and years and years.
And these poor fucking tenants would die
a lonely death and then they'd build a
statute statute to the fucking slum
lord or name a subway stop after him.
You know, what was that one
on? Off The six, the fuck,
I can't remember the name of the Stop
I used to get off at all the time.
And walk over to the fucking store.
I remember everything I saw in New
York. I just, anybody at his statue,
I just started looking
them up on the Internet.
But it was all this shit that they did.
But if you went to about
page three f four, it was the
other stuff that they did.
Oh yeah.
Um,
people,
if I live long enough,
I'm going to do a show this weekend at
the Fox theater in Atlanta, Georgia.
And then you know what I'm going to do
then following day, you know what I mean?
Go on to do what?
I'm getting in a fucking rental car and
I'm driving over the fucking Talladega
and I'm going to go watch a bunch of
fucking rednecks watching their dream cars
going around the track.
One more time.
Okay,
one more fucking top. Hey, stock
car racing going to change.
Now that Ford is fucking phasing out all
of their sedans. Did you guys see that?
They're not making any cars anymore.
They're going to still have the Mustang,
you know, cause what would a fucking
tourists rent when they come to la?
You got to get the Red Mustang convertible
and put the fucking top down and
drive around like a Dosha, right?
Oh, do you know you want to hear,
you want to hear some self-involved Shit.
They're always talking about the
millennials. You know what I mean?
You ask a millennial, what's the top
fucking social issue out there today?
And they'd say, lack of cell
service, you know, in a tunnel. No,
actually they said climate change and
they're determined to tackle the issue.
That's what I just read today.
Millennials think that climate change
is the number one social issue courses.
And they are 100% right. God bless them
and they're determined to tackle it.
You know, wait till they get a
little bit of debt under their belts.
Wait to those banker cuts can scare
them out of their fucking, you know,
get a run on the wheel. You
know, wait til they get married.
Yeah. I went to that APP. And so
you start getting fucking Nag,
then your priority becomes pay enough
my fucking house and fucking redoing the
garage. So I got a place
for myself. But until then,
until that right, you saved the
polar bear. So I hope you do it.
I hope you stick to hope.
You keep it real man.
Like whenever you see an old hippie
still rocking the long fucking, you know,
hair,
even if he went bald,
still has it all gathered
in the back, you know? Um,
anyways, what the fuck was I going?
I was, God dammit. Bill Kia Tangent.
So something I was going
to talk about there.
What I brown was talking about
cold medicine being sick.
Okay.
Led me to the cars.
Tattle dagger. Ah, fuck.
If I know,
I don't fucking know.
All I know is that I've been sick too
fucking long and I've had this fucking
thing started Wednesday of last week.
These are these new super colts
because everybody takes antibiotics and
everything, right? And rather
than killing the virus,
all you do is slap it around a
little pit and it toughens up.
You know what I mean? It's
like, oh, that, you know,
it starts to know your tendencies.
He leads with the left.
Fucking Jeb always follows
it with an overhand right.
He doesn't like when you crowd them in
the ring. Oh Shit. Somebody is calling me.
Oh, it's my mother, a mom.
I've told my podcasts, let
me call you right back. Yeah.
Uh, anyways. Um,
fuck. I don't even want I'm talking
about anymore. Oh yes or no.
And so I woke up at like
four in the morning,
just fucking hacking or
hacking away. And um, you know,
upstairs in the guest room,
that's where I've been, you know,
sent my wife has also sick,
you know,
but she gets to stay in the big bet.
Do you see how that works? You know,
with the Nice fucking master
bathroom right next door,
she has a fucking humidifier going.
She's got her fucking clean x with the,
uh, you know, you won't get as sore noise.
Knows fucking missed autumn.
I'm up in the fucking guest
room, you know, throw my drawer,
my old drum DVDs and shit, blowing
my nose with towels, toilet paper.
That's how it works, you know,
and you, what do you see?
All you see is women just
constantly complaining about
the way the way men treat
women and their position in society.
Right. So this is a society, right?
What about me? What about
my existence? You know,
where's my ribbon?
Where's my Hashtag?
Yeah.
How come I can't get somebody fired?
You know,
I'd actually been winning arguments lately
with my wife. It's been good. You know,
it's cost her to kind of like,
you know,
do a couple things around the house
that I've been asking her to do it,
but I know it's going to go back the
other way. The same way. Like she goes,
so you got to watch your temper and then
for a few days I'd walk around smiling
like a lunatic before I go back to who
I am. But you know, I accept it for her.
She is all right.
That's what you have to do after awhile.
Yeah. Are you ladies out there you think
you gonna Change your man? You're not,
you're not going to change them. The best
you can hope to do is break his spirit.
Yeah.
Okay.
In fact, if that's what gets you off.
What about all of that shit? Yeah.
How about a ribbon for all
the broken men out there?
I don't know why I'm talking about
all of this shit. It's just fucking,
it always makes me laugh. Um, anyways,
how bout those bro is here we go
bro and say we'd, we go bump. Bump.
Wow.
Did I think we were going to lose that
game seven now when we started our fourth
fucking line and immediately gave
up a goddamn goal, I was like, wow,
that reminds me of certain,
somebody not starting to game
crying before the Superbowl.
The fuck are we doing right? Then
we tie it up, then we go ahead.
All right.
It was two to one and we scored my right
before the first fucking period ended
or something that was like, oh boy,
it's three to to look at that.
That's what I was, it was one,
nothing them then one,
one us and then they immediately fucking
scored like they always did and then we
fucking, and we went up three to two and
I'm like, okay, maybe, maybe you know,
whatever. And then they score of two
fucking goals throughout five to three.
This is one thing I've noticed about
the Bruins. We don't hit anybody.
Finally started hitting somebody in
the third period. But Jesus Christ,
when the other team is faster than yeah,
you supposed to add them
to try to slow him down,
given away too much fucking
space. I thought, you know,
I thought Anderson looks shaky in
the first period. So I was like,
let's pepper him with some
shots there in the second.
And we barely got a shot on him.
It felt so.
I thought that allowed them to settle
down what Jesus Christ was Iraq.
Yeah,
I'll tell you, you hate to
see it. You hate to see it
with a fellow fellow ginger.
You know, fuck it as a
game like that, you know,
I guess toward Kruger was a little
bit screened, but uh, he left.
He let up a fucking softy. That next
one was f goal number five was a softy.
And also one of the first
three wasn't a good one either.
Okay.
Not to put it all on him. Uh, but anyways,
my condolences to fucking Toronto
may police saying, Jesus Christ,
you know,
and you got to it up to the ones that
still have the heart to fucking go down
the maple leaf square,
whatever the fuck they call it,
and stand there knowing that their joy
is eventually going to turn to anger
and then they're just going to be part
of a fucking reaction video. A bad one.
Okay.
But you have to go right as a leaf San,
you gotta go,
cause one of these times
you're going to fucking win.
I liked what that one guy in the leaf
said. He said, obviously it sucks,
but I think in the future we're going
to be a team to be reckoned with.
I always love that expression
team to be reckoned with.
They think they're going to be mmm.
You know,
full of freckles settles
down a little bit.
They get a little more playoff experience.
I'll tell you what the Bruins need.
They need a physical presence
in front of the each day.
You know, we still haven't made up
for fucking loot Cheech departure.
There's no,
we always had that runaway fucking train
that were just flat and people actually,
we used to have like three of them.
We just don't have that anymore.
Now we're fucking fast as shit.
At least I thought we were until we
played the maple leafs. Um, anyway,
so now the Bruins move on.
We got to Tampa Bay lightning,
part of that hotbed of
hockey fans down there.
I went to a Tampa Bay lightning game down
there, right. And went with four Shah.
We were sitting there and there was,
he's a Florida northern Florida redneck
spinus some of my favorite rednecks.
I like rednecks, you know, uh,
there was not a fixed shit.
I'll fix it. Ain't going to
fit well, it'll hang off Nass.
Um, we would sit sitting there and
they had on the diamond vision,
they put this little baby
up there, right. You know,
they had an infant up on the screen.
The guy behind us goes, look,
I had a little baby.
I Dunno why.
They just stuck with us a
little rest of the road trip.
You driving over to fucking
Orlando dead silence in the car.
And the forest just be like a little baby.
Uh,
it was hilarious and also scary.
Just listen to the guy cause he didn't
sound real bright and just the fact that
you know,
his TJ's can also make babies.
I just wished that like your level of
intelligence made you, oh, so like,
like your Iq should be
the same level as your,
a reproductive like a potency.
Is that the right word?
Like if you're a fucking moron,
it should be a half court shot that
you're going to get somebody knocked up.
You know,
that's not how it works.
Dumb people usually have like
that super just, you know,
let me just stand next to somebody
and they get fucking pregnant.
Just shooting out fucking kids.
Uh,
that's cause they're too dumb to plan.
You know, they just lay it on the back.
Well it feels good. It
feels good. Feels good.
Well I was my belly sticking out.
Why is my belly moving?
Does anybody else feel weird?
Are for that meal and then they just
fucking shit the kid out on a sofa.
I mean that happens.
That still happens in America out
there on the Appalachian trail.
God knows Hollywood and go out there
and put some cameras on it and turned it
into a fucking reality show.
And next thing you know,
we're buying it and there's
fucking little kid sewing together.
Tee shirts with these
fucking dope faces on it.
All right? And that's what's
wrong with this goddamn country.
MMM.
Jesus Christ. I love all
these people taking the bait
on that fucking Kanye West.
Shit. He obviously, he has an album
coming out. You're fucking morons. Relax.
Okay.
Has he lost his mind?
Did you learn anything with
that beyond say album? Well,
she was acting like she was all annoyed
with JC and that there were all these
problems at all.
What the fuck?
Everybody just starts
gossiping and everybody buys
the fucking album and they're
still together. How many fucking times
you're going to jump on the hook.
He's obviously recording a fucking album.
There's no more MTV.
Billboards are a lot of fucking money.
Why don't you just start saying some
crazy shit that makes no fucking sense.
Okay.
Yeah know. And then people
will listen to your next album.
Okay,
I'm going to fucking do that.
Get my podcasts numbers up.
What the fuck can I, uh,
I going to just start saying
positive shit about women.
Okay.
You know, I think the real
problem beyond global warming,
then that swirl of trash
out in the Pacific Ocean,
even worse than Isis.
Okay.
Oh, I got a text message.
Ah, I dropped the phone.
Jesus Christ Tiki Barber. Pick
it up though. For Christ's sake.
Uh,
shut this fucking thing off.
I think the biggest problem
beyond Isis and isis is a major problem.
I mean,
they're just like the Third Reich.
The Third Reich had no planes or boats
or really any technology,
um,
is white male heterosexuals
and their micro aggression.
Um,
which is why I have decided I can't
even do this because you guys are gonna
fucking retweet this thing. And next
thing you know, it'd be some fucking,
I don't want to get involved in that. I
was going to say that I, I've decided,
okay,
no, I can't say it because everyone's
going to get all fucking upset.
It rhymes with man Zishan
that would be the ultimate right,
if you did that.
Okay.
Be Funny if you, yeah, if he did that,
like as this as a sign of solidarity
with all the pain that women have been
through that you actually,
uh,
went through with the sex change operation
and then everybody called you a hero
and then Diane Sawyer interviewed you
and they made you a woman of the year.
And then after all that cleared,
all these women came forward and said
you were grabbing ass and titties all
through the 90s and two thousands, then
you'd be like, well, I didn't do that.
That was frank.
I'm Francis and I just feel like for me,
and then you're on the
other side of the issue.
MMM.
And they'd be like, well, isn't frank
still in there? And you could be like,
well, I left frank on that, that fucking
operating table. I never was frank.
Frank is my white slave name
given to me by my white parents.
Um, Jesus Christ. How much more time
do I have in this fucking podcast?
I usually like doing these sinks,
man.
But what am I fucking head is
all clogged like this? You know,
when I lay down in my slippers
having to podcasts with a head cold,
that's a day's work. People. Now I know
you guys are out there doing construction.
What the fuck do people do nowadays?
Everybody air quote works from home now,
which means they're out driving around
on the highways during the day cause and
fucking rush hour traffic.
You know what I mean?
Cause they saw something on Pinterest
that they have to go pick up to add to
their fucking wardrobe for their
party that night. Right? Uh,
we should go back to
making our own clothes.
You should go back to that. You make your
own clothes, you grow your own Burgers,
right?
You want to fucking Burger,
go slaughter that calf and then you
figure out how to freeze the rest of that
meter. You're going to start this
winter if they're pilgrim. Um,
I think to something's good,
something like that's gonna happen.
We're either going to regress to that
after the shit hits the fan or this
illuminati stuff is true.
And the robots will kill all of us.
And uh,
oh wow.
That'd be amazing in the future,
right? This, this Illuminati city,
everybody's dead except for
the Illuminati people. Right.
And the other people that they keep
making, they kept enough people, right,
with good genes that they
make fuck each other.
So they keep making babies and stuff that
they can use to fucking, uh, you know,
as almost like a parts car, you know,
for Oregon's, when they reach maturity.
I know this is fucked up, right? Uh,
sort of like Westworld meets a guy
with a head cold doing a podcast on a
Thursday. That's how it pitched
this in Hollywood. I come in,
I say hello everybody. We
do all this small talk, but
Baba Baba, Baba, you know, I,
I read the fucking room. I try to figure
out where the laughs are going to be,
you know,
try to block out the ice cold person.
That douche was just sitting there
fidgeting with their fucking pen.
Um, and I would, I would just pitch it.
I pitch the hell out of it. So anyways,
so then you have an Illuminati city.
All right.
And they feel like they've won,
but their actual actually
prisoners because the robots
have the city surrounded,
you know, and they still have some
robots. The older versions that are good,
you know, that's still work with
the people. But the latest update,
other one went fucking rogue
and killed a couple of the,
it was like the first people that
died other than the parts people
and like hundreds of years.
So they hit the fucking shield
and I got this big bubble,
like the Simpsons set one time,
right?
They got this big bubble over the fucking
city and they stay in there with the
older version of the robots and they're
the ones that have to try to protect him
as the fuck.
And the higher level ones are trying to
figure out how to get into the bubble.
And that's what it is. And it's weird
thing you'd have to root for these pieces,
shit,
humans.
So then obviously what would happen is
you'd have a really good looking parts
person like Ryan Gosling and he,
Hey Nia,
hi, hi. And he would,
uh, he would somehow,
you know, he'd bang like the hottest
Illuminati person and she believed in him.
And then him and one of the
lesser robots then fucking
to feet the next level robots while
freeing all the parts people and then
killing the Illuminati people.
There you go. And you could,
you could finish the story halfway
through it and then get everybody to go to
the second one, right? And then all you,
you have to do is just show up down at
comic con wherein an Obi wan Kenobi rope.
And I think he got $1 billion
franchise. What do you think? Yeah,
you liked that movie? I love it.
What would you name that movie
bills? Great idea for a movie. Oh, Jesus.
What are you doing on my phone? I
wasn't listening. I'm texting myself.
Those pictures. What pictures? The
pictures you took of me earlier.
That's it. Yeah. I got to get back
to our child. Oh, that's right.
I forgot we had a kid
come on you guys.
You know,
so he puts 10,000 hours into that idea.
You got yourself a good
fucking movie Boobie Boobie.
It's a lot of hacky shit in there.
You know,
it's like Westworld
meets fucking Moonraker,
uh, with a dash a happy days. You know,
cause at some point some I'll fucking
Ron Howard directs Ryan Gosling stars.
He probably wouldn't do it because
you already did blade runner.
Do you guys see that one?
The 20,
48 blade runner that moves
the movie was the Shit
I just noticed.
I probably had been coughing like
every five fucking seconds on this.
I apologize. I Apologize, but I'm not
going to take a cough drop. All right.
Okay.
Cough drops if for Socialists.
All right. Anyway, so you know,
like when you do an interview,
when you got to fucking show coming up,
they go pale.
So what can people expect from you?
Wow.
What are you gonna be talking about
when I come to town? What do you what?
I can't fucking tell you that cause
then the jokes are going to be over.
Everybody's going to know what
I'm going to be talking about.
What kind of fucking question is that?
You sound like you're still a
great way under she'll these days,
I'm not angry. It's just
my, my default emotion.
I walk around relaxed and then
when anything happens, good or bad,
I get it and I don't. I don't, I don't
know if it's good. I don't get angry.
I don't know. Hey, we got
a new advertiser. Okay.
We somehow convince somebody else to get
on this sinking ship. Let's see here.
From the halls of Mark Tazo
Ma to the shores of Tripoli.
I will type my far again.
Password.
All right. Oh, butchers box,
butchers box, and we're not
talking about his wife. All right.
Butchers box.
Now these guys actually sent me a bag
of fucking butchered meat and I had a
steak the other day. I may
add my wife cooked it. Uh Huh.
Tell me I'm not running shit in my house.
I was actually sick and she's a sweetheart
and she cooked it and it was fucking
delicious.
It was a giant portion.
So much that I've actually saved it
for a little bit of steak and eggs.
Later on this week,
a butcher box delivers healthy
100% grass fed and finished beef.
I don't know what finished means. They
are. That means they butchered it.
Free Range,
organic chicken and heritage bread.
Pork directly to your
door on a monthly basis.
Eat like you're in the Illuminati.
All their products are humanely raised.
Okay?
Excuse me.
Could you come over here if you wouldn't
mind before I butcher you and never
ever given antibiotics or hormones.
There you go.
If you don't want your kids to hit
puberty at eight butcher blocks,
butcher blocks, butcher box, high
quality, healthy protein you can trust.
You can shake hands with these cows.
100% grass fed and finished beef free
range. Organic chicken. We've said this.
Heritage, bread, pork. What
does Rick flair out there?
That's old world pork before
they bred out all of the fat
and flavor to make it the
other white meat a key a.
This is the way they were meant to be.
I got to look up heritage bread,
pork. That's fascinating. Unbelievable.
It's like a mat and a old
car with matching numbers.
Unbelievable tastes is a huge difference
in taste between animals raised on
pasture and those fed and grain
constant in concentration,
animal feedlot operations. But your
box is changing that. This is great.
This is more and more of these
types of people. Got To love it. Um,
and they offer free shipping
anywhere in the, in the 48 states,
the lower 48 Alaska.
Who's kidding? Who Right?
You're fucking trap in
your own meat and Hawaii.
You a eat pineapples over 20% off plus
free bacon by going up free bacon by
going a butcher box.com/bar and using
the discount code. Bar B, u. R. R.
I tried to, Shit. I ate the shit. I
love this shit. I backed this shit.
Put your box.com/bar. Um, you know,
I've got time to go to the butcher.
Use these guys.
I have to look up heritage, bread, pork,
you know, every former president.
So he's eaten this shit right?
Here we go. Heritage bread, pork heritage,
swine definition.
It's funny when somebody uses the
word swine and it's not an insult.
I fucking love pigs. There's
certain animals that I, I, you know,
I like all animals,
but I fucking love pigs.
Is any cooler than a little piglet
running around deaf Alec Ducks?
Yeah,
I like piglets.
He moves freaked me out.
Dogs are awesome cats I respect,
but you know what I mean?
Okay.
I, you know, I,
there's never any like sort of like every
once in a while you meet a really cool
fucking cat. All right. Definitely.
But they got that Freddy Krueger
claws and shit. You know,
you turned around real quick and they
were like practicing killing, Ya know,
you catch them stock and you and shit.
That fucking weird.
Okay.
You wake up there on
your chest staring at you
like that chicken misery.
All right.
Purpose swine at been a part of the
American agricultural landscape since the
arrival of the new world calling us.
Why do they have to go
that fucking far back?
Yeah.
This is why I don't read books.
Moby Dick get to the fucking whale.
Sorry.
Swine indigenous to Europe were brought
with immigrants during the colonization
of America commercials. Fucking
things in the, the wooden ship.
Freaking the fuck out.
Riding over there with us.
Hairless monkeys knowing
they're going to get killed. Um,
and the many different types of swine.
They brought. Hep provided pork, Lard,
pest control in land improvement
services for centuries.
How to pork on a pigs, help with pest
control cause they fucking eat everything.
I have something else to look up.
This is how you lose a day on the
Internet because there's always an answer.
It doesn't mean it's right, but there's
always someone who some will have a page,
is what I think.
There's why what they do with Bar Mitzvah.
A modern bread associations maintained
pedigree registries of pure bred animals
for each breed that descends
from these colonial oh wow.
These are like the fucking,
the blue bloods of pigs as
well as later introductions.
A registration of animals destined to
become breeding stock is essential to the
longterm security of the breeds.
Registration validates bred status of the
animals and assures their availability
for conservation by future generations.
Many swap lines,
but he swines Bree swine breeds that
were once core components of regional
cultures are now in danger of
extinction as cultures of Homo Homo.
[inaudible] Homo.
Yeah.
Generalized, homogenized. God, I'm stupid.
And historic agricultural traditions
abandoned the flavors and food traditions
that revolved or,
yeah,
check out Monsanto for that one fucking
lunatics definition of heritage swine.
Okay.
I don't even know if it's about sat off.
They always said the fault
people you blame. Who knows?
Allegedly Monsanto heritage swine
must adhere to all of the following
one.
I ain't a true chin.
Genetic bread.
The breed is a true
genetic breed of swine.
That is when made it together.
It reproduces the breed type. All
right. I guess this is from Europe
to de dos. What does it
ains times? I, I don't,
I can't do the chairman
and dangered breed.
The breed is or has been endangered
as defined by the livestock cons.
Okay.
Conservancy and appears on or has
recovered from the con conservancies
conservation priority list and the
critically threatened Jesus Christ.
Long history in the U s purebreds. I
get it. It's pure bread. I like it.
They're fucking in danger
and I'm eating them.
I'm meeting the fucking pig version
of a fucking bald eagle. Um,
okay.
What the fuck did I just, I just
shut that off and I, I wanted to,
what else did I want to look up?
Who is it? Oh, how to pigs
control pass population.
What?
He eat bugs.
Not how, how not how to bill. How do,
okay, here we go. Well,
it just says forbid.
Then information was forbidden.
Practical feral pig control because
feral pig population as the wild pigs.
Anyways. Fuck this shit. How
are their wild pigs by the way?
Well, those, the farmers that got
scalped by the native Americans,
so they just steer pigs just ran off.
Continue to fuck for centuries, you know?
Okay.
I Dunno, I don't have the
answers to these questions,
but I do have some bullshit I have
to do at 10 o'clock. Uh, alright.
That is the podcast. This
was a weird one. All right.
But we came up with a good movie idea.
We learned about heritage page and fucking
a swine from Europe and a Gopro lunch
and Celtics about those Celtics.
And I try to wrap up these Pesky fucking
Milwaukee Bucks. You know I like that.
One guy on Milwaukee,
he looks like a fucking like
a mid sized minuit bull.
Really dark skinned guy.
He hit,
he had some fucking lay up or some shit
to go up by four in the second quarter.
The shush the crowd.
Like he just hit a game winning
three does this second quarter.
Then they go on to lose the
game. I just don't, I tie,
I don't understand these kids today.
All right everybody have a great weekend
[inaudible] and I'll see everybody in
there.
Lana and I'll see you down at
the fucking race track count.
Come Saturday,
listen to the music and enjoy,
you know,
the half hour of our greatest sets
from a Thursday just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast, Thursday
earlier this year, possibly this decade.
All right,
I'll see ya.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast from Monday,
April 26th April,
April 26th,
2010 how the hell are you?
I'm a little late today with the podcasts
doing at three 43 Los angles is time.
Uh, and you probably want to like do what
the fuck you supposed to be doing these
Monday morning. That's why you
call it the Monday morning. So when
I come to work on Monday morning,
I have something to listen to rather
than focusing on the fucking job that I
hate. Well, you're right. Landless. I
am late this week, but you know what,
I was busy fucking busy this week. Uh, I,
I was doing shit this morning,
you know what I mean?
And also not to mention I am filming
this podcast for the first time ever.
I am allowing somebody else into the
Monday morning podcast bunker until now.
People just had to use their imagination
to wonder what the fuck does bill look
like while he does this podcast?
Is he wearing a Tuxedo,
maybe a dinner jacket? Is he
sitting there? You know, I'm not,
I'm in pajamas and my t shirt with my
little radio shack headphones on the exact
way that you pictured me, but I am
filming at this week, um, because, uh,
my DVD is, uh, just about complete
and now we are working on extras.
And I think at my last DVD I did the,
uh, I did a little short history,
a bunch of clubs that I loved in New York.
So you kinda got that whole background
and I figured out my me, I'll do this.
Maybe I'll fill in the podcast,
edit out the hours and
hours of unfunny moments,
right? See, you're going to actually
hear the whole fucking podcast,
these idiots who bought my DVD, who
are going to watch it and just be like,
oh my God,
this is the greatest fucking thing I've
ever seen because of the wonderful world
of editing. So he probably thinking
like, what are you doing bill?
You filming it yourself and you're going
to edit it that, that, that does not,
that's not consistent with the moron
that I'm used to listening to what?
You're right.
I'm not,
I have the wonderfully talented
Brian Spitz is a working the camera.
Yep.
That was him right there.
He actually shot my failed pilot last
year on comedy central. Remember that one?
That was fun and we got excited then we
were like, it's going to happen. It was,
it grow with,
honestly, it was a great
fucking show. Wasn't it
ever in the history and the history
of failed pilots? I, I would say we,
yeah, we weren't, we
were in the, you know,
we just failed as opposed to just a
complete failure. It'd be like, you know,
if a patch passing grade was 60, I think
we, I think we've got about 58 on that,
you know, I don't know. But you
know what the weird thing is,
it's actually up on my imdv page.
That's what I love.
I don't know who put it up there,
but you're not supposed to put shit
on there that isn't on TV or it wasn't
released in cinema or whatever.
And uh, I, for the life of me,
I don't know how to take it down, but
um, you'll take it care. Okay. Thank you.
Because people, all right, well
it was cool. Can you actually,
can you actually call IMD be okay?
Yeah, but that sounded good. I was,
I'm going to call those guys, I'm gonna
call that website and uh, you know,
get those guys on the phone
to see what's up. So yeah.
So if you're ever wondering
what the burn effect was,
that was just a working title
that we gave it to them.
It never aired and it won't air unless
I become hugely famous or infamous.
That's basically it. If I become a
huge movie star or television star,
you'll probably up seeing it in
some form.
Or if I go to a mall and
I just started fucking,
you know, killing puppies at the local
pet store or whatever the fuck you do.
I wouldn't say shooting because every,
everybody's done the shooting thing.
Isn't that like Hackey at this point?
You know what I mean? That's, it's like,
it's like if I was a comedian,
I went on on stage and I started
talking about airline food.
Basically go walking in to
a mall massacring people,
I think it's Hacky at this
point. You know, Yawn.
If I can be so bold to say I'm fucking
bored with that shit. But anyways,
let's get to me and my big fucking
week. Do you guys have a big week? Well,
if you didn't, let me fucking tell
you about my big week. First of all,
I don't know if I've been talking about
this on the podcast as I settle into my
sofa.
Um,
basically everything that identified
me as the person that I am,
uh, a month ago, either it was
expiring or I didn't have it,
you know,
I basically could not prove that
I existed with any sort of paper.
You know, my passport was
expiring my driver's license.
I needed to get that thing
for about fucking two years.
I'm not gonna lie to you when you
first move out to Los Angeles.
I think they give you
about six weeks to get it.
And I've almost been out here
for three fucking years. So, uh,
and my New York license was expiring.
I didn't have a social security
card that I could produce.
I had the number,
you know,
the Illuminati gave me a fucking
number when I was eight years old.
Let's get them on the wheel to get them
on the wheel. Let's get them in debt.
Are you in college? Are you making 200
bucks a week? Hey, here's a visa card.
We'll give you a $3,000 limit.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
Give us 25 bucks a week and just get it
up to you three grand limit and we'll
fucking own your ass. All
right, so I didn't have that.
What else didn't I have my and my birth
certificate, I had nothing. I had nothing.
So I was like a, it was like fuck,
I got to handle this shit. You know,
cause all of a sudden now I'm
doing gigs in Europe, you know,
I think I'm going to Japan
to perform for the troops.
I need pieces of papers saying I am who
I am and I have not done anything fucked
up. So a, in one month I
got my passport renewed,
I went down to the social security office,
I got that fucking thing,
I found my birth certificate.
And the last thing I needed
was my driver's license.
Say figure out the driver's license.
I mean,
that's a pain in the ass to
take the fucking test. You know,
you ever notice like what a pussy you
become as an adult when it comes to tests.
Like I think once you don't take a test
for what you're used to it as a kid,
people are always testing you.
You know where I'm in a spelling
test where I've vocabulary tests,
some bully punches in the face.
He's testing you. You know,
are you going to be a fucking man?
You know,
you Charles Bronson at age 12 or are you
fucking are Richie Cunningham who I was
and got bullied
and sees no reason to go back to a
fucker reunion now. It wasn't that bad.
You know what? I'll be honest
with you. Uh, when was it bad?
Maybe elementary school.
Beginning of middle school,
everybody hit their
growth spurt and I didn't,
I still had a high pitched voice in a, a
an orange Afro. That wasn't a good look.
That wasn't the look you wanted to
rock is the youth says. So. Anyways,
I have to take my driver's test out here
and I brought it up with a couple other
la Los Angelenos and
straight across the board.
Everybody was telling me like they had
horror in their eyes and how difficult
this fucking test was going. Oh my God,
dude, dude, it's dude. It's fucking hard.
It's fucking hard.
They kept saying that.
Remember I was living out here
10 years ago. I took the test.
It wasn't fucking hard, like don't
do it. I'm telling you, dude,
it was fucking hard and I had this
girl with this party was this,
have you been to the DMV on here? Oh
my God. It's not like the DMV. Anyway,
off La. It's just like if on Dale and
I kept saying, well I bended the DMV.
I been to it. I know it's crowded
and she just kept going now.
Now like you don't understand,
there's nothing worse than somebody
just tells me like you don't understand.
It's like from so many from Chicago,
when you try to tell him it was a cold
winter and then they got to go on about
fucking now you don't know what cold is
until you're standing there rubbing your
balls next to fucking Lake Michigan,
you know,
like it's fucking minus 20 degrees in
Boston. But still, that's my, you know,
my family all came from fucking the
Midwest. So anytime I had a paper,
when I bitch about the Colo, let
me tell you, you don't know cold.
You don't go to Chicago.
Let me tell you,
go to Chicago so that all those
fucking idiots and some good barbecue,
I'll do it. You don't know
barbecue? Go to fucking Texas.
That's where they got the bar.
Like,
like they're the only people
who know that shit. All right,
you got a little upset there. Don't
hold it against me. So anyways, uh,
[inaudible] he's telling me I
don't know what the fucking DMV is.
You know what all this does.
This just motivates me to pass this
fucking test and the first time so I can
just make, so I can justify me
judging all these la Douche bags,
like they're just mentally weak fucking
people. So I started studying the test,
get the book, and it's like 90 pages.
I was like, fuck, all right, whatever.
Break it down. I'm going to do 30
pages a day. I outlined this book,
Huh? What are you doing right now sitting
in your cubicle instead of working,
looking at your spreadsheets,
what are you doing?
I hear what I fucking outlined the book.
I outlined the book 30 pages at a fucking
time meticulously like Tom Hanks in
that movie when he was chasing
Leonardo Dicaprio. Catch me if you can.
I was like that, that level
of shit. And I was, I,
I just, you know, fucking
broke the whole book down.
And then I sat there every day for 45
minutes to an hour and I went over all the
shit in two days before the test.
Saturday.
I actually took the sections out that I,
that I still was having problem with
and I just fucking went hardcore on that
section. Memorize that and
went through my all my outline.
I knew the whole fucking thing and
how you want to ask me some questions.
You want to talk about
parking near railroad tracks.
I got to fucking answer for you.
Seven and a half feet.
If you're inside a seven and a half feet,
you're fucked. 18 inches from the curb,
three feet from a fucking handicap ramp.
You know one of these fucking guys
rolling by asking you for a quarter.
Those guys can't get like
three feet close to those guys.
15 feet from a hydro.
You've got to start signaling a
hundred feet before you make a turn.
You get in the turning lane.
You can only drive in it for 200 feet.
He can't use it as a passing lane.
I had the shit down, so I'm like,
fuck all these people. I walked in there
confident. I'm talking Colby Bryan,
eight seconds left. Give me the fucking
ball. All right. I ironed my shirt.
I knew I was getting a picture of that
day for my license to be nothing but
success. So I walk in there, I
don't want to happen immediately.
I start getting fucking nervous. You
know like the first time I did Letterman.
All right, like the first fucking
time you do anything. I'm,
I'm fucking get nervous. I've taken
this fucker test four different times.
Took it in Boston, passed
it, New York passed it,
came out to la 10 years ago I passed it,
moved back to New York, passed the thing.
Why am I fucking nervous?
Cause he's fucking Las holes.
Their voices are in my head. Did it, did
you fucking hard dude, I fucking failed.
You know how to I forgot to mention
is they all said the same shit. Why?
Why they failed. It is cause
they didn't study the first time.
Cause I thought it was gonna be easy
cause they drive every day. Do you really?
How do you just think of how stupid that
statement is, dude, I drive every day.
I know how to do it.
It's those little things,
you know like what does a white curb meat,
you know,
he come up and it's painted white.
What does that mean?
Loading and unloading of passengers
or picking up mail, yellow curb,
what does that mean?
La Loading and unloading of freight.
If you're not in a commercial vehicle,
the driver has to stay with the car.
I studied for the Shit gimme the rock,
it's fucking going in and we're going
to the next round of the playoffs.
I was ready for that shit and I went
in there and I maybe there was just the
overall anxiety, the fucking place. But
I do the whole shit. First of all I do,
what I always do at the DMV is I just
blow off the line and I act like I didn't
see it and that I'm some
sorta like, you know, royalty,
like I'm actually staying at the embassy
for some fucking country and never
heard of.
I'm that guy.
You know when you stand in line and you
followed the rules and then you get up
to the fucking cashier lady
and then there's that dose.
He was just standing there
to the side respectively,
half an inch just behind your peripheral.
But you know he's there and you can't
have a pause in your conversation because
you know that asshole's going to jump in.
That's who the fuck I was. And I said,
Hey, I'm sorry buddy, sorry.
And I wasn't sorry. That was
me really being like, dude,
I'm interrupting you right
now. And I said, ah, I've got
to take this, uh, you know,
I had a previous, you know, a schedule
appointment, where do I go? Like, Oh,
you go around the corner, whatever. So
thank the guy. I wasn't saying thank you.
I don't know what the fuck I was doing.
It's just trying to prevent the guy
from punching me in the face because I
deserved it. And I went over to
go take the fucking test and a,
I'm standing there and they only
got like this walled off area.
Okay. And that's how confident
I was. I didn't even,
I didn't even brush up out in the parking
lot. I was just like, bring the shit on.
You want me to take Lebron? I fucking
got him right. So I walk in there right?
And you got to wait til like only line
of like five people in there at a time.
So the first dude walks out and uh,
you know,
they got the black dude behind the
counter, like the host scared straight.
You need to get your shit
together. Kind of do, you know,
and I'm just sitting there going
off, fuck, here we go. Here we go.
This fucking guy,
this guy's breaking hearts all day and
he doesn't even give a fuck. Look at it.
Look on his face. He doesn't give a fuck
that bill Parcells look on his face,
right?
So there's fucking Indian dude comes up
and he and he hands him the thing and
the guy just fucking puts red all over
it and the guy fails. And then I'm like,
oh fuck the any guy. These guys are
fucking smart, right? Any guys are smart.
They fucking answer our phones over here.
I can't answer phones.
If somebody from India called me, you
know, give myself a fake Indian named,
these fucking people are smart.
These people were running shit until
the English fucked him over, right?
This guy fucking pass. But then I calmed
myself down. I'm like, wait a minute,
this is a second language. This is his
second language. If I went to France,
could I pass the driver's
test? Fuck No. All right,
don't compare yourself to that guy.
And then the next two came
up and it was a slacker.
This white kid who had
like tight jeans yet,
they were hanging off his ass and I just
wanted a boot him right in his fucking
taint. He passes. So it gave me hope
and I went in there, I got the test,
okay, I get eight hours sleep. I
took a deep breath and I'm like,
here we go.
I have the test right in front of me and
the first one was some bullshit about
what is the legal alcohol level. You
know that you can drive on it. I'm like,
this is a fucking joke.
I'm going to ace this test and dude,
I'm going to tell you right
now after the first question,
it just went down fucking hill.
Listen to these questions.
I'm studying all this shit about
how close to park to a curve,
a curb and all that shit.
You must notify the DMV within five days.
If you sell or transfer your vehicle are
cited for a traffic violation. That's,
that's obviously no paint your
vehicle a different color sound like,
oh fuck, I didn't read that
part. I don't remember that part.
Sell or transfer your vehicle,
painted a different color. Five days,
sell a transfer your vehicle.
Don't you have to fucking
tell them right then I want,
they automatically know
with the satellites, they
won't see that transaction.
Go down in the fucking
driveway through it.
And then this is panic just like,
and I, and I, and I was like,
oh my God,
what the fuck?
And I got like six questions in and I
literally put the number two pencil down
and I whispered, yell. I went, really?
As I looked at the black dude when
he wasn't looking at me, of course,
totally passive aggressive and, uh, do it.
I'm not going to lie to
you this fucking test.
So it was brutal to fucking
brutal. And I, you know,
usually when you take
a multiple choice test,
it's like there's the obvious the half
right? And then the fucking ridiculous.
Like when you drink a glass of water,
should you a uh,
make sure you have
enough air in your lungs
before sucking down the entire glass.
And if you do run out of air,
stop drinking and inhale,
you know,
be smashed the glass against your
head, you know, obvious shit. Right?
This shit was like,
when is it legal to use a cell phone?
I have the test right here without a
hands free device while driving. Okay.
When is it legal to use a cell phone
without using a hands free device? Huh?
You got an answer a when making a
call while stopped at a red light,
that's obviously no,
but here's the two close ones.
When making a call for
emergency assistance or never,
when is it legal to use a cell
phone? Hands Free people, hands free,
hands free device and has all this shit
on TV going if he used his cell phone
and it's as bad as fucking
drinking and driving. And the book,
it said never and it
said you could use it to,
if for to make to make an emergency call
after you fucking pulled over and all
that bullshit. Look for somebody riding
a bike. You know, looking for an old guy,
one of those, try
sickles, all of that shit.
So this just said when making a
call for emergency assistance,
it didn't say you pulled over.
It didn't say you didn't pull over.
So I fucking panicked and I wrote
never got it wrong. All right,
let's just, that's fucking
stories taking 10 times longer.
How long it took me to study for
the fucking test. Long story short,
I'd have 18 questions. I
got 15 right. Three wrong.
I fucking pass the test but I owe,
I owe an apology to all you Los Angelenos.
This is a hard ass fucking test. It was
difficult. I know what you're thinking.
Like that way you guys were all talking
shit cause you're relaxed right now.
Right?
We find another difficult one here.
Highways are typically most slippery.
This is a desert question
cause it doesn't rain out here.
And what happens is when it doesn't rain
for a while, oil transmission, fluid,
fluid, and gas all starts to coagulate.
And when it rains, it's like,
I can't say it's like ice, but God knows
people drive like it out here. But this,
this is the question, it says,
uh, uh, would, uh, fuck was it.
Highways are typically most slippery
during a heavy rainstorm in the middle of,
in the middle of summer.
All right. Middle of summer,
it's fucking dry out. You know, maybe
that's it. And then it says when it's,
when it first starts to rain
after a dry spell. Well yeah,
yeah, after a dry spell. Absolutely. But
the summer's dry. What the fuck writes?
And at this point, my Mike fucking heart
rate is going like 9,000 beats a second.
And then it says after it's
been raining for a long time,
if it's been raining for a long time,
the roads are wet.
It's going to still be fucking slippery.
But I know it has to do
with it being dry out here.
So I fucking broke that one
down. I'm like, all right,
it's the middle of summer.
It's a heavy fucking rainstorm.
Who's to say it didn't
fucking rain heavily the day
before and it already washed
all the guests off.
So then I get,
so I guessed when it first starts to
rain after a dry spell and I was fucking
right, but that's the level you had
to break this shit down. All right,
so I passed. That's it. They took
my thumb. The fucking Illuminati,
you know, sent that right to
the Rothschild's fucking house.
Do you know those sons of bitches
actually have the audacity,
the Rothschilds to have a book about
the giant fucking house they bought in
England off of all their fucking
Shylock money from the rest of us.
Do you believe you believe
the fucking balls of that?
Evidently there's something beyond
our mansion. It's called a manner.
That's when you have you,
that's when you do take like fucking
12 mansions and you put it together and
like, people don't even know
how to get to your house.
Like I can guarantee you
something right fucking now. Oh,
this is a great way to see
if they're running shit.
You know when you Google maps, like if
you Google map where the fuck I live?
Not only can you see my place,
they'll probably,
you can probably see my brand
new social security card.
No one gives a fuck about me. But if
you Google map the Rothschild's house,
I guarantee you it doesn't fucking show
up like the God Damn White House cause
they're running shit.
And you know what?
They have my thumbprint on
their fucking wall of the,
of their fucking nine mile wine cellar.
Does that make any sense?
Well it shouldn't because I don't read.
All right.
I don't fucking read anyways.
What else do I got going on here that
wasn't bad hot for being filmed that in
and seem to self conscious. Look at
that. Get a big nod. Eyebrows up.
I think it's going good.
The first filmed Monday morning podcast.
This is what I do.
If you've been listening to this,
I'm talking to the camera right now,
not to you go back to work.
You've been fucking off already
for 19 minutes and 40 seconds.
This is what I do every week.
I sit here in my, in my,
in my pajamas and my little footlocker
tee shirt, you know, is this foot locker?
I don't know what the fuck this is.
Footlocker,
like 87 t shirts for like $9 if you
ever wondered if you ever wondered,
hey,
did a three year old put this shirt
together or was the person at least 16 you
can never be more sure than when you go
to footlocker and you buy those fucking
tee shirts. When you get like
nine of them for eight bucks,
that's guaranteed that that's not
even child. That's like toddler,
toddler fucking labor.
Be funnier if I could fucking say it.
So this is what I do every
week. Okay. Is what I do.
So if you want to listen to the podcast,
go to [inaudible] dot com click
on Monday morning podcasts.
You hate your fucking job. Hopefully
there'll be on iTunes at this point.
They will be, I'm going to talk
shit, they're going to be on iTunes.
You know I have like 14 listeners.
I'm trying to get it up to
15 whenever they put there.
Why the fuck you want from me? All
right, let's plow. Okay, I'm back.
I'm back doing the podcast. Um, all right,
let's get to the stories this week. I,
uh, that was the first story. I'm just
gonna tell some stories this week.
I got another one for
you. Um, at this point,
do you want me to pause Brian and go into
another room to give people something
visually different to look at?
Should I do that? All right,
let's try to hit pause here. Uh, this
is going to be really quick for you.
People listening at home. It's like,
I'm going to pause and then we're back.
So I'm pausing right now.
All right. Yeah, we'll,
we'll put bookshelves and the, okay,
we're back. We're back. We decided,
you know what, we already tried to do
this and I fucking lost the whole podcast.
So we're not doing it. I'm
recording right now. We just,
you don't need to record this.
You don't even, you know,
I'm not going to use this on a DVD.
This is just for the poor bastards
at home listening. I actually,
so that's my deal. Everybody. I'm moving
shit around my apartment right now.
This is exciting.
It's exciting to audit in an audio way
to hear the it isn't. I know it's not,
dude. You know what? Is there
any doctors that listen to this?
How fucking arrogant is that?
Like they have time between surgery
to listen to a moron like me. Well,
a lot of doctors are arrogant anyways.
They save people's lives.
They get that God complex. Just to let
you know. I'll do, that's my water.
All right. That's yours over there.
Okay. Just letting you know. I mean,
I like you when everything, all right. You
did a great job on the pilot, but let's,
let's keep it there. Um, I
fucked up the arch in my foot.
I did it years ago from playing drums,
trying to get my foot as fast as John
Bonham's having no fucking technique and
not having stretched so that that tendon
that runs from the ball of your fucking
foot to your heel every once in a while,
I fuck it up in it and it just takes
forever to heal and I don't know what I'm
supposed to do about it.
All right? I stretch.
I got the tennis ball
rubbing underneath it.
I know I'm not supposed to walk
around, but that's what I do. Okay?
I use my feet. A lot of
people don't, you know,
if you walk into a Mcdonald's
and you see those people,
that's what they use their feet for, to
walk to their car, to sit in their car.
And then if they don't even go in anymore,
they just drive right up.
So I want to know what
else can I be doing?
Is there any sort of aspirin that
I can be taking to get the fucking
inflammation down? And you
probably wondered, okay, you're,
you're probably asking me
this bill because not being
able to use your footage,
fucking annoying. It
goes beyond that. Dr. So,
and so I'll tell you what my problem is.
My problem is I'm going back east for,
for a friend of mine's daughter is
graduating college and I have to go to the
graduation and uh,
I'm getting it back,
get getting together with some
people I used to play drums with,
we used to jam with back in the day when
we all thought we were going to get on
MTV and be the latest hair metal band,
the fact that you had a red head and a
hair metal band and then he could only
grow a fucking Afro right there.
Should've let you know that you weren't
gonna make it. So long story short,
we're getting together and rather than
going back and playing the music we
played in the 80s because that would
just be too sad to go back and play my
Michelle
or whatever the fuck we used to play.
We're like,
let's do something more contemporary.
And I've always played single bass drum
and I became a huge fan of Pantera and
shit.
So I go,
let's do cowboys from hell and it's
got this insane double bass part.
And the second I said that Shit,
I fucked up my foot and I haven't
been able to practice. And meanwhile,
the guitar player, the Bass Player,
they're all shredding, you know,
ignoring their children.
So,
and here I am going to be the foundation
of the band and my foot's fucked up.
So I need a quick remedy.
All right, I need something.
I need something fucking
quickly here. Uh, that,
is there anything that I can take
that, that will just, you know,
I don't want to take roids from my foot
coming there with my right foot twice as
big as the, uh, my left foot.
You know, I don't need that.
Have one big Jason Gme,
Roger Clemens Foot and the other one's
walking around like Willie McGee.
I don't need that shit. All right,
tell me, what do I take aspirin?
Aleve. What do I take? Come
on podcast fucking free.
You can hook me up a
little free medical advice.
Can you email me a prescription or
that just literally, and you're,
you're fucking days as a
doctor. All right, let's,
let's continue on with the podcast.
As I sit here,
rolling a tennis ball underneath
my foot. Um, the next thing, oh,
here's a great story for you,
Brian. You might like this.
Do you know I was a hero this week?
I was actually,
I did something heroic.
I have never,
I have never done anything
heroic in my life. Okay.
And believe me,
I've walked by house fires and saw
people screaming saying there's a ladder
right there. Just put it up. And
I walked away. I walked away.
It's kind of like I didn't hear him.
I'm that kind of a fucking guy. Um, no,
this is the deal. It was
a Sunday. And you know,
people go to brunch on Sunday on like,
all right, fuck it. I'll go to brunch.
I'll go to brunch. Right? Remember that
bid? Huh? Pace $18 as fast as the Wa.
Is that a, this, how did that bit go?
Is that as, I thought it was pesto.
It's asparagus. I can't remember.
So we go to brunch and a, you know,
it's the usual shit.
Do you want to sit inside?
You want to sit out outside as a redhead?
I'm always going inside.
Let's fucking sit inside.
I got enough freckles.
I've had enough fucking pain in my life.
Please.
Let's sit inside now.
But you know,
I'm always with broads cause they always
want to go to brunch and it's fun.
It's fun. It's always fucking
nice when they go to brunch.
It's never raining is it? Right.
Sorry. All right, let's sit outside.
We sit outside and
because I'm the gentlemen,
I have to sit with my back to the
road so I can brace, you know,
and protect my girlfriend and her mom
and case a bread truck comes flying in
because the guys text
messaging or something, right?
So I'm sitting there and uh,
all of a sudden I just feel it.
I just feel like something's fucking
wrong and something my caveman DNA,
like when you get in
stocked by a saber tooth,
tiger just kicks in and something
just tells me to fucking look left.
And I look left and here comes this
crazy fucking lady and I'm talking crazy.
I'm talking shutter island.
Remember that chick that shushed
Leonardo Dicaprio set the second Leonardo
Dicaprio fucking reference.
There you go.
You remember that chick who
shushed him and shutter island?
That's what this girl looked like, except
with sort of brownish red hair. Okay?
It's basically one of these people who
should be getting professional help is
straight up bat shit crazy, and
there's just, this state is bankrupt,
so they just let them go.
They just let these fucking people go
and you don't see Sarah McLaughlin wine
and about these people come
out and rescue these fucking,
these people who are
talking to telephone poles.
It's all about the dogs with her.
Her priorities are so fucked up.
It's ridiculous.
I hope she sees this.
I am so disappointed in
you Sarah McLaughlin. Huh?
When are you going to grow up and stop
whining about those little pussy ass
fucking dogs? All right. That was
mean. All right, let's get back to it.
So she starts coming down
the street and she's like,
she looks like she's going to
start fucking crying. Okay. Like,
and it's just one of those things,
you know, you just feel it.
This fucking person is going
to do something and I have
a feeling they're going
to do it to me. So I, I'm, I'm
working out my shit. I'm like first,
fortunately the chairs with these really
light wicker sorta kind of Douchey
Brunchy chairs.
So I was just going to grab the fucking
chair and I was going to smash her in
the face if I didn't have time or if I
had time I was going to leap to my feet
on my bad fucking foot and out like
a lion tamer, get back crazy person,
right.
Start whipping her with the fucking tulips
on the Nice, beautiful brunch table.
That's what I was going to do.
So she doesn't lunge at me,
but she walks by means that awful moment,
the blind spot, you know what I mean?
Where she's not to my left,
she's not to my right.
She's right behind me and she fucking
goes by me and I'm like, thank God.
I was seriously fucking nervous
and I looked left again just to,
you know,
I don't know why I looked left again.
And then I see this fucking sad looking
woman slowly following the crazy person
with this look on her face like she
had been wronged. I, next thing I know,
next thing I fucking know,
she's talking to the table
next to us and talking to us,
talking about how that crazy
woman had just walked up to her,
reached up to her sweater
and just fucking ripped.
I know she had a brooch.
She just fucking took it off her
chest and walked away with it.
And I'm looking at the lady and she has
the lady and she has this fucking hole
in her sweater where something
had clearly been ripped off.
And for the life of me,
I don't know why I
immediately just got up.
I don't know why. I have no
fucking idea why there was a fight.
I don't do this shit.
I get up and now I'm going down the
street following the shutter island lady
with no training whatsoever
in this situation.
I'm literally walking and now I couldn't
sit down. I couldn't get sit down. Like,
I have this, this fucking
Lee Marvin, I'm going to go,
I'm going to make shit right moment.
And then I go, you know what?
Maybe I'll sit down.
I look at the biggest pussy ever and
not only my girlfriend and my mother's
there. So I had to keep going. So now I'm
following this girl and I'm literally,
I'm fine.
Haven't been so fucking nervous in my
life because it would have been bad enough
if we, if it was like a crazy
dude, a crazy guy. He's scary.
But at least you know if, if, if it
gets physical, I mean, what, what,
what are the rules in that? Do
you know Brian? What did you know?
You can't hit a woman, but what if
she's crazy and she just stole a brooch?
How about a jab? Just kind of get
a mitten, a face like Larry Holmes,
so she doesn't see the overhand, right.
Anyways, I don't know what to do,
so,
but I can't go back to the table or I'm
going to look like a bitch in front of
my girlfriend and my mom saw,
I'm like, fuck, why didn't
I get up? Why did I get up?
Why didn't I, why didn't I say sit
inside? I wanted to sit inside,
but I didn't want to seem like a root
prick in front of my girlfriend's mom.
Like I tell her what to do.
Like she says,
kept fucking woman
Saddam in this situation.
So I'm walking down the street and this
is what I do. She's on the sidewalk.
I'm literally in the
street. Okay. I'm like,
is that circumnavigation I'm doing some
police shit where I'm staying outside of
whatever she can throw at me scratching.
It's one of these people,
you got to get like a tetanus shot if
you roll around the ground or hepatitis
Assam Shit. So I'm like, what
am I going to do? What do I do?
So I don't know what happened. I just
said I, I basically, I just started going,
hey ya. Hey Sweetheart.
Hey Sweetie. I basically,
I think I started calling her affectionate
name from like the 1940s hey ya,
fucking tall drink of water.
And I finally got her attention and she
turns around and looks at me with this
crazy look with tears in her
eyes. And I just say, uh, I, I,
I think you have something that
doesn't belong to you. And meanwhile,
there's a fucking pathetic lady who just
let her walk up to her to begin with.
It's like he didn't see that she was
crazy. That's why I'm in this situation,
right.
She fucking,
she ends up walking up to the
girl and the h when I said,
I think you have something
that doesn't belong to you.
She just sort of looked at
me and like in slow motion,
lifted up her left arm and she had this
green pea soup look and sweater on and
she had the brooch pinned to like just
right around her wrist and she just held
it up. So at this point I'm like,
I'm not touching this bitch.
So I let the, the, the fucking victim
lady with the sad puppy dog eyes,
she comes in and I'm basically sitting
there like an NHL ref with respect for
two goons that are about
ready to go at it. Right.
And I'm just going to jump in when I
see that I can jump in to stop this,
this fight that's going to happen without
getting hit myself. And uh, so anyways,
the lady starts unpinning the
brooch and the whole time she's,
she basically followed my lead by being
nice. She just kept gone. Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
I really appreciate this.
And she couldn't get
the fucking thing off.
It was like one of those action movies
with like the clock's going down for the
bomb and I'm sitting there going
lady and my head, I'm like,
would you get that fucking brooch
off this crazy bitches arm?
And I just kept looking at her right
hand cause I knew at some point she was
either going to gouge her eye out,
just do some crazy shit. Right?
Like you know that the scrap metal that
these people put pickup and floss their
teeth. What she was just going to stick
it right in the juggler. So finally,
long story short, she gets the fucking
broach off and then we, we back away
who's like, ah, exchange. Like we
were like, wait, we gave some money,
briefcase and we got the abducted
kid back and we fucking walk away.
And I'm like, Oh fuck. Thank God.
Thank God that worked on actually walked
back to the, to the brunch. All right.
Walk back to the brunch and I got a
fucking applause break from like all these
people eating eggs benedict and eggs
Florentine. It was fucking awesome.
I was a Goddamn hero this
week. People, uh, scared.
Nervous fucking dude.
I'm tell you Brian,
I didn't come within seven
feet of this woman. I was
literally, you know, you know,
fucking a, the avenue out
there, I'm going to say where,
cause I don't need psychos. Know
where the fuck I live. You know,
like I'm anywhere near that
level of notoriety. Uh,
I was literally fucking like, she's one of
that wall is over there. I'm going, hey,
sweeter to people who didn't
know what was going on.
They probably thought it
was some construction worker
hitting on her look in the
fucking games on there. So,
uh, yeah, that was my week.
That was my weak people. I got my
pass, my fucking driver's test,
and I was at God damn hero.
Huh? What did you do this week?
You know what that reminds me of?
What was that shitty action
movie that ended that way?
That started that emaciated bitch? That
fucking, uh, uh, I was going to say,
Brian Johnson. Brad Pitt's
dating. What's her name?
Natasha or wrote Robin Linskey. She's
got one of those. I'm a hot girl names.
What's her name?
Angelina.
You ever seen a fucking ugly girl
named Angelina? Natasha. Brooke.
That's like a hell of a gamble.
You just know your daughter is,
is his fucking is going to be hot. Right?
And she's going to go for the money.
She's going for the gold. So, uh, yeah.
What, what was that movie? She did what?
She was the assassin and the
whole movie was kind of okay.
And then the movie ends with
Blahblahblah and then ends. He goes,
what the fuck did you do today?
Yeah, no, no, not Mrs Mr. Smith.
That was the one after that.
Morgan Freeman was in it and they,
they stayed shoot the gun in the
fucking bullet would, would go, oh,
this is driving everybody on the podcast.
And that's because they know the name
of it. Well, the movie basically ends.
He goes, what the fuck did you do
today? I mean, they got pissed. Hi,
watched the mediocre movie. I
say Meteoric York. Mediocre.
All right, whatever. Go fuck yourselves.
Okay, this is a what, 35 minutes,
then 35 minutes. And this is going to be,
like I said, it's gonna be a DVD extra.
And if you're watching this,
I probably should've said this earlier.
Maybe we'll do it in the wraparounds
not to talk shop. I was going to say,
where the fuck you can go see
this, get this podcast. Um,
but here's something new for some of
you who have actually found my podcast,
which I love at this point, to actually
find my podcast. It's like a fucking test,
really weeding out the
computer illiterate, um,
of which I probably couldn't even
find my own podcast unless I, uh,
if I didn't do it anyways, we
have a new fan page. Uh, it's,
it's www.thempodcast.com,
www.capital letters,
m,
m p and then all lowercase podcast.com.
Uh,
I explained that bad the MMP or all
capital letters. All right. Fuck you.
Www dot the [inaudible]
podcast.com. Go there. Um,
I definitely think there'll be
some pictures of Leonardo Dicaprio.
I make references to shit. Sometimes
Times people don't know what it is.
The movie that I couldn't
remember the name of.
It's driving you nuts
that will be up there. Uh,
and whatever else I fucking talked about.
And as there's youtube videos
and all that type of shit, um,
of which this week, you know what?
I don't have any youtube videos.
I got to admit I was hardcore studying
for this impossibly difficult, um,
test.
What else do I got?
You want me to move again so we
can have something different?
Where else would I go? I went from
the, the, the, the, the sofa. Well,
I was going to go into another room, but
I'm so paranoid then I'm going to wear,
I got to stand up here for a second.
Maybe it be, I'll be standing up here.
Can you get that?
Can you get that with the camera?
Is this interesting to your people
at all? Oh, here's one for you.
The conspiracy theory. Somebody sent
me something from, uh, from England.
All right.
Because the 14 listeners of my podcast
of I'm going international with my
failure,
um,
was saying that in England they're
actually experimenting with, um,
using satellite to catch speeders
satellite technology to catch speeders.
Can you fucking believe that?
Somewhere in the middle of that,
I just lost all outrage.
I knew I was fucking pissed.
I stood up and I just realized
I was really hungry. That's,
that's one of those things that you get,
you got to understand when you're
starving to death. If you sit down,
it doesn't feel as bad.
You know,
if you ever watch those things when Sally
Struthers back in the day used to be
next to those starving
kids and what we just see,
they were always sitting down or laying
down and you think it's because they're
weak. It isn't. They could stand up if
they wanted to, but you just feel hungry.
There's something about your
pancreas sort of fills up that spot.
Oh fuck you. I know. I don't know
what I'm talking about. Um, all right,
let's skip back to conspiracy theories.
Here's a conspiracy theory.
Somebody sent me this week, somebody sent
me this this week, my podcast in my lap,
low level of radiation going into
my nuts right now. You know what?
They should start,
they should make the bottom like give
you some sort of optional lead suit with
these things.
You know,
I think that would be a great thing
of Billy Mills was still alive.
If you could make like some sort of
cell phone led helmet that comes in like
three different colors,
a manly color color,
a a womanly color,
and then a pattern.
There you go.
And then when it becomes huge,
then you start putting sport logos on it.
Then they do that with the snuggie.
Then you could get like a red skin
snuggie for all those people who get cold
while watching football.
Dude,
I'm telling you man,
that's how I'm going to parachute
out of this fucking business.
I got to come up with some
bullshit and just, you know,
I scream all the time when I do my jokes.
I don't know how,
I don't know if you've
ever noticed this Brian,
but I don't know how to write a joke.
So when I do is I say fuck a lot and I
just scream it, you know? And then the,
the reverb of me yelling, you can't hear
that. There was no laughter afterwards.
So I already know how to
do the Billy Mays thing.
So all we can do is just come
up with some hunk of shit.
Old People, old people.
That's where you got to go.
Do you ever go on the can kill me?
When I went to fucking Dwayne Reed one
time and I saw that booster chair for the
toilet seat, I was just like, fuck,
that's brilliant. Yeah. 20
million later that said, people,
you start in a booster chair and you
ended a booster chair. If you're lucky,
if you don't end in a booster chair,
that means you got hit by a bus
and what would you rather do?
Here's a question for you.
Would you rather get hit by a bus at 42
bang and some of the hot ass hardest ass
on the planet,
you know,
or would you rather live to be
70 boost to chair on the toilet?
You know, I've talked
about this before, right?
Your old balls hanging
in the toilet water.
That's why they have the booster chairs.
So you're nuts on hit the water.
Oh my God.
Is it the eighties again?
So do we fucking booze to cheers.
Um, yeah, this is the podcast. Let's
get onto the next thing. Uh, all right.
That was me giving you a little button
there. This is the podcast and we're out.
All right, conspiracy the week. Bill, you
often talk about conspiracies. Yes I do.
And this may or may not fall into that
category, but it definitely pisses me off.
I love this guy already.
I don't know if this is a conspiracy,
but if fucking pisses me off eyeball to
eyeball with you so far, buddy. All right.
I get my cable and Internet
service bundled together
from Time Warner last month
with my bill,
I got an a in insert stating that they
were modifying their privacy policy.
Basically it states timewarner reserves
the right to distribute my internet
content with or without my consent.
From my understanding,
this could mean anything from the
searches I requested from Google to the
websites I have been to. What rights
do we have in this country anymore?
Just venting. All right,
dude. Yeah, absolutely.
Basically what they've been doing the
entire fucking time since the beginning
of the Internet is now becoming legal.
So for all you people out there
who always thought like, uh,
like I love when you watch like those,
those talk shows and they talk about, um,
sexting like where you're, you're,
you're text messaging, you know,
I'm going to fuck you from
behind whatever. Why that's
sexy. I even though idea,
you know, do you think their
thumbs tremble but whatever,
I'm not going to judge or like they,
they talk about Skype sex and there'll
be like, why do these people do this?
Why would somebody who had never done,
they always bring a psychologists on,
right? And always have a
beard. So you know that they
majored in psychology, right?
And then they go, they always say the
same shit and there'll be just like, well,
it's the, uh, anonymity of
it. They, they feel anonymous.
And, and in that situation,
they, they, they, they,
they do things that they normally
wouldn't done. Well, first of all, people,
it's not anonymous. You had dumb fucks.
It isn't, they just saying it's anonymous.
They just sent it. We don't think
that they're building a file on you.
So all these fucking morons who've lived
the life of the straight and narrow get
on Skype and they stick their junk
right in the camera. You're an idiot.
You're done. You're already
done. Because they, they're,
they're building robots right now
to re to fucking replace all of us.
And what did you then,
but they're going to keep some of
us because somebody got an oil.
They're fucking robot joints.
And what did you do?
You stuck your Dick in the camera
yet you're processed. It's over.
It's over. You got to take the
driver's test. I wouldn't even find,
won't even study.
You're fucking finish.
You're going to get processed just like
those people and that fucking movie with
that guy just died. I can never remember
the name. What's the name of the,
Patrick Swayze was in
it. Blood force. Thunder.
New America. What the fuck
was it called? He'll come.
The Russians pissing the radiator.
All that. All that hatred is gonna.
Gonna gonna eat you up.
Keeps me warm.
Remember that Ed Begley Jr was in
it. No, he wasn't the fucking, uh,
the kid who was in Seoul, man was in
it. And he shot his friend avenge me.
C'Mon Red Dawn. Jesus Christ.
Brian, you're a fucking director.
Do you get that man? When you get let you
live that panic, that brain panic. Okay.
He just got it. Okay, good. I thought it
was only me. Uh, yeah, absolutely. No,
this people,
if you want to watch porn like porn,
the porn industry is fucking is going
through what the music industry is going
through right now where all of a sudden
the shit just became free. All right?
So now everybody's fucking whacking
off on the Internet thinking nobody's
watching what?
You're fucking rubbing your shit out too.
They're all watching and they're
building a fucking file. All right.
You think already,
haven't you noticed why the president's
keep getting worse and worse and they
keep fucking getting on their knees
and blowing the banks more and more?
It's because of the Internet.
All they got to do is break out their
internet file and show him some of the
shit that they know that they jerked
off to. When it's fights over,
it's fucking over.
You got to do everything that they're
gonna say they're gonna exposure.
They don't even need to take you to
Dallas anymore. That's old school.
That's why Kennedy got shot in the head.
If there was an internet,
he'd still be walking
around talking right now,
cutting the ribbon at his fucking library,
shitting his pants.
He wouldn't give the eulogy at Fed
head Ted's fucking funeral. Um,
yeah. So that's, that's what I'm
saying. Okay. If you want to,
if you want to jerk off
to something freaky,
I would say go to a porn store and just
deal with the fact that the guy behind
the counter is going to know what you got.
Pay Cash
and walk away. It's a done deal. But
if you're going to go on the Internet
and do some of the shit that you're doing,
all you can hope now is that you're going
to get lost in the shuffle. Actually.
You can continue to do what you're doing
as long as you never tried to effect.
If you never try to effectively
effect change, you know what I mean?
That's, that's when they break out
your Internet file. Other than that,
it just goes on a fucking database.
But the second you start a movement going,
you know what,
dude,
I'm sick of paying 25 bucks in my
first bag when I get on a plane.
If you get enough people behind you,
United will not go to Time Warner
and be like, yeah, Russell Johnson.
Yeah, open his file. What does he
jerk? What's the most fucked up thing?
He's joking.
That is the end of the movement.
Present Fox News will get
it and they'll just be,
it turns out Russell Johnson jerked
off to a trainee and a magic last week.
This was the guy who is going to
lead us. Oh, don't get me wrong.
I'm doing Glenn Beck.
All right, let me, Oh that
fucking guy. Jesus Christ.
I respect those guys cause they were
in show business. I just wish maybe,
maybe they can't admit that they're
in show business. It's like wrestling.
For the longest time they
couldn't say that it was fake,
but now you know at some point come on,
just say, look, we're doing fake news.
We know, we know who's going to
win. In the end of this shit. Oh No,
it's all horrible. All right, well,
how much time are we up to him?
46 fucking minutes. For those of you
at home, I do 50 minutes every week.
It's a free fucking podcast.
Admitted. You don't like your job.
Maybe you don't like your wife.
Maybe you don't like yourself.
You need a laugh on a Monday. I do this
for free. Out of the goodness of my heart.
See that Brian?
I've been a hero every fucking Monday.
Maybe that's what inspired me.
You know what?
It takes it away that you could tell
that I'm an I'm a piece of shit.
Because if I was a true fucking heroin,
I wouldn't have told you that story.
I wouldn't have brought it up on
the podcast. It's like a heathen.
I'm praying in public right now.
I should have just done some
heroic shit and walked away.
That's when you're bad ass right?
Explosion. You don't even look at it.
That's what I should've done and I didn't.
You know why?
Because I'm a fucking coward and I'm
fucking blown away by the fact that I,
you know, Bill, it was a check you as soon
as funny as she weighed like 70 pounds.
That's the funny thing. But she was
crazy. That's, that's mental steroids.
When you crazy, they can all of a sudden
pick you up. Do the airplane spin like
sergeant slaughter. Did he do
that? He didn't do that. Did he?
He had the fucking Cobra Clutch. All
right, let's wrap this podcast up with um,
the overrated underrated segment and
this segment is people send in stuff that
they feel is overrated or underrated.
They make a list.
I comment on it and hopefully,
hopefully it's hilarious.
I will tell you what his fucking
overrated is buying a God damn shoe rack.
I, you like me or you to the point
where your feet have stopped growing.
You don't throw out your fucking sneakers
and you got 58 of them and you got
shoes and he got boots
and all that type of crap.
I got all of that shit and they were
filling up my fucking closet and I'm like,
all right, I got to get one
of those shoe racks. Okay,
but I need one that can
hold a bunch of shoes.
Don't look at the picture on the outside
of the box because they put fucking
doll shoes on those goddamn racks and
it looks like you can easily fit three,
four pairs of breasts and then you
come home one pair of timberlands and a
fucking flip flop.
And that's a whole level.
Then you can't take it back and
says whole fucking thing annoyed me.
That's overrated.
Overrated is doing that.
Just leave his sneakers on the
fucking floor. You know what?
Why don't you go down to fucking, uh, I
was gonna say Grossman's go down to uh,
the, the, the Home Depot and build
your own shoe rack for a fucking adult.
I'm literally sweating in my
own apartment here. Might me,
am I going to be sweaty on the podcast?
The Comey.
Who is that cruises guy for those
people at home? Huh? Who is that guy?
Remember that coach?
I don't remember his coach either,
but he coached the team out in Vegas.
Some of the teeth.
It was like an old Elmer Fudd like
if Elmer Fudd Fuck Don Zimmer.
That's what he looked like. Jesus.
That was insulting. All right,
here's one from somebody underrated.
Uh, Quincy, the show, Quincy,
the Fonz and Sam Malone.
Get all the credit for getting the ladies.
But Quincy got just as
much as any of them.
It seemed like he had a different chicken
is on his houseboat. Every episode.
He was basically a silent assassin.
The best part of it is that he used
the word broad to refer to the ladies.
Those were different times. They
really were. They really were.
Jack Klugman is Quincy. That was
like a, that was the end of an era.
Remember that Brian, he ever hit me
like Yo, when we were growing up,
they take the casting couch when guys
ran this fucking business and now look,
you know what's funny is they thought if,
if they, if the ladies, if they ran it,
that there would be, it would be better,
but it isn't. It's just is unbalanced.
The other fucking direction.
Now you've got a bunch of pussies on TV
who are afraid of their wives. You know,
Ralph Kramden used to
threatened every week.
That's what I loved about
that show because they still
showed them being a moron,
but he's still physically intimidator,
you know, like Larry Johnson,
he had that power forward respect on
that show. That's all I'm looking for.
Just show a guy in a relationship was
getting a little bit of fucking respect,
you know? All right, I'm
going over my time here.
The last thing we're going to talk
about his bad covers. I talk last week,
uh, somebody, Mary j
Blige did a cover of a,
a stairway to heaven and a whole
lot of love and it wasn't bad,
but you know what I mean? I Dunno. It's
just one of those things where this some,
some music, it's just
sacred. It's sacred to you.
So no matter how talented somebody
is, uh, you're like, what the fuck?
So I was talking to last really bad cover
that I heard that it just really just
annoyed the shit on me.
Well,
actually I was in a gym and
somebody had remixed Ah, Shit.
Did the remix of a sympathy for
the devil by the rolling stones.
You know, and I'm gonna go out on a
limb. I think Mick Keith and the guy,
I think they got it right the first
fucking time. These fucking assholes,
first of all, first thing they do is
they edit out the guitar solo. Okay?
Take Keith Guitar Solo out.
And then at one point literally
dropped out everything other than Mick,
Mick Jagger's voice,
and then had some new updated like,
like a Casio drum beat
underneath it. It was just, ah,
it's just a fucking worst Scott Damn
Song I've ever heard. Jesus Christ bill.
How did I not make that funny? I really
bombed with that. Like I started off,
it was decent. I got lost in the middle
of it, you know, I got freaked out.
I was like, what if Mary j
actually buys this fucking DVD?
I went to that arrogance space.
You know what it was.
You know what happened there,
Brian? I cared. I cared,
and the whole fucking thing went away. All
right, let's see. Hit last bad cover. Um,
this here's one from somebody,
and I know this, this, this, this.
Actually the segment
is starting to blow up.
I just didn't have time to
put everybody, so don't, uh,
everybody's bad covers on there.
I want to read these because you guys
really came up with some great ones this
week. Um, here's when he says, all right,
this,
the cover,
the cover song that pissed me off the
most has to be slash in Fergie's slash in
Fergie from the black ips featuring
that dude from Cypress Hill there they
actually redid paradise city.
And uh,
right there I was immediately
going, oh no, oh no.
And he says all that energy and
swagger on the of the original,
everything that made that song a bonafide
classic is ruined in this version.
Anyone that really holds up slash is a
god and trashes axel cannot honestly sit
there and tell me that this song does
more to ruin guns and roses name than the
Chinese democracy. What a
horrible, infuriating idea.
Please, please give this song. That's the
treatment it deserves on your podcast.
I got to admit,
I am a fucking huge is how big a fan of
I am of slash like I was right with them
slash a snake pit. I saw velvet
revolver, anything he does,
I will go fucking see.
I remember I saw Joe Perry project and
he showed up and he played with the band.
It was fucking awesome.
I love slash but I got to tell you this
one that I'm not trashing slash year
because even Dinero has made some bad
fucking movies. But uh, here it is.
You guys want to hear a little,
I'll,
I'll play just a little bit of this and
I'm actually not worry about slash thing
this cause we won't have the rights to
play this on the DVD. So here you go. Um,
I think it's been a really
nice podcast this week. Um,
and you should appreciate it.
Especially a free podcast
from a hero such as myself.
I just like saying it. It's so fucking
annoying. Hey, what do you do? Well,
I'm a comedian and also I'm a hero.
I'm a fucking hero.
Uh,
as long as they're crazy women and
they weigh less than 70 pounds,
I am right there to do my duty as,
as, as a, as a standup citizen.
So here it is everybody.
Everybody have a great week.
Thanks for listening to the podcast
and we're going to close out with the
Paradise City 2.0, I'll play
a little bit of this shit. Uh,
this is slash Fergie from the black eyed
peas and that guy from Cypress Hill,
you know the, the fucking trio that
we've all been waiting for for years.
They finally came together and
here's what it sounds like,
dude. What the fuck are
ready? What the fuck already?
[inaudible]
right here. You going? Okay,
maybe they're going to save it.
Maybe they're going to save it.
Ah, AH, no. Oh my God. Oh my God.
Oh my God, Dude. You ever get like
fucking embarrassed for somebody else?
What the fuck? You know? Hey, I hate,
I can't see why to rappers always have
to let you know who the fuck is in the
building. I can read the liner
notes. We'd go at slaves in the, Ha.
I know he wrote it.
The Duchess Fergie. Ah,
that, that, that is, yeah.
That one didn't bug me as
much as led Zeppelin. I have
to admit like, cause when,
when guns and roses,
when they came out,
I was like 1920 already realized I
could see myself becoming a loser.
It's sent music that you love
when you had hope, you know,
speaking of which is one for my,
my child.
Did I hope for a speedy recover for
our Bret Michaels man. Seriously, man,
I know a lot of people, uh, may,
may or may not like fucking poison,
whatever you've got to hand to the guy
that he stuck around for 25 fucking years
and dies in the hospital right
now. So I hope that guy, uh,
comes out better than fucking
ever. And uh, that's it.
See, that's what a hero does.
He brings it around to a
nice moment. That's the, uh,
that's a podcast for this week. Please
tune in next week. Please keep all the,
um, the questions, comments and all that
stuff coming. I really appreciate it.
Have a great week and a,
that's it. Take it easy.