Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burr and
yeah,
just checking in on your hair on a
Thursday afternoon, just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
What's going on? How are Ya?
Don't I sound chipper today?
You know why?
Cause I go to the gym every day.
It's just become a pop me life.
Yeah.
Well you go to that gym every day.
You can't.
We really mean it.
Um,
actually I've just been eating
right and a oh Billy Bush face,
you know, read it booze bag. I haven't
drank in four days and I feel great.
You know why? Because it's the
morning when you don't drink.
You feel great in the
morning when you don't drink,
you feel horrific at night.
You can hear the fucking clock ticking.
And me just trying to fall asleep.
I almost picked up a book last night.
Anything to get me to fall
asleep and I'll tell you nothing.
Nothing makes me fall asleep.
Like reading a book.
I don't know how these fucking nerds do
it big and just sit there all God damn
day reading a book.
He's fucking idiots.
So jump on a God damn a unicycle and
they're still reading the book. Now,
unicycle a on an elliptical.
There you go. One of those,
one of those things where your
legs are moving but you're not.
Okay.
Well, technically you are, but you're
not going anywhere. It's a metaphor.
Um,
life is like an elliptical machine.
It goes round and round. But do
you ever get anywhere? You know,
next thing you know there's some fucking
nerd with glasses blowing you and
you're like, you know what? I
liked this life of being a poet.
I needs an itchy sweater and let his
beard grow out and I think I got something
going on here. Um, yeah, so I
haven't drank in like four days.
I am. I'm on the wagon. All
right. I've got the Montreal
comedy festival coming up.
That's going to be a tough one.
I'm not going to lie to you.
That is going to be a tough one.
Being up there with all my buddies telling
a little knock knock who's there over
there and a, not drinking afterwards,
but I can get through it, you know? Um,
I had one cigar this week only
because I had one leftover from, um,
from my July 4th cookout that I had.
And it was so,
there was so fucking amazing. I
had to, uh, I had to smoke it.
I couldn't fucking throw it out.
It's,
I don't even know how to say the name
of this fucking thing. Let's see.
Okay.
It looks like Hotman or h up man,
I can't tell.
Does it looks like there's a little dot
there. My eyes are going here. Havana,
Cuba. Um, this fucking cigar
was one of those cigars.
As I was lighting it, I was lighting
the thing and did the first couple of,
you know, to get it going.
And I went, oh my God.
I was by myself sitting on my
front porch and I said out loud,
oh my God,
to nobody.
You had already tasted like the
middle of the cigar on a great cigar.
And that was me just lighting
it. And um, I sat out there,
no booze actually, like
something sweet, you know,
with my cigar.
I'm not one of those guys and wants
to have a smokey whiskey with it.
It's like redundant. You're already got
smoke in your mouth and you got dad.
And sometimes I don't mind it,
but I like something sweet with my cigar,
which is why I usually hang out with Joe
to Rosa when I smoke. Hey, thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. There you go.
That right there. That was a singer.
Well,
my old buddy Joe Rosa Joe's
got a little sugar in his tank.
He can't help it.
Um,
anyways. Um, so anyways, uh,
I been working out and I already
knocked off a couple of pounds.
First day I had to weigh in, you
know, the big before picture,
I went up there like a fucking hairless
seal and albino seal. Just, I didn't even,
I couldn't even move
my legs at that point.
Just I just fucking went up on a scale,
you know,
and a one 86.6,
which wasn't bad because I
was pushing one 90. And uh,
I got on the scale this morning. I was
a buck 84.6. I dropped a couple pounds.
The first week is always easy because
your body is so used to you just be enough
such a cunt,
you know,
drinking whiskey while ordering cake
and all of a sudden if you just have one
bowl of oatmeal,
it's such a shock to your system that
you'll actually drop a couple pounds.
Unfortunately after a week
they like a bodies just like,
oh so this is the new gang,
this is the new game.
Because you're thinking like well shit,
I'm going to drop two pounds
every four days. I'll be,
I'll be in shape by August 1st and then
what happens to another six days goes by
and your lost like half a pound,
you know?
And that's when you got to man up and not
become depressed and bury your face in
a bag of Cheetos.
So many ways.
So I'm just bringing all of
this shit up to you guys.
So you guys will be checking in on me
the way I check in on you. You know?
Yeah.
Cause if I get off it,
you know,
I'm going to get off it cause I won't
talk about it in more than you'd be like,
Hey, you'd have fat
face. What's the matter?
Joe Matters at scale going in
the wrong direction there. Um,
I actually did a spot at the
comedy store the other night.
I had a great time and I came home,
I hadn't looked at my Twitter
account a couple of days. Um,
and I went on there and somebody said
that they were there and they could tell I
was drinking. They said I was a
fat fuck. I'm not gonna lie to you.
It really hurt. And I said
it to Nia. She goes, oh,
that's me and why would they do that?
I got, you don't have to do me a favor.
Do me a favor.
Came from a place of love.
And even if it came from a place of hate,
it probably just has to do with the
fact that they don't like their dad some
shit or they get beaten in gym class.
I don't know what it is.
Or maybe I said something that
they don't like. Um, so anyways,
speaking of stand up, that was
fucking brutal. What happened?
Amy Schumer watching them go after her
about a joke two years and she told the
joke two fucking years ago.
How'd he tell a joke?
And it takes somebody two years
to get fucking offended by it.
You know what I mean?
I don't, I don't fucking understand
that. Two weeks for two fucking years.
It's not a fee. Why all of a
sudden is it? Oh, that's right.
That's right.
She has a giant movie coming out.
This is a critical part of her career
going from a comedian TV star to now movie
star. Like that movie's gonna. You can
see some, some of you just know like,
I don't want to jinx it,
but that in that movie looks like
it's going to be a smash. Right?
So these fucking cops, they know
that that day you go, there you go,
you got something to lose and then they
go in and they bullied you as just the
fucking worse,
you know?
Okay.
As just a fucking worst.
And then you get,
you got to apologize for something
you fucking said to. And then, yeah,
there's this dead shirk off in
the Washington Post is like,
and I know it's a joke, but like that
doesn't, it doesn't matter. It's like,
yeah it does.
It completely fucking matters.
It told the totally fucking matters.
Like there's no difference between
actually meaning it and joking around like
what world do you fucking live?
And I'm just beside myself with that
thought process and this does this
fictional power that they
think comedians have.
Like as if somebody walks in
to a comedy show, not racist.
And then they sit down and then
they hear a joke and then the like,
oh wait a minute,
now I'm racist.
You know, or our, or vice versa.
They walk in racist and then you say
something and then you have the ability to
change their fucking minds to
not be racist. If comedians
really had that power,
what we did would be fucking illegal.
Okay.
Because the government wouldn't
stand for it. They wouldn't have,
you couldn't fucking have that kind of
power can imagine if you just walked on
stage. And just said, Shit. And then
people just went out and did it and they,
and they completely changed for the
rest of their life. That's it. Hey,
you guys got to start eating right.
Do still do some sit ups and get yourself
a six pack and everybody in the crowd
just okay.
And gets up and does it.
Okay?
It's ridiculous.
People are going out to a comedy
club to just blow off some steam,
have a good time, have a couple
of drinks and laugh. All right?
And if you don't like a joke,
you don't like a joke,
but the comic doesn't owe you a
fucking apology. You know what I mean?
You just didn't like that joke.
And it is a joke despite how you took it.
So go fuck yourself and comedians.
Stop apologizing. Please.
For the love of fucking God.
Stop fucking apologizing because all
you're doing is you're just building up
these, these paper tigers. Um,
this is unreal. This is like,
it's like, it's like, I thought we
already went through all this Lenny Bruce,
George Carlin getting arrested. Shit
are we hadn't back towards it. Is
that what's going to
happen? I don't know. Um,
anyways, I'm thinking about the shit
that I say on this fucking podcast. Huh?
How come nobody ever gets offended
by this shit? You know why?
Cause I don't have a movie
coming out.
That is the genius. That is the
genius of being under the radar.
You're not going to get any traction
getting offended by me. You got to wait.
I got that F for fair. I'm predicting
right now thatF is for family.
When that shit comes out,
somebody is going to be like in a
podcast in 2010 but only if it's a hit.
It's a hit show. Um, fucking ridiculous.
It doesn't matter if it's a joke or not.
It doesn't matter if you were serious
or not. Oh, okay. Is that, how,
is that how the world works? A lot of
these people that complain about that,
especially the racial jokes, I,
they just reek of people that like,
you really just only hang out
with people in your culdesac
because anybody who has like,
like a wide variety of friends,
this shit that we say to each other about
each other's races and nationalities
and it's fucking hilarious.
Like you totally joke a joke
around about food stereotypes,
all of that shit all the
fucking time these people do.
They just have like a list of
fucking words like gauge wire, Doral.
Good Dave lives. I'll bet. All right.
They'll shut the fuck up. We get it. Okay.
All right, cool. So anyways, I um,
I had a fucking, I had to go to
the doctor this week, right? Um,
he has been getting on me. I
got in in my, my leg, I got a,
I get this varicose vein on my calf.
It's not bugging me or anything,
but it's starting to look a little gnarly,
you know what I mean? And she goes,
why don't you have somebody to
go down and take a look at it?
It's like I might have somebody cut
out my fucking leg. And she goes, no,
they just inject something
in there. Fucking, you know,
the vein collapses and you're good. So
I go, ah, fuck it. I'll go down there.
So I call up these
people to one 800 number.
They got like 12 different fucking
locations around the country. I'm like,
it already doesn't seem reputable to me.
So I called them up and they're like,
yeah, you know, blood. And they go, what's
your name? Where do you live? And I go,
why do you need to know where I live?
I don't want you to know where I live.
I'm going down there. Well, we need to
know for the billing of insurance. I go,
I have shitty insurance. I don't
have good insurance. All right,
I know I'm going to give you my
insurance card. You're going to say,
we don't take that and then I'm
going to have to pay for it.
So I'm just going to pay cash.
Why do you need to know where I live?
And she goes, because that's how we,
that's part of our policy. And I go, why?
She goes, I just told you
why I go, no you didn't.
You just said it's part of your policy.
I want to know why that's part of
your policy. She just kept going.
I just told you why I go,
no you didn't.
So finally she gets her fucking
supervisor and now we need,
we need an address. So you know what
I did? I just gave him a fake address,
which is what I'm doing from now on.
Just give him a fake address.
Okay.
I gave it to him and then go down there.
I show up at the doctor's
office and they never said, hey,
your address didn't check out.
They didn't. So now it's great too.
I got that misinformation out there
about where I might, where I live,
but when they go to sell it
to some other corporation.
So I walk in there and you know,
uh, there's two, two ladies on the phone,
uh, one young. And what about in her
thirties? The young ones got like jeans,
like ripped jeans on and
stuff like that. And, um,
you know,
I walk up,
so I walk up and there's two fucking
clipboards to sign in and they're both on
the phone. So I just signed it on the one
in front of the ripped jeans go, right?
So I go and I sit down and
she gets off the phone,
she looks at me and then she goes with
their index finger, like, come here.
You know what I mean? And I
stand up and then I'm like, wait,
did she use summons me over like a fucking
toddler? And I walk up and she goes,
do you have an appointment?
And I'm like, yeah. She goes,
what's your name? I'm like,
William Barr. She goes, Oh, you must
be at the other office. And she,
and she points to the lady next to me.
She goes, we're two separate offices.
And I go, all right. So
then I talked to the,
the 35 year old chick and meanwhile this,
this,
the young girl gets on the
phone, she picks up, she's like,
where the hell are you
guys? God, I'm starving.
Are you going there right now?
I'm going to kick your ass like
this isn't like a medical office.
So they tell me to fill out the whole
form. I start filling out the form,
then they go, we need to see your driver's
license. I go for what? They go, well,
we need to make a copy of it. I go, no,
you're not making a copy of my driver's
license. You can look at it. Here it is.
Here's my face. But you're not, you're not
taking, you're not making a copy of it.
And just, she goes, well that's
what we do. I go, what do you,
and what do you do with the copy? And
she goes, it stays here in the office.
I said, yeah, I'm not doing that.
Okay.
And I go, why do you need a copy? I
don't understand why. So she goes,
let me check with my manager and she can,
you know,
and then she comes back and said, yeah,
we need a copy of your driver's license.
You never needed this shit beforehand.
By the way, all these fucking, uh,
slowly moving us towards
micro chips are everywhere.
I go in and see your papers please. And
everybody's got to know fucking, you know,
like give you my driver's license,
my fucking driver's license number
on it and shit, go fuck yourself.
Yeah.
Fucking a steer in a strip mall.
I'm not giving you a fucking copy of my
driver's license. So anyway, she says,
yeah, I just talked to my boss. He says,
we need a copy of your driver's license.
So I go, why? And then the, the
little fucking half a cutie pie,
they're fucking chimes in.
She goes,
cause it Blahblahblahblahblah and I just
look at her and go, you don't work here.
She put her head down and mumbled
something. It just fucking made my day.
There's nothing than one is six thinks
she's a 10 she was such a fucking dope.
I'm not going to lie to you.
She was cute,
but she thought she was the
fucking shit and she wasn't.
There's just the way she was talking
on the phone, how she was like,
so over the fucking job.
It's like you're a fucking dope.
You're a fucking dope. I don't know who
you know that gave you this fucking job,
but I've been in for six minutes and
you suck at it. You fucking suck at it.
So anyways, so I got all, I'd say you
need a cop. My driver's license. I go,
I find to go give me the clipboard.
So I,
I take the clipboard with
all the information I wrote
down and I just fucking
folded it up and I just walked out.
I should've said no dirty looks cause
I know that fucking little Twat was
probably given me a dirty look.
But that's the fucking, you know,
sitting here having this,
this fucking dope Curson into the God
damn telephone and then I'm going to be,
I'm comfortable with you
injecting something into my body.
Can't the fuck outta here it,
the whole thing just felt shady.
You know when I first got there,
there was this fucking guy
from like Transylvania came,
he came out with just like a tee
shirt on and I'm looking like,
is this fucking guy? Is this the doctor
that this guy just fix the radiator?
Then I found out he was a fucking
patient. And, uh, I dunno,
just still his whole vibe.
It looked like they were back
there doing experiments on them.
I just didn't like it. And you know, it
was, it was next, it was in this one.
I was fucking strip malls where it's like,
hey varicose veins,
you want your taxes done.
You know,
and then some Asian thing
that makes noodles, it's like,
I'm gonna have something medical procedure
here. I'm not doing this shit. So, uh,
my, you know what my gut was screaming at
me the second I walked in there, but, um,
I dunno.
I Dunno.
I fucking was laughing the whole
way out to my truck that go,
Eh, it's because of blah, blah, blah.
I'm like, Hey, you don't work here.
She had to put her head down and then
she mumbled something trying to pull
victory out of that fucking
devastating defeat. Who's kidding? Who,
it wasn't devastating to her.
He's probably wind development.
Somebody bought her a new iPhone,
you know,
cause they think that they're going
to fuck her, you know. Anyways,
I was actually telling a buddy
of mine that he was going, man,
I hope my daughter doesn't
end up like that. And I said,
now you already would have sought,
she's three years old.
You can tell if a kid's going to be a
dope or not by the time they're three,
you know,
I'm not saying you can't,
you can't tell if they're
going to be on drugs.
So make a bad choice in that teens.
But you can tell whether or not you
actually got somebody who got the a brain.
You know, and I'm not talking fucking
Einstein, I'm just saying like, you know,
they're on point, they're talking
to you, they're locked in,
you're giving them information,
they're processing it, you know,
and then he got to be brave.
Those almost smart people,
they're the funniest people because they
on some way they kind of know that dumb,
you know, cause straight up dumb
people don't know that dumb.
They just always think that
they're getting fucked,
which is why they have that
dumb look on their face.
That's why their jaws always hanging open
and their brows kind of furrowed cause
they can't figure out what
the fuck happened. You know?
But somebody gets to be brain.
They actually know that they're kind
of dumb and you see them catching
themselves and they'd look
around the table like, wow,
did anybody just catch that?
And there's an intelligence in that and
that's why I grade them as a B right at
right now you guys should
be sitting there going pill.
We obviously know that you actually are
so fucking arrogant that you think that
you got the a brain,
which right there immediately knock,
shoot down to at least a B.
Because anybody who's truly
intelligent doesn't think they are.
They think they're a fucking moron. I
was got lost in all of that. Anyways,
speaking of being a fucking moron,
did you see what Jason Pierre Paul did?
And God knows,
I know even with nine fingers, this
guy could still throw me over my house,
but what? What the fuck?
What the fuck are you doing?
What will you lighten off
that blew off your finger?
I don't understand people that like
it's the 4th of July. I get it.
A couple of bottle rockets have
a Roman candle fight, you know,
put on some goggles. I get it a little
grab ass with some fireworks who gives us,
but these people who like fucking
go to like military grade shit.
You know what I mean?
What the fuck did you light off
that you made the decision that you
know what, just amputate my finger.
I got to get back out on the field now.
My God,
that's a bad finger to fucking lose to.
That's second in command to the thumb.
Like the thumbs, the headliner,
the index finger, right.
That's the feature act.
Okay.
I'd say the Middle Finger is the host
and then your ring finger and you're a
pinky or doing guest spots.
Right. They're not getting paid.
They're doing guest spots. Right. Um,
anyways, so he blew off.
There's no feature act anymore.
So now he basically has like a,
like a lobster claw in our lobster
cloud would be if they were all fucking
together.
I don't know man.
But all I know is he had three options
with the finger and one of them was
amputated. And uh, I mean,
hey, I like playing football.
I liked when I was a kid, but you
know, I like playing drums too,
but I would never hit, I'd be like, you
know what, why don't we wait a minute?
So this fucking thing on,
you know,
see how it goes before I just
said, you know what? Fuck it.
Yeah,
no, it's gotta be funny as his custom
gloves they have to make during the winter
time, those four fingered once he's got
like a Bart Simpson and now you know,
cause animation, they always
had those things. I don't know.
Why am I joking about
something so horrific? I just,
you know what it is just because he
just made the decision to say fuck it.
Just cut the fucking thing off the,
granted it has like most people
when it comes to this story,
I have absolutely no information
other than, you know,
somebody texted me and said Jpp
had his index finger amputated.
Um,
okay.
I Dunno.
All I know is that every NFL contract
from here on out now has that word.
It's somewhere in there.
If they didn't already,
I know you're not allowed
to ride a motorcycle.
I don't think fly a private fly yourself
to get a pilot's license or something.
You're not allowed to do any of that shit.
Probably you have to Larry Bird.
If it taller than six,
six,
you're not allowed to blacktop
your parents fucking driveway. Um,
I dunno. What the fuck. You know
what's funny about the giants?
They can beat the fucking patriots,
but Jesus Christ, they give,
they can't get to a fucking off season
without just somebody doing something.
Right. I was just talking to [inaudible]
about that. He goes, Jesus Christ,
you know, the fucking shooting
themselves in the legs.
Fucking cut in their face off.
But I'll tell you when it cops,
they beat them patriots.
Eh, uh, you know what?
I don't give a shit because we want our
fourth and I'll take four out of six.
I'll take two losses to the giants
for four or six. And speaking of that,
speaking of giants fans,
I'm doing Rappaport's.
I am Rappaport's podcast tomorrow and I'm
expecting that's sad sack New York fan
to come strong with the giants shit talk,
which should be great. It's like, yeah,
but then we want another one, Michael,
that we want another one. We've won four.
Okay.
Since 2000 since February of
2002 we've won four super bowls.
We have won the most super bowls
out of any team in the NFL.
So I will take those to crushing
losses to the giants to win four.
I will make that trade
any day of the week.
And then to add three world series Stanley
Cup and an NBA championship doing all
Anna for soccer championship to evidently,
what do we the Boston fucking tea parties.
I don't know what the hell we are.
The liberty.
Oh that's a fucking WNB 18 I have no idea.
Right.
Okay.
We, we one in five different sports. Ah.
I mean I'm gonna hit him with the
same shit. She'd be like, Michael,
you have 10 teams in New York City.
You guys cannot find in any combination
attended when all four in 10 years.
You just have not been able to do it ever.
It's fucking pathetic.
How many teams do you need to
stay in step with title town,
Boston, Massachusetts.
Um, that right there,
that's a one sided.
That's a one sided. Uh,
okay.
Idea of what the fuck that they're going
to then I'm going to be talking about
on his podcast.
I'm also been playing a bunch of drums.
I'm getting ready for a,
I'm doing the Goddamn comedy jam
up the Montreal Comedy Festival.
I'm going to be doing it three nights
Monday, Tuesday and Thursday. Um,
I think the 20th,
21st and 23rd I'll be doing it.
And so I've been playing a lot of drums
and uh, just having a fucking great time.
Just a great time. I could basically,
man, I have my summer, you know,
after all the traveling I
did crisscross in the land.
I got like the summer off from what I'm
trying to do is not fill up every day
with activities. Uh, cause
that's what I ended up doing.
And then it ends up being
unbelievably stressful. I
mean, I don't have it off off.
I get a fucking punch up.
All these episodes of F is for family
and I got to tell you to do it.
It's coming together.
It's coming together and I've been
watching a lot of animation, Lotta Gotcha.
Bob's burgers. Um, what else did I watch?
Those chickens that smoke weed.
Um,
and I'm not even listening to the jokes.
I'm looking at the movements because,
you know,
they always give you the lowest fucking
budget ever when it comes to animation.
So I'm trying to fucking, uh, see
how with the limited movement,
like on Archer, if you look at it, they
really don't move that much, but you know,
they just have the eyebrows going up,
coming down. I squinting, you know,
and an occasional fucking hand
movement. Um, so I'll be doing that,
but still that will feel like a vacation
as opposed to fucking flying all around.
Oh, by the way, did you guys
check out rolling stone this, uh,
this week or whatever?
Um,
Kim Kardashians tits and Kim
Kardashians are on the cover and a,
they got an article in there about
this guy who all he does is fly around.
That's all he does. He has
not had a home. I don't know.
I don't even get it.
He's been in the air since August in the
air or at an airport waiting to connect
since April of last year.
You know,
he'll still spend the night at like a
five star hotel and then go right back to
the airport. And, uh,
he's sitting there saying how like
he learned how to work the system.
There's all these ins and outs
and all that type of stuff.
It's a really fascinating story because
immediately I'm like going like, dude,
who's getting fucked in this deal?
You're not really living a life.
But he turned it into a business where
everybody gets advice from him now and
now he's allegedly a millionaire.
So I think that sacrifice,
he was able to do it,
but it's a really, um, really interesting.
I just don't understand it.
Like this fucking guy,
like he set the record crossing the
Pacific Ocean like six times in like,
I don't know how many days that can't
be healthy, cannot be fucking healthy.
But you know, he flies like, you know
those double decker, uh, air buses,
they have this,
this thing where you get your own
apartment on one of them and one of the
Singapore Airlines was the first one that,
that had it.
And the ticket is $15,000 and
this dude has so many miles.
He gets it by himself and he's sitting
there acting like he's winning.
But it's just like,
dude,
but you just lit even
that's cool in the air.
But if you had that as an apartment,
you'd be like, this fucking sucks.
I can't even breathe in here.
Not to mention there's a camera
on me at all fucking times,
making sure I don't one out of
fucks something in this bed. Right?
If you had that on the ground,
you'd be like, this is fucked up.
You have it in the air.
You think this is the shit.
But if all you're doing is living
in the air, like I don't know,
but in the end if he was a millionaire
and he enjoyed it, I don't know,
check out the article.
It's really a really fucking interesting.
So we're winding down here on the podcast.
Uh,
I need you guys to help
me out if you could.
I'm looking for a car and a Craiglist
seems to be the best way to do it.
Um, I've pretty much
checked all of California.
I'm looking for a 65 or 66 Ford galaxy
in Wimbledon white and all I'm looking
for, uh, is that it has a straight body,
not all rusted out,
none of that shit.
The body's straight and
the interior is solid,
doesn't even have to be meant as long
as it's solid. It looks like, you know,
most everything is there and then either
no engine or a non original engine,
cause I just can't get myself to take
the original numbers matching engine out
of a car. I just can't fucking do
it. Um, that's what I'm looking for.
I thought you could do a
nationwide search on, um,
on craigslist, but you can't,
you got to go state by state.
So if you live in a state,
check it out. Um, you know,
if he got time, if you don't,
I understand. But that's what I'm
looking for and just tweet at me.
Send me the links if you find one.
Um,
cause that's what I'm looking for.
I've got my truck back in, you know,
like I said, they, they
rebuilt the whole engine,
painted the thing that Ford blue and
it's running like a top and the power
steering just came in and then waiting
on the air conditioning and the slap that
fucking thing on. And uh,
that's gonna be my daily driver.
I've been driving it all over the place.
I absolutely fucking love that truck.
And uh, and only want to do is just
get a 65 Ford galaxy and you know,
Redo that thing.
What I want to do is I want to have the
underneath be 2015 and then up top in
1965 and just be able to drive that
thing across country if I wanted to.
Um, cause I only got three gears in my
truck. I mean I could've switched it out,
made it an automatic or even
just had a five speed put in,
but I just feel like shifted
on the columns to fucking cool.
So when I get on the highway I just
drive it like a granny and when the first
lane going like 50 miles an hour
build, no one gives a fuck. Well I do,
I give a fuck. So anyways, um,
I'm still waiting for the advertising
to come in here. Huh? What am I up to?
29 minutes. That's it. That's
my little fucking half hour.
My little 30 minutes here with the
Oh, he is the reeds. They came in.
It came in.
What do we got you one is a physio funnies
part of the podcast where I fucking
read out loud. All right.
Blue Apron. It's okay.
You can admit it.
Everybody.
The last thing anyone wants to do after
work is waiting in line at the grocery
store,
Schlep home and cook a complicated meal.
Uh, and expensive, unhealthy
takeout is hardly better.
That's where the new
service blue apron comes in.
Blue Apron delivers farm fresh ingredients
and step by step recipes to your home,
allowing you to create healthy,
handcrafted meals at home without
going to the grocery store. Uh,
for less than $10 per meal.
Blue Apron sends you fresh ingredients,
perfectly proportioned, making, cooking
healthy meals, really easy and fun.
No trips to the grocery store and
no waste from unused ingredients.
Plus you're learning to cook with special
ingredients that are normally hard to
find. Blue Apron is the perf
is perfect for date night,
not if she hears this copy,
you spend $8 on me and you already
got her home. Guys, this is the shit.
Don't tell the ladies a blue
apron is perfect for a day.
Cooking with friends and they even
offer a family plans with kid friendly
ingredients so the whole family can eat
well and have fun preparing the meals
together. Each balance meal is 500 to 700
calories. Jesus Christ, I could use this,
um, per serving and so tasty. You'd
never know. That's a red flag.
How is it 500 to 700 calories and
it's so tasty. How is it so tasty?
You're loading it up with sugar and salt.
I'm cooking takes half an hour.
Shipping is flexible and free and
the menus are always news. News, new.
They won't send the same meal twice.
What the,
they must in the same meal twice.
So if I do a 30 days in a fucking row,
what am I eating at that point?
And um,
they work around your schedule and dietary
preferences and blue aprons experts
source only the best seasonal ingredients
for incredible meals like chicken with
lemon sugar, snap peas,
men and Chai potatoes.
I hate saying the names of food. Potatoes
with Spring onion, hash in Indian,
curried Zucchini with lentil salad
and Cherry town Chutney Chutney.
I don't know what it is.
What am I here?
The waitress or the waiter start
saying the specials. It's like,
will you stop fucking saying that shit?
We'd heavy Asian infused. Just
don't get me some chicken. Uh,
you'll cook incredible meals and be blown
away by the quality and freshness of
Blue Apron. It's a better
way to cook. Check it out.
Check out this week's menu and get your
first two meals for free. Oh my God.
You're like a broad here.
You're getting a couple of free meals and
you don't have to do anything by going
to blue apron.com/bar my treat. It's
not my treat. It's their treat. Really.
The first two meals are on blue apron.
When you go to blue
apron.com/burr waiting,
there's no obligations.
Oh my God. Hey guys,
you want to feel like a woman dating.
Why did you for a couple of days,
couple of meals. Here you go. Um,
except nothing tries to fuck you.
So that's the rub. So on a lot of
ways, don't they deserve a free meal?
I think that was progressive. Alright,
draft draftkings everybody. Uh,
baseball is in full swing.
You can be part of the action right there
all seasonLong@draft.com the official
daily fantasy,
pun of major league baseball.
Daily fantasy means no season long
commitments, just instant cash.
Instant gratification.
Hey,
why wait until the end of the season
to get paid when you can win right now,
you can win huge prizes every day at
draftkings. It's like a brand new season.
Every time you play, just pick
two pitchers, a position players,
and pick up your cash.
That's it.
Ask Peter a as Peter from Colorado.
How do we do that?
I'll do we ask him,
okay,
what the fuck? Draft King, how
do I ask Peter From Colorado?
Okay,
he's not here,
but now you just going to say,
last year we won $1 million
in one day. Peter, who?
What is his number?
Simply by playing fantasy baseball at
draftkings have hundreds of thousands of
fantasy sports fans just like you.
I've already cashed in at draft kings
and a hundreds of thousands of others,
probably twice that number have lost.
Always remember that.
So I don't bet more than you can
afford to lose. Now it's your turn.
Call to action.
New contestants start daily.
So I that draft kings.nah.com right
now and how they use the Promo Code
[inaudible] Frey Ted Day $10,000
fantasy baseball contest.
draftkings.com official partner of
major league baseball. That's hilarious.
It's bad if Pete rose does it,
but it's okay if you sitting in the place.
Just uh,
enter defense for free entry now.
draftkings.com draftkings.com
to be annoying.
That's the third time draft
kings.com and finally Mile Iq.
Driving for work is double
is a double edge sword.
Either you're spending too
much time tracking every
mile or you're guesstimating
and end up losing money. I you be honest,
you, I have no idea what this is about.
And even then your estimate fought fails
about 20% falls about 20% short of what
you could be the ducting.
Welcome to Mile Iq,
the gold standard in mileage tracking
all this for truckers. There's for them.
Good old boys out there
delivering the Mac and cheese.
Mile Queue is the only mileage tracker
that detects logs and calculates your
drive for you automatically.
Mile Iq is easy to use and keeps all
your drive securely stored in the cloud.
If you drive for work and you're
not counting every single mile,
then you're burning money every
time you turn on the ignition.
Mile Iq does all the work letting
you focus on what's important.
That's why they've got a five star rating
in both the Google play and the iTunes
APP stores. Stop wasting time manually
tracking your miles and slapped.
Stop using money.
You should be redeeming.
Try Mile Iq for free today
by text and Burp Bay.
You are are.
Okay.
I had to spell that out cause truckers
bar lug bee are gimme a bar. No burpee.
You are R two eight nine eight zero zero
that's burr two eight nine eight zero
zero that's for all the truckers out
there. I always forgot. You know,
maybe truckers do listen to this shit.
I have no idea.
I remember back in the day when I did
the OPN Anthony show on XM satellite
radio,
they used to have a bunch of truckers
that listens. All right? So anyways,
that is the podcast.
Get yourself a free couple of meals at
the Blue Bonnet bowl or whatever the fuck
they are. Blue Apron, don't
blow your fingers off, you know,
and uh, whatever the fuck else I said.
All right. That's it in. And they,
here's a,
here's some throwback shit from back in
the day on the Monday morning podcast.
As always, thank you for listening and
you have a wonderful weekend. You come.
Okay,
good.
Okay.
Yeah.
Recently
I had to return some items at the mall.
Uh,
was the day after Christmas and I
was with a girl, I was dating, uh,
with the girl that I was dating.
She wants to return some shoes.
So we went to the journey
store with his shoes were,
but uh, when she got to the
counter to return the shoes,
the girl behind the counter asked
her for her name, address, email,
and phone number.
Oh my God.
The amount of fucking people who
actually give out that information.
My girlfriend just gave the information
over. As soon as the girl asked for it,
we were leaving the store.
I remark that I thought it was bullshit
that she had to give away personal
information to return a pair of shoes.
She said, uh, it was not a big deal,
but I didn't like it.
All right.
Why the fuck would you give somebody
all that information and just in case
you're new to my podcast,
just say you can say no.
Okay.
Can I, you know, I, I go out to buy shit
all time. Could I have your phone number?
No.
Okay.
I don't even say,
I don't even try and make it nice.
I just say no and then they go, oh, okay.
Yeah.
Know why do you feel like you got
to give them their information?
You're trying to buy something.
I'm sorry I can't,
I can't show you this unless I get your
information. Well, they go fuck yourself.
I'll buy it somewhere else. I
don't even need it. Anyways.
So anyways, he goes, next
we go to American Eagle.
You guys hit all the hot spot,
Huh? Then we went to Cinnabon.
Next we went to American Eagle where I
had to return his shirt. That was a gift.
It was a long line for returns.
Why did you return the shirt?
Did it not fit or was it ugly as hell or
was it both? As I was waiting in line,
one of the employees comes up to me
with a clipboard with the little form to
fill up. Now is anybody else kind of
getting the prison camp vibe here?
You know,
they're standing in line to get processed
and there's a guy coming up on the,
is your name please?
Your phone number? Um,
I stopped the employee.
Uh,
I stopped the employee and asked her
why she needed this information and she
says that it was to verify my purchase.
How fucking dumb our people.
You're gonna verify my purchase. Well,
here's the sales slips there, sweetheart.
This verifies it.
Yeah,
that's it. I don't know what to tell
you. Why don't you and your clipboard?
Why don't you hold that clipboard between
your little fucking beef curtains and
take a fucking walk down the street? How
about that as sweetheart, it's there.
This their reasons. You use that type
of language. Go Fuck Yourself. Huh?
How about I fucking grab that ponytail and
just, no, let's, let's, let's let, let,
let's keep it clean this week,
shall we? People anyways, she,
he goes before I could protest further,
she said that I could
just put my name on it.
Oh,
on the clipboard.
Okay.
When she walked away, I pulled
out the gift receipt has
said to my girlfriend, oh,
here it is. Yeah. This is what
verifies my purchase. Exactly.
The clipboard employee wasn't as
far as way as I thought she was in.
Heard me say,
did I read that wrong?
Get heard me say it's heard me say this,
and she began to explain further why
I needed to give over the information.
This is the part of the email I hate.
He goes, I apologized and told her.
I realized it wasn't her and that it was
just her company's policy that she was
enforcing. She walked
away again. I felt bad.
So the next time I saw
her I apologized and said,
I realized that she was just
doing her job, but she ignored me.
She was probably pissed because it was
the day after Christmas and I was causing
your grief, but you could at least
accept my apology. You Bitch. Um,
I love how you go from being
totally liberal and seeing
somebody fucking side of
it too, being yeah, man
up you can't. Um, anyway,
I got up to the counter and there
wasn't any further problems.
The guy at the register just took my
name and didn't ask me for anything.
I felt as though I had a small
victory against the big corporations.
Then this week I had to go back to the
store to return a hat. My girlfriend, God,
did you guys not make Christmas
lists or all your relatives blind?
The seems to be a lot of,
uh, returning of gifts.
Okay.
This is hilarious. You are returning a
hat that your girlfriend got you dude.
How horrific was that hat? Can you
please send me a picture of it before I,
if you took one before you returned
it. Picture one of those, uh,
plaid Charlie Chaplin Hat. Um,
I had the receipt, but again,
the girl at the register asked me
for my address and phone number.
I said I didn't want to
give that information to her
immediately panic sets in
and her face and she says that I have to,
I said that I didn't have to the day
after Christmas and I wasn't going to now,
good for you.
She calls over a coworker and they both
get defensive and hold to the idea that
I have to give over my information
in order to return a stupid hat.
Even though I had my receipt,
I asked why and they let me slide.
Why the let me slide on this before
and they maintained that I had,
I had to give them my name,
address and phone number.
Okay.
So what did I do in the face
of corporate opposition?
I caved and I gave it to him.
You fucking pussy.
Okay,
dude. The second you saw
the panic on their face,
you knew that they were going
to lose. All right. He goes,
I just don't get it, Bill. Why is a
receipt not enough? Nowadays it is enough.
They say they need our
personal information to verify
purchase then not, dude,
they're not. All right. All of that shit.
All those little save you know you
want to get when our discount store,
they're creating a file on you.
They figure out what you want to buy,
what they can market towards you,
and then they take that information and
they sell it to other fucking companies.
Even though they say they're not going to.
They sell your information.
Your information gets up on the Internet
and that's why there's all these creepy
websites out there right now that have
all this fucking information about you,
about, you know how many siblings you
have, your brothers and sisters names.
They all use that information to
fucking, it's, I'm telling you
this,
don't give him your information.
You don't have to give him your
information and people out there
who just have this fucking attitude
towards these corporations just sitting
there going like, wait,
what are they going to be?
As long as you're not doing
anything wrong. I mean,
what do I care if they know where I live?
What do I keep this fucking morons?
I don't even,
I have explained this shit till I'm blue
in the face and then I always get these
emails from these people. Um,
he just, I don't have the,
I don't know. I can't, if I said
something the other day, you know,
I was sitting there listening.
I was sitting there,
I was listening to a sports radio, you
know, cause I'm a deep thinker, right?
And uh,
this,
this new guy got on sports radio out
here in Los Angeles and you know,
he does what most people do when they
have nothing to say, which is they,
they just start,
they just go over the top arrogant.
You know what I mean? Like he was
talking about how he wanted to get some,
some sort of sports culture
personality on the show,
but he doubted he could get them as
a guest because the guest hated him.
And he goes, you know, cause I
disagreed with them on some he, yeah,
he was talking to a coach and he
was actually disagreeing with the,
with the fucking coach.
He's disagreeing with the guy and he goes,
you know what the problem is,
you know, he goes, look, I'm,
I'm just like such a good debater.
I actually ended up like convincing
myself of my own opinion. Yeah.
She said that over the airwaves.
And I just sort of muttered to myself
that the confidence of morons is
staggering.
You know what I mean?
Morons think they know everything. That's,
that's what makes them fucking morons.
And like the emails I get with
people who don't question the shit,
um, which is, I dunno,
like last week when I,
when I went off on my
little fucking rant there,
just some of the fucking emails I get,
it's like people are sending me Shit.
That kinda is backing up what I'm saying.
And then telling me that it sounded
like I have tin foil on my fucking head,
which obviously I am out of my
fucking mind on some level, but, um,
I'm not out of my mind when I don't
trust corporations and I don't trust them
when they say we're not going to
do anything with this information.
The other day I was in cvs and I go to
buy something and the lady asked me,
did I have a safe card? And I said, no.
She said, do you want one? And I said,
no. And she goes, well,
that's okay. I'll just,
and she swiped the fucking thing
anyways. And I was like, lady,
what did I just say to you?
Let's see if I use my credit card,
they'd have my name and then to match
up to that fucking number and what the
hell I just bought.
And just a little bit more information
about me and my question to all you
people who have this faith
in these corporations,
why does that person do that?
Why are they so hell bent on trying to
make that corporation less money in that
moment?
Okay.
They give me this card.
You know like everybody has those cards
so you're not saving any fucking money.
It's just, it's a big fucking shell
game to make it seem, oh look,
he's saving money.
What they're really doing did they look
at this hand over here is you're giving
them all your personal fucking information
that they can then use to to very
least sell to other corporations to
increase junk mail and it also to a limit
you're fucking level of privacy.
The fact that they can put all that
shit up in the Goddamn Internet.
People have been sending me these random
websites where they have like your name
and your address, where you fucking live
and all this type of shit. It's like,
how do you think that they
get all that information?
Okay.
Do you think there's somebody sitting
there with the phone book and just typing
all of this shit in? I don't
know. I have fuck it though.
Okay.
If some of us were, kills me. If
some fucking random creepy guy,
you know, you standing there waiting
for the subway came up to you,
asked you what's your name,
your phone number and your address was,
would you give it to them?
Yeah.
No,
but for some reason you're inside of
a fucking store and there's socks and
sweaters and somebody has a name
tag. Now all of a sudden you, you,
you give him total fucking trust.
You're writing your mind. So sir,
don't cave in. All right. All you get,
you just say that's unacceptable.
That's unacceptable.
I want to speak to the manager what
they're doing. It's not legal yet.
It's not legal yet,
but I can guarantee you there's somebody
lobbying for it that in Washington
there's some sort of fucking
high powered lobbying group.
I swear to God is probably
lobbying that from here on out.
We need to have a law that if
you're going to return a hat,
you have to give us your name,
your address,
and your social security number just so
there's not another nine 11 could guaran
fucking tee it. So
yeah, you don't have to.
Yeah.
That's actually one of the highlights of
my day. What I do now is when they say,
do you have our little savings
save card? And I say, no, I don't.
Would you like one? No, I don't. I then
say, and please don't swipe another one.
You know,
and then I try to pay with cash. I
love cash. Cash is fucking anonymous.
All you guys out there who was sitting
there watching these commercials where
they make it look like credit
cards is so fucking easy.
Okay,
you're, you're idiots.
Get give, give, give,
buying into exactly what
they want you to buy into,
which is a cashless society so they
can keep track of where you are at all
fucking times and every last fucking
dime that you make so they can get their
greedy little fucking hands on it.
You're out of your mind and you're giving
up an unbelievable amount of fucking
privacy by creating a paper trail.
Everywhere you go,
everywhere you go, what you're
doing, where you're at, you know,
and the Sea of morons who we're
going to sit there and go, Whoa,
have you doing anything wrong?
I mean, I guess maybe,
maybe I'm a paranoid cycle.
You look at all these fucking idiots
who do reality TV's and [inaudible] and
they let cameras come into their house
and they don't seem to care about it.
Maybe, uh, maybe the average Jacquez
doesn't give a shit, but sir,
for the love of God,
you know,
in the end he says,
I'm not crying conspiracy.
It's very plain to see what they're doing.
It's not malicious or evil. Yes it is.
It is malicious and it is
evil and it is a conspiracy.
They're conspiring to get
everybody's information,
find out what they buy,
and they're lying to you
saying that they're not going
to share the information.
It's everything that you're saying. It's
not. It is. All right, and that's it.
That's two weeks in a row. I'm
on the soapbox. See people,
don't you like it better
when I talk about sports?
Wow.
The last thing I'll read you guys.
This guy sent me something about a,
you know I was talking about when you're
going to go buy things and people ask
for your phone and all
this fucking information and it fucking
creeps me out. Every time they do that,
I just think that they should play in
the beginning of that iron main song,
the prisoner.
You remember that from the eighties
do you remember how that thing went?
You remember this?
The new number two.
What was number one?
You are number six most cycle laugh ever.
Yeah.
Can you imagine if your fucking dad would
laugh at you like that back in the day?
Be like, son, how many beers did you have
tonight? You just like, I just had to,
all right, and he just fucking
Dallas and the light stock demand.
It's going to be over. So anyways, this
fucking guy. Does that make any sense,
by the way? I don't know. I'm fucking
sitting in with one microphone.
No headphones in a fucking hotel
room. This is what you get. All right.
So this guy said,
Bill,
can you believe how much
fucking information people
are willing to give away for
no to strangers for no reason.
He goes,
I got my hair cut the other day and the
first thing they say to me before, hello,
or what can I do for you is the first
thing out of the gate is what's your phone
number? So I say, why do you
need my phone number? She says,
so we know who you are when you come in.
Which is bullshit because they
don't know you when you come in.
They still have to ask what
your God damn number is.
C got to love someone who actually fucking
uses their brain. So anyway, she goes,
he says,
I don't want to give you my number.
So then she scoffs in his face and says,
we don't send the information
out to anyone. It's just
to keep track of you here.
That's it. Um, and then
she says, uh, then okay,
then the guy says, the guy written,
wrote this really badly here.
So then I guess he responds to,
that doesn't make me feel any better.
You don't need my phone
number to cut my hair.
Then this slag does this fine,
whatever that sounded exactly like your
exaggerated impression of a dumb broad.
Then she goes, how about your
address too? This is fucking,
you know what all these corporations are
sharing this information to figure out
exactly what you buy when you buy it,
what you liked the best.
So they can just fucking, I
don't know what, you know,
Jack, the prices of the
shit up. So anyways, um, she
goes, how about your address?
And the guy goes, what are you going to
do? Drop the hair, cut off at my house.
Just cut my fucking,
uh,
now there's three people in line behind
me in this worthless tub of come.
Jesus leans around me and says, and says
to I guess to the people behind them,
sorry, this takes longer. When they,
then he writes, they, you know,
don't give any information.
And then he sarcastically, oh,
I see. I'm the one compliment a
complicating this transaction.
And it's not even her fault, it's her.
I'll, oh, and it's not even her fault.
It's their corporate creep bosses.
And all the fucking sheep that
let people do whatever they want.
Okay.
Sorry. This is so long. Well,
he should apologize to my listeners
because they had to listen to me read it.
Yeah, man, don't give those
people your fucking phone numbers.
Don't give him your address.
I do that. Kim, can we get
your phone number? I had. No,
you can't. We're not going to do anything
with it. I, that's fine. That's fine.
I know you're not going
to do anything with it.
I don't want you to have my phone number.
What are you gonna call me up and
see how my fucking hair cuts going?
Is it still short and you
think you need an adjustment?
Did I tell you that story?
But when I went into cvs and that guy who,
look what the peewee Herman Haircut, there
was two, two foreigners in front of me.
They barely spoke English and they,
he asked if they wanted one of those
savings saved cards and they said no.
And he goes, that's all right. I'll
just scan one anyways. And he scans it.
So I walk up and I'm ready for this guy.
He goes,
do you have our little savings save card?
And I say, no I don't. And he goes, well,
I'll just scan it anyways and I got no,
I don't want you to do.
And then he scanned it and I said, I said,
excuse me, what did I just say to you?
I just said, I don't want that.
And you scanned it anyways.
Why did you just do that? And he goes,
it's all right. I'll let it scan it.
I'll let us scan it. And I
go, what? What do you get?
Like half a cent for every
person that you get, you know?
Yeah,
that, that, that you get on the fucking
list there. And he goes, no I don't.
And it's like, really? Is that why
he can't make eye contact with me?
You fucking piece of shit. He probably
didn't even unscathed the God damn thing.
You know, I don't understand. People
will help out corporations. I just don't,
have they done anything to demonstrate
that they give a flying fuck about you or
the drinking water in your town?
Don't help those cons.
I mean you can if you want
to, but that's, I would just,
I think it would be a better world if
these fucking pricks did know every God
damn thing about you.
Do you know pretty soon you're going
to walk in there and they're going to
fucking ask me if you can put,
uh,
did they can just bug you like gene
Hackman in the conversation. Right.
All right dude, I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about. You know what,
I'm going to go down and listen to this
lady singer songs so I don't have to
think there's a nice
little crowd down there.
Has got to be at least
26 people down there,
which I think in downtown San
Jose actually constitutes a mob.
Maybe somebody will get tased and shot
in the abdomen. I don't know what.
All right, that's the podcast
for this week. Thank you
guys so much for listening.
I am in currently revamping my website
and I hope that everything's going to be
up to speed. I recently went over, uh,
10,000 people on my mailing list, so
I'm really excited about that. And, uh,
if you want to know what's going on,
you know, especially like if you see,
you know,
when I switched over to a Lipson with
the podcast and all that fucking shit,
if you were out of the loop,
it's cause you weren't on my mailing list.
I'm not sure. You know how funny
is this? How funny is this?
How fucking hypocritical of mine?
I just said,
don't give your phone
number out to these cons.
And now here I am asking for
your web address. I really just,
why do people listen to this and an idiot.
All right,
I'll talk to you next week.
Yeah,
yeah.
Okay.