Hey, what's going on is bill burr and
it's time for the Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast just before Friday.
And Ah,
just checking it out. Yeah, I can't
do it guys. My fucking voice is shot.
I've been on the road again
for fucking two weeks.
Just about two weeks coming up on two
weeks where we were in Chicago here.
Beautiful Chicago, one of the
most underrated cities out there.
You know what I mean?
Just as far as the sheer size of it.
And everybody talks about New York.
Everybody talks about La.
Everybody's always going on and on about
De Moines, you know, but it's really,
you know,
it's fucking view.
What are the fucking city has
these kinds of views, you know,
right on the water is not a lot of
major cities like this. You know,
that sit on the wall, sit on a lake.
How about that? That'll make it unique.
They sit on a lake, it's fucking
beautiful. You know what I mean?
This is what Detroit will become some day.
It's coming back to slowly coming back.
Cleveland's crushing it.
That's when I found out about this, uh,
this part of the country, man, all these,
these, uh, I think that whole rust
belt things going to go away. You know,
they're not going to have that slogan
anymore. But anyways, last night, uh,
we were in Minneapolis had
a great fucking time. Um,
first show is a little bit
rough. Jesus Christ, you know,
I dunno what the fuck it's the first
time I've snapped on stage and so fucking
long. Um, you know what I mean?
Just this fucking lady just talk and
talk and talk and talk and talk and,
and it's like, I don't give a
shit. I'm still going to get paid.
But I know people around paid
to hear the fucking show.
They didn't pay to hear me go on and
on it. And she was living at one point,
standing up, yelling at me, you know,
it's doing some bit trash and fucking
women. I mean, it's what I do.
You know what I mean? I trash
them. I have fun doing it.
I'm allowed to do it as a comedian
and it doesn't affect anybody's life.
Fucking lunatic, you know?
And the more you yell at me,
then the more I'm going to do it
because debts then it becomes funny.
If you just shut up, it'd be,
it'd be over in like two seconds.
So she's standing up screaming
and yelling at me. Right?
Like I give a fuck and I'm
yelling back at her, you know,
and the security is so funny that
just sorta daintily going, miss, Miss,
you have to sit down and miss. You
have to sit down. And I was joking.
How if that was a guy,
he'd be in a choke hold getting
dragged out into the fucking alley.
You know what I mean? Um, and uh,
finally in the end they were
finally gonna throw her out.
She was living at one point miming rubbing
her pussy with a tongue hanging out.
Um, like that was going to
shock me. It was just like,
I've been doing the
road for like 20 years.
He can have to do a little
better than that. Um,
I just did not, I don't know if she
just was a, uh, maybe she was drunk.
I don't know what her deal
was. But, um, you know,
she decided to take some joke
seriously and felt that it was,
she needed to stand up and start screaming
and yelling. So that happens. Right.
And I finally just snap
in the end because, um,
it was just the first show was just weird.
Like they had the front three rows were
within the spotlight that you stood on.
So they were,
is lit up is I was,
and then the rest of the theater was
completely in the dark and I couldn't see
them.
I couldn't see any of the fucking theater.
So I felt like I was performing to
like, you know, 20 people. It was weird.
And um,
I dunno,
it got a little sideways
there towards the end.
Okay.
And uh, they will finally
going to fucking kick her out.
The guy finally is politely going to kick
her out cause she, cause she's a lady
and uh, I said, no, don't kick
her out. Don't kick her out.
Just let us sit there and act like a
baby was absolutely no ramifications the
way she's been allowed to her whole life.
I mean,
her behavior was so fucking immature.
You know,
and then what kills me is the end
of the fucking shallow, right?
I'm going through the tweets. I'm just
making sure that people in the dark,
he still had a good time. Right. Um,
which stays were saying they were and
they actually people military Minneapolis
who fucking cold is there. They
Will Paul, sorry for that lady,
Blah Blah was still a good time.
So I felt good about that. Right.
And then some woman had
tweeted at me, um, you know,
heckling is never a good idea,
but you know,
being subjected to 40 minutes of sexist
and original material, Yada, Yada,
all this fucking bullshit.
Right. First of all,
I love how she addresses somebody's not
shutting the fuck up for an entire show.
70 minutes. She just said, dre,
she takes care of that with
[inaudible] is never a good idea.
Now that I've addressed that, and then
she exaggerates, it wasn't 40 minutes.
That's sexist material.
It was like 12.
Okay.
And I thought it was pretty original.
Um,
anyways, but we had the
fucking best time, um, in me,
I still had a good time on that fucking
show. And sell right to the end.
But then I felt good because
this woman backstage, you know,
that was running shit back
then. I was saying, Hey,
look at this tweet and I just gotta go
do it. Does it? Am I that fucking bad?
And she goes, look, he goes,
I live alone. I got daughters.
It's all women, the house.
I'm pretty independent. I didn't have
a problem with anything that you said.
I thought it was funny and you're always
going to get one of those at the show.
And I was like, thank you.
Thank you. And then I went out.
I had a great fucking time on the
second show and it got off stage.
I fucking gave her a
hug, you know? Thank you.
I needed to hear that from a lady.
Right?
Oh my God. That fucking
fucking woman. She was a loan.
A tick standing up.
Who the fuck is dumb enough to get that
mad at a comic that you're standing up
yelling? You know, like at
some point I'm going to go,
oh yeah. You know what? That's
a good point. I am. I'm sorry.
Let me,
uh,
let me fucking Redo my whole act now
just for you because you don't seem to be
enjoying it.
Yeah.
Okay.
Uh, you know, in a
perfect world, you know.
Yeah.
Ah, no, I'm not even gonna say it was
fucking me. Whatever. What happened?
Let me just let me get out.
So I'll maybe talk about the great
time that we had in Minneapolis.
So I've gone there last six times.
I've gone there.
I've wanted to go get the juicy Lucy
fucking burger that they have, right.
Just basically they put the cheese in the
patty and then it melts in his fucking
piping hot and all the tourists fucking
bite into it and burn their fucking
mouth. Right. So we finally,
we have barely enough fucking time
cause we were driving in from a up from
Milwaukee. So it was a long ass
fucking drive, like six, seven hours.
It was rain and sleet knowledge shit.
So we literally just
dropped the bags in me, Eh,
and Farsi and this other body of eyes.
We fucking jump in this car and we fucking
drive over to this. Uh, I think it's,
is it match? I kept calling it Mike's,
I think his match match bar, I believe.
Um,
okay.
Hang on, hang on, let me
look it up. Where are we?
I write what the text messages.
I only have it on fucking
soft and it's still fucking
okay.
Go into settings and find mute your whole
view. Go into settings. You can't, um,
the hell is it. Come on, you scroll and
Scroll and Scroll and Scroll and bup. Bup,
Bup Matt Smith's bar.
That's what it would fuck.
We went right now I'm going
to go all these fucking
tweets from people going, oh,
you shouldn't go to fucking cookies in
fucking Saint Paul. I didn't have time.
I went to the closest one and it was
fucking delicious. Char Broil Burger.
And we, we go there and the lady was nice.
The lady, she goes, hey guys, she goes,
nibble around. She saw it,
you know, you know for his,
he had a Yankees hat and my other
buddy at a mets hat, so you know,
I look like a fucking jerk off says, and
they knew we weren't from there. Right.
So she goes, uh, just make sure you're
nimble. That cheese is hot, right?
So maybe the other guy, that's what we do
first. He fucking thanks. He's nibbling,
but he's so fucking hungry bites right
into the cheese and he just goes,
he's like spitting it out, right?
So before I can laugh at them,
he fucking takes another book
just as deep and he's going like,
we fucking crying, laughing boy, for what
the fuck is wrong with you? He goes to,
what the fuck? She said to take a
nibble. I took it and said, no, you tend,
you took half a bite.
Okay,
you just Italian do.
You don't know how to nibble.
You fucking stuck in your mouth.
You fucking jerk off. And he goes,
boy did I go this second bite. He bedded
so deep, he pulled out half the pickle,
burn the shit out of his mouth and we
will fucking cry and laugh and tease the
shit out of him.
He kept trying to blame the waitress.
Yeah,
each app trying to blame the wedge.
It sounds just like, hey, you know,
we didn't have a problem. We completely
understood it. We didn't burn our mouth.
I was joking last night, he sounded
like he was hitting a heavy bag like ha,
I've been dreaming about getting up to
fucking sandwich every time I go there.
And that was the big thing.
I was thinking, I had like
a game plan. I was like,
yeah, cut it in half and I'll
let it melt. The big thing is,
is once you actually bite into it a little
bit, it's still gonna be a little hot.
But uh, once that air gets on the
cheese, it really, it kind of,
it's almost like a blows through the
whole Burger and then a fucking cools it
off and then you're able
to completely enjoy it.
And I'm totally 100% lived up to the hype.
Even Versie after he burned his
fucking mouth. Ha Ha. Um, he,
he even, he's still fucking a
joke. It's just a great burger.
So thank you to people there at
match bar full, hooking us up, uh,
hooking us up by just being open.
They didn't give it to us for free,
can't just me. You know
what I'm saying? So, um,
and the day before we were in Milwaukee,
now that great fucking city and uh,
played the Riverside theater
and that might have been a,
that was right up there with fucking
Indianapolis as far as like the crowd just
being right on top of you.
And uh,
we had one of the,
you know what I was steered or does
it just has the fucking magic man.
It was fucking awesome.
And upstairs they had a,
this crazy green room and they had a chef
up there who made the salads with all
this stuff was fucking on it.
Got I got treated like rock stars and
then as flat screen TV and we watched the,
uh, the royals come back and
beat the mets for game one.
I missed all the game too. But um,
I know people are freaking out.
And of course I, as a red sox fan,
I'm immediately thinking, well,
the mets were down o two, an 86. And
I remember how that one turned out.
That has our little
roller it out of Buckner.
What does it say?
[inaudible] with a bag between the bag.
I want to,
I can't even remember how it goes anymore.
And mads when it,
that's what you remember how it ended.
You know what's funny about
that fucking clip now is now,
it's just hilarious to me because thank
God we finally won it and then we got
two more for good measure. So
now when I watch it, I just,
I just,
it's just funny to me now.
Okay.
The fucking, the disappointment
that that was was just funny.
How the fuck did you get it?
There's a little roller up the field.
I'll get to pass Buckner and the
match went, ah, that's what it was.
Jesus Christ. That still
hurts to say that. You know,
it's the funniest thing is when nights
scores, he's fucking running at one point.
He puts both his hands on his head.
To me, that sums up the whole game.
That was literally like, I can't,
I can't fucking believe these guys.
Just fuck that game up. Um, you know,
forget Buckner fucking Bob Stanley
just comes waddling in deck guy.
He wasn't a, he wasn't even
in beer league softball shape.
Fucking horrible comes fucking walking in,
you know,
besides that, we let them, you know,
they came back and be, I can't remember,
we were like up by like fucking three
runs or something, something crazy.
And then in the bottom of the ninth,
we will one fucking strike away.
And I swear to God,
I feel like we let up 17 singles in a row.
They just kept getting hits and
can't get it. Kept getting heads.
And then the past bald tied it up.
Oh my God.
You're just sitting there like
this isn't real. They count a cow.
Could you fuck this up?
Gets passed back gear
and their mats weight.
Oh man, that'll toughen you up.
As a sports fed. Jesus grow.
We went up three nothing.
And the next game. I was too,
too young as a red sox fan at that
point. I still had hope. I was just like,
I am a fucking one. That one kind of
fuck did I get on that? Oh, that's right.
I said we were in Milwaukee. So
anyways, um, before we went there,
we've actually found a steam room.
Right.
So me and [inaudible] will walking up
the street and the guy fucking at the
hotel we were staying at and I was
like four blocks up the street.
So first it comes out of the hotel,
you know,
versus he's one of those backpack guys.
Like he,
he does not bring luggage and he just,
I dunno,
I dunno how he gets it all in there.
So his,
his wardrobe options are very limited.
So he's walking down the street, right?
He's got on dark socks in the flip
flops that he's going to wear,
the sandals that he's going to
wear in the fucking, uh, the sauna.
He's got on like basketball shorts down
to his fucking knees, passes needs,
I should say that Jordan ones. Right. And
then he's got one of those fucking, uh,
you know,
it was army I fly airplane jackets
that have the Zipper on the arm and his
fucking Yankee Hat, right? Just walking
down the street. He looked like he was,
I dunno,
like,
cause his building caught on fire and
he just grabbed a jacket and ran out.
That's what the fuck he looks at freezing.
Uh,
Bart Nicks and other coach shorts guy.
And then he'd get me walking
down the street. Like I say,
looking like a sickly Ron Howard and a,
it turns out the fucking thing was like,
I dunno,
like 20 blocks up the street and first
he's Pinky toe is killing him and his
flip flop, it was fucking cry and laugh.
And as we go up there, so the hotel,
the hotel we go up to,
I swear to God with the steam room is in,
is called the Pfister
swear to God,
p f. I. S. T. E r the Pfister.
If you ever go to Milwaukee,
you got to stay at the Pfister,
all right?
Cause they got this sick
ass fucking stay bro and uh,
spy and all that shit. So we
fucking go down there, right?
And it's like individual steam room
that you get off of the fucking room.
We're like freaking out. It's all these
beautiful women walking around that work.
They're like, oh, this is
great. So finally was sitting
there drinking spa water,
right, dressed the way we look, right.
Look and like fucking animals. And,
uh, all of a sudden, like
three people come out, right?
Too cute women in this dude.
And I'm just thinking,
what the fuck is he doing here? And then
he just goes, ah, he's like, ah, Mr. Byrd.
I'm like, Hey, you gotta be
fucking kidding me, right?
So we go over it, right?
And he shows me how to use the spa,
the steam,
because all I'm doing is taking the
steam. And he's like, yeah, you do this,
then you do that. And I was
just like, yeah, yeah, I
know how to use. And he goes,
hey,
I just so fucking disappointed.
Right guys should not work at
fucking spas. They just shouldn't.
It should be all fucking ladies,
right?
So I'm not a sexist pig. The Lady Shit
on the fucking thing too. How about that?
Does that make you feel all right? You
fucking dumb. Cunt. Minneapolis. Um,
so afterwards, right? So the thing is,
I did listen to the guy explained
the fucking Steve. Thanks.
So the fucking steam thing turns on, dude.
And it is like angry. It's angry steam.
And I'm sitting there like, I got to
pull my fucking feet up onto the bench.
They don't burn off and I'm
huddled in the corner and uh,
you know, I'm like, it was so fucking
hot. I had to, I had to get out.
I just had fucking walk out like twice.
I was read as a fucking tomato and
I kept going back in or whatever.
And um, long story short, he get
out of the spa and then Barton,
it can forsee they'd come out of
theirs and they were going, oh my God,
that was fucking amazing.
I was like, dude, it wasn't
too hot. It wasn't too hard.
He goes, no, he, they go,
we just stood on the other side
of the steam where the shower was.
He just like turned the
shower on. I was like, ah,
I didn't fucking think to do
that. And they were like, well,
the guy didn't tell you how
to do it. And I said, Nah,
I shoot him out of there because I
was pissed and I didn't get a woman.
And then first he starts
laughing. He goes, dude,
the second that guy came walking
out with those two women, he goes,
I said a quick prayer
that I didn't get the guy.
And then I laughed and I said,
yeah, I didn't. I thought it was,
what the fuck is this guy
doing here? Oh, you know what?
They should have guys at spas for women.
That's what they should have.
You know what I mean? It's all
part of the fucking sparks spirit.
She's supposed to be looking at
something beautiful. All right.
I don't want to see some stubbled
face jackass coming down. You know,
if he's listening to this,
God bless. Should Dude,
you tried to fucking explain
the Steve to me. Um, so anyways,
what was another great
thing too about that,
that Gig was a Riverside theater was
right down the street and next to it,
almost built into, it was a
fucking bar and a uh, and a cigar,
a tobacco store. And I want to thank
everybody there for hooking us up.
They stayed, they stayed open
late for us. We showed up.
They had two large fucking pizzas,
right?
And then they had all these
fucking sick ass cigars and um,
it was just one of those great nights
on the road. Wait a second, go. Fuck.
I can't fucking type of password
and talk at the same time. Hang on.
Fucking screensaver, God damn
fucking thing. Um, anyway,
so I don't even know how to, I don't
even know how to say the name. The Tibet.
It's like u h l e you'll
tobacco company.
I don't know how to say it.
Thank you so much to them and
thank you to the guy next door.
I didn't get the name of the bar. He
apologize, but it's right next door.
Thanks for hooking us up with the
shots. And uh, we stayed there til like,
you know,
three 30 in the morning,
the guys there and one of the women there,
they weren't a motorcycles,
so they were showing me
all you custom motorcycles.
I'm showing video of my truck. We just
said we had a fucking awesome time. Um,
got to make sure I thank everybody.
Thank you to the person who made
us that bread. That was delicious.
Thank you to the people person who
made those fucking hilarious cookies.
Okay.
Yeah. This guy had cookies in one
of them. Said, ginger, count on it.
Go Fuck Yourself. Monday morning
podcast, the name of my dog,
all of that shit. Uh, what else?
There was a guy when we will
always in, um, Pittsburgh,
I think made a half
patriots have Steelers,
a jersey.
Okay.
So one side was Tom Brady.
Yellow was,
I think I talked to about this Hines
ward because we play in Heinz Hall or
whatever. I mean, you know, you guys don't
have to do that stuff by the way. Uh,
but you know, it's greatly
appreciated. You know,
I want to make sure I thank people
don't think you have to fudge it.
Just show up.
Just show up and,
and enjoy the jokes and don't try to
pretend like to rub your clam and stand up
and yell at me. I mean, you could do it,
but you're only fucking over the
other people there. So anyways, um,
with that, I should probably read a little
bit of fucking advertising here, Huh?
What am I up to 19 minutes and running
my fucking mouth. Um, all right.
Zip Recruiter. Everybody.
As a business owner,
your company is only as good as
the people you hire. No Shit.
Posting jobs in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
Is it short staffing leaves little
time to post a to dozens of jobs,
sites, position, zip
recruiter as the solution.
Why do they leave that in the copy?
Aren't you supposed to do that
or is this like tips for the person's
writing the copy for the life of me?
I don't know why they leave that in there.
Like I'm supposed to start riffing here.
Like I'm some jazz singer, school lip up,
Deepa, zip recruiter, um,
compose to 100 plus job sites.
It's the worst scat singing ever.
Uh,
with one single click be instantly
matched to candidates from over 6 million
resumes plus watch brand new
candidates roll into ZipRecruiter's,
easy to use interface
within 24 hours or one day.
Ziprecruiter has been used
by over 400,000 businesses.
I'm not reading any capital
letters anymore. Uh,
today you can try zip recruiter for free.
Go to ziprecruiter.com/bird that's
ziprecruiter.com/burr hi ziprecruiter.com/
[inaudible] right club Debbie Taylor.
Evil doers.
Don't you hate it?
One wine looks like a 10,
but why ends up tasting like a six or
even worse when you walk into the store to
pick out your wine, you could easily be
fooled into a situation just like this.
Was that a whole sentence?
Don't you hate it when your wine looks
like a 10 but winds up chasing like a six
period or even worse? Question Mark.
Exclamation point. That is a fragment.
When you walk into the
store to pick out your wine.
Oh Dash you could easily be fooled into
a situation just like this. All right,
that was my fault. Uh,
well now there's new, uh,
this new wine club called club dubby
care named near port after my daddy.
They've changed everything.
No more being fooled by winds that
pretend to be harder or tastier than they
actually are.
It's easy.
You just go to club debbie.com
and answer six simple questions.
Their algorithm creates a
palate profile just for you.
Then they send wine directly to your door,
perfectly customized to
match your taste club.
Debbie sports troops is leading the
grape to glass of wine revolution.
They work directly with the vineyards to
cut out the man, which saves you money.
So with the club Debbie Club
distortion, distortion, folks out,
I don't like the Dixie chicks.
You get free me of wine,
customized your tastes and a third
of what you'd pay at the store.
They even have none,
no risk,
hundred percent guarantee that
you'll love whatever they send you.
An right now club,
Debbie,
I'm going to Bosch and land it sits on
an aquifer is offering my listeners 50%
off your first order when you go to club
Debbie [inaudible] dot com slash burr
so stop wasting time and money messing
around at our retail stores and start
drinking wine.
You know you're gonna love.
Just go to club Debbie
and each stop the war.
Warm care.com/bird it gets 50% off
your first order. That's Club Gabby
out. Shit, Shane, I'll throw out the
first pitch. I'll fucking kill it.
Dotcom slash bar or club w.
Dot com slash or high club w.com/bro.
All right,
let's get back to the, uh,
the, the podcast here. Um,
so anyways, hey, how about those Bruins?
Huh? Hey, are we go bro, when or we go,
Bob Bob scoring six goals against six
and nothing took against the fucking shut
up.
Ah,
Jeremy. Hey, he's got a goal.
Anytime he fucking scores. I'm
pitching this right now at the TD bank,
north well's Fargo Center or wherever
the fuck they call it. The old,
the new Boston Garden.
Anytime Jimmy Hayes scores,
they should show that clip from Goodfellas
with Ray Liotta in the shower going up
Chevy.
You
got to do it.
Everybody loves good.
And who doesn't love it when a seven
foot fucking winger scores when he's got
that Bruins logo on? So I was
excited that I was excited for Milan.
Lou Cheats got his first fucking goal
with the Kings. Can't root against him.
And,
um,
I have to tip my fucking cap as much
as I don't want it it to the Montreal
Canadians went in nine and a fucking row
actually wanted to see them break the
record just because I don't
want to see them win a cup.
But I like seeing records get broken,
you know,
the Vancouver Canucks Canucks
contacts or they'd beat them,
you know, they'll always be constantly,
you know, I just didn't like,
I don't have burrows guy biting the guy's
fucking figure. You know what I mean?
That was the stupidest fucking
media realized they were
going to like maybe even
sweep us and that he bit a guy's finger
and acted like it. He poked the bear.
Why? Why, why would you do
that? And then what happened?
Everybody knew you fucked
up the series and then your,
your fans went out and they
burned down all the Starbucks.
And to this day when you go to Vancouver,
you cannot get a good cup of coffee.
It's a true story. That's
a hockey story. You know,
that you could see that on the
NHL network. Um, by the way,
if you listen to me and you get frustrated
with how little I know about hockey,
you should listen to Joe Barton. It's
puck off. I'll tell you right now,
nobody fucking like,
if you just want to listen to an
absolutely fucking rabid fans,
they come up with nicknames.
They got all these cool awards like the
Claude Lemieux award is when you come
out of the penalty box and you, you
immediately score. It's got all that,
all that type of shit on that,
uh, on his podcast. But whatever.
Let's get back to the fucking, uh,
what else did I want to talk about?
I got to work out guy.
So I'm not going to lie to you.
I haven't need like a fucking animal.
Last night on the bus,
we watched Godfather One
and godfather two and a,
we swung by a swung by this
great fucking Italian Deli in,
uh, Minneapolis. Um, I thought
it was, you know, I thought
it was great, but you know,
partner can fucking fuzzy. They
also enjoyed it. They enjoyed it.
But like Italians, the reason why they're
so fucking great it food is they, their,
their critiques. Most people would be
like, good sub dorma goes for good.
Unbelievable. Oh that fucking
broaden that Denny's or whatever.
The fucking olive garden. Oh
my God, it's so decadent. Um,
they have like,
they have like 9,000 levels of bad,
decent and unbelievable.
So like we got this fucking meat plate
right? And I'm sitting like, oh my God,
this is fucking delicious.
This is delicious. And
they're like, well, you know,
you know, you know,
the Gaba ghoul is good,
but we got spoiled with the stuff in
Pittsburgh. The Salami is outstanding.
The pursuit is, is, is decent. It's not
as good as Pittsburgh. I'm just like,
how could you guys fucking even tell
it's fucking delicious. Whatever it is,
it's fucking delicious. But the Cannalis
and the bread were fucking unbelievable.
It was all fucking good.
I probably shouldn't have
said that because now people
are gonna think that I'm
shitting on the fuck. I'm shitting on the,
uh, the place and that we went to, uh,
oh, I'm going to say this.
Broders B, r, O, d, r,
S. Broaders Caseen Italiana. Um,
the that leads Italian,
catch him.
I'm fucking can onlys were amazing.
Everything was great there.
You know what I mean? But I will
say the Gaba wool from fucking, uh,
I gotta get off towards these guys.
They're turning me into a fucking
Pi's on here. Um, food was great.
So then we put on, uh, and we
literally, when we didn't have any wine,
so we got out out of the bus,
walked over.
I'll tell you if this podcast doesn't
make you want to be a fucking comedian,
by the way, it's like the greatest
life ever, right? So we fucking,
we walk over to this bar,
we went in and we bought like
two bottles of Cabernet, right?
And then it's the perfect moment
to drop a good fellas line. Right?
Second, we got the wine, we
go, okay, now we can eat.
Never gets old.
Oh,
I actually quoted Frankie Carbo
when that lady wouldn't shut up.
And I was blaming,
I was blaming everybody,
every guy in the front row for not keeping
their woman shut. I go at some point,
I'm not advocate domestic violence,
but you got to go a little
Frankie Carbone here,
you've got a wad up that
fucking make coke, shut the
fuck up and opened the door.
Got a huge laugh. Um, so anyway,
so my almost done with this fucking
podcast. I really have to go work out.
I got to do it,
man.
They got a scale actually here in
this hotel. And I tell you right now,
I don't dare get on it because I'm
going to hate myself. Um, I'm open.
I just put on like five to seven and
then I got like two weeks before Madison
Square Gardens.
So then what I'm gonna do is I'm just
going to drop three pounds both weeks.
That's it.
I'm going right back to eating as
perfectly as I know how to eat and do an
insane amount of fucking cardio. I'm going
to try to do that. But next week, um,
play in, uh, in Philadelphia,
in somebody's already told me where
to go to get a fucking cheese take.
Cause I always go down and he did.
The people that you go to the genome
as you go to fucking blah, blah blah.
And the more I go to Philly,
I find out that the only people that
go to those places that are kind of the
younger people,
because they don't know any better because
they're going to stand in a fucking
huge line. So someone was
telling me, hey, by the way,
fairly people, if you know a
spot, cause I, I've eaten it,
both of them.
All right,
I can't remember which one I'd like
last time we meet verse, he went there,
we got a, we got one at
each, cut them in half,
you know, and then switched, you know, so
we both got, you know, half of each one.
And I remember there
was one I liked the uh,
cheese better on one and I like to
something the bread better on the other or
something like that.
So anyways,
if you guys know of a
different place to go to,
I'm trying to scroll right now and find
what this person told me to go to. Um,
they said go to Steve's Prince of steaks.
If you guys know one of those,
cause I don't Rose's the Rose's from
Philly and he goes, Nah man. He goes,
I never go down there to
fucking lines are too long.
He had one that's off the beaten path.
So it seems like everybody knows though.
So, uh, give a couple of tours. So Hook
up here, let us know where to go. Um,
well if you don't want to blow
up your spot. I understand. Um,
so I'll be there and
then I'm doing a casino,
I think in Bethlehem or something like
that, Pennsylvania. And then I got a,
I dunno what I'm doing, I think some
sorta some Gig, I don't even understand.
I think it's a casino. I don't know what
it is. Someplace down in Daytona, Florida.
And then I'm up in New York and I'll be
in New York for the whole fucking week,
getting ready to do a,
the Madison Square Garden Show,
which should be a,
obviously pretty fucking memorable.
So I'm getting pretty excited about that.
But I got to go to the gym every day.
It's got to become a poppy life. And
if you don't want, I'll be fading away.
You go to the gym every day, you'd cut
I gotta I gotta get back to that. Um,
I do find, I gotta get back
to that. I'm a fucking idiot.
But he's like a fucking jerk off sitting
here eating cookies with my name on it
today. Fucking loser. Anyways.
All right. Coming up. Who are
the brewers got this week?
I got so many fucking games. I got
to watch all the, Oh hey, by the way,
if you want to learn like
some of the NHL lines,
I cannot promote daily face off.com more.
It's the fucking greatest.
Yeah.
Not only do they have the top layer
of the one lines one through four,
they have the fucking, uh, they
have their, their, their uh,
penalty kill, whatever the team,
whatever the fuck you call it.
I told you listen to bark nick. He knows
how to say it right. Daily face off.
There it is.
Okay.
Yeah. Line combinations.
Right. And they come right up.
You Click on line combinations. Like
right now I just brought up the island.
There's, cause that's the last time
I was trying to watch a Bruins game.
When we beat the island.
There's so they,
and they got all the lines one
through four. They got the German,
they got little jerseys with the
fucking number and the name on the back.
You can't fuck it up. All right.
The islanders number one line.
Josh Bailey, left wing center
John Two bars. Right wing.
Ryan's Trump say that.
Okay.
There you go. Then they got the,
uh, did the offensive pairings,
the first power play unit,
the second power play unit,
the goalies and then the fucking
injury list. So there you go.
Fucking phenomenal. Uh,
daily face off.com. No,
they are not asking me to promote
them. I'm just saying, uh,
I'm just, I'm just promoting
them and I'll, I'll promote the,
a couple Bruins games here and then that's
going to be yet, what do we got next?
Oh,
we got the Carolina Panthers.
Yeah.
Who Do we got here the
next couple of games.
Okay.
We've got the panthers.
Oh,
we got back to back games
Friday, Saturday, the panthers,
the lightning Taryn through Florida.
Oh.
And then we start picking up the pace.
And then we got, we got the ducks,
the capitals, we got the hated habs
and then the islanders. Jesus Christ,
a ton of fucking games.
I'm going to miss most of those.
I'll be all caught up on the
haves and the fucking islanders.
Why are you guys still listen to this?
All right. Uh, for the bottom of my heart.
Thank you to everybody who's come
out and showed up on this tour. Man,
it could not have been a more fun
toward the whole fucking thing.
From top to bottom. The guys that I went
on tour with, Jason Lalia, Joe Barr,
Nick Paul Versey, and everybody
came out to the shows, the venues,
all of that shit.
Even that fucking crazy broad last
night on the first fucking show,
I don't get any fucking hate for
you. Whatever. You know what?
I bet if we went out and had a drink,
we would have had a great fucking time.
You know, that admitted? Come on.
We could have traded notes on the ladies.
Um,
all right. That's the, uh, I
was just checking in on, you.
Hope you guys have a wonderful weekend.
You can't send now.
We got a so cool music.
You guys always ask me about the
music that's on this thing. Um,
I don't pick it out. Uh,
Andrew [inaudible] does,
so look him up on fucking
Twitter, Twitter. Um, he's,
he's a young fella.
He knows all the cool fucking music.
He's the one that tells me what the fuck
to listen to and I've been downloaded
some of the shit that he puts up
there. Um, I really get into the band.
Fucking God,
Jira.
I hope I'm saying it right.
It's Godzilla.
But that name was taken so they just
wrote it how someone would say with an
Asian accent. Gojira and they're
fucking drummer is insane.
Fucking insane. And I've never been into
that rope. Barbara. I'd like lamb of God.
I like,
like for me,
there's still has to be like a couple of
songs where they slow it down and maybe
the guy actually sings regular if he know
bands like that where there's still at
least a little bit of melody
to it as opposed to just like,
just blistering, beating
the shit out of you. Um,
oh, by the way, somebody actually
sent me some of this swag too. Um,
I've got to thank him for that, man.
It's been a fucking amazing tour.
So now I've got three nights at the
legendary a Chicago theater and for my
money,
for my money,
it's the best in most
iconic marquee in the,
uh, I've any theater I
play, I've, I've, alright.
Even just seeing just that,
that fucking vertical sign where it
just says Chicago, it's just went out.
You know,
what I love too is whenever the Blackhawks
have a big game of back in the day,
the bulls that the Jordan Pippin bowls,
whenever they were,
they had like a big playoff
game and they would show,
they always showed the fucking river,
you know,
the seers fucking tower or whatever.
They show the fucking, you know,
sky long along along the lake.
But they always showed the
Chicago Theater mannose fucking
um,
I saw that for years as a sports fan.
So to be able to play it is amazing and
a little bit of a backstage shit here
for you. Um, this is the only theater
that I've ever played where, um,
you actually see a Frank Sinatra Dean
Martin and Sammy Davis Jr have their names
on the wall.
They actually signed it and they,
they have it behind glass cause everybody
autographs the wall and then they have,
um, when you're backstage, if
you're walking from left to right,
you go all the way over to the right
and way, way, way, way up on the wall.
I don't know what sort of fucking ladder
they gave the chairman of the board,
but it says Frank Sinatra. Oh, it says,
I hope, I hope you had a good time.
I know I did. Frank Sinatra.
It's fucking amazing. So, uh,
fucking just awesome wave
started off with Notre Dame,
USC and we end up at fucking
dish Chicago theater.
Could not have been more of a
perfect tour. Um, and that's it.
I'm done gushing here thanking everybody,
but we really didn't have a good time.
All right, go fuck yourself. So
have a wonderful weekend. I see.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn. It's
the Monday morning podcasts from Monday,
October 3rd, 2011. Why?
How's it going? You
hear that echo? Oh Yup.
Um,
I'm in a new place.
I moved no more angry old guy beneath me.
I'm in a new place and uh, it's sparsely
furnished, some sitting in an old chair.
So it's going to be creaking a little
bit during the podcast and actually got
out of it cause I just
realized that sonically, that
could be a little annoying.
Um, yeah. Move to a new
place. Little bigger,
little better. Right? The
American dream still existing,
you know, instead of taking giant leaps,
you take little steps. Little baby steps.
Ooh, look at that. The kitchens
up to about six inches bigger.
Um, no, I'm psyched. First
Time my fucking life.
I don't have some cut live
in below me or above me.
So you know what that means.
All I got to do is piss off my
neighbors and I think I'll be all right.
No, we got it. We a nice place.
So we're site my girls happy,
which is a great thing as a guy, you
know, that's a great thing. You know,
you get something new and shiny and what
are the names and then they're happy
and then your life is great.
That's all you want.
You just want them to be happy.
Maybe if they're happy they'll
stop fucking bitching at me. Stuck.
I, you booed me. Maybe
that'll stop, you know.
But you know how broads
are, you know, they are,
no matter how cool they are,
how fucking hot day. Yeah.
Eventually they find something.
Eventually they find something,
you know,
and you sit in there and you'll listen
to him talk and you nod and you know it
and your head. Ah, yeah. Ah, okay. Yeah,
I'll work on that. Yeah, definitely.
I'll work on that. And then your head,
you just sitting there going like really,
really fucking unreal.
I swear to God,
I swear to fucking God. I was talking
to Paul Versey about this the other day.
We were on the phone joking
about this shit going,
I bet Donald fucking Trump gets nagged,
you know,
sitting there looking out the fucking
helicopter window that has his Goddamn
name on it.
Right.
And His fucking wife is probably sitting
next to him if he's even married,
whatever his fucking girlfriend,
he likes those Transylvania
hotties that Olga kind of chicks,
whatever.
He's just staring out the window
of his fucking Chapa. Right.
Just fucking sitting there
shaking his head, you know,
whole head moving to pay,
sitting still, you know.
Right on top of his head on a swivel.
Right.
She's just fucking sitting
there nagging him. You know?
I just thought you could have gotten a
little more social if like I was having,
those are my friends.
Okay. Those are my friends.
Those people are important to
me the same way you are. Okay.
You have to accept all of me.
Donald's stop looking at your skyscrapers.
I'm talking to you here.
This is us. Okay. I or just who? You're
the dawn. You have a hit show. Okay.
This is us. Okay. This
is your foundation. Well,
I don't feel like you're listening to me
because I'm staring at the back of your
orange hair. Okay? Okay. I'm sorry.
I know hair is sensitive
to you. It's just I'm, I'm,
I'm emotional right now and I felt okay.
They were,
I was going to invite my friends over,
right?
And then they go into that shit right
now here's a little quiz for you fellas.
Why did that fictitious bitch start
crying in that fictitious monologue?
Why did she cry? I'll give you a
couple of seconds to come up with it.
It was because she was really, I feel
like I'm giving a lecture right now.
It's just really sending my ego through
the fucking roof. Why did she cry?
Was it because she felt like he didn't
love her was because she was truly upset
that he wasn't nice to her friends or
was it because she took the argument to a
place where she knew she was wrong
by bringing up his fucked up hair?
That's what it was. Since she just, Oh
my God, I'm going to start losing this.
So then they immediately go to the tears.
That's what they do. They're terrible,
awful living things with a vagina now.
I'm kidding.
Um, anyways, but I'm not kidding about
why she cried. All right, so there it is.
So that's what you have to do as a guy.
You have to assess, why is she crying?
Am I being a Dick? If you're being
a dick and she starts crying,
that's when you go in and you hold them.
Any telling me you're sorry. All right.
And say please don't cry. But if it's
got nothing to do with fucking anything,
it's just, it's just a manipulative
technique to make you feel like,
like you're the hulk. You know when
you're screaming in their face. All right,
so you don't always have
to go in for the hug.
You don't always have to do it to
stand back and assess the situation.
One of them fucking
coordinators on the sidelines.
[inaudible] so listen to this shit.
I've come to Copenhagen
when I, when I travel to other countries,
boys and girls, believe it or not,
I am on my best behavior.
I always try to be overly polite.
I try and learn a couple of words and
a, I try to figure out their, their,
their money system. So I'm not
like going, you know, you know,
one of the weirdest things,
where are you going to another countries?
You immediately feel like a child,
especially if you don't know
the language and you're just,
the funniest thing is money transactions.
You just come up and you're like,
hey,
like hoping they speak English.
You almost say like hello with an accent.
Like hello.
I see.
Until you basically speak English in
your interpretation of their accent,
hoping they're going to understand you
and then they're like on 2000 Deutsche
marks or something. And then you
just a handful of fucking coins
and you just guess and your hand until,
you know, you just feel like a little kid.
Like,
is this enough for that Stubbs?
And you hand it to them and then you just
wait and you're waiting for that. Like,
uh, could I have a little more
or are you fucking shitting me?
Or they just sort of
take it and, um, anyways,
what's cool over here is a Denmark
they got, they have really cool, uh,
I liked their money.
I like any sort of money that has a
little hole drilled in the middle of it,
you know,
like some little Peush and people use
it as wheels and they somehow remove the
axle. And then the giant people used it
as currency. I liked that type of stuff.
So anyway,
so I come over here,
I'm on my best fucking behavior and when
I'm in the states and somebody comes
over there and they're
from another country,
I try to be extra nice store so they
have something nice to say. So anyways,
so I come here to Copenhagen.
Okay.
Um, which is in Denmark for all you
Americans, fellow Americans, I should say.
Look,
let me try to separate myself as if I
could find it on a map before I came here.
Um,
okay.
We jumped in the cab and I'm talking to
the promoter who's going to take me all
the way through Scandinavia.
You know,
that has all the ladies that
Hitler used to rub one out to,
wants to have blonde hair and
blue eyes. Yeah. Oh yeah. Right.
And, um, this is one of the
most fucked up podcasts so far.
How many times can you bring up Hitler?
Let's go for the record, shall we?
It's early on and podcasting history.
Um,
the first person to set the record,
or at least the first time it was tracked,
was bill burr back in
the early two thousands.
He had a podcast called
the Monday morning podcast.
It was highly successful until one day
it was permanently suspended from iTunes.
If you turn to page 17 in your
Monday morning podcast textbooks.
Um, so anyways, I'm in this
fucking cab and I have this thing.
Um,
I can never remember it from west to east.
If it goes, if it goes
Norway, Sweden, Finland,
or if it goes Finland, Sweden,
Norway. I always fucking forget.
Okay.
And why wouldn't I forget?
Those fuckers are never in the
God damn news other than that,
that tragedy and Norway. But other
than that, they're cool countries.
They don't fuck with people.
Yeah.
So they don't make the news. The only
reason why these fucking cunts over here,
nowhere America is, is because
we're bombing people. You know,
because we have basis in their country
because we're annoying the shit out of so
much of the world.
That's why they know where we're at.
Yeah.
So I'm in this cab and I'm having this
conversation with the promoter gun.
Does it go know what Norway,
Sweden, Finland, Finland, Sweden.
I can ever remember. And he
explains it to me. I go, okay, okay.
And then the cab ride ends and then the
cab driver turns around and goes on the
Americans. And so Stopa was the geography.
And then he goes, I'm just kidding John,
to be passive aggressive. I said,
Oh yeah, you fucking Danish.
Where's Tennessee in relation to
Missouri? And he goes, don't know.
I'm stupid to go fuck yourself
with your passive aggressive.
This cut said that shit. America is, yeah.
So still put was the geography and then
he does his little pussy smile and he's
just kidding. No, you're
not. No, you're not. You're
serious. You're miserable cunt.
Oh yeah.
You're so smart.
Did you go to fucking premed
to become a taxi cab driver?
You fucking Dosha and right there.
I swear to God.
In my head I was like,
fuck Denmark and fuck this show
tonight for like the next half hour.
That's what I was thinking.
And uh, then I was like, no,
I can't judge the whole fucking city.
I can't judge the whole country because
one douche drive and a cap. All right.
Put yourself in America. Do you find
cab drivers in America to be pleasant?
No, I do not. Do you find them to
be slightly miserable? Yes, I do.
If you drove a cab, would you be a
mess? Miserable. Cont yes, I would be.
And then I said, fuck it, let's give
these Danish cons of fucking show.
And um,
actually I was still nervous before
I went in to do the show and uh,
you know, you come all the way over
here and as much as they speak English,
you're, you're kind of
wondering, you know,
how much are they going to get?
And fortunately,
the night before I was in London and I
just made this decision probably about
10,
the first 10 months of my set in England,
I felt like I was a little on my heels
going and here's this joke and are you
going to get this? Okay,
here's another joke.
Are you going to get this? And then
I find he just said, you know what?
Fuck this.
I'm just doing my shit.
All right. And if they laugh, cool.
If they don't have Jesus, is this going
to be room service? Hang on one second.
Hang on one second. You're going to get
to hear me talk to a Danish person here.
Hello? Yes, yes, no, no, no.
Many wives. Cool. Okay.
Okay. All right. Thank you.
Oops, I got it. God
Damn European doors, I
can't even close it. Um,
so anyways, yeah, so I kind of,
I learned that when I was
in doing the show in London,
I just said to hell with it, you
know, just say, just do this shit.
Like you're standing in the
middle of Kentucky. Fuck it.
Just do your act and off they laughed.
They laugh and if they don't,
I will address it.
I will then make fun of the fact that
I was so stupid that you thought I was
going to get it or
something will come to me.
And then I was able to relax and
I had this fucking show in London,
so I was like, well, it
worked in London. Let me, uh,
let me do that over here.
Okay.
So I show up to this place in
Denmark and it's probably like a,
I dunno, 400 seater and I'm
not going to lie to you.
Only about 125 people showed
up, you know? But why,
why would foreign to people show up? I've
never been on TV over here, whatever.
This is the whole purpose of it.
And I got free DVDs for all these people,
right? So the, the, the, the
basic marketing strategies,
I'm going to go on stage,
fucking destroyed.
And then they're going to take these DVDs
and go onto, you must see this America,
next time it comes to Tanya.
Uh,
I apologize to anybody
from fucking Denmark who,
cause I keep making you guys
talk like fucking ss people.
I, I don't know. I can't,
I can't do your accent. Go fuck
yourselves. I'm trying. So,
um, they have this dude from Sweden
opened the show and he comes up and he's
speaking a, I don't know, Swedish Danish,
I don't know what the fuck Juan's
gals tries in face Andrade.
And uh, the crowd is, you know,
sort of Giggling, sort of laugh.
And it was kind of a weird thing where
there was a bunch of comedians in the
crowd. So, uh, this guy goes
on stage, he's a comedian,
he's a newer comedian. I don't
know what the deal is. And uh,
they're sort of laughing, but not really.
And then in my head I'm like, gone off.
Fuck is this, what's going to
happen to me and uh, but I dunno,
I just felt like this
great vibe in the room.
I went out there and I am the,
and I did what I would do in the states
cause I was sitting there in my head
going that's fucking cunt and the taxi
cab but mannequins that so stupid with
the geography was bugging
the shit out of me.
But I didn't want to go up there and
shit on one of their country man cause I
thought they would all pull back
and then they wouldn't like me.
Then I was like well what if this was
the states? What if you were down south?
You're clearly a fucking Yankee.
If some guys said, hey buddy,
you booked and critique
the Saskatoon Razz game.
That's what the fuck I would open
with soy. I said to hell with it.
That's what I'm doing here.
And I went out there and I shit all
over the guy add a and I basically said
something to the effect of Yeah did you
go to medical school to become a taxi
driver? And they laughed their asses
off and I was like, oh look at this.
Just like America,
except they're bilingual and uh,
and everything went great after that.
So,
and there's my European stories so far.
[inaudible]
underrated for the week.
Direct TV and getting
the NFL network people,
I don't give a shit what your landlord
says. Put a fucking addition on the side,
figure out a way to do it.
Steal somebody else's direct TV.
I got it is fucking phenomenal.
It's funny,
it's like you're on sports bar.
It's the greatest fucking thing ever
except you can just sit there and chill.
You don't have to fucking sit there and
listen to all those idiots who ruined
the gang. You know, you know those idiots,
those Jersey wearing
ball watching jack asses,
you know?
Okay.
Who like something happens and then
they yell at your table all day.
They do that shit.
That's some tough as shit.
Who couldn't even catch a basket of potato
skins if you under handed it to him.
Like he was a fucking three year old,
all of that shit.
Ah, oh. One of the last
times I went to a sports bar.
It was when the saints were on their run
and all of a sudden for the first time
in my life I saw saints fans,
you know,
and they all got their brand new fucking
jerseys on typical sports bar fans.
Brand new fucking jerseys
on. Go on. Who that? Who Dat,
who dat date they're going to beat them.
Saints.
It's just like where under what
fucking rock did you crawl?
What? Where the fuck are You Ben?
Right ball watching Jack asses.
You get the NFL package.
You don't have to deal with it anymore.
You don't have to fucking
deal with it anymore. I got,
I got that and I got the NHL
package and that's what I'm doing.
I'm going to get the MLB
package when that comes around,
I am going to have a $400 a month cable
bill and I'm going to sit there with a,
with a fucking Nirvana,
like look on my face as I pay
the cable bill every year.
I am every month I am
done with sports bars.
I don't know why the
fuck you would ever go.
Okay,
why the fuck you would ever go?
What do you want to see?
You want to see the sports bar horse.
Those are some of my favorite ones.
Isn't that great?
How women can make anything look sexy.
And all those girls that come there and
they tie their fucking jerseys off and
they put some grease out
of their eyes and he just,
and the little fucking Pony tail and
they act like they're there to watch the
game when they're really there,
you know,
just to test their pussy power
just to kind of walk around.
Okay.
Get everybody all fucking worked up.
I went to a place out
here a few weeks ago, uh,
down on Melrose called parlor live.
And I don't know,
I don't know if I'm getting old or what,
but it was a fucking mob scene.
You know something,
if I was in my twenties I would go
down there cause there was a ton of hot
chicks down there, you know, and
isn't that what you want? Is a guy,
some hot chick with a fucking pony
tail who actually watches sports,
you know, so I, I get, you know what,
I just realized I was too fucking old to
go down it cause I literally went down
there and I was like, why
does, why the TV so loud?
I can't hear myself back. Um, whatever.
All I'm saying is I'm telling you,
if you're younger,
you're in your twenties just don't,
don't,
don't go drink it for
a couple of weekends.
Pool that money together with your
roommates and go out and get a dish.
You fucking Douche bags.
I'm telling you. All right.
And then what you do is
you have people bootcamp,
you have those fucking sports
whores come over to your place.
There's your TV three feet over. Oh,
there's your desk. There's your bedroom.
It's right fucking there. Then they're
already used to coming over to your place.
If you hang out with them another
night and you invite them up,
the places already familiar. Oh Shit. I
think I'm on to summarize what you do.
If you're in your 20s pool your money
together with the other fucking slob.
Have a roommate or slobs. All
right, and this is the big thing.
And you invite your friends over and they
bring their brides over to, all right,
this is to get laid by the way,
cause I know a lot of sports fans will be,
well you don't want any girls there cause
they're just going to talk during the
game and shut up during the commercials.
I understand that,
but if you want to bang a couple of them,
this is what I do. You get that shit.
And the big thing is make sure
your fucking apartment is clean.
Make it immaculate.
All right?
There's nothing that dries up a pussy
like a dirty apartment. I'm telling you,
if they walk in and they feel that
they're gonna fuck inside of a laundry bag
that they're out, they're out the
door. And if you try and make a move,
you have a 30% chance that they're
going to scream rape. All right?
All that shit that everybody
says is for fucking cool
centered,
can't get something,
some sort of fucking decent
smell going on in there.
Take the shit from your male friends
when they come in like, dude,
it smells like a fucking candle store.
Would you pull that thing out of your ass?
Take that shit.
All right.
All you have to show is this in your 20s
all you gotta do is show remotely some
level of fucking maturity and I'm
telling you, you're in the God damn game.
I don't know. There's something about him.
He dresses nice. His apartment is clean.
I think he's worthy of
answering my vagina,
right?
What the fuck is I, I don't even
get me started with that shit.
Those people who dress up for games,
you know like those stupid
fucking raider fans,
what are they doing?
Do they understand how it went from one
of the scariest places you could ever
play to now looking,
it looks like a musical looks
like a Broadway musical.
Like I look at that and all,
I don't think intimidating.
I think Phantom of the opera.
I really wish I knew some of that music.
I'm sure a lot of the people in the black
hole and they stand up for the whole
game.
Do they?
Hey, look, it's Darth Vader. Gee,
I don't know if I can
catch this football now,
raider nation, you guys have the best
fucking uniforms and all of football.
You have the best logo.
You have the baddest fucking tradition,
and I don't know what you guys did to it.
You need to get those Saifai road warrior
want to be out of your stadium and you
got to go back to looking like the
fucking hell's angels like you used to be.
You know, look, I'm not going to
stop. I'm not gonna lie to you.
I was actually gonna go to the Patriots
game up there with a buddy of mine and
he's like, dude, we're not wearing any
patriots shit. I go, fuck a fuck. No,
this is the west coast. The Shit isn't
fun out here. People get stabbed,
they get shot. You lose an eye. They're
out of their fucking minds. All right?
But I can tell you right now, Boba
Fett is not doing that shit. Okay.
Or the guy with his fucking shoulder pads
and his fake spikes coming out of it.
Oh, with the band bandanas
in your face makeup.
You know, what I love about those
guys is I just want to see them,
you know when they're their alter ego,
you know like when they're in Burt ward
mode and they're just waddling down the
street going to work.
Yeah.
No
Jesus Christ.
Um,
yeah I think you guys need to go back
to looking like fucking Ken Stabler and
Jack Tatum. You know, you really should
go back to that and you know something.
I'm actually being,
I'm not being fair to open rate of fans
right now cause I've been to a game up
there and most of them look that way and
I actually talked to a couple of them
and they fucking can't stand those guys
who dress up like they were in the rocky
horror picture show and typical TV,
typical TV.
Who Do they put on,
do they put on the real rate of fan was
just sitting there maybe with the rate
of t shirt or just dressing
with the black tee shirt.
It looks like he'd slice your throat.
You know,
like a normal upstanding raider fan
looks like. Now who do they put on?
They put on the guy dress like the chef,
the muppet show,
the fake scar pain and on is do it.
At one point they had some guy,
I was watching the game and this
Douche bag is just sitting there,
this face painted and he's like,
yeah,
okay.
Like what happened to you?
You know what happened?
His balls dried up this disappoint.
Like they don't really talk
about this in health class.
In high school you get to a point where
you're such a douchebag and it's been so
long since you actually laid
down with the woman that you're,
your balls turned into saw dust and uh,
the estrogen levels go up. And
the next thing you know, you,
you go out and you buy a
little vanity and you're like,
I just don't want to
go to a football game.
I want to go there and character
five thick Theban eight.
Shaneal um,
Oh God,
help me the next time I go up
to the bay area. Um, so anyways,
so we were going to go to
the game and they, and right
off the bat I'm like, Dude,
I'm not wearing any patch
shit. And the dude's like,
yeah, absolutely not. I don't,
you know, why would you do that to
yourself? You know? Why would you get,
especially out on the west
coast where you get shot,
stabbed the Illusia fucking eye.
So we came up with this great plan.
I ended up not going up there, but I, I
want to pass this on to my listeners here.
This is a great thing that you can do,
especially when you know
your team's going to win.
You go there dressed in the other team's
colors and then you act upset when your
team is kicking the shit out of him.
That's what I was going to do.
I wasn't going to wear a Raiders thing.
I was going to go there and a black,
black thermal,
and it's Tom Brady was marching up and
down the field and everybody around me
was going, oh, what the fuck? I
be like, yeah, come on, watch.
They're probably going to score
again. Oh Great. Just what we needed.
You know, it's funny, nobody would have
noticed. No one would ever stop and go,
wait a minute,
this guy looks like a fucking Leprechaun.
We don't have any red heads and in fucking
Oakland, this guy's a double agent.
They never would have been able to
figure it out. You know why? Cause they
too much makeup in their eyes.
[inaudible]
I've got to say this was I right?
Was I right about Mark Sanchez?
I'm sure he's a great guy. I'm sure
he makes a hell of a Salisbury steak.
You know, I'm sitting there watching ESPN.
Okay. And I've been saying it for years.
Like the way to beat the jets is
you have to go up by two scores,
touchdown in a field goal.
That's all you need.
And then all of a sudden mark has to
be a quarterback and he has to make
something happen. He can't just manage
the game and be like, don't throw, pick,
don't throw a pick mark and just
fucking throw it out bounds.
He has to try and do something.
Okay.
All right. Well this year, you know,
they lost a couple of players on d.
They got a couple of injuries.
Now all mark has to be captain come back.
And uh, you know, I was watching TV on
ESPN. They said, you know what do you,
when you're running games
not working it and a,
you could only hit intermediate passes
and you can't throw the ball deep pla.
That's going to be easy to defend against.
And I'm sitting there on the
couch going say it. Say it,
just fucking say it.
He's not as good as you tried to tell
me that he was okay. And New York is,
if you ever wondered why everybody
fucking hates you guys. All right.
Yes we are jealous of your fucking
awesome city. It is awesome. All right,
but not cause you're there before
you puff up your man tits. All right?
This is why I can't stand
New York, because if you
play sports in New York City,
if you just scratch your ass, they call
you a fucking star. It's ridiculous.
If Mark Sanchez played for the fucking
Seahawks, if he played for the chiefs,
if he was down there in Texas playing
for them, fucking texted down in Houston,
you wouldn't hear a fucking
word about that guy.
All right?
But all of a sudden he plays in New
York and he's got dreams. Me Ice, man,
you stay. Start Ramming them now my
throat, like he's this fucking superstar.
Very fast guy. Very elusive. Difficult
to sac. I'll give him that shit.
All right, was the last time
you saw him throw a frozen rope.
Put that fucker ball. Ace does the back
shoulder thing. Oh, he's all right.
You know. Well, everybody down
there saying he's a fucking stock.
Give me a God damn break.
All right.
Give me a fucking break.
That guy is his upper mediocre.
Yeah.
I would rather have Philip Rivers.
Then I wouldn't Mark Sanchez and that's
sitting there throwing this guy now my
God damn throat. While his
defense is winning games,
he's like, fucking Jim McMann.
Jimmy
man walking around with spiked hair
and sunglasses on while I was fucking
defense. Shuts everybody down. Oh
Gee, did you win the gang? Jimmy.