Hey,
what's going on is Phil Berger and uh,
just checking it on you so I can't yell
too loud. Okay. Yell too loud. The street.
I thought Monday the peas and everything
will pop it on this fucking thing.
So I'm gonna try to hold
it a little further away.
Maybe talk a little bit louder.
Um,
welcome to the Thursday afternoon.
Monday morning podcast just before Friday,
Aka the just checking in
on podcast for June 4th,
2015. Ah, fuck. I'm
missing everything. Oh No.
I miss game one of the Stanley Cup finals.
I literally just woke up about an
hour ago. I'm still fucking jetlagged.
So, uh, I stay up and I drink as a cafe.
Wait until like,
that's how I put myself to sleep.
Like Nia is always going to take a
sleeping pill. Just take one of these.
And I'm always like, I'm not taking
that thing. She goes, why? I go,
cause that's like a 10 day
bender to u of t your liver.
Why don't I go down to the cafe and I'll
fucking drink like Ernest Hemingway,
you know, which is really just like, yeah,
it's only a one day bender to your liver.
Right.
I guess if you drink like
Hemingway or John Bottom,
then it's considered maybe like a
three day bender. I don't know what,
but that's how I do it. That
is how I do it. Sorry. So, um,
okay.
Yeah. Well last night neo
was more tired than I was,
so she came back to La Plata Mount and um,
she was going to go to sleep.
So I was like,
why am I gonna fucking be
down here by myself, you know,
like some goddamned degenerate.
Um, so I came back here.
Uh,
I don't know that I've been fucking up
every sense and I was not up ever since.
I stayed up to like three,
four in the morning,
ended up waking me up inadvertently.
And um,
okay.
So we started watching this,
this video of this trial,
I guess it already happened. This, this
woman who seem really, really nice.
She met this guy who was some his parents
smoked crystal meth and he got himself
out of it, raised themselves,
became uh, uh, um,
okay.
Are Those Byu People
Mormon became a Mormon,
you know, was trying to abstain from
sex. He got himself a little side piece.
Basically she was just a side piece to
him and she loved him and then he ends up
dumping her and then she's still kinda
came back and hooked up with them every
once in awhile.
And uh,
okay.
and then she realized that she was getting
the old heave Ho a keyword there is
how,
that's how she felt like she was being
treated and she came back one night and
she fucking killed him, stabbed him
up, shot him, and then stabbed him,
fucking slit his throat,
all this crazy shit.
And then came up with the worst fucking
story ever was that there was two people
that intruded
killed him,
put the gun to her head, pulled the
fucking trigger and the gun didn't go off.
And then she grabbed your person or your
keys and all that ran out of the house
as the, I guess the two of them are going
like, can you believe it didn't go off?
Wait a minute,
where did that woman goes?
So then she gets in the
car and fucking drove away,
stunned out into the middle of the
desert and didn't call anybody or tell
anybody anything and actually visited
other people and never said a fucking word
to anybody. And, uh, five days later,
the dude's friends came into the
apartment and found his body and uh,
and she got the, she got
the death penalty. Fucking
crazy story. Isn't that nice?
Is that uplifting for Thursday,
Thursday afternoon?
I got to tell you,
I was watching an interview and she
really seemed like a nice person.
She seemed like a sweetheart. And I
like to think that I got a good gauge,
but it was fucking a, I
dunno, it's disturbing.
I don't know. You know, it was even
more disturbing than that was yesterday.
I went out and I got a cheeseburger.
Right. Ah, they got this place,
has cheeseburger over here in Nia
is fucking hilarious. She goes, hey,
there's got the best burger in Paris
is supposed to be at this place.
And I'm like, fuck yeah, I
like cheeseburgers, let's go.
And it wasn't until after I've finished
the cheeseburger and said it was fucking
delicious that she told me that she
learned about the place by watching a
keeping up with the Kardashians and Chloe,
he said that that was her favorite
fucking place to get a burger. And I go,
why wouldn't you tell me that?
And she goes,
because if I fucking told you that you
wouldn't want it to eat here or are you
trying to come in? Uh, hang on a second.
The lovely mia. Everybody
posts show up. Punch. Your mom
was deaf. No, I say madame,
I sent him a dumb cause you're married,
right? Wait, wait. All right, come on
Kim. On Aqua. Chloe's the big one,
right as j law had says the power forward,
power forward of the Kardashians.
Lay down here cause I don't really mind.
I would say she's the tallest.
Maybe not the biggest since Kim is
pregnant. Congratulations Kimi cakes.
All right. You have, you will have
to leave. All right. So anyways,
so here's the thing. I did the most
disgusting thing I ever did in my life.
Like we are a side dish
or macaroni and cheese.
I took the macaroni and cheese and
I put it in the bottle of Greece.
It was ag on the, on the Burger
too. So there was bake. No,
but I'm saying the puddle was the Ang
yoke in the grease from the Burger and I
put macaroni and cheese in it.
It's the most disgusting
thing I've ever done.
But it was absolutely fucking delicious.
I you can't tell me I didn't block
at least one of my, uh, what is it?
Your aorta arteries, your
ventricle, the vulva.
I'm very [inaudible] was amazing.
I would go back
before the end of this
trip to be honest with you.
I was thinking about it this morning.
I'm off Saturday.
I'm just thinking of friends within
our bump. Paris highly recommended. Oh,
you have to text for a reservation,
which you won't be able to
figure out unless you're near,
cause I wouldn't have been
able to figure out what,
I'm sick of the French with their
little tables. Oh wait. Oh really? Why?
Oh,
because it just like if they got these
little fucking table table table every,
not everything is little here.
Well that's because it's a fucking
rip off. You know, it's like New York.
It was a super small apartments,
but I mean New York you can sit down
and have an adult size table at those
fucking doll house tables make,
God forbid you order some food,
you got to pick your drink up. Don't
let me see. It was almost all pleased.
Your moves the glass. Um, so anyways,
I'm glad you're here to taper
this part. Uh, so I was,
I was over here and Nia showed me
the cover of what magazine was that?
Vanity Fair. Vanity Fair was
talking about Caitlyn Jenner. Yeah,
the Dash Kardashians just blew it.
I was going to fucking build the whole
thing up cause I was looking at how do I
know, I'm like, how do I know that chick?
Is that somebody we know you're a woman?
And I was thinking she's not good enough.
She's not good looking enough to be
on the cover. Is she a publicist?
Is She some famous publicists? And
then it was Mick, Caitlyn Jenner.
Caitlin with us. See,
wow. I gotta tell you man,
that is the most relations Katelyn
cakes. I know. I got to tell you,
that is the most,
listen,
those was hardcore thing
I've ever seen played out.
Okay.
And like,
uh,
all that Marilyn Manson Shit and Alice
Cooper and Ozzie biting the head off a
bat. Nothing compares to
the what the fuck factor.
And I'm not saying I'm to like, you
know, you're comparing like, like shock,
shock, shock rock tactics to someone
becoming transgendered. I really don't.
Somebody that you knew not, can you
let me, can you let me continue up?
They're ignorant thought. Sure.
No, you shouldn't say that.
This is the first time
I ever experienced this.
I had to be able to fucking say
what I'm thinking. You see his own,
his own daughters that go
in like so wait a minute,
you're going to be
borrowing my toenail Polish.
They got to get their head around it.
I'm allowed to get my head
around I so I bless him. Okay.
That's what he wanted to tilt chair.
Well he did it now he's now he's a shape.
Is He? But he still has his Dick, right?
Bell does he or she wants to be called
she, she wants to be called Kaylin.
Okay. I'm cool. I'm all right with
that. She has not had surgery.
No she has not.
Yeah
I think that's an issue if you chase.
So she has a penis and she,
she still is she at this point?
Correct. Cause those are,
the reality is is you don't
have to do any of that.
You can say I want to be called Chez
and people should just respect it pretty
much because it's the whole idea about
gender not necessarily being rooted in
physicality or sexuality. It being more
of a state of mind. So this is like,
so this is a big debate of course.
So this is like some Ornette Coleman Shit.
Who is that with your
body or their Coleman?
He was one of those guys who
played so free with jazz.
There was really no one and even like
Charlie Parker would walk off the band
stair going, I don't know what the fuck
these guys are playing. Okay. So right.
I think this is a groundbreaking thing
that he's the first and he will be like,
he's like the uh, I don't
know what though. Well,
I'm not going to wade into that
fucking sinkhole. God knows.
I'll say the wrong fucking thing first.
The chance gendered person on the
cover of Time magazine last year,
which was actually the first, no, no,
but I mean as far as Cox
from orange is the new black.
And what was her name before
that? Larry? I don't know.
And it doesn't fucking matter. I think
you should, you should keep your like,
like I, I would, I would be, I go
Trump bill. I would be Beth. Beth,
can we talk about that?
Decided to transition was you
really go bad, bad? No, I think,
I think I'd be Janet and
I would be such a cunt.
Ridiculous.
Yeah.
But you don't mean now as a
male I'm awarded for being
an asshole. You know, that,
that ridiculous feminist theory that
if a woman does it, she's a con.
But if a guy does a Doula,
you want to be president.
Moron's um, I feel like, man,
I did not hear the microphone
assholes when they're assholes,
but I don't think they're morons for
saying that men get to get to do what it
get to act, especially in
business. And the more, um,
let's say cut cutthroat like a mark Cuban.
Mark Cuban is a fucking deck,
but Mark Cuban is also brilliant
and a really successful businessman.
But I feel like more often than not,
he gets called brilliant and amazing.
Even think it's called a jackass.
All the tests all the time when he runs
out on the court and it does all that
stuff hit off the court. You Jackass
for always saying like, you know,
Mark Cuban is a business
genius and you know, no, yes,
but he is. He's undeniably is. But
he does, he doesn't get good reviews.
That guy gets trashed on the time in
order to answer is you guys have bad
experiences with men while you're dating
and they get to be dicks and bang you
and then leave and you never
quite are able to wash that off.
So I think that you guys then
look at us in a certain way.
I'm able to separate my experiences from
dating Dick's to dealing with Dixon day
to day life. I am not so simple
minded and like one dimensional that
me one time and now they're all
deck like you fucking kidding me.
But there was a period in your life,
you can't tell me that you didn't get a
little petty. I did. I actually never did.
I did all those guys that dumped me.
No,
I did not necessarily have
the track record with men,
but I didn't write you all off because
of that. I still was looking for love.
So what I'm saying is as far as like the
most hardcore fucking thing I've ever
seen as far as just spinning in your head
around like Holy Shit is the fact that
Bruce Jenner, unlike that other woman,
why don't even know who the fuck that is.
Who's on Time magazine is that this
guy you're going to send my whole life.
I've known this guy from like second
grade on, he wanted the catalog.
He was on the Wheaties box.
He was on chips.
He got a nose job and then he
disappeared and then he came back on the
Kardashians and he was walking
around in the background.
I remember law had had this great fucking
bit. Yes. It's been like, what the,
why are you sitting there getting bitch
said you got to fucking gold medal for
the catalog. They got you walking
around in the background. You know,
like you know,
I used to be walking around with that
medal around your neck or something.
Right to then,
I remember when when Tmz was chasing
around saying that he was having a sex sex
change, I was like, oh my God,
leave the guy alone. You know,
he doesn't like his face
and out and I dunno he's,
he's doing whatever the fuck he's doing
it and then it turned out they were
right and now when he comes out,
call me Caitlyn.
I mean this is the thing like,
because what, I don't know,
I said this is going to be a lot of people
that get in trouble as they're trying
to fucking process this
for the first time.
This is their first time experience and
I think you want to allow people to have
that,
that first dumb thing that comes out of
their mouth not understanding and being
like, what? But everybody's
going to jump on him and someone,
someone will lose their career to sit
down and watch this guy like you wanted to
be this guy,
you wanted to be Bruce Jenner.
I wanted my hair parted down the
middle and fed it to the side.
I wanted to be a motorcycle cop.
I wanted to do all of that shit.
And then all of a sudden I remember
reading articles about him,
like his fucking life, you
know, he's in between, you know,
girlfriends or whatever.
And uh,
they went to his house and
he had some Porsche target.
I still remember this in Sports Cilia,
porch target in the garage that he
walked by and he ran his fingers along.
He had a little bit of dust on
it. I'm like, this guy, he's so,
this shit that he just has
a leftover Porsche. I mean,
who was like a guy's guy that
then boom, go the other, that 180,
the other other fucking way.
I think people should be
allowed to be honest with it.
I just feel like the cruelty is, is what's
unnecessary. No, no, no. Not Cruelty.
But you want to be able to say like,
Bruce, what the, sorry, Kate lucked up.
Wow. Wait a minute. Leyla
and I sit down for a Sunday.
We're talking governments in one of
his sons from his other marriages,
like Brandon or something. And
she lifted up her dress. So,
uh, his other new boobs and he
goes, Whoa, I'm still your son.
Cause it's like, Whoa,
wait, just give me a second.
And then another one of his foot,
he was snow show his balls of course.
What you came from John?
Of course. No, of course.
It was definitely I that would
be very uh, uh, weird. No,
but that's always been my theory,
but, and the girls who get fake boobs,
we'll show them to you like they got
their nails done cause it's an insecurity
thing.
So it'd be like saying
I have two friends was amazing boob jobs.
I never would have known there.
So the Soca, you gotta he gotta pay
for it. You know what I'm saying?
He can't go out in there
and get discount plastic.
Danny's when you're getting a boob job,
like whatever,
the facial reconstruction that
Caitlin has had is a fucking amazing.
Now of course she's still is a handsome
woman, but like it really, it looks good.
And those, those, those times,
she's still a handsome woman.
Did you mean that she started
off as a handsome guy? No,
there were some women
that are like handsome.
This whole thing that I'm saying right
now, this whole thing that I just said,
what do you mean like that?
The assist the handsome guy or like the
woman right now, you know what this,
this is,
this whole fucking scenario is why I
never watched lost what is why I never
watched lost.
How did you come the dream state?
Is there a fucking monster down here?
What's going on?
And then now you're jumping
back and forth on either side.
It's like he's playing tennis
against himself right now.
It's kind of like your add
brain actually. Oh, is it?
It's kind of like bringing around, look,
I'm on vacation in front of a good size.
Um, but you know what else?
Um, uh, one of his kids,
her kids to see even I'm slipping
with the Pronoun. You homophobe,
transgendered, hater, what's
your career? We need to, and it,
uh, my career is lagging
around with you and France
on Twitter gave me shit.
Anybody who starts at tweet with the word,
maybe I'm done with,
maybe don't, blah, blah, blah. Oh No.
I was saying one of Caitlin's. Dot.
I son said I'm, I'm, I'm hoping,
I think or something like that. Katelyn
will be a better parent than Bruce was.
No, I mean he's been, I mean
she's been pretty open and add it.
And then if Katelyn Stone's
crying and be like, Kayla,
I wasn't talking to you
talking about no by, uh,
by all accounts, especially his, his first
set of kids, he wasn't there. They were,
Bruce wasn't there for them cause
he was a fucking man. And now that,
now that now that Bruce
has become Caitlyn,
you think feminine and
he won the gold medal,
Caitlin still has to prove
herself. She hasn't won shit. Yes,
she's won all of our
hearts. Um, all right,
well but you know something else then
there's also the then falling all over
yourself. There's, there's the
ignorant being mean about it.
Then also the going the other way
where you fall all over yourself and if
Caitlyn's being a cunt, you can't
call her. Cause she used to be Bruce,
which is bullshit.
Well,
I guess Bruce was an asshole because
Bruce really wanted to be Kaitlin and it
was struggling and was taking it out on
other people and was literally running
away. I think Katelyn, who's
going to be the biggest gossipy,
he's going to go to brunch and just talk
shit about everybody in her immediate
circle. I'm pretty excited to see
how this unfolds. Actually, it's,
it's pretty a major. Are you
going to watch the her show? No,
I never watched the Kardashians.
Oh, that's true. I hate
those fucking shows. Yeah,
that makes sense. And to be
honest with you, I would have,
I'll just sort of walk by the
TV and occasionally glance over.
I need to ease my way into,
you are my soul there and I am done.
I have the fucking right to
do that. Yes you do. Yeah.
When you make that big of a fucking
change, Jesus Christ, I shaved my head.
People like,
what the,
yeah, you've got to give people, you
gotta have you gotta be courteous.
It let people like fucking
guy. Let me, uh, okay. Okay.
You should have like five minute visits
and then they increased the 10 and you
just got to gradually like,
I mean,
you literally get like you
killed off the other person.
Yeah.
You know what I mean? Pretty much.
Yeah. Yeah. Like where are they?
Yup.
Nolan.
Yeah. So then it, and then
it's weird. It's like, well,
I technically should be liking you.
Right. But you're not the other person,
but you still,
you.
Hmm.
Do you think he did something like
he sold his soul to the devil.
He's like trying to beat the
devil at his own game and that,
that'll be just becoming like a woman
at the end of his life so he could save
his soul. And the devil's
it, it's like, I don't know,
like angel hot. Are you talking
about a movie with Lisa Monet?
Yeah, Mickey Rourke. We cipher.
Um, anyways, I don't fucking know
bill burns. Caitlyn Jenner.
No, I didn't. I fucking,
I'm getting my head around it because I'm,
I should allow it to be allowed to do,
um,
anyway.
Anyways.
MMM.
A lot of shit to say. Oh, you don't
want to miss last night was the, uh,
cause I couldn't find my fucking password.
God knows I was awake.
Was the first of the Stanley Cup playoffs.
And um, is it that time of
the year again? All right.
That time of day when you could say so.
I'm sure we can find some errors.
French pub,
Irish French pub. They're going to have
soccer or they're going to have rugby.
Oh Zero Roland Garros highlights.
Oh well listen.
So I saw Tampa was up one to nothing
when I fell asleep and I was like, wow,
wouldn't that be really amazing
if they won game one? Um,
well wait, is it in Tampa?
I think it's in Tampa.
I'm trying to think of the highlights.
I think Chicago had on
their white jerseys. I can't
remember. They won game one.
Like what that would do to this series.
Like immediately you got to think
it's going to six or seven. Um,
so anyway,
so the rough one and nothing.
Okay.
And then am I excited that, you
know, Chicago score too late.
Goals to win the game.
So I got all excited.
I want to put on the
highlights of Seiu scored.
So I put on the highlights and it ended
up depressing the hell out of me when I
watched it because, uh, you know,
to Tampa Bay lightning fans who have been,
uh, just let you know as a Bruins Fan,
I've been there against Chicago.
It was the deciding game.
Like we were trying to force a game
seven and we were up by a goal.
It's like a a minute nine left and they
scored two goals in the final minute to
not only beat us to win the Stanley
Cup and celebrate on our ice and our
building. So kind of took me back
to that, but uh, what, uh, I don't,
I can't remember who did what,
but that first goal they had, um,
that guy who stole the puck just
poke checked it away. It just,
that just gives you the idea how fucking
good those guys are at that level.
You just poke checked away in two seconds
later. It's in the back of the neck.
And uh, just amazing. I
hope Tampa wins game too,
cause I really want to see a series
and I'm hoping it's still going to go.
Both the NBA and the NHL Finals will
be for games and when we get back,
and I'm obviously open for serious.
Would you like out of
Cleveland in Sacramento?
Near Cleveland has Lebron
James Sacramento's got a
Steph curry who's forever
chewing his mouthpiece.
Um,
okay. Thank you. You don't
watch. All right. Let me, uh,
let me wrap this thing up.
All right.
You want me to get up because we're done
talking about reality TV and Shimizu
CBU play
[inaudible] see,
we'll play. Um, anyway. Uh,
so I'm psyched to see that.
I gotta get my password and uh,
I think this is what I'm going to do.
I'm going to fucking hang out here.
I'm going to booze it up and then at
night I'm going to come back and watch the
NBA and the Stanley Cup finals.
That wouldn't suck. Right.
Um,
so what else did I want to talk about?
Oh fuck. I forgot to
bring this up since, uh,
two weeks ago when I was
telling you guys to watch,
I watched that Bollywood movie, that
Res Return of Singham or single returns.
I gotta tell you something.
I saw the most bootleg fucking NBA tee
shirt I've ever seen in my life is in
that, in that movie. And uh,
the bad guys wearing it.
Anybody from India,
if you could please explain
to me the context of this.
It was a Chicago Bulls tee shirt,
red tee shirt with the,
uh,
with the red bull mascot and above
where it should have said bowls.
It said chef,
like c h e s like someone's
going to cook you a meal.
And I remember looking at that code.
How to the chef, is that like a
Hindu for fucking bull? I have
no fucking idea. You know,
and then I'm thinking of bowls.
A male cow.
And they don't eat cows over there
or they're not supposed to with,
some of them are,
you know,
so why would they say that?
Is that like some punk rock shit?
Like this guy is such a bad guy. He's
saying he's going to eat the fucking bull.
No, right. Fuck you. I can hear you
laughing in India from here. All right.
Just let me know what the hell that
means if you don't mind. So, um,
anyways, uh, I'm sorry guys.
We don't have a fucking TV here.
I don't know what's going on in the world.
So I would have to just rip something
here to give you your fucking half hour
for the week.
Yeah.
I've never been more home sector when I
watched fucking those nhls highlights.
Okay.
All right. Google news. God
knows this is reputable, right?
Where do we go here? Where
do we go? Google news. Bam.
All right. So you think six things
to know about Rick Perry? I Dunno.
One thing about it with a fucking see.
So you think Texas got former Texas
governor Rick Perry who launched this 2016
campaign on Thursday.
Six things you may know about him.
Oh, he's from Texas. That
means he's tough on crime.
He doesn't like gay people and he thinks
she ought to be able to smoke in public.
That's what I'm guessing.
There's three things I'm going to guess
about a son of paint creek Perry's life
until he attended college,
revolved around the small hand
scrabble community of pain.
I don't give a fuck about that.
He's a former Democrat pilot wings.
He joined the famous corp of cadets at
Texas a and m university to earn an Air
Force commission upon his graduation.
All right. I like them creating jobs,
felony charges. You also skipped by the
good stuff. Let's get to the juice here.
Perry's attorneys, I've asked the
Texas appeals court to dismiss charges,
discharge, felony charges against
him, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
What the fuck did he do sentence
for drunk drive enough? I did that.
A union member.
He's a Republican who was a card carrying
union member. All right, awesome.
That's a good mix. Hey, I remember what
I have. Somebody sent me to talk about.
Did you guys see that article on the
Red Cross raising all of that money,
like $1 billion or something for,
for aid and Haiti and they only,
they said they were going to build all
these houses and roads and get people
electricity and all they've been able
to accomplish is get make six houses and
um,
some people are blaming the uh,
the lack of infrastructure
and on Haiti or whatever.
But I'm telling you right now,
more and more of these ds.
Yeah.
These, uh, I guess charities are,
are getting exposed for, I mean,
I can't say that they're all,
they're all bad. Um, sorry,
I'm looking at this fucking thing up.
But
Yeah,
Red Cross Haiti scandal. Let me
look this up so maybe I can read it.
So it's somewhat intelligent
here. Where is it? Where is it?
Red Cross misuse of funds for Haiti.
Sparks protest.
Sorry. All right, here we go.
Yeah.
354 million raised 1.6
million spent and allocated.
MMM.
Haitian American organizer
issued organizers issued
a series of complaints and
called for strict accountability early
last week over the misuse of over one
11.6 billion in donated funds.
Promise for post earthquake
relief in Haiti. 11.6 billion.
You could rebuild the whole
fucking country, couldn't
you? It's a little island.
What does he hate?
He shares a Dominican Republic is with
Cuba and then Haiti's their own little
island. Right? I Dunno Macy. I don't
know anything about the covenant meal.
Uh, whatever. So classic fucking thing.
Hang on one second. Hang on, hang on him.
Okay.
Alright, I'm back. Sorry
about that. This dummy.
Can somebody tell me like a
charity that you just know?
It seems like Saint Jude is the
only one that I, Jimmy Fund.
The Cam Nealy House. Oh, the only
ones that I've seen that really just
like the lion's share of the money.
Yeah. For obvious expenses. You know,
you've got to rent out a
venue and that type of shit.
All the Patrice O'Neal benefit.
I can tell you without a doubt.
What'd you guys do with Sunday?
You found out?
I was actually keeping all the fucking
man, that would just be the end.
It'd be end of everything.
Me Stepping out of my
Prius have a no comment.
By the way, we're looking at the first
Tuesday in March for the next one. Um,
so anyways,
one of the,
somebody said all of the money
the Red Cross has collected,
uh,
yeah,
I know of only one location where they
gave out plastic bottles of water while
providing no shelter or any
significant amount of food.
I mean, these guys, they getting them
and they're getting trashed here.
Now please tell me,
is this making national news?
Is this anywhere on the
news or are they not there?
Because what ends up happening
is the Red Cross, you know,
they advertise on television so they
don't get to advertise for free.
So those networks are making money off
of the Red Cross and that sound networks
make their money is through advertising.
So there's an immediate conflict
of interest where it's like,
should we do this report?
You know,
these guys give us $1 million
a year up to advertise.
We're throwing $1 million
out the fuck window.
If we say that these fucking guys
aren't doing the right thing. Um,
so I dunno,
I'm not in the state so I'm going to,
if they're actually show
him the same anyways,
this whole fucking thing's just
petering out. Um, all right,
so four days end of this trip.
I'm not going to lie to you
already miss being home. Um,
but I got that a sporting event coming
up and going to the tennis game.
So that's my, my big thing. Other than
that, I'm just over here sitting in cafes,
boozing it up. Oh by no fucking
way. If you ever come over here,
which you should include,
that negative content got mad at me for
fucking bringing it up that I was over
here.
Like I'm supposed to lie when I'm supposed
to be and if you're listening you're
a Douche bag.
Your tweet really depressed the hell
out of me for like five seconds.
Cause not because I give
a fuck what you think.
It's because when I was
young and was not confident,
it was an introvert.
Someone like you could have fucked me
out of becoming a comedian. All right?
You need to work on yourself.
And you know,
it doesn't cost that much
fucking money to come over here.
He kept college kids come
over here and backpack,
just sleep in a fucking hostile. You want
to come over, you can make it happen.
Lay off the booze, you know,
make some sacrifices, you know,
fucking asshole,
making it seem like I bought Paris
over here on his fucking seven day
bender. So anyways, um,
and if you have somebody like debt your
life, you've got to get rid of them.
Don't ever be afraid to literally just
fire a friend, you know what I mean?
Call them into your office and just
say, listen, this isn't working out.
And they'll be like, why? What
are you talking about this?
Because anytime I want to do anything
with my life that's going to take me into
a direction they want to go.
You fucking pull it back the
reins because you're a client.
So you're right in my life. So anyways,
so when you do come over here, everybody,
if you choose to,
um,
you got to watch out for the
fucking Gypsies bad. These guys,
these men and women are,
they're so good at pickpocket
and you can't even get mad at it.
I'm a cab driver gave us
the whole fucking breakdown.
They actually there to the point
now because everybody's on to them.
Like don't Fret French police are run to,
they actually,
they show up dressed like tourists.
They have cameras around their neck,
socks pulled up too high,
you know,
just walking around like a
bunch of fucking nerds like me.
And they will literally walk up to you
one bumps into the others in your fucking
pockets before he,
before you even know what's going on.
And I know what you're saying, like, oh,
that old trick, that old trick. You wait,
you wait, you'll come over here
and you'll be like, uh, you know,
finish in a fucking meal.
And UBS using while at the TCO,
TCO, TCO, TCO. See, we'll
play music check, right?
Then I'll bring it over to you and you
go to gold for your fucking wallet.
And it's God. You're
like, well, I, I didn't,
I didn't walk near anybody.
I just fucking glided over here.
I think I said hello to one press.
I got you say a load on them and
they got your fucking wallet.
So you got to watch out.
So I know a lot of you guys are thinking,
where are they from?
Where are these Gypsies from?
That's the question I asked. We just
travel around and not from anywhere.
Um,
should,
I probably shouldn't say where they're
from cause I'm sure there's plenty of
decent people there.
Uh,
but it rhymes with Romania.
So anyways, that's the Thursday
afternoon. Just before Monday morning.
Thursday.
What is fine Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcasts just
before Friday. And other
words, nobody's. Yeah. Yeah.
Um, it was a classic kit from fucking
back in the data and what they're going to
play. Uh, anyways, I'm going
to try to watch the, uh,
gay more than the NBA finals tonight
and that's it. Have a wonderful day. Uh,
and go fuck yourself.
Yeah.
Oh,
do I see the star light?
No
kisses
camera two. Hey Bill, uh, maybe you
can help me out with this um, thing.
Now I haven't read any of these things
people. So, uh, bear with me here. Uh,
this sounds ridiculous but hear me out.
I met this girl a couple of weeks ago
and I've been talking to her and hanging
out with her nonstop.
Okay.
We is pretty
what?
I guess it's, she is
pretty, she's pretty funny,
intelligent and one of the most upfront
and upfront and honest people I've ever
met in my life. In fact,
maybe a little too honest,
cause she tells me every day how great,
cute and
honest I am. And it's a little
much sometimes. Anyways,
we've been hitting it off like crazy.
And on Saturday she spent the night and
we hung out all day Sunday about nine,
around 9:00 PM,
we got on the topic of old jobs.
Fuck is she a dancer?
And she told me that a few years
ago she worked in a pet store. Okay.
I guess wrong.
There was a hamster there that would bite
her every day drawing blood and would
attack coworkers and customers.
Generally,
the hamster was a crazy douche.
One day her,
her and a coworker decided they had to
do something about this thing to put the
hamster in a bag and
smashed it against the wall.
Whoa.
Okay.
What?
Jesus Christ,
what a fucking left turn that was.
They put it in a bag and
smashed it against the wall.
Needless to say, I was shocked.
The first thing I said was,
holy shit lay.
That's Kinda crazy.
That makes
wait.
That's the kind of crazy that makes
a wife cut her husband's Dick off.
I'm sorry dude.
That was a hilarious line and I blew it.
The first thing I said was,
Holy Shit Lady.
That's the kind of crazy that makes
it wife cut her husband's Dick off.
She said she still feels horrible about
it and that she killed it that way
because she couldn't think of any
other way to make it quick, but Jeez,
I mean, I never been in that situation,
but it seems kind of crazy. Lol.
This seems like something straight
out of a Seinfeld episode,
but I just keep thinking about it.
Every time me and this chick's
are are getting together.
Should I just accept this is a crazy
story or is this a sign that she has
serious issues?
Remember,
this happened years ago and
she seems absolutely sane.
Otherwise,
please help potential murder
victim question mark through.
Some of you guys are really fucking funny
man. The way you guys write this shit.
I, I you, but you've got to met.
I haven't proved with my reading.
I feel so bad that I butchered
that God damn line. Um,
yeah.
Okay. Jesus Christ. What
do you do with this one?
This is fucked up on like so
many different levels. Okay.
Let's start with the first thing.
The cruelty to animals.
Okay.
Not only cruelty to animals
like I could what she did,
I could do that to an aunt.
I won't even do it to a spider.
I could do it to a fucking mosquito.
Yeah.
That's what she basically treated
a hamster like a fucking mosquito.
Yeah.
Now granted a hamster. Okay, let, let's
try to be a little empathetic here.
Empathetic.
Let me try to put myself in her situation.
If I was younger,
20 years younger and a hamster bit me
every day at work and I met working at a
fucking pet store, uh, what?
I smashed it against the wall and
a bag. No, I wouldn't. However,
yeah,
I love do something
to it.
I would do something. You know what
I would do? I would take a ruler
and if I would wait,
I would wait till it was a fallen asleep
and I would just write on it's fucking
hamster ass and it woke up
whenever the fuck it did.
I would just take the ruler and I
would pin it against the fucking cage.
They just watch. You get all
upset. I just, I would bully it.
That's what basically what I would do.
And I you liked that?
You liked that you little fucking
hamster, Huh? I wouldn't hurt it.
I just keep it pinned there.
I'm a frustrated,
I would frustrate the living shit
out of it. That's what I would do.
I would do something like that,
I that I think I would do that,
but I would not smash it against the
fucking wall. They put it in a bag.
Now did,
was it repeated strikes?
Jesus Christ, you know, some of this
shit kids used to do in my neighborhood.
You know,
I had a friend of mine,
he's take his house cat and he'd put
it in an empty Pellis Kelo case and he
would fucking spin it over his head like
someone, like it was at a Steelers game,
you know,
that's what the fuck he would do.
And then sometimes he'd
put it in the dryer.
They used to tell me these stories and
I used to laugh my fucking ass off for
some reason. I found it funny back
then. Now I find it absolutely horrific.
And uh, I would never do it, but if I
had to do it to either a dog or a cat,
I would definitely do it to a cat. But
it'd have to be a real douche of a cat.
All right,
so we're getting off the subject here.
So it's cruelty to animals
and she works at a pet store.
So that's bizarre because he
figured if you work at a pet store,
that means you either
you love animals or you,
you like I had a low level deal pot.
You,
you've, you're dealing weed
on a low level, you know
what I mean? You're that guy.
You like the burnout, Matthew mcconaughey.
At least that's how they used to be.
But then there's the other option
that serial killers, you know,
they start off with small animals.
You know,
they watch a ton of porn and they start
torturing small animals and then they
gradually work their way up, uh, you know,
to a fucking human being.
So yeah, you could possibly,
you could possibly be dealing with
that right now. Then also, you know,
you're looking at it like this is,
that's the mother. Your children
put a hamster
in a fucking,
I could see if it was fucking
1911 rather than 2011.
Yeah.
People back then, they kill
an animal. They didn't give
a fuck. They just walk out.
What do you guys want for dinner?
Good.
It's has some goose in the
fucking mom would walk out.
They grabbed the goose by the neck and
then they fucking act like they were
trying to start up a model t ah,
fucking body Susan.
They've just break its
neck nice and quick. Um,
and then they pluck it, Nick Cook
it and that was it. And that was,
that was dinner 1911. Did
you like that little piece,
piece of history? Uh, I don't,
dude, I don't know what to
tell you. This is like, um,
that's really fucking insane
and at the very least,
um, if you get into a fight with
her, she's at the very least,
I think she's going to throw something
at you. She may be one of those.
I have no idea. Dude. How
hot is this girl? I think I,
some of these people I need like a
picture to see if it's like worth it.
You guys seem to be connecting
on like a personality level,
but I really got to tell you,
you know,
that's just like something
Roger Clemens would do.
I could picture him doing
that. You know, he is at posy,
posy from the fucking dirty
dozen sort of vibe about them.
Hugs forward
to the
please come back to
come to me last be sweethearts.
Did you want, shall we? Um, so anyways,
this is why I've been cooped up in
Cincinnati the entire fucking weekend is
because, uh, this is what
I've learned about Cincinnati.
Evidently they have what's known
as good downtown and bad downtown.
But as far as I can tell,
it's all fucked up because I'm
supposed to be in good downtown.
And um, I've been walking
around this, you know, I've,
I've lived in cities and I
performed in cities enough for,
I know what the fucking red
flags are when it means,
hey bill, why don't you go back to
your hotel room or at the very least,
take your watch off. Put it
in your pocket. I love that.
That's the classic White
Guy, suburban Wolf. I know.
I'll take it off and put it in my pocket.
What exactly does that do?
You know,
other than maybe save you
from getting a broken arm,
you know that somebody is just
ripping your pocket off your jeans.
So this is the deal. I walk out.
This is, these are the red flags.
I walk out of my hotel the first block,
I see a check cashing place. All right?
This is for tourists. The people,
if you see a check cashing place a
hail a cab and get the fuck out of that
neighborhood,
or at the very least stop the direction
you're walking in and going the other
direction. All right. Which is what
I did. I was like, well, you know,
I don't think I want to get food down
this way. Let me go this other way.
So I start walking up the street a
little bit more and what do I see on the
right hand side of the street?
I see a hat store,
a store that sells nothing but
hats and I don't mean like Lids,
baseball hats. Oh, those Brian
Johnson, I'm a fan of ACDC,
had some talking like Venus
fly trap fucking bitch.
Where's my money hats?
And right next to it they had a store
that sold the suits that went with those
bitch, where's my money hats? So I'm
like, all right, I'm in a pimp, Allie.
All right. I am not a fucking
pimp. I don't have any bitches.
Let me get the fuck out of there. But
then I see an oasis. I see Walgreens.
I'm like, okay, that's a chain.
All right, it's a corporate chain.
I will walk in there and I will regroup
and I'll ask somebody in there with the
fid Rutgers's you know,
so I walk in there and I go in there
and once again I see another red flag.
The lotion,
lotion people was locked
in a glass cabinet.
All right. 18 years on the road.
I have never fucking seen that.
How much does lotion cost
people? It doesn't cost that
fucking munch. All right.
You have to lock it up like
it's fucking razor blades,
which I still don't think that they should
cost that fucking much. Razor blades,
they lock up because they just,
they make them seem like these,
they're these diamonds
and they're very rare.
So for some reason they are 40 bucks for
eight of them and everybody knows it's
bullshit. So they're going to
steal them. But this is lotion.
Every fucking drug still you go into,
you know the shampoos out in the ocean,
out in the ocean, out in the
open. The lotion is my brain,
always three words ahead of where the
fuck I'm going to say you'd like to add
open and lotion, you get ocean. Um,
yeah. So I was like, all right, what the
fuck? And then I walked out and I saw, uh,
I saw a black dude under the age of
35 with a Jheri curl. And right there,
that was it. I was like, I'm done. I'm
going back to my fucking hotel because,
oh no. And then the last thing
was all decent, respectable.
A Brady bunch looking white people
and Huxtable look and black people all
vacated the city at five Oh one leaving
depression era looking white people,
you know,
do you guys ever see peewee's
big adventure and he's on
that train with that Guy
Jimmy cracked corn and I don't care.
That's what all the fucking
white guys look like.
And the black guys all
look like Pac man Jones.
Actually they didn't know it was
just one guy. One of my shows he did,
he had the Paul Wall Grill in his
mouth. And uh, you know, I dunno.
So I've just been sitting here ordering
room service my entire fucking weekend
reading about Cincinnati
anyways, so I was so bored this
week and I was just like, ah,
I'm going into a negative funk here.
I have got to do something positive.
So I actually went up and I go,
you know,
after I started reading about Cincinnati,
I was like, maybe I'll go to a museum.
So the closest museum was this museum
about the underground railroad,
the underground, not like that.
That's what the, uh, Swedes called.
They're a call the subway,
the underground in England,
they call it the tube. You know,
look at make fucking world traveler.
I know how to say grilled cheese in
five different languages. Um, uh, God,
my brain's so fucking tired. Come on
belts. You can make it, you can make it.
Here we go. What am I talking
about here? So I go, all right,
go to the underground railroad and I use,
usually I don't like going
to shit like that. Okay.
I understand how evil
white people are. And, uh,
I've seen enough shit in my lifetime
that I really don't want to be reminded.
I go on Youtube, I see all the shit that
people, right, it's fucking, you know,
it's depressing, but I'm figuring
this is the underground railroad.
There's a happy ending after this shit,
right? It starts off with the slavery,
but then there's freedom, right? And
there's going to be a big, you know,
we are the world thing at the end,
you know.
So I walk in there and they gave me
this little radio and I go, all right,
and I go,
it's one of these museums.
We start at the top and then you
wind your way all the way down.
And I walked in there and
it was fucking horrific.
It was horrific.
Just see,
and they stacked them up like
fucking wood in these God damn ships.
Now people's families getting separated.
And it was just in every fucking picture.
Just had some black dude,
a woman just getting the shit kicked out
of him and then some evil looking white
guy. And, uh, I quickly realized that was
one of the only white people in there.
So now I'm looking at black people and I'm
feeling like an asshole. Like Ah, yeah.
Hey, uh, yeah, sorry about that. I
kinda got a little out of control.
It wasn't only me,
it was my ancestors and I just want to
get the fuck out of there. Right. So, oh,
it was, it was brutal. I can only, I
can only be in there for like half,
like half hour, 40 minutes. And I
was like, I already know this shit.
I know this shit. I already know
this shit's fucking, it was horrible.
It was fucking horrible.
And I just basically fast walked down
like five flights of stairs to get,
it wasn't even stairs. It was
like a round thing, you know,
I should have just been gone, I'm
sorry. All the way down. Right.
And then when I fucking went to leave,
this is the best part.
I handed my radio and I'm so full of
white guilt at that point then I'm to be
friendly as possible.
Then when I hand it to the lady,
the lady behind the counter, this
black woman, she goes, she goes,
how did you enjoy the museum? And I was
so trying to say something positive.
I went to big, I went, it was great.
I felt like an asshole.
I sounded like I enjoyed it too much
and I want to be like, great, like,
like informative. Great. You
know, not great. Like, you know,
woo slavery,
slavery on two on two,
ready break. Um, AH, yeah.
Fuck. It was brutal. It
was brutal. So I dunno,
that's it.
Yeah,
no.