Hey, what's going on is Bill Byrd
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And I am checking in all of you.
Woo. What's going on?
How's your week been going?
Oh Jesus. That's wonderful.
That's fantastic.
I'm out here in La. It's
overcast, it's gloomy, it's rainy.
Okay.
Which is a good thing.
Which is a good thing because we
always need the fucking rain out here.
And I'm so pissed at whoever
the, I don't, it was the mayor.
I don't know who it was,
but last year it rained like it's never
rained out here and this fucking asshole
goes, oh good. You know the
droughts officially over.
It's like, it's never over.
There was never supposed to be a city
out here. Okay. So whatever we got,
we need to conserve.
Okay.
Because who the fuck knows
when it's going to rain again?
So what do I see? What do I see the other
day? I see this whole fucking thing,
this video about how they put
these giant black rubber balls.
They just roll them into lakes,
I think.
And I believe that it's to try to prevent,
you know,
to slow down the evaporation of the
water in the searing heat out here.
And once again,
they're saying that we're in a drought
and does anybody go back to the stupid
ass fucking mayor or the governor or
the lieutenant something, whatever,
whatever the fuck the person's position
is that makes the ignorant statement
that the drought is over.
So it'd be stupid cunt out here.
It goes back to fucking
taken an extra long shower.
Of course not. Why would you
do that? Why would you do that?
It's not your job as a politician.
You job as a politician is not
to tell people what's going on.
It's to make people feel that
everything is going to be okay.
You make them feel like
everything's going to be okay when,
when everything isn't okay.
And then you make people scared shitless
when there's really nothing to be
afraid of. And that is my cynical fucking
view on a cloudy fucking la morning.
Now these people all, they're, they're,
they're coming to catch Ya. Oh,
there's plenty of water.
Fucking take a nice long shower.
You stupid content.
Um, well that's not it. That's, you know,
we're getting towards the end of the week.
Why, why, why, why, why would
I come at you? So in this way,
I'm a little grumpy today.
I'm a little grumpy thing.
Get a lot of sleep last night.
And then I got a while.
I'm going out to Pittsburgh today.
I got Pittsburgh,
I got to Cincinnati this weekend too.
Fucking towns and people
ain't afraid of work lease.
Their dads weren't and their Dad's dad.
But these kids now sit around playing
video games trying to fucking come up with
an APP that ain't still working.
Is it? Um, I'm going out there.
Some of my great friends that I've met
in this business live in Pittsburgh
and uh, so I'm going to be doing tomorrow
morning. I'm going to be on the uh,
the morning show, Randy Bauman
and Bill Crawford, wd v. E.
So tune in if you're in Pittsburgh.
Um,
I always try to make sure that I want
to come back, that I do their show,
cause I rem I member back in the day when
I would go there and I would play the
fucking Pittsburgh
improv out at the stacks.
This is small out there and they literally
had the kept to stacks from, you know,
when we used to fucking produce
shit in this country and for me,
all steel mills or whatever.
And uh,
I used to go down there and I'd
sell low about 30, 35 tickets.
Okay.
I mean it was a fucking hard
ticket to sell. I can't explain it,
that God damn mall,
first of all,
there was one way in and one
way out on this skinny bridge,
if I remember correctly.
And it took,
it just took forever to get in
and out of there and a half.
Nobody knew who the fuck you where it
was very difficult to sell tickets.
So a Randy used to put me on the show.
He'd be like,
don't just come in Tuesday to do
the fucking show every single day.
Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday,
Friday. I'd come in. I would
do it. Just sit in for the,
almost the whole show,
all four days in a row.
And then I finally started
selling tickets. So, you know,
now that I'm selling tickets,
I don't want to come back to Pittsburgh,
like gold belly, big shot. Right.
I gotta go back there and kiss the
fucking ring there. Made me when I,
she and you steal shit.
Um,
and of course they're going to probably
fucking give me shit. I already already,
okay.
Willing to believe that they're going
to give me shit about the last patriots.
Steelers game.
Those poor fucking people.
I can't remember the last
time the Steelers beat the
Patriots. It's unbelievable.
He used to beat the fuck
out of us when we were kids.
I'm just trying to enjoy the last fucking
whatever Tom Brady has left because I
know it's going to be,
it's like dolphin fence.
They're still waiting for the next day.
A marina.
They'd been waiting since 99 and
entire generation has grown up.
Okay.
Watching them lose to the
Patriots in my whole childhood,
I watched just lose to the dolphins.
Bob fucking Gracie.
Right. And then he finally retired.
It's like, oh, thank God. Right.
And then somehow Don Shula's still
got David Woodley and don Strock
to trade off at that position and they
went to another fucking Superbowl.
Granted, they lost, they
still kicked our ass
and then they get Dan Marino.
So our lives were fucking miserable for
a good 17 years. So, uh, you know what?
That's an interesting question.
I would love to see what is the Patriots
that lifetime record against the Miami
Dolphins.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Patriots first.
Dolphins.
All time.
All right. What did I just say? I
said it perfectly. Lifetime record.
See if we get it here.
This is why the Internet is fucking great.
Yeah.
This is why it's fucking great.
Wait,
what do you mean the pate?
The Patriots won 11 one 11 and 10 in
the eighties against the dolphins.
It's not fucking possible.
Wait a minute.
Okay.
And the 60s that dolphins won,
they won four out of,
so there were four and three and
the 70s they were 13 and seven
in the 80 [inaudible] patriots are 11
and 10 I never would have known that in
the 90s they were 14 and seven
Oh, we didn't even do that. Well
against him in 2011 and nine verse them.
I didn't even know that
there was that close.
I thought they destroyed us in the 80s
and we won one more game than them,
and I thought we killed them in the two
thousands we were 11 and nine and then
this Dick Decade, we were
12 and four. All right,
so who's winning here? Oh,
Jesus. 12 and 11 is 23 everybody,
I can't fucking do this.
This is going to take forever.
You know what I just realized I don't
care to can, can you do give me a total,
do I have to fucking think?
I mean, this is the Internet.
The whole fucking reason to get on
this is not the thing. All right,
let's see here.
Dolphins,
one 1717 and 10 after two decades
than they were 27 and 21
ah.
Then they crushed us 27 and 21 then
they were 35 and 28 my brain's going to
explode here at 35 and 28
then they were 44 in 39
then 48 and 51 I believe I
just did the math correctly.
They're 48 and 51 at a time
swap it.
Taper the willow for fucking decades,
so your that right there.
Whenever I gamble on football,
I always stay away from division rivalry
because it makes no fucking sense,
but somehow it's like the jets.
As much as the jets suck,
they still are the bills or whatever that
you're still going to go like you know,
I don't know. One of them is going to
get you. You're going to have a letdown.
Gay play it twice a year. It's really
hard to beat the two times he said,
David says, say pocket season. All right,
let's get down to what I
really want to talk about.
Dean del Rey's 52nd birthday
party slash tribute to bond.
Scott at the Avalon might've been
the most fun I've ever fucking had,
um, since I got into this business. Um,
it was a standup show slash
comedy show if you don't,
if you didn't see the fly.
And um,
the stand up show was Joey Diaz who should
have been closing and then Mark Marin
and then myself, they should have
flipped the fucking order. But uh,
we came out,
we did done dean of course hosted
the show was sold out and a,
and then in the end,
Dean went up in front of this all star
band and sang the entire power age album.
I got to see Mark Marin play lead guitar
and I got to sit in on three songs on
drums and a,
it's the best day ever played.
And I still had a train rector and
fucking livewire. But other than that,
it was fucking great and uh,
thought it was,
I just want to thank everybody who
played in, let me be a part of that.
Dean del Ray for putting it together.
Scotty and Nikki Sixx, Mike, Devin,
Rudy Sasso.
See Dave pushed her.
Steve Gorman fucking murdered
it on drums. Uh, Mark Marin,
George Lynch, I know, I probably
forgot a couple of people. Um,
whoever the one got all,
like they got like the,
the same amps and guitars in exact
gear that ACDC used back then.
So they had that crunch song sound.
I know that we've been posting clips
on Instagram and everything and, uh,
around the, around the internet,
but it was fucking unbelievable.
Unbelievable night. And I already knew
that. I loved Steve Gorman has a drummer,
but just watching him fucking
murdering for an entire hour,
uh, it was incredible. I still see, I
still cannot believe that that happened.
Fucking playing drums and I'm looking
up in this fucking fucking Nikki Sixx
playing bass, Scotty and on
guitar. I don't think I'll
ever get over that people.
Um, that was another thing, you know,
and that the part is thing about
doing that is, is sitting there going,
how the fuck? What the
fuck am I doing here? Um,
but Jesus Christ, Dean Delray, I've never
heard him sing better. Um, you know,
cause now he got himself
in like ridiculous shape.
You know, it's hilarious.
He said,
if you can somehow find clips two years
ago and we did it and dean sang the
entire highway to hell album and I
believe the next day or two days later,
he went to the doctor trying to figure
it out while he was still tired and his
levels of something. We're often, and
that's when he, uh, he went on this diet,
you know, his new diet that, you know,
that fucking guy gets locked into
something and he's just into it.
You know what I mean? You know, I
just quit drinking and then, you know,
eventually I come back to it. That dude
quits. It's fucking over. It's past them.
And, um, but if you
look at the difference,
he doesn't even look like the same person.
Like two,
two, little over two years ago when we did
the last one, he looked like a fucking,
he looked like he'd been on the police
force with a desk job for like fucking 25
years. Um, did undercover work.
He got in a little too deep and then they
fucking, they pulled them out, you know,
can he got rid of whatever drug addiction
he had and he put it into fucking
donuts and eat and color for cereal.
That's what this fucking guy looked like.
And like you look at him now, he doesn't
even look like the same person. In fact,
he told me the other day,
he ran into somebody and started talking
to them and they will get acting all
weird.
And he had to like reintroduce himself
cause they just thought he was some sort
of weird fan.
So,
um, he already killed it
a few years ago, but uh,
and he was horrifically out of shape
and now this year he was in unbelievable
shape and he fucking
fucking murdered it at. Uh,
and I want to also give a shout out to,
there's one dude in the crowd.
The crowd was amazing,
but this one fucking dude,
he took me back to the 80s when I used
to see shows that the Worcester Centrum
was the providence civic center.
This guy,
he had the long hair not styled at all.
Okay.
Not the way after a while they learned
back in the day when you just grew your
hair to piss off your parents,
you just didn't cut it. You know,
if you look at like fucking Robert Plant's
hair in like before he got the do in
the 80s, right? You just
let it go out. This guy had,
I guess it was more of a 70 circuit.
He just parted it down the middle
and let it fucking go. He had the,
the black fingerless gloves,
the Jean jacket with the
band patches on it and shit.
And he was headbanging
vintage headbang and like,
it was like 84 before Glam came in and
he wasn't just headbanging with the beat.
He was whatever the guitars were doing.
Uh, like my neck hurt watching him.
And I don't know if he noticed,
but everybody that was on the show at
some point notice him and was pointing
like laughing going like this fucking
guy. I remember guys like this. And, uh,
we actually, I actually ran into him
at the end of the show and, uh, uh,
feminists took a little bit
of video, so hopefully, yeah.
Yeah.
It was just the coolest fucking crowd
ever. Like somebody walked by the line,
it's like,
dude,
it looks like heavy metal parking
lot meets the comedy store.
It was perfect. So, um, I mean, I dunno,
I haven't heard of Dean's
going to do it again,
but I got to feel it was so much fun.
There's no fucking way he's not
going to do it again. And um,
yeah,
you, you, you owe it to yourself.
You gotta come out here cause
people going like, dude,
you got to take this show on the road.
It's just too many fucking amazing
people that have their own careers.
All those musicians.
I don't know how the fuck you would
get that on the road somewhere.
Maybe you could do a one off somewhere
in New York City or something.
I have no idea.
Um,
but that's another great
thing about living in La is
all these guys are out here
in la and everybody's
always shitting on La
[inaudible].
Yeah.
Then that happens. That happens. Um,
and everyone was so generous and I
remember afterwards like a, I don't know,
it just,
everybody was just so fucking,
everybody like was literally a fan of
ACDC and it was just the greatest night
ever.
So thank you to Dean del Rey,
the all things comedy network.
Um,
let there be talk podcast and uh,
amazing comedian now who gets
sustained rounds of applause. Uh,
um, last couple of dates I did
with them. I'm so happy for him.
It was just a fucking night of my
life of his life too. I should say.
I'm fucking making it
about myself. Um, anyways.
Uh,
I dunno. That's weird.
That was all positive.
Now that's kind of thrown
me off my game here.
I got to trash something now.
Oh,
I actually am taking a connecting flight
to Pittsburgh because he only direct
flight is on southwest and I just cannot
fucking handle these standup comedy
that they tried to do on those
things. It just, it's excruciating.
The jokes never work,
at least when I'm on there.
And then there's just this awkward pause
and everybody sort of laughs side of
the awkwardness and it's just, I find
it unbelievably fucking unprofessional
considering we're all on a fucking
plane. That always, you know,
they'd see always the outside
chance this thing could crash
is we going down the tarmac and the
guy's doing a Darth Vader voice,
make sure your seat belt is on
doing this shit and everybody's
fucking lab. It's like, dude,
what the fuck are you doing?
Sorry.
Um,
I don't, I don't know why it bothers me
as much as it does because I actually,
I told you last time I went on the
Internet and I tried to find people that
agreed with me and I
couldn't find one post.
I went through four pages of the
Internet when I searched, you know,
flight attendant's doing their
comedy routines and all it was,
was glowing reviews. So at some point, I
guess I just have to admit that it's me.
That is me. But uh, you know, they have
an incredible safety record over there.
They really do. But I don't think
it's because of those fucking,
those fuck away. I don't know. I
almost made a fucking joke that I,
I,
I'm not gonna do that joke cause we
live in a time that you just can't make
jokes like that. But just know
that in involved Mohammed. Atta,
how about those Boston Bruins,
everybody,
they are tied. We just got smoked by the
Tampa Bay lightning four to nothing. Uh,
we are tied for points. We got
three games left, we're paying,
playing the panthers, there's
sadness and then the pant is again,
um,
to see who's to have I guess home ice
throughout the whole eastern corporates.
Buchard playoffs, congratulations
to them. This amazing season,
this amazing rebuilt,
you know,
since we let all of those
guys go from our 2011,
essentially 2011 Stanley Cup team.
The fact that they turned it
around this quick quickly, um,
has been incredible. And the only thing
that sucks right now as a Canadian suck,
you know, cause I would be like really
excited. You know, when we get this good,
you want to go play a good Canadian team,
a Montreal Canadiens team and have
a great classic seven game series.
And, um, you know,
it's like if the Yankees suck and the
red sox are good or vice versa, it's,
it's not fun for the fence,
you know,
unless you're just a Douche bag and you'd
like to see a one sided event, but, um,
plants to coming up,
Celtics, it's coming up.
I haven't been able to
watch any fucking games.
The amount of times I've had five or six
games, Bruins games is Celtics Games.
Just, you know, back logged. And I, I can
only watch the first period of one game.
Like I did the lightning game and then
I got to erase all of them because it
takes up too much space.
I just don't have the fucking time.
You who should be yardy yardy like
the fucking parent I am right now.
Proud to be a parent. But Jesus Christ,
you're fucking, and I, you know,
I got all the packages and I,
I think I'm gonna have to get rid of him.
I don't even, I can't, you know what? I
don't have fucking time to watch them.
This is all good reasons why I don't
have time to watch him. But, uh,
you know, the red sox came out,
I think we're like five in one.
Everybody's excited
about our pitching staff,
the Red Sox who are now the evil empire
and the Yankees have this little team
that could, that has, you know,
500 zillion fucking dollars. Uh,
but the way the Yankees did it
versus the way the red sox did it,
we've literally become them. But, uh,
it seems to be working for us
and it's working for the Yankees.
So I have a bet this
year with Paul Versey,
the pride of Trenton fee in Newark,
New Jersey.
Paul Versey 50 bucks a
game in the regular season.
And I also have another
50 bucks a game with, uh,
with my agent who books me on the road.
So I figure if I,
if I put some money on it,
I'll be able to, you know,
at least pay attention cause I don't
want to miss all this shit. I don't know,
become that dad that doesn't know any,
any of the players' names. You know,
it starts talking about Omar
Marino and fucking Dave full, uh,
the Fuck Temp Foley de Felice
from camp kids in the hall.
Tim Foley and all these old guys.
Widleen McGee,
you know, like listen to that guy
doesn't know. You know when I was a kid,
talk still talking about
Stan mutual. Um, right.
Let me read some of the fucking
advertising game and then I got to La.
I got to get the fuck Outta here.
I gotta pack
my bags, go out to Burbank,
get on a fucking plane. Um,
where am I going here? Who Do we got here?
We got a, all right. Dollar Shave Club.
Everybody. All right. Get rid of all the
junk that's lying around your bathroom.
It give it the cleaning it deserves.
Unless you live with a woman,
then just continue to joy.
You're one eighth of the fucking
counter top in the bathroom.
You probably don't really have any
clutter. Do you freshen it up with,
do you ever try to like
clean up your side,
your little fucking third of the House
to try to guilt your wife and to picking
up some of her stretchy pants?
It doesn't really work. Does it?
Yeah,
that was my goal. I was just going to
be, I'm just going to fuck it. I'm out.
I'm going to, I'm going to lead by
example. You can't lead by example.
He got to lead by example and you'd
have to accompany it with, um, allowed.
Sighing.
Okay.
And then passive aggressive.
What's the matter? Nothing.
What do you mean nothing?
What's the matter? Well, you
know, it's just, you know,
you kinda got your
stretchy pants all over
the, Oh, I'm sorry.
I mean, I, I didn't do
it on purpose. Um, fresh.
Where does that go? Where does it go?
It goes nowhere. It goes nowhere. Okay.
That's why God invented the garage.
That's the place where you just go out
there where you had the stuff that you
really love, that you kind of have locked
out there so she won't throw it out.
A fresh ended up with high quality
products from Dollar Shave Club.
Dollar Shave Club members
can get everything they need
delivered right to their
door. Dollar Shave Club has
raises, shave butter, shampoo,
body wash, toothpaste, everything you
need to look, smell and feel your best.
You'll get an amazing high quality shave
every morning using dollar shave club's
executive razor.
I can't stop yawning.
Okay,
dear Dr Covey's, you know,
it's going to happen.
I'm going to get on that fucking plane
and everybody's gonna have the shades
down except for that one fucking asshole
who not only has this shade open,
also has the overhead lighting on it.
You get an amazing high quality shoe,
uh,
shave every morning using dollar
shave club's executive razor there.
Dr Coffee's easy shave
butter goes on clear.
She can see where you're shaving. That
makes no sense, but it goes on clear.
How can you see where you're shaving?
You need the fucking white foam to show
that you already did that part of your
face, right? You're saying that you
can see through the shave butter.
Okay.
I Dunno. And since dollar shave
club delivers everything to you,
you don't have to,
you don't have to set a foot in
a store wanting around the isles,
hunting for razors, shampoo, body
wash, toothpaste, none of it.
You can just eat yourself
into an early grave.
Eventually your wife has to
fucking Shavia clean up. Yo. Let's,
how about a round of applause
for all the people that stay with people
that get that big, you know what I mean?
And they got to take them down to
the fucking car wash, you know,
the self car wash and take out that
fucking scrubber that the soaps shoots out
of,
you know,
tie the person to the fucking front
fender like a goddamned make a shot,
an elk and you just scrub them down.
Um,
clean up your bathroom and your morning
and your morning routine with dollar
shave club's daily essential static kit,
but just $5 with free shipping.
You get the six blade executive razor
plus trial sizes of shave butter body
cleanser in one wipe Charri Charri.
Then keep the blades coming
for a few bucks more a month.
Speaking of your next month for a limited
time only use the code burpee you are
are at checkout to get $5 off
your second month of the club.
That's Code burr@dollarshaveclub.com
to save $5 on your second month.
Join the club today. Alright, legal zoom.
It's a fact of life.
Attorneys are expensive.
You're likely to pay around $300 an hour.
Okay.
Fuck.
That's just one reason why smart business
owners turned to legal zoom. Sure.
Over 2 million Americans
have used legal zoom.
Just start their businesses with
ls, LLCs, incorporations and more.
I got to take out the fucking Invisalign.
Here we go.
But even right after your business
is set up, legal zoom can help you,
can help you out.
Things like lease agreements,
changing tax laws and contract reviews.
Can you fucking do a postnuptial
prenup with this? I Dunno.
Are all part of running your own business.
Do you promise to love hold and Cherice
and pick up your fucking stretchy pants
when he sighs loudly, do, well, maybe.
I don't know why you being mean to me,
but these are precisely the kinds of
legal hurdles that take time and effort
away from growing your business.
That's why legal zoom created
their business legal plan with it.
You get legal advice for your business
from vetted independent attorneys vetted.
That means they didn't take their dick out
at work. That's what vetted means. Now,
at least in Hollywood, right, and tax
professionals available in every state.
You can also raise,
you also receive access to Ndas,
lease agreements and more.
The best part is you don't,
you won't get charged by the hour.
Since legalzoom isn't a law firm.
Instead you just pay
one low upfront price.
Ah,
call to action legal zone yawns
have nothing to do with you.
Check out legal zoom is business legal
plan and legal zoom.com now and get
special savings when you
enter burr at checkout.
Legal Zoom where life meets legal legal,
zoom.com is sons of bitches.
All right, what else do I have to
say? Do I have anything else to say?
Um,
actually I don't.
Let's talk about how I know
how to pack now. Alright,
one pair of jeans, two shirts,
underwear and socks, and that's it.
He Slam it in a fucking bag.
You never have to sit there
at the fucking turnstile.
I don't give a fuck if I was, if I was
going on the road for the for a year,
that's exactly what I would bring.
Yeah. Never coming home again.
I don't give a fuck.
And you were black.
I sweat Johnny Cash wore black so they
couldn't tell he was wearing the same
fucking shirt every day.
Right.
Okay.
That's it. That's how you gotta do what
you got to wear dark colors. You know,
you start walking around
dressing all flashy.
All of a sudden you gotta be like Mariah
Carey bringing all this bedazzled shit
out on the fucking road.
I always think that that's
why she's always in such a
mood. You know what I mean?
Should we seems to be talking yet also
thinking about something else at the same
time, I think she's probably
wondering, did I pack those,
the dazzle red bottom shoes,
that half my face in diamonds on them?
Can we talk about divas for a
minute? You know, is there a reason,
you know why they're vetting all
these men out here in Hollywood yet?
They're leaving the divas alone.
I mean,
just stick about how many phones they've
thrown in fucking people that are
probably working for free.
You know,
the amount of time they've slapped people
in the face just said horrible things.
At what point are we going to hold the
Diana Ross is fucking high heel shoes to
the fire.
That's what I want to know that that's
your homework between now and Monday
chain.
When people say that that's your homework.
I took a yoga class the other day.
It was fucking awesome.
I went there with my wife,
you know, and uh, I actually,
I actually, I found this, um, you know,
they have,
they have fake mess must statutes.
They actually now have like fake man
buns and I actually had a little fucking
velcro strip strip that yeah.
Glued to my head and I stuck it on
the back of my head, my bald head.
And I went there and it was great. I've
noticed at Yoga teachers for some reason,
they can't just take you through the
fucking class. They always have to,
for whatever reason,
they always have to tell you a fucking
story about how they fail during their
life and then they remembered,
oh look who's hair come
busting through the door.
Hey Buddy,
do you got your AC DC high
voltage rock and roll.
1975 one Xeon.
Okay.
I guess I got to put the mic down
because somebody wants to hug
you. Have any idea how much I'm going to
miss you over the next couple of days?
Huh?
Do you know?
That's why I take the earliest
flight back so I can see you sing.
You the itsy bitsy spider.
Huh?
I Bet I can sing you some
ACDC this morning. Huh?
Back in black. He'd said,
I bet you know what?
I had to be back without getting
loose. Probably loose. You know it was,
that was the song for Bon Scott back
in black, like they were at a funeral.
Um, all right, I'm done with the podcast.
What are you guys having for breakfast?
Hi,
you say hi.
Nothing. Hey a Gol. Hi.
All right.
I'll be in there in a minute.
Thanks for helping me get to the last 90
seconds of the podcast, Cutie Pie. Um,
oh yeah,
we got all,
I got all this rock stuff that I
always put her up whenever she,
whenever I dress her, you
know, they've got these things.
I got these Motley Crue onesies.
What is it called? Hey, what is it?
What's Somali crew?
One set of shouted,
deviled shout at your Mama there.
They're fucking adorable.
What the hell is it called?
They're all like these,
these cute like toddler puns and uh,
the does a level of clothes that kids can
wear now, even as toddlers, I tend it,
they didn't have any of that shit when I
was a kid. We had like Choo Choo trains,
you know,
some sort of cowboys and Indians that
just completely ignored the genocide that
happened.
That's what the fuck we had.
We didn't have all these
cool rock onesies, you know,
but [inaudible] spoiled today. Um, oh,
I need to save this.
I signed up for global entry.
You know,
the Illuminati one step closer to me
building my fucking robot replacement when
I answer all these fucking
questions. But, um, I just,
I just gotta have it now that I'm
bringing my family and I'm fucking proud.
That makes me feel this to say
that I actually have a family,
you have to just be in this isolated
psycho. It's the fucking greatest.
It's the greatest thing ever. I love going
to the mall. I like going to the park,
pushing my kid on the swing.
I remember looking at people thinking
now I always knew having a kid was cool,
but I used to think some of it some level.
I was sad for those people.
I had it totally fucking wrong.
So anyways, I'm going to, uh,
I'm doing a Gig in London, England,
Dublin, and then over to London,
a two in Royal Albert Hall,
which was an absolute dream of mine.
And I'm going to record that night.
Hopefully I'm going to do enough time.
I'm going to make the double album.
Then I'm only going to put out on vinyl
after I made fun of people that listen
to records only on my last podcast.
That's what I'm going to do is what I
want to do at Madison Square Garden.
And the recording got fucked up, so I'm
going to make sure I get it done right.
And,
uh,
I also must try to get a drum kit there
so I can play during the day and hope
they can find some fucking somebody
to jam with over there. Uh,
but anyways, afterwards I'm
going to take a little week off.
I'm um, over there in Europe and
I'm bringing the whole family over.
So when he got a little
one flying that far,
it's going to be a frigging nightmare.
Uh,
so the very least we can lease blow
through the security by giving up a
ridiculous amount of privacy by
answering all these questions. That's I,
I just had to do, well, you know what's,
I had to make a sacrifice there. So,
um, that's it. That's
the podcast. Once again,
thank you to everybody
involved with Dean del Rey's,
a birthday celebration and all of that.
I mean that was just,
I can't, I, you know, I, I took some video
during sound check. I got to put it up.
You cannot fucking believe
how good that band sounded.
They are top notch musicians playing
out of all that gear from the late
seventies. It was fun. I was
getting like goosebumps. Uh,
I know I took a couple of MMM.
I walked out into where the crowd
was going to be before they, they,
they brought everybody in
and just listening to those
how fucking good they are.
And I got to tell you too,
Steve Gorman,
just watching a professional
fucking drummer is just my favorite.
God dammed up that close is my
favorite thing. It's just a sec.
How do they make it sound that
good? He was incredible. Um,
okay. So anyway, so I'll
try to post some of that.
And after I came down for the sound
check cause I was so nervous that I was
going to inevitably fuck up the songs,
which of course I did in a number
of areas. Um, but I plowed through,
but I wanted to make sure I had one more
crack at it before the people came in.
But, uh, after we were done
with the sound check. MMM.
It was me, Mike, Devin, I think Josh Z.
And we just, we just started playing.
I started playing some bottom beats and
then they just jumped right in and Devon
started singing and I put the immigrant
song up there and uh, it was just,
I was so much fucking fun.
Um,
so I hope dean continues to do that
every other year or whatever the fuck he
wants to do. And anytime he wants
to do it, if they'll have me on,
I would be honored to be there. Cause
uh, that really was, it's perfect.
It's perfect.
My dream of being a stand up comedian
and then my dream hobby that I was never
good enough to do professionally cleaned
drums. It's just fucking awesome.
So a thousand thanks to him. All
right. With that. Here's some,
here's some music picked out by Andrew
Feminist before we give you another half
hour from a Thursday afternoon podcasts
from earlier this year or a year gone by.
I don't know what, but that's it. Have a
great weekend. I'll talk to you on Monday.
This youtube video of this week.
You really have to watch it. Okay.
It's one of those shows. It's
basically, it's a rip off of the view.
It's for broad sitting around and they
got, you know, the same thing. You know,
they got the older one,
they got the sexy one,
they got the one who was fat and then got
her fucking stomach tied up like a God
damn balloon. Not now. She's dropping
weight faster than a junkie. Right.
I don't even know if that's true. I
just looked around them. You know,
they've got the racially mixed chick
and they all got on their fucking shoes
right there. Little outfits.
Uh, hang on a second.
Hang on a second. Someone's knocking.
I'll let you know what this is.
Okay.
All right.
You guys aren't going to believe this
shit that was security and they just said
that they had a noise complaint
anyways. You know what?
Some rich counsel on the other side of
the door with the fucking piece of one of
those really fancy glasses that they
think came from France but actually came
from a fucking pottery barn.
Um, if you can hear me,
go fuck yourself. This is what you get
for nuke in the economy. Um, anyway,
so these four fucking
broads and are on TV, right?
And they ended up there talking about
that guy there doing that story.
You know that story where that
dude get his dick cut off.
Brace yourselves because we're about
to go there because this woman,
this woman that allegedly did, according
to the Orange County DA's office,
Katherine Q.
Becker is accused of cutting off her
husband's penis with a nice taking his
penis and throwing it
into the garbage disposal.
So talking about that guy who
got his dick cut off his wife,
dragged him, tied him to
a bed, cut his dick off,
threw it in the garbage
disposal and turned it on.
And it was basically because
he wanted to get a divorce from her
police, say back or attacked him
because he filed for divorce,
she mutilate and um,
she ended the guy's fucking life
and he saw of quality life is over.
Okay.
And these women are talking
about it and lo and behold,
it's fucking hilarious to them.
California,
they had all they could do to keep a
straight face during the first minute of
setting up the story.
And then all the jokes come and they're
laughing their fucking asses off.
I do think it's quite fabulous.
I mean,
yeah. Cool. I would've just
thrown it in the dog's bowl.
Why does the dog have to
suffer chewing on an old bones?
It's the funniest fucking thing ever.
And this right here,
it's because of that type of shit.
Then I don't feel that I am misogynistic.
I just don't.
I think that I am just like women.
I trash women the way they trash guys.
It's just nobody pays attention
to the broads. They don't.
Do you think of a guide mutilated a woman
in any shape or form that four guys on
a pregame NFL show would be laughing about
it and we'll hear more of that talk a
little bit later as well.
Sharon Osborne was the guest and she goes,
somebody asks, do you think the
guy deserves, and she goes, well,
it depends on what he did.
I think I would have just
depending on why she cut it off.
I mean it does depend on the
reasons why does it, oh yeah.
The reason I'll think of one,
you know I made that fun is
totally overlaps the thought
of those morons in the
Middle East who cut women's clits off.
You know,
it's fucking medieval thought
and it's just considered silly.
I don't know what it is.
I don't know.
But it maintains what I've always
fucking said that women will do it to you
exactly what they don't want you
to do to them. If you let him.
And I think why so many guys are miserable
in marriages is they get married to
fucking young before they really
know how to stick up for themselves.
In a relationship and that's
why before you know it,
you're married and all your shit is
either in the basement or the garage and
she's barely touching it and a,
and you're wondering what the fuck
happened to your life. You know,
I dunno.
The video is,
is going to be up on the [inaudible]
podcast.com you know something.
This is actually,
I like this talking like this.
This is very challenging to try and
be funny with a late night DJ voice.
Okay.
All right. This next chunk of the
podcast goes out to the ladies. Ladies,
if you're out there and you're sitting,
hang in, there is a date. Rape is
okay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It is a bill burr and this is the
Monday morning podcasts for Monday.
Uh,
I'm going to go with April 4th.
I had no fucking idea
what day it is because a,
I'm doing something a
unique this week where, uh,
people have asked me Saint Bill,
you know, every week, you know,
you do your podcast. It's just you
babbling. Sometimes it's funny,
sometimes it isn't.
Why don't you have a fucking guest
on there every once in a while.
How about a comedian that people,
uh,
people want to know about
or already know about?
Want to hear his views on other shit?
So this week,
this is a very special episode
of the Monday morning podcast.
Well I will be doing it with the one
and only Mark Marin. Mark going on.
Thank you for having me go.
I didn't realize that I was actually one
of the first guests who've never had a
guest. I've had Joe to Rosa who
I do a, I do a show with on uh,
every once every, I think a leap year we
do an episode of the show. Uninformed.
We used to do it on x.
How much along fucking story.
But you have to have money cause
he lives in your apartment. Yeah,
he peaked there. There you go. That's
it. Part of the contract in his week.
It's basically, yeah, he lets me crash
when I come back to New York to do a,
to do Caroline's. He sees the mixer.
I feel bad. I'm like, all right,
grab a microphone. Here we go. But
yeah, you're the, you're the first.
You're the first one outside of the,
uh, the family. You know what you are,
you're Tim Roth and reservoir dogs.
You're the only one. I'm not sure.
So I end up with a gut shot. Yeah. The
media who laying there in the garage,
the whole fucking movie.
You're going to tell me you're a cop or
something towards the end of this. Oh,
I'm not good to tell you that.
I wish I had that biggest
secret. No, but basically,
you know what the funny thing is is uh,
uh, if, if the audio sounds different,
which means clear this week is, um,
um, actually this is how I have guests.
This is the only way I do guests on
the Monday morning podcast is if they
already have microphones and
a mixer. And then I, yeah,
I invited mark onto my podcast and
I'm like, I got a rescue pit bull.
I don't want to get sued.
So can half hour into it.
So I'm literally sitting in
Mark's compound out here. Yeah.
And you brought your own equipment,
which I thought was very polite. Ia,
but I just automatically assume we
just jump on my mix and, oh, I get it.
You don't think I'm a gentleman?
No worries. I brought me on mixer.
I brought my own mix and then when we
sit there and I'm sitting there with my
little stupid fucking travel
radio show and I'm like,
I got a mixer and all that
and then mark smiling.
Oh you know I kind of got that
already set up. You want to use mine?
I got the travel bag. I got the bag right
there for when I have to uh, you know,
you had talked to people on the road in
hotel rooms and make me feel awkward.
Look mark and like a lady
in my relationships on the
rocks and I've officially
moved in. You don't realize
that. Oh my God, now
I'm fucking with the car.
Okay. That's all right buddy.
If you can just sleep in here and
if you knew how to run a mixer,
you could help me out there. We get, how
can I be your assistant? Yeah, absolutely.
A lot of people trying to
move up in this business.
I'm going to try to go backwards. Can I
ask you a question? Absolutely. All right.
So I'm in,
I'm in Scotland for the Glasgow Festival
for five days and I'm playing pub
basements. And I did my one
man show it in, not in a pub
basement, but in a pub, uh,
uh, attic and I see posters
a you, yeah, they're,
they're betting the big money on Bill
Byrd. I talking to them, promoted there.
I'm like, is he a big drawn
out here? She's like, I dunno,
we're going to see out of go. Um,
I drew like 200 and then they,
they papered another 400 drunk Scott's,
oh, get him in there at the, uh,
the king's theater. But it went great.
You know, hopefully, uh, you know,
I'll come back again and I mean, I,
how'd you, I loved it over there. I had,
I actually,
I talked about it on my podcast.
I had a great time because I had a
resentment of the Scots and of the UK in
general only because the last time I
went there I had a bad experience and I,
and I chose to blame them other than
myself. What happened? Well I was in,
I was in Edinburgh for 30 days doing
that fringe festival and I, you know,
I was literally three months since
my wife left me. I was miserable,
I was broken and I was on a double bill
with Kirk Fox that we were brought out
there,
which is the best part of it cause they
paid for our lodging and everything else.
Usually I have to pay for your own
shit and I couldn't give it away.
I mean we were drawing audiences of nine
and you'll have to two weeks of that.
You're like, holy crap, I didn't want
to kill yourself. Yeah. It's like,
it's like open mic every night. It's like
doing a show in denim. Yeah. It's like,
it's like doing a show at a bar in
Dedham. Who, you know what's funny dude?
That's why I never did Edinburgh.
I always wanted to go over there,
but it's a fucking month.
Same thing with Australia.
There's some sort of Australia
comedy festival and it's like, well,
can I go there for 10 days? And like,
no, you gotta be over here for 30 days.
And it's like,
well what will they,
the way they were supposed to do
with my fucking life back here,
you just put it on hold.
He gets somebody to watch your dog and
you hope your girlfriend doesn't run away.
That's that tiger woods.
Shit I was talking about last week when
I went off on his wife. You know what,
how can these fucking women who they
get like a w w where they ha they,
they marry these rich fucking guys.
Yeah. They don't have a job. Right.
And then they have kids and they still
get help. They get like a fucking nanny.
There's somebody clipping
the hedges. They, they,
they don't do if somebody
clipping the kid, everything.
Everything. Yeah. So I said,
so as jokingly just fucking around.
I was saying the reason why I messed
around on her is because she's lazy.
Oh yeah. And it's, that's a
very, I don't know about you,
that's very untrue and
attractive. Uh, uh, quality,
messy if you want to. Yeah. The same shit.
They don't like it. Who knows? I mean,
if you want to talk about entitlement,
you know, I just found, you know,
because I've had the processes over
and over again in terms of, uh,
in terms of what the whole spousal support
thing. I mean, my wife didn't that,
you know, she wrote a book, she
didn't have a job or whatever,
and then afterwards done, you think you're
equals, but then they're like, you know,
I want support, I want this.
And they can exploit that.
That's the saddest thing about fucking
divorce is that it's set up so the woman
can break you no matter what.
And the reason I was put into place
might have been in earnest. I mean,
if you think about people when they
first put support, spousal support,
I'm talking without kids, not
alimony, spousal support. So granted,
if you're married to a woman for 20
years and she's been doing nothing but
making you feel better
for your miserable life,
and then all of a sudden it's done because
he went and fucked somebody who did
whatever and she's got to enter
the world again with nothing.
I understand why you, she owes a euro or
a little payment, you get us off started,
but if you're married fucking 10 minutes
and the chick is perfectly capable of
doing whatever the fuck she needs to
do to make a living and then she still
busted and takes half your shit. That
shit where it's like when it's a good,
when it,
when there's something good on the table,
they're just as good as you and they're
equals and they want their 50% but when
it's something bad,
I'm just the girl
and they get it coming and going because
guys want to fuck them and that's why
the judge, the judge half the time
when he's judging against you,
was thinking he's going to fucking get
some action with your ex wife by judge
towards he throws her little look.
We had this little wink,
you're sitting there like, am I not
fucking sitting here? All right,
so I'm married to this woman. She's
a comic. She's an equal. We always,
she's a cunt. I was like, wow,
you're really gonna fucking
Yo Yo. No, no, no. I mean, I,
I'm not going to do that.
Look, I will take my side, I
will own my, my shit there.
I had an anger problem. You know, it took
me a long time to learn that, you know,
but I did learn it.
If you're an angry guy,
that means it probably with somebody
married to or living with or involved in a
relationship with someone who's a pain
sponge that will deserve, you know,
absorb your bile and bullshit
until they can't take any more.
And then they'll want to be wrung
out by somebody else. But you know,
as an angry guy, I knew that.
What I learned is that, you
know, when you're angry,
you compensate for it in other ways. You
know, like I used to make her breakfast,
you know, espresso,
waffles, pancakes, you know,
no one got to me softly weeped in the
corner. That's right. That's right.
This will make up for it. But, but
what I learned, you know, after, uh,
after nine years, there's no number of
pancakes or race said shut the fuck up.
Shut your fucking mouth.
[inaudible] before we get,
I get too deep. But why don't we, uh,
why don't you back up here
for a second island? No,
just cause I've known you so long.
You know,
some of my listeners here cross here
just so they know, you know, uh,
how long have you been doing stand up
or where you started out? Oh, well let,
let's, let's get into stand
up inside the actor's studio.
I think that the first time, uh, you
know, I did stand up, I was in a,
I was in college,
I did an open mic.
I was in a team with another guy I met
in College Guy Steve Brill when they went
on stage with, with, with another,
originally we put the, we put the,
I put my first standup together,
always wanting to do it,
but I met this guy in college who,
uh, we auditioned for something,
catch a rising star at that time.
It must've been 80, 83, 82 83.
And that's one in Cambridge in Boston?
No, no, this was the original one.
That one didn't exist then. It
was the old, the original catch,
a rising star that was still up on the
upper east side in a, in New York City,
the original green kitchen.
Right, right. Okay. So, uh,
so they had posted all these signs
around my college, uh, you know, uh,
catch a rising star live on campus.
They were putting together a show,
like a showcase of college
acts, like new acts. So,
so we put together this team bit and
we auditioned for them, you know,
in a room and they liked it. And then we,
we, uh, audition for them. Uh, what was,
what was the name of it?
Marin in something.
And I don't remember if we had a name. I
think it was just Martin and Brill. Uh,
and you know, it was a series of
sketches. It wasn't even real team.
It wasn't like teen comedy. It wasn't
like a straight guy and a goofy guy.
We actually had several different sketches
that we did. I kind of remember them.
They're the one sketch was, uh, you
know, where the word nigger came from.
Oh, it's Jesus. You came right out
bolt. Barrel's well, no, it was like,
and I hate to say that word even,
you know, even in the context of, uh,
of a casual conversation, even though I,
yeah, cause I get in trouble for that one.
It's when,
what I was trying to have a conversation
about that word with a couple of black
comics and I said the word as I just did
now, and a woman in my audience said,
just the fact that you said it, I'm
done with you. See, that's retarded.
That's another word you're not supposed
to fucking say. It's just how like,
you can't even like that. That's when
your, uh, people who do stuff like that,
it's like they're not even listening to
you. They just have lists of words like,
these words are good. He's lords of
bad debts. There's no like a, right.
But I can't make gate tech feeling that
she had. I mean, you know, if that word,
no matter what context it is,
makes her co horrendously upset,
then there's nothing I can do about that.
Whether it's right or wrong, I, you know,
I can't account for her feeling. So we
did that sketch, which was these two, uh,
these two guys that were like,
you know,
white guys who were working and they
were trying to name the, you know,
the figure out a nickname for the people.
And it was like diggers and it was stupid.
And then we did another one.
We did a Neil Armstrong's,
if Neil Armstrong were on the moon,
the first moon walk if you were on acid.
So my buddy played ground
control and I play,
I was doing the bit where I was on the
memo and crushed. Yeah, I would did well.
And then we did another one
that, uh, a Japs funeral.
Like we did these two Jewish girls who
were at a funeral of a friend, you know,
and they were like, oh my God, she looks
so thin. You have that kind of shit.
They ain't go. You kind of got
everybody. Yeah. Yeah. Lacks Jews.
So what happens then is
that, uh, we, uh, we, we, we,
we auditioned him at the comedy
connection. We go to do it live.
We had done it in a room and they said,
we want to see you alive. And we bombed.
Bombed. It's just like sucking silence
now. What, what do you think? So the,
wait a minute. Wait, so the first
time you ever did it on comedy stage,
now I've always said the first
time if I bomb the first time,
I don't know if I would ever have the
courage to go back and do it again.
Well that that's the difference
between people that are, are, are,
are hooked on it and people,
yeah.
People who are born comics and people
who are just, you know, dabbling.
Is that like really, if you bond you
would have done it again. It would've,
it would've taken me a minute. I
would had it been like, just the,
the sheer fucking embarrassment
of, uh, of taking the hit. I mean,
you can, this is deal with stand up. You
can still eat it today. I'm 18 years in.
I kinda, yeah, you can eat
it, but this is the thing.
You have years of good shows to be like,
well you know,
I know I don't suck at this.
I had a bad night.
But you know right out of the gate. Oh
yeah. The bad night thing is hard to,
to really get around. You had,
cause it still hurts me if I bombed,
but when you're up there and you know
you have this whole idea that you know,
it's, it's never, the
audience is bullshit. I mean
sometimes it's the audience,
right. And you know,
like you, you can tell,
you know you've done your shit and you
can see where they're peaking laughter
wise and you know,
after a certain point that they're
not going to go any further than that.
So I'll get after it.
I'm just going to have to realize this
is the best I'm going to do in this
situation and either eat it
and you don't take the hit or,
or make light of the fact. Yeah. I've,
I've learned like there's nothing worse
than being angry on stage, but I heard,
I actually heard a funny story last
night. I was doing a Gig and uh, this, uh,
this book or Jeff Wills from the note
yet. Yeah. He was telling a story.
He saw one night said Bill Hicks did
an entire show with his back to the
audience. It was like a
Bachelorette party. There was
every fucking thing it did.
Yeah. Those like those Booker's they love
to talk about those stories, you know?
But if anyone else did that now,
they would never fucking work in that
club again. All these guys pretend like,
you know, like, oh,
Bill Hicks was the guy and he went
onstage and angrily tanked and a brilliant
inspired way almost all the time.
But if someone existed like that
now he wouldn't have a fucking shot.
It think so. Absolutely. Well, I bet.
I bet he was still selling tickets at
that point because you can't, you can't,
you can't turn your back on a fucking
crowd and everything that you're going to
work.
I don't think that's true.
I think that the reason he got booked
in this country primarily was to,
to make club owners feel like they were,
you know,
they were at least championing
something terrific.
Like I think they innately knew this guy
was special. There was no one like him.
And even the fact that he didn't sell
tickets or alienated the audience every
time they were going to have him twice a
year to keep their content straight. Oh.
So that can be dicks to everybody else
basically. Yeah. But just sort of like to,
to at least support that.
At least they knew well enough
that he was an inspired guy.
But I've gotten angry on stage. I did
it the other night, dude, not in it.
And it had been a long time because I
used to snap all the tabs and I say,
that's kind of an understatement coming
from you. Yeah. But that's like me saying,
I've snapped. No, but, but you know,
I'm pretty accessible now. No, no. Yeah.
You're your way your way. Uh, but
it happened at the store, dude.
It happened how long ago?
Two nights ago. And I, I, I,
I could've done this whole thing. Yeah,
much better now. Much better enough.
I snap one time. One is that 48 hours
ago, I couldn't believe I did it.
It's such a different person. You
know, that place brings it out of you.
Come on the comedy store brings
it out of here sometimes. I,
that's what I love it though. It's so
fucking so I'm on stage. It is evil.
It is. It's just painted
on heat. You know,
you feel the walls wanting you to lose
it, you know, it's just in the place.
So I'm on stage,
it's like 40 people in the room and like,
I'm already like just right when
I get in there. You have some kid,
that kid David Taylor, you know that
kid, he's a tall guy, used to do comedy.
He's very, you know, cynical and negative
and I just, I wasn't in the mood for it.
I hadn't seen him in months.
And then I said hi to him and he goes,
I'm staying around just to see you.
You better be good.
And so right away I'm like,
I haven't seen you in a fucking long time.
You have no right to fucking talk like
that to me enough with the negative shit.
You know what? I bought it, stormed
off, get again and anger for,
and I walked back and made me feel
really good about myself by them because
usually I sound like the angry psycho.
I can be like the happy person.
Just take a break. Yeah, there you
go. Go ahead. You Go. All right. So,
so I get onstage magical one on who
I think is just terrific. I love owl.
He's fine. I think he's fucking hilarious.
Really original, unique stylists,
real storyteller. He does good, you
know? And then he brings me up and then,
you know,
I'm getting laughs.
There's only like 30 or 40 people
in the or and it's going fine.
There's an old couple up front,
the Oh maybe in their mid
fifties early sixties and they,
if someone talked to him and
they asked him about religion,
I think Neal Brennan did. They said
they were Jews. I'm like, fine.
So I'm doing my show and
they're not laughing at nothing.
And I looked at them and I said,
uh, I'm sorry, my two filthy.
You want me to talk some political
stuff, you know, is, is that what it is?
And then the old man looks at me, he
goes, you're not funny. Yeah. And I,
and I just had this moment where I'm like,
all right, dude, all right. And I said,
you know what? I am
funny. I know I'm funny.
I'm doing well with the rest
of the audience. All right.
And, and I, and, and I,
I understand what you're saying.
And uh,
and then like for some reason
I just looked at him, I said,
but the fact that that's what you had
to pull out of your guts to say to me in
this situation makes me fucking hate you.
And,
and, and the Syrup punchline there,
mark, now you lose the rest of the crowd.
It's right there. Just quiet in a room.
And I'm like, what? That wasn't funny.
What did I say? Did Not come out funny?
Now you turn on the rest of them.
All right. Then I turned on the rest of
them. And then, uh, and then he goes,
you know, you asked and I said, well,
you could've qualified it. Like,
how about you're not funny to me.
All of a sudden you're the god of this
fucking room. You're the Almighty.
You're the one that has the last
word. Fuck that. Right. And so that,
and then like you were in a bad mood
before you got there because you really
don't, because I've got to say the
read of this guy saying are not funny.
Sounds to me like you said some
shit that he didn't want to hear.
It was more of a subject thing. Not,
not, no, I just, it was a general thing.
So then I,
and the rest of the act,
I'm doing my act and everyone's
laughing every time everyone else will.
After I looked at him and I went,
Huh, Huh. And then like, you know,
at the end of my set and bringing
up Brenda's is easy and he,
he stands up with his wife and they
walk out at, while I'm still on stage,
bring it up Steve. And like a very
powerful statement. Very powerful.
I'll see you later, dad. Ah,
Jesus, mark. Cause that's what
I said to him. I said, hey,
now you know, it's like every fucking
Jewish guy that has that kind of judgment.
That's your rage. It's just some
surrogate for my father. And I understand.
I'm translate.
I'm transposing some contempt under you,
but you could have fucking
shows a different way. All
right. All right. Anyway,
Mark Marin here on Monday morning
park. But that's not funny. No, no, no,
I'm just letting people know I'm
acting northern. I that just did there.
I acted like this was a live show. I
like it. Like we'll take some color,
like when it takes him. We're actually
doing this on Easter Sunday and I,
uh, mark asked me what I want to do and
I said, I will do it Sunday. And you go,
you do realize it's Easter. And I was
like, yeah, I'm really not into that shit.
But I actually went to church
this morning with my, uh,
with my girlfriend and her and
her mom because her mom goes,
so I went with her and a dude. You
should've heard the homily. Yeah.
That guy was up there.
The homily is basically after they tell
one of those you're Jewish, right? Yeah.
Yeah. So after they tell like the
little Jesus, diddy, yeah, they have,
they have like an opener.
Yeah.
It tells a couple of little ones than
the pre springs at home. You know,
it's all dressed up. The headliner come
Catholic. A Catholic. Oh yeah. Oh yeah.
The whole thing.
Deaf kids looking confused outside.
How is anyone any adhere to that
religion after this? You can,
I even told, I even was talking
to some, some older people,
they were saying the same thing. Like
when the collection thing went around,
I wanted to give money for the
fucking car wash or whatever.
But I'm thinking like,
yeah,
but isn't this going to go towards a
defense attorney for somebody who did all
the fucking deaf kid? I'm not giving
you any more money. Sort that out first.
And now it's like,
it's not an American thing.
It's also in Europe and in the
numbers and this has been going on for
generations. It's almost like it
was a contest with these guys.
Does it count if you do the same kid
twice? Yeah. Do you want to be a cardinal?
You've got to digital at least fucking
three. I have a theory about it.
I think I know why there's so many gay,
uh,
or pedophile priests because I think that
these communities going back, you know,
hundreds of years,
certainly in this country,
and I imagine other countries that when
a mother or a community saw that one of
their male kids was going the way of the,
the cock,
then they started to pick up that they
were feminine. I mean the, you know,
communities are gay thing just,
no, no, no, no, no. Wait, let
me go this way. All right.
I know what you know. What I'm saying
is that when they saw that happening,
they muscled these kids into the
priesthood. They said that as,
as opposed to live a life of sin as
a homosexual, probably go that way.
Let's push them towards the priesthood.
Now the,
and I'm not saying this will offset
the Dick Sucking. That's right.
And I think what happens,
it'll be safe,
but they couldn't do that in the
priesthood. So I think a lot of them, uh,
you know, I'm not saying that
they're, they're homosexuals.
I know that they're pedophiles,
but I think that the guilt compounded
with the idea that they may have been
homosexual and then that actually made
them more evil cause then they would prey
upon these kids that couldn't say
anything that they could terrify and
completely control with this
horrendous urge they have.
I gotta be honest with you. I have no idea
because it fascinates me because like,
um, I think cause a lot of people
out there, they confuse, uh,
it being gay with being a pedophile
because it is a guy and a boy,
you know what I mean? So that's completely
different yet because it's like,
all right,
you know,
you could stick me and in that place and
say that I can't hook up with anybody.
Yeah. And, uh, I'm still not going to
fuck a little girl. You know what I mean?
But I had a file,
but I think that that's absolutely true.
But I'm saying that I bet you a lot
of them were probably on the, on the,
on the Troy,
on the train.
If they weren't abused by
priests themselves on the train.
That's the thing about those guys is what
they've 16,000 it's like not only you
ruined, you ruin someone's
life. The second you do that,
that childhood is fucking over. You ruined
them. You blow a hole in their soul,
it's over.
And then this is the thing.
And then they go on to have kids and
even if even if they don't do anything to
them, it's just, it's attach
them. You generations.
Anytime you're talking 16,000 people
like that old prowl commercial,
they have five kids, they have five kids
here. They're all affected by that. Oh,
and you know what?
That troubled in loss of
their more candidates for the,
for, for the church. Yeah.
They, they become comedians. That's right.
They're actually creating new loss to
people in hopes that they will come back
to the Catholic church. Yeah.
So I think this, this priest,
because it was mandated,
all of that shit was kind of
opened this week. This priest,
I guess this guy is kind of
like, he's like the, the,
the instead of the comic's comic,
this guy's like the priest priests like
the back of the room to the deacons in
the back. This guys great lets the Guy
Great, you know, but he um, he like,
he's actually admitted that he actually
thought about leaving the priesthood for
awhile. He's actually, he didn't say why,
but today during his homily when
he's surmising the Jesus story,
he said something, he goes, you know, um,
a lot of people look at this religion,
you know, look at our religion like
we do. We say the, uh, the, the,
the wafer is the body of Christ and the
wine is his blood and they think that's
nonsense.
A lot of people think that because we
think that Jesus dwells in all of us,
that that's nonsense.
And he kept going,
just kept talking about major cornerstones
that are religion and people thinking
was nonsense. And I was
sitting there going, oh my God,
this is like the fucking Domino's pizza
moment where they finally admit that
their pizza sucks. Remember that whole
like, dude, what happened? Fucked up.
We're not recording. No, we are
recording, but I thought, I think,
see this is why we should have used to
me one. Okay. We're okay. We're okay.
We're okay. Yeah. There was a little jump
there. I apologize. I think we're okay.
I thought it had the metric.
We freaked on me.
We just actually literally for the first
time and the two and a half years of
the Monday morning podcast, it came.
It's stopped. It never stopped.
It's alive. God damn show. I just wanted
to make sure that wasn't it. Oh he, yeah.
He thought he thought the metronome was
on. That would be bad. My bad. My bad.
I just don't. So he was basically
Christ and he's sitting there.
He's having like the Domino's pizza mom,
you know where they,
they admit that that pizza sucked after
all these years and then they still try
to put out a fucking large
pizza for five bucks.
What do you think is going
to taste like idiots.
But he somehow spun it around where
uh, it was, it was the clothes.
You know what he's doing?
He's actually telling the truth,
the way he can tell the truth without
having it be a national scandal.
Just going, I can't explain the way
he did the guy, he's fucking good.
I got a minute. I got admitted. David tell
was a priest. Yeah, this guy, he got ya.
I was like, this guy, this guy is good.
Look, and I got into it this year,
this week with like, I used to
do this, this, this section on,
on the podcast called old g h and I
would talk about a religion and you know,
for the most part, you know, I was
saying that they, they, ah, I don't know,
I can't even get into it.
But every once in a while people listened
to the old podcast where I was kind of
trashed and organized religion and they
come at me and they drive me fucking
nuts because they just
make grand statements.
Like he, like, like I said,
you know, I went like,
I went to church for the first time, 15
years, like a month, like two months ago.
Right. And when I went it was like,
I didn't like what they were saying,
but there was a feeling I had,
I liked the sense of community and
then what they do is they go, yeah,
that feeling you were feeling how
was, yeah, they always got the date,
like they own that fucking feeling.
So then I'm sitting there going like
talking about their fucking stories that
don't even make sense. Adam and eve
forget about how, you know, their,
their kids would then have to fuck and
then we'd be all descendants of retarded
children. Right. They, they, they don't
even address the dinosaurs. I'm like,
what about the dinosaurs and all that?
Never addressed that. They always just,
they never opened the
emails back and forth.
They will never address the
fucking points you make.
They just spend it all often to others.
It's okay,
Jesus is waiting for you and all
this type of shit. And it just,
it drives me fucking nuts. Like, and
then I, I show them were science,
like this is what I can't stand.
They'll attack scientist and say what
they're saying is wrong until they can't
fucking deny it anymore.
Like the fact that the,
that the sun doesn't go
around the earth and after,
if they've tortured and
killed fucking people,
then what they do is then they embrace
it and then they act like it's theirs.
And then they're like, well, who made the
scientist? Jesus made the same teacher.
And it's like,
it's just a spin thing and they just
hold on to their beliefs until it becomes
irrefutable. And then they sort, it's sort
of like those people like, well, how I,
what I always thought was
fascinating is that these colts,
you remember years ago,
there was more of them where you'd have
this cult where the leader would say,
the world is going to end on
this date to tomorrow's the day.
And they get these, these, these followers
frothing that and like ready, prepared.
They're underground, they're
in bunkers, they're gonna go,
they're all strapped in and then the
day comes and it passes and it doesn't
happen. I would love to be at that sermon
because then it's sort of like, well,
you know,
it doesn't mean it's not going to happen.
And now that we've got all
this underground infrastructure
that's right here,
let's start a mushroom farm.
Let's use this. Yeah. Now
that we're in the basement,
I just don't understand how they re read,
bought. Tell you why. Because you've got,
people are so fucking stupid. They're
stupid. That's true. That that, yeah,
you got it. But you're seeing
that now even outside of
religion, even in politics,
that because there's so much information
out there, people, here's what,
here's what really fascinates me is they
will believe what they believe and you
can't shake their beliefs
even with facts because now,
because there's so much information
because the internet, they can just go,
well that's your version. That's,
that's the spin. The truth.
The facts are the spin and that they,
you know, that you can believe that,
but you're wrong.
No, do it. It drives me,
it drives me nuts in it.
And then they'll just like at one
point, uh, I want to go and like,
and like you guys have persecuted
science. Like basically my, my,
my theory is that science is religion
for intelligent people forward thinking
people and religion is science for morons
because whatever they can explain they
just invent fucking bushes talking to
people and albatrosses or whatever the
fuck they have conspiracy theories
and this is what they ended up saying.
She ends up riding back.
Well actually science has proven the
Bible correct over and over again.
So I'm like, okay, what's the, where's
the followup statement to support that?
Nothing. Yeah, there's nothing.
Yeah, there's nothing, there's no,
no followup statement whatsoever. All
they do is they just, they, they, they,
they like I can actually sit here and
prove to you that the fucking earth goes
around the sun because of scientists.
I'm too fucking stupid approval,
but it actually on makes sense.
None of this shit can
be proven on paper and,
and then when you show stuff that can
be proven on paper that disproves their
shit, then they do that. She'll,
well, God created the scientist.
He created the paper that they
wrote it. Yeah. I actually find,
I tapped out in that moment. I was like,
you know what? I get it now. You, you,
no matter what I say are going to believe
what you're going to say and I'm never
going to convince you that's right
of the way that I think so fuck it.
So I'm done with it.
But we also,
funny thing, I'm done with it yet
you can't, you can't go to it.
There's no reason to go to war with those
people because belief is impenetrable
no matter how delusional they are.
It's based in complete ignorance and it's
something, it's something outside of,
of intelligence.
Yeah. But this is what I don't care,
cause I bought into it when I was a kid.
We were scared and I was,
I was listening to us scared and
then also thinking like, all right,
and some of this is good. It was like
my fucking house. It was like my life.
Someone who was good,
someone was bad at.
But then he's just got to
a point where it's like,
this shit doesn't make sense and it's so
loud in your head you can't ignore it.
And I don't understand.
I,
well that's because that's a
real fucking arrogant statement.
I'm going to say only.
Yeah,
you got to be a moron to just continue to,
uh,
to, to, to block it out.
That's the difference between free
thinking and thinking based in fear. You,
you know, cause like the way it
works in my mind is what? Look,
the world is a scary place.
Everything is, is serendipitous.
Who the hell knows when you're
going to get hit by a truck?
Who knows when the earth is going to
fall into the sea or start shaking?
No one knows anything.
There's very little,
there's very few things we have control
over in our wife. Just is, I mean, you,
you know how this, this garage could
slide down the hill at any second.
Who the hell knows very
few things out of our,
are in our control
almost nothing right now,
depending on how frightening that is. Even
if you understand everything in, in, uh,
uh, you know, proportionately,
like, you know, the,
the possibility of this
happening versus that having,
even if you're scientific
about the, the how, how, how,
how much fate has to do
with our everyday life,
that is not completely
comforting. So depending on how
overwhelmed you are, right,
you, I, yeah.
So I believe on some level the need
to believe or feel like you're part of
something bigger than you to,
to sort of justify your existence or
make you feel comfortable in the world is
probably almost genetic.
I just feel that, that,
that the way communities function
or whatever, but you know,
you can make it your community,
you can make it a, your television,
you can make it sports,
whatever the hell it is.
There's part of our brain that wants to
be part of a bigger thing in order to
feel that were significant.
Thank you.
Just go in the ground and I'm comfortable
with that because that's a whole
different thing,
right?
But I'm just talking about the
need to believe now you know what,
you're gonna be able to grow
unbelievable potatoes. That's fine.
It's my Irish DNA in the soil.
But I think that the people that,
whose lives are so fucking miserable
that they can't even fathom post us happy
go lucky son's, we got a lot
to be grateful for it. We do.
It doesn't mean we appreciate it. That's
true. That's true. But, but, but there,
I think there's some people
that handle it and, and the,
the idea of having to them,
which I agree with you is ridiculous and,
and frankly boring. I mean the idea
that we live forever, I, you know,
I can barely get through this
one. Right. And, and, and the,
and the idea of that and the idea that
like it's going to be better because of
boredom. Oh my God, that
doesn't even make sense.
Like if it's absolute
fucking euphoria forever,
it would get boring. Oh my God, they
will get boring. And that's like,
at some point you'd be like,
can I get a day pass the hell I
want to fucking have a good time.
They'd be the hell would be like Vegas
and having a tail. What are you going?
I'm going to hell for three weeks.
You've got some time off from this
tedious fucking happy bullshit.
I want to be able to feel happiness again,
like me on fire for fucking three weeks,
so I can appreciate that it go.
Have you been to the fifth ring? Awesome.
Awesome. It great. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
We went there. The wife and
I went, it was tremendous.
They had great performance.
You'll all the comics went to hell.
So they're all there. You got to go
to the fifth ring. It's tremendous.
Great shows. Great. Surely the heck, not
even the hacks. You can see Houdini there.
It's amazing. Through speaking
of that Shit, you know, I did a,
like I did a theater, uh, what was it,
the San Jose Improv recently and uh,
he allegedly performed there
and all these guys, it was fun.
It was a classic old theater that had,
had gone through that a hundred years
of history of like the most beautiful
thing ever.
And people flocked and an opulent place
and then slowly deteriorated to like a
porn porno movies.
People jerking off.
Somebody like Jackie Onassis
put some money together and
they fucking revive its,
got a colorful history of corruption
and filth. Oh yeah. Great. Absolutely.
Absolutely. Just like show business
should, yeah. So I went to, I did the, uh,
the Gibson amphitheatre last night for
the Kevin and being show a radio show it
of this cancer. But I remember
when a bean was in, uh,
what was the name of the comedy team?
Steven Bean.
Christina Zito and being from Boston,
is that right?
Fuck you did not even know
that. Yeah. Chris bean or Steve.
I always heard about her. Yeah. Those guys
used to kill. That's that. That's them.
Okay. Ju Ju Ju Ju Ju Ju
they used to open with Ima,
Judah [inaudible] today he's a Waba.
Yeah.
That was either being, yeah,
that was a fucking eighties,
man. That was before, uh,
when, when, when, when
did you start? Well,
getting back to me after
I did the team thing,
I was more thinking how to Waapa Dude
Wapa do would actually get a laugh. Well,
no, no. I might ignore
it to think that shit.
We were talking about
the up the other night,
we were looking at a particular
comedian going, you know what,
if this is a fucking eighties,
this guy would be famous by now because
it just seemed everybody back then is
completely subjective. If,
if, if you have, like if you
had any sort of a character,
the glasses you're wearing,
if you always wore those on stage,
if you did back then three evening
at the Improv classes. Yeah,
but you can't even get a pair of
glasses. It doesn't look like this. Now,
believe me, I don't want to surrender
to the horn rims, but you really,
you really have to struggle and fight
to find something different. Right now,
buddy Holly's there. They're everywhere.
I mean, some version of them.
I used to wear round glasses member and a,
and I,
I can find out what's funny about you.
Yeah. You got that whole rock star looks.
So when you were the round ones, you
had the John Lennon look, and now,
now you're looking a little a buddy
Holly and the crickets. That's all right.
I'd rather be a Peggy shoe then. Uh,
then, uh, no, that's not true. They're,
they're both good. I'm not going to
take anything away from John Lennon,
but speaking of the eighties,
it's just quickly cause I
feel like I left it hanging.
Is that after I did the team thing,
you know,
he graduated and went on to direct
Adam Sandler movies. I, you know,
I wrote a whatever it
Steve Brill did. Um, but I,
I stayed in Boston and I started on
my own. I started to play it again,
Sam's and the basement doing open mics,
but Kenny Rogers and everybody else.
My last year of college I was doing
open mics that summer and I drank myself
almost to death and was
waiting all night long.
Have those stories when you bring up
Kenny? Yeah. Well I, I mean not with him,
but I used to just wait. You hit back
then you had to wait to go on to,
everyone else was done for three people.
I couldn't take it.
And then when I graduated college,
I moved to Hollywood.
I became a doorman at the comedy store.
I was there for a year and then I hit
the wall and drugs and I went back to
Boston. Started over catch. Well wait a
minute, slow down here. Let's do this.
Do the behind the music here.
Mark Marin.
A lot of people know that story already
know you don't want to put it out there
again. Oh no I don't care. But I,
I mean the people who know me know why I
came out to after I graduated college I
already had a pretty good uh, coke
monkey on my back. So I drove out here.
I moved in, I was in Culver city living
with Steve. Just out of curiosity,
did you start before the ad campaign?
Uh, cocaine, the big lie. Oh of course.
I started, I, I started when
the ad campaign was a coke.
It's good for you. Yeah.
Yeah. It was no more addictive
than a caffeine. Good
Times. We were all doing it.
So I come out here and I can
move into a place in Culver city.
Would Steve Brill that guy?
We wrote a screenplay and then I never
wanted to talk to them again cause we're
is unbearable. And then, uh, I auditioned
at the store. Uh, it, uh, you know, to,
to see if I could start doing
comedy and Mitzi, you're funny,
you can be a doorman. So, uh,
so I immediately moved into Crest
Hill and I was a doorman in 1987.
Uh, you know, when Kennison was, uh, was
just starting to come to break. And I met,
I met Carl and Carl was Sam's best
friend and he, uh, Carl, yeah,
he gave me a watch and said, you're
good people. When Sam comes back,
I want you to meet him and you don't
know the story. No, I'd tell it to you.
So a fly through it, I can tell you
sick of tell them no, no, I'm not,
I haven't done it that much.
And certainly people on your
podcast might not know it.
The people that don't
listen to both of ours,
but they know if they know
Sam Kennison favorites.
This is a selfish fucking moment. I
want to, I'll tell you what, Harry,
it's a great story. All right.
Uh, so like I, you know,
I didn't really know that much
about Canada and when I got there,
I'd seen him once or twice, but I had
really dismissed him as this novelty act,
you know, this screaming guy and I,
I wasn't here nor there with them.
So when Carl said,
I'll meet an introduce you to Sam,
I didn't know what that meant.
So Sam comes in,
you know Carlos like does that guy that's
talking to you, he's talking about,
he's the new head Doorman and San
Jose Guy, the doorman. So you're,
you're a new guy, you know, am I?
Yeah, yeah. And he's like, Hey,
we should hang out and talk.
And I'm like, all right, so,
so I'm living in Crest Hill, so
he knows that place too. Right.
So the first night I ever hang out
with Sam Kennison, he, you know,
he comes up to Cresto,
which is that house Mitzi used to own.
And I'm standing there,
you and guys,
she used to live there a lot of pieces
so that, yeah, that's that classic house.
Just to tell my listeners, know when
comics, like you would move out to La,
if Mitzi tapped you on the
shoulder and knighted you,
you then moved into this house where
you had to pay rent and also drive the
fucking jeep and take me, go get
her chicken. Totally. Totally.
But like the amount of Comedians who
lived there? Oh yeah. Dice with their,
the Todd was there to mio,
this was the tricky thing to
[inaudible] who used to date?
Sam was the Japanese comic.
I don't know what happened to her,
but she lived upstairs. You know,
I lived in dices old room. Uh,
Todd wasn't moved in yet.
I'm trying to think of who Todd lemme,
she w w later went on to have,
he used to call himself that Todd and
he eventually had some sort of aneurysm
and, and you know, showed up at the club
saying, you know, years after Sam died,
say in Tim's, come in and you
know, he was sent to Florida Bay.
But if that's a Shubert lived there
for awhile, the places evil. Yeah.
Oh definitely. Definitely.
So, so what happens is I'm
living up there and, and uh,
and Sam says, you know, let's
go up to the house, you know,
and this is the way it worked
back then as Monday night, uh,
in the late eighties was no cover
night and all the rooms were free.
So all the freaks from Hollywood and
everywhere came to the store on Monday
night. And that was Sam's night.
He would show up at about 1130,
12 o'clock on a Monday,
take over the stage and the main room,
which was just filled with rock
and roll drug freaks and just say,
this is like hair, metal, hair metal,
but all different kinds of hair metal.
The end of, towards the end of the
hair metal. Yeah. So like, you know,
the people that would come to the club
where it was pretty spectacular, you know,
and I was a doorman and at that time that
people you'd see on stage where people
like dice Damon Wayans Kennison prior
was still coming by occasionally.
Riced um, you know, so I was just,
I just entered this world, right?
So Sam says, let's hang out.
So we go up to the house,
it's just me and Sam were doing coke.
He pulls out all this coke and we're
just sitting there and he's like, sure,
you're the new guy, you know? And he's
looking right in my face. He's like, look,
me in the eyes mayor, and a lack of men
who can look me in the eyes. And I'm like,
Holy Shit. All right, I'm looking right.
So we're sitting there doing coke
and I thought I was Mr Rock and roll.
I can handle coke. So I'm doing coke with
Sam and he's laying out the the world,
you know, as Sam, you know,
Deq. And the thing, I cannot
tell you how it works here.
Who mayor and you know, and then like,
you know, I didn't know where he goes,
Hey Marin, you ever, you ever burned
money? And I'm like, no. And he's like,
let's burn some money.
So Sam pulls out these hundred dollar
bills and we start burning money at Sam's.
I'm figuring, fuck, fuck yeah.
Okay, what's burden? Some money.
So we're sitting there burning money and
we're getting fucked up and it's about
three 34 in the morning and you were at
a coke and Sam's wasted and I'm kind of
wasting, he's like, we need
more money to no he, yeah,
he shouldn't have done that to me cause
I called that back later and he wasn't
at that happy about it. I mean I
made them do it like the way this,
I'll tell you what happens is the first
night, so he's like, we're at a coke,
let's go get some more coke. And
I'm like, all right, I don't,
I don't know where we're going.
So we get in my car,
I'm driving like pretty much one of
the biggest stars in comedy through the
Hollywood hills at like three
30 in the fucking morning.
He's half passed out in my car like, and
I'm driving like, where are we going?
Where are we going? He like, he like wakes
up and he goes, I don't even know you.
You could kill me. And I'm
like, where are we going dude?
So we ended up at this guy's house.
Now at this point is he stopped being Sam
Kennison and it's become some annoying
guy that you're partying with.
No,
he is still really good at
staying in say still Sam. Okay.
Even when he was like swappy,
you know when it got pathetic,
he still held on to that thing and it was
always sort of men and Sam were burned
money. Dude, I, I started too
fucking late in this business. I so,
so we fund was gone so we'd
get to this guy's house,
this guy who as as time went on, I real,
I grew to know was a hairdresser by day,
but with Sam's coke dealer
at the time and it's out on,
that was done on crescent heights,
wasn't that far from the store.
So we knock on this door, this guy
shows up at the door in his bathrobe,
clearly woke him up from sweeping.
I got Sam there. He's like,
we need some coke and we barrel into
this guy's house and we're in this guy's
bedroom and Sam just sits on the floor and
crashes on the floor. He goes, got any,
you got any booze? And,
and this guy was like,
I just got these miniatures
I got on the plane.
So now Sam is sitting there with these
like smear enough bottles of vodka,
drinking the smeared out.
If you look like a giant,
like he should have been surrounded
by into the rock and roll people going
and then like, you know, he passes
out in this guy's floor and you know,
the guy gives me the coke,
you know,
I ended up paying for it
and then I go out there,
an Asian guy throwing fire fireworks.
It should have been, it should have.
So I'm like, well I don't know what the
hell to tell you I'm going to take off.
I guess he'll deal with him. He's like,
dude, you're not fucking leaving him here.
I don't want him to pull a Belushi on me.
And I'm like, what? And I'm like, Oh fuck.
So now I've got to get him up and walked
him out and throw them in the car and
he was big and I get
them back to the house.
We go in and he doesn't even do the coke.
He ends up crawling on the
floor in the living room,
just laying on the floor and passing out,
which is something he did a lot because
that house became the party houses.
He draped in the scarves and
12 fucking head wraps. Not yet.
I mean this is early Sam. So it was still
just a trench coat and the cap dude,
this is not, this is pre
rock and roll. Sam. He's,
I don't have any story that can
match this. The falling out was,
was the better story. I mean cause like
that year, well how does that night,
and he just passes out. You pass this out
and then, you know, he wakes up and then,
you know, we'd, we'd build this bond.
I get sucked into the Kennison
entourage and I'm now like, you know,
doing my graduate work and cutting
coke for Sam Kennison. And,
and it was my job at that
point to organize the party.
Like Sam would do this every,
every Monday night.
It became very taxing because
I knew he was coming in.
What would happen is he'd show up in the
fucking party would start and like he'd
show up at the store,
he'd give me a couple of hundred
bucks and I'd go by all the booze and
cigarettes and mixers and everyone
needed to bring up to the house.
So I would get into this pattern.
After a while I knew how long
the party could go on for.
It could go on for two or
three days, 15 years. I didn't,
I had no idea who did
this stuff. Yeah. So like,
so I used to get this shit
so I'd go buy all this booze,
but I know what would happen is that
he'd show up with 20 people and then come
day two or three. It just be me and Sam
and some freaks like, you know, you know,
it ended up like eight people. So I would
hide the liquor all around the house.
Now you up for the three days.
That hardcore shit.
How the fuck did you write any jokes?
Well,
I was only working the belly room
and you know, we were all in the,
and we were on in the comedy store at
school in the Sam school where she's like,
you know,
you lived your life as hard as possible
when he got up there and you fucking did
the work. Well other newer
comedians resent you that you,
you got into the Sam because like
at that time, you know, it was like,
who the fuck would want to
be in that entourage? Right.
I mean at that time the guy who used
to be Mitsis assistant was like, uh,
you know, he used to call us the
Manson family because you know,
Sam was like this weird charismatic
freak that dwelled in the underworld.
In most of the comics there were, you
know, were sort of like, you know,
just working comics. I mean he was one of
a kind. That's what always blew my mind.
If I could just stop this for just
half a second was where did guys like
Seinfeld fit in? Cause he was
around during that time. Like,
I just can't imagine like that universe
where there was like a level of party
anyway, he would just come in. But he was
singular in that, you know, he, he, he,
you know, he was, you
know, he celebrated it.
I mean there's a lot of comics as you
known as we all know that had their abuse
and substance of problems,
but you know,
they would try and hide
it and just do their job.
There were plenty of hacky comics
that were fucked up on drugs,
but the fact that Sam had to live the
life as the beast, like out of the beast,
he had the honor it.
So he was the first one that the,
that was shameless about it. And then
you'd see all these other comics that you,
I don't need to drop names, are mentioned
names where they'd come around and,
you know,
they'd hang out and do some blow,
but they wouldn't want to
be tagged with it. You know,
there was a lot of guys that would hang
out and do coke and be like, you know,
don't, don't nobody, you know,
I mean I saw a lot of that.
I mean there are certain people that
would come up and party with us that we
weren't allowed to do drugs.
Like one time Ted Nugent was hanging
around and saying it was like no drugs
because dad is clean.
So we had to sit there and I'll behave
ourselves for the three hours that Nugent
sat there and talked
whole wild boar stories.
Well he used to hold court at this house.
So I go out and stock up the place and
set up the party and then he'd come up
with all this freaks and then it just,
a lot of times would end up just me
and him are and two or three people and
eventually I started to lose my mind
and I wasn't progressing as a comic.
I was losing a lot of weight.
I was sleep deprived.
I was driving poor fuckers to the airport
in Mitsis w when they had to go play
the dunes because that was part of my,
my job to work at the store was
to drive the guys to the airport.
I remember one time I was driving, you
know, Mendoza and camp and era to the,
to the Burbank airport because they had
to go play the comedy store that was at
the dunes at that time.
And I'd been up all night and there
was no gas and I could've killed those
fucking guys. It's Christ. So like, so
what, it ultimately started happening,
I started losing my mind, you know, you
get to sleep deprived, too much drugs.
He started to hear voices, hearing voices
in your head and I, you know, and you're,
you're a conspiracy guy.
I had a mystical conspiracy organized
around Sam and Hollywood and how I,
you know, like I used to do this
bit about how like, you know,
I thought I was special. I didn't think
it was a sickness because you know,
when you hear voices in your head,
it's never one. It's always many.
And he spent a lot of time trying to
get them to pick a fucking leader.
You have someone's got something to say,
step to the front of the head.
I need instructions.
So I'm losing my mind and,
and thank fucking God, you know,
uh, the shit hit the fan. Uh,
ultimately after almost a year of this
living like this, you know, uh, you know,
Sam had, he, you know,
every week for a year you were
up for three days straight.
And then once I got out, unless I went
out, well, you know, Tim, now two, three,
two days, but you'd have to take breaks.
I mean, it wasn't, he'd go on the road.
I mean, it wasn't that
steady, but you know,
it was part of a cycle because even when
he was gone, we were all hopped up and,
uh, like he'd do weird shit, you
know. I mean, the one time, you know,
there's this chick,
I remember one night at the table,
there was some girl like
sitting at the table,
you never knew who showed up there.
And I started to get that creepy
feeling like someone's going to die.
And it might be me cause there was just
too much weirdness going on up there.
And I remember one night like,
um,
some chick was at the table and
she had a bandaged wrist, you know,
and I didn't know when she was all
wasted and like, uh, you know, so I said,
why is your risk bandage? And she goes,
well I tried to kill myself. And I said,
well, once you do the
other wrist, and she goes,
cause I didn't want to fuck up my watch.
And I'm like, what? You know, and,
and then she, she goes, I just remember.
So she goes into the other room and
passes out in a couple of hours later or
spark, he comes up to me and goes, I think
Sam pissed on that girl. And I'm like,
what are you talking about?
And like she was weighing in Todd's,
Ben's there was pissed all over the place.
And Sam at this weird thing
where occasionally he pissed
on things. It was just,
he was weird. So essentially killing my
Sam Kinison all right, go ahead. Well,
here's the, here's the story though. I
like, I didn't know he did the drugs.
I just don't need to know the
peeing. Well, this is the,
this is the punchline of this story and
I apologize if people have heard this
story, but it is sort of
comedy lore that interests you.
Okay. These to be this guy
that hung around the comedy
store, he was a satanist.
He, his name was Dave London and uh,
I, I should fictionalize his name.
His name was Dave. I don't
know what, it's too late.
So this guy had like a Pentagram tech I,
you said his whole name and then he goes,
I'm going to fictionalize it.
And he just said, just his
real first. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm just trying to help out.
I don't want to hurt anyone's
feelings or get myself in trouble.
So this guy had a pentagram
tattooed on his heart. He
had six, six, six on his arm.
He had the mark of the
Illuminati on the other arm.
You look at Christopher walk and he was
a dope fiend and he used to hang around
the store and we couldn't get rid of them.
You know how the store is,
it attracts these fucking people in
there. There, there, there will be,
because there's no, it's just that
open hallway where people, it's also,
it's a psychic drain for fucking dark
weird people. You know, it's a home. They,
it's for the, for the people who don't
fit in, fit in at the store, you know,
which is why I love it so much.
But this,
you guys used to hang around and Sam hated
him. I don't, I never knew really why.
So one night, you know,
a couple of nights,
I can't remember if it was a couple of
days before his HBO special premiered. Uh,
he,
he brought all his guitars and shit.
He played guitar up to the House and
we had this big jam session out on the
patio.
It was great.
Sam brought him up with a saint and Sam
just setting up the story and you know,
he took off and I'd put all the equipment
in my bedroom because Sam didn't want
to take it home. So a couple of nights
after that, we have a party at the house,
you know, Sam's up there.
And this guy, Dave,
the satanist shows up and we're all
doing drugs and it's getting weird and
they're sitting at the table and everyone,
he's holding court.
Sam isn't in Dave's there and a few other
people and, and Dave, the Stna says,
you know, like they're getting into
it about satanism like, you know,
it's like the beast versus the mini beast.
It was ridiculous. And then Dave goes,
I'm going to tell Anton levay about you.
You're not a real sadness.
And Sam just like stands up. And this
was a common tactic he used in fighting.
He stands up, he throws a drink in this
guy's face and pops him. Oh, that's good.
That's like the old throw salt and
the guy that does it. Sand. Yeah.
And there's a fight and there's a scuffle.
And then, you know, and then I'm like,
you know,
I break it up and Dave's all fucked up
and all the other people in the room are
freaked out and Dade, the Satan is his
shirts all ripped up. And I'm like,
you gotta get Outta here man.
You just gotta get Outta here.
You gotta get out of his face. He's
like, I'm not fucking even fuck that.
And I'm like,
well I got to leave cause I got to
pick up a buddy of mine at the airport.
I don't know what the hell to do it yet.
So I lock them in my room. All right.
I locked them in my room with the guitars.
That sounded like a good idea to me.
Right.
So I have to leave cause my buddy's
flying in and I told him I'd been hanging
out with Sam and this can be high right
now. Of course I will always high.
So I got to go pick up my buddy up at
the airport and I'd been telling him all
about Sam, you know, and this guy
was in Boston and he's like, yeah,
I used to do coke with him too.
And he was excited to come out.
So I picked them up at the airport.
We go to his hotel and I'm like,
I want to stay out of there.
I don't want to go back tonight.
I'm gonna crash at the hotel. So
I crashed at the hotel. All right.
And then we drive back to the house, you
know, me and my buddy in the morning,
all right. And we walk in
and it's like, you know it,
I walk into my room and it's been,
you know,
if the door had been kicked in the beds
all fucked up, all the equipments gone.
And I'm like, Oh fuck. What happened?
That walk into the living room and there
Sam sitting with two or three other
people, a weird mix of people and
they'd been at it all night, you know.
And I walk in and I'm with my
friend and uh, and I'm like,
this is my buddy bill and Sam just
sitting there. He goes, Marin,
I pissed on your bed.
You want to know why?
And I go, yeah, I do want
to know, have Sammy goes,
cause you let that idiot
sweep with my guitars.
And I know that apparently I turned
to my friend bill and I said,
I told you I knew him.
That was the last time I ever slept in
that bed night. And then I, that was,
I did the guy fuck up his guitars
and everything like that. No,
we didn't do anything. Sam just had
his fucking freak out. You know,
it's manic psychotic cocaine free guy.
I don't know what the hell transpired,
but I never signed no one.
I never slept in that bed again.
In a couple of days later I snapped at
the store and lost my shit and I packed
up everything.
I went up to the coke dealer who was
not the hairdresser at this point.
It was just Palestinian dude who was
kind of scary. I said, don't get it man.
I'm kicked out of the group, man.
What the fuck am I going to do?
And the coke dealer said,
you gotta get Outta here man.
You got to start your own thing. And when
the drug dealers telling you to leave,
yeah. You gotta lead.
Yeah. So I pack up my car,
I gave away everything and you
go find Jesus son back up my car.
And I think I'm hearing voices and um,
you know, and I, and I leave, I leave,
I call my brother and two
sides and I'm fucked up.
I'm coming to stay with you for a
few days. Do I get straightened out,
I got to go clean up. And uh, you know,
this is Christ you sound like slash.
Yeah. Well, so fucking
unbelievable. I was 21 years old to,
I was 21 old and I think,
can I
just pause for one second now and the
all you guys, uh, who know, you know,
listen to this podcast a lot and I
talk about my early days of stand up.
I swear to God, Mark, when I started
stand up in Boston, Massachusetts,
I started doing too well,
the amount of headliners,
I would say like 65% of the headliners
that I work with in my first three years,
they're opening line to their set
was saw a, been sober for six months.
Everybody was in fucking Aa.
Everybody you'd cleaned up.
And half of those guys were,
um, were what? She'd gone,
dude on the mic there. They, the a
half of those guys were like, um,
uh,
like their,
their wages were getting garnished by the
IRS because they were making like four
grand. Those guys like Sweeney and uh,
you know, I don't want to name names here.
That's one of the things on the podcast.
We don't name names,
you got to tell you that shit.
So they, they basically, yeah,
like these guys had fucking,
you know,
they've been making four grand cash
every fucking weekend for 10 years and
didn't pay a diamond taxes.
Right.
And then all of them basically couldn't
leave Massachusetts unless they got a
written note from the IRS or some shit.
So by the time I came in,
the rebellious thing to do was to go
on stage sober. Oh. If it was kind of,
it was tough. I should even say
rebellious. It was the norm.
So when I came in and the
guys I started out with,
and I'll mention names here just
because I'm not saying anything bad,
but I started off with Dane and Patrice
and like those guys just didn't drink.
And I came from a, like me and my friends,
we have a bunch of booze bags. Yeah.
And when I came in they didn't drink
and I saw how fucked up these guys were.
You know, who made, yeah. And, and, and
you know, in some of them had some regret.
Not all of them, but some of them
were. I should have done that yet.
So I immediately equated with,
oh, getting fucked up is stupid.
And so I started my whole
career, I started off, you know,
work totally clean and I w and I was and
I was totally sober and then a fucking,
this year I had to actually go in the
wagon for like two and a half months.
I don't know when it happened. Touring,
touring, he did it to me. No, it's,
he breaks you down. It's a
tough racket. But you know,
I mean I always wanted to be that. I
mean I, you know, before I got to La,
I always want him to be, you know,
I, all my heroes were fucks up.
We were fucked up. You know,
all my heroes, all, you know,
all the comics, you know,
all everyone, I respect. Why
is it so romantic that that
whole fucking cause I'm,
cause I'm sitting there going like
even as fucked up as that story is,
I'm sitting there like feeling like I'm
like show business light because I don't
have any stories of being up for
fucking three days and, and, and,
and I'm old enough to know I
don't want those fucking stories,
but you just don't want to
have a boring autobiography.
You know when you do that,
when the comedian,
when you finally hit and they give you
the book deal and you got to have unit
your head on your hand, like, well,
you know, they might take on life.
The truth of the matter is, is that,
you know, it doesn't help you and you,
you know, and if you stay
doing that, it will kill you.
There's no way around it that no,
but you want to have a couple of
fucking gets it. Great Story. Oh,
there's another story.
When I was hanging out with Sam Tani Lena
Aa meetings just to fucking listen to
the, Oh, he should Tommy Lee. I mean
I've been sober for over 10 years.
Over 10 years. You haven't done anything?
No, I, you know, I got, I got straight
got into the program, you know, you
know, learned how to rewire my brain.
I've done nothing. I'm a sober guy, 10
years it, but you know, whatever. Yeah,
but you know what?
You're a cool sober guy cause I
didn't even know that about you.
I mentioned to somebody last
night to get guns. I, you know,
I didn't drink for two and a half months
and then I went to England. I was like,
I've got to try these beers,
beers on it now.
I'm like bummed when I go three
fucking days. And I was like, fuck,
I was up to like 75 and then all of a
sudden he just got real serious. He goes,
do you want to get
sober? I'm like, really?
Like looking into my soul
and my Jesus Christ dude, now
I'm, I'm not like that. No.
The only question is,
is like, look, you know,
I don't care what anyone
does and you know,
and I certainly appreciate the process
of drinking and boozing and doing drugs.
I loved it, but he, you know,
it really just comes down to,
if you get to that point,
the only time you need to get sober really
is if you all of a sudden, you know,
tried to stop and you can't, or you
liked becomes unmanageable. That's it.
You know? And then that's when you
need help. That's it. All right, well,
this is where I'm at. I'm, I'm, uh,
I have stopped and done, you know, but I,
I don't want to stop. It's
not that I can't, I like it.
Like last night I'm sitting
there doing the Gig.
It was a place I always wanted to
perform it. I fucking destroyed.
I even yelled out of blues brothers line.
Yeah.
That John Belushi said on stage in the
Minoan got it. But I did it for me.
I just had a fucking great time,
you know,
and afterwards they
got this big ice chest,
the fucking Heineken's just staring at
me and I didn't drink one because I knew
that, you know, I didn't
want one. I wanted one,
wanted to drink all of them and then
stuffed my face into the ice when I was
done. So I, I, I like it
the way I like cookies.
I won't eat the whole fucking bag.
All right,
so then you know what that's
called was set alcoholism. No,
it is okay to go telling me that
denial. I'm not an El. No, no.
Look, the bottom line is you can do it
however you want. You know, they, he,
it's like he,
a lot of people you have to understand
something about people in the program is
that most of them, you know, who
are especially gung ho about it,
it's saved their fucking life and it does
every fucking day. That's it. You know,
and you know,
that's really interesting.
So now I'll be more forgiving of
somebody who, fanatics of any kind,
but they're not trying to
push Jesus on you. I mean,
part of the program is really,
it's based on helping other alcoholics.
So they actually, when they do that,
it's, it's in a way, you know, you know,
uh,
in terms of the way the program works,
it's helping them see it
teaches pathologically self
centered people who can't
control themselves to behave like,
like regular people by helping other
people in a very specific way. So yeah,
that's it. Yeah. I mean it's
not, usually they don't,
it's not a hard line thing and no one's
ever going to come up to you like an,
you know, I've actually really though, uh,
monitored my drinking is because I'm
so fucking vain. I liked the, uh, the,
the how my face looks a lot better when
you drink, when I don't, oh, cause to,
I don't cause I lose, I loaded that
however you want it and that, you know,
the thing is, is like if it's not
destroying your life, so be it.
And if you want to go up and
down and quit here and there,
and if it's not destroying your life,
that's it. Yeah. Like after I go do
this,
my Easter dinner is going to be,
I'm going to go to somebodies house
and we're watching to watch the red sox
Yankees.
It's great now how to fuck
not too. The thing is, it
really comes down to in, in, in,
in light of what you're talking about,
if you've tried to stop with all your
heart over and over again because you want
to stop drinking and you can right then,
then it's something to be addressed.
If you want to take a break,
but you like to drink,
but it's not ruining your life and you're
just a weird kind of controlling guy
in your mind and you're like, fuck,
I had two months and you know,
but if it's not a plague bucket,
this is, this is what's killing
me. I had a buddy of mine, uh, he,
he quit for a minute and I swear to God,
like, he's one of these guys who quit.
I'm like, dude, what the
fuck are you Quintin for? You
don't have a problem. Okay,
this guy quit for like maybe 17 days
and I think he lost about 30 pounds.
And I was like, checks is Christ, you
will fucking Busan. And he looked great.
He usually, you know what, he looked
like? He looked like an Oscar, but that's,
he was the exact, I can't wait to
hit them with that one if you didn't,
if you knew this guy,
he looked literally like his body,
the silhouette of an Oscar.
And uh,
and then one day called me and said,
hey,
and I started drinking and I
realized I didn't have a problem.
I just was drinking too much and blah,
blah. So now he's back on the drinking.
Okay. I saw him again and dude,
he looked like fucking hell.
He looked like he got run over by a
bus man. Terrible, tricky business.
It's a tricky shit, man. Yeah.
Like he just look, uh, he,
you know what he looked like
when he stopped drinking
for three weeks, you know,
those fucking shows that
they do a make over,
we're going to give you a new hip haircut
or going to give you a shiny shirt and
all of a sudden you come
walk up. Yeah. Yeah. And,
and all of a sudden the women's
start paying it. That's,
that's what he looked like. He
came down to the club and, uh,
eating my girlfriend was
like, Jesus, look at you. Wow.
And this is the thing about him.
He didn't even go to the fucking gym.
He just stopped drinking. Yeah. So, uh,
that is the one aspect of
it as my face look better.
And then one girl told me that my skin
look great. Yeah. So that's, you know,
I'm so [inaudible] so insecure
and so fucking vain. I'm like,
I can't drink my mother. My Skin's
looking great right now. Yeah.
Oh yeah. I, I, I'm with you
on that. I mean, I used to
talk, I talk about it a lot,
you know, in a sense onstage and how it
is. I mean, like I said, it's just, I'm,
I'm happy I lived through it because,
uh, there's a, there's periods there,
you know, and whatever
anyone thinks, you know,
either that's your life and that's the
lifestyle you want to live or you're
going to make a drastic change or you
just deal with the ups and downs of it.
But I, I used to say when I got
sober, used to say, you know,
the great thing about sobriety's how
clearly you can see you're disappointed
thing I was joking about is how fucking
long a year is when you're sober.
It's like, I remember every second of
this other than when I was sleeping.
It's like, it was like February. I was
like, I can't believe it's not may yet.
It's just fucking insane. I like that
though. I, you know, as I get older,
I'd much rather time just drip
by then rush by. It's brutal.
I don't even want to happen in
this last fucking decade, I think.
I think we're getting close to what are
we up to there on your, on your computer?
How many hundred minutes? I don't know.
We have no idea. No, it's three 20.
What time did we start? About two 15.
We might be a little bit over now.
You want to do it? Uh, yeah. Well
let me, let me, let me, yeah,
let me give a chance here.
You listening to mark Marin?
It just for the future when I
do these interviews. So, uh,
it's always uncomfortable given other
comedians complements where we were such
self loving people. But I think
seriously, mark for my, for my money,
you've always been when the one of the
fucking best comics in the country.
So if mark is coming to your
area, definitely go see him. He's,
he does not pander to the audience.
He says what the fuck he's wants to say.
I think you're fucking awesome.
And every comic from here on out,
if they're on my show,
they fit that bill.
I don't know if there'll be
able to follow your stories,
but every once in a while we're
going to do this on the podcast.
I'm going to have a comedian that I really
admire and I admired your work for a
long time.
So how about let me know some of the
gigs are my listeners know where you're
going to be a, he got anything
coming up? Well, yeah,
this week I'm going to be in Tempe,
Arizona at the mad madcap theaters.
He can go to mad cap theaters.com
that's a this weekend.
If you're dropping this today, this is
Monday. And I'll be with Eddie Pepitone,
madcap theaters.
Dot.
Come Friday and Saturday I'll be at the
Bridgetown comedy festival in Portland
because Portland, Oregon. Okay. And
then, uh, in April, the end of April,
I'll be a comics in New York with Garaffo
oil. Well, that's a huge show. Good deal,
man. And I now also hype your
podcast podcast WTF with Marc Maron.
You can get a WTF pod.com or you can
just go to iTunes and look up WTF.
And there's a bill burr episode on there
and a lot of your favorite comics on
there. All of them are on there.
Well, there you go, man. All right.
That's been the Monday morning podcasts.
It very special Monday morning podcasts
from the Mark Marin bunker out here,
and a la hope. You guys all had
a nice eastern. Enjoy your week.
[inaudible].