Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
just checking in on you.
What's going on? How I
yeah. Um, I'm fucking,
ah, I didn't want to get into
it. We're up to episode 10.
I have no life.
I'm trying to fuck and I'm trying to get
in a quick workout before I go to work
because I am,
I'm fucking right back up to where I
was last year when I was like a buck 86.
[inaudible] 87 I am. I, you want
kills me. I've been working out.
Why do you work out?
You're still putting, um,
you know, it is, it's late night. I'm
coming home. I'm eating like a fat chick,
you know, meet like some sad
fellow doesn't like herself.
I just come home and I'm fucking fried.
I get home at like seven o'clock
at night and I go, ah, fuck it.
That's what I say. I get all the way to
my street going, I'm going to get a salad.
I've got to have a protein.
I'm going to fucking eat the
bag of beans or whatever.
And then I just drive into my
driveway and I go, ah, fuck it. Right.
And I order a fucking pizza or a burger,
you know,
or have a beer or something like that.
And MIH. Yes. That's it. That's it.
I go to my looking at getting on my
fucking second trimester right now. Ah,
it's just my wife the other
day and went to a fucking mall,
which is something I never do. Go
into a fucking mall. Right. You know,
people go to a malls, people with
children. I get it. You get him out there.
They fucking watched the trolley go by
and you know Santa Claus is there. Right.
Just fucking sit there waiting for
you to put your kid in his lap.
You fucking Weirdos. Right? Hey,
let's keep the lie going to the point we
put our child in some fucking perverts
fucking lap. So they think he comes
down the Goddamn Chimi me. Yeah.
Is it any wonder? So many people end up
in cars they don't want to be in? Well,
that's a, that's how you start off
their life. You know, some fucking dude,
we don't know. You know, don't really
talk to sort of God like, you know,
sort of culty right?
Charlie Manson hair all fucking,
he's fucking coming in and everything's
cool. You go sit in his fucking lap,
but don't talk to strangers,
right? I don't, I don't fucking,
I'm just so whenever we go to this
fucking thing and we're walking by the
fountain, right? There's a trolley and a
fountain. This is like the fucking gay,
his place you can ever go to. And I don't
mean gay in like the homophobic way.
I mean, the way it used to mean
like the 1890s, the gay nineties,
as in, Oh my God, could a
decade get any happier? Right?
It was everything but fucking
showgirls coming down, you know,
like the end of the family guy song.
That was the only thing that was missing.
And I just was like, what is all
the excitement? We're fucking,
everybody's here buying pants.
Why are we having a fucking parade?
You know? So I went in there and
I just took her to go see the, uh,
the secret lives of pets, which I really
enjoyed because, you know, I'm a dog.
All right. I love fucking dogs.
And you know what, I was curious,
what does my dog do when I leave ever
dentally? They have quite the adventures.
No, it was a fucking really
good movie. I liked it.
And that was a bunch of kids in there
screaming and yelling and that's what I
want it,
you know what I mean?
And I went to the matinee showing and
just have a bunch of kids screaming and
yeah, I wanted the full effect
of watching that fucking movie.
You know what I mean?
It's like when you go to a horror movie,
you got to go see it and there's going
to be a bunch of people yelling at the
screen. Right. And either that,
that's part of the fucking experience.
If you want to go see a movie,
when everybody shuts the fuck up, you
know, you got to do it in your house.
Maybe slap a few people around before
the movie starts, you know, set the tone.
Daddy ain't putting up with this
shit. All right. So anyways,
long story short and I dressed up a little
bit when I went down there. You know,
I've been working a lot,
so I'm going to take out my lady.
So when we're walking out we'll
go and buy the fountain, you know,
and there's like all, you know, like
the plane, like fucking Tony Bennett.
If I ruled the world every day would
be like the first day of spring.
Every douche would have such a wonderful
song to sing. If I ruled the world,
what a wonderful world it would be.
And everybody's just
sitting there mesmerized,
eaten this fucking ice cream
and shit. Yeah, abide pants.
It was fucking weird, man. It
was like, when you go to this,
you go to some of these fucking balls.
It's like you're in a Christmas special.
I'm telling you, I wouldn't be surprised
if they got a fucking mess. Right?
And they're putting some sort of like,
like little little dopamine in the air
and you get like this fucking high.
And all of a sudden you're like,
you know what,
I already have fucking nine
pairs of pants. I one more.
I'm in the double digits, seven days
in the week. I want the overlap.
I'm going to go over the bar line, right?
Like Vinny, call Uta in a pants white.
Um, so anyways, so I go,
all right, I'm, I'm gonna,
I dunno what had came over
and me, we walked by the
fountain. I said, I need you,
let's get a picture. She's like,
she couldn't fucking believe it.
I was going to take a picture next to,
in front of a fountain at a moth.
This is not me behavior. Right? Of course
she's all over it. Women love that time,
right? It just makes you
want to start crying. Let go.
What happened to me. Right?
So all I want to do is take a fucking
selfie. Right, right. You know,
get up fucking heads in it.
My head taken up three quarters of it
cause it's so fucking big. And some do,
she has to come along and be like, oh,
you all little took a picture for you.
And I'm thinking, no, I want you to,
I don't want to prolong this moment.
You fucking asshole. Where's your guy
called? Of course my wife goes, oh my God,
that would be great. Right? So why
does he do? He fucking takes one. Oh,
let's get one more for right.
Takes another one.
Oh my God. And know I look at this
picture in the fucking horror that I see.
Okay.
Fucking stomach pushing out the
bottom of my button down shirt.
And then when you really just
know you're just getting fat,
is that fucking button right?
A right on your breast plate?
It looks like it's doing the iron cross.
Just trying to hold both parts
of the shirt together. And uh,
I looked so fucking bad.
I almost got mad at my wife.
Like you letting me walk
around looking like that.
It's like I get that you love me,
but you know,
how about a little bit of tough love,
you know, how about a little, hey,
fatty cakes, you know, you're really
going to have waffles again this morning.
Exhibit a right. And, you know, bust
out a fucking photo you took of me.
Nothing will make you lose weight like
a bad fucking photo. Huh? Jesus Christ.
You know, it's bad enough when they
catch you in your own backyard, you know?
But I'll tell you,
you take a photo in public,
in front of a fucking fountain at a mall
that as a trolley while Tony Bennett's
playing. I mean, I'm glad I didn't
look at it until I got home.
I would have fucking jumped
in 10 a sailor's dive right
into the bottom of that
fountain.
Now I'm too vain to kill myself.
I'll just hang around and make everybody
else miserable. That's what you do.
That's what you do. Um, oh, by the way,
I w I finally, I watched the, uh, the
record of the, uh, the British Grand Prix,
um, fascinating fucking race
with all the rain there.
Who's going to go in and change the tires?
Who's going to keep going?
And by fucking lap seven, everybody
changed their fucking tires, right?
It kind of seems,
if you get pole position,
you're basically going to win the race.
These guys are so good and the
cars are so equal. You can't,
I've never seen nobody does this stroke
a race thing where your way in the back
and all of a sudden you know you pass
three people and you do the little Zz top
fucking Olay move. You know?
Remember the fucking movie.
He's key goes by three cars that are
all fucking it align draft in each other
and I've watched enough NASCAR with the
skull bone Harry Harrogate car, right?
Darrell Waltrip,
Cale Yarborough.
I watched enough of that shit that know
of two people that draft and they're
going to slingshot around you.
I'll tell you what,
not when Burt Reynolds is there,
I don't know what he did.
Did he take off his two panes,
stick his head out the window and make
himself a little more fucking aerodynamic?
Is that how he went by three cars? I
don't know. Fastest chicken in the south.
That shit does not happen in Formula One.
If you're not one of the top three
fucking drivers of the Illuminati,
you're basically,
as far as I can tell,
the five races I've ever watched
from star stat to finish,
you're not going to win the Goddamn race,
you know,
unless the two guys up front don't like
each other and they smashed into each
other.
Jesus Christ,
Lewis Hamilton and Nico Rosberg
right at the end of the fucking race.
Lewis Hamilton.
When's it right guys from fucking England?
Every bile a man or everybody's
going fucking nuts. And uh,
as I mentioned before,
those two don't like each other though.
He smashed into each other.
So in the end they always show the green
room afterwards, after somebody one.
And um,
it was just like,
they didn't say one word to each other.
Fucking meow fellows.
They didn't say one fight.
I think the fucking Todo Guy,
all I want to do when I wake up in the
morning is feel your ass. When he fought,
he fucking set the two of them down.
He goes, listen, you can't, all right.
I know you went out there
and you watch stroker ace.
I know you'll watch said Kenny Rogers
movie where he adopts the six kids,
but never really legally, and nobody
had a fucking problem with that.
I know you're watched days of
thunder. All right? This ain't that.
This cost real fucking money. Stop
smashing into each other. All right?
And I'll take you back to Germany and
I'll reopen. Why I can't go that far.
Uh,
Oh,
the Germans, you know,
I'm telling you right now,
if you take out about 10 years of day
history, they're great people. Um,
and you pick one wrong guy.
That's what so scary about this fucking
okay.
This election,
I think that they should make Trump
and Hillary both put on a Hitler mask.
Matt and the mask put on
a Hitler fucking mustache.
And whoever looks the closest,
you vote for the other person.
Okay?
You know what? The results may surprise
you. Somebody make a clickbait. Fucking,
I'm a clickbait. Fucking whatever the
hell you call the meme or the, the,
the, the fucking vine. You know,
we put both the presidential
candidates in a Hitler Mass,
a Hitler mustache. Why can't I talk
this morning? And Hitler Mustache,
the results may surprise you and
just, you know, whoever you're for,
you just make the other person, I guess.
And I don't, I don't know how you've,
I don't know how you bring that one
home. You know all you kids today. Oh,
you fucking internet superstars.
You know,
I went into a place the other day to get
some lunch of fucking salad with some
chicken, right? Desperately trying to
fucking bring down the belly, you know,
fucking mobit day. That's what it looked
like right now. You know, shaved head,
fucking ghost, white body. You know,
there's a lot of blubber on me right now.
You know, if I was to swim in the ocean,
my biggest fear would not be sharks.
You know,
it'd be some hipsters out there fucking
whale hunting because they thought,
you know, they would take it back, right?
Get fucking happy wound there.
Um, the fuck was I talking about?
Oh yeah.
So I went in to go get this fucking salad
and I'm standing there and there's a
guy in line wearing a fucking Versace
robe, a gold Versace robe. And slippers.
So I texted my wife going, there's
a dude in here, you know? Yeah.
Do you want me to take a picture?
You've got to see this guy, right?
So I fucking take a picture of
the guy and she's like, oh my God,
my friend knows that person.
He makes these vines, right?
So then I clicked on his youtube and
the guys, not whatever Twitter page,
the guy's fucking hilarious
and I'm just sitting.
They go is this fucking guy?
He doesn't need to be in a writer's room
while he's has his own fucking show.
And he gets to walk around in his bathrobe
and slippers all day making cooking
videos. God bless him. I don't know
what the point of all his, his,
I think the point of all this is I need
to get back on elliptical soon so I
don't have a fucking heart
attack before I go to a,
I'm going to say the Middle East
before I go to the fucking, um,
go over to England. Uh, anyways, so yeah,
I got to fucking knock this shit.
I gotta knock off this
podcast and then I have a
okay,
actually have some people coming over
here because our kitchen's all fucked up.
Do you know what's wrong bill?
What's wrong with the kitchen?
Oh I don't know whether you put on
the hot water or the cold water.
The hot water still comes out, you know,
problem. I fixed fucking nine times.
You got to shut off the fucking hot water.
The handle comes off.
Cupboards are all falling apart,
you know,
everything else in the
house is pretty much nice.
I probably shouldn't even say
that shit. So, um, I got this,
like the final fucking thing I have to do.
You know what I mean?
Cause I fixed up the rest of the house.
I'm hoping it's the final
fucking thing I have to do.
But if for the most part I fixed up the
rest of the house and so now like the
kitchen is bitch to become like
this. I sh I saw, you know,
it'd be like if you bought a brand new
suit and he had these old shitty shoes,
you know, and people look down and
they would just like, you know what,
I was going to get in
business with this guy,
but what the fuck is with those shoes?
You,
what are you fucking Willy Loman there?
You're fucking Willy Loman.
Um, so that nightmare project
is about ready to start.
People coming over today with their ideas.
I have an idea.
Like what if we just took
everything out and put new stuff in,
in the exact same place
except for a couple of things.
And it costs you fucking three
zillion dollars. How about that?
I could be rustic yet
modern yet postmodern,
but kind of art deco ish,
but doesn't compromise the
integrity of the structure.
Okay.
I'm signing up for that shit
again. Um, but you know what,
don't you know, I think it probably
put it into six weeks. In other words,
in about nine months, I think it Oughta
be done breathing in a bunch of dust.
I'll have fucking, um, coal
miner's daughter, lung,
whatever the fuck they call it.
I have no idea. Um, we
don't have any Goddamn, um,
I don't have any questions on this one.
And I also don't have any advertising.
You know, I will do some
advertising here Tuesday night.
I went back to the troubadour and
I saw Wheeler Walker Jr right?
You say it's over.
Pack up your stuff.
Something,
something.
You've had a nurse that fuck you bitch.
You broke my heart.
Fuck you France.
Tearing us apart.
Fuck your dog.
Hope he never comes home. I
saw that guy fucking live, man.
It was I what a fun fucking show is great.
And the band killer,
the Bass player actually plays in
one of my favorite fucking bans,
truth and salvage company.
He's on the road with them,
had a killer band and the dope comes out.
Wheeler Walker Jr he fucking murdered.
Absolutely fucking murdered it.
Um,
I didn't know what to expect
when I went down the, you know,
when somebody goes down there, they're
doing funny songs. You're like, oh,
I don't know what's going to happen here.
Is this going to be like a one joke
song and then you fucking like still
standing there for another 45
minutes. It was, it was great.
And he was fucking hilarious in between
songs, his band or what the crowd,
what I'm saying is if you get a chance
to see wheeler walker jr he's coming to a
fucking club near you
theater near you arena,
fucking a amphitheater.
Hey a car port.
I don't know,
I'm trying to think of every
structure I can think of.
Definitely go out and see him. He's, he's,
he's absolutely worth the money and uh,
in the band.
Sounds great.
And he had a s on another
band open up in front of them.
Two ladies with guitars. They were
great. Just the fucking killer show.
And I ran into a bunch of
comics when I was there,
ran into Doug Benson and all these other
guys. Look at me dropping names here,
drop and fucking names.
And I sat there in the back of the club
and I just drank water all night cause
I'm fucking fat. Right? I'm not gonna
lie to you. I had one whiskey, you know,
you've got to have one. You know,
even John Wayne would have won,
you know, before he ate half a
fucking cow that he barely cooked.
Isn't that what happened to him?
Yeah.
You know, that's what, you know what
happened? All those guys back in the day,
they just kept eating red
meat because back then it was
all about, well, you know,
why would I eat hamburger when
I got steak at home? Right?
Isn't that what they said?
Weren't they literally talking about food?
Considering what most of them died off?
I know that was about the ladies. Um,
but anyways, uh, back then, right,
if you will like a guy's guy, you were
eating steak. If you were fucking,
if you're successful,
it was considered the highest cut,
a fucking meat and all that.
You didn't realize it was tearing
apart your fucking guts and back then,
there's no way you let another man
fucking look in your ass to make sure you
weren't going to die of ass cancer.
Right?
There's no fucking way you could do that.
And then get on a horse and call
yourself a cowboy. That's not what it,
what it was about. All
right. He kept eating steak.
Then you, when you, and you would,
your wife was done making the steak.
You're fucking fucking wrapped it with
the frying pan. I said clean it up. Right?
Then you went over and you put butter
on the steak and then that was it.
And I think it was better for
the environment back then.
You know what I mean?
Women were being beaten,
so they were drinking themselves to death.
So they died earlier and guys fucking
eight themselves to death. And you know,
people got out of the way and there
was only like fucking a couple billion
people on the planet. Now look at
everybody. Everybody's doing yoga.
Nobody's beating their wives, right?
Everybody's having a fucking salad.
And now this seven and a half
billion people on the fucking planet.
Yeah.
You know, and I think it's high time
that we go back to the way it was,
you know, oh, what happened? What
led Hillary becomes president,
and at the end of her 48 year run,
then it goes back to
the fucking dark ages.
We go back to a feudal system,
the real one. You know,
where you're actually aware of what was
happening rather than now where it's
just bankers fucking silently sucking
the life out of the fucking middle. Oh,
Jesus. Pill. You're going to get on a
fucking, you know, fucking kills me.
Bernie Sanders,
arguably the scientists from back to
the future fucking endorses Hillary
Clinton. Guinea. Can
you fucking any of them?
Can any of them just fucking have a
point of view and just stick with it?
They're always like,
this is what I'm above.
You could vote for me because I'm
above this. Right? And then the second,
all of a sudden they start taking on
water or this or the thing that's working.
Speaking of water. Do you know
there's more shark attacks than ever.
Okay.
And they're doing fucking stories about
what should we do about this? It's like,
well, you know, you could not
swim in the ocean. You'd dump con.
There's plenty of fucking, it's
plenty of lakes. You know what I mean?
You know, Shit. Fill up your bathtub,
you know, make a day of that, you know,
but a snorkel on and stare at your
balls. I mean, do whatever you gotta do,
but don't go in the fucking water.
Right?
What do you think there's more shark
attacks now? Well, two reasons. One,
there's more fucking people until
we're eating all the fucking fish.
So the menu is becoming more limited.
You know, back in the day shark,
it'd be like, oh, look at that
fucking surf. Or Eh, you know,
like the fucking board gets between my
teeth. It's not rented. It's tougher meat.
You know,
he's still in polities and that's quote,
and they'll look at that school of tuna.
Okay,
Toro, Toro, right? I'm going to go
over there and fucking have some toner.
All those options aren't there anymore.
And these people still go out there
and their boogie boards, right?
If you got on a boogie board,
you're like a slider, like children,
children on Boogie boards. That's
like a slider now for a fucking shark.
And then you get to the a, you get
to the bigger people. You know,
I'll tell you right now how fat I am.
There's no fucking way
I would go out there.
They'd think I was a fucking c line and
Albino Sea lion that got shunned by the
rest of the herd.
You know?
Is there anything worse than watching a
fucking animal on one of those animals
shows getting shunned by the
rest of the herd. You know,
animals are like super fucking racist.
I don't know what it is to second
somebody is a fucking albino.
They show a little bit of weakness.
I mean,
they're really terrible people and
you never hear Peter Bring that up.
Okay?
I mean, sure. They sit there and they
talk about how bad human beings are. Hey,
you know, guilty as charged.
You're looking at it. I'd be,
I've gone down to fucking
Kentucky Fried Chicken.
I've eaten their beak list chicken,
you know,
all walking around roid it up like
McGuire and fucking Sosa fallen on their
fucking faces because people like
the white meat more. You know,
I've eaten that shit.
Guilty fucking charge.
But what they don't talk about
is how those fucking chickens,
if they were allowed to keep their beaks,
you know,
and not have chest so
big that they fell down,
they would be bullying the
fucking week. His hand, you know,
you don't deserve to have children,
right?
Just go over and they'd Pecker to death
and they never, you know, they go, oh,
you know,
that's just how they are.
Okay.
You know,
it's survival of the fittest and all
that shit and then all of a sudden human
beings start doing it,
right.
Some fucking narc gets thrown into a
locker and all of a sudden it's this
national fucking story.
I think when human beings,
is it going to turn it around and was
the day we just admit that we're just a
bunch of fucking animals. You know? I
have no idea what I'm talking about.
I just,
I have not looked at any news.
I don't know what this fucking Pokemon
thing is about. Everybody's talking about.
I finally asked somebody at work.
I know that there's like,
okay,
I know it was a movie.
I know kids were intuitive.
I guess just people running
around with their phones,
trying to find the Pokemon's to,
to capture them in the
middle of the fucking day. We
were in the writer's Roman.
These kids ran up to this dumpster and it
was like a fucking Wednesday afternoon.
So don't you have to go to work?
Shouldn't you be somewhere right now?
You know what I mean? She'd be out there
blaming your parents for something. Um,
yeah,
I dunno. It's really making that pope
Pokemon things really making me feel old.
Everybody is going around,
a lot of people going around doing it
and then there's people watching people
doing it.
So it's like they're not doing anything
and then you're watching them doing
nothing.
Okay.
It's kind of fucking weird, right? It's
like, I saw this thing the other day,
you know, on roller coasters now that
some of the new rollercoasters say, yeah,
having people get on the roller coaster
and then you put on virtual reality
glasses, right? And it's like,
it's not enough to be on the rollercoaster
and then you've got to be on the,
put the glasses on and you go up the hill
and then as you go over the top and he
had that big drop,
they make it feel as though you're
falling off of a building or something.
It's like, well, you know, you're
kind of doing that in real life.
Why don't you take them off and enjoy
it? I don't, you know what it is.
It's all of us just slowly but
surely working our way to robots.
You know, having a robot, mom
and dad and these, fuck ain't no,
I ran into some nerd the other day
that was into fucking robotics.
Believe it or not.
Yeah.
Did this benefit for a,
that tragedy there in Orlando,
right?
Do you guys remember that tragedy as it
had been 52 more fucking shooting since
then that people don't even remember it.
Right?
So we did a benefit for that and um,
upstanding out in the alley afterwards
having a fucking cigar. Right?
And this kid comes up,
I call him a kid.
That means he was like 26 years old and
he was fucking talking about how he's
into robotics and all this type of shit.
And I was just like,
why are you doing that? What does
our way, he wasn't into robotics,
what the fuck was he into?
Okay.
It was into some shit that would just
basically gather information on the user
without the person really knowing
it. And it's just like, why?
Why are you doing that? You
know? And he's got well, but
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I just kept hammering them with
the questions and hammer them with the
questions. And at the end of the day,
the only way he could defend what he,
what he was doing was he basically said
this, well, you know, if I didn't do it,
someone else would right there.
That's the devil.
That's the devil song right there.
Hi Ho. Hi Ho. If I didn't do it,
someone else would. It doesn't
rhyme. Who gives a fuck?
I hope let's go fucking do something
evil as it might've been the worst song
ever. If you have to justify your
fucking job by basically say, you know,
if I didn't do it,
somebody else would.
What jobs are those spying
on people dealing drugs,
right?
Fucking, I dunno what
shooting porno dropping bombs.
I mean, anytime. The only way to justify
your job is as if I didn't do it.
Somebody else would,
uh, you know, I dunno,
but these fucking assholes making these
robots, man, they're making them too good.
I used to do a bit about it.
You know, that basic, you know,
I don't mind if you make the
fucking thing super smart,
just don't have it be able to
run like fucking Bo Jackson,
which is what they're doing because they
keep trying to improve it and they're
fucking competing with somebody
else. Some other con uh, companies,
fucking robot and they're just making
the thing into the $6 million man.
It's like, guys, guys,
you already stuck every fucking answer
to any question ever. And it between,
it's fucking nonexistent metal fucking
ears. I guess it has metal lyrics.
Nonexisting human years and now you're
going to be able to make it run a fucking
four 40 you know like this, this
thing knows the answers to everything,
right.
You know, and it, and it can make the
fucking Seahawks secondary. That's,
that's what the fuck you're building
and you don't think that that's going to
come back and bite us in the ass.
It knows the answer to everything.
So it basically knows how to do open heart
surgery and also how to load and fire
an AK 47
flying f six stayed.
I mean it's limitless.
Like you remember those fucking
action movies where like the fucking,
this the hero of the movie.
I don't care.
Kind of mode of transportation
of fucking boat, a helicopter,
a motorcycle,
the space shuttle.
This fucking guy knows how to use it.
No pre flight.
You just start the fucking helicopter up.
He yanked the guts out of it.
You know,
I took a ride in a fucking a star the
other day and I, there's no firewall.
I wouldn't be able to figure out how to
fucking start that thing up. I got over,
I got to got 120 hours
flying a Robinson 22.
You stick me in an a star. It's
like, hey kids, little help
these fucking Rambo guys,
these Steven Seagal guys,
these muscle from Brussels
guys, Chuck Norris, right?
Eddie D's in all of them.
They just fucking ran up and could just
do it and used to always laugh going,
that's fucking pull anybody. You know,
if you had a boat, you just be like, wow,
I went off. What? They didn't
know where the fucking keys were.
Just jumps right in.
The fucking keys are right there and he
knows exactly where the fucking throttle
is. He doesn't have to look around and
get his bearings like, hey, this is this.
That's that.
He just fucking jumps in like it's his
boat and it always makes you laugh going,
yet that would never happen in real
life. Well guess what? In 2016,
that's going to happen.
These fucking robots.
I don't know why they
would be running away.
They're not going to be
running away from us.
They're going to be running
after us. And, uh, you know,
if they get sick of fucking running,
which why would they,
they don't have a respiratory system as
long as they charged up like a fucking
Tesla, they're never going to stop.
But it doesn't make a difference.
What mode of transportation,
what weapon is nearby?
That was another thing with those
action heroes, whatever. Fucking they,
they'd pick up a goddamn garden and how,
and all of a sudden this spinning
around like Bruce Lee, it's like Jesus,
where you, when you were in band,
you, when you were a major Rhett too,
you went time to fucking
master all the martial arts.
Learn how to use not only
every mode of transportation,
every fucking aberration of that
fucking mode of transportation.
Is that the right word? You know,
every style of fucking boat.
I don't give a fuck if it's sailing.
If it's a submarine or
a fucking cruise ship,
you know how to get that fucking thing
going and the docket and tie it off all
at the same fucking time.
Right? These robots can do that.
But at least Rambo,
at least Rambo bled.
He had to take time to fucking
so himself back up. He's robots,
don't we think of bleeds, we can kill
it. The fucking robots don't bleed.
You know what I mean?
And you know these fucking nerds,
you know back in the day he poured a
Dixie Cup of water on down their back,
you know, and they didn't do like a
person lift their shoulders up and go,
all right, they don't, they fucking short
circuit out and then they fall down.
So you know what these nerds at doing,
they're like, well we can't have that.
You know the competition's robot.
If you dump a little bit
of water down its back,
it shorts out and they goes fucking a
zillion dollars with the technology,
you know that they're making, they're
going to make these full fucking robots.
They're going to make
them be able to swim.
Okay,
bye. Do everything is going to
be just like that fucking movie.
Well that guy had all those fucking lady
robots and he was fucking him and shit,
right? And then the one kid gets locked
in the breezeway and he's screaming like,
I thought you loved me. And she
just goes away with the expression,
this look on her face. That's what
they're going to do. I guarantee,
I bet you right now as I'm talking,
somebody somewhere is fucking a robot.
Okay.
Then Alex got the lab coat on and shit.
So he makes him feel
like he's doing research
and there's a bunch of other scientist
watching him fucking the robot. Right.
And then afterwards he's going to give
the feedback. Oh No. You know what it is?
It's,
it's a fucking,
it's probably just some regular person
who has like Hep c but can't afford that
1090 $5 a pill to get rid of it as
somebody's HIV positive. So they go,
hey man,
you want dead fucking pill?
You got to come in here and
fuck this robot on film.
Yeah.
Oh, this last thing I'll tell
you and I got to go to work.
Did you fucking see, uh,
have you seen this? Evidently, I
don't know if this is fucking true,
but ever since finally,
the pharmaceutical lobbyists,
any states where weed is
legal, debt going after, uh,
the legalization of weed because any,
any state where weed is legal,
um, the prescriptions go down.
I don't know if this is true,
but somebody told me it was and I
never looked up any information,
so I'm going to say it's true and I
owe big apology to all the fucking weed
smokers out there. Evidently
you were right. Um, so anyways,
but I'm going to keep drinking 'em too
far down this fucking road. All right.
I gotta get Outta here.
I gotta go to fucking work and knock out
this last fucking won for Christ sake.
That's the podcast should cons.
I will talk to you on Thursday.
I'll check in on you. All right, go fuck
yourselves and I'll see you Thursday.
Three
things.
Okay.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill.
This is the Monday morning
podcast for the week of July 10th,
2008. Is it July 10th? I have no idea.
I just got off a plane coming back from,
uh, from Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania. I flew us there.
I sat and see 18 a and um,
there were uh, to people
about, Oh, I dunno.
19 rows behind me talking really
loudly. You know, those people,
they laugh at everything that they
say and they never say anything funny.
Four hours of that shit for fucking hours
of that. People just go and you know,
how many hours are left on the
flight? I don't know. Four and a half.
He just started laughing.
It was fucking killing me was,
it was torture. Oh, flight. I
ended up, you know, I end up doing,
I got a new battery for my,
uh, made of wood laptop,
so I was able to watch good fellas.
So I was able to drown her out
for how long has good fellas? Huh?
So like two hours long or some shit.
So I had that on,
had Goodfellas on Kranked is
high as I could, you know,
we did, but we won it. We were wise guys.
I had that fucking crank is high as I
could to try to drown out this would
dickless group of people. I don't know.
I, you know what I mean? Maybe it's me,
maybe I'm so fucking miserable,
you know?
Am I so miserable that I actually need
something to be funny to laugh at?
You know? I mean I was sitting there in
the end of it trying, you don't want to.
And they finally, you know, I actually,
I didn't know watch the end of end
of Goodfellas. I hate when he's,
when he fucking becomes a Druggie, you
know what I mean? He just pisses me off,
you know? And then, then, then he feels
like all, he feels like he's the victim,
you know,
6,000 bucks for a life of work.
He gives me six grand.
You're lucky he didn't fucking
blow your brains out right there.
He told you not to fuck with the drugs,
the exact fucking thing he told you
not to do. You went out, you did it.
And then he ends up going
to jail and dying in jail.
You piece of Shit I fucking hate at
the beginning of that movie is great
right up through the, was that the Lewenza
fucking robbery. That movie is awesome.
And then the second, his
second, he gets that coke whore.
And that flophouse apartment and then
he's got that retard with the attitude
though the girl, they're the fucking
babysitter and I got to get my hack.
I Dunno. I Dunno. So anyway,
that's what I was doing.
I was fucking listening to that
movie on 10 Janice Lassie is Zoho.
I had that fucking blasting in my ears.
One of my heroes is ringing right now.
I already have tinnitus in one ear from
playing drums years ago and fucking it's
going to be ringing even more because
of these fucking idiots, man. It's just,
I dunno, does anybody, you know, you got
anybody who does that shit. They just,
you know,
come walking up and you'll,
you'll be standing there waiting for
an elevator and they just go, hey,
you're doing and you're like,
good. And then I ha ha good
know
if you go to anybody
fucking Lou does it at work.
Just discretely leave a book on self
confidence in their little cubicle area.
Something, you know what I mean? People
either do that or though they said,
oh they hum songs. I think I already
joked about that about 28 podcasts ago,
but for those of you who are new to
my podcast, I used to work with a guy.
You ever work with someone who uh,
hums a tune that doesn't exist,
you know what I mean?
Used to walk around the office
[inaudible] [inaudible] all fucking
day long. And I used to be like,
what the fuck? That's not a song. Right.
It's not a state that sound like a
song when I hummed it. Yeah, exactly.
But that's a dead on rendition of
his fucking, you know, it just,
it went on forever. Like one of
those progressive prog rock bands,
a Dave Matthews, I saw, I'm in
concert of fucking was this terrible.
Somebody hooked me up with
tickets and it was one of those,
those bands that you get after
fucking a song and a half,
and then there's a black guy
playing a fiddle, which is,
which is weird, you know,
I usually like random shit like that, you
know, like seeing a fat Asian, you know,
he's, don't see that too often. You know,
black guy playing a fiddle, you know,
she'll be like, she'll
be, you know, isn't that,
but you think that he would, he would
do with the black guy way. You know,
we're all of a sudden he teaches white
people that have fiddle can actually be
cool as opposed to some,
you know,
redneck instrument or a,
I guess in classical music it's cool.
But you know what I mean? Let me,
black people made happy birthdays,
make a cool sound, you know, cool song.
Keep thinking. You know, that's what I,
that's when I saw black guy with the
fiddle. That's what I thought. Okay.
He's gonna, he's gonna.
He's don't break it down.
I thought someone was going to happen
and he just was playing that skip to my
Lou spin your partner
round to a ride that,
that style,
I think the black guy who plays the
saxophone and the Dave Matthews band,
I bet he doesn't talk to the
blackout plays the fiddle.
I bet he thinks he's a seller just coming
up. So whenever you show, you know,
motherfucker, it's bad enough you'd
be playing a motherfucking violin.
It'd be doing that shit every night
and for all these mother fucking white
people.
How do you think that makes me feel?
That was a worst impression of a black
saxophone player in a band that I don't
like, that I'll ever do, but
I don't give a fuck a ride.
He's got off a Goddamn plane. Cut me
some slack. I listened to people laugh,
but you know, it's like a nightmare
fucking comedy show. You know what I mean?
We're all of a sudden, it didn't,
it didn't make sense anymore.
Like you just said anything
like, Hey, can I get up?
I need to need to go to
the bathroom. Yeah. Okay.
All right. Anyway, let's get on
with the podcast here. Ah, um,
what do we got here? I'm, what
am I gonna do with this week?
We'll start with the questions.
Not Fuck that. I want to,
I want to hype the shit first.
First of all,
I just got back from the
Improv in Pittsburgh.
Unbelievable turnout and
99.9% of that has to go to,
uh,
the Jim and Randy show on WTV.
Those guys totally hooked me up.
They let me come in on a Wednesday on a
Thursday and on a Friday I did like nine
hours a fucking radio with those guys
letting everybody know that I was going to
be over at the stacks, the
mall over there. And uh,
other than the fact that a couple of
people got shot and one was murdered, um,
I think it was a good week over there
at the mall. Get an happened one week,
one night we were out drinking and uh,
all of a sudden we couldn't leave
the mall cause somebody got shot.
And this is fucking unbelievable.
Stand within a stone's throw of
a stone stone, no pun intended,
a Coldstone creamery. It's not supposed
to happen, isn't it? When you, you know,
when you see a Fuddruckers,
right. I just don't,
I just don't associate that with violence.
But anyways,
I had a great week out there and I want
to thank all the guys over at DV for
hooking me up and everybody
who came out to see me,
I'm also once again to remind you,
I have a one hour special
coming out on comedy central.
August 23rd all right,
say your Tivo six weeks ahead.
For some reason my fucking CD
comes out before the special,
which makes no sense to me,
but I believe that's in stores on August
5th and then the DVD DVD comes out I
think September 14th.
I know it's bizarre if you guys are
going to be sick of me by mid September.
But anyways, uh, please check it out.
I'm really proud of the special
we shot at ourselves. Uh,
it's all your friends to
watch it and a whatever.
Hopefully they become fans of what I do.
And then they show up at my shows and
someday I can afford to take a private jet
or at the very least set up in first class
where I can afford those Bose headset
where I can drown out people if they
fucking are laughing about shit that isn't
funny. Alright, let's get on
with the podcast questions.
If you new to my podcast,
this is what I do every week I babble.
I bitch about people in airports.
I answer questions.
I riff about the Dave Matthews band
and I hide my shit. I'm not, I don't,
I don't riff about the Dave Matthews Fan.
I don't even know any of this
fucking songs. I just know, uh,
I know crash in [inaudible].
Yeah,
they bay. Um, and then I come into you,
he really is like disgusting lyrics
when you really think about it,
but he thinks he thinks in nicely.
I don't like that little James
Brown fucking Jiggy does either.
When he's sitting there
with his acoustic guitar,
I never really noticed how much I
didn't like that. Ben, do you know what?
I'm gonna have to think about this.
I'm going to get back if you have to get
back to you guys on this one. Listen,
I'm stuttering.
I'm so fucking annoyed from that flight.
Maybe I'm really just pissed at
the people on the plane and uh,
I'm taking it out on the Dave Matthews
band. Misdirected anger. All right,
let's get into the questions here.
People.
I got to make this one a quick one because
I've got a bunch of bull shit I got
to do today. Um, and one of them
is the fix my attitude. All right,
question number one. Bill, I
have a question for you podcast.
Why don't you just ask it? Okay. It's
like people go, let me tell you something.
He said, he just fucking saying it.
I said, I think I do that. All right.
I have a question for you. Podcasts,
being a comic from New York City,
which coast do you think is best
for standup comedy? First of all,
I am not a comic from New York City.
I'm a comic from Boston,
Massachusetts who then moved
to New York City. Um, okay.
Uh, I would is, what's the
question? Which coast too,
I think is best for standup comedy?
Uh,
Christ, I don't know. I ain't go,
how's that for fucking a bad
answer. Um, New York City,
if you just want to become a great comic,
there's nothing better than New York City.
It's got like 9 million clubs.
He can do like 10 sets a night. If
you want, not 10, you could do 10.
But I think realistically you do seven or
eight. Once you run with all the clubs,
at least she could back in the day.
I just keep digressing
with everything I'm saying.
So I would say New York was great.
And then there's other,
other cities that are good to start
out in, which is a, Boston was great.
Houston's always have a good
scene. Denver, San Francisco,
Seattle's a bunch of funny guys there.
Minnesota has got a great scene.
Um, yeah. You know what I
mean? I worked in Atlanta.
I don't know if you're funny,
just get your shit together,
but I guess you're asking me, should you
move to New York City or la? Um, you,
I would visit both places before
you went out there because, uh,
I don't know,
New York City just felt like home when
I went there and when I went to La,
you know, the weather was
great and everything was
cool, but it was a, you know,
I stood in line for fucking nine hours
to do way yet to sign up for a three
minute spot at the laugh factory
and a at a fucking sunburn.
I got there at nine in the morning for
a sign up that was at six at night.
This is no bullshit, right. Sat
right there on sunset avenue.
Did it take you guys down memory lane?
So I'm sitting there and uh,
I just remember there was these
two fat chicks. I'm fucking Utah,
something that had really bad tattoos.
I was third in line by nine in the
morning. That's all I remember. And uh,
yeah. And then I wasn't down
there with anybody else,
so I couldn't leave other than
quickly to go take a bathroom break.
Like there was literally a whole
system was a fucking nightmare. Right.
Ended up getting a sunburn right
on my huge forehead and uh,
went home after I signed up,
it's six, went back to the kids,
a problem where I was staying,
showered really quickly,
came back down and had to
do three minutes of standup,
which is practically impossible.
You know what I mean?
That's like trying to finish a bowl of
cereal in like two scoops, you know?
So I went down there and I
don't know how to fuck I did it,
but I went on stage and I absolutely
fucking destroyed for three minutes.
I did a tight three minutes
set that had a beginning,
a middle and an end probably cause I
only had like a half hour material.
I knew I figured out how to do it. So
I'm sitting there going like, Oh man,
I got off stage. I was like,
that's it. I'm in at this club.
I'm going to get a manager. This is,
you know, everything's going to happen.
And then I went upstairs and uh,
I met the infamous Jamie Masada
who calls everybody body.
So I'm sitting there and he had his
table and I sit down at his table.
I'm thinking, this guy is
just going to kiss my ass.
You know, I'm some young buck.
I went up there fucking destroyed.
I was better than, you know,
the two fat chicks from Utah.
This is it. It's over. Right.
So I sit down,
you know,
my ego's through the fucking
roof and he's just like,
I don't mean he sat the
stared at me for a second,
he had his hands together like
not in a fist, but sort of like a,
he's doing the church and the steeple
thing except all these things are up.
And he had his index fingers up
on his mouth and he just goes,
you're very funny. And I was like, oh,
thank you very much. I'm like, okay,
here comes sit, comes here comes, he's
going to have to manage me. Right.
And he's like, uh, you
know, you, you, you talk,
you talk a lot about Bilal, about
your father, you know? Yeah. Go. Yeah,
yeah.
You can say you should do more.
You should do more about do mono bunch
of father. And I'm like, Oh yeah, yeah.
You know, I, I've got a
ton of stuff about my dad.
I got some more stuff about my mom
and as I'm saying that he holds my,
his hand up to silence me.
At which point I literally shut the
fuck up and he just goes, you'll father,
let me ask you a question.
How does it make you feel
when your father yells?
And then he leaned back in his
chair, right? And it was like,
I felt like he was going to give me the
answer to all my standup questions in
the form of a riddle.
And immediately I,
I begin grabbing the legs on the back of
the chair because I was going to smash
it over his fucking head because I was
so fun. I was so pissed. I was like,
you gotta be,
I just fucking kill for three minutes
and now you're going to act like you the
Standup Guru, you Jack Ass.
And that's exactly what he did.
He didn't ask to manage me.
He just gave me a little, how does it
make you feel when your dad yells, Jamie,
I hope you'll listen to this cause
I'm playing your club this week.
How do you think it made me feel?
Made me feel like a semi feel sad.
Is that what you wanted to hear?
Jesus Christ.
This guy came at me like one of those
guys ever see those interviews when the
interview somebody after like a tornado
hit the house and killed their favorite
dog,
you know?
And they're sitting there interviewing
them and they want them to cry and then
not crying.
So then they got to,
they got to sit there and
ask them questions to try
and make them fucking cry.
I think that's what he
was trying to do to me.
So I literally was grabbing the back
of the chair, the legs and the back.
I distinctly remember doing that and
I was like, fuck this guy. Fuck La.
I'm going to New York.
That's how I ended up in New York.
One three minutes set after
nine hours in a second degree,
sunburn on my forehead.
I decided that the east coast
was the place I needed to
be. You know what I mean?
And uh, you know, I worked out well for
me. You know what? You know what's funny?
Somebody who's probably going to fucking
tell Jamie then I actually said that
shit just so they can try to get a
three minute and audition on Tuesday.
So this week when I go down there,
Jamie's going to be like, buddy Bobby,
what do you, what do, what are you doing
buddy? I actually love Jamie now man.
And I'm not kissing his ass
either cause I don't give a fuck.
But he said the funniest shit to me.
Like three weeks ago,
I'm working this club and I'm standing
in the lobby and these two gorgeous
girls, you know, La to fucking gorgeous.
So I'm looking at them, you know,
eyes bugging out of my head and Jamie's
like, buddy, buddy, buddy. Well,
what are you doing man? What, what,
what do I go? Do you mind? I go,
what do you mean what am I doing? Am I go,
I'm looking at the girls. He goes, yeah,
buddy. But what? Why? Why are
you looking at the girls? I go,
cause they're beautiful. I
go, why wouldn't I be looking
at the girls? And he goes,
cause you're a fag.
I think I butchered that. He said it
even better. It was a fucking, he saw,
he totally set me up, son of a
bitch. And if you live in La,
I'm going to be down there Tuesday night,
Thursday night,
Friday night and Saturday night all on
the 10 o'clock show and I'll be having a
good time down there. All right. So
there you go. See that? I Trust Jamie.
Then I tell a funny story where he trashes
me and then I hype is club and then
it's all good. Huh? Who the fuck's in
show business? I am. I know how to do it.
I know how to escape the fucking lines.
All right, so that's what I would do, son.
I would,
I would go to New York and La and
figure out which one you want to be in.
All right. That's it. All
right. Question number three.
Have you ever had any thoughts about
doing a European tour of your show?
Absolutely. I feel that I'm
going to conspiracy theory.
I feel like they're crashing the dollar
and all these corporations that are all
going global,
so I'm going global with them.
I'm not going to be caught flat footed
with a pocket full of currency that isn't
worth the Goddamn peso.
So I'm actually setting up a European
tour for the beginning part of next year,
or at some point in 2009, I should say.
Uh, I want to get over to England, Sweden.
Uh, I did some shit one
time in the Netherlands.
It's really disappointed when I went
to know Netherlands when I got off the
plane and the first thing I saw
was like a fucking Dunkin donuts.
You know what I mean? And like a
Mcdonald's, it just, it just really is.
I understand why people
find America so annoying.
It's because the urban sprawl
of our fucking corporations,
you know what I mean?
I literally think that that I
could go to like fucking Nah,
let me pick up to take a fucking nice
obscure country that I don't even know
where it is on a map.
Let me think of something
Bosnia now I know why that's
fucking eastern Europe, Olivia.
And it was one of those,
that law that's in South America,
whatever you gotta fucking Bolivia,
you think he can go down there and see
that fucking that guy from the tee shirt
that everybody wears,
cig go viral, Gutierrez,
whatever his name is, balance
way, that fucking guy.
And he'd go down and he'd get off with
the first thing you see Colonel Sanders
on a big bucket of fucking chicken.
I think that's what Hugo Chavez
is big fuck. I love that guy, man.
That guy is the shit. You
know what I mean? Those guys,
they remind me like Tony Montana,
that's what Hugo Chavez is.
Too Much Java has taken on the u s
knowing full well that we could fucking
Newcomb anytime we wanted to
talk and shit about us at the UN.
He's like in his early Tony Montana
use, you know? Um, so for us,
Jesus, his is and annoying. He's
in his early Tony Montana years,
like right before he, uh, he gets the, uh,
the Cadillac with the leopard skin.
You know what I mean?
When he's still washing dishes with that,
that fucking Robin Williams,
Hawaiian sharp. That's what Hugo
Chavez right now. All right,
question number four. This is very,
a little jet lag here, people. Sorry.
I mean fucking blow through these and
I'll stop wasting your time. All right,
question number four. A Oh God.
This one has a backstory. Yes.
I attempted to renew my Norton Antivirus,
all that God wanted me to sing
a song about Microsoft. I can't,
I can't remix this song it unless they
have a song. You know what I mean? You,
you gotta,
you gotta you gotta pick one.
You got to pick a product that annoys you,
that actually has a song and I will do a
fucking puff daddy remix of it that has
the word continent and it'll make you
feel better. All right. All right.
Question number five. Hey
Bill, here's a question.
Have you ever had people bring
their kids to your shows?
And I'm not talking 18 years old. I
mean like five years old. Absolutely.
I've had people bring babies and I've
been in the middle of talking about
something really a, I don't know, evil,
talking about going to a
titty bar and now I hate that,
you know regular girls go
to titty bars now, you know,
cause they killed the perverted
vibe of the club. I was doing that.
This talking about how strip clubs are
for horizontally and then I can't feel
comfortable leering at a stripper when
I'm sitting next to Melissa and don't
doing that joke and all of a
sudden he just hit his baby.
Baby starts crying in the back
and then it's it, you know,
something that's even more awkward
when they bring a kid that can speak.
You know,
why don't I just say a five,
five years old or over other than having
you guys picture mutes or something.
Yeah. I've actually, I've
had people bring kids.
I'm trying to think and
hasn't happened in a while.
There was actually girl this week in
Pittsburgh. She laughed like a little kid.
So it was weird.
She sounded like a little kid,
so it was freaking all the comics out.
And then it turned out
she wasn't a little kid.
She was just an adult with
a really annoying voice.
And then she came up to me afterwards and
she had these huge teddies and she was
saying, come on down to plush, which
is some strip club in Pittsburgh.
And she had that classic,
uh, Anna Nichole Smith.
I'm going to overdose in
a hard rock cafe voice.
So if she's listening,
I hope you're still alive.
And he didn't know di did
I ever tell you that story?
I played the same hardrock cafe that
fucking Anna Nicole Smith died in.
And I gotta tell you something that's
been there for three fucking days.
I get it. I think she killed herself. I
don't think it was an overdose. I think,
you know, an accidental, I think
she did it on purpose because, uh,
that place sucks. All right,
question number seven, Bell.
I recently went to an open Mike and my
local comedy club for the first time just
to watch the club,
just to watch Jesus Christ.
Nobody puts capital letters
anymore or punctuation.
I just went right to the next sentence.
Bill.
I recently went to open mic night and
my local comedy club for the first time
just to watch the club only has
open Mike night once a month,
which is gay,
but I can't do anything about it anyway.
I figure most of the, most of the
commerce that got up would suck and bomb.
Maybe a few would do okay.
But there were about 14 and 13 of
them ended up doing really well.
This was discouraging to me because I
figured most open micros would suck,
which would make me feel better
about myself and my call me comedy.
Is this how open Mike was for you? Please
share your wisdom with me. Alright.
I'll share my stories. Wisdoms
going a little too far.
Yeah, that's what it's like.
You go down there and there's people who
are still doing open mikes but they're,
they're better than being an open
Mike Micros at that point. Um,
but they still need to stage time and uh,
you know,
sometimes you know features and sometimes
even a headline I might drop it and
that's Kinda how it is. And uh, yeah,
your first few open mics, so lonely,
but uh,
he just got to see the humor and it just
go up there the first time you do it.
It's not even about doing well
whether Ed don't judge it,
whether you did good or bad
the first time you go on stage,
it's just all about having the balls to
go up there when they call your name,
you know, and if you have the balls
to go up there, then you know,
you got more balls than 95%
of people in that situation.
So just take that as a victory tape.
You said keep it,
lock it away in a safe and then someday
when you're good at it you can take it
out and just laugh your ass
off at the shift that you,
that the shit that you attempt it. I
wish I take my first one. I didn't,
I mean just to give you, make you feel
better. I was supposed to do five minutes.
I think I did about three. I walked up
there and the second I saw the microphone,
I forgot everything I was going to say.
And I started in the middle of the shit
that I wanted to say and then brought it
back around to the front kinda. I've
followed the same pattern of pulp fiction,
you know what I mean?
Well they start with that,
oh you mother fuckers get on the ground,
all that bullshit.
And then he goes to the beginning and
then fucking you end up seeing that scene.
I like Goodfellas, same
fucking thing. That's how I,
that's how my first stand up set went
except unlike those awesome movies.
Mine was terrible.
So just picture if they
w was that the happening?
If m m night Shambhala Dingdong
made that fucking movie,
the way they made pulp fiction that,
you know, that's the way my friend,
I'm trying to tell you, my first
set sucks, so don't worry about it.
Don't worry about,
just go up there and I get it.
You've got to find the humor and bombing.
There's nothing funnier than bombing.
It's fucking hilarious.
It's just something undeniably funny
about standing in front of a room full of
people and just putting it out there.
Especially if you're high energy and
you and your joke fucking bad at bat and
everybody's just fucking staring at you.
There's just no other way to describe
what a fucking tool you feel like.
But everybody's been there, you
know, bring some water up there.
You're going to get dry mouth. All right.
And just, just do it, man. It's, you know,
you'll be fine. You'll be fine.
Fuck it. All right, last question.
All right. Yes. It's actually a story, um,
which I actually find really interesting.
Kay. Hey Bill. And on, what
the fuck happened? My email
last week, a blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah. All right,
here we go. Oh, okay. Well,
auto damage related.
This is a real fucking long one.
Let me try to get to the
meat of this thing. Um, okay.
This is an auto damage related story.
All right.
I must preface this story with the fact
that I find it very difficult to contain
my temper already.
I liked the story with even I really
difficult to contain my temper with even
the most meaningless shit,
such as stubbing my toe are getting
cut off while driving anyways,
uh,
when something of actual meaning happens
to me having something of mine stolen,
let's say I really lose my shit.
All right.
A few months ago I had an expensive set
of knives missing from my kitchen and I
flew into a rage through
deductive reasoning.
I concluded it must've been
stolen by one of two people.
Now listen to the description so you
can guess where this story's going. Uh,
he was either a,
the sketchy Jewish kid who lived upstairs
or be the Mexican repairment who still
had a key and a key since I just moved in.
While the reasoning part of my
tamper tantrum was taking place,
a few racial slurs may have slipped
out and as one made to Deuce,
a temper tantrum is often accompanied
by loud screaming, oh, that's great.
They're okay. The screaming is
most often followed by regret,
usually concluding with embarrassment.
Anyhow,
the following day I went out to my car,
which was parked out front to
gather some belongings in the trunk.
When I got to my car,
I noticed that some thoughtful neighbor
who obviously heard my screaming the day
before notched a large swastika
and the center rear of my car.
After a few moments of
careful contemplation,
I laughed and decided to keep
it there for shameful posterity.
The swastika remains is a painful reminder
for me to get a handle on my anger.
The steak knives were never
found. All right. You know what,
I find that fucking really
to be an interesting story
because the guy actually,
he seems like, you know, he's trying
to improve himself as a person.
You know, he knows he has a temper
and a, he knows what he did was wrong.
And, uh, I would, this is a
question I have for you guys.
If somebody flies and cause you
know, they always say that, you know,
I dunno like your,
your real thoughts come out in anger.
I don't know if I like
100 100% believe that.
I think when you get
angry sometimes it isn't.
Like you have this deep seated hate.
Sometimes it just,
it just trying to hurt the other person.
You know?
Like if you get mad at some
you fucking cock sucker.
I mean do you really think that
they're out there sucking dick?
You know what I mean?
But then he got the other side
is all of a sudden when somebody goes
into the, into actually, you know,
racial slurs that's like above
and beyond. I know, I dunno.
I Dunno about that one. Do the eye.
That's what I'm asking is that,
you know like if somebody, if somebody
gets mad at me, a fucking Dick,
like I don't think that they
really think I'm a dick.
I think that they're mad at me and
they called me a dick. Now there's,
does anybody think that it's possible?
Because this guy seems like good dude.
He left the swastika on it. He realized,
all right, I'm a fucking ass and I gotta,
you know, keep my temper in
check. Does anybody think,
is it possible?
That's what I want to know to lose your
shit and you start yelling racial slurs
and you still stick it in the same
category of like, I was just mad it see,
just calling. Just call him, you know?
I Dunno. I don't fucking know. You know
what? Be Thankful you're not famous.
You know what I mean? You would ended up
like a Kramer. You went out to go on a,
actually, you wouldn't have
gone on Al Sharpton show.
You wouldn't had to go on Jesus Christ
who is a Jewish guy with a bad perm or a
Mexican guy with a bad perm.
You know how shocked and would do a lot
more for his credibility if you would
really get rid of that pimp haircut.
You know what I mean?
I always felt he looked
like boss hog. Like if, if,
if they ever did like the black boss
Hog, you know what I mean? All that,
that's like the hacky thing to do in
Hollywood. Like once you rotted ideas,
you just take, you know, a sitcom.
Like it's Alice but it's
black and then a legit,
I didn't know what the fuck I'm
talking about this point. Anyways,
I got shit to do here. Okay.
This is a long ass podcast
as always. Uh, once again,
thanks. Everybody came out to
my show in Pittsburgh. Man.
It's fucking unbelievable.
I couldn't,
last time was there was only like 18
people, so I really appreciate it. And um,
I got the comedy works
coming up in Denver.
Chuck died July 31st through August 2nd,
I believe.
I don't have my calendar
in front of me right now.
And also I'm going to be at the Improv
in Miami and in the middle of August.
And uh, that's, it will be
adding some more dates today. Um,
I think I got a month straight at dates.
One is in stress factory in New Jersey.
I think I'm doing umass Amhurst
with Charlie Murphy and a,
I think that's about it.
But anyways, everybody,
thanks for listening to these podcasts.
I also got a new video I'm going
to be putting up on youtube. Um,
I add a new video last week.
If you missed last week's podcast is
right underneath the podcast thing.
It's entitled thank you.
Cause this is what that lady was yelling
at me after every fucking punchline.
And, uh, I'll be adding another one.
Just come stop putting random
shit up from shows that I do. Uh,
people seem to enjoy it and
it's a way to make you laugh,
show you some new standup without
burning any bits. So, uh, so that's it.
Once again, thanks to everybody, uh,
listened to these podcasts and please
remember to watch my special on August
23rd uncommon comedy central. All right,
that's it. You guys have a good week.