Hey, what's going on is bill burn is time
for the Monday morning. Now it isn't.
God dammit. It's the Thursday
afternoon, just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast and
Ah,
just checking in on you and the volumes
too loud and the volumes to lab.
What's going on? Hey, hey. Hey,
test has two, two, check check two,
two Oh Jesus Christ.
Happy Thanksgiving to you.
Woo.
Happy thanksgiving.
United States of a man.
Ah,
happy Thanksgiving to you.
What's going on?
Happy Thanksgiving to the United
States of America's citizens.
Each and every one of you.
I am thankful to be in America,
sitting here with McGovern,
eating the fucking doughnut,
getting fat and Ham.
Fun The my wife miles off to me.
Go and slap her in the face.
Get Marcel some pie and then
make fun of another race.
Hey, all right, what's going on?
This is it while you were around the world
and you want to know what the fuck at
Thanksgiving is all about.
This is what it's about.
It's about sitting down and overreading
celebrating the fact that on this day,
thanksgiving, 17, 76,
the United States of America kicked
the shit out of the fucking bread.
It's British people at the
battle of thanksgiving.
You know, this black dude
Crispus addicts, attic,
Eric's Attica,
whatever his fucking name was,
he came walking out and he said,
he said, Yo, motherfuckers,
what's, what's your
pattern when pitch. Right?
And then the English will like,
you can't talk to me like dad,
especially with dead skin complexion.
Then they tried to shoot nobody fucking
Stab King Henry the, uh, the eighth.
Yeah, right in the throat with the, uh,
with the Turkey bone, broke his larynx.
The guy survived. We took it
out on his wife, you know,
beat her to death with a chastity belt.
This is all true and you can look it up,
but at the end of the day,
the end of the day,
that small act was what
created this country. And,
um,
I'm thankful for Crispus
addicts where his name was,
go back to my history classes.
You know,
was that the only black guy they
talked about? I think it was,
they sort of touched on slavery.
Um,
all these white guys
did this amazing stuff.
Slavery and then they
built the White House.
Um, anyways, I don't know what the fuck
I'm talking about and who cares that
Oh, here we go. We're back. Went
Back. Yeah. I don't give a shit.
This is one of these podcasts. I don't
care. I don't care from entertaining you.
I don't care if I'm confusing you.
I don't care if I'm ruining your fucking
meal because I am in a resentful moved.
A lot of people are thankful today.
I am not thankful and I'll tell you why.
Cause I'm working right now.
I'm doing a podcast so you can hear my
daughter screaming in the background.
She's already half in the bag.
Everybody's boozing and having a
great time and old Billy. No Fun.
No Fun is continuing with his streak.
Why is he continued with his streak?
Is it cause he's vain?
I don't know why I'm continuing.
I just don't want to be a fat
booze bag again. Can I do,
I'm just going to ride out the rest
of the year. I'll see what I'll see,
what the vibe is for 2018.
You know that first day when I roll
out of bed I'll see how I feel.
Granted I'll be at the rose bowl
so I'll be very excited. Um,
which this year is going to be a,
I was one of those semifinal plas.
I think the Miami hurricanes
are going to be there. Um,
somebody was saying that I have no idea.
All I know is I'm going,
I'm going right that,
that that's what I did.
I bought some tickets for myself and my
friends for the rose bowl cause I was
giving thanks to living in this wonderful
country that has the stadiums you can
go to,
right.
It used to be able to get drunk and have
a good time. Can't do that anymore. Ah,
you can't do that anymore.
Somebody was jerking off vigorously with
the fucking shrimp cocktail and now ne
everybody shut it down.
It's going to be no fun anymore.
No Fun in the comedy clubs,
Dude.
Fucking the vibe and comedy clubs
to pending on what you talk about.
If you talk about absolutely nothing,
I'm sure nothing has changed,
but if you even remotely
touch on fucking anything,
there's so many subjects now and these
fucking millennials, they swear to God,
they just, they just sit there.
It's like doing a cruise ship Gig.
Can you imagine? Sorry,
didn't mean to scream,
but can you imagine the fucking midlife
crisis that millennials are going to
have?
They're not having any fun.
This sitting around staring
at the goddamn screens,
they're afraid to say anything.
Everything's been judged and labeled.
It's like this, this fucking bizarre
like way back in the day, oh hey,
back in the day they, they used
to say that the government, right,
they're going to come down
on you, man, you're going to
take away free speech, man,
blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Wasn't social media.
Social media has made
everything so fucking important.
Your quote,
everybody's on eggshells.
It's really different the amount of
times I have to sit there as almost a 50
year old man and tell young
people to snap out of it.
And then they always applaud like,
Yay, we want to snap on him. And what
I'm calling this right now,
I don't know what's going to come out of
this at the very least is going to be a
great wrestling character.
You know, if I were,
if I actually could take the beating,
the punishment of professional wrestling,
you know, and I was a younger fellow, my
character's name would be the millennial,
right. And I would be
fucking sanctimonious my,
the word I learned this year,
self-righteous, which is basically the
same thing, set in a different way,
isn't it?
And I would act like how much I cared,
and then I would go into the ring and
be a selfish fucking prick who just
cheated and fucked over everybody all the
way to my victory. Something like that.
That's,
that's the loose,
or maybe maybe it's not too late
for me to be a wrestling manager.
I'm too old to be a millennial.
I'll be proud of my millennial children.
I don't fucking know. This
is why I don't rest. Well,
I don't write for the fucking WWF or
whatever they're called now, the WWE.
Um,
Jesus Christ.
Jesus Christ. So how was your guys'
Wednesday, just before thanksgiving.
How was it?
Did you go to the local bar
and did you see that lady?
Did you see that fella?
Maybe you wanted to bang one of your
teachers? Did you hook up? Did it happen?
I is a creepy teacher. That's what
I would do. You know what I mean?
To keep my job.
I wouldn't try to bang one of my students,
but I would hit every fucking Wednesday
before Thanksgiving at the local
watering hole, you know,
by then when the fucking,
whoever the hell I wanted to
bang was of age and I'd show up,
you know what I mean?
Just fucking chalk dust on my pants.
Do a little dance. Mega Little
Love Bug your teacher. Um,
hey ladies, have you ever gone
the Wednesday before thanksgiving?
Did you just check in on one of your
teachers if you ever done that? You know,
not an old crusty guy, but
they had new guy. All right.
The guy who was like in his
thirties seemed like he had
it all together at least
to you.
And you were sitting in your class
before you realize these probably make it
only 18 grand a year with no benefits.
Of course he has the whole summer off,
which would be great for the
kids and the above ground pool,
underrated above ground pool under
fucking rated the above ground pool.
I mean,
how much into the water do you need to be?
As long as it goes up to your neck, you're
fine right there in the winter time.
You let it freeze over
and you can skate on it.
Actually bill for above ground pool,
little of water. Shut the fuck up up.
Nobody cares about your sites.
So listen to this.
I told you last week I fucked up my ribs
or I fucking the cartilage around them.
I don't know what happened. So, uh,
I went to him with Seuss, you know,
which is what you wanna do.
You want to go to ah, fuck.
You want to go to an a Seuss just
sitting up purse. If you want to go to,
you want to go to a fucking misuse
that knows what the fuck they're doing.
Cause basically all my muscles were spasms
and this guy fucking fixed all of it.
And I walked out of there
and they felt great.
And then like the German Irish asshole I
was, I'm like, well you know about 60%.
I guess I can go play drums at
a 100% now and see what happens.
And I came out of there and I felt
like I got hit by a fucking car. Um,
in a way it is because they'll bill,
he's working on his double bass pedal.
He's got the double pedal now.
Huh.
And you know what the deal is if you're
a white guy and you're fun and you're
white drummer if you're a warmer,
right.
What are the first couple of
songs you're going to learn? Huh?
Motley Crue live wire
before you move up to
Pantera cowboys from hell.
That's what it is.
And I'm actually finding that fucking
triplet like is easier than actually just
playing 16th, 16th pass,
like fucking 95 100 bpms.
I just sound like a Horse
Gallop and down the street,
but I didn't realize was how
much I was engaging my obliques.
And the right side is all fucked
up. So whatever. I have a, uh,
I have another appointment
next fucking week. But dude,
I got to tell you something right now.
You guys out there,
all you old fucks like me.
If you have aches and pains in your
body before you go to a doctor,
I'm telling you go see him as Seuss.
All right?
That actually I a top shelf messsage
that knows what that understands the body
and how it fucking works.
Cause I'm telling you right
now, if you go to a doctor,
you, you know what they gonna do. What
is it? Heart. This is my specialty.
I'm a knee doctor,
so I'm just looking at your fucking
knee and then they're going to give you
prescriptions. They're going to give
you some pain medications, you know,
next thing you know, you're, you're
fucking on heroin. You don't need, Oh,
you could just go to [inaudible] and
not play drums at the end of the day.
And I think you'll be fine. As always.
I have no idea what I'm talking about,
but it does warm my heart
on things I do give.
Thanks right now thinking that I'm,
I'm possibly ignoring,
not ignoring annoying
somebody in the medical field.
Okay.
That's not true on the new doctor.
I take in consideration the
hip joint to fucking pharynx,
your larynx, pharynx, the
hypothalamus, pharynx.
I think I just invented
a body part that she, ah,
it's your thyroid and your
larynx where they connect.
It's like the taint
between the two of them.
Larynx is somewhere in your
voice box and your thyroid.
I don't where there that
isn't that in your neck
of a swollen thyroid. Yeah. And you also
got something on the side of your mouth.
So if you don't pick up the conversation,
I'm walking away cause I don't give a
shit about you fucking can I say that?
Can I say that on the podcast?
Will I offend thyroid Americans?
Um, anyways, so I, uh,
I fucking made of sweet potato pie first
time this year. And what I learned was,
uh, there's no sweet potato and a sweet
potato pie. It's actually fucking yams.
I didn't know that I'm
white. I don't know. So I,
it was the least of fucking sweet potatoes
I got when I fucking boiled them and
got the skin off them, they will, they
will Hawaii. So I was thinking, all right,
maybe the cinnamon and nutmeg and
that shit turns it Brown. It did not.
I basically made a sweet,
uh, I made a potato pie.
The had a little bit of sweetness to it,
so I had to fucking get rid of that
thing. Went back, got some yams. You know,
you got to understand people that I'm
essentially going to be one of the few
white people at my Thanksgiving dinner.
And rather than making a Hawaiian Pie,
I'm making a pie that is the staple of
the black communities as far as I've been
told. So there's all this
fucking pressure. Um,
I'm thinking I'm going to take a
pounding today as far as like, you know,
I should have put these,
should have put some vanilla in there.
You should have done this. You should've
done that. We'll see what happens.
We'll see how I survive.
You know what I mean?
Which is probably a good thing that I'm
not drinking today. You know what I mean?
Cause then, you know, I would
have all that alcohol in me,
everybody be criticizing my Pi and
then I'd start crying like a sad drunk.
Speaking of sad,
I realized I just fucking set back,
which is not what you want to do because
now I've got to make that noise again
when I fucking sit up.
Um, anyways, congrats.
You know what I'm thankful for something
else and I'm thankful for is the Celtic
16 game winning streak.
What an absolute gift
to start off the season.
I'm thankful for Danny Ainge
or as I like to call them,
Bill Belicheck junior.
Look what this man is doing with draft
picks. Look what this guy has done.
Anybody can be like the Lakers
and just sit around and go,
who's the best players in the league?
I will have them. Thank you very much.
Oh did you already developed them?
But to actually sit there and hold on
to your draft picks for years and then
exquisitely use them to trade,
to move up in the draft to pick
the guys to assemble the pieces.
Who's kidding?
Who were in the east?
So everybody in the east is
doing the exact same thing.
We're waiting for Lebron to get old.
You know?
It's like everybody in
the AFC east and football.
It's just how long is this motherfucker
Tom Brady going to be great for?
You know,
you know what the turning point his
career was was getting with Jazelle.
All right, so what she
has him on, she eat,
he's like on that fucking wheat grass
yoga diet. He's all flexible and stuff.
You know what I mean?
He's eating like a stab and model.
Right.
You show when he came into the league,
came right in out of the fucking
dorms eating fucking Jalapeno poppers.
Did they even have those back
then? That's how old he is, like,
like a new appetizer has come around
since he started in the league.
That's when you know your old,
you know what I mean?
When all you want is those little mini
fucking hot dogs with the mustard on them
and somebody go, we have Jalapeno
poppers. What? What? What are those?
I am not familiar with those.
Do you want some?
A one set fucking weird one that's
smores. Let's say one. Every.
All those other weird families.
You know what the weird families are
that basically people that cook the shit
that you don't eat,
you know that's smores.
Not Charlie Brown's, what do they
call him? I said some chocolate thing.
It just sounds like a sweet
name for taking a dump.
I can't remember what the fuck it is. They
have no, he's he, you want one of these?
It's like, no I don't, I don't.
I'm hoping the lovely Nia will come
in here and join me at some point on
Thanksgiving,
so I give thanks for having a lovely wife.
I was hoping that that was going
to happen at some point, you know?
You know what?
My wife is like,
she's like Louie Depalma on fucking taxi
as far as the way she always gives me a
fucking other jobs.
Sick.
She's like dispatch every time I'm out
driving around you got to shut your phone
off. Cause if you don't, you're just
going to get all these assignments. Hey,
are you like 40 miles
away from the dry cleaner?
Could you go over there
and pick up some stuff?
Yes.
How many are trashing you?
Happy Thanksgiving to you bought a Booboo,
booboo. Hurry guys, like today. You like
the lines. Do you like the cowboys? Oh,
here we go. Oh look
who's here. There she is.
Mrs Mrs burb up Baba Baba Baba booboo.
Boo.
A triumphant return making a triumphant
maternal. Aw Man, I was just trashing you.
Can you, uh, can you pull up the, uh, the,
your chair there I was comparing
you to Louie Depalma on taxi member.
How he's in dispatch and it was always
telling the guys where to go and pick up
stuff.
You're 10 years older than me and I don't
does this references a lot of times I
don't get, well, it's classic.
Have you ever seen the Maltese Falcon
in college, but I don't remember it. Oh,
you don't? Oh, that's right. What's
your plan? What is my point of?
I like how aggressive you're going into
this. This is very offensive. I like it.
But you just said to me, you
trashing me, so why wouldn't I be I,
I wasn't saying that it was wrong.
What was your point?
Is it me or is there a lot of tension
for a holiday? Yes. Yes, there is.
I was just saying that I'm going
to start when I go out and about,
when I drive around Hollywood,
checking out the scene,
I'm going to start shutting off my phone.
Okay.
Because you're always giving me jobs.
Do you notice when you go out, I don't
call you up and be like, Hey Nia,
can you go by the two page
shop and pick up my, my rug?
[inaudible] [inaudible] [inaudible]
yeah. I mean it's a real, it's a
real hard time for you. I understand.
It's difficult for you.
I get that kind of thing.
You're just going to go with arrogance.
So beyond your capabilities.
So that's cool. I'll manage
my expectations. Thank you.
Thank you. Can you do that?
Can you stop giving me assignments? It's
really hot in here. Does it just me?
Is it really? It's really hot in
here. So take off your bathrobe.
Um, come on, stop it.
Be Fun on the podcast.
Just cause I went in there and I trashed
you right out of the gate rather than
being thankful. Oh my God. Oh my God.
Hey did you, um, where were you giving me
shit for coming in? So late last night.
Cause I was wondering where that Effie,
where I was upstairs. First of all. Okay.
I came home and I went to turn on the
fucking TV to watch the Bruins first.
The New Jersey devils and the fast forward
button worked and then I couldn't get
it to stop. But you always
worse. It was on one. Oh No,
it was actually trying
to watch it like Ah,
and I realized it needed new batteries.
First world problems. Right. All right.
So tell me what happened with your
Thanksgiving dinner. Oh Wow. You know,
I don't like to trash
people in the podcast,
but I will say that this
particular company that I
ordered from you promised you
a peach cobbler and you got there
and it wasn't there, you know?
And so I made it known via a very short,
simple email that I was disappointed
in that fact. And you know,
I was waiting two and a half
hours to pick it up and you know,
nobody could have nobody came
out and said, hey, listen,
doesn't look like the peach
cobbler is happening. I'm so sorry.
Because then I would've been like,
okay,
well let me maybe run out and try
to grab something. But you know,
I waited for two and a half hours in
the parking lot and got my food and came
home.
I was exhausted.
And you're going to write those people
back because they responded to your email
with like a four page Gettysburg address.
I'm telling you,
she write him back and be like,
if you spend as much time making my
peach cobbler rather than giving me four
pages of excuses where you're the victim,
here's a good one for your
business in the future.
Don't promise what you can't deliver.
That's much
what I yeah, yeah. They said you ordered
really late and don't take the order.
Yeah, they sent us that now. All right.
Um, hey, but they were doing me a favor.
Is is basically the tone that I got back
was that they were doing me a favor and
you know,
um,
it was difficult to get my
payments information but
it's like I missed a couple
of phone calls cause I was with the baby.
So now you have excuses and then when
they would call a pod here on a third
time, I gave them the information
and for the full amount,
not the half deposit that
they initially requested,
I was like go ahead and do the
full amount. But you know, um,
three guys think that when
will there be a second date?
Do you guys think you're ever going to,
this is the second date per call.
So this is this, there will
not be a third date. You know,
life goes on and uh,
yeah,
that's why you cook your own fucking meal.
I'm telling you,
I see that some have to deal
with other people. Bullshit.
You know, it's, it's, it's fine though.
It's like I expected this response back
because I have dealt with this person
before. So, you know,
this isn't surprising that it would be
like a whole list of reasons of excuses,
I should say. Not even
reasons. It's excuse.
I loved how she kept complimenting
you and telling you to have a happy
thanksgiving. Oh, all in catalytic.
Just the air getting on an airplane
and we're jetting away to enjoy our,
the anger as opposed to being like,
I know you're disappointed.
Sorry about that. Sorry, we promised
something that we couldn't deliver,
but here's four pages of excuses.
Yeah. Here's a bunch of excuses why.
And then to like, you know,
bring my mother into it as
well, which is very classy.
Very, very classy on, on this
person's part. But you know,
I feel like Andy Cohen Roginos like I
wish the other person who didn't make the
sweet potato pie was here.
Sweet Potato Pie guy.
I don't, oh, come on. So Nia,
um, I have to do what? Have you started
your Christmas shopping yet? No, I have,
I am fucking crushing it.
Nieces, nephews done. Okay.
You done what's I'm done with you.
I'm breaking up with, you know,
Christmas gift for you. No, I'm actually,
I'm going to wrap some shit and
then I'm going to wrap my presence.
Sorry.
Can't read a little bit.
Did you see the Christmas wrapping
paper that I got for you? For the kids?
I thought it was cute. Like peanuts
and then like Rudolph or Mickey,
your gifts are always going
to be wrapped in that.
We have other wrapping paper. All
right, let me read this thing here.
This frigging side feel so much
better today after not moving.
I think the key, the key to letting
your rib cage heal is to not move.
So I want to let you know today.
I'm not avoiding you and your relatives.
It's just not, I'm nursing my side. Okay.
Are you going to be able to handle a
sober me on the holidays? I mean having,
I've been handling it for the last
however long. You haven't
been drinking? No,
but on the holidays usually
get all drunk and belligerent.
Start telling everybody around the room
with their problem is, it's anytime.
I'm a happy drunk. I liked it. So
silly and goofy and you're very loving.
You're one of those drunks that calls
me up at four in the morning and telling
me how much you love
me. I do. It's so funny.
That's why I don't need weed, man. I don't
need the we, I'm done with that shit.
You say that all the time. Yeah,
but I don't smoke that much,
so every time I do I just ate. Always
fucking burns my throat. I don't get it.
I just don't know how to control your
inhale. Yeah. And I just don't get it.
You're just doing like these bong rip
type of things and like I do shots.
What do you want? Because you're
trying to get that same effect.
It doesn't work like that.
Got I not just trying to
fucking inhale and fill it out.
I don't know. Yeah. I don't want to get
good at it. I don't want to get good at,
but whenever I don't drink then I'll,
every once in a while I'll come around.
It'll be all right.
I gotta I gotta do something.
I got to break up the monotony here.
Thank God you're not into heroin
or I'd be doing that, but heroin.
I made a sweet potato pie. I feel
like I'm down. I feel like I'm woke.
All right. Frame Bridge. Everybody.
If you've previously
listened to this show,
you've heard me talk about frame bridge.
They make it so easy and affordable to
co two custom frame favorite things from
art prints and posters to
the photos on your phone.
I actually collected all the pictures
of our lovely daughter and put it on a
hard drive and there was so many of
them that I was like, you know what?
I think frame bridge could really help
me out with this one. There you go.
That's a personal story.
Men's health says frame
bridge has disrupted the
custom framing industry making
what has typically been a
frustrating and expensive process.
Easy and affordable shots
fired in the custom big frame.
Take that.
Yeah,
custom framers and with the holiday
around the corner of frame bridge is the
perfect way to send truly one of a kind
gifts without that much thought out,
right to everyone on your list. This
is perfect. This is what you need.
The thing about it is,
is so many people that you don't like,
but you have to get him something.
You know what I mean? That's perfect.
You don't have the fucking time. Just
scroll through your Goddamn cell phone.
Go past the Dick Pics.
Go Pass that dead dead picture
of the directions. Okay.
That you have saved on
there for whatever reason,
and find that picture of you and this
person you just required to get a stocking
stuffer for right?
And go in there and just send it up
and then it's done and then it's done.
There you go. There you go. What's
a way did you go during all of that?
You just fucking started staring a
hole through my giant head here. Um,
what do you think you're
thinking about the meal, right?
I am. You're a little off.
You're a little off on this
podcast. I'm sorry, I'm bx.
I'm trying to figure out if I'm going
to respond to this email or not.
I don't think I'm going
to, oh, I would have to,
I would just real quickly,
I would just be,
I would just pay something along that
and going back and forth and back and
forth about it. You know what I mean? Like
it's just going to be more of the same,
you know,
I said what I had to say and that was
that they said to say and you know,
there you go.
You know what you guys both said,
but you had to say and I think she's
supposed to be thankful that you, uh,
you know why I'm doing this and
highly favored equal letters.
Do I keep doing this?
What I'm thankful for is I fucking hate.
That's the one thing about Thanksgiving
that I cannot stand is listening to
adults.
No.
Like just you don't think that's a nice,
I don't like listening to it because
I am so jaded that I'm just like,
I just feel like people try to top one
another about like what they're thankful
for and how much more they understand
what's really makes you happy in life.
Yeah.
Um,
it's like when people have a baby and
they tried to sit there and talk about
like how much they love their babies,
so then they have to top the other person.
Oh my God, my heart is just filled
to the brim with love. Oh yeah.
I feel like my heart is on the outside
of my body now and then they just keep
fucking going about their heart
and she's like to, to begin at elm.
You can't love your kid.
Yes, I get it. Oh my God.
Is it standing up like all babies
eventually do. That is incredible.
Actually. Some babies can't and that's
what we need to be thankful for.
That's right. All right. Just go
to frame bridge dot. Yeah. Calm
blowed your photo from your computer
or directly from your Instagram feed.
Fucking ribs being messed up. You can't
sneeze and you can't laugh. I mean,
that is basically, that's my
wheelhouse of emotion. I live,
I live between laughing and sneezing.
I'm going to be robotic today.
Do we have ribs for as a, as
part of our entrees. Well,
I hope you didn't get into the peach
cobbler fight before they made those
goddamn things.
No,
I waited until I just pictured him
pictured him taking the ribs and running.
It'll right along the crack of his ass.
No.
Is Your glaze for your mother fucker?
I don't think he would ever do that.
He's actually very classy,
I think.
Who wants sticky buns or if
you have a physical item,
they'll provide secure prepaid package
so you can mail it in for free.
Preview your photo. Oh,
online in any frame style.
Choose your favorite or get free
help from the talented designers.
He's a great idea.
Somebody you don't like,
you just take a selfie if you scowling
at them and then get it framed.
Yeah. And have a tee shirt on that says,
don't call me, you know, like that.
I like it. The, uh, the
expert team at frame bridge.
We'll custom your item in days,
not weeks or months and deliver your
finished place directly to you or your
loved ones along with the handwritten
gift or note. Here's one to send to an ex.
You'd somehow just having great fun with
a maniacal smile waving and with the
tee shirt says, I'm moving on. You
can have a lot of fun with these.
The best part, instead of the hundred
shoe pay at framing a framing store,
their prices start at $39 in all
shipping is free. You know it isn't.
The best part is this copy's going to
keep going even though everybody already
gets the concept frame.
Bridge even offers a happiness guaranteed.
Unlike those peach cobbler people,
if for any reason you aren't
100% satisfied with the order,
they'll make it right. Go to [inaudible]
dot com and use Promo Code [inaudible].
You'll save an additional
15% off your first order.
Just go to frame bridge.com
Promo Code burr frame,
bridge.com Promo Code [inaudible].
Hey,
next year we're going to
go back to cooking our own
meal, right? Oh, absolutely.
This is just because we got
the little one this year.
I feel like vinyl over as this like
a little overwhelming. So, you know,
I thought I could like you have a cheat
on a test and then he'd get it back and
you have kind of that feeling of
guilt. I never did. Uh, me undies.
Everybody. Ah, Ba du, Du, du [inaudible].
Where's my fucking pie? Du Doo.
Do Doo me undies me undies.
Make it as someone's gonna die.
I don't give a fuck about all your
excuses. Make the fucking thing,
put it in the caboose and I'm
going to drive away nice and happy.
I guess we don't get to zero. You'd
fucking cones there. All right.
Every year millions of people receive
the least light gift of all time
underwear. But we, I like what,
you know what's funny is buying
your wife sexy underwear. I mean,
is that really a gift?
Hey, put this on dressing.
Who Does d flower? You, you
like lingerie? I love lingerie.
You just like the word makes you
feel bilingual. Um, lingerie on,
but we still give it to try it.
We still give it to our family.
That's what you do. You take a picture
of underwear, you get it framed,
and then you send it to
somebody. And that's two for
one. That's weird, isn't it?
Sounds like some weird like Jeffrey
Dahmer Shit. It's just the underwear.
I'm not saying you're in it with a stiffy,
but we still give it to our families and
our loved ones who just don't want it.
Uh, but maybe it's not, I
couldn't even just chuckle there,
but it's not that underwear to go.
Ha ha ha.
Oh that wasn't a bad one.
But maybe no,
because what happens is the muscle
spasms and they'll just fucking,
they start locking up. Okay. You know,
it's funny, he's trying to sneeze.
Relaxed.
When I tried to do was just exhale as
much air out as I can and then he'd just
go, who needs and it doesn't
get out. And then it just,
yeah, you need that Guy Barnes from
platoon and your face gone take the pain.
But maybe it's not that an underwears
the problem. It's the kind of underwear.
Let, Oh, let, let me
tell you about me undies.
The only underwear that makes for
an amazing gift, soft, flexible,
like the whore up the street waistband
three times softer than cotton.
Naturally sustainable sourced fiber.
The undies made underwear.
The perfect gift that everyone is going
to love. Just going to love you for,
you know it's funny.
Did they break up with modal modal?
Cause they don't talk about the fabric
anymore. Can they send me some underwear?
Underwear.
Can I have some too?
I don't want you walking around and
guys underwear. Oh wait a minute.
They also make them for the lady.
It's a Goddamn holiday miracle this year.
Don't give it. Don't give underwear.
It gives me undies.
The holiday season dooby dooby do to
get your exclusive 20% off the softest
underwear and socks you will ever wear.
Free Shipping and 100%
satisfaction guaranteed.
Go to me undies.com/.
[inaudible] that's me.
undies.com/bar. How many?
Two more. Jesus Christ lift.
Nia. Can I come back? Oh absolutely.
I'll turn down the volume.
Change change into what?
Did you buy lunch at a Turkey dress.
Do you have the little Wu Shin
Peach Cobbler? That was a,
that sounds like a wrestler. Oh,
maybe that'll be my restaurant name.
Peach Cobbler. Peach Cobbler. I like
it. I was going to go as the millennial.
I just think it's a great
wrestling character.
You just get offended by everything
and then you go when you do some self
righteous con. Yeah. I'm going to be
peach cobbler. I like it. Okay. Okay.
There she goes. Everybody. All right.
I wonder if I use two microphones.
Will I be half is funny or twice as
funny? All right, lift everybody.
Lyft knows that drivers are what keeps
them moving so they do everything they
can to make sure their drivers
are happy on every trip.
Lift believes that being a ride
sharing drivers should be fun.
Oh, don't have too much fun. You
fucking drive in the car, man.
That's like when you fly one of these
stupid airlines in the stewardess says as
a singing songs like on southwest,
it's like,
will you shut the fuck up and
try to be remotely professional?
My life is in your hands.
You know,
I hate more is the people that laugh and
applaud and just egg them on and we got
a free show. I don't even know why we
have to get off the plane in Vegas. Uh,
lift believes that being a ride sharing
drivers should be fun if you have a good
time. So are the passengers. Um,
if you're choosing a Roger's
picture and everybody boozing it up,
we're having a great time,
right?
You're all going to be okay.
I said it God damn fucking words.
If you're choosing a ride
sharing company to drive for,
go with the company
that treats you better.
Lift Lyft was the first to offer in
APP tipping. When you drive for lip,
you get 100% of the tips.
Drivers have been paid over 200 million
in tips since the feature was introduced.
Lyft has taken the
guesswork out of pickups.
The new amp device.
Is it supposed to be app amp device uses
color coding to help passengers find
their drivers? Well, that's
the light and the car.
You can earn hundreds of dollars a
week plus tips. One earned money,
drive more time. You want to earn
more money? Everybody worked more.
It's never been easier
to give yourself a raise.
It's a simple formula that's not a race.
Uh,
raises you make more an hour.
A raise is not you work more.
Jesus fucking Christ. I suck at math
than even I saw too. That bullshit.
It's as simple formula.
Happy drivers mean happy passengers make.
Maybe that's why nine out of 10 Lyft rides
get a perfect five star rating. Yeah,
and one out of 10 are good at math. Uh, s
of Jesus built. Don't burn this one down.
I love Lyft. I love Lyft.
Do you know what I mean?
Less people die from drinking and
driving because of Lyft. I love Lyft.
I love lamp.
I love Lyft.
So join the ride sharing company that
believes in treating its people betters.
Go to lift.com/bird today
and get a $500 new bonus.
That's lyft.com/ [inaudible] dot com
slash bird I want to fuck a become a Lyft
driver. I would love to do that.
Just fucking cruise around the city,
you know, talking to people.
Everybody gets a free fucking DVD.
I don't have a DVD player on grateful.
Fuck.
Simply safe. If you want to protect
your home this holiday season,
listen up. This is a
very, this is very cool.
My listeners now have early access to
simply save [inaudible] biggest black
Friday sale ever $200 of simply
safe's holiday security system.
This is a true bestseller,
a 13 piece arsenal that
covers your whole home.
If you want to protect your family,
this should be how you do it.
Simply safe has made everything
about security effortless.
You're barely, you barely lift
a finger, just order it online.
It's delivered right to
your door for free shipping.
It takes less than an hour to set up.
A 10 year old can do this. No pressure.
So when you fucked this up, Christ at
10 year old, get doored and I can't.
Simply safe has no longterm contract,
no pushy sales guy,
no hidden fees. The prices are
honestly are honest and fair.
15 bucks a month for the best in industry
24 seven alarm monitoring and with
simply safe, you'll never,
you're never locked in.
Go right now to simply safe.com and
you get $200 off your security system.
Hurry, this offer ends soon and
these systems will fly off the shelf.
That's simply safe.
bird.com for $200 off
simply safe cbre.com.
All right, where are we in
the podcast? Oh 38 minutes.
Are you guys thankful for the extra
eight minutes that I gave you?
Um, so I got my Christmas shopping
started. I'm very excited about that.
I think I'm actually going to do
a family Christmas card this year.
Every year we were like, we should do
that and we never did it well this year.
God dammit we're going to do it
cause we've got a kid now, right?
If you don't have a fucking kid, you know,
past a certain age is, if it's just you,
you, your significant
other and your family pet,
don't you start feeling like
the other people judging you?
They haven't reproduced. What's
wrong with them? I don't know.
Maybe they're informed, they understand
how much you know, population.
Let's not get into the population problem.
Hey, hey. Hey. Fair enough. Fair enough.
Speaking of, fair enough, the
throwback podcast for you,
for those of you who are new to my
podcast and you're listening for the first
time,
which I am so thankful for,
I just feel it for me. If I
have board lists and Aries, um,
Andrew who I am also thankful for the
wonderful producer who picks out the music
every week. When we do the, the, uh,
after I, I babbled for a half hour,
we then had listened to some music
little interlude and then we go into a
classic podcast from a Thursday gone
by and another year or possibly earlier
this year, evidently last year,
one of these years I gave the uh,
the now classic.
I like to call it a classic
because I would like to do
something classic in life.
So I'm going to say that what I did
was classic. Ah, the fair enough.
Like how to get through your Thanksgiving
dinner with the simple phrase.
Fair enough,
Huh?
You don't feel that a
boarding a child is murder.
Fair enough. It is. You
killed something. Right?
Cause if you didn't do it, I mean dead,
dead based something. Fair enough.
I like doing that. I like arguing
the opposite side of political shit.
Like if I was in a conservative,
a conservative fucking state,
I would argue pro pro choice.
When I'm in La I argue
prolife and nothing,
none of it has to do with the
fetus or anything like that.
All it has to do with is me annoying
the person that I'm talking to them.
That's what I do. Anyways, that's,
that's the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday. Monday morning
podcast. God bless all of you.
I am so thankful.
I'm so thankful to be able to go out and
tell jokes every night and I just feel
like for me,
all right,
have a great thanksgiving weekend you
cunt and I will talk to you on Monday.
I cannot wait to watch the football
game. And unfortunately, my wife has gone
into that fucking Westminster dog show,
which I really enjoy except for the fact
that it comes on at the same time as
the football game there.
I set it by
[inaudible]
the Turkey day to you all,
you know,
stuffing and potatoes and pie and beer,
cranberries and gravy and
your cousin who's gay.
Um, hey, what's going on? How
are you? Happy thanksgiving.
Happy not having to fucking
go to work today. Huh?
You around the table.
You're sitting down yet both.
You haven't gone downstairs yet.
I got, I got some advice for you.
Today is going to be a day.
I think that's going to be
a lot of fucking arguments.
A lot of fucking arguments at the
table, right? The big fucking election.
Some people wanted the
guy with the eyebrows.
Some people wanted the fucking
lady with the pants suit,
right? Um, this is what
you gotta do is see you.
You're already going to have a fight,
right?
There's already going to be your older
brother. There's going to be this person.
There's going to be another per,
somebody's going to say something, right?
And you're going to be, you're going to
have a couple of wild fucking turkeys.
He's just standing over there,
you know,
eating a fucking appetizer or two and
somebody is going to be getting on your
nerves. Maybe somebody fucking
wife who won't shut the fuck up,
right? Why the fuck did he marry?
Or maybe maybe it's the husband,
Jesus Christ.
What is she doing with this guy?
All he does is fucking talk about himself.
Something's going to drive you up
the fucking wall. If it's not this,
it's going to be that this is,
this is the phrase,
this is a phrase that's going to save your
day. Okay? Save the whole fucking day.
Cause you're not going to change anybody's
opinion. Oh, these fucking jerk off.
Still yelling. He Hug. Well,
could you vote for Trump? Well,
what the Fuck About Hillary?
You're not changing.
You're just gonna fucking
yell at each other.
So here's the phrase she got to use to
get through this fucking day. All right.
Along with the alcohol or whatever
drug you fucking want to use.
Fair enough. You know? Hey, fair enough.
That's all I, that's all you gotta do.
What'd you say? Hey, hey guys, guys, guys,
fair enough. Fair enough. Whatever.
You don't need to see
him anymore right now,
if you're younger and you still live
there, that's kind of fucking tough.
I don't know what to tell you, but if
you've already moved out of the house,
why are you still arguing
with these people?
Why are you still trying to
change their fucking minds?
You're not going to change their
minds. All right? I don't give a fuck.
If you majored in debating it,
you stupid fucking skull in the woods,
whatever the fuck it is.
You did the,
now you're coming back and now you think
you know something and you think that
you fucking siblings want to hear it.
You know what? They don't the same way.
You don't want to hear the way
they fucking eat. When they had,
they've had a couple, two, three,
right? And all the sudden the man,
everything just sounds like they're
eating fucking mashed potatoes. You know?
You start having these murderers
fucking thoughts, you know,
just fair enough. Hey,
fair enough. Whenever it,
whenever it was that what
you think is that it's there.
How you look at the world. Hey God bless
Ya. Pass the fucking peas and carrots.
Fair enough. Fair enough. You know,
and that's all you got to do that
eventually the meal's going to be over.
All right,
and you're going to get in your fucking
car and you're going to drive away
unless you stay in there for the weekend,
then you've got to go out to,
I don't know, you got to.
Oh, but you gotta write,
you gotta get the fuck out of
there. Yeah. Thanksgiving is a,
it's such a great day.
There's no pressure to get any
gifts eaten a bunch of great food.
All of that is tremendous. Okay. Unless,
unless you go into her fucking
family's house or his family's house,
that's a weird one because you know,
you're used to all your
family's food and thanksgiving.
You know how it's supposed to taste
that you're going to go somewhere else.
It's going to taste a little
bit different. You know,
this is like a classics standup
bit like here's how it usually is,
but when you're fucking blah, blah,
blah, it's a whole different story,
right? Then you just got to suck
it up and just be like, you know,
worst case scenario, this
absolutely fucking sucks, you know,
in which case, fair enough. You know,
you don't know how to cook. Okay,
you're supposed to cook
today. You know, it's,
it's like when it's somebody's birthday,
most people can't sing, but God dammit,
you got to sing the songs. So they
do the best they can. Happy Birthday,
right? They do what the
fuck they can. Well,
sometimes she got to take the,
the,
the same fucking theory of a tone deaf
person singing happy birthday to you
because they love you. Right? You
get, you got to apply that to food,
which is a motherfucker,
which brings it to how do I make it
look like I ate the shit when I really
didn't? Well, oh Jesus,
I don't know how to do this one. What you
gotta do is you've got to fucking, uh,
you got to engage in a lot of conversation
as you just sort of fucking hit and
the plate with your fork a little
bit as if you almost like, you know,
that noise people make when they
want someone to make a speech.
That annoying fucking
thing, you know? Oh my God,
nothing fucking makes
my god damn blood boil.
Like when I'm in the middle of a fucking
conversation at some con starts hitting
the glass with the fork and then for
whatever social fucking reason I have to
now shut up, you know? Oh
my God, that gets me going.
But not today. Not Today. Everybody.
Hey, fair enough. Hey somebody sounds so.
He's down the fucking street
over there with a little,
a little fucking stone knocking
against some glass. You know,
I guess we all have to start as adults.
We have to shut the fuck up, right?
Yeah.
Like we're working for this asshole
bay. You know what? Hey, fair enough.
Fair enough. You know, he
just fucking sit there. Oh,
here we go. Oh good. Oh, here's a cliched
what? I'm thankful for speech. Oh,
is that what you're thankful for?
You know what? I'm thankful for lady.
Every fucking word that comes out
of your mouth is one less worry.
It was one word closer to the end of
whatever the fuck it is you're saying.
You know?
Okay.
That's when you know you're the passive
aggressive movies is when someone's in
the middle of that is you. You fucking
as some, it is just kind of pointed.
Somebody pointed some a plate,
you know, little fucking,
give me that bottle right there.
They're still yammering on. You know,
you know back in 1983 when we
first saw this house, right?
And you just sit there
butter in your fucking roll.
Oh is this why the fuck are going to
go every God damn year from 1983 hey,
you know what? Fair enough. Fair enough.
Yeah. I didn't want to wear this sweater.
Right.
Okay.
He's fucking have these potatoes
instant these fucking potatoes it. Hey,
fair enough. Hey, you didn't, you didn't
have time to fucking cook rail once.
Maybe they ran out of them down the quiz,
the last fucking time they
ever ran out of potatoes.
They never run out of
potatoes and this country,
it's why so many fucking Irish people
over here, right? Fucking Irishmen.
And they tapped out on their
own country one fucking time.
And their whole history,
they run out of potatoes and
everybody fucking jumped ship. Right?
But not the real Irishman.
The Real Irishmen and real ladies,
they fucking stuck around.
Okay.
I like these cowards that all
move to fucking New Jersey. Um,
but you know what a fair enough,
you know, they wanted some potatoes.
This is one of these days people, you
know, and if you're a younger man,
you got to enjoy the holidays cause
cause they're never going to get,
it doesn't get better then, you know,
cause you don't know any better.
So the food tastes the way the fucking
food is supposed to taste in your world.
Right? Everyone who's
supposed to be there is there.
You know,
it's when you get older and you start
expanding your fucking world and all of a
sudden you know Jesus Christ. I mean,
you're sitting there with somebody,
you might even, we have me and might be
sitting at their fucking table being,
I don't even know if with the right
person right now, what the fuck am I day?
You know what, hey say
what? Be Fair enough.
I'm with somebody that I probably was
never really in love with but didn't
realize what love was. You
know, and now here I am,
okay.
And all I gotta do is not getting
in an argument for one fucking day.
I can do this right by Saturday,
I want to be out of this
fucking relationship and you
know what all I'm going to
be thankful then
you bet your sweet ass.
MMM.
Oh my God.
If it starts going into politics,
if it starts going into politics,
she almost need like a referee
during this period of us history.
She just literally step in with one of
those footlocker fucking athlete's foot
ref shirts.
Blow a fucking where's so,
and just send the two people
to opposite fucking Lazy Boys.
Let it go.
Let an AA. It's all she went
home. She went home solving.
Okay. She's not coming back. I don't
think she's got a third runner.
All right. Sit down. Sit
down. Sit Down Buddy.
Nobody's building a wall today.
Okay. Just fucking relax.
Maybe it could be the peacemaker.
Who knows who the fuck knows.
Um, I'm actually very excited.
You wouldn't know it this
year for Thanksgiving because
I'm back in my house. Um,
yeah, there's going to be a
lot of arguments today and
it'll be a victory if I'm,
you know,
if you don't get in,
what maybe it could be that person that
keeps everybody out of it is everybody
starts screaming and yelling. You know,
you know, he's a fucking sex offender,
blah blah, blah. Well,
she's a fucking day,
all that type of shit and you
can be in the back. I like,
Yay.
Just walk right in the middle of it.
Okay.
Oh Man.
I want to see a compilation of youtube
videos of the political fucking,
okay.
I've almost said discourse.
That's probably the wrong fucking word.
You realize how many fucking words I
know that I don't even know what the fuck
they mean. I just know what
words they go with. You know,
discourse goes with political,
political discourse.
You know, you use the word or
Nate when you were in a theater.
I don't know what it means.
I remember, you know,
I got a computer I can look at.
Hey, fair enough. I can look it up.
Why am I going to bore
you guys with the ship?
[inaudible]
can we switch?
Hey, what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is,
see Monday morning podcast for Monday,
November 23rd listen to my voice.
Does it sound tired?
Does it sound sexy?
Um,
I just got back from the Improv in Tempe,
Arizona and uh,
you know,
what does that my 11th fucking week on
the road in the last couple of weeks.
Well, that doesn't make sense.
Mathematically. I whatever,
I been on the road a lot.
My fucking voice is tired. So, uh,
this is going to be my easy listening
vibe for you this Monday. And, uh,
I imagine some of you will complain.
I liked it better when you were angrier.
Go Fuck Yourself. How about that?
Is that angry enough for you? Okay.
I don't really have the fucking
energy to get as mad as I usually do,
but just know you know that I'm
thinking hateful thoughts towards you.
All right? You fucking angry. Cons. See,
that's why you got to watch out who you
surround yourself with is because when
you actually make a positive step
in your life, for example, uh,
being less angry, they actually, they try
to make it seem like it's a bad thing.
Dude, you changed man. You fucking change.
Look at you, you're smiling, you're happy.
You know, what are you doing? You
know what I'm doing right now?
I'm sitting here on my fucking couch
in the living room and it is my fucking
couch. If I was on the Selfie,
just sales on the software.
That's what I have in my living room.
I have a sofa and I have a fucking couch.
The fucking couch is fucking comfortable,
hence its name and I'm on it
because I'm fucking tired. Um,
let's try to hype my shit. Let's try
to be smart with this podcast, uh,
to begin with. Um, all right.
I'm doing a standup special I next hour
long special of filth and silly faces,
which might be the name. It'd be a
good name, Huh? Filson silly faces. Um,
maybe this, I don't fucking know. Listen
to me. I'm exhausted. Fucking exhausted.
All right.
Uh,
I'm going to be taping it at the Fillmore
in San Francisco on December 17th.
I'm doing two shows,
one at one time and one at another time.
I don't have the information, but I
do have the link right on my website.
If you go on to [inaudible] dot
com and you go down to a, you know,
scroll down in the lower left hand corner
and you will get to the link and it'll
take you to live nation.com
we'll see tickets for
Julio Iglesias,
um,
fucking men at work.
You know,
what's the name of that other group
is the name of that fucking group.
What was the name of the group?
It was the name of the song and it was
the name of the album and lead singer
killed himself.
There's a trivia question.
Do you remember early
eighties big country,
there was a band called big country.
They had an album called big country
and the name of their hit song was big
country.
Needless to say,
with a well of talent
like that to pull from,
I dunno how they only had one hit song.
We're called cupcake is our thong
cupcake for our album. Cupcake.
Fucking calve.
K toodaloo and then that's it.
I mean what the fuck is wrong with you?
Don't think about switching
it up a little bit.
It's actually isn't funny cause the
lead singer ended up killing himself.
Okay.
You know the song should have been
called continent I. What was I thinking?
Um, anyways, so if you go on
ego on the live nation.com,
let me see if I can even fucking do it.
If I even can find tickets to my special,
I'll go to [inaudible] dot com
I ain't blue. I'll look at that.
What a good looking guy.
All right,
I'm going to click on the link and it
takes me to live nation.com let me do this
with you because so many of you fucking
idiots are going to it. Couldn't find it.
I clicked on the link and it
didn't do everything for me.
I don't know what to do.
You know what it's like?
That's like those Douche bags
you see on youtube. By the way,
you can learn how to play drums,
guitar of fucking Sitar.
Whatever you want to
learn right on youtube.
Somebody is going to show you how to play.
You know a Didgeridoo.
So these fucking guys get on
there and they show you. Exactly.
They slow it down and they
show you how to play it.
And people still ask for tabs. Great
Video, but do you have any tabs?
Why didn't you just ask the guy to fucking
go over there and put your fingers on
the Fret Board for ya? You Lazy.
Fuck. Oh, there's Lampinelli.
They got a nice picture
of Lisa Lampanelli on.
Now let's see if my picture comes up.
No,
it goes right to fucking you too.
Okay.
And some guy with a cowboy hat named Brad
Paisley on his American Saturday night
tour. All right, let's see if
there's some sort of search here.
Okay.
All right, let's go to
the bees. Blue Rodeo.
Bob Dylan,
boys like girls brand new Brandi Carlile.
Brian Regan and know me well,
that's good.
Well I'm glad I fucking dead. This.
How do we do this on sale now?
Top 10 tours. I know that's not going
to be me. Top 10 venues, the Fillmore,
Bam. That's what you do. All right,
so you get on the homepage. All right.
And then you scroll down,
you'll see top 10 venues.
You Click on the Fillmore and
then you wait for your slow computer.
All right. Live nation at the Fillmore.
And then you scroll down. Let's see,
he was going to be playing there.
The Black Crowes la Los
Lobos bill bar right there.
So that's what you do.
All right.
So I don't need any fucking emails from
you whiny bitches about how you can't
find fucking tickets cause I just
did it in real time. All right.
So anyways,
as I said,
I'm sitting on my fucking couch here and
I'm actually watching a replay or the
Bruins sabers game. I don't know who wins.
Don't fucking tell me. Um, as what I do,
I take all the hockey games and I come
back like a fucking scout and I watched
like seven games. I already watched
when the Bruins beat the, uh,
Atlanta thrashers and I
gotta tell you something.
They got a great fucking team and I
don't know why they have an NHL team in
Atlanta because you should,
you should have seen the amount of
sales look like a fucking a AA meeting.
That's how many people were there for
the fucking thrashers game, you know?
And they got eagle yet Coleville Chuck
and a couple other fucking guys with
names. Like they should be
working the Russian border,
but they're fucking great players. But I
don't understand why did they put what,
what the fuck is wrong with the NHL?
Why did they put another team in Atlanta?
You know,
I don't understand cities that fail in a
sport and then get another opportunity.
You know,
I'm one of the few people that understands
why Los Angeles doesn't have an NFL
team. Well, let's say you
had two of them and you'll,
they both left you. Now,
right there, I mean,
granted, I don't know why the
fuck they left. Typical me.
I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about,
but all I know is you don't put
fucking hockey in Atlanta. All right?
If the fact that the,
the original Atlanta
flames left 30 years ago,
if that wasn't enough of a tip,
why don't you listen to parliament
and they'll let you know that it's a
chocolate city.
You know who the fuck is
from Atlanta Little Wayne.
You've got everyone from like
little Wayne to like rem.
And I'm going to go out on a limb here
and I'm going to say Michael Stipe is,
he doesn't strike me as a
fucking hockey fan. You know,
the fuck is wrong with you. So
anyways, I'm watching the game.
There's like 30 people in the crowd.
There's no fucking energy whatsoever.
But now I'm watching the
Bruins sabers and I always,
never the Bruins play the savers.
I have to listen to the, uh,
the Sabres announcer.
I Dunno what the fucking guy's name is,
but I swear to God he could make,
he can make watching somebody sit
waiting for a bus. Sound exciting.
He's one of the best guys in the league.
So I always watch that fucking guy.
So that's what I'm doing. Was that boring?
I hope it was. Cause I'm fucking tired.
I'm really country this week. Um,
uh, why am I being an asshole?
It's thanksgiving. Thanksgiving is
come up is coming up. Let me, uh,
let me switch the tone
here. Um, you know, people,
this is a week when everyone,
all Americans should sit down no chain.
When those fucking
Douche bags get on TV,
you know,
with the ear muffs and their
little fucking NBC gloves,
they're fucking overcoats with the
floats going by in the background,
they start telling you about why you
should be so fucking thankful for your
fucking miserable life. You know, we not,
maybe if I was on network television,
you know,
with the cashmere coat that I
didn't have to fucking pay for,
I could enjoy my Turkey a little
more. This year. You know,
you know what all Americans
should be given. Thanks right now.
They should be sitting around going, what
the fuck happened? For whatever reason,
everything from the bankers did that
fucking Twat who dropped you out nowhere.
Supposed to sit there and happy and you're
catatonic state with cranberry sauce
dripping down your fucking chin.
You know I can't. That's, you know,
this is such a great fucking holiday.
If you don't listen to anybody,
you know you don't have to buy any gifts.
And by the way,
Wednesday of this week,
for all you drunks out there,
I know you know this information,
but just bear with me for all you
amateur drinkers, drinkers out there.
This is the best.
The Wednesday before Thanksgiving is
the best night of drinking all year.
Hands down. All right? It's not new years.
You know when all his fucking idiots
go out with their silly hats and those
noise makers, why anyone goes out
that night? His fucking beyond me.
Unless you're out there telling jokes
trying to make money, which I understand.
All right?
That night and Saint Patrick's day and
everyone's got their green plastic hats
and they're singing those stupid fucking
side green alligator and along net
goes, why are all eating corned beef
sandwiches? Let me ask you this.
During the course of the fucking year,
the amount of times you go out
to eat and grab a sandwich,
do you ever order a corned beef sandwich?
She had doubt cause she'd know.
Does anybody even know what animal
that comes from? Cause I don't
corn beef is ETA. That's
cattle, right? Beef.
Pork is a pig.
Oh fuck it though.
You know,
you know I was riffing about this week
and I'll actually talk about it here in
the podcast because I don't give a fuck
about burning this joke just cause it's
a topical joke. Why did they
stop calling it the swine flu?
Did all the farmers complain? We ain't
going to be a wholesale no fucking pig.
You keep calling it
the swine flu you want,
you want bacon up to your fucking eyeballs
in every fucking pig warehouse out
there.
You know,
and don't even act like a don't affect
he because government is going to have to
buy it back. So why don't you come
up with a new fucking name forward?
H One n one is not the
name of a fucking plague.
The black death. That's the name of
a plague. All right. You know what?
Let me fucking look that up.
That's what it's pissing me off
here is we finally got a plague.
You know something that I've been for for
a long fucking time.
Imagine if I ended up getting it.
They'd play this at my
funeral. Well, you know, we uh,
he died the way he wanted to die. I
mean, the guy was into the fucking
swine flu and let me, let
me, let me search here.
Great plagues.
There's no way.
I'm not on some FBI fucking watch
list after this goddamn search.
How the fuck do you self spell plague?
I know it's not that way.
Pla gue great plagues.
Did you mean I liked that after you,
you fucking spell it wrong and then
Google is like, did you mean this?
You fucking moron?
Of course I did.
Yeah.
All right. I guess there was
one called the great plague.
What do I need to search?
Awesome plagues. Plagues.
How would I just search plagues? All
right. This is a long fucking way to go.
Just tell you why that they should
still call it the fucking swine flu.
The 10 plagues of Egypt, Jesus
Christ, and one of the fluff.
So fucking skinny over there, Huh? Time.
You turn around them as a great way
to lose weight. 10 plagues in a row,
even if you survive it,
right?
There's no way you're gonna be more
than a buck 40 are Egyptian skinny.
I don't even know what they are. You only
a gypsy Shin. I know. Is Anwar Sadat,
right? The 10 plagues. Ah.
Who gives a fuck? All right.
Wait. The plague of lice.
The plague of flies.
What does it some biblical Shit I fucking
give up. You know what I'm saying?
They swine flu. That's a great
name. We'll think about it.
If you could just put yourself a
hundred years in the hit in history.
If you look back and they talk about,
you know,
if when we're old we talk about it,
every day much going. Great. And
then in 2009 the swine flu came,
Ga Ga grabber.
Where did the swine flu come from?
I'll show you where it came from.
Some foreign are fucked or fucking peg.
Have you guys noticed that?
All the new diseases,
there's never any sort of scientific
explanation of where they come from.
So all you can do is go get down to
your local bar and listen to people
hypothesize. I don't know if you've
noticed, but anytime you go into a bar,
if you ask where a disease came from,
that's the answer you always get.
Somebody from another country had sex
with an animal and now we're all gonna die
ever since age. Remember that? Do
it. I'll tell you what happened.
Somebody fucking blew a monkey and
then they fucked this. Store this in.
There you go. You know, you always have
to have some sort of nationalism in it.
You know, dude, you don't see anybody
fucking pigs in this country, right?
It's why we need to close the borders.
Oh fuck yeah. I think the swine
flu would be great. You know,
it'd be a nice cleansing,
a nice cleansing,
get rid of bunch of, you know, you're
not going to die of it. Just
take some vitamins, put on
a sweater, you'll be fine.
It's just going to kill the week.
And that's what needs to happen.
If you notice every other animal,
all the strong survive,
all the weak die.
And that's why there's no,
there's no traffic in the
squirrel community. Have you ever,
have you ever just seen just a
fucking highways worth of squirrels,
you know,
peaking over each other's shoulders trying
to figure out what the fuck is going
on upfront as are all waiting
to try to get some fucking,
not a whatever the fuck they eat.
You know, you don't, you know why?
Because they cause the weak don't survive.
And the problem is is we have
medicine and we keep saving people.
And that's why you can't get an empty row
on a plane anymore because seated next
to you, a two fucking people who should
have died 30 fucking years ago. You know,
and if you don't believe me,
watch them.
Try to get their oversized
bag into the fucking, uh,
overhead compartment and
watch how their brain works.
As you're sitting there visually seeing,
why doesn't he just turn it sideways?
If he has it going that way,
there's no way the door can close.
I can't believe he just tried to close
the door again. Are you a fucking moron?
And then I like when they're
sitting there with a suitcase,
which I don't know if you've
noticed, is a solid object. Okay.
And it's in the shape that it's in.
You can't push it in further.
Like it's a fucking beanbag and it's going
to take the shape of the compartment.
Like it's some sort of water based
thing. Alright. Jesus Christ,
Cleo. Oh my God, the fucking
dog just farted really bad.
Really? You just got to lay there.
That's, you know, that's what kills me.
It's not that my dog farts, it's the
complete lack of guilt on her face.
She just doesn't give a shit.
Okay.
Evidently that causes a lot of stress,
doesn't it? Holding farts in or whatever.
Some sort of methane gas.
I can tell you right now,
there's not a fucking ounce in my dog
clout.
Okay,
why I button you that nice big bed.
I bought my dog this fucking insane.
That cost me like 200 bucks,
you know and I,
you know who spends 200 bucks in a bed?
I'll tell you I'd fucking dog owner dies
because that's how much she love you
dog. Right? And I swear to God I've
gotten this thing there and it literally,
it loves his bed so much. You know
what it looks like when it's sleeves,
how hard this fucking dog sleeps on
that bed. You guys watch pro football,
you haven't noticed when somebody gets
knocked out for some reason when a wide
receiver gets knocked out,
this always ends up happening there.
Legs always end up crossed and then
they got that one arm like don't,
he's like stuck up in the air.
You know,
like they will right in the
middle of making a point.
Like they were pontificating.
If anybody that you haven't noticed
that that's how she fucking sleeps.
Her back legs get crossed and one of her
and she lays on her back and one of her
pauses up in the air. Like she just
got drilled by fucking Ray Lewis.
Um, anyways, I don't know what the
fuck I'm talking about here. Uh,
now I'm interested in
this 10 plagues of Egypt.
This has to be some sort of biblical Shit,
right?
That they're still fighting about today
that makes them want to kill Jews in
Egypt and Egypt and
Israel as number three.
They always end up arguing about,
um,
I say you let them fight it out. That's
my solution to the Middle East. You know,
why don't we just pull up stakes
and let them have at it. You know,
you want to fucking kill each other. Go
ahead. It's great for the environment,
you know,
sort of a manmade plague.
All right. That's what I do.
The week of Thanksgiving,
I say, Oh, I'm pro war. Um, all right,
let's, let's talk about football.
I got a lot of shit last week
from people who are fans of, um,
Peyton manning for, uh, talking about
what a cry baby that cry baby is.
And then a lot of points
that people brought up. Uh,
for some reason I can't fucking find them.
I don't know where the hell they are.
Maybe they're in junk, but I'll
basically paraphrase it. They're like, Oh
God, you're going to, you're going
to give Peyton manning shitty.
And you can say Brady's not a cry baby.
What about that time earlier this year
when he turned around and asked for a
flag and got the call?
What do you mean? Oh,
that's your example of Brady being a cry
baby because he got hit and he turned
around and asked for a fucking flag.
What you mean?
Like every wide receiver
when they don't catch a ball,
every fucking play in the NFL.
Every fucking guy gets up
bitch and looking for a flag.
He got the flag.
The same way Michael Jordan is allowed
to push off people and doesn't get called
for a foul cause. He's one of the
stars in the fucking league. All right,
and other points somebody tried to make,
they're talking about all the roughing,
the passer,
the Tom Brady rule.
Tom Brady did not fucking
campaign for that rule. He didn't.
That was a fucking NFL rule where
they're like, wait a minute.
If our pretty boy
quarterbacks aren't playing,
the viewership goes down and we make
less money. That was a business decision.
Tom Brady didn't campaign
for that fucking rule,
which brings me back to the crybaby,
Peyton Manning,
who lost a playoff game that the patriots
and fucking cried at the end of the
fucking game. And then he and his
coach, Tony Dungy made a fucking a tape,
a game tape, sent it to the league. They
cried some more at the fucking pro bowl.
Two weeks later, a week after
the Patriots won another title,
they're fucking crying again about it.
And then he cried about it at the draft.
That's why he's a fucking baby.
And I forgot to bring up the fact when
he didn't win the Heisman trophy that's
on fucking youtube.
I believe Ricky Williams won it that year.
And when he didn't win it,
the look of entitlement,
Uber to put your professional quarterback.
I was bred for this.
That fucking look on his face.
He's a fucking baby.
Tom Brady has never lost a game and
then thrown his teammates under the bus.
Peyton manning.
How many fucking
more examples do you need?
All right.
You Jack Asses with the fucking
surrogate fucking team out there.
It's the Baltimore Colts, by
the way. All right. Or Colts.
When I say boss Baltimore Coats, I don't
fucking know. Fuck all of you guys.
You just fucking hate the Patriots because
we fucking win. And what did I say?
Did I not say that the Patriots
were going to fucking kill the jets,
which we did yesterday.
Other than that little brief hiccup,
31 14 all right.
And I called that Rex Ryan Shit too.
I've been saying it since the third
week. Rex Ryan, that poor bastard,
the guy's out of his fucking mind.
He's gonna make a halfhearted
attempt at his life this week. I did.
My prediction is he's going to break his,
he's going to break his tailbone
trying to hang himself and yes,
that is a fat joke. All right. I
think I already did this on a podcast.
My psychological breakdown of Rex Ryan,
this is when I knew that guy
was out of his mind. Okay.
When he first said when the Patriots
were going to play him and he was like,
you know, I'm not here to kiss their
rings. I thought it was funny and I like,
I like this guy, you know,
even though he's a coach of
the jets, he's talking shit.
But then there was that week when a
player from another team said something
derogatory about them and
he actually responded to it,
a hedge co head coach responding to some
player on another team and he's trying
to act all cocky and confident and
it was something about his smile.
I saw it in his face.
I'm like,
this guy fucking cries himself to sleep
every night with a pint of fucking ice
cream.
You know,
this is what I think happened.
All right? His Dad, Buddy Ryan,
one of the great defensive coaches
came up with the 40 60 fence, you know,
won a Superbowl. I'll tell
ya, doing something like that,
you don't have time to raise your kid
and you don't have time to be there for.
So all this shit talk and fucking Rex Ryan
does all the shitty sane is this shit.
He wished his dad said to
him when he was a kid kid,
so he could have built up some
sort of confidence, but he didn't.
He wasn't around.
So the combination is still looking for
his dad's fucking approval and living in
the shadow of a man who created the 46
fucking defense has caused this guy to be
an insecure shit talk and psychopath.
And I think in his head he knows that
he can coach at the professional level,
but the the fucking deafening
voice of doubt that he goes,
that fucking is in that guy's head. I'm
telling you, that's why you overeat.
He's one of those guys, you know
when that voice in his head's gone,
racks, what are you doing coaching
at the professional level?
You're not as good as your dad.
They're going to find out what
you're going to get fired.
You'll never coach again.
You're going to have to move
home with your fucking parents.
They're going to kick you out.
You get to be always [inaudible] fuck it.
Oh yeah.
That's why eats all that ice cream.
He gives himself that fucking ice cream
headache and that's all you can focus on.
It only takes a couple of Tylenol pms,
and then he goes to sleep and the next
day he wakes up with all that dairy
product rolling around in his fucking
intestines and he's hung over from all the
Tylenol PM's and then he
does a press conference.
He doesn't know what the fuck he's doing.
He's like one of those wrestlers,
you know, he's got the sickness. He's
like, Jake, the snake. If he was fat,
Hey, you know what? Speaking of which,
somebody asked me a question. Um,
this week they said a bill,
you always drop references to
wrestling on your podcasts. Um,
and during your appearances a,
the ric flair mentioned suplex thing,
a girl you've said that
during your standup special.
So are you actually a fan or were you
a fan back when you were a kid? Um,
I don't think,
I know one adult in real life who
watches wrestling and I don't blame him
because a lot of the time it's corny
and it's Corny as hell help. Uh,
I'm still a fan and it's just one
of those things I never grew out of.
And if you're a fan, who is your
all time favorite? All right. Uh,
your first guess was correct.
I was
each fan when I was a kid and,
um,
but Rick Flair, I have to
admit, I got into ric flair
because of one of the listeners here
when he brought up the flare chop and I
started watching Rick flair and I realized
what a fucking genius he was. So, um,
I watched the WWF when I grew up,
so ric flair was in something else.
I think with the von Erickson,
I kind of used to watch that,
but I,
I watched WWF and when I first started
watching Bob Backlund was the champion.
And I want to say Bruno Bruno Sammartino
might've been Ted dibiase was the
intercontinental champion until Pat
Patterson took that foreign object out of
his trunks, smashed him in the face with
it, and somehow the ref didn't see it.
Then Pat Patterson became Unicon
Anelle champion and a, let's see me.
I sound like the fucking rain man,
as I always do when I try
to remember this shit.
Uh,
the tag team champion was Tony
Galleria and Larry's a Bisco and uh,
okay.
I don't know fuck else.
Ivan put ski Polish Power Bulldog Brower.
Okay.
Mr Fuji, Mr Sido, the moon.
Remember the fucking moon dogs,
those three fat hillbillies
with their overalls.
Yeah.
And then one wouldn't be laying on the
floor with the dog bone. And I was,
I was scared shitless to them. You
noticed as used to scare me with George,
the animal Steele when he came out with
a green tongue and he'd be eating the
belt buckle. I thought it was
fucking real is fucking Harry back.
Killer Khan the way you used to scream
that big Mongolian son of a bitch used to
scare the shit out of me, you
know. Then I realized like George,
the animal Steele was like a fucking
substitute teacher on to Detroit and it
just kind of all fell
apart. So then I, you know,
I watched it right through Mr.
Wonderful Rowdy Roddy Piper.
MMM Jesse
the body Ventura when he used to call
a Tito Santana used to call him Chico
Santana.
I don't care about no Chico Santana.
I used to watch back then and then I
briefly 10 years ago I got back into it
cause I was roommates with Robert Kelly
and he started watching the Rock and
stone cold Steve Austin.
I got into it briefly during then,
but I used to mainly watch, uh, just
the shit talking on the mic but,
and it hasn't been good for a while,
so there you go.
There's my long drawn out question.
Fucking answer to your question there. Um,
all right, let's get on with the
podcast here. Um, oh wait a minute.
I have to hype one other thing.
I'm really all over the place
as opposed to the usual.
I'm even more so all over the place.
Um,
I have a new website out there.
It's called a uninformed radio.com and a,
that's the radio show. I deal with Joe to
Rosa and myself. Uninformed, no reading,
no research, just strong
opinions. It's our radio show. Um,
we are unable to get it onto iTunes
because we're not going through some big
conglomerate. Um, so we're just
going to be putting them up for free.
You can listen for free and eventually
you'll be able to download them for a
buck of whack. So there you go.
That'll be your options. You know,
if you don't want to pay,
you can just sit there and
listen to it at your computer.
But if you know you want to take it on
your iPod and become the hit of the year,
the next party you go to,
you know,
just in case you go to a party and
they don't have a fucking computer,
you can download it, you can
download it for a buck. So, uh,
we're going to be trying to get that
up as quickly as possible. And, uh,
and that's it. So anyways,
really been all over the place.
You know what I did last last week?
No, Bill, what the fuck did you do?
I went and I saw,
uh,
the best rock show I've seen in a
long time. I went to go see, uh,
uh, what does it them crick, those crick
them crooked vultures. So what the fuck?
I kept calling them crooked buzzards,
them crooked vultures.
I went to go see which is uh, uh, I
guess it's, that's super group. Scott,
John Paul Jones from led Zeppelin,
uh,
David Grohl on drums and I don't know
how to say the lead singer's name cause I
never heard anybody say is that Josh
Hommie from Queens of the Stone Age and
eagles of death metal.
I've been listening to all those bands
for years just because, uh, you know,
I've been a big fan of Dave girls drama.
And so whenever he would go, you know,
do like killing joke or he'd
be in Queens of the Stone Age,
I got into those guys. So anyways,
I went to go see the show. Um,
and I bought their new album.
They were actually selling it on vinyl,
so I had to get it so I could
seem cool at my next party.
And if you get a chance,
um,
I mean their whole album is up on
youtube, so listen to it. If you like it,
don't be a cunt. Go out and go buy
it and then go see them on tour. Man,
they will fucking unreal.
And Dave Grohl might be the best
live rock drummer I've ever seen. Uh,
the guy that he's just, he's fucking
unreal. The guy was the shit. And uh,
I dunno man. I felt like I was like a
fucking kid watching that were, you know,
even when you watch a great band and you
just wish you were up there doing it,
and then as you're driving home,
you start thinking all the cool stuff
that happened and then were actually
fantasizing
that it was you that did it. Like
that's how fucking good the, uh,
that's how I was just fucking
awesome. They just a fucking
killer band and uh, uh,
it's all I've been doing is listening to
this shit. So, uh, if you get a chance,
definitely go check those guys out.
Or if you want to see
the show that I went to,
what's already up on fucking youtube
because people record everything. Um,
just search them crooked
vultures will turn w I l,
T, e, r, n and then Los Angeles
and you'll get to see the fucking
show. I saw it. You know, I haven't,
I've been fucking sitting here.
I got the God damn game on mute here.
Who's winning?
Is it still one to one
my allowed to do that or am I on some
sort of copyright infringement here? Oh,
it's one to one the third period.
Okay.
Buffalo's got a fucking great goaltender,
sons of bitches.
You know something I wouldn't mind seeing
buffalo winning poor bastard. You know,
you got fucked in 99.
What else did you go to the finals.
So you go to the finals in the 70s.
Was that Saint Louis?
Do you lose to the flyers? I don't
fucking know. No one gives a shit bill.
All right, let's plow ahead here. Uh,
last week I did the answer to the, uh,
the women thing.
Why is it never enough?
And that created an
absolute shit storm and a,
of basically misogynistic
trashing of women.
So let's continue it. No, I'm kidding. Uh,
we're going to try to balance it
out here. I actually, I took one,
two comments from women,
one supporting what we said last week,
and another one who just really brought
up the point that should have been made
from the beginning. So let me read the
first one. All right. Uh, first off,
bill loved the podcast.
Especially this week's,
I have rarely heard someone so succinctly
describe what is wrong with the
predominant attitudes of
women, even men today. Um,
you know what most women really
want from men? It's not material,
nor is it being spontaneous.
It runs deeper than that.
Women wants sacrifice. Did I read this
last week? I can't fucking remember.
Maybe I did. I'm losing my
mind. Women, one sacrifice.
Most women will tell you, uh,
your dreams are selfish if
they don't revolve around them.
And that real love is
compromised and commitment. Uh,
they want you to drop. I'm just trying
to remember, did I already read this?
I have fucking,
I'm going to plow ahead.
They want you to drop
your hopes and dreams.
They want to see the moment you give up.
I emphasize that because once that moment
has passed and you have nothing left
to sacrifice,
you become that 30 to 40 year old loser
that they will leave to the guy who asks,
why is it never enough?
It isn't until you've given up
everything that is important to you.
This is what love is for most women.
It's not even that they are selfish,
but propose precisely the opposite.
It's the complete other lack of self.
I think I already read this,
didn't I?
The nature of love is not
that of a host and a parasite.
Love is only possible between two complete
our independent individuals who do
not require sacrifice from one another.
Real selfish people do not need
approval or love from others.
They simply would not give a fuck.
I don't know if I agree with that.
What you're basically saying is you need
a significant part of your life that
it's not two overlapping circles.
It's two intersecting circles
is basically what it is.
So where you intersect is your lives
together and where you're not is your own
fucking life that you're allowed to lead.
Um,
sign off. That was a bunch
of generalizations but
that's what we do here.
But this, this lady here just basically
sums up the whole thing. She says,
Bill Lady,
you've been talking about men who have
been doing all these nice things for
women and the women have been
complaining about it like selfish cuts.
My response is this,
men need to stop allowing women to get
away with anything they fucking want.
Seriously, it's the pursuit of pussy turn
men into all men and to whiny bitches.
All these guys have been whining about
the way these girls react when they do
something they think is nice.
What these guys really need to do is
stand up for themselves and tell these
chicks they have two options. Say thank
you or I don't get number two. It says,
try to be nice and let them
and let him complain about it.
I don't know what that means.
Um,
these guys are writing to you instead
of country confronting these women.
So the women aren't even aware that
their behavior needs to change.
They are only making it worse.
Exactly.
That's really the truth of all
of this shit. You know, I mean,
I actually ran into the guy when I
was in Tempe who wrote that, uh, that,
that letter of why isn't it enough?
I met his girl,
she was a sweetheart and everything.
It's just kind of a,
it just was a great question to ask.
That set off a lot of fucking
frustration and a yeah.
What the reality is,
is what this woman wrote here is that
100% true is that you really shouldn't be
writing me bitching about it. You
should be talking to you, a woman.
But you know, some of it is, you
know, people just want to vent.
And then there's other times people are
there in fucked up situations and by
fucked up situations, I mean,
they're married. So, um,
I think what a lot of guys learned quickly
is when they get married is now that
they're legally bound to someone
and if they break up with them,
they lose half their shit.
It becomes,
it's not a balanced situation,
you know,
if, I shouldn't just just put that
on guys, but it's whoever has more,
whoever brought more into the
relationship when you get married,
you fucked because you stand to lose more,
which we can in you're arguing position,
which you have to do is get to that zen
place where you don't give a fuck about
materialistic goods and then you can
really go off on whoever the fuck you're
with. But the reality is, you know, same
thing, like when you see like, you know,
the big thing,
when I first started doing comedy,
as I used to always see female comics
would go on stage and they'd be joking
about how guys don't know what they're
doing in bed. Debbie. Like, oh my God,
they have no idea where it is or what
the dual ba Ba ba Ba, Ba, you know,
which I understand the frustration
of that. But it's like, so you know,
I'll wait. Sam Kinison did the bit,
just tell us, tell us what to do,
we'll fucking do it. Um, I think
that's what a lot of complaining is.
God knows a lot of my complaining.
I said,
well why don't you just walk up to the
person or thing that you're bitching
about and tell him how you feel and
just take out all the fucks and the
insulting the,
the insults,
I dunno, you know, at this
podcast fucking sucks.
I'm going to call it out before you guys.
It's just podcast is just
sucked this week. All right,
I'm all over the fucking place.
I'm fucking exhausted.
It's a Goddamn holiday weekend.
You can you guys and really,
how hard are you work in this week?
You know,
hasn't somebody gone come in and brought
a pie in and somebody is wearing an
awful brown and orange
Thanksgiving sweater. You know,
maybe it's your manager to show
that he has a human side. You know?
Isn't that the worst when
you hate your fucking boss?
And then around the holidays,
all of a sudden he just lets up a little
bit and tries to act nice, you know,
or it's a female. She gets a
little bit nicer, you know,
and the whole time she's sitting there
wishing you a happy thanksgiving.
You just want to fucking kicker
right in the box, you know?
But you can't,
you fucking can't.
Well, I was sad. What the fuck is it?
It's one to one 1515 minutes left
in the third period you don't,
one of the hardest things to do I think
is to be an announcer for hockey now
that they took and taken out the red line,
the fucking game.
You'll break your neck sitting
there watching the fucking game.
That's why I like it watching it on TVs
because I don't have to keep turning my
head. The camera, the camera moves
for me. It does all the work.
What? I'm literally out
of Shit to say, you know?
I feel like right now the south bad,
this podcast is when you bomb is a
comedian is that works. When, when,
when shit is going great,
when everything you say is killing,
when you're on stage,
basically what happens is,
is you've done about 20
minutes of material and you
look down at your watch and
you watch says you've been
up there for 55 minutes.
That's when you know that you're
fucking killing. And conversely,
when you're bombing,
you will do an hour's worth of material
in 17 minutes and all you have left is
your closing bit.
And you look down at your watch and you
realize that you've been on stage for
just under 20 minutes and
you're like, wow, now what
the fuck am I doing? You know,
your mouth gets dry. That's when
you start going into the crowd.
Hey is, you know, so what's there
to do around here and a Raleigh,
North Carolina. Look at
this guy over here. Ah,
what do you do sir? Oh,
you're a plumber. Really? Oh,
so a, I bet your butt crack is
always shot. Fucking kill me.
You know, then you just,
you just fucked. Hey,
how about a round of applause for the wait
staff, you know, keep it going for him.
You know, and I just want to
thank all you guys for showing up.
I know it's a recession and I appreciate,
uh,
you know how bad I am for the
tropes. You know, you know,
whether you support going to war or not,
you know,
these kids are out there that laying
down their lives and they're away from
their families in thanksgivings this week.
I think we should all sit back and give
thanks and be appreciative that I've
already done an hours worth of fucking
jokes and you conserve and laughed at
anything.
So now I'm technically in overtime
even though contractually I already,
I owe you like another 40 minutes
of fucking comedy, you know,
and let's not forget all the people who
have died in boating accidents this year.
You know,
a lot of people don't know that boating
accidents is one of the leading,
leading causes of death.
When human beings are out in the ocean
and you start remembering jokes
from the early party, your act,
and you start telling him, you know,
yeah, they did a study the other day.
They said, you know, 90% is shark attacks
actually happened in shallow water.
No Shit. That's where the people are.
It's called the fucking beach. Oh yeah.
What are their people swimming to Europe?
Let's go to France. You pussies. Ah,
you like that joke.
That's a joke for my act in 2001.
I'm too fucking old jokes in my act.
What else did I used to fucking do?
Okay,
I already did one of those. My
original jokes. You guys see these uh,
rap group criss cross warm it up, Chris.
Warming up, Chris. Hey, go to bed.
Chris. What do you like
nine years old? Oh.
Oh my God.
I had horrible jokes.
Okay.
Easy jokes about working in a dental
office. A people, I got news for you.
Six years and neglect is not cured by
a tic tac in the waiting room. Hey,
you guys ready for your next deck? Too
Bad. I still got another 30 minutes to do.
Ladies back me up. Guys are crazy, right?
I mean, you know, where are we?
We don't give a shit that's going be
just searching for shit to say what,
but I'm, it's, it's great to be here
in Raleigh. You know what I mean?
It's guy, you know, you come out here
to Raleigh, you know, they got a,
he got a mall. All right folks, I'm
not gonna lie to you. I'm out of jokes.
I wish you could just do that and
just fucking become honest. I'm,
I'm out of fucking material. I don't
know what the fuck you guys want from me.
Come on. Tic, tic, tic, tic, tic,
tic, tic, tic. All right, 41 minutes.
Does that qualify as a podcast?
Oh, I actually, you know,
I forgot one story was
supposed to be here. I think
I got one other question. This is a
Phillips some time as I scroll down,
what's up with scrolling?
There's another when you won't do a full
conclusive Haber with some old rolling
on. All right, unacceptable. Here you go.
Here's a classic example where somebody
should just have used the phrase
unacceptable and I really want to
go into this bar with this guy.
When there's a classic
fuck over. Um, so bill,
I show up to this local sports bar at
11:00 PM the night before my birthday by
myself. While do, that's
your fucking fault, you know?
Yeah.
I don't know what your problem is.
Stop lashing out at the people
around you right now. Look at me.
I'm taking it out on you cause I'm out
of material here and whatever the fuck it
is, I've lost my stream of consciousness.
Still one to one, by the way,
with 12 minutes and 32 seconds to go.
Hey,
if anybody knows the name of the announcer
for the, uh, the Sabres I'd love,
I'd love to know the guy's name.
I mean, I guess I could Google it,
but I know when I do, there's going
to be like fucking 58, you know,
buffalo sabers.net backslash org.
And I don't want to go through that shit.
All right. So anyways, Bill,
I show up to a local sports bar at
11:00 PM the night before my birthday by
myself. All right. He goes, the bartender
asked for my id, I give it to her,
she hands it back and
ask me what I would like.
Now I'm not looking for comments,
but you would,
you would think the bartender would be
aware of the date and time and have some
snide remark about hanging out by myself.
Um,
okay.
This close to my birthday.
Well,
I think she's just trying to see or he's
trying to see if you're of age and hunt.
Right? I don't fucking know.
Anyways. Uh, I'm not upset.
I'm just expecting a stupid comment.
So I ask, uh, what the specials are.
She tells me that the large domestics
are three bucks and well drinks or two
bucks. I see they have blue
moon on tap. I'm not a huge fan,
but as 22 ounces of beer for three bucks,
I'll suck it up.
I order. She says, okay. And serves
it. Fast forward to the bill,
it seems a tad high and I
see I was charged for 50
for each of the three beers.
I ask about the bill and she said, oh,
only domestics are $3. My reply was,
blue moon is a domestic beer. It's
made in America, and she says, no,
domestics are Bud Miller and
course. Now, wait a minute.
I thought Blue Moon wasn't
that made and fucking Belgium.
Now I got to fucking look it up before
I take your side here because I really
want to be blue moon.
All right.
Blue Moon brewing company. All right,
here we go. Let's see what we got here.
Oh, Jesus Christ. It's a whole
fucking website isn't Blooma.
It's not a Belgian beer date of birth.
Enter.
Okay.
I have to give you a valid date
of birth to read about beer.
Are you fucking kidding me? All
right, let's go to Wikipedia.
God knows that's fucking accurate,
right?
A blue moon is a full moon. It's
not what I want. Blue Moon bear.
You fucking, no one gives a shit
about space. Actually, I do.
My brother's really in this space
and I learned the other day I thought
something was the north star. He's
like, that's not in the north star.
That's Jupiter. I don't get the fuck out
of here. He goes, yeah. First of all,
he goes, stars, twinkle
planets reflect light.
So ever since then I've been
looking up at the sky and go on.
That's a fucking planet.
I want to know what that is and
I want to go buy a telescope.
But there's no way to buy telescope
without looking like a fucking pervert.
You know what I mean?
That's yet another thing that pervert to
fucking ruin the same way gay guys have
ruined cowboy boots, cowboy hats, and foo
man shoes. You can't fucking, you know,
you can't wear any of that shit unless
you're on a fucking ranch rustling of
fucking cow to the Goddamn ground rules.
People think you're out
there blowing someone. Um,
okay.
All right. Blue Moon Beer. Let's see here.
Blue Moon beer is Molson
Coors brewing company.
All right, so Yaz fucking right, good.
Now I can side with you because
I really want to go off on this.
So the fucking dude is ordering
a domestic beer and she goes,
no domestics or Bud Miller
and cores. Two things. First,
why couldn't she mentioned that Blue Moon
is not considered a domestic beer when
I ordered, but second, let's look at
the bigger picture. I'm sure bill,
you've run into this. You're told
domestics are on sale for happy hour.
So you order a Sam Adams.
At which point you told Sam Adams
this is considered a domestic beer.
Well actually, um, you
may have thought, yes,
Sam Adams is a domestic beer.
It was made by the blood of the
American patriots. He had dumb cunt.
I liked this guy. Uh,
who made the decision?
Who made the decision to call
Shitty Beers? Domestic beer.
What kind of a euphemism is that?
Whenever this happens in the future,
I'm going to ask for a manager and tell
them that not including all domestic
beers with their domestic
specials is unacceptable. Dude,
you should just fucking said that unless
this is actually made an a different
company, a country and Molson
Coors brewing just bought it.
You guys want to hear about it?
Blue Moon is a Belgian style wheat beer
brewed by the Molson brewing company in
Golden,
Colorado.
It's a fucking domestic beer was launched
in 1995 in Canada is marketed as a
similar beer called Rickard's white.
Why do they not have blue moon's up there
is blue moon offensive and it's brewed
in Montreal, Quebec. All right, so some
of it is brewed in another country.
Is that they're out? Well then it should
be called Rickard's white, right dude,
bottom line is you got fucked.
Yeah, that's what they should say.
Our are cheap ass beers are a r three
bucks and anything with any sort of hops
and flavor in it is going
to be for 50 they go,
that's the big outrage of the week.
This dude get fucked. All right.
That's the end of my lackluster one.
You know what I mean?
What the fuck do you guys want from me?
I do one of these every fucking week.
I'm running out of stories to tell you.
I already did that. Gay Guy joked before.
I've already done the fucking,
I think I need to take a break.
Just like the foo fighters. You know
when they sold out Wembley Stadium,
they sold it out twice and
they were sitting around going,
what the fuck else can we
do? Just like when, uh,
the Beatles sold out Shea stadium
or the police sold out Shea stadium,
that's when you just realized, well,
the only way to go now is to go down.
I think I've begun the backward slide.
I'm sliding down the backside of a,
of the podcast and I was
actually thinking about that.
How long am I going to do this
podcast? You know, Oprah's retiring.
She's calling it quits
after 25 fucking years.
Okay.
I mean,
I've basically done one episode every
week for the past two and a half years or
two years. Two months. So 52 weeks a year.
That's 104 episodes plus like another
20 maybe move up to 125 episodes.
All right. Back in the
day, if you did a sitcom,
you needed a hundred episodes
to go into syndication.
I'm in syndication right now, so
think about that shit. I'm like,
if this was the drew Carey show,
I would be in like the seventh season,
you know when they've added the
fat chick with the crazy makeup.
Cause we're on a story ideas,
you know.
So my question to you is how,
how much longer should I do this?
When do I bow out gracefully
and come out with a new,
a new form of a,
what do they call this
shit on the Internet? Huh?
Viral. Do I, do I take it to
the next level? I do a video.
Maybe I'll do a video podcast next and
I'll do like, I'll, I'll have puppets now,
right? I'll have the cont puppet. Right.
What'd you just be sorta some twice
shape tortilla with a red lips on it,
you know, that can talk
and uh, whatever. I'm,
I'm just sort of brainstorming here
and a fucking, I'll puppets a creepy,
you know,
you ever go back and watch
Mr. RogersRogers' and
just see how creepy those
fucking puppets are. You know why?
Cause their mouse did move king Friday.
Yeah.
Hello Lady McMullen.
My name is much think I'm
out of my fucking mind.
I actually did it in the living
room this week. You know,
that's why I had the Nice
Carnegie Hall sort of, Ah,
acoustics in here.
All my dog fucking walked out on me.
You don't have really think my dog finds
me annoying. You know, my practice,
my guitar,
she has a habit of going,
gives me like a big fucking exhale.
And if I'm practicing anything up high,
like I was trying to learn how to play
the beginning of, for those about to rock,
we salute you,
which is way up on the neck of the guitar.
And I was trying to play it the way
Angus plays it, which is a combination,
a using a pick
and plucking with two other fingers.
So needless to say,
it sounded like somebody was choking
a sparrow. And, uh, my dog, you know,
she sort of got,
you know,
just lifted her head up and sort of looked
at me and I laughed because I knew I
was bugging her.
And then I was so focused on trying to
be able to play this for some stupid
fucking reason. And, uh,
when I came out of my fucking comatose
state, I looked and the dog had left.
So, uh, I don't know what the point of
that was. You know what the point was?
The point was to somehow get
to 50 minutes because um,
if I don't do it for 50 minutes,
then I can't continue to,
to not get paid for this.
Um, let's hype my website,
[inaudible] Dot com I'm once
again go there and a fucking,
I dunno, go to my show in Cleveland or
go to my show at Sacramento. It was in a,
in a,
the punchline is Sacramento.
There's the next two weeks I have coming
up and a or come on out and watch my
live taping. Oh, somebody asked
me a question and they're like,
which one of the two shows
are being taped that night?
Are both of them being taped?
And if you take both,
will you combine both and
make one special? Yes. Okay.
Yes I will.
That's what happens.
You take both of them and if I just have
one set that's just fucking awesome and
I loved it. Wire to wire, which
I hope is going to happen.
I'll just take that cause I'm,
I'm really big into a,
you know, not creating a
performance that didn't happen. Um,
my CD is all one show. Why
do I do this? We only did,
we only taped one show, so that's
all one show. Uh, my HBO special,
we did too.
And I forget which one joke is from the
first show and the rest was all from the
second show.
It's so it's basically
one performance and um,
yeah, so that's what I'm hoping for.
So yes. If you're wondering, yes,
both shows will be taped and um,
this is what you basically hope for.
What you do is you go out and you
fucking rock on the first one. See like,
all right,
I've got a great special already and
then you can just totally relax and fuck
around on the second one. You know,
kind of the way you, you know,
you get into like your head,
like you just in a club rather than,
than doing a special, that's
where you want to be. Um,
and that's what I want to try
to hope to do. So that's it.
I need to rest my voice. I hope
everybody has a wonderful thanksgiving.
I would have played a Thanksgiving
song on my guitar, but uh,
none of them exist.
There aren't any thanksgiving songs.
And I'd like saying Shit like
that cause there's always a,
actually there is one.
The Lawrence Welk Orchestra did.
Why nobody gives a fuck.
There's none. There's no
claims. Is there a famous
one? You know what,
this is the last thing I'm
going to Google this week.
Let me see if I can find a fucking
thanksgiving song. You know,
we used to do for Thanksgiving,
me and my family,
we are the family that I was part of.
It really wasn't my family.
MMM,
okay.
We used to fucking, uh, we used to,
we decided we were going to play football
one year and it became a tradition.
We would play football and it was great.
It divided the family in half and it
would always be sleeting and raining and
uh, we would end up getting into
huge fights. Like, fuck you,
fuck you fist fights. And,
uh, it was really bizarre.
And then we'd sit down, we'd all
be fucking soaking wet, you know,
grass stains and,
uh,
that the food was great. You know,
still one of my favorite days.
Thanksgiving
music.
Okay.
Get the fuck Outta here.
Thanksgiving songs.
They actually have thanksgiving music.
You fucking kidding me?
The Fuck Outta here.
Okay.
No, you don't. You know what this is.
This is a classic thing when you go to
search something and it's just music shit
just came up. There's no
thanks. Wait a minute.
We go to fucking the evil that is iTunes.
This is the last thing I'm gonna do.
This is overtime people.
You don't have to listen to this.
This is all for me right now.
Just checking this out for
me. All right, let's see.
Itunes.
Let's click on that.
Yeah.
You know,
it really is time to end this fucking
show when you guys listen to me just
fucking googling. Um, all
right, here we go here. Uh,
thanks.
Giving music.
Yeah,
Susan Boyle.
She do Thanksgiving music.
The thanksgiving waltz.
Okay.
The harvest home come.
Ye Thankful.
A Charlie Brown thanksgiving. Let's listen
to that. Let's have a listen to that.
Am I the only person who finds Charlie
Brown music? Unbelievably depressing.
Get off the black keys. You
can't, I'm trying to be happy.
Jesus Christ with the miners.
Is that minor chords in
their minors or sad? Right?
Majors are happy. Somebody is taking
guitar lessons. Actually I'm not.
What is that fucking
we're out of potatoes.
I wish I knew about classical music. I
could have made that funny. This is where,
uh,
yeah,
we're out of potatoes. The fifth
movement, whatever the fuck they say.
This is the harvest home.
Is that the same?
I hate that.
Fucking inbred music at Bluegrass Shit.
He's Ye thankful.
There you go. That's some, uh,
that's come ye thankful people
enjoy thanksgiving. Don't have sex.
You're all going to hell. That was the
name of that song. All right. Yeah,
I guess there was Thanksgiving music.
Who gives a fuck? Um, all right,
everybody have a great thanksgiving.
It's still one to one, as far as I know.
Hey, you go brings it into the
zone. Craig g wheeler, right?
Lou Cheech is back.
How about a score?
There we go for 41 left,
one to one and a stoppage of play and
a stoppage of the podcast. All right,
everybody, happy Thanksgiving
and I'll talk to you next week.
Yeah.
Yes.