Hey, what's going on? It's
bill bird. Just checking in
for a quick little half hour on a
Thursday. How you been everybody?
How you been? Huh? How you been?
How was your Tuesday and Wednesday?
Was it everything you thought
it was going to be? Huh?
You feeling good today? Have they
given you your little checky pool yet?
When did they give it to ya?
When you walked through the door?
They make it gets fucking sit down,
work a little bit,
get through the morning breaks and then
sometime around lunchtime it comes your
boss, that fucking jerk off, right?
Coming down the fucking hall with these
Beer Gut slacks you can make out as
giant package, you know? Oh,
he's those big fucking book tooth glass.
People always had some big fucking unit
just swaying back and forth inside this
slacks.
You tried not to look at it,
but every time they sat down
you're just like, Jesus Christ,
this guy's a fucking animal. I know. I
work for this guy. You know what I mean?
Um,
I used to work for a guy like that.
He had glasses and he had this fucking
slacks like mc hammer pants and he had to
have him because he had this giant
fucking unit that everybody knew you had a
giant and the guy couldn't hide it.
He just had this fucking, you know,
I don't know why I'm
thinking a Mars moon unit.
I Dunno what I'm thinking of.
Anyways, this is the Thursday,
a Monday morning podcast where you know,
I just pop in.
She how your weeks go in
case you're having a bad one.
I give you a couple of
chuckles for 30 minutes.
And then at the end of this
we got uh, some of the, uh,
some of the highlights over the year.
Some Monday morning podcast selects that
we uh, that we pull out. I don't know.
We're going to have this week.
I have no idea. Um, but anyways,
what's been going on with
me the last couple of days,
this is getting weird guys.
If you can listen to two of these a week,
like it's really getting to
the point that, uh, you know,
you've got to start paying rent here.
I'm letting you into my house
twice a fucking week. Oh,
my wife was fucking pissed at me last
night. Oh, Jesus Christ when she met.
Um, I've been really tired lately and
when I'm really tired or if I'm drunk,
I fucking snore. That's the
only time I snore. And, um,
I had a couple of whiskeys and I was
really tired and I told the last time I
snore and go,
just wake me up up,
fucking go upstairs and I'll sleep on
the couch asleep in the bedroom upstairs.
Right? And she's like a, she's like, okay,
so I'm fucking snooze.
And
all of a sudden she fucking hits me. She
goes, Bill, go upstairs. You snoring.
So I'm laying there going
like, oh yeah, this is bad.
This is not fair to my wife
going to get up. I'm getting,
getting up like a minute.
Let me just lay here.
And I'm just laying there and I'm
awake, but my eyes are closed. And uh,
I don't know what happened. All of a
sudden you started boom, boom, boom, boom.
And I look up and I saw my wife walking
out of the room and she went upstairs.
And, um, so you know the
deal, you're like, all right,
well I guess tomorrow morning
is going to suck. Right.
You know, here we go. She's
fucking Matt. You know,
they're always mad.
They're always mad about something.
Something's going to happen, doesn't
make a difference. So she was actually,
surprisingly not mad at me,
but what I was smart enough to
do was I woke up in the morning,
paddle by Dow Pope and I walked out the
door and I went to the gym and got on
the treadmill. Um, I fucking, uh,
yeah, I just left in the morning
and, uh, I got a bunch of shit done,
you know, picked up dry cleaning
and dental is fucking shit.
And then I also said I went to the grocery
store as to what she wanted and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, and
miraculously be kind of smoothed over.
And she's still a little pissed at me,
but not a, not in a big way, but, uh,
but I'm back.
Billy freckles is back in the gym.
Hey old Billy's back again
again, again, again, again.
Why Buy Dewalt Bop, Bop, beep beep.
Um, old people understood that joke. Oh,
people watch that fucking
cartoon. Remember that? Oh,
Billy is back. Yeah. Yeah.
Again, again, again, again. And then
the dude would just start with him.
Yeah,
I got no fucking, I've got no water
in my mouth, man. And fucking okay.
Hydrated for being on the treadmill.
Of course, you go to the gym,
you walk in the men's locker room.
What are you going to see?
You're going to see the naked guy.
You know?
Here's the thing you got to expect.
If you go into a men's locker room,
somebody's going to be naked. All
right? It's not that you're naked.
It's the level of comfortable
that you're naked. Right.
I went to nam changing. I'm going to
fucking leave and as I go to leave,
I look over at, you know, just walking
over to the sink to wash my fucking hands.
And there's this guy standing there,
okay.
He's got the towel covering the
front of him. He sort of holding it,
but he's just standing there
with his fucking ass out.
Like the level of comfortable that he was.
Okay.
He was like a hey on. Just to remind
you, I've got that meeting today.
It's six southern.
There'd be home a little late,
like he was that level comfortable naked.
That's what he should have been yelling
out. Just fucking stand in there.
Why does it bug me? I don't know
why it does. You know what I mean?
I'm usually fucking cool about stuff
like this. Like I'm only as people,
I walk into a men's room, you know, and
it smells like shit. It's like, yeah,
it's supposed to people
shit in here better.
They did it in here then in the
restaurant. I've never understood that.
The soundbite walking in a men's locker.
It's just like,
just can you just make a fucking effort?
Okay.
I Dunno.
Is that weird?
That guys are so uncomfortable with
other naked around other naked guys.
Women don't give a shit.
Right?
You sit around and talking
about each other's tits. I mean,
maybe we should do that.
Hey look, you balls.
Oh, Jay, Jay's these only six minute,
and he's talking about balls in a locker,
rum balls in a locker room,
the new fucking standup DVD by Bill Barr.
Um,
so I hit the gym all fucking
week for the most part. And, uh,
I just about perfectly,
I did all these hours of cardio,
but two fucking days in a row when I
went to Atlanta for my last time ever
working at the punchline.
And, uh, when I went to, um,
the next day I did one day at South by
southwest to hype the all things comedy
network with Al Madrigal did a
little panel thing with him and, uh,
Doug Benson, which was a
fucking great time. Uh,
Doug Benson is hilarious.
I'm gonna tell you something right now.
If you're thinking about not seeing
fast and furious parts seven,
just listen to Doug loves
movies or ask him about it.
He had me laughing so hard talking
about that movie. Like, he,
he knows what the movie is,
what I love about him.
He knows what the movie is and it
goes in with those expectations.
You know what I mean? You know
what he said to me? He said like,
there's like five times in a move in
the movie where somebody looks over at
somebody and goes, hang on. And then the
car drives off a cliff and nobody dies.
And he was just laughing. But he
thoroughly enjoyed it and I was just like,
you know, what am I going to see that
movie? I'm going to get an a stupid mood.
Go see that fast and furious parts seven,
driving from building to building.
Hang on one [inaudible] you know,
fast and furious really ought to be able
to uh, they should really kick uh, the,
the um,
the creators of chips some money every
time they make one of those movies.
Cause whenever I see the
fucking pile ups in that movie,
I mean I think that goes back to chips.
They did that every fucking week.
Every fucking week.
There was like a 200 car pile up back in
the day when you could wreck all those
cars and that was your job. What do you
do? I'm a stunt man. I go out now, Rick,
them I'll work on chips or work on the
fall guy and I work on Simon is Simon and
every week.
Okay,
well I'm not slamming jumping or
rolling it over. I ain't living.
Why is he southern? Why can't a
stunt man be intelligent, Bill?
Why is the southern accents
synonymous with stupid?
Why would you do that a month before
you're on the road again, but ab PPD,
Papa booboo. Um, I don't
know why I would do that.
All I know is I got my tickets to
the Kentucky Derby coming up all Gj.
We're going to have such a fucking
great time on that, that tour. And um,
I'm actually worried that I'm
going to out every fucking, uh,
all the good shit I'm
doing in the gym right now.
I'm going to lose those two weeks on
the fucking bus. I got to figure it out.
I'm already mentally in my head.
[inaudible] I'm starting the day
with great nuts and a banana, right?
This is one for y'all. You
fatties out there. You got
to have a fucking game plan.
You don't just show up on a bus.
Next thing you know,
you're gonna be sitting there with a
bunch of yodels and those fucking one of
those pink marshmallow things you
fucking guys eat. What do you do?
You killing yourself. Fucking killing
yourself. You know what I mean?
He just standing there out of breath. You
sound like you just ran a 40 yard dash.
She can't do that to
yourself. All right? So, uh,
I'm going great nuts with
bananas and then, uh,
okay.
I Dunno. I'll have a sandwich
for lunch somewhere in the house.
Phone and orange and an apple.
And then I figure at night,
that's when I'm going to go to a whatever
local place that somebody from down
south suggests. Um, Jesus Christ.
Look at those fucking cheerleaders
with their thick thighs.
Fucking Texas southern. There you
go. The talent is off the court.
They're fucking down by 25.
Dude,
Arizona, who? I don't know that
number five is on an Arizona,
but he's like Ben Wallace meets fucking
Lebron James. He had a dunk in the phone.
First half surprise. My flat screen
didn't fall off the fucking wall.
Don't you hate the first round
of March madness number one.
I'm watching number two against 15 the
fucking up by like, I can't do the math.
What do we got here? 26, 27 points.
Okay.
15 minutes to fucking go,
you know,
number six days. Never been a one bud.
You know, it's bound to happen sometime.
I can't fucking take that. Cool. Um,
but what's great about the first two
rounds, it's just fucking, you know,
you know fucking right there Fred,
go from 64 all the way down to what?
60 fucking white guy.
How do you miss that donkey? A God damn
asshole. Jesus. Don't you know what?
All being judged by that.
You're fucking unbelievable too.
Where did fucking dunk?
The guy's like six fucking 11.
Uh, I mean he got fouled, but how do
you miss her too? In his fucking dunk.
Look at that guy. Fucking eastern
Europeans. Ah, there you go.
Click it off the back of the room.
And why are you giving the guide?
I hate that in basketball when the guy
misses the fucking foul shots and he's
still go over and they fucking slap
him five. You know what I mean?
Like when you watch the family
feud in some moron name, uh,
a color of a car.
Ah Jeez.
Mahogany.
And then the whole family's like that
to stripe or they'll go a good answer.
Good answer. Fucked him.
You say Brown, you asshole.
Look Far Mahogany
Wilson family with the change the steel.
We're going to say blue.
Richard.
Stop Kissing my wife.
Oh my God, I got it. You think
I didn't fucking hear it?
If I didn't answer it fucking
three seconds later it's
going to go and then I'm
going to pick it up. I swear to God, I
got to go back to a flip phone. I got it.
You know I want a walkie talkie. I'm going
to go super old school. I'm gonna out.
Hipster a fucking hipster.
You know east bound Dan.
Load it up and trucking and any
truckers listening to this week?
Hell you get you years old. Big Daddy. Oh,
you sitting on an inner tube cause you
got fucking, what do you got? Hemorrhoids.
How the fuck do you guys,
how do you guys lose weight?
You know, driving that truck. That's got
to be a bitch. What are you doing? Huh?
Jason does some, he, she
and a fucking rest area.
He's got a dick.
Oh Shit. That'd be a tough
one, man. That's what you do.
You guys sit there eating Brussels
sprouts all day long, driving that truck.
Let me ask you a truck as a question,
how, how your fantasy has to be,
you know, like when people in cars
just cut in front of you, you know,
and then slam on the brakes
with no respect for the
amount of weight you have in
the back of your truck and how you,
you have a fucking heart attack trying
to not have the thing jack knife you have
it. Just, just think, you know,
one of these days I'm just not going to
fucking put my foot on the brake and I'm
just going to fucking plow.
I'm gonna drive right up and
over like one of them monster.
She must've nother fucking dunk.
Okay.
Why is he out in the court?
And he got the ball stolen from him.
Can we get this guy off the court?
I know they were up by 30 but
Jesus Christ is making us look bad.
Why are you fucking going to the
rack? You're, you're fucking white.
Do some Larry Bird Shit. Just shoot
the eyes out of the fucking hoops.
I've tried to, he goes his foul
shot. Oh, Jesus. He hadn't won.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I'm reverse racist when it
comes to fucking watching basketball.
I get like annoyed
when my team puts a white guy out there.
It's just like, oh well,
okay, we're down by eight.
What are you going to
be down by 16 is that,
was that what we're trying to do
here? What'd you guys bet? Did you do,
did you bet the over? Huh? Did you
bet the other fucking team? Well,
what are we doing here? Um, I don't
know. Shit about hoop. All right,
so all you fucking people looking to
get pissed at me a little bit to what?
Both fucking Jim or Jim or
something or other at Byu.
Let GM or could fucking man,
I'll tell you
right now.
He used to go out there and
all the frustration he got
from not getting his Dick
sucked out there and Utah.
He fucking beat just focus.
I said Shit on taking jumpers
on the side of a barn.
80 to anybody. Watch a, I
hate Christian. Laettner
yeah,
I'm so pissed.
I miss that guy's whole career because
that was right about when I was starting.
MMM.
I was starting to be a comedian.
Well I started in 92 did he go 88 to
92 or [inaudible] 89 to 93 I don't know
what, but I was a failing
miserably in college. I just,
I completely missed that guy's
career and I have to tell you,
that guy is one of the greatest
villains I've ever seen in my life.
The look on his face and the way he would,
he would look at opposing fans and how
we just completely didn't give a shit
what people thought of them.
It was like watching a comedian going
on stage and the crowd turns on them and
they just stay with their
fucking material. Um,
was one of the most
enjoyable 30 for 30 PSI. Uh,
I watched and I thought that the people,
uh,
okay,
that hated them came off. I mean it
might've been the way that they edit it,
but they just came off as kind of a,
yeah,
I don't think they came off like
they were the jerks. I mean the,
the interview two people, right? One
Guy wrote a book called Duke Sucks,
you know,
I mean right there it's
like, well obviously they
don't, if they did suck this,
we could just look at the stats. You
know, we could look at the standings,
but the fact that you gotta write Duke
Sucks. That means obviously the mean,
you know that right away they're winning.
Right?
Like how everybody hates man United. I
don't know shit about the premier league.
I obviously know that they got a lot of
money and they've had a lot of success
with the level of fucking hatred.
The combination of that.
And then the combination of someone
like myself who knows nothing about,
uh,
soccer, football, whatever the
fuck I'm supposed to call it.
And I still know who man United is.
I know that they play in Liverpool and um,
what else do I know about them?
Um,
they got blue and white uniforms and um,
they're fond to having
ginger's on their team and uh,
just trying to piss off
as many English people.
If fucking Manchester shut the fuck up.
All right,
let me know when they pick the ball up.
Um,
I actually really enjoy it.
I like premiere the Premiere
League. If you go there,
it's fucking great. Most people
singing songs. Next thing you know,
you're eating fish and chips and fucking
slamming beers, right? Z Pack Ian,
even tighter,
Nexia nail you fucking ear lobe the
ear lobe with some fucking Neo Nazi.
Right?
But isn't that the experience?
Somebody starts choking you
with your little colorful scarf.
I have no fucking idea what
I'm talking about. Um, anyways,
am I out of Shit to talk
about? How about those fucking
Bruins man? Goddamn it,
they were playing great and then
a game we really needed to win.
We needed to beat the fucking capitols.
And what happens?
We fucking lose two to
nothing. But, um, I dunno.
I like the way that they're playing.
And even though this year,
obviously I don't think
we're going to win anything,
but I do see a solid team being built
for the future around some young guys.
Um,
Boston not can fucking Spooner.
And, uh, that other guy that begins with
an s and somebody else, I don't know.
I've been fucking busy. Um, anyways, so
listen, the movie, I have Zam beaver.
That's right. A movie about beavers
that turn into zombies. Okay.
There's hot women in it.
People get killed and all freckles makes
an appearance in the beginning with, uh,
someone who's way more
known than I am right there.
You got to go see the fucking movie. You
got to support this movie. You have to,
you don't have to,
but I would appreciate it if he did.
It's been out for like two days.
It'd be nice to see if it could, uh,
compete with transformers.
What'd you think? Um, anyways,
I got a crazy week coming up.
Uh,
I'm in town and then I go to New York
next week and I'm doing a couple of
benefits.
One at Madison Square Garden.
And then like the other one I'm doing,
um,
at the theater at Madison Square Garden,
not with a Nixon Rangers play. Uh,
and then I'm doing,
um,
another benefit for actually Paul
versus unfortunately Paul brother in
brother-in-law passed away a while ago,
about a year and a half ago.
And um,
so they have a benefit for him at levity,
live levity live.
I never deliberately lever the law lived.
Um, that's going down a week
from today, Thursday. Um,
it's a great cause,
you know,
I dunno, I dunno what to say. It's a
fucking really sad story or whatever.
So I'm out there. I'm doing that,
doing a couple of benefits, you know,
trying to fucking balance out my Karma
here by doing some fucking good things
with all this selfish shit
I've done in my life. Um,
did anybody watch the end of the genx?
Anybody at all?
Jesus Christ.
Well that wasn't good.
Nah, they got your card now. Just
talking to himself in the bathroom,
doesn't realize he's miked up.
What happened? What do you
think happened? I killed him.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Jesus Christ.
That was fucking UN,
one of the most amazing
documentary series.
Even if you know what the fuck happens,
you've got to see the fucking thing.
Hey, it's Bob calling. Um,
I'd like to sit down and talk
some more while, you know,
California is a big state.
I don't know. Those are
block letters. I mean,
okay.
I guess when you look at them, Beverly
is spelled the wrong way. Both times
I wrote that one. I did not
write the other one. I just,
I'm driving my wife crazy.
Okay.
Imitate anal. Tell I'm, if I'm trying
to drive new guy's fucking nuts. Um,
there's a new documentary
that guitar guitar made,
um, on slash dad is a, I don't know,
I got through the second
hour and a half long.
I saw the first half of it and
it's just fucking awesome. And um,
Alice Cooper says the funniest shit.
He was just talking about the changes
in music and he was talking about grunge
music and he was talking about at
the peak of grunge music. He goes,
there was a time when I wanted
to go to Seattle and roundup,
all of the bands put them on a
bus and take them to Disneyland.
And he wasn't being a dick.
He was saying it from like a place of
concern because everything was so fucking
miserable. All the music,
you know, everybody,
it just was such a turn in the music. You
went from people dressing up like women
to like fucking everybody like re
I hate my fear of um,
whoa
PE.
Wow baby, boom. Um,
what the fuck does it take?
Who started that style of singing?
Was it Lane Stan Stanley there?
[inaudible] you know, just,
I dunno,
it's like she's singing in the back of
your throat and on either side of your
tongue. Um, I dunno, actually,
I shouldn't say that.
I think that that, uh,
lead singer Alice in chains and when
the most original ways of seeing him,
Perry Farrell from that era,
him, Perry Farrell and axl rose,
I thought he had the most unique phrasing
when it came to a white guy sing.
And there were there any black singers
in that era that I can think of or was
it, and you know, well, they all
wrap it. My world is very different.
I was in a suburb back then
buried in my whiteness.
Let's see what black artists did. I know
back then, C and c music factory. Factory,
right? Wayne, Wayne,
Wayne, Wayne. Well, Wayne,
you know I'm thinking of that song cause
I'm going to the gym and they just play
the worst fucking music at the gym.
I don't know what it is.
I was fuck yesterday, yesterday,
couple days after Sam,
hey,
I fucking go to the gym
and I'm changing right in,
in the time I'm checking.
Like I took my headphones off.
I'd gotten off fucking country
as the lip, elliptical,
right? A lip, the elliptical,
and that's the new improved one. Um,
I got off the elliptical and I took,
I took my headphones off
when it got into the, uh,
the locker room and I heard the,
the end of greases,
the word. And then the next song
they went into was a Banana Rama.
I heard a rumor. I Dunno
what it is. Like they can't,
they always have to be like 25 to 30
years behind and it has to be the most
poppy fucking horseshit. I'm trying
to think if I've ever been at it,
Jim, that plays good music. The only
time I ever heard worst music was a,
I did a cruise ship Gig. I
did it one time. He had to,
we needed the money. Oh. And uh, you know,
they have me staying in the bottom of
the ship. I was so far down on the ship,
like I walked by cargo and the,
then the window to my room was round,
you know what I mean?
And, um, they fucking, uh,
that was the only time I just
remember really bad music,
really fat people and Jello with whip
cream and like these nuts on top of it,
which was fucking gross.
And I just hated the fact.
Okay.
I just hated the fact that I
couldn't eat when I want it to,
you know what I mean? The one that I was
done, I was on some shit fucking cruise.
I then I need to think
that was called those.
I was on shit liner and we went to a
yeah,
Cozumel somewhere in Florida,
in New Orleans.
And uh,
I remember I worked with a juggler.
Juggler opened up for me and um,
I remember him complaining that his joints
ached from all the years of juggling
and he was buying all this
real estate in uh, Florida.
And I just remember thinking like,
I could not be any further away from show
business than sitting here talking to
this juggler about real estate in Florida
on a fucking boat in the middle of the
Gulf of Mexico. This is back when
you eat no cell phone service.
This is like 12 years ago. No cell
phone service, no Internet connection,
no nothing. I'm just on this
fucking thing. And they lied to me.
They told me that it was going to
be though, this is the cool one.
This is one that the young kids
going, cause I said, I said, dude,
I don't think my ex going to work
well on a fucking cruise ship. And uh,
Lo and behold, I show up. I think I
told this story before I show it up.
And the first thing I see
is this Vietnamese woman,
I think she was Vietnamese because she
had that hat on that whenever you watch a
movie about platoon of Vietnam,
you know those hats that they wear when
they're out there in the fields and shit.
She had one of those on and she was,
she looked like she was like
110 and she was already asleep.
Like the cruise was starting
and she's already asleep.
Like not excited whatsoever. Like,
this woman is clearly dying and she's,
her mouth is open and uh,
you know,
she was missing all the teeth,
like from,
from six to 11 numbers, the canine,
and you're right, number six,
that's number six, seven, eight, nine
down front, 10 and Lt. Other Kayla Canine,
that's 11 if you ever want to know
how dentists number their teeth,
it starts on your upper right jaw,
the wisdom tooth.
That's number one as the first
round draft pick. All right?
Okay.
And you got two,
three.
Those are your other molas that you're
going to keep unless you're a fucking
caveman. You got two sets of
fucking wisdom teeth and I don't,
I don't know how to number of
those. So that's three, four.
Then you've got those other two ones.
I forget what those are called, right?
All right. One, two, three, four, five.
And then you have the k nine to six,
seven, eight, nine a down front, right?
Vip Seating,
10 and then 11 you can do the rest.
And then the weird thing is,
is when you go down below, you don't
start back on the right side of the Dji.
You go straight down.
So you count from the upper right wisdom
tooth all the way over to the upper
left wisdom tooth.
And then you drop straight down,
lower collective settling
with power down to a,
what is it? Uh, that would
be 33, I guess, right?
Not 33. You got 32 fucking teeth.
33 I can't fucking remember.
It's a long time ago. Composite and
all of that shit. Pouring up models
I've had,
I've lived a lot of lives.
I could have said I could assist
on a fucking dental procedure.
I still know how to take x rays. I
could pour up a fucking model, you know,
sold newspaper subscriptions.
I had a paper route and unloaded trucks.
I can drive a forklift.
Well, I'll tell you,
I'm sorry. Anyways. All right,
we're winding down here.
So there's your little half hour. Isn't
this nice? You got a fucking paycheck.
What are you gonna do with that money
by the way? Oh, you're dumb. Fuck.
Are you going to blow it?
Are you going to use it to get yourself
in even more debt or are you going to
use it to free yourself?
That's the one thing you got to learn.
You have to learn about money.
Okay?
It's a bunch of people bitching about
rich people and who's kidding who their
cons. All right, they got their foot
on your throat, the back of your neck,
whatever you want to fucking say. But
that doesn't mean it's got to stay there.
You can wiggle out, you can wiggle out
and they'll let you go because it's like,
I dunno,
it's like just imagine grabbing a whole
pile of gold in the center of a table
and as he polling it towards you,
some of them fall off.
You don't give a fuck as long
as you get the line share.
So those are like people that they
want to just keep underneath them self,
a few fall off, they don't give
a fuck. So your goal in life,
if you're poor and middle class is to
be one of those coins that rolls off the
fucking table to freedom.
And how you got to do that is got to
make your money work for yourself.
All right?
That's what you have to do.
All these fucking jerk offs going
out lease and BMWs and buying stupid
sunglasses and that type of shit. And
they don't get a pot to piss in morons.
Okay.
I guess I understand it on some
level you're trying to attack,
attract a better look and woman,
right?
Cause what kind of woman who's room
even remotely good looking is going to
settle for some broke asshole.
Why would you,
you know,
they have dreams,
they have dreams of spending your money.
Um,
but uh,
okay.
Oh look at that car. Jesus
Christ. I fucking love cars,
man. The old school ones,
I'm still searching for the one that
I know the model and I'm getting,
I'm not going to tell you what year,
but you know,
I'm a Ford Guy and I also like sedans.
I'm going for a mid 60 Ford sedan that's
going to look like the year of it on
top and underneath is going to be
fucking 2015 right down to the chassis.
MMM.
It's going to be a five speed and the
biggest fucking engine I can stick under
that fucking hood and
that's going to be a,
that's going to be my car. I'll have
my old truck, I'll have my car and,
and what the fuck else do you need?
Right?
At least fucking morons going out and
buying it. And I don't know. What do you,
what are you doing? Huh? With your
selfie stick? You dumb cunt. Oh God.
You know what I'm saying?
Fucking kills me that I didn't come up
with a selfie stick that was just right
there waiting to be invented,
waiting to be invented. Right?
And then you take it to those shark
tank, fucking constant. A gun.
It's a great idea. Tell you
what, we're going to own it.
And I will take the patent and then the
money will go to us and I will tell you
what we made.
That's how business works.
It's legalized stealing.
It's why you got to get out from
underneath that soul if you are
okay,
if you are in debt, you got to get
yourself out of it. You know what I mean?
Just fucking baby step you
fucking way out of it. Um,
and then the great thing,
then you start saving up money
and then you have freedom.
You know,
God forbid if you lose your fucking job,
you know,
you got some fucking money or whatever.
I don't know.
I don't even know what I'm saying.
Even know how to intelligently say
what I'm saying and I'm actually right.
How fucking pathetic is that?
All right,
well there's your little half
hour fucking riffing, you know,
just to brighten your day. Add a little
more sunshine to your payday, right?
Do me a favor. Don't
blow all of it. Alright.
Take some of that money and knocked
down the principal on something.
Pay a little extra on your
car. Do something. All right.
Do something to get yourself out
of that fucking, that prison, man.
You can't fucking do that to you.
Suffer, right? You only got one life.
He should be living it
in a happy way with,
it's not some fucking asshole with his
foot in the back of your fucking neck,
which is how the thing is set up.
All right? So they go, I don't
know if that was motivational.
I Dunno what? Oh yes. Like party to t two
days is fucking week. So I only ended up,
I have to all the fucking word
guy did all I did. I lost
one God damn pound. I'm 179.
I told you I'm going to be down
to one 62 by my birthday in June.
I have to somehow do that and uh,
somehow do that when going to the gym
fucking five out of seven days only makes
you lose one pound cause you fucking
drank like an asshole on two of,
I can't fucking believe it.
You know what it was?
I got a Burrito and I shouldn't
have got the case of deer,
but I was drunk and I got that too.
And I'm just shoveling it in my fucking
pie hole. Just guy, you know, I'm only,
I'm just going to be bad today. I'll
just be bad. The only today. Yeah, no,
it doesn't work that way. I swear to God,
my stomach. I, you know what I look like?
I look like I could do that shot.
Demi Moore did. Dimi let me,
she did that shot when she got pregnant,
she covered a fucking titty and then was
holding where the baby was instead of a
baby. It's a fucking Burrito
and some Miller high life. Um,
all right. That's the, um, this is
just me checking in. That's all.
I'm just checking in on you.
I don't know what this is the Thursday,
Monday morning podcast d uh oh,
Billy's back again again,
again, again. Podcasts. I don't know what
the fuck to call it. I don't give a shit.
All right. Um, what else?
That's what this is. And uh,
that's what this was and that's it.
All right.
You enjoy your fucking weekend.
Hi.
Okay.
You go out there and you talk to some
broads. You get down to buy you a drink.
You turn the fucking tables. Uh, all
right. That's it. Go fuck yourselves.
I'll talk to you on Monday.
All right.
I don't know why I just
fucking ended the podcast.
I ended up the live part of it, not
the live, then the new part of it.
Now we're going to go into some classic
clips from a bygone era in podcasting
when I was only one of 43,000
comedians that had a podcast, uh,
as opposed to now where there's 7 million,
859,000 podcasts.
All right. And Joy, these
classic clips. And, um,
and that is all I'll
talk to you on Monday.
Oh,
tell you a fantastic fucking
story last night. All right.
So I'm working on the road with
Joe to Rosa Young Joe de Rosa,
the fucking teen idol from the opiate
Anthony Show who was actually going to be
on the cover of teen beat this,
uh, this month. And it's actually,
I saw a little bit of the photo shoot.
He's doing a tribute to
Annette Funicello and, uh,
that other fucking guy was it Tony Curtis
who the fuck she used to make those
beach movies with or whatever.
Joe's going to be there shirtless,
holding a surfboard, and now I tell you
he needs, he's never looks sexier. Um,
so, uh, the fuck am I
talking about? I Christ,
I don't even know anymore. Um, yeah.
So we go out last night, right?
We're doing the show is these two big
titted horse sitting in the front fucking
row. All right? So we're like,
Oh wow, look at these girls.
These girls would probably be fun,
right? And I'm going to relationship,
but you know, I like being the wing man.
You know, I love being the wing man.
I'd love it. I love talking shit.
The girls, I love hitting on girls.
I fucking do it all the time and then
I try to pawn them off to wherever the
fuck I am. And uh, you know, so I
don't have any goddamn guilt, you know?
So anyways,
so long story short,
we're talking to these broads and it's
clear that there's some sort of strippers.
I Dunno what the fucking deal is. Okay.
So we meet everybody from whatever,
I'm going to stop naming names here.
Okay. So a huge group of us from the show,
from the crowd and everything. We go
and we head out to this bar, right?
So
one of the strippers is cool,
the other one has a voice that could
literally crack a flat screen TV.
All right,
so the cool one shows up.
First she sits down, I'm like,
hey, how you doing? You know,
I like at the end of the week I hang out,
buy a round for some people, you know,
I'm in a great mood. I had a good
time, I'm on my way home, you know,
up by some people, some drinks. So I say
to her, hey, what would you like to drink?
She's like, I'll have a fact and gag at
Google, one of those fucking chick drinks.
So you know, so I get her a drink, I buy
young Joe to Rosa fucking drink, right?
Everybody's having a good time.
And then this other person shows up who
I knew and she was a real nice person.
I said, hey, what do you want
for a drink? And she was like,
I'll get a vodka red bull,
right?
I got my $20 bill out and then this
trip is like, yeah, make it too right.
And I was like, wait, what?
What do you mean make it to you
haven't even finished your first make.
Don't be ordering off my money. You've
finished your first one there, young lady.
All right. Stand the fuck down. You're
not working right now. Not some dip shit.
Getting a fucking lap dance.
All right.
Finish your fucking milk and
cookies first. So needless to say,
the conversation cooled
between the two of us.
But I didn't give a fuck man. I was
having a good time, but whatever.
It was still kind of, you know,
whatever, just talking shit.
We were talking sports. The bartender
was cool, you know, we, everything,
everything was going great.
So which Shell and out and all
of a sudden this fucking, uh,
the other fucking stripper girl
shows up out and was so fucking,
it was just such classic female shit.
She's got a tits hanging out.
She's got the fuck me pumps on
and she comes up, she goes, hey.
And she sees a friend with the drink and
she knows God damn well she didn't pay
for it. So she looks over at
me as less. It's like, well,
that must've been the SAP.
Who fucking bought it. Right? So she
looks at me, she goes, hey, Belle.
And she's like, she's like,
what are you drinking? Right?
And I know what she's doing.
I'm like,
I'm drinking one of those Sam
Adams October fest that is,
leave it like that.
Nice and awkward. Right?
Cause I know what she's trying
to get a drink out of me. Right?
So she doesn't know what to
do. She's like, ah, is it good?
I'm like, why? Yes. Yes
it is. At this point,
Derosa knows what's going on. I don't
know that he knows what's going on.
So she looks at me like, okay, well
evidently he's not buying any more drinks.
And then she looks at Jo,
she's like, uh, hey Joe,
what are you tracking? And Joe gets
his shitty and grin on his face.
He goes, why? I'm drinking a bud light.
Why would you like to buy me one?
And she didn't know what the fuck to
do. She's like, ah, I, yeah, I guess.
He goes,
you know what?
I think you should buy me a bud light and
then you should by my good friend bill
burr here, another October 1st.
What do you think about that?
And at that point I'm fucking
dying laughing. The other
stripper girl next to me,
she's laughing her ass off
cause she knows what happened.
And then the fucking girl with this
screechy voice is sitting there.
She doesn't know what the fuck to do.
We fucking nailed it.
And then wait and then like she's going,
she didn't know what to do.
And Joe's just going,
yes,
why don't you pay it forward for all the
drinks that guys have boughten you and
that you've drank. And then immediately
turned around and fucking walked away.
Why don't you for once by a Goddamn by
a couple of drinks for a couple of guys
and she's, I said, you put it
that way. Fine, I will. I will.
I'll buy you a fucking drink. And
Joe's like, how bout some shots too?
And she just was, I don't know what
her fucking ego was that she goes fine,
I'll fucking do that too.
So we actually got to strip it up
by his two beers and two shots.
So we're filling like the kings of the
world and then all of a sudden we found
out from this waitress that on the slide
she tried to put it on a boyfriends
fucking credit card.
What a scumbag. Right?
So we bust her and we all week and when
there's big commotion breaks out right
before the fucking bar,
chances are about ready to
swipe the boyfriend's credit
card. We were like, Joe,
chill, Joe Ed. I just like
an officer and a gentleman.
I got nowhere else to go.
Right?
We get them to stop and they take out her
ATM and she had the fucking pay for it
and it was a done deal.
We had two drinks,
two shots from that fucking person who
you know has never paid for a drink since
she got her fucking tits. Right.
And this was the best part.
The second we got our drinks,
we set thanks a lot.
And we both got up and we walked away.
Oh, it's tremendous. Tremendous.
It was the best night ever.
And I'm just standing there drinking my
drink like 20 minutes later I'm milking
it for all it's worth.
This free fucking beer that has
stripper bought me was awesome.
Brian and Joe was talking to some
girl across the way. He looked at it.
All of a sudden I just yelled over. I go,
Joe, and he looks over at me and I did.
I did the Robert De Niro line from
when he was eating the Joe Pesci,
his mom right before they hacked up. Billy
Batts, right. He looks up and he's like,
what's up? And I just pointed at the beer
the stripper had bought and I just went
delicious. Delicious.
And that was my evening.
Yeah, it was fucking
raining out. This one,
one thing I've learned that when you go
to a football game and you're dealing
with the elements,
this is the more of a douchebag you
look like the warmer you're going to be.
All right. I saw the rain
and I said, fuck this,
and we went right to Dick's sporting goods
and I'm like, I'm buying that fucking,
I'm going to buy a raincoat with
the matching rank. Coach slacks,
I don't give a fuck.
I bought a pair of a wool
socks and I was good to go.
So I'm with Versie and you know they only
had like two rank coats left and they
were the exact same color.
This fucking great slush puppy purple.
So we both have matching
extra large fucking,
we got the jacket and the pants like we're
working at a fucking airport and what
Quinn we're bringing in the fucking soul
plane, right? That was a purple airplane,
right. That's what we look like.
So we show up to the game, right?
Neither one of us has comfortable because
neither one of us is a jets or a bills
fan. So we're in enemy territory and
a, it's fucking drizzling and out.
It's fucking cold. So I proceed to put
on this Barney the dinosaur outfit,
right? And right off the
bat, Versie starts Punkin out
gone, man. I'm just going to,
I'm just going to wear that.
I'm just going to wear the top.
I'm just going to weigh the top.
Trying to act like it's not raining
out that bad. The reality is,
is he didn't want to go through the
hazing that he would have to if the two of
us walked in with our purple on
Purple Fucking Rain Coats Times too.
We would have got a ton of shit and
I was prepared to take it. I had an,
I had a whole fucking silly walk
I was going to be doing. I had,
I don't give a fuck. So
he punked out. So, uh,
we ended up walking in and
put my head's cold, right?
All I have is a baseball cap on. So
I'm like, fuck, I got to buy a hat.
Can I buy a bills? Who gives a
fuck? They were in last place,
mangled by a bill's hat, and then I saw
this, this one with a Patriot logo on it.
I said, fuck it. I'll get that. Once
I put that one on, I'm nice and warm.
We go to, we'll call,
we pick up our tickets.
We go into that high school football
stadium that they have out there that I
actually love,
looks like an old school football stadium.
You know what I like about
that football stadium?
That's about the size of a football
stadium that holds real fans.
You know what I mean?
All these,
these new ones that hold
like a 100,000 fucking pants,
all the bandwagon shitheads.
You know when you're all in for the
real fucking fans show up or oh in three
right? So he walked into the Goddamn
stadium. We love in life, right?
I'm already laughing at Versie cause
I know damn well what's going happen.
He's going to walk out there.
There's going to be some shitty little
plastic seat that's going to be covered
in fucking water and the only way he's
going to be able to absorb it is through
his God damn jeans and his fucking bbds
and he's going to be sitting there with
a wrinkled up nuts sack that's going
to be getting a hyperthermia by second
quarter. Why do I know this?
Because I've been there.
So we'd get a couple of bears.
We get this fucking beef on a stick
or whatever the fuck they call it.
We're good to go. We
go in there, sit down.
He sits basically down in
a fucking puddle. He tried
to stick a newspaper down,
which is very absorbent. And uh, I dunno,
we sat there and I had hoped for about
eight seconds in that game and the jets
came down and just fucking Jew.
They just kicked the shit out of him.
Christ.
They kicked ass shit out of 'em and uh,
and it was just over them.
So we'd, so immediately,
our solution is just to start drinking
the way we drank at the masters.
We're like, fuck it, let's, let's,
let's get going here. Right?
So we'll make a trip after trip and all
of a sudden I gotta take a Piss, right?
So I go and I'm standing in
line and all of a sudden this,
this fucking six foot five
goofy looking jackass,
one of those guys who's like six foot
five, but you still think he can take him,
cause he's just covered in baby fat.
You know,
he's got a couple of whiskers on his
chin and his cheeks a rosier than saint
nick. Right? And he's got this
Jersey on and this big stupid,
I'm a buffalo bills fan with the
horns on it and stuff. You know,
he's the wacky guy so I'm not
even thinking shit. Right.
This is bill's jets. I don't have a dog
in this fight. I'm not talking any shit.
I'm fine.
I forgot I was wearing my patriots
hat and all of a sudden this big goofy
jackass starts going [inaudible]
patriots fan. He liked the rats.
We got to ran away the rats. He likes
to fucking read this shit, right?
And I'm like, yeah, yeah, no,
whatever. He starts giving me Shit,
I start giving him shit back then the
weirdest fucking thing happened. I,
by the time I get in to
the actual men's room,
I've talked,
I've given these people so much fucking
shit that actually there's bills and
jets fans at a bills and jets game.
They're playing each other.
They stopped giving each other shit
and they teamed up together and started
giving me shit. Right. And then I just
said, I don't know what I was thinking.
I felt like I was on stage cause it was
like a crowd. I wasn't thinking like, Hey,
you know what,
Bill,
you really haven't had a fight outside
of your family since maybe playing
fucking street hockey in the sixth grade.
I didn't give a fuck.
I'm in a goddamn bathroom waiting to take
a piss in a goddamn trough, by the way.
And uh,
and then they just started giving a fuck.
And this one dude on top where he sucks
Dick, he shucks dig and he's like,
miming it like ridiculously wealth.
So I'm like, yeah, you're nobody.
You do that real wealth. Because I learned
it by watching Tom Brady. I'm like,
oh yeah, do you rent that porno? You
fucking fag gets a little uglier,
gets a little uglier than this other dude.
What the fuck did I came up with the
hell he was saying to me and I just said,
look, I'm sorry you guys have
never won a super bowl. You know?
Then the jets fan pipes in.
I go,
do you realize the last time
you guys won a Superbowl,
Charlie Chaplin was still alive?
Do you understand that?
Do you know what cars look like the
last time you won? You fucking morons.
And then, uh, then this other guy got
up until we've won three super bowls.
I'm sorry. Right. And then the guy goes,
well, you didn't play in the games. I go,
neither did you. Then he's just standing
there with this dumb look on his face.
Like, oh, that's where I keep staring
forward. You got nothing for getting that.
I don't know how to fight.
So all of a sudden it's my turn to pes.
I take my dick out,
I'm ready to Piss.
And one of these fucking pussies pushed
me in the back hoping that I was pissing
at the time. Fortunately I
wasn't. So I turn around,
I put my dick away cause I'm
a gentleman. I said, I go,
is that how you guys do
it out here? Really? I go,
which one you guys push me like I'm
gonna fuck, I'm fucking Jackie Chan.
And for some reason none
of them said anything.
I don't know if it was my purple on
purple rain coat or the look of fire in my
eye, but I'm a fucking 42 year old,
balding redhead talking shit in there.
And none of them said anything.
So now it's kind of funny to me.
I felt like I was in like the world
series of poker and I went all in and I,
and I didn't have a hand whatsoever,
so I don't know who the fuck pushed me,
but that's what I mean. Come on.
Bitchy is moving the fucking week.
How do you do that? How do
you do that? How do you,
how do you push another man when he's got
his Goddamn Dick out trying to piss it
to a fucking trough? How do you get lower
than that? Do you guys have any ideas?
How do you get lower than that? So then
after none of them sending anything,
I go back and I started taking a piss
and then that other dude who was miming
somebody's sucking a dick unbelievably
well right next to me were one of those
stupid hats that has the toggles on this
side and he's still trying to give me
shit and I'm going to haggle,
go fuck yourself.
And then he just starts
screaming over and over again.
Are you looking at my deck?
Are you looking at my
dick like maniacally,
like five times.
I just sort of stared at him like why
do you keep going this, this gay angle?
Like why is there always a,
I dunno.
I think he was one of those guys.
He was kind of in the closet and then uh,
so he just goes to football games and
he gets really drunk trying to just kill
it. The families, I think he
liked me. It's what I'm saying.
So if he's listening to
this, I'm sorry. Uh, I'm,
I'm spoken for you fucking pants and
you fucking believe that first of all,
what's wrong with me? I really
replay it, all of that in my head.
Cause once I got out of there I was like,
I really started thinking like, what,
what did you think you
were going to do in there?
They're not Clint Eastwood yet saying
things. Clint Eastwood would say, what?
What the fuck is wrong with you dude?
Like I don't know if I've
said this before in a podcast,
a public bathroom is the worst fucking
place to ever get into a fight.
There is nothing soft.
This,
everything is porcelain pipes,
that concrete floor and then
it has a mist of piss and shit.
It's just the fucking, it's the
worst. It's the worst place ever,
you know, not to mention it usually
starts evidently when one person as begun,
the pissing process.
Okay.
So, uh, you know, older, little bit wiser.
So then I'm standing in line to go get
some more alcohol cause God knows that's
what you need after an incident like that.
And I was just kind of just sitting
there thinking like, all right,
now how should I have played that?
It w it should have ended when the
dude with the water buffalo hat started
giving me shit. What I should've
done was rolled with it. I should,
you liked the patriots. I
shouldn't be like, hey, you know,
you guys scored 30 on his last week,
man. You guys look great man. I,
I bet the jets, I mean,
I bet against the jets.
I hope you guys should have just ended
it with that and did it. I, I should,
uh,
I should have extended an olive branch.
That's what I should've
done in the future.
That's what the fuck I'm
going to do because, uh,
that was a, a, that was a potentially
ugly situation. But fortunately,
um, I think the people who
are doing it, you know,
had jobs and no one wanted to get sued
and no one was willing to take it to that
level. Uh, and when I say fortunately,
I mean for me and my face,
okay,
oh,
do you know how bad that would have been
to get stomped in that fucking purple
on purple rain coat laying there
with my dirty fucking patriots hat
and my team wasn't even playing.
I would have lost the lawsuit.
They would have been like, let me get
this straight. You're a patriots fan.
You are a patriots hat to a bill's jets
game and you somehow managed to get the
shit kicked out of you. What
the fuck did you say? You know,
that's one of the great things about
being a guy is you actually have to take
responsibility for your, for your
actions. See, a woman would be like,
there's no excuse. There's no
reason. I don't care what happened.
You don't hit a girl, which is
true. You don't hit a fucking girl,
but there's no learning in that.
There's no lesson. You know?
Even my best friends would have been like,
yeah, those guys are fucking assholes.
And the button, you know, that would've
been an awkward pause and it to be like,
dude,
what the fuck he talking shit by
yourself at a gay when your team isn't
even fucking play. What's wrong with you?
You're 42 years old,
get your shit to you.
And they would have been right.