Yeah.
Hey, how are you? Um, it's the, uh,
Thursday afternoon,
Monday morning podcast just before
Friday and just checking in.
Okay.
How's your week going? [inaudible]
you know, you know something.
I got this dumb ass show on TV in the
background with some chick fucking who's
using way too much moose in her hair
and she's got like nine zillion fucking
dollars in debt.
Just got to dumb parents who also use a
bunch of fucking moose in their hair and
somehow she's so out of control.
They have to go on television to
Friday to try it near check podcast.
I know this, the show is
crazy. Where she, she,
everybody that were Maria. Yes. Romaji
job. Let's talk about this brought here.
She is so much most in her hair. She
looks shit faced even when she's sober.
It's a show here in Montreal,
Canada, maybe monorail,
ballsy called Princess.
Some of them off the
ends are dollar signs.
And I guess the whole premise of this
show is to get these young spoiled women
who are just
out of control with their spending to
get a wake up call and learn how to be
responsible. But she has like
boozy eyes to saying her dad,
she has a dad the same. Yes.
Booze eyes. They advertise,
they have like bedroom eyes.
They're kind of like look like they
about to go to sleep heavy eyebrows.
I sound terrible right now.
I think cause I,
you didn't have any booze last night.
You somehow just a guy,
I didn't have a cigar but I had
drank booze and I sound like,
like you drank some booze. Yeah,
we'll look at, now she's back out.
We got this on the background. She's
sitting there, she's going out to the,
I don't understand people that
lose control of their kids.
It's like you're taller than them,
you know, you just intimidate them.
Well she's not a child. She's like 20
something years old. So yeah, but the,
it never should have
got to this. Yeah. Well,
that's the whole premise of this show
and now she's going to like do chores and
earn her keep and all that kind of
stuff and she's going to learn a lesson.
It's just, it's TV, it's fake.
I'll turn it off. I understand.
I understand it's that,
but you can't tell me that this is not
actually people that lose control of
their kids. Yeah, she is a fucking mess.
You can't marry that mass. She's
unmarriageable with that fucking hair.
She looks like she fucking
Moses it with ges. Oh,
she just looks like a total party whore.
There's not one guy.
It's going to look at
that other than the only,
his only thought is going
to be like a fuck that.
That's all you're gonna do with that.
Well that's all she's
concerned about right now.
So what do you think party on Wayne?
What do you think about maybe
that's all she's confirmed forward.
She's still fucking dope.
Yeah.
So yeah, a lot of young
girls are like, go wow,
your party it up. Yolo and whatnot. We,
you stopped seeing this.
I don't see it on like on a regular basis.
Saying that I don't say right.
The Instagram pinched to grandma
and yet too fucking old,
let's say Yolo,
I'm too old to be participating
in the call. You don't know.
It helps my act because you know all
the pop stars Shit. What was, you know,
I was surprised.
I knew that Taylor swift song last night.
I was very surprised that they tell me
the name of it and I'll sing it shaken up.
Oh yeah. Players gonna play, play,
play, play and somebody is gonna hate.
Shake it off. Shake it up. Shake
it. Yeah. Cause you play that shit.
I fucking hate that song.
Play that shit.
Is that literally written
on a piece of paper?
Players want to play because she go dot,
dot, dot. Or she really right. Play, play,
play, play, play of
whenever. I'm sure she did.
I got creeped out by her. I always
think she looks like a, like a,
like a little fucking sexed
up mere cat to me. Jeremy.
That's like up on her hind
legs looking at the whole,
you know, she looks very, I think she's
tall and then she wears heels and so yeah,
she's very,
I just remember on 60 minutes and alert
when we were watching her and the little
girls would be screaming in the upper
deck and she would look up there and she
would just sort of mouth,
oh my God.
It was the fucking phoniest. I think
even if I was sick, I'd be like,
this a, this lady's fake. This is fake.
She's not blown away by this right now.
She's just trying to,
maybe if you were that far,
what am I at six years old with
a sport coat on up in here,
like I know what's going on.
I probably be like,
why is my little six year old Dick?
Sorry.
Listen,
it's not something that you can relate to,
but the first time you're a little
kid and had fucking stands up,
you don't understand. When I first
understood that it was related to sex,
I was in a fucking tree.
Fort Wright and this kid had stolen
playboys from his dad is the 70s we didn't
have the internet like these kids, we
could actually watch video of real people,
fucking poor kids. So he, we were
looking at the things, right.
We were sitting there,
you know,
in the tree fort and there was like five
of us looking at him and this other kid
fucking balled up his fist and punched
me in the Dick. And I was like, oh,
that's when I realized like,
oh,
so what's going on with my dick is
going on with everybody else's Dick.
And that's what happens when
you look at naked women. What's,
that's how I learned,
cause somebody punched me right in
my fucking little hard on. Ouch.
Yeah. I take strong. It took it, took it
on. The Chin was rolled out the round.
God got back to the corner, you know,
through some water on it.
Anyways.
Yeah. So I know a little bit
about pop culture. Who are
some of the other, uh, uh,
ladies of a, or maybe
guys, I know a few people.
You do.
Do you know who one direction
is one direction? The, the,
the, uh, the, the Biebers, right. They
all got the Bieber, the Bieber hair,
and they all face the crowd.
When they sing one direction,
they,
they send it out as a weird name for
them to be called because I assume the
whole thing is like,
we only go in one direction and that's up,
but they should call it same direction
because when that band flop, sorry,
that was really bad. Um, I'm not
offering you, but this or not.
I'm fucking crushing it.
People are liking.
I just sank Taylor swift into first
fucking six minutes. It's no what,
what? Um, what's one of the
songs they sing up, but I know
they have a song, I think call you.
You don't know. You're beautiful.
What they, you don't know.
You're beautiful. That's
what makes you beautiful.
Or something like that.
Despite the fact she robbed me.
And you calves are rarely fat. I
Dunno. I have to be honest with you.
I don't fuck freckles,
but it's not about all that.
That's pretty close. Sad.
You're fucking beautiful.
And I'd let you suck my Dick
in the back of tour bus.
You got to go out the window.
You know what the other band mates to
see it. Oh my God. He's thinking to me
some boy band lyrics right there. Yeah.
Did you say hanging tough earlier?
Yeah. Shout out to Joe.
Joey Mack from the heat,
from the um, the he yay.
My favorite new kid.
Joe Mac. But really what were your options
you had to do with the mosquito face,
right? What do you mean
mosquito fan? Yeah, the other
guy who wasn't mark Walberg
and I got the other guy who looked
like the guy with the mosquitoes.
They were brothers. And I know
you're talking about, I like Donny.
Give me a fucking break. I gotta make
it funny. Donny dated Halle Berry.
Are you kidding me? Like Donnie
was crushing it back in the day.
When did he date her? Well, when he
was on the cop show, like in the 80s,
maybe early nineties, she
was like 14. She wasn't,
there was options for every girl
with that band yet. Tough guy. Donny,
Donny. And then you had Jordan his
sang in that crazy false that, oh,
with the dark hair. Right. And
then you had the brothers. Dot.
Think I'm combining them with like
fucking one of those other bands like Oh,
town or, uh, why do you keep bringing up
old town? I feel like I heard you say,
oh Tom, last night during your show, did
you say, oh, town during your ear bit.
Hey, it's my fuck. [inaudible]
lady. I remember. No, but a flash.
It was a boy band. They were, well they
were called. I was the guy with the,
he had this synchronized
tattoos. Yeah. Yes, exactly.
I want to on that side.
Then later on he shot heroin
in the same vein on both sides.
And then he was on the Rehab show.
Steven Adler. Yeah. Wait, what's he,
oh, was he in celebrity rehab?
Well anyway, yes. He was kind of,
they were kind of a boy band ish. I think
you can tell by this podcast that yes,
there is a presidential
election coming up.
I love how much you're getting
annoyed by Donald Trump.
This guy's the most entertaining thing.
That's ever since other than that fat
so that they had up here in Toronto and
only annoyed because you were the one
that was trying to like get me to prove to
you that other people thought that
Donald Trump was an asshole long,
long ago and you were like, prove
it. Prove it. What are your sources?
All that night I was hammered
sores that came up did before we,
I gave up drinking.
I was fucking hammered and I watched one
of his speeches and I wanted to hear it
because it was a great piece of comedy
and you will fucking kill that guy.
I can't believe you said that.
Like this guy's actually
going to become president.
Like it's this as he's like the fucking
guy the first week on American idol who
can't fucking sing. It's just funny
to watch. I love what we gave out.
That person's phone number, like a
seventh grade girl fucking deal with that.
Do you think he fucking, he did a little
flip to his cowlick after he did that?
Yeah.
He's just an asshole though.
John Mccain is a war hero
because he got caught.
He got captured
fucking terrible thing to say.
I know it's terrible.
I know,
but his above his head. Can I tell
you this right now? And you say he's,
he's a hero because he got captured.
I know, but here's the thing you do.
You know who has the right to
get offended by that John Mccain,
why can't I be offended?
Because you never went to war.
And that means that because I
didn't have that direct experience.
I can't have a strong reaction to you can,
you know you cannot be offended.
You shouldn't be offended by,
you can be,
you can sit there and have
empathy and be like, wow,
that's a really fucked up
thing to say to John Mccain,
but to sit there and literally
get offended like he owes
you a fucking apology.
You weren't net bamboo fucking cage.
Is that what it's about being about
being offended about something like you
shouldn't be offended because
you didn't experience it.
You can just feel like,
I don't understand that rationale.
You feel like if someone's offended
by something, they're taking it super,
super personally.
Look,
I can sit there and I could watch that
and realize what he said was completely
fucked up.
I can see why it's so fucking fun.
The fact that he's going to offend so
many people by saying it makes it fucking
hilarious. Watching his reaction to people
being offended is fucking hilarious.
But the people that went through it,
they're the ones who are truly fucking
affect. Like how would, uh, it's,
it's insulting to John Mccain for me
to get fucking offended by it. Like,
oh, it hurt. Did it hurt your bill
is you sit there and your pj's,
you fucking marry here.
Just coming at it from light,
that comedian perspective though.
You guys have this whole thing about
people being offended. That's what,
that's all I'm not,
I can be offended by what Trump says
and not have been in the war myself.
I can be and not, not that. Like
I'm offended for John Mccain.
He can obviously fend for himself. The
man, I think the guy can fend for himself.
He was fucking tortured. He didn't
break. But I can be like I'm,
I'm fucking offended by that.
As what other people who
have any respect for what?
John Mccain.
Why don't you just say I don't approve
what you said Donald and you need to grow
up and I feel like I could say that to
you cause you don't have my cell phone
because I can be offended if I want to.
I don't know why you were saying that.
I can't be offended by it.
I said it's the wrong wording.
I think it's childish for you to
be offended. All right. I think,
I think you just want to, you want
to be part of the group like yeah,
that affected me too. Yeah,
exactly where I'm coming from.
I'm all about being a part of the group
offended this week about something. Yep.
That's my emo.
Why do you hate me?
They donate it. Do you always,
you know what you have to,
you know what shit deal is near look
deal is you always got to take me down a
fucking notch. You just got
to make sure I get, what am I,
what am I doing over here? And you, Oh,
you're telling me I can't be offended.
I guess that's kind of an asshole move.
I wish you wouldn't be offended.
I wish people who didn't go to war. I,
look, if you've got to fucking relative,
that's in the military. I'll give you that
too. But people like me and I do. I do.
Oh good.
My Dad was in the fucking navy.
I mean I don't fucking sit
there acting like, you know,
I have some direct connection with
the military. I'm a softie. All right.
I never got a deferment,
but I would have second,
I was out there marching in
the sun. I can't take, oh,
pick up your fucking cover pile.
And that's what they were saying that
he like a avoided the draft like five
times. I hate when they
say that about rich people.
What do you mean why they avoided
the draft? Yeah, of course they did.
Of course they did.
They did exactly what you would have
done if you had hundreds of millions of
fucking dollars,
you wouldn't have gone.
I love all these fucking people that
act like if they were sitting there,
you know with a Butler that they'd fucking
join the marines and be on the front
lines and they would have fought.
They wouldn't have,
you would have done the same
fucking thing that they did.
I would think that he knows. Some people
like they, they volunteer for that Shit.
Even today they're like,
I want to go and you know something.
Those people are so few and far between
that they make movies about them.
And I'm not talking about people that
volunteer. I'm not talking about that.
I'm talking about somebody that's
sitting there with a golden spoon
in their mouth. Sorry Rick Flair.
He goes pointing out my mouth.
If you're fucking dude. No, I'm trying.
You may me one fucking blue
blooded kid sitting there.
He doesn't even have a trained set.
He has like a real train that goes
around his fucking house. Rich. Yeah.
Did he have a real train? Oh No. Not
a silver spoons. Silver spoons. Maybe.
It wasn't like a real as rain,
but it was a train that went around.
Speaking of trains. Quit derailing
this idea over here. Oh Jesus.
Um,
someone like someone like that,
like came from a really fucking rich
family in my lifetime. Yeah. You know,
maybe if you want to go back to
the Kennedys, but even then though,
you know they were fucking
bootleggers that right. So they,
as much as they tried to be all
hoity toity they were filthy near,
there's a bunch of animals.
You will fucking everything that
moved down there. You know La. Yah.
I would like to have sex with her next.
Uh Huh.
What did you just cover
the microphone for?
Like I have some sort of connection to
that family. What are you talking about?
Oh nevermind.
I'll tell you afterward.
Okay.
I, I don't give a shit. Alright.
It's podcast is not about,
yeah,
it's not about fucking caring
about people's feelings.
They need it. Do me a favor,
shake it off, shake it off.
I really can't believe you know that
song I had because I never played it for
you. Well, I don't understand
tailored does it? No.
Barely anybody pop culturally,
like what's a lie towards me the other
week they'll remember how we were talking
about how bills interpretation of
gone girl was. Where'd the bitch ago?
Like that's just kind of how,
but I knew,
I knew that was wrong and I knew it
was enough in the right direction.
One direction did that. Fuck you know
what I was talking about. All right,
you're going to quiz me on pop
culture right after these messages.
Now hang on one second
here. I have to, uh,
I get to make sure I do this right.
This is gonna Cause I need your microphone
here. Gimme your microphone here.
That's right.
Whenever I grabbed the other microphone,
that means it's time.
Oh fuck you with the fucking edge.
You son of a bitch.
Why don't people are gonna realize
you've got to get your message in or five
seconds if you're gonna fucking anyways,
so here we go.
It's time.
Yeah.
For another video. Doorbell read.
Why isn't the fucking music working?
Can you please play?
Oh, it's not going to play when I
got the fucking thing going here.
You fucking suck.
Okay.
Why?
I want to do that because it's the
fucking mini iPad and it doesn't have that
ability. Ah, these fucking nerds, man.
Well, when were they ever have just,
that just kills my whole fucking thing.
I got to read the video doorbell with
the sad music underneath the door.
That doesn't count. Well,
hang on a second. What is
that come? It doesn't work.
It's sad.
Anna Mae Music collection and
evidently it's a masterpiece.
How did you find this? I just,
I just look up sad music.
All right, I'll read the other one while
you get the sad music going. All right.
Mile Iq, Iq, everybody. Uh,
driving for work is a double edge sword.
Okay.
A, somebody punched me in my sword
when I was looking at playboys.
Either you're spending too
much time tracking every
mile or you're guesstimating
and end up losing money and even then
your estimate falls about 20% short of
what you could be deducting.
Welcome to Mile Iq,
the gold standard in mileage tracking.
My Iq is the only mileage tractor that
detects logs and calculates your drive
for you automatically.
Mile Iq is easy to use and keeps all of
your drive securely stored in the cloud.
If you drive for work and you're
not counting every single mile,
then you're burning money every time
he turned on the ignition. Mile.
Iq does all the work letting you
focus on what's important. You know,
it's funny they'd said, I, they didn't
think that I understood the copy. Um,
are they correct? No, I'm getting this.
That's why they've got a five star rating
in both the Google play and the iTunes
APP store. Stop wasting time manually
tracking your miles and stop losing money.
You should be redeeming. Try Mile
Iq for free today by Texting Burb,
B U.
R r two eight nine eight zero zero
that's burr eight nine eight zero zero
all right.
That was mile Iq.
I guess I don't understand it.
I just kind of like a vision of you in
middle schools. They drive it for work.
It's a short class and just like this is
the seeds being planted right there are
driving for work. All right. You're
a cab driver. You're a, you're a,
you're a taxi driver.
He'd drive a limo and he was
spending too much time track oh sins.
Rather than having to write it down.
The sink does it for you.
Then you can just cruise around, right?
Jesus. Six days on the road. You got it.
All right. Well there you
go. I over explained it then.
I guess everybody else understood it. Is
this the one? Sometimes I have to, yeah.
Okay. Hold on. Sad. Anna
Mae music masterpiece,
sat enemy music masterpiece. Take one.
Are you hold the microphone up to this.
Huh? [inaudible] cheese.
It's been a big goal.
Is that one of those ad you can't skip?
This is just going off the fucking rails.
They should only just,
you just make five second ads.
All right.
He turned it down a little bit.
Mike.
Hello again,
friends
and I'd like to take a moment to
talk to you and the ones who vote
video doorbell.
This is the sound of a package
being delivered, being bombed,
supposed to have a dog or
friends coming over to dinner,
but it's also the sound of
someone planning to rob you blind
each year. Over 95% of the home
break ins happened during the day.
You'd think the old people across
the street would say something,
but they have cataracts
in burglars.
Almost always start by ringing your
doorbell to see if someone's home before,
but what do they do after
you answer the door,
we'd take the lift their mascot up.
Sorry about that.
Don't you weren't going to be,
oh,
but for pillaging your possessions
with the ring video doorbell,
you can see and talk to anyone at
your door from anywhere in the world
using your smartphone
rings. Advanced motion
detection, alert shoe.
Even if someone doesn't ring the doorbell,
it's like caller id for your home.
Please share a personal story or how
this could happen to someone you love.
I know this guy, Scott, he
lives in Boise at once. I mean,
he was at work and someone rang his
doorbell and he wasn't home to answer.
They took his playstation.
They're
installing ring takes
minutes and, and it works
with either your current wiring
or built in rechargeable battery.
Put your mind at ease and protect your
home with video doorbell Time magazine
named one of the top 10 gadgets,
2014 how about inventions?
Can you,
can you bump it up to invention and
it's a nice little gadget. You get them
right now.
My listeners start fading it though my
listeners get ring video door bill for
only $174 that's $25 off the normal price.
Go to [inaudible] dot com slash burn
now protect your home and have peace of
mind with ring. Go to ring.com/birth
for only $25 for $25 off.
That's ring.com/burr.
Thank you
and God bless America.
I liked it. You brought it back. All
right, let's talk pop music here.
That is really sad music.
It is perfect. It's sad.
Anna Mae Music. All right,
what do you got here? Go ahead,
quiz me. I got, we've got another
six minutes here and you know,
a lot of people are loving the music
that comes on at the end of this.
Speaking of, uh, being up
to date and all that stuff,
their Yolo Instagram or Instagram or,
um,
everybody's giving me credit for
that cool music. Uh, it's not me.
It's a Mr Andrew Feminists,
uh, who, who, you know,
he's the one that puts together all this
shit. Andrew. Andy, you, what'd he say?
What'd he say?
They're [inaudible] big as an boy.
All right.
What do you got quite quiz me.
You got six minutes to stump the fucking,
can you name all the actresses that have
been cast in the new Ghostbusters film
directed by Paul Feig and go Leslie Jones.
Kristen wig. Uh, Emilio Estevez.
No, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait. Most of McCarthy, Bam.
And there's four of them.
Kate Mckinnon also from
Saturday night live.
All right, I got three out of four. It's
pretty damn good. There you go. Go ahead.
You're going to owe me an apology at the
end of this. Good. And apology for what?
For questioning my pop culture.
Uh, I'm do me a favor. Nini,
don't hate, hate, hate, hate.
What was the actual name of
the film that you called?
Um, uh, well shit,
now I can't remember Dracula and all the
last days of dragging your last days of
Dracula was actually called
interview with the vampire. Okay.
This is an Oldie, but no,
it's pop culture. Pop Culture.
It's now pop culture is happening
right now. It's constantly changing.
You got to give me 2015 shit.
Oh, I got to give you 2015. Yeah.
Cause all those other people, if you're
going to go back to fucking, you know,
old town and all of them. And those
are your references though. Yeah.
But what is the name of the film that
you called? Two whores in a pool.
Oh
fuck.
That was with the chick.
A Richardson that married a
Emilio's touching Charlie Sheen.
Denise Richards, right. Denise
Richards hoarded up in a pool.
Um, what's that movie called? Was
it Kevin Bacon? Was he in that?
He Bam. And then there was
the chick from party of five
and they took out the Tinny,
what was it called?
A chlorine clam.
Wild thing.
I know what you did in the shallow end.
Okay.
Wow.
All right.
Who has been carols with two good looking
women who has been cast as the new
Batman? Ben Affleck. Oh my God. The
whole nerd and universe flipped out.
I'm an old man.
I go on Facebook.
I will tell you that Batman mask it is
really hard to not look like a jerk off
and that thing that is
just not a flattering.
It's all he got to have the Ben Affleck,
jaw Clooney.
You have to have a fucking jaw.
You know would have been a great Batman
if he could have lost the gut with
sergeant slaughter. He had, he had
the quintessential fucking Batman Joe.
God's name is sergeant slaughter.
He's a veteran.
I bet he was offended by fucking John
Mccain who's been cast. John Mccain,
a Jared Leto who has been
cast as Harley Quinn.
I don't know who is Harley Quinn?
She's a character in the comic
books. I don't know. Superman.
Oh,
these are fucking obscure.
Do you know how loud and awful
the last one superman was?
I sat there watching that
fucking superman. This is what?
This is nerd shit. Nerds don't get
laid. That's not popular. Go go to the,
I thought you're going to do music.
Come on. Oh, music. Yeah, go ahead.
I think I did pretty good.
I think I did pretty good with the movies.
You gotta admit.
What are some of the songs and we
listened to when we were in Paris that you
like. It's just, it's just
sing it because that's, that's,
that's better than you trying to figure
out the names of it. I don't remember.
I'm the melody. The TDD. Oh,
I'd like to make money get turned.
I like to make money.
Get Dark. I like to make
money. Gay Turn. I got to walk.
Go during a bowl.
The work.
I got a white girl are her or you kept
like a whole bottle of Rosae when he just
fucking starts. Just keep saying
it up to the music goes in the end.
What's his name? Is that generic? Why
Mannequin Mannequin?
Does he spell it in a cool way?
In a graffiti type way?
Exactly.
Man is all capitalized and there's a k
in there and with the fucking Q with a
couple of dots over it. Not that, but
yeah, he spells out in a funky way.
Alright. Alright. I feel like
this is dying is you know why?
Because I actually did fucking great on
it. I did great on it. Well you know what,
I bring it down.
Bring it down for a second.
I want to thank you all for coming out
Thursday afternoon podcast. Um, anyways,
ear crowds in Montreal have been awesome.
Yes,
they happen and I'd been having a great
time during the goddamn comedy jam.
I had a good time. You can send that one
night. Yes I did. I played all right.
You've played really, really well. Yeah,
so I did and tonight you're going to
yeah, I got my last comedy jam. I'm doing
the Ron Bennington unmasked. Uh Huh.
And then I got on Mass Gilbert.
What's behind those freckles
and the freckles,
the bill birth story.
You'll feel like when you got punched
in your six year old Dick that then
informed you as a comedian. Wait,
why did the kid punched you?
Because we were all looking at naked
girls up the playboys and it was like all
the old days back when you didn't have
play dates and shit and you stole stuff
from somebody else's dad and you
looked at it and there was kids of all
different age groups so they understood
what the fuck was going on and the kid
fuck any did the all right
dear Fred did my fucking Dick.
I ain't, you know, I learned something.
What did you learn from that?
That that happens when you look at a
naked woman and that it hurts to get
punched again. And on that note, Oh,
it hurts even more when it's
fucking standing up. Um, all right,
sorry if you guys envisioning that
this has been the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday, Monday morning
podcast, I got turned around in that,
um, I got one more day here before I go
back. I had just a great time last night,
um, before show was awesome and then this
check second show went to a whole other
level. And um, you know what, I
was up here. I've been dressing up,
you know when our old sport coat here
trying to out French the frogs and a
French Canadian. That's right. You
know it was great. Last night was,
I actually was talking about and I brought
up, you know I was flying into Boston.
Somebody yelled,
Boston sucks and did they?
Why did I just stopped by? I said, why?
Because we win all the championships
and they were like, oh yeah, oh yeah.
I rubbed it in,
I fucking rubbed it in and then they
tried to give me shit about the Bruins
trades and it's stupid. Don't do that.
Montreal Canadien fans. All right.
Because then I could just say, well, we'll
least, we want a cup in this century,
and then they go, well,
we want blah, blah, blah,
and I just started singing glory days.
They'll pass you by glory days
and the wink of booing Patrick Wall.
All right,
that's the podcast for this Thursday.
I hope you guys have.
Thanks and I'll talk to you on Monday.
Hey, what's going on? It's milk bar.
This is a very special edition
of the Monday morning podcasts.
Those of you who are longtime listeners,
all 15 of you,
um, you know, every once
in a while I will, um,
rather than Babel for an hour about
the inane shit that pisses me off.
I'll actually bring in,
uh,
a comedian friend of mine and like I
told you these only guys that I respect,
only people that I find funny hack lists
hacklabs podcasting here and today we
are a, have the pleasure of having on
our show the wonderful, the talented,
the cock suck in Greg
Fitzsimmons everybody. What's
up Gregory? I got to tell you.
And being a standup comedian and you know,
in the media in general,
there is, what other job
begins with a stroking session,
you know,
I mean I really needed that.
I had a shit day and I'm
sitting here in your house,
you've invited me out so
I know I'm not a hack.
And then you get a nice little build up.
This guy is a good guy.
What if you were a plumber? You think
you'd show up at someone's house?
We think it's shit and knee deep in there.
Get in there and clean up the shit.
I know that's like my dad's a dentist.
I worked with him when I was younger,
then just handed him the shit is,
he yanked off the teeth and
every other person will come in.
The first thing he's saying,
first of all,
just wanna let you know I
hate the dentist. And that's
all he heard all day long.
Number one, suicide rate of any
profession. Is that right? Yeah,
that's absolutely true. Well, give it
up for my dad for hanging in there.
We all did you notice a lot of
depression in him? Uh, no. Jesus Christ.
We've really gone deep here and me. Yes.
Not In him. Jesus. I got a two man lately.
It's hit me hard. No, but I got a beat.
I know how to beat it. I actually,
now I stepped back and I observe the
thoughts in my head and I just see a bad
one. I'm like, do I want to, uh,
do I want to spoon with that idea for
the next fucking three days? Yeah.
And hate my life. I literally,
I'll go out, I'll go on a hike.
I find that walking around and getting
the blood going and just start telling
myself lies. You're amazing. You're
amazing. See what you just did though.
That's exactly.
Look like music on.
And I fantasize that I'm playing it like
I'm Stevie Ray Vaughan and it gets me
out of it. Well, I took
a yoga class yesterday.
That helps me a lot because not
only you get the physical exertion,
your deep breathing,
and then there's hot ass every direction,
all getting stretched out.
That's why I, in another life I
would do, I would be like that,
that Yoga instruction shit. Oh hell
yeah. Yeah. You get a pony tail.
You would, and not only do
these women have hot bodies,
they give a shit about themselves enough
to go to a place to make themselves
better. I'm all stretched out before
you bang them, Greg. I mean it's like,
I used to go to this one out in
Santa Monica and this guy was why I,
it was because it wasn't
that chanting shit.
It was the teacher was this
angry guy trying to be happy.
So I totally related to him,
but he used, he used to do,
this is true dude, this and he was
a great teacher and he used to,
he used to be teaching the class while
subtly putting out how sensual he was
during lovemaking. You'd like, he
would be like, he would just, yeah,
I can't even she do that
with your podcast, man. It
wouldn't work at this point.
And people know I hate women. Yeah.
Individually. I like women one on one,
but as a group,
when they all start yammering around a
table like that fucking show the view.
I mean, I mean, yeah, when I look at the
view or I think of, uh, uh, what was that?
Just sex and the city or now cougar town.
I really do.
I say to myself, women, the
best is the Bachelorette party.
That's what sums up with
all those shows are,
it's an attempt by women to be men
instead of being women in a group.
When you're with a woman alone,
they are empathetic,
acted emotional there, everything that
you kind of want to dude one on one,
but a guy can't go there.
Like you have a strong female side and
sometimes we really connect on that level,
but very often you're just the angry
dude. But women are always, that means,
but okay. No you don't. Funny.
I was hoping that someone was gonna come
here and finally actually compliment
women after all the trashing that I've
done. I'm like, Greg, he's married,
he's got a couple of kids. This would
be a nice thing. You come right in.
Just kicking them right in the
Twat. But he told me about, I said,
you're a sensitive guy. No, not me. I
was talking about like women you like,
they want to be mellow. I was
just picturing all of them
rolling their eyes. Well,
let's actually pick,
let's pick a strong female role.
Know we like who's abroad out there.
You're like,
I don't mind those women
who stand on the sidelines.
I liked their business suits.
The football games. Oh yeah.
Shoulder pads and a skirt. Why don't you
just get in the fucking game sweetheart.
No, you don't. To me, it's like, you know,
my wife and I've been with her
for 11 years and you know I,
I'm one of the few comedians that
can tell you I fucking love my wife.
I have not had a day in my
life that I didn't think.
How did I get this check? And
she's perfect. There you go.
And you've met her. Now she's
the greatest, isn't Jayla.
I knew she was a good one.
That time when we were,
we were driving back from Boston.
Holy that we did this gig somewhere in
Boston or Rhode Island for like two or
three weeks.
Where are we going to,
where are we going anyway?
Yeah. Anyways, whatever. We,
I thought we were doing a Gig.
It was, you meet Tom Carter.
We were going to a wedding. It was
Robbie Prince, his wedding. Yah, Austin.
Cause I didn't go to
Shannon. No, no. Okay.
Well let's just get to the meat of
the story. Okay. Well coming back,
Tom Carter was hung over and you and me
are in the car doing the Boston accent
on 11 and just saying the most ignorant
racist shit you could possibly say.
AIDS, Joe Jo, everything, just
total green room, standup comedy,
just driving Tom nuts. Trying to make
a few key. Remember that. And Eric,
I remember.
What's the laugh laughing the entire
time at the ridiculousness of it.
My favorite part was when it got quiet
and Tom Thought after two states of doing
it that we'd finally given up and we
drove over this bridge and there was this,
this lake or something underneath
and you and the back just go water.
Which of course started it all up again.
A Fitzy,
you're fucking fudge pig.
Let's get some beers. Go down the
Cape, beat up some colored kids. Oh,
three states, three states. We did that
and just watching Tom just being like,
dude,
it's not funny anymore from that trip
to this day I do the Boston accent and
it's immediate. It's like this Pavlovian
response. She just starts laughing again.
It's the worst.
And I was reading George Carr.
Did you read George Carlin
before we get too deep and let's,
let's get onto what you're hyping here.
Greg Simmons actually wrote a book that's
coming out. Uh, what's the name of it?
It's called Dear Mrs Fitzsimmons dear Mrs
Fitzsimmons and that will be available
in stores when, well, he
can preorder preorder now,
which they actually just bumped up my, uh,
you know, they do an order of the books.
They just bumped up to a second order,
are ready the chopping
up a body next door.
Just ignore the smell of the
podcasts. I love that they, um,
so to the book, basically it's
doing great. Preorder. Go to Fitz,
dog.com Fatz dog. And
it's a, basically my,
it's about us.
It's about Irish guys,
a lot of anger that do the opposite of
what they're told to do their whole life.
Oh,
there you go.
So my mother saved every letter that
was ever sent home from teachers.
Police clipped out things from
the newspaper when I was there,
and then I saved them all from
adulthood. So it's like, uh,
my life through bad letters that were
sent home. That's phenomenal. Man.
Phenomenal. Yeah. And the Ebook is
cool to have people buy the ebook.
I've actually, I got celebrities.
I, I can get a shoot you after this,
who they read the letters.
So when you're reading,
when you're on your iPad you can,
you can click on a particular letter and
all of a sudden Pete Yorn is reading it
or Zach Galifianakis or Natalie May.
So it's very hard on that div.
Yeah, you're very, you know something I
have to hand this to you is you're very,
you're not afraid of the Internet the
way I am. I am really, who's that guy?
Andy Rooney. The 60 minutes. That's fine.
Why is everybody going over to Facebook?
I'm just younger and notice where he is
on 60 minutes in that 30 seconds after
the night commercial. Yeah. And he's
just the, and I'm so trying not to be,
that guy just hates everything new,
but it really is like I really,
you were ahead of the
way with this podcast.
You've been doing this longer than
I have. Yeah. This appealed to my,
a psychosis of just being by myself.
Like I do this thing by myself
every week just for like an hour.
Do you ever pause it or do
you go straight through it?
Just go straight through and I do.
I do what I do.
Probably one out of four or five, I'm
alone and I, they're my favorite one.
If you start bombing,
you just talk about how you're bombing
and then people actually laugh at you.
Struggling trying to get back on
the, uh, the road to comedy people.
I find I get more comments on the alone
ones in any other ones. They're like,
I love,
I did one,
I was down staying with my mom and
Florida with my family and I went out,
sat in her car
across the street from our condo and
did one just ripping her a new asshole,
hating everybody.
And is by far the best podcast.
Overrated for this week.
This is a great one. Overrated.
When change let's, it says,
I hate the annoying clink clink
sound with a fucking passion.
What is wrong with the people? Huh?
What's wrong with people? Seriously,
the world is not loud enough.
You have to fucking add to it.
You know,
they,
they do believe this sounds will make
them better people or make life better.
You know what dude? You want
such a great role to you, right?
Broke that fucking sentences.
Oh,
what do they believe the sounds will make
them better people or make their life
better? I found it most
annoying and have an invasive,
right? I find it the honor Jesus Christ.
I'm never drinking on the podcast again.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right. What
is wrong with people? Where am I?
I find it the most annoying and
invasive thing I am forced to listen to,
even with closed windows,
but they're so peaceful.
Um,
if you fucking like the sound,
why don't you put him up inside your
home and half the fucking fan going
in any way? What gives anybody the right
to push their taste on others? Dude,
I totally agree. It's like if you're
gonna make smokers smoke outside,
then you want to make these fucking wind
chime. People take that shit indoors.
I can't tell you how annoying that is.
You know what's annoying about it is it's
an annoying sound that's trying to be
fucking spiritual. That's what
kills me. It's even, it's,
it's more annoying than just the loud,
annoying sound that's fucking annoying.
Cause at least the loud annoying sound
has to fucking courage to be annoying.
Those fucking things. They actually,
they're, they're there. You know what?
When I go on Youtube and just get some
fucking wind chime sounds for all you
dumb [inaudible] out there who do yoga,
you know and actually think that these
fucking things sound good. Here we go.
Wind fucking chimes. Youtube.
Let's see what we got. Here we go.
Yeah, cause somebody fucking loves
him so much. They put up a video.
Here we go for all you cats out there.
Here it is.
Okay.
I got to met.
Those are nice.
This isn't fair.
This guy's got fucking,
he's got the professional
grade level ones.
He thinks look like the exhaust on a
God damn. Oh that's giant wind chimes.
All right. I just learned
something. I don't mind. Giant
wind chimes. Oh, here's one.
Here's the one of these little douchey
ones you get at a fucking hardware store.
It's typical youtube. You just
can't put wind chimes. Elliot Bay,
Beautiful Wind Chime
is just the Cantisano.
There it is.
You know what the great thing is,
is they're made out of metal.
So when you rip 'em off,
you have a fucking blunt object to
beat your neighbor to death with.
That's what you do.
And then you dip it and fucking peroxide
bleach and you hook it back up again.
Let those a and e comes to figure out
that murder a man murdered on his porch.
You know, somehow they'd
find, you know, and a fucking,
I dunno, an eighth of an inch of his
face imprint on that fucking wind chime.
If you ever watch shows and things,
how they catch people, it's,
it's like it's not even fucking fair.
Do you ever see the one as I take
another healthy swap. I got news for you.
I'm having another beer.
This might be the new thing.
I might do this shit Thursday night.
Take a night off from stand up.
Tell my chick to hit the fucking bricks.
Is anything better than
drinking your own goddamn house.
It just makes you want to start screaming
about the shit you own. You know
I paid for this shit.
You hear that old man downstairs,
I'm going to get louder and
he's going to come up here.
That would be the ultimate podcast.
You know the thing about old people is
you always have to worry that they are a
fucking, like they, they, they fought
in a fucking work cause I never had,
I never have.
So I have total respect for
fucking veterans and the
fact that they still got it
in him, you know, that would be insane.
One night if I actually just totally
pissed him off and he really did fight in
the Korean War and he just fucking through
whatever that fucking thing is your
throw up when you, when you get to climb
up the rope on the side of the building,
you know that, that, that fucking
land fish hook thing throws it up.
Dan just climbs up, comes over my railing
as I'm sitting here doing this podcast,
half in the bag, he's got a
kitchen knife between his teeth,
like a fucking pirate.
What would I do?
I've probably taken 12 karate classes
in my life and they've all been like,
you know,
six years apart.
Fucking guide coming in full.
Lay me.
Okay.
You know?
I don't fucking know. I just sat back
and I just lost the screen here. Yeah.
So whatever wind chimes are
fucking overrated. They really are.
But I got to tell you, if you get
the giant ones, the giant ones,
a nice listen to the giant ones.
A giant ones have a nice tone to them.
It's a little deeper.
I think I figured it out.
Okay.
Come on man. You gotta admit that's
not bad if you let go of the anger,
your childhood, right? Like,
oh, your anger for a second
c sound of a ship in the background,
uh,
hoshin coming up on the beach.
Yeah. We get to that point right when
you're going to get relaxed and let go,
and then he gets so fucking scared.
You get right back into the anger and
then you want to punch somebody in fucking
yoga pants.
Okay.
Fucking went to go to this pizza place.
I really try to do fun things.
When I was in Portland, tried to be
healthy. I went for a fucking hike.
I was sticking with my smoothies,
you know,
dropping pounds here.
And uh,
anyway, somebody tells me that in, in
Portland, they have this fucking room.
They got this pizza parlor where they
had the best God damn pizza and all the
fucking northwest.
So this guy has like this homemade goddamn
doe and he only makes so much of it
every day. And when he's done making
the dough, he's done making pizza.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right.
So I'm like, well shit,
I got to try this pizza. So I go on the
Internet, I look up, I see where it is.
It's right on Hawthorne Street,
like 45th and Hawthorne,
46 and Hawthorne, something like
that, right? So I'm like, all right,
I gotta go check this fucking thing out.
So I allow,
I get myself an hour and a half before
the show to get there to get a God damn
pizza, right? It's a fucking pizza. Okay.
So I call up just something told
me to call just to call this place.
And uh, I call up the, it rings like 11,
12 fucking times and uh,
nobody picks up. So my guy,
you know what, they're probably busy. No
big deal. I got an a, I'm, I'll get there.
We're an hour and a half before,
right? I get a God damn cab.
I'm driving over there. Cab driver
goes, oh, just to let you know,
this guy's kind of like the
pizza Nazis, like, like the,
like the fucking a soup Nazi on Seinfeld.
So I show up and I walk in. Lo
and behold, the place is packed,
but I see this little two top gets up,
waitresses cleaning off the table.
She walks away.
So I go over and I sit down
getting ready to order the pizzas,
checking out what people are ordering
of getting excited is what I'm trying to
tell you. And then the waitress
comes over, she's like, um,
well you over in the waiting room next
door or did you just like walk in here
and sit down? And I was like, um, I
just came in and sat down. She goes,
yeah,
I'm,
you have to like thein when I'm next door.
You know those people,
everything's, everything's a question
you have to like sign in next door.
And I'm like, oh, all right. I go, well,
how long is the wait? She's like, wow,
I can't really like say it's, you
know, it's kind of busy at that point.
He's like a quarter of it go,
well, I got to show at eight.
It's a quarter to seven. Am I going to
have time to order a pizza and eat it?
She's like, yeah, no,
now.
And um,
and then that's when my blood starts
fucking boiling because I realized what I
just walked into.
You know what I walked into?
I walked into the pizza version of
pink's hot dogs out here in fucking La,
the pizza version of Magnolia Bakery
in New York City or that fucking place.
We get the hot dogs in Chicago,
you know,
hour and 15 minutes to
make a fucking pizza.
You can't do that guy sitting
here acting like, you know,
like he's making some sort of gourmet
for now. I'll tell you right now,
that's my overrated for the fucking week.
Standing in line at any restaurant.
These, you know, the, the,
the breakfast place in your neighborhood
and your girlfriend's like, oh my God,
the stuffed French toast is to die for
and you stand there and fucking line,
never worth it. It's never
worth the hype, okay?
If you learn anything from this podcast,
other than I'm an ignorant asshole,
don't ever stand in line for
fucking food, okay? And less some,
there's a natural disaster.
The place is flooded and this dis
scooping out fucking pea soup. You know,
when you're putting it into your
baseball hat, then you'll stand in line,
soup kitchen. You stand in life, but
don't stand outside these fucking places.
It's stupid. It's never worth
it. You know, fancy restaurants.
You don't stand outside. You call
up, you make a fucking reservation.
But I'm not standing out there
like I'm waiting to fucking
okay.
Do they even make God damn sense?
You know what I mean?
He's fucking people in New
York. They stand outside for
90 minutes for a cupcake,
for fucking cupcake.
It's gone in three seconds.
You know it's going to Piss me off
is some people in Portland. Okay.
They're actually going to figure out
what pizza parlor I'm talking about and
then they're going to tell, tell me
dude, it's totally fucking worth it.
These low self esteem Douche bags
who just allow themselves to get totally
treated like absolute fucking shit for
pizza.
Yeah.
Yeah. Sorry, I can't make you a
pizza within an hour and 15 minutes.
Will you know what?
Fuck you and your fucking pizza.
What do you think about that and
your number one God damn rating.
I'll go to pizza hut.
Eat their fucking slop.
You. What's killing me is that I
know I'm going to have to go back.
I have to try it.
People hyped it so much.
That's what I'm really
mad about is as I know.
As much as I just fucking
talked about that shit.
I'm going to have to go back there and
go get it and for all you guys wonder and
yelled at Magnolia. It's a great
cupcake, but it's not that great.
It's not that great to have to stand there
and listen to that awful conversation.
Yeah.
Now, if people driving by looking
at you, trying to figure it out,
what are they standing in line for?
You know
it's the president.
They're doing a book signing.
Is there a pornstar there? It was going
to blow you at the front of the line.
Can I raise the stakes for something
funny within the last seven minutes?
All right. Fuck this. Fuck
this podcast. Here we go.