Hey, what's good? Oh Jesus. Hey,
what's going on at the fuck was that?
It's bill birth and it's time for the
Thursday afternoon. Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And
just checking in on you.
Just checking in on you.
Sorry, I just woke up. I'm at a frog
in my throat. Oh, Billy. No VOCs.
William without 12 days in here.
No booze,
no cigars. Although you wouldn't know
what that frog Aj said my throat. No,
nothing. Uh, he's been a full Billy angel.
I'm going to open for Chris Angel out
there and a fucking Vegas and I'm going to
sit there and just wag my finger
at everybody in the crowd.
Tell him how they live in a life of vice.
I have to tell you people
when you find Christ, um,
I got the,
the mornings.
The mornings are the best when you lived
a vice free life the night before you
wake up. It's amazing. The birds
are singing a little louder.
There's a few more nooks and crannies
in your fucking English muffin.
She'd sit there watching the
melting into it.
Um, yeah, I, I, you know,
if the mornings are great,
I'm bored out of my fucking mind
at night out of my mind. Bored.
Um, anyways, let's, uh,
let's, but you know,
here's one for sobriety. No one of
those fucking poor bastards at AIA.
Just sit there,
Chow and donuts and smoking cigarettes.
They need something they got, they're
trying to get a buzz, nicotine,
sugar, something to break
up the fucking monotony.
Yeah, let me gay. Yeah. Fuck it.
To glazed the fucking Jelly donut.
Do shoving it down their pie hole.
Um,
that's the worst thing about opening
Pandora's box because once you fucking do
that,
then you just know how much
fun you could be having,
you know, is just sitting around
playing Fantana or something like that.
Drinking a Goddamn Arnold Palmer.
You know, I remember one time
I was hanging out with this guy,
I'm not gonna name the name of the person,
but he was hanging out with
this super fucking legendary,
famous fucking rockstar.
The dude had never got married,
never had any kids or whatever. And I
remember hanging out with that guy and he,
and like he could not,
it was all these beautiful women around.
He was barely looking at him.
He could not have been more bored because
he had gone so far down that fucking
road.
Like what?
Literally what it took at that point
to even the pilot light going and his
fucking eyes. I'm not going
to sit here with this fucking,
hang on a second.
Sorry.
I had to clear my throat there. I want
to fuck did I hit stop instead of pause.
Now I'm going to edit those two
things together. You know what it is.
It's when you're living as clean as I am,
the toxins through years of abuse start
to come to the surface and your body is
reading them, cleansing them. Um,
anyways, just so this guy,
when he was just like,
there wasn't any woman in there
that could turn his fucking head.
There wasn't a joke that
could make them smile.
Yeah.
This guy, he just, he
just, he went too far,
went too far down the hall.
He got pulled out and now he's just
sitting there just fucking bored.
Do you know if, I mean
I had a fuck, you know,
what'd you participate in like an orgy
and you're the only male participant.
I just don't understand like why,
you know,
what the fuck does that guy do?
Hey,
you want to go to Brunch?
You know,
hey, let's go, uh, let's
go to this. Go to a game.
Okay,
let's go to this arena that you're sold
out and had an orgy and then let's go
watch other people fucking chase a puck.
You want to go do that?
There's like nothing you could suggest
to this guy. He'd have to, you know what,
that,
that guy like his next fucking move to
get his adrenaline going would probably
be do that red bull jump where
you just falling from outer space.
Um, anyways, I don't know what the fuck
I'm talking about, but that's, that's,
that's what you expect.
Okay.
Switch. You expect to this one.
I expect out of this podcast
and that's what's wrong with America.
Americans podcasting with absolutely
no expectations on how well the show's
going to go. All right, let's
talk. Let's Talk Yankees,
red sox all it's heating up again.
The Red Sox rape the keys.
14 to one on Monday.
Was it Monday? I'm sorry.
Tuesday. All right.
Remember what I remember when I was a kid,
they'd be like,
they should save these runs for tomorrow.
Like you can save runs.
Okay.
And then yesterday, our stat and
pitch a pricey got fart or something.
So our pitching was shit yesterday
and the achy set it up winning, uh,
which is fine. Um, there's
like 9 million games left,
but I think it was really stupid of the
red sox to get into a fight with them.
That fight was, was good for the Yankees
because they're not as good at team.
They got bats, but they don't
have pitching. And pitching
is always going to win.
Come October. You don't need to
get involved in that stupid shit.
And um,
and we did.
So now they have, now they're
all fucking blow, go, go, go.
They're all fucking excited.
You don't do that. You know, the guy
wants to slide like that. I mean,
up until last year, that
was legal. Who gives a shit?
Who gives a shit to strike the guy out,
have him sit down with this
big fucking stupid face.
I hate baseball players in this stupid
fighting where everybody comes out and
piles on each other and uh,
nobody does the A,
you're lucky you're holding me back
better than fucking baseball players.
Maybe basketball players.
I Dunno. That's stupid.
After the fight and there's like two
guys holding you back and then you still
have to do that stupid charge, you
know, you're not going to get there.
It's over
button your shirt and go to the showers.
Um,
but anyway, so we were getting
killed and we still like,
it was almost like the Yankees
couldn't score enough runs.
So we have bats and we have pitching.
We're in a great position.
Why would we get involved
in that Tom Foolery? I mean,
this is sober bill talking.
Oh, you know, it's so stupid.
It's in the middle of the fight that
you just hit this guy go Yankees red sox
fed.
Can we retire that stupid shit already.
It's like it's, it's like fucking
Manchurian candidate level.
Like the second anything happens.
You've got to start chanting that.
Um,
not that Yankee fans are innocent
with that stupid 1918 forever.
And then when they,
when that champ was over,
then they switched it to a Boston saw,
which is the worst chat
ever. Um, I don't know.
There's so much of it that I,
it just makes me want to hit unmute the
sweet Caroline, the Yankees suck chant,
all of that stuff.
It just,
it says to me that people do not think
for themselves and that fucking mob
mentality,
I don't like the Yankees,
but we beat them.
The movie is over.
It's over roll credits.
We won the world series.
They are now reduced to go at,
hey remember what we did
last century member that,
I mean that's what
they've been reduced to.
Why would you like make them actually
feel that they hold some sort of
positioned by continuing to chant?
Yankees suck.
They don't suck.
They're a good fucking team and I love
the way that they've built from their
farm team. And then added that big
free agent from Miami or Florida,
her fucking, uh, Tuscaloosa whenever
the fuck they call themselves now.
MMM.
Oh, pit Shelby. The Okeechobee
Marlin's um, I like what they've done.
They don't suck.
And I think that Aaron Boone is going
to be a great manager and I look forward
to the competition between both teams
and who gives a fuck? Either we win
or they win or somebody else wins.
Who gives a shit?
Just enjoy the fucking game.
Don't go there and be a fucking
mouth breathing for the love of God.
Where you sit down when they
play that stupid sweet Caroline.
How many fucking times can you do it by
the fucking Yankee fence at this
cigarette? Fucking why MCA. I,
you know what, I want to, I should,
I shouldn't go this heart. You know,
it's for the kids. It's tradition.
It's what brings people together.
I Dunno. I thought the Yankees did
pretty good before they had this thing,
that fucking song during the seventh
and the stupid grounds crew doing the
little twirly twirl. Oh my
God, I'm such a continent.
Um,
anyways,
I'm sure Dan Shaughnessy is very excited
that it's heated up again and you can
actually write about the sport that he
knows about and ignore the Bruins playoff
run.
Why do I always pick on Dan Shaughnessy?
I don't hate that guy.
I just like picking on up cause I will
never forgive that fucking guy for after
2004 when we won and then 2005,
we were in first place in September.
We got a bunch of injuries
which clearly affected the team.
And then the $200 million Yankees I
believe ended up coming in passing us and,
and she's like, is the curse
back? I was like right there.
You're not a red sox fan.
You're just not.
You're a guy making money off of misery.
You're your own little corporation,
you know,
profiting off of war in a sports sense.
Jesus, Bill, you went big there. Yes,
I did.
And I'll do it again.
Yeah.
Anyways,
the Bruins playoff run starts tonight
and I have a lot of nerve given Shaun to
see shit considering I may
watch four games this year. Um,
now that I got the little one and um,
we're playing the Toronto Maple leafs
and those poor bastards are going to have
to fucking ender the highlight reel of
what happened the last time we played
them and just know that I was at that
fucking game. Um, I
actually know something.
It's funny, I feel like maple
leaf fans hate the Bruins.
Um, and uh, I don't hate the maple
leaf. I actually liked the maple leaf.
I hate the Canadians.
That's it in a couple of knee
breakers on the penguins.
Other than that, and not even at
the penguins have in the breakers.
It's just that they then
turn around and complain,
but somebody gets a little
rough on the other team.
They were attacking Sydney.
They bug me. Um, that's it. Other than
that, I don't have a problem to anybody.
I'm looking forward to wonderful.
A seven game series.
We'll see how it goes. But, uh, it
comes on at four o'clock. Here I am.
I'm balancing my entire fucking schedules
that it said how he said my entire
fucking schedule is, uh, is
going to be based around that.
My daughter takes a
nap from three to five,
so I figure I'll get to watch
the first period and then,
um, and then I'll probably
be fucked. Who's kid? No.
Um,
I'm actually flying to the Rio tomorrow.
I'm flying out to shall it
for the rough and rowdy fight.
I'm going to be commentating,
watching regular people's
Americans on Americans fighting.
There's going to be over 40 fights and
I'm feeling that this is going to be like
when I did the Joe Rogan Doug Stan Hope,
uh,
end of the universe
podcasts on election night.
That's the vibe that I feel
like it is going to be going on.
So I'm just going to be,
I'm trying to get in as
many jokes as I can't.
It's already entertaining while getting
out of the way of the action. Um,
I've never done any shit like this.
I remember when I was a kid,
my mother thought I should
be a sports commentator.
I don't think she pictured me doing,
starting my career in an event like this.
But I'm looking forward to
it. I really am. And, uh,
it's a $15 pay for you unless
you wait till the day of.
So today's the last day we can get a
flight 1599 and after that it goes up to
1999. But if you're a college kid,
you know, a couple, two, three,
you've fence throwing like
five and a half bucks each.
Get yourself a Domino's pizza
and whatever else you want to do.
Is Mike goal liquid?
Say An adult beverage and uh,
enjoy the fights. Um, anyways,
plowing ahead here.
Uh,
I've started my workout,
my serious,
my theory is workout regimen to somehow
stave off the fact that I'm turning 50
in fucking June the big
file, but Papa, Papa,
ah,
you fucking fucking old you fucking balls.
Hey Dan to the thought.
Um,
I actually feel fortunate to be,
to have made it this long,
considered a bunch of my friends did not.
And then also the direction
we seem to be going here.
Why are we bombing Syria?
Why are we going to do this?
How much further into this
fucking Middle East Shit,
how are we going to go?
I don't understand why France, US, Russia,
all of these fucking people.
Why the fuck do we keep
intervening over there?
You know what I mean?
Is people have been fighting with each
other forever and then we're going to
come in a, hey, settle down, settle
down. Give us the oil. Settle down.
You shouldn't do that to what another
give us the oil stopped doing that.
Frances President Emmanuel Macron says
he has proof that the Syrian government
attack the town of Doma
with chemical weapons.
Last weekend he said he would decide
in due course whether to respond with
airstrikes. Um, I dunno how these cases,
world leaders do that
shit. It's like, you know,
you can respond with airstrikes
and they're not all going
to land on the people
that did it. And then you have to go
to bed that night going like, well, I,
I think most of them landed on the
people that were guilty. You know,
the others landed in a food court.
I think that's why they age. Um,
although I think Donald Trump is going
to age wonderfully during his presidency
because I don't think he
really understands the
ramifications of what the fuck
it is that he's saying or doing.
Um,
who the fuck tweets about when a country's
going to strike another countries and
that's supposed to kind of be a secret
or the way he's trying to do the three
card Monte. It could be now. It
could be not at all or maybe later.
You know, it's funny, there's probably
Syrian people actually looking at his
and his tweets,
you know, like, uh,
like looking at it like, like
they found clues. I'm sorry,
I just got this fucking email.
These God damn fucking state of Wisconsin
just hit me with this huge God damn
tax bill. I just like, Huh, fuck. Do I
owe you guys all that God their money.
Yeah, I know. I know why they hit me
with that shit. I know why. I know why.
Cause it was spending money in this
country in a bunch of other shifts.
Then I come down there and they fucking
pull the pants down. They give, oh,
freckles a good spank. And before I
leave the state, that's like a new thing.
All of these scams do you
know in Pittsburgh they had
an entertainment tax for
awhile.
If you are an entertainer,
if you spun plates and
you went to Pittsburgh,
they taxed you for entertaining people.
Literally doing your job.
When I was in Saint Louis one time I was
in a hotel and I actually took the time
to look at the bill and this,
the city of Saint Louis or the
state of Missouri charged me.
Uh,
what the fuck did they call it?
An occupation tax on the room.
They taxed me for occupying the room.
They just shaking like fucking third 20,
30 bucks out of your pocket.
We'll take that.
Thank you for coming here.
Did you get a chance to
visit the fucking Ozarks?
Um, I dunno. I'll tell you.
It's all the God damn scam.
What am I going to do?
Am I going to take on a whole fucking
state? Michael Moore would do it.
Um, all right. The penguins, Jesus Christ.
What they went 18 and nothing
against the fucking flyers. Um,
I didn't get to watch any
of the hockey last night.
I was editing season three
of f is for family. Um,
okay.
I think I'm just gonna tell you right now,
and I can say this with total confidence.
This is without a doubt,
our best season.
It's a,
it's a noticeable jump between
the first and second seasons.
Um, and I can't wait for you guys
to see it, but it's animation.
So I'm be like Donald Trump,
you could be seeing these
episodes soon or maybe later,
possibly not at all.
Or maybe they're on right now.
She get a giant fucking toupee.
Lucky he doesn't have a toupee.
I think he did a comb over and then he
did some hair plugs and they didn't work.
But now the hair plugs up better
than I think maybe they worked.
But then he just has to kind of commit
okay.
To the comb over,
you know,
if I actually think he kinda
has nice hair, you know,
the way he gets died, all golden
when it goes orange, it's bad.
But he has like the golden sort
of fucking a stray cats haircut.
You know. We're going to bomb this town
bomb. It is sad and I think it's a, uh,
I think it's a good look.
I could see him with like an upright bass.
I want to get one of those fucking,
what would you guys do if
somehow I got a fucking, oh,
I actually caved and I got
fucking hair plugs, right?
And I had a giant red stray cats
fucking hairdo outta nowhere.
No, not out of nowhere. You would,
you would notice it like
pictures of me after shows going,
what's going on with
the top of bird's head?
And I refuse to like when
someone's slowly transitioning,
does that thing of like, wow,
that's an interesting outfit.
And then people started, are you Trent?
And then finally they'd say, yeah,
you know what I, yeah, I would,
I would do what Bruce Jenner
did except to my hair.
All right,
but what if I never fucking addressed it?
What if I never went on and talked
to Diane Store Sawyer? You know,
and just sat there going,
I was the story.
Okay,
What if I never did that and refused
to ever address my new quaff of fucking
hair and I tried to just, I
just, I erased all my podcast.
Any fucking evidence of me ever admitted
that I went bald and I would just say
that I was just, well,
she was too, you know,
like Turkey when they refuse to
see. Yeah, that never happened.
If you say it happens,
you're going to jail.
How much would I be getting heckled
if I came out with a fucking ric flair
haircut?
Oh fuck.
You know something I was talking
about Moto GP and the, uh,
what was it? The Art Argentina. A
Grand Prix. Is that where it was?
What a fucking race that was.
I don't even, I don't even,
I haven't watched racing enough to
even understand what the fuck happened.
And I was dealing with my kids and all
of a sudden the race starts and there was
like one person in the front row,
nobody in like 30 rows back
or something like that.
And then a bunch of people in the back,
mark mark has installed this bike. So,
according to the rules, he had to
leave and go restart it or something.
And he was driving around in circles,
refusing to fucking leave.
Um, so then he ended up, those race starts
okay.
And he gets penalized or
penalized depending on what
part of the country you're
from.
He got penal lies and he goes to the back
of the race and this fucking guy just
okay.
Raw. He was like, I swear to God,
he was like 40 seconds ahead of everybody
who's going to win the race going away.
It was one of those tracks
where, and it was, um,
it was still wet or whatever and he was
just riding way faster than everybody
else. I don't know how, and uh,
they say, buddy, buddy, you,
uh, you've, you've got to go to
the back of the, this is so stupid.
I didn't want to talk about,
you got to go to the back of the race.
So they sent them all the way to the back,
goes to the pits first,
and then they send them to the back of
the race because he fucking ran over this
guy,
you know,
he basically right.
Went to go pass somebody. He's,
he's bumping them out of the way.
Like they in cars, except they're run
motorcycles and he would wave like,
sorry about that and continue on.
They're like, hey buddy, you got to go
to the back of the fucking race, right?
The first time.
I think today he bumped into somebody.
They made him sit there in the pits.
I don't remember. I think they,
they penalize this guy so many
fucking times. Long story short,
he went from first place
all the way to last.
So now he's blowing by everybody
and he gets up to Valentino Rossi,
who's basically the Wayne Gretzky,
uh,
the Lewis Hamilton,
the fucking person you're not supposed
to touch a fuck with and he's trying to
get around them. And Valentino
Rossi, he's like, fuck you.
You're not getting around me. And A,
rather than waiting for a straight away,
he tried to pass him on a turn and
he just fucking slammed into him.
And Valentino got it, got pushed to the
outside and he had control the bike.
But then he went on the grass and he
wiped out the, uh, fell off his bike.
And Mark has turns around waves
like, sorry, pop that right.
Valentino gets up, but he's Italian. He
goes up, my blah blah blah, blah. I right.
And then he picks his bike up.
Now he's ride.
Now all the Valentino Rossi fans are like,
what the fuck is with this guy? Mark?
Mark has gets penalized again,
I believe.
And uh,
so at the end of the fucking race,
mark has walks down with somebody
else to Valentino's a pit area,
what they call it, the pageant, I
forget what they call it, the of of p.
And Valentino is like, oh my God,
I am like, so not talking to you.
Some of the mechanics of the chief
fucking steward, stewardess down there,
something. He's yelling at Marquez
and Marquez ends up walking away.
And then Valentino Rossi said he wasn't
man enough to come down by himself.
He came down with somebody else,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I'm sitting there agreeing with
Valentino Rossi and then all of a sudden
everybody starts sending all these
fucking highlights from like three years
earlier when Rossi,
basically donkey kick to mark.
Mark has off his fucking bike or out of
the goddamn race or something like that.
So it's, it just seemed like, um, Lewis
Hamilton behavior where it's like,
it's okay if I do it,
but if you do it,
you're a fucking asshole and now I'm
going to have a hissy fit about it.
So I think I like Mark Marquez
better. You know, I respect Rossi.
You know the little I know about the
sport being the legend that he is a,
but I like Marquez. Fuck it. If he
did that two years earlier, yeah,
pass them on to turn,
knock him off his bike and give
them a wave. Who gives a shit?
I'm telling you guys, you're
missing out of this, this,
all of this took place in like 25 laps.
You can watch your race in like 40
minutes and you can watch these,
these unbelievable,
this unbelievable fucking sport.
I can't even tell you how
sold I am on motor GP. Um,
just to let you know,
there's moto GP two and three and they're
all going to get recorded and there's
going to be like five recordings of
them and there's a chance your, your,
your recorder's going to shut off,
which is what would have happened to me.
I would have missed the
end of the fucking race.
But fortunately I've got to watch it live.
Um,
I don't understand. Trying to take one
of those races is practically impossible,
so I have to make sure I don't,
I don't lose the one here.
The Moto GP of the Americas
is what they call it.
Why don't they say they say Argentina?
You know,
they say they say Italy,
why can't we say USA?
You know, what are we embarrassed the
Americas, whereas it Canada, Mexico,
Falkland Islands, um,
anyways, check it out. If he,
if he get a chance. Um, you know,
usually this is the time when I actually
do a read or something. And it's just,
I don't have any advertising.
You know what I mean?
I'm like that real housewife on the real
housewives that just trashes too many
fucking people and then the,
you know,
just doesn't have any friends anymore.
Uh,
that's where the advertising
is slowly going. Okay.
On this podcast and
okay,
I am, now that I've cleaned
up my act as far as my,
you know,
offstage behavior,
I am now going to clean up this
podcast in an effort to try to get my
advertising back.
Yeah.
I am not going to have
any sort of opinions.
The just stop right now and just talk
about how amazing and strong women are and
how whatever,
look at your,
your girlfriend or wife right now and
just look at whatever she's doing and just
realize how strong she is and really
just take time in your day to understand
how amazing women are
and how right they are and how
they do nothing wrong whatsoever,
ever.
And if they do something wrong,
just know that it's because
of something that you did.
I want everybody to close their eyes.
Yeah.
It talked to Jesus right now.
Should I go that far? No, I
think that'd be too limiting.
I think if I just say
positive things about women,
I can't do this. I am fucking,
annoys the shit out of me.
A clutch.
Is there any more annoying than a clutch?
It goes to buy my house. I don't have
any pockets. Can you hold all my shit?
Eight. Why don't you bring
money? Your fucking bags?
Why don't you make a bunch of
one of those recycling bags?
Why don't you throw that
over your fucking outfit?
Maybe you'll be making some
new fashion statement, right?
Like back in the day when women will wear
business suits in, in fucking sneakers,
put on something nice and then have
like a little fucking grocery bag.
You don't even sticks to
call you shit in there.
Okay.
You giant fucking Hell fucking cell phone.
I already have my cell phone in my pocket.
You want to meet him?
Radiate fucking both sides of my scrotum.
I mean,
not to mention my taint. Do you have any
sort of consideration for me whatsoever?
I might just a fucking pack mule.
Yeah.
Once you get a smaller phone,
you're going to walk around with a clutch.
I say you go back to a flip phone.
That's what I say.
That's my big controversial
fucking take on this Thursday,
a playoff hockey tonight.
Everybody playoff hockey.
The third game of the Red Sox Yankees,
90 million games that we're
going to play this year.
I got 50 bucks on every game with uh,
my booking agent and uh,
Paul Versey.
Okay.
And I called the two of the panic
brothers because that first game they will
literally go and like we're done.
Oh my God, wait. So squared, uh,
bullpens admit the Yankees
had major problems and they'd
like literally the next
Gabe,
it's just like dough.
We'll go to the world series and
then all of a sudden fucking, uh,
Hanley Ramirez had said Grand Slam and
we go down for being like fucking down
eight to two and now it's eight to six.
And that was all of a sudden,
it's like if we blow this, the
bullpens, the problem, it's like, dude,
this is 150 games left.
I can't fucking do this.
But it's so funny to watch the Yankee fans
act like how red sox fans used to act.
Um,
they don't have any swag or anymore.
They're a bunch of fucking
nervous nellies. It's tremendous.
Which is why once again, we shouldn't have
gotten to that stupid fight with them.
Stupid. Why give them an emotional
point to rally around you.
The better God damn team. But it doesn't
mean that the better team is gonna win.
It doesn't mean it. Because when you start
getting involved in that stupid shit,
it's fucking baseball.
Nobody's gonna get hurt.
Everybody's going to come running out.
I always wanted to talk to people like
who come running out of the bullpen,
you know? Is that like a knowing
that by the time you get there,
like the fights are already been over
for fucking three minutes, you know,
and you could tell the way they come
running out. It's like, what do you,
you're going to just,
you're going to be sitting there.
You're not pitching that day.
Right. You're blowing bubbles.
You coming up with fucking game.
She can play to get through the fucking
Gab thinking I'm looking at something
great. And your buddy's gone
are the green monster. Nope.
Uh, the person's, uh, red
sox, Saint Patty's Day hat.
Right? And all of a sudden
you're like, is that a fight?
Is that a fight in the phone?
Fucking rings. Hey Buddy. Yeah.
I don't know if you noticed,
but there's like a 40 on 40 fight about a,
about a football field away. Why
don't you come out? It's good.
It's gonna look good for the team and
a half and he gets up without fucking
stretching and you see him jog out there
and they're not going to come running
out their full fucking full speed.
They're going to pull a hamstring.
They're going to throw a punch and fuck
up their hand. They can't their pictures,
their pitches. You, you, you're
looking at a Ken doll. It's, it's got,
it has no fucking, uh, no
genitalia. It's running out. What?
That every once in a while he see somebody
come running out and that's usually
the fucking warmup catcher.
That guy will come flying out of there.
He's got to do something to keep, make
sure he stays on the God damn team, right?
That guy only catches the knuckle
baller. He's like, oh Jesus,
I get to do something.
Right.
Anyway,
a rough and Rowdy Charlotte,
North Carolina in the house
to ric flair built. Um,
I cannot fucking wait and I am actually
going out to buy little habit dash for
the fucking, uh, I'm, I'm going
all out for this thing and uh,
it's going to be a great fucking time.
All right.
It's going to be as great as
every woman on the planet is.
They're just great people.
Every single one of them.
None of them needs to do any
sort of self examination.
Anything that they're doing,
it's because of the man that's in their
life or maybe a man who isn't even in
their life.
Maybe a man that they've never even met
before is the reason for their behavior.
Um, that's it. Everybody have a
great weekend and go fuck yourself.
She comments and I will,
I will talk to you on Monday.
I look forward to high level competition
tonight between the Boston Red Sox and
the New York Yankees.
All right.
See Ya.
Yeah,
correct
boss.
Here's the story.
Gotta beat.
Marsha got to get closer than a quarter
of an inch rubber that when Greg Brady
striving that fucking caprice classic
or whatever the fuck they had,
whipping it around the parking lot,
get closer than an engineer,
make it fun or how broads can't drive
one of my favorite fucking episodes.
And that's a typical
male chauvinist reaction.
You're prejudice against women drivers.
Not as long as they stay off the roads.
It's not prejudice, it's just that men
are naturally superior drivers. Right?
Two favorite episodes was the first half.
Not that Brady Bunch episode when Greg
Brady was bringing the fucking hammer
down and was gone. Let me tell you
three fucking stepsister bitches,
something nutty.
You broads know how to drive.
And that includes your mother
who I'm banging by the way,
who I'm banging by the way.
All right.
With their weird ass haircut,
whatever the fuck you know.
But, um, yeah, I had a date
with him and you know, it was,
I kind of felt like I was,
if you were in school
and I were the teacher,
did anybody ever have that fucking
haircut? Uh, other than her. I mean,
that is like,
I dunno what it was.
She took like Mo from the three stooges
haircut and then she put a fucking sort
of mullet that she did a little
flipped to on the back. Anyways,
let's get back to you broads.
You don't know how to fucking drive.
That goes for you with the
fucking speech impediment.
You don't know how to fucking drive
Jan with your awful fucking Hasidic Jew
fucking curls. I don't know what
you're trying to do. You know, and,
and,
and Marcia who,
I don't know why I'm not banging you some
reason we skipped over you and started
banging your mother, right? None
of you bitches can fucking drive.
And I'm watching this episode going this,
see Greg Brady says, shit, Greg, Bro,
fuck Fonzie. You know, with
his stupid fucking, you know,
spinning around a punching a
jukebox. So play Shabaam Shit, boom.
I don't give a fuck about that.
I like Greg Brady, you know,
for as much as Fonzie was talking shit,
he was always nice to the ladies.
And that's,
that's seventh grade game with a woman.
[inaudible]
Greg Brady.
That's it.
That's how Greg ended up fucking their
mom because he didn't give a shit.
You didn't give a fuck Greg. Fuck
you Carol. You're not my mother.
You know how to drive either. Oh my God.
Took them in that fucking groovy addict.
They had started blowing up.
It's why his hair got all curly.
So anyways,
that episode,
he's telling these fucking broads
that they don't know how to drive.
And then in the end of course,
cause they always have to cater to women.
He's Nerdy fucking writers, you know,
and then the, uh, they fucking, you know,
Marsha goes around this stupid fucking
track and they had a cone with a little
egg on it. You guys are seeing this and
she fucking, you know, I forget whatever,
Marsha in the beginning,
and then
in the end, just to fuck and even
it out. So everybody's happy.
And they could sell tide during the
commercials. They have Greg. Fuck up.
Knock the I golf. That's, that's
what I was trying to get to.
Wasn't that what I was trying to
get to that one on so fucking long.
I can't even remember.
All I'm saying is
that the guy you want?
You don't,
it doesn't fucking matter
how many yards you throw
in the regular season.
It doesn't
fucking pattern.
Ah,
what's
going on
podcasts for Monday,
April 12th, 2010. And uh,
I'm actually just putting this up here
right now to let you guys know that I'm
not doing a podcast this week. I
apologize. I'm calling in sick.
All right. I'm fucking,
you know, everyone, cal,
cal Ripkin voluntarily took himself out
of that game and he ended his streak.
I'm ending my podcast streak.
This is the first week that I, uh,
I'll ever willingly not do
a fucking podcast. You know,
it's like an NFL football. The
big question is, can you go,
we tape it up and we freeze it.
Can you go?
And this is the first time I
could tell you no, I can't,
I can't go this week.
Everybody. I apologize.
So we're going to have a substitute this
week. I'm going to pass the mic. No,
I'm fucking with you. I really
should have someone stand in. I'm a,
I'm spent.
All right,
I'm back to drinking. I'm
disgusted with myself. I,
uh, was in Atlanta this week.
I didn't drink Wednesday. Okay.
And I didn't drink Thursday.
Okay.
And then Friday was coming
along and I was tired.
Now my buddy was open and for me,
and I had a couple of drinks.
I had two beers and then
I switched to water,
which is a great thing and it usually
makes me stop. But the thing was,
is I left the punchline in
Atlanta. Uh, that's where I was at.
I was at the punchline and I walked
across the street to this club to 90
and okay.
I Dunno.
Somewhere walking from the punchline
across the parking lot to club,
to 90. I then switched back to, uh,
to alcohol. I don't know
what happened. Jesus Christ.
Hear my phone ringing in the background.
How many times getting a ring before you
realize either I'm not home or I'm not
picking it up.
It was probably some fucking telemarketer.
Oh Jesus. There you go. Person
finally quit. So anyways,
anyways,
I walk over there and people are drinking.
So I add a couple more Budweisers and
then the fucking bartender over there.
If you guys live in the Atlanta area,
and I feel really bad telling you this.
All right.
Cause it's such a cool fucking thing
that I don't want it to get ruined and
become anything touristy.
You know?
I can't even know what the name of
the thing was. Just go in there.
There's a bartender named Tommy and
just ask him if he can spin the wheel.
All right. This guy out of nowhere
says to me, and Paul Versey,
who's opening up for me, you
fucking killed all weekend. He,
he just pulls out this drum head and
it's got an Arrow and it has a bunch of
shit written all around the rim of the
drum head. And he goes, spin the air on,
you'd spin it. And He, I
didn't even, I was so drunk,
I don't even know what I got.
And Paul spun at first, he got something,
the guy goes, okay, you got this.
Then he has me spinning and he
goes, all right, you got, you know,
you got this. And then he walks
over and he picks up this,
I dunno what it is. You don't like that
thing like that. They put like a Yeager,
Erin, you know when you do
like they have Yeager on tap,
you know all those things.
He basically picked up something like
that that had a door on the front of it
and he just puts it on top
of his head and he's just
staring at us
and all of a sudden he opens the door
and he has this dumb cross eyed look on
his face and he starts singing
slash rapping. I don't know what,
and it doesn't even sound like English.
And at the end of every sentence it
could kind of fucking rhymes and right as
you start to figure out what he's saying,
he stops,
makes a weird face and slams
the door right in his face.
It's the most fucked up thing. When he
first did it, I was like all defensive,
like is this Guy gonna make me look
like a fucking asshole? And then I,
and then right as I caught on that
he was just acting like an idiot.
He slammed the door on himself and it
was the best fucking laugh I've had in
like three months. I can't even imitate
what he did. And that was just for Paul.
So now he's standing,
he just slammed the door,
this fucking thing on his writing
his own face as little door.
And now he's just standing
there looking at me,
but he's not looking at me cause he's
got this fucking thing on him on his head
and I know I'm next and all of a
sudden he opens the door again.
He's got that same dumb look on his
face and he said, ah, Bill bird up,
but deputize Deborah today.
I can't even fucking do what he was doing.
And me and Paul at this point,
I'm like pounding the bar,
fucking dying laughing and
you didn't want it to end.
And all of a sudden he just stops with,
is fucked up,
look on his face and he slams the
door in his face again, club to 90.
The guy's name's Tommy. Just
hang out there. I'm telling you,
I do all the fucking weird Shit I've seen
in bars with people doing tricks with
matchbooks people telling you jokes and
everything was the most unique fucking
thing I've ever seen in my life.
And um,
it's called the club to 90, just just
go in there, whatever. That's it.
The next night I was going to bring
actually my video camera and video tape it
and put it up on Youtube,
but I didn't want to because youtube
ruins everything because everything then
becomes mainstream and it can't be a,
it was just this cool underground thing.
So what I did to keep it underground was
not videotape it and then fucking talk
about it on my podcast. What
an asshole. Um, so anyways,
so I went hard that night and I stayed
out till like four in the morning and we
ended up driving out of there and uh,
and version is going,
come on, hey, is anything open? I want
to get something to eat. I'm like, dude,
I'm not eating this fucking late.
Actually it was like three,
I got to sleep by force was a little bit
before three. And he goes, no, no, no.
He goes, I think Mcdonald's
opened. I'm like, dude,
it's not going to be open this late.
And he's like, all right, come on.
Just drive up there. So I say,
fuck it. I drive up there.
He sees the lights are on and he see,
you see that one lonely fucking person
standing in there walking around doing
everything and he's all excited, dude.
Do the drive through throughs open? Yes.
It's fucking open, right? So we go, we go
to the drive through and he's like, dude,
you got to get some like, no, dude,
I'm not getting any of this shit.
I can't eat this fucking laid up too,
too old to beat and it's light, right?
So we go up to the drive through and
the guy goes, hey, welcome Mcdonald's.
Can I take your order? And immediately
my mouth just starts going, yeah,
let me get two double cheeseburgers,
a small fry and a coke and verse.
He just starts laughing at me.
Cause two seconds ago I wasn't going
to get anything in the second I just
started smelling those
fries. I said, you know what?
Actually now that I think of it,
I'm going to order about
1,280 calories of trans fats.
I think that that's what I'm going to do.
So we get our shit fucking
drive back to the hotel,
fucking eat it and his Roman.
Then I go to bed. You know,
I wake up the next day at like
1230 and I'm not worth shit.
I'm not worth fucking shit. We
get up, we go to the waffle house.
This is what I did to my body this week.
This is why there's no podcast this
week. This is not a podcast. Okay?
So if you guys don't like this podcast,
don't write me and say
that podcasts sucked.
Well you need to say is
you're unbelievably long
statement announcing why you
weren't going to do a podcast sucked.
All right.
All right. Get it right there. Cunt face.
So, uh, yeah, we go into the waffle.
We're both fucking
hung over.
I had been to the waffle house a bunch
of times because I traveled this fucking
country.
Paul Versey has never been to the fucking
waffle house because he doesn't work
this part of the country much.
Or maybe he just never went to it,
which I would understand because of the
piss yellow sign that they have with the
incredibly bland black
font. It is, um, um,
is a question for you guys and
this non podcasts, what do,
when you guys look at like fast food,
don't you know what like some signs of
like appealing and they make you want to
eat the food or at the very least try it.
We have an an earthquake.
Is that just wind and having a
lot of earthquakes lately? Um,
total is one of those little ones.
Every once in a while I'll get one of
those little ones out here. And, uh,
it just feels like,
you know,
if your eyes are closed at
night and you get one of those,
you feel like if you opened your eyes,
they'd be some guys standard at the
end of your bed. Just shaking it. Heck,
I'm going to fucking kill
you. Um, anyway, so we got,
uh, which, uh, Jesus,
I said I got nothing.
This is not a podcast everybody.
I can't even fucking think right now.
I had a Muffin, a bag of
m and m's, a water in,
some sort of chicken wrap,
all airport fucking food.
I've destroyed my body.
I think at least two of my
organs of shutdown at this point.
I'm going to go with one kidney and,
uh, let's see the pancreas now that's,
that's the fucking grand central
of the, uh, Oregon's isn't it?
What exactly does the pancreas do?
That's for all you geeks out there who
let me know that facetious is not the
only word that has all
the vowels in a row.
You hear that geeky
person who sent me that fucking email
that said the intercity league of both.
The word facetious is it's the
only word in the English language.
We're all the, uh, all the vowels,
not only all the vowels in the
English language in the word,
they're actually in order. It's the
only word in the English language.
I'm sorry to tell you sir,
you're actually wrong and a,
I can't remember what the other word is,
but at least two other nerds emailed me
to let me know that you are wrong. So,
uh, I'm not gonna read the emails
because this is not a podcast this week.
I am taking this week off.
So what you need to do is you need to
deepen the level of nerd that you fucking
hang out with before you make an ass of
yourself like that again on the podcast.
Lucky for you.
I'm not trashing you on another podcast
or as you would be embarrassed right now.
Fortunately for you,
this got buried on the back page
of this non podcasts this week.
So anyways, what, which
have fast food restaurant.
You guys feel like the sign makes the
food look like the least appealing for me?
I would go with the waffle house because
they have like that piss yellow fucking
sign and they have the
plaintiff's black font.
It's just horrible. Absolutely horrible.
And it makes me sick to my stomach. Arby's
is another one that blood orange color,
that fucking hat, and they're
gray roast beef. And by the way,
I ate there last night.
It about fucking one in the morning.
Jesus Christ.
You know what I used to hate to was this
the subway back in the day when they
had those piss yellow counters in the
newspaper articles all on the walls.
Remember that they literally had
urine colored tables with newspapers.
The only thing was missing was a
homeless guy rolled up in the wallpaper,
pissing on the tables.
That was the,
that was basically subconsciously what
they were creating. And not only that,
the pictures on the wall on, oh, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no. The newspapers,
Oh,
I'm fucking this up.
The subway used to have
pictures of Old New York on it.
That's what it had. Wow. I fucked that up.
The newspapers were actually the
tabletops of the old Wendy's.
There's a bunch of guys,
41 years old and older right now
fucking punch in their dashboard going.
That's why I was going to fucking
say that. I remember that Shit.
You go in there and you'd,
you'd order the triple you ever one time.
You don't dice it. You
remember what time? You know,
one time I was standing in line at
Wendy's and I was making my girl crack up,
or maybe my girlfriend at the time,
I can't even fucking think this week,
I was making her laugh her ass off
because I was making fun of who the fuck
orders a triple, uh, triple cheeseburger,
you know, I don't even know of him,
what I was saying,
but I had a dying laughing and I was so
site that I was making her laugh because
it was making me feel good.
I had a cry and laugh and then I had
said triple cheeseburger so many fucking
times that when I walked up to the
register, I ended up ordering it.
And then she looked at me like,
what the fuck did you do that for?
And then I felt stupid for ordering it,
but then I asked, it felt, you know,
I didn't want to be like, oh
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I didn't want to look like an asshole.
And then the glutinous side of me is like,
oh great, I get to eat at triple
cheeseburger, you know, like a fat fuck.
So anyways, I would go with Arby's and I
would go with the waffle house signage.
So anyways,
we walked into the waffle house.
So for those of you who have
never been to a waffle house, uh,
don't ever put your elbows on the table
because you won't be able to get them
off without taking off at least
two layers of skin because there's
somebody kill me.
You know,
I just had an urge to do him
wearing a thermal right now.
I had the urge to take this thing
off and hang myself by the sleeves.
I got nothing. I got absolutely
nothing this week, this statement.
It's uh,
it's just gonna be a long statement of
someone who ways we walk into the fucking
waffle house. And yes, I did
lose some energy in my voice.
I'm running out of batteries here.
Uh, yeah, I'm sweating here. Uh,
we walk into the waffle house and we're
both fucking hung over it and I've been
to the waffle house hundreds of times,
so I already know the menu.
Paul on the other hand,
does not know the menu.
So the waitress comes over and she goes,
you guys ready to order?
And I'm like, yeah, yeah,
actually I'm ready to order it.
So Versie goes into a fucking panic and
it's a big overwhelming fucking menu.
They have like 98
different kinds of, of, uh,
hashbrowns smothered covered fucking
sheet shit on or whatever the fuck you
supposed to say there that he just, you
know, I order what I order and then he,
he didn't know what the fuck did dope.
These, just looking at the pictures,
pancakes, toast, eggs. And he
finally just goes, yet you have a,
what are the order?
He ordered eggs benedict
fucking waffle house.
You know
who the fuck? Oh, that's like trying to
order like a ribeye steak at Mcdonald's.
They don't have it.
Paul over easy or fucking scrambled.
I mean there's like toothless truckers in,
they're convicted felons has been rappers.
It's a shit, it's a shit hole. But
their waffles a delicious especial,
especially when you're hung
over their food. So fattening.
I actually had a little hiccup
there as I was just describing it.
So anyways, and this is the,
this is, this is the kicker.
Like that night I have three
fucking shows. All right.
But because I'm a professional,
I'm able to push all the feelings that I
have of the horror that I've done to my
body over the last fucking 24
hours. I go onstage, kill its seven,
kill a 10 I do, I go to Duke was
seven nine and 11 the 11 o'clock show.
I literally have a
splitting fucking headache.
And all I can think of is Jerry Lewis.
And how he never ever sat down in his
Tuxedo pants and he always gave him a
fucking show. And I was like, you
know, instead of what would Jesus do,
what would Jerry do?
He would give them Michelle Lady.
So I plowed through that one and uh,
then that was the end of my weekend.
So he probably thinking
to yourself right now.
Well then why are you issuing
a statement bill? You fucking,
you will finish Saturday. It's fucking
Monday. Did you recuperate yesterday? No,
I did not.
I went to the masters yesterday and
watch Phil Mickelson when his third green
jacket.
And uh,
it was an incredible experience. I
went to the Superbowl golf, everybody.
And after having gone there and seen
how fucking beautiful that golf courses,
I don't know why they don't call the
Superbowl, the masters of football.
You know why?
Because nobody fucking watches golf to
the level that they watched football.
That's why I knew the
answer to that question.
I'm just trying to tell you that
was a beautiful course and, and,
and basically you don't get
tickets to the masters. All right.
Cause I want to tell you guys, this is
just like Royal Albert Hall that I saw.
This is another thing
that if you're into golf,
you have to do at some
point you don't get tickets.
What you do is you get a badge and you
have to get a badge from some sort of
dude who knows a member
who knows a fucking guy,
who knows a guy who fucking
knew a guy who knew a guy.
And when you go to pick up your tickets,
you actually fucking,
at least we did.
We actually drove to somebodies house
and I remember I thought it was gonna be
like, some will call shit and it wasn't.
We were driving through this neighborhood
and I'm looking at the addresses and
I'm like, I think it's the next house.
It's a house.
I must be on the wrong street.
And then I look and there's this woman
sitting in a garage waving at us.
And I was like,
all right,
well either this is the place where
we're supposed to be or this is the
friendliest fucking neighborhood
I've ever been to. Well,
maybe I looked like one of her neighbors
or maybe she has a rape fantasy and she
ordered a redhead
because you know how many Red
Juggalos are out there? Everybody
telling you were in demand.
We're, we're dying off. Well,
like the white rhinos
of fucking human beings.
People are trying to bang us before
we disappear. Let me think about it.
Think about the Dodo bird.
Think about if you actually stuck
your dick in a Dodo bird. The, the,
the fuck you Trump every story in a bar.
I fucked something that
doesn't exist anymore.
What do you necrophilia act? No, you
fucking asshole. I fucked the Dodo bird.
Um, anyways, now, right there,
I would have complained if
that was on a regular podcast.
I would have complained
about that last bit there.
But fortunately this is not a podcast.
I'm just issuing a statement that I do
not have the energy to fucking do this
this week.
So anyway,
we get these fucking badges and they
actually bring you into the house.
We sit in this library and I'm sitting
there and this woman is debriefing me
about these badges.
Okay.
I'm already freaked out about going to
the masters because there's a level of
whiteness and a level of education that,
uh,
even intimidates me is white as I am now.
Um,
if statically a, e, s, t, h, e, t, I,
C, a, l, l, Y. Aesthetically, I don't
even know if I spelled it right,
but I know how to spell it when
I'm not fucking brain dead.
It's one of my spelling words.
Let's get smart America. Um,
statically I'm very white.
Alabaster. If he asked my girlfriend,
that's how she describes
me. Um, porcelain ask,
that's how wide I am. But, uh, there's,
this is the different kind of white,
this is the most of the whole,
the food kind of white and a ivy
league kind of white Illuminati,
you know,
rubbing elbows with the Kennedys.
We summer in the Hamptons,
we have a house on Martha's vineyard.
You know, when Jesus comes back, he's
going to have to be buzzed into our house.
After we talked to our lawyer, our lawyer
will be present when Jesus judges me,
like that level of fucking white.
So I went on the Internet
and I actually was like the,
I know there's a dress code here and the
last thing I want to do when I go to a
place like that is I don't want to
come in there and disrespect the place.
I don't give a fuck about the approval of
those people. But you know what I mean?
You go into that place.
It's an unbelievable golf event.
I respect the history of it. Arnold
Palmer, Jack Nicklaus, Ben Hogan,
all that type of stuff.
So I want to go there and show it the
respect that it deserves. All right.
And also I don't want to walk in
there looking like a fucking bum.
So I go on the Internet and I check
out the dress code and it's literally
college shirt, no jeans
allowed, all this shit. So I,
for the first time in about,
I think 20 years, I actually,
when I had some sort of a suit job,
I actually bought a pair of dockers,
dockers, everybody, I at least I went
with the black ones. I did not buy khaki.
I refuse to ever wear khaki.
There's only two people in the world
where a khaki animal experts and date
rapists. All right, I'm not wearing khaki.
So I bought a pair of
black doctors and uh,
I had this blue like Nike Golf Shirt
and then I had the tiger woods,
um, the tiger woods, Nike Hat,
the black one with the Red v.
Why am I acting like I'm walking the
red carpet from my movie date night that
came out last weekend, which is
a huge fucking hit. Everybody.
I'm so fucking site.
Date night was a huge head.
It made a ton of fucking money and
if you went out and saw it, um,
I I want to say thank you because I hope
it's such a huge hit that they make a
fucking sequel and uh,
maybe I'll be able to repop
reprise my role as detective Walsh.
You know, maybe I'll be, if I'll,
I'll turn bad in the second one,
like a fucking key Ho
and another 48 hours.
Remember that I'll grow one of those.
A walrus mustaches.
I don't give a shit. It's the first movie
I've really booked ever in my career.
I'm averaging one every 18 years.
If I can go on a run with this thing,
I'll be psyched. For those
of you who haven't seen it
and, uh, enjoy this podcast.
This is not a podcast. This
is just a statement, uh,
but enjoy all the other free podcasts.
He just let me like, you know what,
he never comes and tours in my area
or I don't care to see his act live,
but I would like to
somehow pay it forward.
You could pay it forward by buying a
ticket to date night. You could even do,
we have bigger favor is if you're gonna,
if you've already seen it or you
don't even want to fucking see it,
you'd rather see another movie.
Do me a favor.
Just buy two tickets to date night and
just go into the other movie that you
wanted to anyways,
just so it pads the stats,
um, date nights starring
Steve Carell and Tina Fey.
Is that a local Cineplex near you?
Please go see it. So anyways, um,
so we get the badges and uh,
this is the deal.
You're not allowed to
bring a cell phone in.
You're not allowed to bring a camera
and you're not allowed to bring video
equipment and you're not
allowed to bring shit in.
All you're allowed to bring in is
yourself the close that cover you and some
fucking cash, some sunblock. That's it.
All right.
So you walk in there and you literally
get going through like a metal detector
like you going through the airport
and immediately there's this sense of,
uh, is the president nearby because
that's what this security feels like.
And uh,
and the big thing with these badges is
it's not like you get the badge at the
person's house. So where, however the
fuck you get it and you get to keep it,
you have to return the badge.
And when you have this badge,
you have the responsibility to not break
any rules because if they kick you out,
they take your badge.
So you'll never come again.
So not only can you never come again,
the person who's badge it was does not
get it back ever again no matter what.
Because you are obviously not good enough.
A judge of character,
considering that you gave this badge to
this person that we now have to eject.
And when I went there,
all I heard was stories of people that
they had seen get a Jackson, some ejected,
some guy actually got a cell phone in
there and it rang at some point during the
match. And people just
appear out of nowhere. Okay.
One guy puts you in a fucking show cold,
another guy snatches the badge off your
shirt and the badge has to be displayed
at all times. And you would think
with all those fucking people there,
if he didn't have it
displayed, you had, you know,
very small chance of someone's
stopping you. I didn't have my,
I had mine in my pocket and I
walked like 10 feet with it and Oh,
this guy just appeared out
of nowhere with his master's.
That green colored shirts or was your
batch, where's your bad sir, sir?
Do you have a badge? You
know, fucking gun drawn.
He may be reached in my pocket with
two fingers, you know, pull it on kin,
whatever. Um, so anyways,
so we walk out onto
that. W we get there. Uh,
first thing we do is we walk into the
pro shop and I already told myself I was
going to spend it like 400
bucks and I got dammit if I,
if I didn't see exactly what I did,
I got some shot glasses,
I got some golf balls,
I got some hats for people.
They actually sell those masters.
The flags,
you know that they have on the pins
all around there just as the masters,
2010 for re clean,
very elegant.
The Shit bought a bunch of those for
some friends and a couple of golf shirts,
you know, the usual bullshit. And
then I bought one of those, uh,
the best and the best souvenir I
ended up getting is you actually,
cause you don't want to stand up for
fucking 12 hours watching people golf.
What's up Cleo? Are you doing, I
didn't know you were lay in there.
Now you're do when you guys haven't
heard of fucking Moen lately.
Anyways, um, I just do that
for me. Um, so anyways,
uh, they sell these, these chairs there
that you can, uh, sit on. Oh Jesus.
You see, this is why this isn't a
podcast. And you hear what I just said.
They sell these chairs
that are you can set on,
is that what you do with the chair bill?
And they actually ended up being
one of the most coveted um,
souvenirs because when you go to
get on the plane the next day,
you see everybody got him,
they got him slung over their shoulders.
The way they fold up.
It looks like you're carrying like a yoga
mat except that weighs like fucking 20
pounds. So anyways, let's,
let's cut to the chase here cause I
got to finish this statement early. Um,
I went out onto the golf course and
those of you who are big fans of golf and
you watched the masters every year,
you got to go there because when
you go and you see the club house,
she can't go in it.
But when you see it and you
just start walking the course,
this is,
this is what I suggest.
Get there at like eight in the morning
and start at 18 and just walk the course
backwards all the way to the front.
I didn't do that because I had too
much shit that I bought and uh,
I just walk to different
holes that I really liked,
but that's what this guy told me to do,
walk the whole fucking course.
But we got there a little late because,
uh,
I was in a bar the night before watching
a guy with a box on his head sing songs
that I couldn't really understand.
Um,
but anyways,
you go onto the course and I,
I've never been to anything
like this as far as nature goes.
I've seen it was like seeing famous people
except they were, they were fair ways.
Like I walked
up in around,
so when I came to 18 I was in between
where you tee off and looking down the
fairway.
You know when someone's just bringing
it home and is going to win the masters,
there's a roadway where you walk across
and I looked right down that fairway and
I dunno. It's one of those fucking
things we just like, this really exists.
You know it isn't.
This is real.
And then you go over the
number 12 [inaudible].
I ain't got the little pamphlet here.
They've got all the holes are named the
12th hole. What the fuck do they call it?
They have like the Golden Bell is the
name of this is how white this is.
You guys want to hear
the names of the holes.
Now usually when I talk
about holes on the Pod,
it's a lot more crass than this
whole number one is called t olive.
All right? That's not to whole.
Number two is called Pink Dogwood.
Tell me there isn't a porno to
be made with some of these names.
Flowering Peach.
It's the third wall.
These are all mildly sexual.
They flowery crab.
Apple. Oh, that's the one where like if
you're into watching guys fuck old women,
this is really just going to get
disgusting. Fifth hole is Magnolia.
You get the point.
Juniper's is sixth
pompous. I don't what the fuck
at yellow jasmine, but whatever.
They got all these flowers and
everything's in bloom and it's just,
it's unbelievable.
It's unbelievable.
Walk around looking at all these famous
holes like I couldn't believe when I was
coming up onto 12 to see that little
bridge there on a whatever the fuck they
call it, the pink Petunia Golden Bell.
It's just unbelievable when you see it.
It's literally iconic. The same feeling
I got when I saw Big Ben in London.
How fucking awesome is my life
this past month when I saw Big Ben,
you just stare at it.
You can't believe it.
It's just something you've seen in your
whole life and now you're standing there
looking at it and I'm telling you
the fucking urge. This is the thing
about it. There was so many things.
You can't talk to the golfers. Like
if tiger hit something, hit the ball,
hits something. His wife, if
tiger hit the fucking ball,
you could literally go like, uh, you
know, as he came walking up to Bali back,
come on tiger. You could say something
like that maybe, but that's it.
After you hit the ball, he couldn't
be like, you're the big toe. You too.
I love you. That's it. Someone would
pair out of nowhere. Chloroform,
rag right over your fucking nose. Somebody
yells, yanks off your fucking badge.
And that's it.
They pummel you with Billy clubs that are,
that are the same colors,
the masters green and they just beat the
shit out of you and they toss you over
the fucking fence.
That's how it works. Um,
but I got to admit with all those rules,
all those rules,
the urge to just do something
like that and get kicked out,
like I almost had like Tourette's.
Um,
cause what I ended up doing is I settled
on the 15th hole and I sat in the
bleachers and I don't know
what that one's called,
wispy pubic hair with the
fuck do they call this one?
The 15th fucking hole is called
Firethorne and it had this,
uh,
so this is basically what we did.
We realized that there was so many
fucking people there and we had our chairs
that we had to lug around and
$40 worth of shit in his bag.
I wasn't gonna walk 18 holes
and just follow tiger around.
I didn't want to do it because there's
too many fucking people and there's
people camped out around where they tee
off and they're camped out around the
green.
So what you can basically do is run
down the fucking fairway if you can get
there,
knowing that all the golfers have a point
a to point B once they once you know,
just to keep playing,
moving.
You on the other hand have specific areas
where you can crossover fairways and
that type of shit. And if you don't,
they fucking, they, they, they,
they destroy you and they take your badge.
So,
um, we just said, fuck it. We're going
to go to 15. We're going to sit there.
We can watch them hit their second shots,
a power five,
and we look over our shoulder.
We can't see him tee off on 16,
but we could see the result of their shot.
And uh,
we sat there in the bleachers and
knowing that we had a good two and a half
hours to wait until they came,
I think it was actually three hours.
So we just sat there and a,
you would think it would be
boring as hell and it wasn't.
You just shoot the shit with other people,
older people who've gone to the
masters since like the early seventies,
late seventies, one guy from like 1952,
I didn't get a chance to talk to them,
but they talk about, you
know, Nicholas when in 86 and
all this shit was, you know,
if you're a sports fan,
it was fucking incredible.
And meanwhile all we're doing is we're
sitting waiting for the beer trap taps to
be turned on.
And this is how this sounds secretive,
this fucking places is no one had any
idea when they get turned on somebody up
in the clubhouse, in the inner
fucking catacombs of the clubhouse,
gives everybody the go ahead
to turn on the beer taps.
And they can't even tell you when they,
I don't know, maybe 1230, maybe one.
We're not sure. And they don't have any
advertising, so just says domestic beer,
regular beer. The whole fucking thing
is just like, look, we're in control.
All right, you want an
import? This is important.
You want to domestic. This is domestic.
What kind is it? I can't disclose that.
I'm not allowed to tell you when,
when are you turning to bear on?
We're not allowed to tell you, sir,
why are you being hostile? You know?
So we're just sitting there and there's
a couple of turtles outside the fucking
pawn there.
We start gambling on the turtles.
Which one's going to go in
the fucking water first?
Then they turn on the beer and we start
getting shit faced and we're waiting for
the first fucking golfers
to come. And then it's just
like the Indy 500. You just,
you just,
you just bet on golfers.
It's like the most elegant
track you've ever been to.
And you just wait and they come in
through to where time Ernie els, you know,
Kenny Paris coming through
fucking, uh, Sergio Valenti,
whatever his fucking name is, eat. And
they just right in front of you, the shit.
And you're just sitting there getting
hammered betting on golfers in fucking
turtles. That's what I did
all day. Sitting in the sun.
Fucking saw two holes in one,
or at least the results of them.
I heard him hit the green. No, it hits
the Green. And I hear the crowd go crazy.
I look over and I see it roll in the
cup and everybody goes fucking nuts. Um,
I lost 100 bucks in the first one
and one a hundred on the next one.
So I was even,
and I got to admit to it,
when you sit there and all of a
sudden you look in the end, you know,
taggers coming next because
you've got like the, uh,
the whole list of golfers
is fucking unreal. And you
see him come over the hill.
All right?
Like a fucking
one of those deer hunters say
15 horn fucking dare, man.
20 point are coming over the
hill and I got it. My such man,
I'm going to shoot her
ride the fucking head.
That was the other word is like target
comes over the Damn Hill he's wearing,
he sees, see him again, even see
him. He's so far away. You see a guy,
you see a black guy,
looks like a black guy who was actually
a mostly fucking Asian or whatever the
hell he is.
I don't know what the hell he is.
You see some Tan Dude beyond the Tan
that a white guy can get coming over the
hill with a red shirt and the
fucking black pants on you.
Like that's fucking tiger woods.
And a hush
just falls over the entire,
the entire hole is like 3000 people
sitting there and it's dead quiet.
And you just see that ball fucking just
flying. I saw an eagle, the fucking hall.
I saw him, Eagle it. I saw
Kim, the Korean Dude Eagle it.
Uh,
I think I saw that it was an Ernie els.
That was another thing that kinda sucked,
was kind of hard to tell if
it was their second or third.
You just knew with guys like
Kim [inaudible], tiger woods,
the way they drove that, it
was his second shot. Anyways,
whatever was fucking awesome.
And uh,
Phil Mickelson came in last cause he
was on the leaderboard and once he went
past us, I ran, I ran off
the bleachers, went down.
And actually he's the
only guy I watched t off,
watched him tee off on 16 and then we
grabbed our shit and we ran over to 18 and
tiger. It already finished. But we
stood there halfway down the f three,
three quarters of the way up the 18th
at at Augusta and watched Mickelson tee
off. We watched him hit his
second shot and then we were,
we couldn't see through the crowd
when he sunk the winning Putt, eh,
but we stood there and I looked between
a bunch of fucking blue bloods heads and
I watched him put the green jacket on and
get choked up when he talked about his
wife. And it was one of the most
incredible experiences I've ever had.
And uh, it's making me really thankful
for the incredible fucking life I have.
And A, I hope this isn't building
resentment with you guys. You know,
you just lay off drinking
for a little bit. You know,
you could get by one of those badges
by his stinking badge and go next year.
Just do one thing. Do One fucking
thing. You know, I don't fucking know.
I don't know what I'm saying.
This is, these are just,
this is just my statement that
I'm not doing a podcast this week.
I'm not fucking doing it, but I
know you could. You can go there.
It was cost me 600 bucks. I know that's
a of fucking money. I know it is.
But think how much money you blow
each weekend and a bar. All right?
Figure out what you blow each weekend
and a bar. Here's a good way to do it.
It's a nice healthy way.
And just,
just go on the wagon for a while and then
just take the money that you would've
spent on booze.
He put it into your Augusta Fund.
You know it just fucking drive there.
Do a fucking road trip.
Get yourself a pair of dockers
and a golf shirt. All right,
have a nice and pressed and clean
drive like a God damn maniac.
Both you and your buddy. Even if
you live in Seattle, trade off,
drive all the fuck way down there. Go
into somebody's house, get debriefed,
walk in there,
act like a gentleman and get
to see something that most
people never get to see.
And what's great is
there all the souvenirs.
They don't really sell
anything on the Internet.
So that's why you buy a ton of shit is
because everybody asks you to get him
some stuff. And even
if they don't, you got,
you got great gifts for
the rest of the year.
You know he can do all your
Christmas shopping right there.
You get somebody a fucking
hat at the masters,
they're going to be site because no one
else is going to have that fucking hat.
And unless they went there.
So there you go.
And that's the end of my
statement for this week. People,
38 minutes statement actually
flew back this morning.
And uh, I was, I was an idiot. I
got something in me like I was,
I was a little more buzz than I thought
it was and I was really tired and I got
three hours sleep. I'm fucking
embarrassed. I yelled at a cop
when I drove out of the master's,
it was like,
it was really late because we stuck
around to the end and it was like,
it was,
we sat through this fucking traffic
and all I had to do was make a left and
drive like 40 yards down the road and I
could jump on the fucking highway and I
was on my way and I was exhausted
and I wanted to go to sleep.
And what ends up happening,
it's one of those deals with a cop's
decide that everybody's going to go right.
We're forcing everyone,
right?
And I want to go left so I can go a
cunt hair down the street and get on the
highway. So I got my window down. I'm
like, I can't go left the guy or not.
He could keep the, keep going.
So I'm driving and I'm not,
I know what they're doing. So I get to
the third cop and I see a gas station.
I'm just like, I just want
to get some gas. Can I get
some gas guys? Like keep it,
go and keep him moving. I just
went to one, I can't get some gas,
just like that.
Fucking screamed at him as I drove by
because he was on foot and cause I was a
little drunk and then I drove
away and all of a sudden I was,
couldn't feel my legs going like,
did I just fucking do that as a Yankee
in the middle of fucking Georgia?
Did I just yell at that guy clearly
though, was I just obnoxious?
And then I was like, I don't give a
shit. And the first left I could make,
I made a left and then I banked
one of the most illegal fucking,
you turns to hybrid three
point fucking turns.
And there were two cops sitting
right there. And my buddy's like Doo,
Doo Doo Doo dote, which is
universal for, there's a cop,
Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh, Doh. And I was like,
yeah, I don't give a fuck. And he's like,
what's wrong with you?
And I'm Michael [inaudible].
I'm a little buzzed and
I'm a control freak.
Don't fucking tell me where I can't go.
I've been on that Goddamn
golf course every day.
All I wanted to do is run out of the
bleachers on somebody approaching shot on
15 and do a fucking cannon ball
right into that little mini lake.
Already had it planned out. It's going to
give my badge to my buddy and tell him,
don't take a walk though. What do you
mean take? Just take a fucking walk.
And he'd see it, my eyes
and be like, all right man.
And he just grabbed my shit
and he'd just walk away.
And then what I would do is I do a cannon
ball right into the fucking lake. Okay.
And I would immediately
be a fucking legend,
an absolute fucking legend on the,
on jackass.com if there's something, you
know, I'd be right up there with fan man,
that fucking kid at Yankee stadium who
jumped off into the, into the, the,
the backstop netting.
I Dunno who else.
That dude who ran out and grabbed the
football and got slammed down to the
ground by the linebacker on Monday night
football. I'd be one of those guys.
I'd be put on that fucking, you
know, whacked out sports or whatever.
I would be on that shit forever.
And then when they asked me, when
they pulled me out of there, you know,
and they went to grab my badge, I
wouldn't have it. Where's your badge?
I know it must be at the bottom
of the pond there. Thurston,
why don't you take off your loafers and
roll up your slacks and go in there and
try and find it.
What's the worst you're going to do to me?
Prosecute me to the full
extent of the law. You know,
they know every big judge in the state.
I'd probably still be in fucking prison,
but I got to admit and I dunno.
So anyways,
so then I just drove the rest of the
fucking way home. I stopped at Arby's,
went to bed at fucking 12 midnight,
had to get up at six 30 and had gone
on a fucking plane. I had a Muffin,
I had an m and m's and there
was a baby crying the whole way.
And I don't give a shit. I know I
never care when babies cry on planes,
I don't give a fuck.
But there was some square had cut in
front of me who kept turning around and
looking at them, you know,
that was like, all right,
that's the career woman who hates kids.
I see why she's looking at him.
She didn't want to have kids.
So she's annoyed with their presence.
And then I see she has a
wedding ring and what's what's,
there's only one reason to get
married. They have kids. Okay.
So I'm looking at her like she
must be the worst mother ever.
Cause every time this kid cries,
she turns around,
starts looking for a mother
shooting alert, shooting
her look, shaking our heads,
and just want to be like, you know what?
It's a fucking baby. It's a fucking base.
She had a baby, man. It's a
fucking baby. It's unbelievable.
When I hate when people do that shit, it's
like, how do you not understand? Like,
you know, we're in a pressurized cabin.
That thing does the Bait, the thing,
the baby does not a clear its ears.
It's a fucking baby. Stupid cunt.
So at one point I fucking,
she looked and I gave her such a dirty
look for fucking given the mother a dirty
look that when her
fucking eyes met my eyes,
she looked at me like surprised at first
and then realized that she was being a
cunt. And then she tried to play it off
with this smile like yeah, isn't it cute?
Isn't that cute? That the baby's crying
too late? I've already judged you.
You're a horrible mother and you're
a horrible person. And that stands.
This is the conclusion of my statement.
43 minutes said that I am not
doing a podcast this week.
I regret to inform all of you that due
to circumstances beyond your control,
um,
our hosts this week,
Bill burr abused his body
to such a fucking level that
he had an inability to do
a podcast this week and only
had an ability to, you know,
I should have done I in,
in,
in the spirit of the masters when I should
have done was I should have issued an
apology just like tiger woods
and droned on for 45 minutes.
Boring the shit out of you. Oh, wait
a minute. I think I already did that.
I believe I already did that.
All right,
that's the podcast for this week.
Once again,
I'm so sorry that I couldn't
give you a podcast this week.
I couldn't give you some laughs.
Um, I will become an hour fucking,
I'll give you both barrels next week.
Speaking of which,
I'm going to be at the funny
bone in a Newport, Kentucky, uh,
right across the river from Cincinnati.
And I gotta be honest with you guys.
I got to, I already have a new
killer hour. That's right. I said it,
I said it all right. Maybe
it's not a killer hour.
It's like 40 minutes out of the hour.
I already have 40 new fucking minutes.
How do you like that shit?
I just taped a special in December.
All right.
We're midway through April and I already
can run my fucking mouth for 40 minutes
with some new shit provided them on.
If I'm off,
I have eight new minutes.
That's where my act, his act.
But I'm not going to lie to you.
I talked about Tiger Woods for
like 11 minutes the other night.
All of it's funny, crushing,
destroying. I was so sites,
but in the back of my head,
I'm like,
you realize that now after
he plays the masters,
uh, that, you know, I can only
tell that story for so long.
It's basically mid May. It's going
to be an old story. It already is.
I'm still talking about that
lady who got killed at seaworld.
I'm going to give you a little preview
of what we'll be talking about.
The white talking about my trip to
church and when, again, by the way,
uh, what again? On Easter.
I went on Easter Sunday,
you know, my girlfriend's
mom wanted to go to church.
She didn't want to go by herself. So
I said, all right, I'll go with you.
We all went little happy
family. I went there, sat there,
bored shitless.
It was extra packs took
to eat that piece of
cardboard at the end of it.
And whatever other of offensive
thing you want me to say.
Uh, I dunno, I literally
am like sitting here.
I'm laying here right now and I have, I'm
like, my eyes are squinting. Like, uh,
there's a doctor and he's like, you
know, like by fucked up my elbow.
And he's like, tell me, tell me,
does this hurt? Does this yet? Yeah,
you heard yet right there.
I'm literally doing that right now as
I'm doing this fucking podcast. Um,
I got nothing.
All right,
I got nothing for you this week and I'm
the first one to tell it to you. And uh,
oh, did I, you know what
I say actually did this,
started this podcast like six fucking
times. I forget if I said this, but, uh,
somebody sent me a really
nasty email yelling,
cursing me out because they sent me an
email and I didn't answer their email.
And he said,
because you didn't answer my email.
I didn't go to see any of
your shows in Atlanta. And,
uh, I don't know if I
already talked about this.
I apologize if I didn't. Uh, sir, I
don't give a shit. All right. If you,
if you haven't learned anything for my
podcast is I really don't give a fuck.
I don't give a fuck if you
listen to this or you don't.
I don't give a fuck if you go to my
shows, but you don't, I don't give a fuck.
You know, do I, do I not want people
to come to my shows? Of course I do.
Do I not want people listen to my podcast?
Of course I don't. I want, fuck, I don't,
I ain't got, I got, I got messed
up there in those double negatives.
I want people to come to my shows.
I want people to listen to my podcast,
but let me tell you some right now. Fuck.
Oh, I don't respond to fucking threats.
Don't fucking threaten me or no fucking,
you know,
try to put some sorta almond is bullshit
on how you want me to fucking behave
with your fucking email.
I don't give a fuck about email.
I get a fucking hundreds of emails every
God Damn Week and if I don't get to
yours, I don't fucking get to
yours. So go fuck yourself.
If you want to pout and not come
to my show, don't go to my show.
I don't give a fuck.
You sound like a cunt anyways.
You probably go to my show and then
fucking judge it. It'd be like, oh,
the first eight minutes. We're
good. Did they do it for me?
12 to 17 go fuck yourself.
All right,
why don't you go stick your head
through your fucking computer monitor.
God knows you probably still
have one of those old ones,
you know shaped like a fucking microwave.
Is that what you got?
Is you work? Look how fast people
drive in this fucking street.
I'm literally getting to that age,
yelling out the window at kids.
Stop driving like I did.
At your age.
There's another good
character for a sketch,
you know, crabby, honest,
old man, honest, crabby,
old man.
Stop treating me with the same disrespect
I had from my elders when I was at
your age. Um, or maybe not shit.
God knows.
SNL could turn that into like it's 15
minutes sketch and then stretch it into an
hour and 40 minute movie.
Um, all right, there we go.
I burned a bridge.
I burned a bridge there.
Like I was going to get cast on
that at 41. Uh, maybe I could,
it didn't feel harm again on old or what
I perceived to be old when he got on.
He was probably like 34 at the time, which
was ancient to me. And now at my age,
I would love to be, I would
love to be fucking 34 again, uh,
to be that age. Um, you know, I remember,
you know what was great about
when I was a fuck when I was 34,
I could run like a fucking seven,
nine 40,
when I was 30,
when I was 34.
It was a very good year.
I fucking dog.
Just lick the bottom of my foot.
It's a goddamn freak.
I didn't have a dog that shit on
the floor or needed to go outside.
I did what I wanted.
I went down water slides
when I was 34 what's up Cleo?
How you doing?
You know site that wants to see you.
You know it's like to see you
cause you were psyched to see me.
You're always psyched to see me, aren't
you? You know my dog actually misses me.
Comes into the bedroom at night and it
fucking looks around for me and then it
runs into my little office
area looking for me. Right.
If I'm not around who you're
going to wrestle with.
Let me see if I can get you to mode.
You won't do it.
Will you know what you're,
why you liked that fucking frog and
bugs bunny and beat by peak water back.
Then all of a sudden I bring in somewhere.
Hey Cleo,
let me see if I can get you to
how you want to go outside. Cleo,
this is going to be worth it. People just
listen. Cleo. You want to go outside?
Huh?
Cleo.
Cleo. Okay. She's getting psyched to Cleo.
Clio. Clio. I wonder to how,
come on Cleo,
you want to go side
Cleo, but you fucking do it please. Clia.
Clia. Ah, you fucking burned
in me right now. Cleo.
Hey. Fuck it. Cleo
on the west side.
Okay,
Cleo. You know what? Go Fuck
Yourself. Jesus Christ. What
was that? Three minutes.
Yup. Below it. Cleo. Why won't you,
how for these people
and in conclusion, uh, there
is no podcasts this week.
I regret to inform you.
Don't come over now. Don't come
over now. You want some food?
You want to go outside,
Cleo?
Well, let me one more temp.
Yeah, you want to go outside?
Hmm. Cleo. Yeah.
Oh,
Jesus screen or this is like,
you know what you mean right
now you have these like,
you know the hot chick that'll never
fuck you and she just keeps giving you a
glimmer of hope and to keep coming back.
You keep coming back,
whatever. I still love you cleo. You know,
even though he just made me look like
a fucking asshole, you really did.
It was literally the Buler.
Anybody? Anybody. All right.
That concludes my statement.
That's the statement I'm sticking by.
It's all in the police report is tiger
woods would say, ah, there you go.
There's another thing you should do.
Pick one of these fucking things to do
and if one of you guys ends up doing
something that I told you
to do and you enjoy it,
please send me an email like a year
from now. If you go to the masters,
Lemmy fucking no. All right. Cause I
think I'm going to go again next year.
That's how much fucking fun I had.
Or go to England,
do some shit to something for fuck sakes.
Alright, I'll talk to you next time.