Hey, what's going on is bill burn?
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And I am just checking in on you will,
oh, sorry. I didn't bring my
fucking microphone like an asshole.
Um, all right. How you
doing? I'm out in New Jersey.
Oh Gee.
To this fucking room is nasty.
You know what the first fucking thing
I found here was a goddamned raising on
the floor. Then there was some
sort of stain on the dead. God,
the fucking New Jersey man. I
swear to God, swear there was just,
you know what they'll do?
They'll never be able to vacuum and
scrub the fucking hair metal out of this
state.
It's just what went on out in this
God damn part of the world in the 80s.
I swear to God,
fucking played like the A,
I had one of these great travel
days and then it sucked. You know,
I uh, found a cheap
ticket, got an exit row.
There was nobody in the middle
seat. Right? The person on
the aisle was courteous.
We had a fucking tailwind.
One point I was watching us,
we go on 603 miles an hour.
I'm like, what are we on?
The fucking Kong could always,
um,
it was great. So then we land, you know,
I'm no longer with budget rental car.
Fuck those guys.
I don't know what happened with them.
I've been meaning to like leave
them for six years. There was a,
there was something
happened over the last five,
six years and I have lose meaning
to walk out on a typical of me.
And when I'm in a bad relationship,
it takes a good half a decade
for me to get out of it. So, um,
yeah,
yeah. After that, that last
fucking conversation I had,
mmm.
You know, with them where they were like,
oh, you, you didn't close your account.
And I had to get back on the phone and
talk to those fucking assholes. It's like,
just close the fucking thing so you
have to be on the phone. I got it, dude.
I don't have time for this. He
said, sir, the more you talk,
and I just hung up on him. I was just, I
could lead to the fucking leave it open.
I don't give a shit.
Okay.
Why you acting like I still have the car.
Sorry. Um, when am I gonna like
react to things in a mature way?
I just don't, I, every time I
take the fucking bag, I freak out.
I got into it with the Sklar brothers.
I did their fucking podcast. Right.
And both of them, you know,
talk in sports, both of them
agreeing with each other.
And then one was in the, it was like, it
was just like, it was like arguing with,
with one person and Stereo.
Okay.
And one of them,
Randy adjacent,
they never reintroduced themselves either.
They'll like fucking identical twins.
They're always changing their facial hair.
I literally, I've called each one of them
buddy for fucking 15 years. Hey Buddy,
what's going on? I used to know Randy
because Randy had the facial hair. So my,
my thing in my head was like rugged Randy.
He's got the facial hair.
Then they started fucking switching
off with the goatees and, and I,
and the fucking, uh, Don
Mattingly Baseball fucking, uh,
mustaches. I don't know
who's who anymore. Right.
Okay.
So you know, we're having a nice
podcast. Everything's going good,
and we'd brings up Tom Brady and he has
to bring up fucking deflate gate and I
fucking lost it.
I fucking lost it.
I just hate the gym or say like,
he like one.
Yeah,
he successfully ran a fucking bullshit
smear campaign that will follow that guy.
Okay.
An innocent man for the
rest of his fucking career.
Okay.
You know what he should've done?
He should've had performance enhancing
drugs sent to his house in his wife name
because evidently benches fitches
flies away. That's no big deal.
Unreal on fucking real.
And then it was funny though,
they're that cool though because
afterwards I was so fucking annoyed.
Okay.
By him just seeing it that way and like
blaming Tom Brady for not getting out in
front of this stupid witch hunt.
Right. That I actually called him up.
This is how much time I wasted my life
being upset and caring about sports for
whatever fucking reason.
You know,
I'd call him up and I start talking to
them and it finds out like he didn't even
know half the facts of the story.
Okay.
So I was like,
dude,
that's like reprehensible few be going
on in their trash and this guy and you
don't even know that the fucking
better say paid for that fucking dope.
It wasn't all at that.
Should I know this is all right.
But he brought it back up again,
you know,
and uh,
I got to give it up to him.
He fucking manned up and went back on his
podcast and actually apologize for not
knowing a couple of those fucking things,
but I just all you fucking,
I'm telling you right now,
yeah.
It's just a bunch of fucking
patriots haters at this point.
If you're going to ignore
fucking hearing aids and helmets,
performance enhancing drugs,
centi wife for you out in
all of that just goes away.
But this fucking deflated fucking cunt
hair with the air out of a ball doesn't,
then I eat. You are, you are in
my world. You are just, you just,
you just hate on the Patriots. All right.
Now if you give everybody shit, okay.
And every time they bring up these other
guys' names, you go, oh, wait a minute.
You mean the guy who's offensive
line head, the hearing aids.
You mean that guy,
you're going to do that,
then they're not going to fucking do that.
You're not going to do it.
And it happened in Indianapolis.
Yeah.
That doesn't matter.
Those are simple people out there.
They put their pants on one leg at
a time. Hey Guy, I get it. It, yeah,
fucking give a shit bag. Um, so
anyways, my travels going great.
And um,
so I was actually upset at
myself for getting that worked up
okay.
About something that I really thought
I was over. You know what I mean?
It was like seeing a chick he broke
up with, he was like, you know,
I'm finally ready to fucking move on.
And then, you know, you run into in a,
and she just says that one thing and you
go right back to the fucking end of the
relationship,
fucking talking yourself in the bathroom.
And she'd taken a shower,
you know,
just completely losing your shit while
kind of watching yourself going like,
dude, she's winning. Just shut
up. She's winning. And you just,
but you got to get it out of you.
MMM.
So anyways, I was sitting on the plane,
right? We get off the fucking plane
and,
uh,
I drive out here to fucking Red
Bank, New Jersey, and I show up
and I got my bags and it's like seven,
I think it was seven 48 in the morning.
I took a red eye,
right?
And I come walking in and the second I
saw the lady behind the desk looks at me.
I know my room's not going to be ready.
And I come walking in and I'm like, Yay,
I got a reservation. And she's
already shaking your head. She's like,
we don't have, it's seven 48 in
the morning. I go, no, no, no. Uh,
but I paid for the room overnight so I
could come in early and she sits like,
yeah, no you didn't.
Yeah, we don't have that.
And then my blood starts going
up so I start going like,
you mean to tell me that I have to and
I almost fell asleep on the ride over
here cause I couldn't
really sleep on the plane.
MMM.
I blood starts going up and
I'm sitting there going like,
are you mean to tell me I have to
drive around red bank until like two,
three o'clock in the afternoon?
She's like, I can try to expedite.
But I was able to calm myself
down. I was like, you know what?
I already got into it
with the Sklar brothers.
Why do I want to get involved with this
fucking person? This nice person here,
you know, she had, see she,
she has nothing to do with
these decisions. I fucked up.
Somebody fucked up, but she didn't.
Right. So I just said, I find, she goes,
you want to drop off your bags? I say yes.
I vaguely remember driving to a diner.
Okay.
And getting some eggs benedict
looking at this guy,
you know, who do you ever see those
guys? They just slept. I Dunno.
They just have bandaids all over him.
Like just, they had like 20 tests.
Just take my second. I saw the guy
was like, this guy is not good.
This guy's not gonna be around for
a long time. You know what I mean?
I was in like one of these Tony
Soprano fucking, uh, you know,
looked like that one. You know what?
You don't let one where, uh, Jimmy,
the gent comes walking
out and he knocks on the,
the guy's falling up their window.
Let's go fuck hoes.
They kicked me up all night.
They look like one of those places
and I just looking at this guy,
why this guy is not going to be,
he's not gonna be around for awhile.
Um,
you know,
man, he was like, fuck it. And he was
eating eggs and bacon. It's just like, oh,
there you go. Go out the way
you want to go out. Right.
So I get back in the car and like,
I don't know what did,
what am I going to fuck do you do? So I
just drove back to the hotel parking lot,
reclined the seat,
crack the whip and just slept in the car.
It was funny was every 40 minutes I wake
up and I'd be sweating because the sun
was coming up more and more in the
car was getting hotter and hotter.
So I'd have to turn the car on,
roll the windows down a little more
and then go back to sleep. And uh,
I did that for about like from,
I dunno,
30 in the morning to
about a quarter to 12.
I'm 25 years into my career and this,
the road is always going to be the road.
This is well, he's going to happen
and uh, I got to tell you though,
I feel great.
I got a fucking really
good three hours came in,
checked in, grabbed my
bags, hit the hotel gym,
knocking out the podcast.
Um,
anyways. Yeah, you guys
got to listen to that,
that Sklar one cause it's really good.
Those guys fucking know that shit man.
They really know their shit when it comes
to a fucking, uh, sports and everything.
And I kept teasing them that they
did not look athletic at all.
You know when they would like trash
and Michael Jordan saying he petty,
he's petty and it's just like, you guys
aren't going to be those guys are you?
The last guy picked it,
did gym class and then when there's
somebody as great as Michael Jordan,
okay,
you, you, you just can't accept
it. He's great. You still have to,
who the fuck says Michael? Jordan's
petty. Like you hung out with them.
You Watch one speech,
he brings up the guy,
okay.
That he beat out in high school to
introduce him. That makes him petty.
You don't know him.
What it really is is you see yourself
in that guy given the intro to Mike.
So now you got to look at him like he's
like, he's an asshole or something.
Give me a fucking break and then
we'll do bug you guy who gave the,
gave you oh really? Heavier.
Hung out with them then shut up.
And also all of them, they've, Jordan
never walked into their studio,
they would never call him petty.
Their voices would go up nine octaves.
They'd ask him to sign this form,
there's a fucking forehead draw the
Air Jordan thing right on there.
They go down to a tattoo parlor and have
it tattooed. So, uh, enough already.
Um, so anyways, sorry, I'm,
I'm literally gonna get worked up about
that thing. Oh, so anyways, it bugged,
it bugged him. A one of them, I don't know
what if it was Randy adjacent. Alright.
It Bud, one of them that I was
saying, they weren't athletic,
so he sends me a video of him and his
culdesac shooting a basketball in slow
motion from really far
away and it goes in.
And that was some sort of
demonstration that he was athletic.
I still haven't trashed him for it yet.
Okay.
It's just like, dude, there was nobody
garden you, it wasn't a game. You know,
he's like,
that was the second attempt.
I hate those stupid fucking videos.
There was one the other night where a
guy's in a helicopter is in the Robinson
44 and he throws him fucking basketball
out and it goes through the hoop.
It's like if you, if he
could do it consistently, if
he did it on the first try.
Yeah. That's impressive. That
poor guy flying the helicopter.
You point me to keep landing cause they
kept collecting the basketballs and they
fucking go back up. Then it
finally goes through. Yeah.
You know you do it enough times.
Yeah. It's going to go in. Um,
anyways, uh, so I'm going
to try to eat like an angel.
I've been doing really good. I
The ball, Billy knows booze bag.
You know when I went out Tuesday night
cause it was Joe to Rose's birthday and
I'll tell you right now, I'm on my liver
is so happy. Joe's only turn 40 once.
Oh Oh let me tell you,
I was so hung over the next day I woke
up like laughing. It was like, it was,
it was so pathetic. I felt so bad
it wasn't, it wasn't even like,
it would be redundant to actually
feel bad at that point. And, uh,
I actually got up,
forced down half a glass of water
and I went out and I worked out,
hung over as shit,
you know,
stretching out the hammies my big dumb
fucking head down towards my ankles,
you know, stretching out my hands and my
head was just going to Gush, Gush, Gush,
you know. But I gotta tell you that's
where it be in German. Irish comes in,
cause you will plow fucking
through anything. You know
what I mean? Is that was,
that was Versie with
this Mediterranean blood,
knowing how to live life and, you
know, smell the roses. Eh, this,
he would've called in sick to work
if he got up a second before 2:00
AM I'm telling you, Paul Versey,
he would have been moaning. You know what
I mean? Like he just shattered his leg.
Uh Oh did, we had a great time. We
had a great time. We went to two.
We went to this old school when
the oldest restaurants in, um,
and a Hollywood on Hollywood boulevard.
Got It. I got a great steak, uh,
split it with Nia and Joe got this
fucking prime rib that I'm telling you,
dude was like, I know that people
always say the Flintstones.
It was fucking gigantic. And I
looked at it and he goes, dude,
you gotta try it man. This
is amazing. I was like, wow.
And I looked down and I swear to God,
it felt like six minutes later and I
looked up and he was like down to the last
two bites.
I mean,
did they take the kids and animal 40
years old is no slowing them down.
And then we ended up at
the American Legion and um,
yeah. And I don't remember much after
that. I remember I, I got him a cake,
you know, that's said a bunch of
horrible things about them on it.
And next thing you know,
I was sitting in something that sort
of resembled a tree fort or like a band
stand kind of thing outside in the parking
lot with like nine other people that
I don't even know where they came from.
And we were all smoking cigars
and then I did the Irish goodbye.
Um, somebody called me an Uber and
that was it. But you know what?
I'm right back on it though. You know,
every once in a while you know, you don't,
you gotta, you gotta fucking slap you
liver ramp, let it know who's boss. Okay.
Then other than that, you know, you
take, you take care of it. You know,
I have an abusive relationship with
my, with my liver, but, uh, anyways,
I'm out here, uh, doing red
bank count Basie, theater,
theater, uh, let me know some good spots
to eat out here. If you guys know, um,
I've never stayed out here,
but I'm excited to be out here and not
have to deal with the fucking traffic
coming out of Manhattan and,
um,
I can't wait to do these fucking shows
because once these things is a great
theater and, uh, I'm really loving where
my act is at. And then on Sunday night,
all things,
comedy network is producing its first
standup special with Paul Versey.
Forsee yeah, yeah, yeah.
At the Tarrytown theater
and beautiful Tarrytown, New
York City. I mean, Tarrytown,
New York, Not New York City,
upstate New York or I don't know,
they get all upset if you say
upstate upstate to them is pick kipsy
um, the Westchester area,
whatever the fuck it is. Um,
it's right on the water. Um, if you guys
never been to that part of the country,
I mean it really is.
It's fucking gorgeous.
Like sleepy hollow is up there.
You got the Hudson River. I mean,
it's like, um, you know what it's like,
it's,
it's like how most non white people
think white people live valley think all
white people live. Um, it
is really, really, really,
really quaint. I made, it's just
like, I mean, it's just see like I,
where's the pumpkin patch? It's like shit
like that, you know, homemade ice cream.
Yeah. This everything, but those,
what does those fucking creepy things the
girls used to hold and they would skip
around a little girls and the playground.
Okay, here we go. Round the fucking day.
The fuck could they wonder, was it called
the Mayberry at the Mayberry Bush? No,
they just, you know, that's back when
they didn't let women do anything.
So like that was their idea of playing.
You just grab on this string and you guys
skip around. Yeah. You know what I mean?
Why we're fucking guys are playing sports.
Trying to figure out each other's
weaknesses. I guess women were doing that,
but on a different level. Right.
I bet she doesn't like her nose.
I'm going to say something
about that. Um, I'm sorry.
I'm still, uh, I'm still fucking
shit. What do you want from me?
I slept on a fucking, I mean,
you know what I, by the way,
I don't even know what
the fuck I slept in.
He's got Damn Carson and they all
looked the same and then I don't,
their logos are so
fucking like jazzy. I can,
you know the Honda used to just
be a fucking age. Yeah, isn't it?
So the fucking shit that I get upset about
it. It's just so stupid. Really value.
Well, why don't you just fucking go
on the Internet and look them up?
What are they supposed to have the
same logo for the rest of the law? I,
fair enough. Hey, fair
enough. Fair enough.
They've got freckles. Needs
fucking meditate here. Um, anyways,
how about those five of those red socks,
Huh?
Yeah.
Just tearing through the bottom
part of the fucking league.
The real test comes this weekend when
they play the ag right where we were with
you. She'll be again. Now it isn't,
it all ended in 2004 but it's still fun,
right?
The baby bombers first to
fucking $200 million Red Sox,
all the dealer that,
you know what?
I Bet America would be rooting
for the Yankees. You know,
they created all of this shit.
You know,
you know what the Yankees are? They're
like, dude, fucking the bad influence.
Older brother, you know who did
well and like, you know, uh,
preschool,
elementary,
right through middle school and then
somewhere in high school just start,
just went off the fucking rails.
And then the red socks.
I like the next brother who had
the fucking try to outdo him.
That's what we're doing.
We went right over the cliff.
Now spend it too and fucking
million dollars. 200 million.
God Damn Doll was the middle child,
the fucking middle child.
Um,
but anyways,
we went nine and one in the last 10 games
were up for games on the Yankees over
there.
Thank you to the Tampa Bay devil rays.
I'm still calling you the
devil race instead of the race.
Ray's Pizza,
Ray Romano. Come on, right.
What are you, you're the devil race. Um,
that's gotta be one of the,
like,
that's one of another thing goes back
to that Colin Kaepernick thing. Like,
it's a fucking,
it's just,
it's a corporation is everybody
tries to put race on it.
At the end of the day it's a fucking
corporation and that's what it is.
All they have to do is look
at the Tampa Bay devil rays.
There was probably nine Jesus freaks
that weren't going to buy a fucking devil
rays tee shirt and God forbid they lose
that fucking hundred and 60 bucks or
whatever, whatever, whatever, 180
bucks or 20 bucks a whack, right?
God forbid that that goes out the door.
They take the fuck they
took the devil right off it.
We're losing our a Jesus Freak,
a fan base.
You know, and I think that's what the
NFL is doing with Colin Kaepernick.
God forbid they lose the racist dollar.
That's what it is.
They are catering to the racist by not
putting this guy on cause they don't want
to lose cause a racist dollars are also
green and that's all they give a shit
about. Right. They don't give a fuck.
Look at the fucking Goddamn Tigers.
They're gonna fingerprint
their own fucking fence.
What do you think those
tigers front office is going
to do with that information?
Where do you think they're
going to sell that?
Do you know what? This is the
thing, most people, I swear to God,
I hate to be this cynical,
but they just,
they just fucking go into life and they're
looking for like someone else to fill
the role of their parents. And that's
why the micro chipping the fingerprints,
all of that will be inevitable because
there's so many people who should be
walking around wearing a fucking diaper.
I hate to say, but they do, you know,
oh, he's crying. Life fucked
me over there. You know what?
I'm going to start to sell it. I'm going
to start selling adult size rattles
as I sit here whining and crying about
sports, I got a lot of fucking nerve.
You know, that's one of the great things
about me. I'm a God damn hypocrite. Hey,
guess what? I got to, I got a, uh,
I've got a Gopro for my birthday last
year and I finally had Andrew come over
and show me how to fucking
get the thing going.
I just saw the wires and the
small printing. I just like,
I'm never going to figure that out.
I can't get it out of the case.
I actually got this thing to film
when I was flying, uh, you know,
the helicopter and uh, I got all
the shit that I needed and I just,
I don't know. Oh, I know.
I fucked up my back last year
so I couldn't fly because
my feet were going numb
there.
Yeah.
MMM.
So anyways, I, let me, let me
read a little bit of advertising.
Can we try to gracefully get out of this?
Um,
I feel bad about that Sklar podcast
cause I think they thought I really got
upset. It's just, I don't think they
know me well enough to be like, no,
that's just kinda how the fuck I get
when I talk about sports to somebody's
bugging me in two seconds later,
you know, it's, it's gone. You know,
it will come back, but I mean,
it's gone. It's over. All
right, Luke. Craig, everybody.
Give me a be the envy of your friends
and get your 100% exclusive crates at
[inaudible] dot com slash burr and
enter my code bar to save $3 off any new
subscription.
August Lou Craig theme his kingdom.
Um, if you're more of a
fanatical fashion Easter,
then try loot where monthly wearables
and accessories with cold classics and
your favorite franchises. I this mine is
well being a different fucking language.
I have no idea what this stuff is.
Is this just a bunch of shit so you
can dress up like the people on,
on the shows you like that I've never
heard of. If you want to get fancy,
get a bigger box with an even bigger Lu
Lu with loot crate dx one to kick out
your pet. Try loop pets. Oh Jesus.
Offer expires August 19th at 9:00
PM Pacific and August loot crate.
You'll find items from
the legends of Zelda.
Yeah.
Who's that?
Some old queen adventure,
adventure time and Lord of the rings.
Oh my God.
Oh that you could fucking have a world
further from what I'm in right there.
I went to one of those Lord of the
Rings, I swear to God, I thought it,
I thought the movie was over like 19
times. It kept fading down. I'm like, oh,
thank God he's a credit.
A head fade back up again.
You looking over another valley,
uh,
one lucky subscriber will also when a
mega crane or seriously epic of seriously
epic proportions.
Okay.
You have until the 19th at 9:00 PM
Pacific time to subscribe and receive that
month's crate. And when the cutoff
happens, that's it. It's over.
You can no longer get your robe and your
crown in prince around like the Lord of
the ring.
Go to loot crate.com/burr and enter
my code burr to save $3 off on any new
subscription today. All right. How
many of these fucking things we got?
Yeah,
mega crate. There must be a mega
church. Come on down to a mega church.
I was listening to Joel Olsteen
on the way over here, you know,
and he's like the Pied
Piper of fucking losers.
He's always talking about people
losing in life. You know what I mean?
It's like they'll do any winners.
Go to your church. He's always like,
I know you fucking, I know. Uh, I know
your plumbing doesn't work. I know this.
Does he? He know, but God wants you. God
wants you to have working water. Blink,
blink, blink, blink, blink, blink,
blink. All right, lift everybody.
Lyft knows that their drivers are
what keeps them moving on Jesus.
And why weren't they had a
meeting to figure that out.
So they do everything they can to make
sure that drivers are happy on every trip.
Lyft was the first to order in APP
tipping. When you drive for lip,
you keep 100% of the tips.
Drivers had been paid over $200 million
in tips since the feature was introduced.
That's really great though. You know,
that's like that Guy Papa John's pizza.
I was watching that. Jay Leno, Jay
Jay's garage, and that guy, uh,
the guy who does the Papa John's pizzas,
you know,
he had to sell his car to
keep his dad's bar going.
He was making the pizza in
the back in 1971 Camaro.
Z 28 gold with the black
stripes and he fucked 20 years,
was looking for the car track
down the exact fucking car.
But he's talking about it like
30% of the profits he brings.
He puts back into the business
as far as like, you know,
given bonuses to all of us employees.
I don't know why more
corporations don't do that.
You know,
why don't you do that? They then
people are happy to work for you.
And then when I walk
into but order a pizza,
I don't get some grumpy ass
holes getting fucked over.
Yeah.
Who knows? I don't know why
the same reason why they
won't sign Colin Kaepernick.
Uh,
express pay lets drivers get paid almost
instantly instead of waiting for weeks.
Lyft has even taken the
guesswork out of pickups.
The new amp device uses color coding
to help passengers find their drivers.
You can earn hundreds of dollars a week
plus tips what are and more money drive
more. It's never been easier to give
yourself a raise. It's a simple formula.
Happy drivers mean happy passengers.
Maybe that's why nine out of 10 Lyft
rides get a perfect five star ratings.
So join the ride sharing company that
believes in treating its people better.
Go to lift.com/bird today and
get a $500 new driver bonus.
That's lyft.com/burr lyft.com/bar
limited time only terms apply.
You know what? I swear to
God, if I wasn't so busy,
I would actually do that
just for the fun. I mean, I,
when was coming up as a comedian,
there's no fucking way I
wouldn't have done that.
I absolutely would have done that
during the fucking day. I do it now.
I do it at night. We funny
to fucking picking up drunk
people and Shit. You know,
I mean, until they puke in
the back seat of your car.
Uh,
I don't know. I would actually get into
that job. Play some good tunes, you know,
Nice smelling car.
All pick up some fucking assholes,
Dr Morel Ego next to you fucking drunk.
All right.
Listen to somebody's bitching about their
wife. Gets to be like a psychologist.
It's like a fucking bartender driving
around. Right. All right. The Black Tux,
everybody, you know there's only so many
opportunities in life to wear a Tuxedo.
So when your big day or special event
rolls around this summer, just look,
just look just as great as you feel with
suits from the black tux.com with high
quality rental suits and Tuxedos
delivered to your doorstep.
I shout when they
capitalized the Black Tux,
the black Tux gives you a new way to
rent. Yeah. Plus with their home. Try on,
you can say the Fed and fail the quality
of your suit months before your event
and the best part is it's
completely done online.
Do the way this is written,
you could get the average NFL defensive
linemen to jump off site. You know,
check,
do seven blue 90 day plus
with their prayer right there.
They'll cross. All right. The Black Tux,
the black Tux Scott Com lets you
create your look or choose from tons of
stylistics selected outfit suits.
Like these usually
retails for $1,200 really?
But at the be black Tux
they started just 95 bucks.
You're telling me you can do some.
That looks like for 1200
for 90 it starts at 95
okay.
All right.
If you have any questions or issues,
their expert customer care team has
your back every step of the way.
After ordering your suit will
arrive 14 days before your event.
If anything is less than perfect,
the black Tux will send you a
free replacement right away.
When your event's over,
just drop the rental back in the mail.
Shipping is free both ways.
How easy is that stand out at your event
for the right reason with the black Tux
call to action to get
$20 off your purchase,
visit the black tux.com/bar that's
the black tux.com/bar for $20 off your
purchase. And lastly, but not
leastly. Oh, I love these guys.
They always give me nice succinct copy.
Do I always shave club dude?
Dollar Shave Club is this smarter choice.
Yeah,
you'll get a great shave at a great price,
conveniently delivered right to your door.
You no longer have to Schlep to this
still to buy a cheap disposable razor that
gives you a cheap shape or spend a
fortune on races with gimmicky shaving
technology, you know, fucking maid.
And when you use dollar Shave Club's
executive razor with a dog to a cab,
okay,
the blade gently glides
giving you a smooth shave.
Dr. Carver shave butter is transgender.
Transparent for more precise shave
helps prevent ingrown hairs and fights.
Razor bumps make the smarter choice by
joining Dollar Shave Club for a limited
time,
new members can get their first month of
the executive razor with a tube of the
Dr Carver's easy shape for
only $5 with free shipping.
After that, razors are just a few bucks
a month. That's a $15 value for only $5.
There are no hidden fees
and no commitments cancel.
Anytime you fucking want a
fuck what's going on by foot?
I got a cramp in my foot. Ah, Jesus.
Okay.
Fucking Christ. All right, it's gone away.
It's gone away. It's part of being
old right there. You know, by the way,
anytime you get a cramping, like if you
ever bring your toes back towards you,
you know, you stretch in the morning, she
started pointing your toes, your face,
and you've legs cramp up immediately.
Just point your toes the other way.
It goes right away.
All right?
You don't have to sit there
going, fuck, fuck. You know,
he kicks it down the hall
thinking get died. Uh,
there's no hidden fees and no commitments.
Cancel anytime you like,
you can only get this,
uh,
offer exclusively@dollarshaveclub.com
slash bar.
That's dollar shave club.com/bar.
Now,
from what I've been told, the reason
why that is getting back to the, uh,
the cramping in your legs. All
right? If you go the other way is, is
it's sorta like a ying and a Yang.
You know what I mean?
The muscles on the front of your body
versus the back of your body. Like I,
my shoulders got fucked up
cause I was doing pushups,
I was doing curls out doing and all that,
but I wasn't doing enough back exercises.
So my shoulders started rolling
forward. All right, there's a balance.
So whatever the fuck you do, I don't
know medically what happens, but if you,
you do the exact opposite motion,
when you get that cramp,
it fucking whatever is tightening
up, then release this. Now you go.
And you know what,
after I tried to explain it,
you're no closer to understanding
it. Okay? I'm all, by the way,
I did the gym Jeffrey show this week. Uh,
I'll put, I'll tweet out a link for that.
Um, I had a great time on that. What
a great interviewer he is. You know,
I didn't know how that was going to
go to fucking Comedians, you know,
was shit that they want to say. I was, uh,
I felt like I do when I'm on Conan.
Conan is like an old school Johnny Carson
guy where it's like if you're killing,
he lets you go. He laughs at your
jokes. He makes you look great.
If you start struggling,
he comes to the rescue,
right.
And um,
Jim Jefferies was the exact same way.
Old School fucking guy.
So a highly recommend that show.
Um,
dude, he was killing,
he was killing so hard,
like even just doing like some stuff
where he was just doing like a, hey,
Seattle watched the show, blah, blah,
blah, whatever you call those things.
He was killing so hard when
he was just messing those up.
Like just constantly was killing that.
I was standing backstage like laughing,
thinking like, this guy doesn't need me,
really doesn't need me as a guy.
You appreciate him having a yard.
But he really could have just done
this by himself. He really is. Um,
you know, when you go see Jim
Jeffries, I mean, I'm, I'm not,
I don't think I'm bullshitting when
I would say that guy's probably cause
everybody's top five, top three, you
know, that's always arguable. You know,
you can argue you to whoever you think
is the best. He's without a doubt.
I would say top three
in the fucking world.
He's like one of the best comedians
in the fucking world. It's,
that's the real deal. So a
checkout his show, please come out.
There's still a few tickets
left for a Paul [inaudible],
a special and Gera. But
bubba, Bubba, Bubba,
bubba above the 33 minutes. Okay,
please enjoy this music here. Um,
I'm going to try out my GoPro.
I'm very excited to try this thing
out to see what comes about this.
And um,
I've been threatening to do a show
of me driving around freaking out.
I don't need,
don't know if I need to put that out there
anymore with me fucking freaking out.
I do it enough on podcasts and shit, but
uh, we'll see. We'll see where it goes.
So enjoy this music as we transition
into a Thursday afternoon podcasts from a
Thursday from, I don't know
when a joy it and uh, hey,
shout out to Darren King and,
and the unbelievable drumming that he
did when he was with mute math and good
luck to him and all of his future
projects and good luck to mute math,
um, on their upcoming tour. Um,
I forget the drama is named Dave
Hutchinson or something like that.
They got to replace Darren King,
uh,
mute mass new album is coming out in
September. I've already preordered it.
Very excited,
very excited to see them on this tour.
And very excited to see what
Darren's going to be doing, um,
with whatever his next project
is. A, that's it. Okay.
Thank you guys for listening.
Have a great weekend. You concern,
I'll, uh, I'll talk to you on Monday.
I Dunno.
All over the map. That's why like, you
know, certain ways of looking at shit,
like when people
talk about guns,
like let's just make them what,
let's just make them illegal as
a no, we all have them. You know,
like that's sort of like
thought process is your,
you're acting as though the world is a
utopia and that there's not morons and
that there's not, uh, people who say,
I don't give a fuck what the rules are.
You're totally not even
taking into consideration
sociopath's which is why that
new fucking thing that Obama signed,
that whole defense package where now they
can just arrest people without a trial
and put you in jail forever with,
without a trial because they just
think you're a fucking terrorist.
You can't give people that level of power.
I'm a fucking moron. And I know
you can't do that. Historically,
no one has ever handled
that level of power. Well,
anybody here want to go live in China
and now we out there practicing your nun
chucks wearing your wooden slippers and
all of a sudden the van pulls up and you
disappear and that's it. Forever. You
want to live there? Of course you don't.
You want to live here where they can't
fucking do it. Well, they can do it now.
You know? They just put in a fucking
order for a bunch of black fans.
That's what I heard. According to Holy
shit.com that's what's going down.
I don't understand why stuff at that
level that affects citizens to that level.
Why we don't get to vote on it.
Do you think it's because we'd
say, Hey, you know what? Fuck that.
Do you want me to stand like
that is just a jump off point.
Do you think like that's
just how it's going to stall?
As long as you're not a terrorist
in there, you ain't got to fuck bro.
You think it's just
going to stop with that.
That's not how you take away freedom.
You don't just fucking do it all in
one fell swoop. It's incremental.
It's just like when you're dating some
fucking woman and you're not paying
attention and she just gradually, every
day it takes another foot of real estate.
Next thing you know you're
in goal line d going,
how the fuck did I end up in
this situation? We started
at the 50 a little push,
a little poll, right? Everything was
fine. Seen all Europe against the Golan.
The you think that they're just going
to keep it with the terrorist thing,
you know?
You know they'll wait for a whole nother
generation of babies to be born and
they always grew up with government having
that level of power and then they had
something else to it. Then they
had something else. Then that's it.
You can't have it.
Okay.
If Tiger Woods can't handle the
level of free pussy on a golf tour,
how the fuck is our government going
to handle a new defense package?
Which basically gave them a mute
button when you love to, hey,
how would you handle that if
you had that power, do you,
how long before you just
started abusing that?
If you could just hit mute on anybody
who ever disagreed with you and it just,
and you could have them whisked away.
I mean that is the sociopath's wet dream.
That's what that is. That is a
fucking mute button, Mr Style and
don't you think that's it?
He hit mute. You're done.
You're gone. See Ya. I think,
I think it's fucking insane and I'm,
the only thing that I get out of it is
that I feel like I was proven correct
that I don't think it
matters at that level.
Whether you vote Democrat or Republican
Obama, the first black president ever,
you would think this would be the most
liberal a politician in the history of
this country.
Okay.
Because of his background. You would
think that he signed off on that shit.
All right. I'm telling you, I don't know
what happens when you become president,
but I think they let you peek just
enough behind the curtain and you there,
there is
fucking agenda that we are
moving towards because it does,
I don't think it fucking matters.
I really don't,
which is why I always
vote for the Ralph Nader,
the fuck and Ron Paul, all those guys
that all those fucking idiots go.
Oh do cause you did that. You've
ruined the election. Really?
Did I?
Okay.
I feel like those guys wouldn't
have signed shit like that.
I feel like their track record shows
that they would not sign shit like that.
Um, I, I don't know.
I have no, I imagine I'm going to get
a ton of fucking emails I'm on with.
Somebody was yelling at me one time saying
that because I voted for Ralph Nader
in 2000.
That's why George W.
Bush won and they just going on and on
and on about it. And I was like, dude,
I live in New York. Al
Gore won my state. Okay.
Do you understand that? So
your whole fucking theory
right now is out the window.
I voted for Ralph Nader in New York
and Al Gore still won the state.
So go fuck yourself. What
I'm trying to do, uh,
missed a fucking red and blue tie here.
I'm trying to fucking encourage
more people like that devote.
So mission accomplished. That's what I'm
trying to fuck and have to vote to run,
you know.
Uncorruptible how far can you get if
you're uncorruptible I would say that you
can get to the uh,
or whatever level politics is when you
decide whether or not they should put a
gazebo in the center of town.
I think beat, once you get
beyond that, you got it.
You got to be a little dirty.
Right.
I love talking about this shit cause
it just stirs people up, you know?
Um,
you know,
maybe you should all read a little more
before the next time you took an ohm.
Really? What are you reading? What
are you reading? What they give you?
Is that what you're reading?
Fuck head.
Why you acting like you have clearance
to the bottom floors of the fucking
Pentagon? You're guessing? Just
like I am. All right, Mr. Informed,
I read the pamphlet,
I don't buy a fucking word of it.
You know,
you can use coca cola to take rust
off of metal. You can use it for that.
You know,
you understand that yet they're
still able to sell it to us.
Like it's refreshing.
I don't know what that point meant either.
Okay.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and this is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
August the 10th 2009 that I'm
actually doing on Tuesday,
August the 11th,
because a DHS wasn't
enough hours in the day.
Oh my God, I got south swamps. No,
I did. I don't know what happened.
I know what happened.
I had a big audition for something and uh,
I had to just keep doing the
audition over and over again.
And when I wasn't doing that,
I was curled up in the fetal position.
Go and please bill, don't fuck
this up. This is a big opportunity.
And fortunately I did not,
whether they pick me a knot
is out of my hands, but, um,
and then I just said
a bunch of other shit.
Why does it sound like it's
echoing in here? I Dunno.
I'm trying a new recording level,
uh, this week by the way, people,
I don't know if the quality's
going to suffer, but, um,
I had a number of people and by
a number, I mean like six, um,
which I think is about one third of
my listeners. So it was big to me. Uh,
we're saying that a, I needed to get more
bandwidth or I needed to do something.
Basically they couldn't download my,
uh,
my podcast off of iTunes or whatever.
And somebody finally called it to my
attention that I was recording at music
level quality.
So my files were huge and considering
that I wasn't recording musical
instruments that I could actually record
at a lower and they would be smaller
files thus easier to download. So I
said, I know what I'm going to do.
Okay.
I'm going to fucking go find the owner's
manual and I'm going to figure out how
to do that. And, uh, even
though I have a little file,
it'll little fucking a big piece of
Tupperware. Whatever the fuck you call it,
big plastic bin that's going to
be here 9,000 years from now.
Um,
I have all my owner's
manuals for everything I ever
bought except for my Olympus
ls 10.
I don't know where the fuck it is.
So I just went into menu and I put it
on MP three and I'm recording at 128
fucking killer. What's a, what's a
white's? Whatever the fuck you call him.
I don't know what the, I don't know what
it is. So I'm going to try it this week.
So you guys give me a feedback,
let me know how the quality sounds.
Was it easier to download?
Was it harder to download?
Was it the same?
Was it just a futile fucking attempt?
Um, anyways, he almost hit a
bad bit, right? They're like,
why is it that you can find everything
move of who you're looking for?
Um, all right. I got a lot of stories for
you. Why this week? Let's start off with,
I had a, uh, you know,
I had a nice district cremant this
morning was somebody in particular and I
realized in that fight that the
secret to success is basically,
I mean, I'm sure somebody
is already written a book
about this, but I don't read.
So I'm feeling like I'm
breaking new ground here.
The secret to success in life
is the word yes and the word no.
That is it. If you want to be a
happy person, if somebody says,
do you want to do this shit
and you want to do it? Say yes,
yes I do. And then if they're like,
but do you want to do this shit?
And you don't say, no, I don't.
Now I know that sounds simple,
but it's afterwards.
That is the hard part.
And I feel as the reason
why so many people say yes
when they mean no and vice a
versa is because basically the
fucking reaction of the other person,
you have to just completely
block out their reaction.
You know? Do you want
to do this? No, I don't.
Usually when you say no negative,
don't want to do it,
the other person is just like,
why? Why don't you want to do it?
I thought it'd be fun.
I thought we could do it together.
I thought it would be a choice of,
well, why don't you want to do it?
Because you asked me and the
first fucking thing in me,
wherever that voice in me said,
no, I don't want to do it.
So then I said no, right. I
heard what you said, Glen,
and I am going to fucking speak
it out loud. So this other person,
because they can't hear my inner
voice. No, the answer is no.
And then they always go,
you're ridiculous. You
just, you just being a jerk.
You're being crazy. Really? Is
that what my inner voice is a jerk?
You know how many French I want to ask
you guys is how many friendships in your
life do you have right now where,
uh, you can actually say, no,
I don't want to do that shit. And the
other person's cool with it. You know,
people will give you a little bit of
grief but you gotta be careful because a
lot of times there's a lot
of concern out there and uh,
how they deem somebody,
a friend is basically that they do
everything that they want them to do.
You know, and then the second
you start going, hey, you know,
I really don't feel like doing that stuff,
dude.
You changed what the fucks with you.
God, go fuck yourself. You're a cunt.
All right.
What do you,
what do you think you're perfect
and you always have the best idea.
Go Fuck Yourself. I don't want to do
what you want to do right now. You know,
I just got a big God
damn argument because uh,
I want to flip to find,
I went the fuck it was about as
far as I was trying to tell me.
I never want to fucking do anything.
I mean I've worn a door.
Anything I want to do my Monday morning
podcast you saying that's nothing. Okay.
Cause if you are, I'll tell you,
I got 18 listeners. You have to,
you have to fucking talk to buddy.
What was, that's all I'm saying.
All right? Somebody asked you if you want
to do something, if you want to do it,
say yes. If you don't want to do with
say now, okay and fuck their reaction,
unless they can kick the shit out of
you, at which point you say, yeah,
I'd love to. And then you sort of mutter
to yourself the rest of the evening,
and then what you do is on the side,
you start taking some martial art classes,
either that or you call a moving company
that can pack up all your shit and move
it to another state while other person
who can kick the shit out of you.
Is it work? That's how you do it. Okay?
There's nothing wrong. I think
the word coward is overused. Um,
you know,
and I think it's used by the person
who wanted to kick the shit out of you,
but you were smart enough not to be
in the vicinity of them, to let them,
you're know how you work,
how you didn't let me fucking smash your
face into your fucking ear. You Coward.
Well, you know, Dude, uh, I
listened to my inner voice.
Men or voice did not want my nose over
by my ear, so I decided to avoid it.
Yes. You know, you are stronger than me.
You can kick the shit out of me. Okay.
But you know, that doesn't mean I'm
not better at checkers. You know,
there's something,
this is a subject you can pick then
I'm better at it than you, but it may,
maybe fighting's not one
of them. Why does it? Oh,
that's what it always comes
down to with guys. You know,
in the end I can beat the fuck out of you.
So therefore I'm right.
You know. Oh Jesus, I'm getting deep
here. Isn't that how the world works?
Mine is right. Isn't that what? Oh,
is not how everybody's
foreign policy works.
You fucking seeing other country and
they have some shit that you want.
So what do you do? Do you say,
hey, how's it going? How are you?
Maybe do that beginning just so that
you can get within fucking striking
distance and then you grab him by the
front of the a button down. You know,
when you sort of lift
them up off the ground,
so part of their shirt
is obscuring their view.
So they don't see the overhand right
coming. Isn't that what we do? Isn't it?
I don't fucking know. You
know, I was watching our,
the bill Maher show the other day and
he was, uh, yesterday actually, and um,
at the end of the show he was giving
out these statistics and he was saying
stuff like, uh, he's basically talking
about how fucking stupid Americans are,
which I'm really getting tired of that,
you know,
I'm not saying we're not fucking stupid,
I'm just like, as compared to who,
you know, I've, you know, I haven't
traveled to a lot of places,
but I've been to some places that were
not flying the American flag and there's
just as many fucking morons,
you know, if everybody's smart,
then there's no smart guys. You're
just regular, you know what I mean?
Jesus. Wow. Bill, that was fucking
deep. Fuck you. Fuck you want from me?
I'm just saying, you know what I mean?
So anyways, here he's doing this poll.
Actually,
I actually really liked his show.
One of the things I love
about Bill Maher is, uh,
he's not really likable and he doesn't
seem to give a fuck. And you know,
I mean,
yeah,
I mean does that the kind of person
you want to have over for dinner?
Probably not, but, uh, that's
a good recipe for getting
a lot of pussy in life. Um,
well we'll discuss that
later. Um, plowing ahead here.
So he starts doing all these polls and
he's sitting there going, you know,
18% only 18% of Americans
could name a new,
Oh knew that there was two senators for
every state and a only 11% could name
who are,
you know,
so immediately that's supposed to
make it seem like everybody's dumb.
And my first thought was, okay, 18%
can know that you get two senators
per state, but I bet you know,
a good 28% could explain the
cover two defense. You know,
it just depends on what
the fuck you're into.
I like when people are really into
something and you're not into it.
And then they consider you stupid.
Make granted we are talking about the
people who determine how we live our
lives. Actually they don't.
That's the illusion. You know,
it's the fucking bankers. Okay. They
run everything, man. I'm telling,
I'm not going to do that again this week
and embarrass myself with my incredible
lack of knowledge, but you know, whatever.
I just don't think people are
as fucking dumb as they're lazy,
you know? But the way that they
really just depict people out there,
like people are just walking around
with their fucking mouths hanging open,
not realizing that they're drooling.
All of the,
all over the front of their Kenny Chesney
shirt. And I, you know, Kenny Chesney is,
I mean,
I know he's a country singer.
Who was that the one who was married to
that chick who's fucking face squints up
whenever she smiles.
Yeah.
And they were married for like three days
ball dude. Is that who the fuck it is?
Huh? I don't know. I can't stand
country music. It's just depressing.
It's depressing and it's Geeky
and everybody sings like they, they're
in puberty. There you go. That was nice.
Generalizations.
Huh?
Ooh,
that shit.
I can't fucking stay on that.
And I don't like rednecks blind
pride in being an American,
you know,
cause it always involves sticking a boot
up somebody's ass or whatever the fuck.
It's just like, why can't you be
here and just be happy, you know,
and watch to a fucking farming equipments.
Try to pull in opposite directions as
you fucking rare your head back and
fucking scream at the moon.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Fucking nothing wrong with that.
Why do you gotta be so God damn it?
Why you gotta be like me and be
angry? Huh? You Straw hat. It can't.
All right. Uh, moving on.
Um, so my dog, uh, is,
she's in heat right now cause she
hasn't been fixed and uh, yeah,
it looks like a fucking crime scene here
around here because she's a female and
I'm going to leave it at that.
And uh,
she scheduled to be a
mutilated later on this month.
That's really what it is. Mutilated.
I'm gonna have my dog mutilated.
I'm against it, but I, I got
tired of arguing about it and,
uh, you know, I don't,
I don't understand why
you have to have your dog.
I just don't fucking get it. You
know, I get it. But you know,
if everybody did what Bob Barker said,
there'd be no more dogs and cats within
15 years because they'd all be spayed or
neutered, you know? And since,
when does a leathery 90 year old know
anything about fucking animals when his
main Gig is to host a fucking game show?
You know,
I love how that fat fuck with
the itchy beard, you know,
he gets all shit for his,
oh,
this document I can never met Michael
Moore can never remember people's fucking
names. Is that the same guy who, who
doesn't?
Michael Moore looked like the son of
that other fat dude with the itchy beard,
but it, it's all white.
You know, he sorta,
it looks like in a feminine Santa Claus
and he wears those red glasses and he
writes like Oscar jokes for, uh, uh,
Billy crystal. God, I suck at
names. Billy Crystal. You know,
the guy I'm talking about doesn't,
Michael Moore looked like the
son of that fucking guy. Hey,
doesn't this guy who I can't remember
his fucking name look like the other guy
who I can't remember his name. That was
really brutal. I apologize for that.
Let's get back to clear off. So clean.
I was doing fucking great, but the only,
I only have one problem with her.
Um,
the main problem with her
is she does not like men.
She doesn't like guys.
Um, unless they come over,
they come over to the house,
you know,
we bring them in and they sit down
and she can kind of sniff them out.
Then shit is cool.
But when she walks down the street,
um, you know, when guys, second
secondary is based in somebody's voice,
she's such freaking out and a,
I don't know how to stop her from doing
it. I keep disciplining her, but she,
she really blows me off. She blows
me off with that. And squirrels,
you know, she starts dragging
me down the fucking street.
I could literally water ski behind this
Goddamn Dog. It's so strong. And, uh,
I know went out to this breakfast
place the other day and you know,
this fucking old lady shows up with
her husband who has osteoporosis.
You know,
if you don't know what that is,
you have a see old people who look like
they're fascinated with their feet.
You know, that's fucking osteoporosis. So
anyways, he's fucking comes walking in.
So he looks at my dog who's totally
chill and he just keeps staring at her in
the eyes and then she
rah Rah Rah Rah Rah Rah.
And then she fucking jumped up at
him. A fucking 90 year old man. Cleo,
what's wrong with you
cleo?
Come over here for a second.
Did you could make your debut here on
the Monday morning pocket. Come here.
Come on, get off here. Is there a
fucking reason? Come on, get up here.
Come on.
Is there a reason?
Is there a reason why you fucking tried
to kill a 90 year old man the other day?
Huh? That's all you got
to say. Fucking jackass.
She was seen. He jumped right on
off one after the God damn dude.
Just sorta lunged.
Just sorta lunch.
This guy is probably a veteran
of world war two. Right. And uh,
then I brought it down and then the
old Eddie goes is ad Pitbull Bay.
They shouldn't be allowed around paper,
you know, and I fucking let it go.
Believe it or not. I did let
it go. I didn't really say
really yield fucking bat.
How did you get here?
How'd you drive down the street?
When did you get your fucking
driver's license? Huh?
Do they even have driver's license
when you fucking cranked your first
automobile? Huh? You're wrinkled
up. Pruny little fucking Twat.
I didn't say that. I just sat there. I had
respect. I have respect for all people.
I mean, I think that shit, I just
don't say it. I just sat there.
You know when you do that shit,
when someone's yelling at you
and you can't yell back at them,
you don't look at them and you do
that shit where your lips disappear.
When you make that thing,
you'll lips mouth is a straight line.
You just sit there nodding, Hey Chad and
bail out of our paper by at night. Right.
Or I'd get around a goddamn
right parking the car.
And I just sat there nodding as
everyone else was looking at her.
And then it was funny as hell because
my dog was totally chill until that evil
old couple showed up, like on blaming
them now. Right. So I have to,
she tells me basically my dog
should not be allowed around people,
which is fucking true in a lot of ways.
She walks around the corner and
then there's just some cute little,
I want to play Frisbee dog. And the
second they came around the corner,
that dog started freaking out.
Okay.
So you know,
maybe it wasn't my dog.
Cleo, can you do me a favor? Can you just
not, if you're going to bite somebody,
I'm going to have to go to court.
Okay.
And they're probably going to use
this podcast as evidence. You know,
God help me if they abuse his podcast,
he knew what was going to happen
and he called her an old cut.
Now if you could do me a
favor, hey, look at me Cleo.
No, fuck you. So just don't make
it somebody old. Give me a chance,
just give me a chance to
maybe win the court case.
Okay.
You liked that? That's what she does.
Want to give her a good scratch.
She starts fucking moment.
Ah,
what the fuck am I going to deal with you?
How the hell did you show up in my life?
You know what I like about you though?
You don't ask me to do shit
that I don't want to fucking do.
And then when I say I don't want to do it,
you don't act all fucking weird.
Like I got a problem. So anyways,
that was my week. That was my weekend.
You know what? I went 20 days
without drinking. And then I,
last night I finally just said,
you know,
I actually got scared that eventually
I was, I was gonna have a drink and,
but I, I would have gone like 80 days and
then I, I could never go on a run again.
I've tried to be sober because I know I
would never break if I ever went 80 days
being sober, there's no fuck
that would be like, you know,
trying to beat Joe Dimaggio's hitting
streak. There's no fucking, it's like,
why even try, you know? So I,
I called it quits at 20, and I am
ashamed at what I called it quits with.
I went to this fucking bar and I ordered,
went to order a blue moon because I'm
a, I'm a, I'm a snobby cont, you know,
give me a blue moon with little slice of
orange in it and I'll sit here with my
legs crossed, like I'm selling art.
Right. That's what I wanted to do.
And uh, they are like, oh
wait, I have, when I have it
here, we're all out all out.
And I was like a corona. Yeah,
we, yeah. No, now you don't,
we don't, we don't have karate. We
don't, not trying to here. All right,
let me get you a list of bears.
And they had their list of beers and then
I ordered a Miller lite. She's like, oh,
hey Kai. Yeah, you're going to kill me.
We just ran out of mail at
high and I was like, bitch,
what the fuck do you have
here? I'm going to say, bitch.
I looked down at the bar and I did sort
of a fucking stupid smile and I was
like,
what beers do you have with your
fucking content was underneath it.
Which is ridiculous because I don't
think she was in charge of ordering it.
She's just in charge of,
you know,
selling it or whatever it serving it.
That's the worst about having a
public job where you get a job.
Will you deal with the public is most
of the Times it's not your fault.
So not only do you have your job,
the other part of your job is to get
yelled at for shit that people above you
did, you know? So anyway,
so I ordered a fucking Amstel light
and it tasted like ass in out.
It tasted like somebody rubbed
their armpit on somebody's
ass. That's what a time
that didn't even fuck it. Make
sense? It just, it didn't taste good.
And I had one of those and then
I went right back to fucking,
I went back to coax. I know,
I like it. I like being,
I like going to bars and not
fucking drinking. I cannot.
I'm starting to enjoy it.
And then watching everybody else get
hammered and say dumb shit that they're
going to have to apologize for.
I think I've done that enough in life.
I've apologized enough times. Have
an eye. All right. And with that,
I'm going to get onto
some hyping some shit.
This has been a damn good podcasts so
far. I feel good. I'm well rested, Huh?
Isn't that right? Cleo? You liked that?
Yeah. She fucking love set,
Huh? Right on the rib cage.
Um, put my dog in a headlock.
You know I do that shit. Come in.
It's almost like the rear naked choke.
Just like doing it.
Look at that Jesus Christ.
Fucking size of your nipples.
What kind of message are you
trying to send out there? Huh?
You little whore walking around
trying to get some doggy Dick.
I've seen you sniffing every
fucking blade of grass.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
That's not how we raised you. Then again,
you were down by the river for Awhile,
Huh? And Yeah, you were definitely hungry,
but you were reading, Huh? How
did you get all those meals? Cleo?
How many Douggie Dick's. Did you have
a new man? Right? That's fucking weird.
All right. Ah, you don't,
I didn't notice about dogs is um,
their,
their front legs,
which are my world are the
arms and the back legs. Uh,
they bend the exact opposite as a humans.
I've never noticed that before.
You know? Well, I guess down towards
the bottom they do. Now wait a minute.
The front ones do. I'm an idiot. They've
been the same way at the front. Ones do,
but in the same way. All
right, you got me on that one.
So that's sorta like its wrist and elbow,
but the back legs, that's what it is.
They're fucking dare a,
their knee,
their knee joint goes the opposite way.
In fact, your fucking look at that. Your,
your Patella is behind your leg.
You see this.
This is why you can't get a
job in the real world. Cleo,
your fucking knees are on
the wrong side of your legs.
You know that. Other than that,
you don't have a shirt on.
You're fucking nipples showing to the
world and you get a job at the circus.
You know,
I'm not trying to be a dick here,
but why don't you fucking kick him
for some rent? Every once in a while.
I've got to buy another big
bag of fucking dog food. Look,
you're just laying there like he can't
hear me. You know what I'm talking about?
Leave your fancy new collar.
G last owners do that.
I don't think so. This is an abusive
relationship here. All right,
let's move on here.
Let's,
let's talk about some shit that
I have that I have going on.
I don't know why I had to say that
twice that I hit up, that I have. Oh,
look at that. I'm learning
how to play. Shoot the thrill.
Shoot to thrill the video tutorial.
Anybody out there play a guitar?
You want to a good youtube,
uh, this, this Guy Solo Dallas.
He's got all these fucking uh,
ACDC songs.
He shows you how to play
a man. It's a, I dunno.
And then you can be the hit at your next
party. Such a fucking loser. All right,
let's get back to what the
hell I was talking about here.
This is what I got coming up.
You notice how it was a great podcast
until I said it was a great podcast and
now I'm not living up to it. Um, anyways,
this is what I got coming up this week,
Friday,
Saturday and Sunday.
I'm going to be at the punchline in
Atlanta and I'm coming up in September.
I'm going to be at the helium comedy
club in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Uh,
September 10th through the 12th.
And I added a date.
I added two dates.
One is for all you California people.
All right.
And I really need you to show up for
this one because the [inaudible] are
basically paying me like fucking $5 in
a new pair of shoe laces because they
don't feel that I can draw out
here in California because,
uh, because I'm a light guy, I think, you
know, not a lot of white guys out here.
You know, that was my big mistake. I
should've gone out laid in the sun.
I just would've been all red. It would
have thought it was a native American.
They would've booked me in a fucking
casino. Anyways, I'm gonna be at the, uh,
the Improv in Ontario,
California for four fucking days.
September 17th, 18th, 19th,
and 20th for the love of God could you
and 48 of your closest fucking white,
black, Mexican, Asian,
whatever you can grab,
please bring them out to those
shows because it sucks, man.
I live out here in la. There's three
clubs that I could be playing, you know,
where I could actually not have
to fucking jump in an airplane.
I want to play Los Angeles area.
I really would like to,
but I really need you motherfuckers to
show up because if you don't show up,
I can't play out here any more because
they offer me $5 in a new pair of shoe
laces. Okay. And uh, I said, fuck it.
I'll do it for that Gig and I'm going
to show that I can draw out here so they
can come out here, you know, and not to
have to get on a plane every fucking week.
All right.
So I added that date.
And then the other date that I added
was I added a date and Seattle,
Washington at one of my favorite
clubs, giggles comedy club, uh,
for December 10th, 11th, and the 12th.
And I scheduled that around a Seattle
Seahawks home game mother fuckers.
And when I go to that,
that is going to be my 100th franchise
that I've seen actually not won't be
because I'm doing the champion problems,
see the Phoenix Suns and I'm going to
come in a day early for Seattle so I can
go to Portland trails trailblazer's
game because I have OCD.
I have to go to all of them. Why do I have
to go to all of them? I don't know why.
I don't know why.
That's why I do on the plane.
I sat there and I check them off like
the fucking rain, man. I'm a Weirdo.
So anyways,
when I go to all of those,
I'll basically have Ben to everything
out here, west of Denver, everything,
all the way up Edmonton, all of
that shit. I've been to all of them.
And you know what? It hasn't filled
me up a bit. I'm still fucking empty.
All right, that was sad. That was just
sad. Let's get back to, uh, you know what?
I gave you guys some homework last week.
Uh,
I told you to go out and go see the movie,
the orphan because I wanted
to make fun of that movie,
but I didn't want to ruin it for you.
So if you didn't go and see it,
that's your own God damn fault.
And you probably want to fast forward
through the next four minutes of this
podcast because I want
to talk about this movie.
It's a horror movie that
I, uh, I actually loved.
I loved it even though it kind of stunk.
It was,
it reminded me of a horror
movies from the 1980s.
And, uh, one of the things that,
there was always the requirement
of is that you had to have,
oh,
do you hear that alarm?
If I told you what kind of car that was,
it's like a fucking
1988 now it's not that,
and it's probably like a
1991 Honda accord, a site,
you know, it's the classic,
nobody's going to steal that car.
And every time a truck drives by or
somebody says, I don't want to do it.
And they punch the top of their bureau.
It's sets the fucking alarm often
that God damn car. And uh, I dunno.
I think it's funny because it's far
enough away where it's not annoying to me.
But I know it's fucking driving somebody
up. The wall is now, right Cleo.
Huh? As you go to look at me
and she puts her head back down,
she doesn't give a fuck. All
right, so that movie, the orphan,
if you haven't seen it, if he driven
by any sort of bus stop or anything,
it's that one that has
that really cycle look,
an eight year old on it and it says,
uh,
there's something wrong with the, what
the fuck is her name? It's not ama.
It's one of those old person named Emma,
not Elvira.
Ah, Shit. See that's how my
brain works. Now I'm fucked.
What the fuck is that little twats name?
There is something wrong.
Yeah. Christ, whatever it says there's
something wrong with this fucking chick.
Eight year old girl with an old
person's name. Alright. So you go,
you watch the fucking movie. Basically,
she's an orphan. This couple comes down,
they want to, you know, they want to
adopt a kid for some fucking reason.
So they picked this girl who is dressed
like she's from the 18 hundreds,
and she has like a piece of thread around
her throat that she won't take off and
on wrists have few times people try
to remove it at the orphanage and she
completely freaks out, sell the whole
time she's been a fucking psycho.
She's trying to kill their natural kids.
And um,
you know,
their life was basically fine and
then they get this kid and everything,
you know, the fucking house catches
on fire, all this fucked up stuff.
But one of the requirements of
old school horror movies is,
is you have to have unbelievably
stupid people in it. And um,
I actually, the, the white people
in this movie were so fucking dumb.
I almost got offended.
I almost like wrote a letter.
It's like they got this giant
tree fort and the dude looks,
he looks out the window and the fucking
thing is engulfed in flames as his
natural son is hanging from
the tree trying not to fall,
which he does and ends up
in intensive fucking care.
And the fucking wife is
sitting there going like,
I think there's something wrong with
this fucking chick with the old person
named that dresses like she's in
the 18 hundreds and the kicker,
she has a Transylvanian accent
Ivonne to play the piano. What? I
can't even fucking do it. She's just,
it's like you're a psycho. Get
the fuck out of my life. Right?
Then she starts killing people.
People start disappearing right and
fucking left and they're sitting there,
the cub, Whoa, what's
going on? She's big. So we,
all right. So basically in
the end, what you find out,
what's wrong with the girl is
that she's not eight years old.
She's actually 33 she has,
she has some sort of disease that makes
her look like she's eight and she used
to be in an insane asylum because she
murdered her family and she escaped
somehow from Germany.
She somehow escaped the insane asylum,
got herself in an orphanage with no
fucking passport, no paperwork whatsoever,
got herself into an orphanage in America
and the kicker is she somehow went to a
dentist who agreed to make her a full
upper and a full lower denture of
children's teeth,
which she pulls out in the end as you're
discovering that she's 33 years old and
then there's little fucking
dwarf middle-age psycho
cunt comes in and somehow is
able to stab to death and adult I,
it was just the stupidest fucking thing
I was. It was great. It's just a fucking,
and even though I told you
everything basically that happens,
it's still a fucking hilarious movie.
It was where it's,
somebody wrote this great email to me.
They were so pissed that I told
him to go see the movie. They said,
I've never been absolutely terrified while
laughing my ass off for 90 minutes in
my entire life.
And that is the experience of the orphan.
It's just a fucking great stupid movie.
I don't know,
it just reminded me how it
had all the cheesy lines.
She's crawling out of the pond, Mami
Save, you save me. And then she's like,
for the last time I'm
not your fucking mother.
And then she kicks her right
in her fucking 33 year old,
eight 58 year old face and she goes
back down to the bottom of the pond.
And I guess that was supposed
to be the applause break,
which it would have got if it
was still 1984 but whatever,
it's, I know as much as I just
trashed it, it still a good movie.
I felt bad for the actor playing the
dad in the movie because I just pictured
him in between takes trying to figure
out how he could be that guy and just
looking at the director going sell
basically. My character's a fucking moron,
right?
So in this seed,
I'm still a moron who can't put
one and one together and get,
um, maybe, you know,
cause nothing caught on fire and no woman
was murdered in my house before we got
the fucking chick who sounds like
she's doing a Dracula impression.
Maybe I could put those two fucking
numbers together and guests that it's,
it's Ama or Ezra or whatever
the fuck her fucking name.
Is this something wrong with her?
The fuck is it? I have to look it up.
I got to get this orphan.
Let me type this in. Clear.
What the fuck was that psycho
chick's name. Huh? Orphan.
Showtimes. Uh, you
motherfucker plot words.
Keys.
Yeah.
Full cast and crew.
Here we go. Here we go.
Anyway, reason there's
something wrong with Esther.
Had a fuck that I forget that Esther
to cause a little white girl Esther.
That's it. That's an old black
woman name, isn't it Esther?
Was that the name of it?
Was that the name of Florida Evan's
character or was that the name of the,
of the ugly girl on a Sanford and
son? It was aunt Esther. That was,
yeah.
And therefore because I saw one person
who was black who had that name,
therefore everybody see how I do that?
I like to generalize everybody
cause I'm a moron. All right,
let's get back to the
fucking podcast here. Um,
here we go.
Here's some youtube videos.
Did you guys can watch this weekend your
cubicles instead of working? All right.
Um, let me see here. What
do we got here? All right,
so I noticed a lot of them because the
first one that I nominated was really
violent.
Most of these youtube videos that people
are nominating involve somebody getting
punched in the face. Like, here's one
British director slammed into a table.
This is,
um,
Twat on Twat crime just to let you
know it's female versus female and um,
it has a WWF quality to it.
When the lady gets slammed,
she puts her arms out like the way they
do when wrestlers pretend to slam their
heads off a table. Um, but for all
of you who don't like violence,
I have a couple of Nice ones. Here's
one for you. Cute puppy whistle.
Look up that one and tell me that won't
melt your fucking cheerios if they're
meltable. Um, and there's
another great one. This one,
Jerry needs no help playing with his ball.
I know that sounds like a porno,
but I swear to God it's an adorable video.
Jerry needs no help playing with his ball.
Just write this down on a little post.
It act like you're taking notes
and looking at a spreadsheet. Um,
here's one for the guys, a
fat kid on a bicycle. Um,
I challenge you to watch this and
not fucking laugh your balls off.
And it's great if he just, you know
what's great is after the kid falls off,
if you look really closely it,
what happens is,
is when he goes flying over the handlebars
in his fucking meatball body lands,
you haven't seen anybody's played.
Sports has done this.
She ever get tackled in football and
your arms underneath you and your fucking
elbow basically goes into your spleen,
up under your liver and then fucking,
you know, smashes into your heart.
That's basically what happens to this kid.
And he makes,
he makes the greatest.
He made you want to hear the noise?
Tell you what I'll play.
They'll play the audio and I'm going
to test your willpower that if you can
actually hear the fucking
audio to this and not watch it,
you're definitely, you get you have,
you have some serious fucking willpower.
Let me type this in real quick. Fat,
there's a lot of audio on this one.
I had my dog. Fuck Kid. Wait a minute.
What the fuck? I just messed that up.
Fair kid on a bicycle.
I'm sorry I can't type with one hand.
Just bear with me children.
Just bear with me.
Just talk amongst yourselves.
Do you ever have that when you teach her
was going through a divorce and she'd
start breaking down.
Just talk amongst yourselves.
Fat Kid on a sic code.
Bam. Come on. Where the fuck is it?
Oh, that's great. Bill,
you gave me the wrong.
Maybe it's fat kid falls.
Ah,
you fucking asshole bill fat.
I wrote fat on a bicycle. That'd be
disgusting ones. There's a bag of fat.
All right. Fat Kid on a bicycle
and I get the same videos.
Fat Kid fall on a jumping on a bike.
Where is his mother fucker?
I'm the worst. I swear to God. It's funny.
You're not gonna be able to find
now I have to fuck. Oh, there it is.
Kid on a bicycle. I got it. Here
we go. Listen to this audio.
All right,
here he comes. Here he
comes. Here he comes.
Hello.
Ah,
oh. That's the funniest fucking thing
ever. And he's got big fat thighs.
He's got these little booty shorts.
Ah
God. That's a fucking great one.
There's nothing better that way is,
it's so funny to watch somebody get
hurt. I don't know why. Anyways,
here's another one,
and I know this,
this one has a couple
of your kid's ears here,
but this one is called current
smasher. C U. N. T. A. Smasher.
And I know that sounds like,
you know somebody just give somebody
an uppercut to the baby maker.
That's not what happens. Believe
it or not, this is actually,
it's a male stripper and I swear to God,
I think it's Bobby blots,
sir from rat. That's what
it looks like. Um, it's,
you might want to fast forward through
some of it, but it's just fucking,
it's hilarious.
Um,
it's gotta be from like 1988 just judging
by the guy's fucking hair metal hair
and he's spinning these knives around
and it's just a classic why guys are not
sexy and women or guys I think turn
women on if they're like doing shit,
you know, you come over, you know,
you're fucking the of the cable guy
and you're installing cable, you know,
and you bend over and you'd Dickies.
I don't fucking know.
You know what I mean?
That's how women get turned on and they
see some guy with a little yellow hard
hat and he's up a telephone pole. Oh my
God. He can fix stuff. I want to blow him.
Right.
I Dunno how they find a sexy,
but I know it's not wearing a fucking
leather jumpsuit spinning around kitchen
knives. That really, I dunno, but
you got to watch it. That's what,
that's a great one. Um, and these are
all recommended by people, by the way,
other than fat kid on a bike.
That's one of my favorite ones. Um,
gay weatherman is a grace w great
one. Uh, there's another one,
worst blooper ever.
And uh,
then there's another good one,
a British punch.
Just look that up at some British
dude who gets punched in the face.
And his reaction is,
um,
stereotypical British where
it's just really polite.
Where'd you go and do something like that?
I came out to fuck he did.
The guy gets punched in the face
and he doesn't attack the other kid.
He doesn't laugh. Hey, why
did you go? I came with the F.
I can't do fucking accents.
I don't even know why.
Check those out instead of working. That's
what you can do this week. All right.
Um, or if he gets sick of working. What
are we up to here? 40 minutes. All right.
I gotta wrap up. I have some, I have
a computer question for you people.
All right. I have a, I have the Mac book
now. All the nerds are listening up.
Alright. Perk in their ears up. I have a
brand new Mac book brand. By brand new,
I mean nonetheless,
like fucking four months or whatever.
And I got that thing where,
you know,
if I put my hand on the little square
thing down there that I don't know what
it's called. You know the
mousy area. I know if I,
if I flick the cursor to the upper
right hand, all the windows disappear.
If I go down to the lower right, they
separate, upper left makes it go black,
lower left,
uh,
makes the four windows and you know,
we can have something in all four windows.
Um, but my question is, is what?
I don't know how I do this,
but every once in a while I do something
on the mouse area accidentally.
And what happens is,
is I'll have two windows open and
when I click on one of the windows,
the other window goes exit
stage right off of my thing.
And then if I click the other one,
then the,
then it comes back while the
other one goes exit stage left.
And sometimes I want to look
at both fucking windows.
How do I make it stop doing that?
So I guess I want to know how do I make
it do that and then how do I make it
stop doing that because I want to stop
yelling at my computer like it's a person.
I hope I explained that correctly.
And with that,
let's move on to a revenge story. Remember
that topic? All those great stories.
Remember how like everybody had
his story, uh, how they, you know,
how you got revenge was basically
you didn't confront the person.
You basically fucked up some of their
personal property and a lot of people sort
of came to the conclusion that that really
wasn't revenge as much as it was sort
of a bitchy little move where here's
a great revenge story done by a guy.
This is a fucking great story. I wish I
lived this story. All right, here we go.
I grew up in Brooklyn, New York. Uh, many
years ago when I was in the sixth grade,
I was 11 years old. There was a guy
named PJ used to torment me all the time.
He bullied me, bully me, and robbed
me of my money. Every time he saw me.
This lasted for about four years.
As I became a teenager,
he stopped trying to rob me,
but he was,
he still tried to intimidate
me every chance he got.
So one day in the summer we were playing
five on five basketball and there was
about 40 guys standing all around
the court watching the game.
I got the ball on a steel and the
only guy back on defense was PJ.
As I drove to the hoop,
he jumped to block my shot and
I dunked right in his face.
The whole park exploded.
Guys were running to the court
yelling and laughing at PJ's. Pj,
the screams were so loud.
My friends who lived a block away heard
the noise and came running to the park
to see what happened.
The look on PJ's face was priceless.
He was humiliated in front of just about
everybody we mutually knew at that time.
Um, I went on to play Division
One college ball and had success,
but nothing ever compared to that day.
I remember like it was yesterday
and it happened over 20 years ago.
He never spoke or bothered me ever
again after that day either though.
That story is the shit,
you know.
Can you imagine Dunkin on some
asshole is treating me like shit.
You know what I thought it was and I'm
going to go out on a limb here and get,
you know at the risk of
being called a racist again.
I'm going to guess that
that was a black guy.
Not too many white guys have
a story of Holly got revenge,
was they fucking stole a ball.
Somebody jumped up to block their shot
and they basically jumped over him and
dunked on him. You know, I dunno.
Maybe, I dunno. I'm just saying right.
I mean I,
I was in my white brain,
what I was thinking was everyone was
there at the basketball game and you're
going to do the meatballs thing
and pulled down his shorts. See
that's what you have to do when you can't
jump when you don't have that fucking
option. Cause I don't care how
many fucking, how many whatever,
jump shots you throw him in
somebody's face. It's not
the same. It's not the same.
That's like you just fucking attacked.
Okay.
I mean, I dunno. Getting
dunked on, I mean that's,
that's right up there with just sleep.
She minds was just slapped
his mother right in his face.
I think that's fantastic. That's
what I want to nominate. That is,
that's the one of the best revenge
stories ever because it wasn't sneaky.
It wasn't bitchy.
It was right in the dude's face and a,
and it had the desired effect.
The guy never fucked with them again.
And I'm going to go out on a limb and
say that this dude had the last laugh.
So congratulations.
Jesus Christ.
That should be like one of those
afterschool special movies.
It really had a feel good ending
to it and nobody really got hurt.
So he just got put in their place.
They should fucking film that story and
play it around the holidays just to make
people feel better. All right,
let's get with questions here. Um,
hey bill, I am, I'm a big fan of
your comedy. We bitty, bitty, bitty.
Thank you very much. Uh, I was
looking for a, what the fuck?
I was looking to get some tickets
to the DC improv show on October.
Is curious about your thoughts.
Oh,
I was curious about your thoughts on
the difference between the early and the
late shows. I know when you're a pro
you can kill whether it's the first,
second or second show on any given night,
but I was just wondering which
performance do you prefer and why?
And is the law the single show on Sunday,
the most depressing Gig of the rung
of the run. All right. You know, you,
believe it or not, I get asked this
question a lot of times when people go,
hey man, I'm buying tickets to
your show. I'm coming Friday.
Which one do you think I should go to?
The early one of the late one.
And the reality is, um, you never know.
You never know.
Like this past weekend I was working the
comedy connection in Providence and I
had great shows,
but that one went the standard way where
the early crowd was more sober and more
receptive and the lay crowd was,
uh,
sort of drunk and not paying attention.
Well,
one of the nights it on the Friday night,
it was like the red sox and Yankees
were playing and I guess they went 13
innings or something like that.
It was into extra innings.
So half of the crowd they're face
is glowing by half the crowd.
I mean five fucking people,
but that feels like half to crop.
Their face is glowing because
they're watching the pitch by pitch.
Um, I mean who the fuck is into sports
to that level? You know what I mean?
Breaking ball outside till it,
but you know,
you're gonna fucking end and you
don't even have that guy saying that.
But what happened? They were watching
that shit but then you know what the fuck,
but whatever.
So they weren't paying attention.
So the second show kind of
sucked on that one. But um,
when I was in Denver,
I had a show where the early show they
would drunk maniacs yelling out shit.
It was still fun. Um, so yeah, dude,
it's a crap shoot just like you.
I have no idea either and I
just sort of play off. Well,
however people are doing it.
But I got to admit, I ever,
I have a really good crowd
of people that comes out.
And even when people yell shit out at me,
like I'm,
I don't like if someone's just trying
to be a dick. But if I say something,
someone has an opinion on it
and they yell it out, you know,
as long as it isn't every five seconds,
like that really doesn't bother me.
I actually think it's one of the things
that makes stand up a cool art that uh,
you know, it's one of the few like
public speaking things where like you,
it's kind of accepted in a way that you
can just yell, hey, you fucking suck.
You know? I mean it happens to
bands and that type of shit,
but she can drown them out with your
instruments. I Dunno. I Dunno. Fuck.
I mean, you know, I'm basically, this
is the only thing I've done in public,
so I really don't know what
the fuck I'm talking about. Um,
let's move off to fucking listen.
I want to say there was something
about provenance. I wanted her to say,
well that's out of my head now. Um, okay.
This is how we've been ending a lot of
these podcasts lately where all of a
sudden people are sending me these really,
uh,
heavier questions. This
is sort of the, uh,
the doctor bill section I think is what
I'm going to call it because I'm not
qualified no, that I'm not qualified
to answer any of this shit.
But, uh, this is another one of
these death of a relative thing. So,
uh, after we had the feel
good story, God dammit,
I should've read the revenge
one after this one. But, uh,
this one is sort of
depressing, but not, not,
I'm just going to shut up and
read it. Okay. Bill, my bill,
my mom's oldest sister died from
cancer three weeks ago and wow.
What an opening sentence and
has one surviving sister, um,
during the process of going
through her things. All right,
so let's slow down here
because this gets confusing.
So you have a mom and she had a sister
die and she has one other surviving
sisters.
So it's your mom and your aunt who's
alive at this point and your other aunt
died or aunt, whatever
the fuck you from. Um,
during the process or going through
her things and settling her affairs.
Quite a few interesting
secrets have popped up for one.
We thought my aunt never owned a car,
but have since found out that she
owned several over the last 20 years.
Sounds like the beginning of one
of those a and e murder things.
They thought she was quiet. It didn't
have any carers. Um, for second,
um, we always thought after two
divorces that she had sworn off men.
Turns out,
um,
this gave her license to
sample both sides of the fence.
Any race we're fucking above.
We were about chest deep
and, and this one already,
four sentences in,
have I forgotten to mention that
she was an avid collector of books.
Some might call it a obsessive compulsive.
Needless to say,
I have cited with OCD because she has
five over 5,000 books in a one bedroom
condo on the lake front here in Chicago.
We have found college era photos of her
half naked with a cigarette in one hand
in various background items that
would suggest early seventies era.
Uh,
mostly because the gigantic stereos
with turntables and eight track slot.
So, okay. Um, through this
process, my mom's middle sister,
I guess this is the surviving one and
her two kids and families have distanced
themselves from the,
this estate settling process.
While my mom and I have spent 80 plus
man hours going through the Condo,
my middle aunt and her family
have consistently talked
about how busy they are.
Uh,
um, and that they have all but said,
we don't care how much you've done.
And I, dude, you were a little vague here.
Are they getting stuff from the will?
I was a little confused with that.
Um, but anyways, I realize, um,
there was a very complex set
of emotions going on here.
Perhaps their show of indifference is
because they feel guilty about not seeing
my dead aunt when she was alive.
Perhaps they live in a nearly perfect
world and don't want to be bothered.
Perhaps they are unfeeling jackasses
and don't care. It's hard to judge.
I really want to tell them to
go fuck themselves. And several,
several contact with them once and for
all, once the will is paid out. Okay.
So evidently I get it.
So they're entitled to some Shit
and they're not helping out. Uh,
but they are family and I was brought
to respect family while they apparently
were not,
it pains me to know that they are blood
relatives and that their mindset is
indicative of my middle
Anse upbringing of them.
MMM.
I guess that's just surviving aunt.
Um,
I feel loss and sorrow for
losing my aunt to cat cancer,
but I also feel loss and sorrow about
losing my other aunt and her kids and
families because they are
not who I thought they were.
Any advice you could give would be great.
Add Dude, I don't know what to tell you.
MMM.
Yeah.
It's fucked up that they're going to get
some money out of this shit and they're
not helping you go through her stuff.
MMM.
But, uh, I dunno dude. How
often do you see these?
Yeah.
You know,
I dunno,
I kind of draw the line
at your immediate family.
If he's talking about aunts and
cousins and that type of shit,
if they're assholes,
they're really, you know,
like you ever think of how barely your
cousins are part of your family tree?
I mean, you basically have to go up
the tree and then back down the tree,
two limbs to get to him. So fuck
them. They're out right now.
Really held my cousins
don't listen to this podcast
and then your aunt. I mean, I dunno.
I Dunno. It's, it's your aunt.
Fuck them. Fuck them. Go
with you got fuck them.
Clear out the mortgage and then uh,
yeah, fuck them. I mean they sound,
I mean, the way you've talked about on
the kind of sound like assholes. I mean,
what do you want to debate their house
smells to the way you've described them.
You want to go over into
this smelly house, you know,
to watch the Billy Bass that they bought
with your dead ants. Money. Fuck them.
Go with your gut. Fuck them. You know,
at some point you, you, you could,
I don't know. Do you want to
have that confrontation? Yeah,
I think the only weird thing of
the cousins is not a weird thing.
I don't think the fact that
they're not involved is,
is a weird thing because a lot of times,
you know,
people could be really separated.
But like the weird thing is your aunt
not giving a shit that your other aunt
died because their sisters, that's
just fucking bizarre to me. But, uh,
who knows?
Maybe a dead ant did something to her.
He didn't know that she
had 20 fucking cars.
Maybe you should keep sifting
through the pictures and uh,
maybe you'll discover something. I
don't know what, I don't know what,
but I dunno what do that advice sucked.
Okay.
I'm not qualified for a
yeah.
You know,
I don't know that level of stuff,
but feel free to keep sending me stuff
like that cause it must be fun to listen
to me a squirm. Speaking of that. Um,
here's some shit about,
uh, you know, something,
somebody sent me something great about
banks trying to help me explain what the
fuck I was trying to say last week,
but really couldn't explain
it in an intelligent way.
And I lost the email because I,
I didn't have any internet over the
weekend and I had it on my blackberry.
I got rid of it.
But basically this guy was touching
on some shit that I had heard before.
That basically when you,
if you take a thousand of your own
dollars and you put it in a bank,
believe it or not,
the bank can legally loan that thousand
dollars out to like nine different
people.
I don't mean nine people get a
portion that totals up to a thousand.
I mean nine people can get $1,000 loan
off of the thousand dollars that you put
in. So if you're sitting there going,
well then didn't they just invent,
um,
$8,000 they just created out of thin air?
Yeah.
And um, I don't know if that's
why our money really has no value.
They just created out of thin air.
And this guy was basically explaining
that one of the reasons our money has
value is basically the
person who takes the loan,
them promising to pay it
back, gives it value. But uh,
I dunno,
I have no idea.
I wish that there was some sort of uh,
yeah,
like home kit where you could make
your own bank. You know what I mean?
The same way people make their own
fucking beer in the bathtub or they make
lemonade this, you know, that'd be a
great fight. Billy Mays was still alive.
He could sell that shit.
You know, I'm Billy Mays.
Are you sick of putting your money in
the banks and having a loan out to a
budget? Can't you don't even pay it
back. So then you fucking lose Hedrick.
Dozy your own personal baggage.
He basically showed you how to convert
your garage into a brick. Fucking,
I dunno what have some homeless
guy that would be your security.
You just have some homeless guy that
smells so fucking bad. You know,
granted all your money would smell,
but like no one would go near.
I don't know what. I don't
know what to tell you, but I,
I feel like an idiot every week taking
my money and then putting it into a bank,
but there's no other fucking options,
you know,
short of sticking it in my mattress,
and then you make yourself
a target, you know, hey,
you see that skinny red at over there.
It doesn't know how to fight a,
he's got a fucking thousand dollars
in his pillowcase. Hey guys. Hey,
you want to play Frisbee?
Let's get blasted in the face
and not only am I out 1000 bucks,
I ought to buy a new pillow because I
noticed that's one thing about when people
steal, they have to ruin your
place too. They have to ransack it.
They can't just reach into your pillow.
It's wide open. Just reach in and take it.
Not how I got to rip it
off and fucking stab it up.
You know
something about putting on a cat suit
that makes people extra destructive.
All right. Anyways, that's
the podcast for this week.
I hope to see you guys out at my show.
I am getting geared up for my special,
I'm not drinking, I'm not boozing, so
please don't tempt me when I'm out there,
but if you want to show me your tits,
that is fine and I will happily sign them.
See, there's a balance to my
life also. Um, please try to cut.
If you're anywhere near
Ontario, California, please
come out to my show out there.
I would really love to sell a bunch
of tickets out there because, um,
I don't have much of a presence
here in the lower California area.
I don't have anything in San Diego.
I got nothing going on in the greater
la area and I usually don't plead with
people to this level to come to my
shows, but I am right now. All right.
I'm like fucking what's his face and that,
that fucking Miller's crossing.
Look into your heart.
Look into you
John. Turturro. What a
great fucking movie that is.
I finally saw that one the other day.
Wasn't that a great,
you guys want to hear cleo
getting scratched one more
time to hear what fucking
ecstasy sounds like. No, I
she won't do it. Here we go.
Yeah,
there you go. That wasn't as good as
yellow ones. Whatever. Go Fuck Yourself.
This is life. That's how it goes. All
right. Now let me know how this works out.
Is it a smaller file and all that type
of shit? You guys have a good week and a,
I will talk to you next Monday,
although it will be a little bit
later cause I am flying back from,
from Atlanta on, uh, on
Monday. So there you go.
All right, so don't be like, dude,
where the fuck is it? It's common.
It's always calming. All right. Might be
a little fucking late, but it is coming.
All right,
you guys have a good week.
Okay.