Hey, what's going on is bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcasting.
Just checking it all you what's going on?
It's just fucking global
warming. Awesome. Or what?
Jesus Christ is summer just keeps going.
It's incredible.
Um,
the Golden Age,
the golden age of global warming and
joy it before the sea levels rise up.
MMM.
By your waterfront property
in West Virginia. Soon.
Sorry, I don't want to go with all
gloom and doom here. Um, it is, uh,
12:46 AM Thursday.
Uh,
so I have gone 56 days.
All right.
56 days. Two months. Sorry,
two months. No fucking booze.
And 56.
Now what does the number of 56 mean to
you all you baseball fans out there.
October playoff baseball,
56.
Jolton Joe Dimaggio's
unbeatable hit record,
hit for 56 games in a row.
And it's true.
I think it's very poignant that I bring
up a great Yaggie when those fucking
cons just came back against
the, uh, Cleveland Indians.
And, uh, I have to tell
you, it was a red sox fan.
The Yankees are common and they're
going to be good for a while.
They've got a bunch of,
you know what I love about the Yankees?
Is there a fucking team?
You know what I mean?
I fucking hate that they're going to
be good, but I got to acknowledge it.
They're fucking good. Um,
poor fucking Cleveland.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Jesus Christ g oh Jesus.
That's an oh Jesus. Right
there. Up Two games to none.
Or You just had to win one more.
You know, fucking do it. Oh,
fucking comedy of errors.
I didn't see the game four.
I guess they fucked up a bunch of
average and then they just, you know,
the fucking guy in left field,
that's the single turn into a double.
Then they overtake fucking alligator arm.
A fucking cutoff and the guy scratch
this was a fucking shit show. However,
the only thing I don't like
about the fucking, by the way,
Brett gardeners at bat legendary a bed,
their shortstop, dare, I don't know if I'm
going to say his name right. He's a DD.
Great. Glorious. I have no
idea. Two huge fucking home run.
Smiley. My only question mark, if
I can go sports radio right now.
Are you buying or are you selling?
I don't know about Chapman is the closer,
you know, I know he closed the
fucking game. That was great for him.
I know he wanted for the cubs last year,
but I don't know.
I don't think you got a fucking strong
closer when he walks the first guy and
you already have somebody
else up in the bullpen.
Maybe I'm spoiled after all those
years when I watched Marianna Rivera,
nobody fucking got
okay.
It's fucking Marianna were very, that
gave it, the game's tied. The game's over.
Except in 2004 of clothes. Of
course I'll bill. You can't,
that was impressive. So now they're
going to play the Houston Astros.
A franchise without an identity.
I Dunno what it is about them.
I was just talking to a j law head,
you know, giving them my condolences. I
congratulated Versie my teams out of it.
I'm not a cunt. Right? Well I
am, but not that big of a cut.
Um,
I was just at what the fuck?
Why are the Astros' so not exciting?
Okay.
Is it the uniforms?
Maybe I'm just an old guy.
When they were in the fucking
national league and they had,
I don't know what you would
call those fucking uniforms,
those things with his shit.
They sorta had the, uh,
the gay bar flag,
you know,
gay friendly fucking flag.
They were flying those
colors really progressive way
back in the late seventies.
They played on the National League.
So it was all hitting run.
They had the astro turf day,
a Jr Richards.
They had hope say cruise Enos Cabell
you remember that fucking team way back
when? I don't think that they've
been fucking exciting ever since.
At some point they decided to
have those fucking bland uniforms.
It's like dark color.
You don't what it looks
like they did uniform.
It's a uniform or equivalent
to when you go on a diet,
you know, you have your first
little fucking chest pains and they,
the doctor goes, look, I'm
gonna tell you right now,
he needed to take off 30 pounds.
You need to cut all this salt and sugar
out of your diet, right? And you're like,
yeah, fuck it. You just sitting there
eating lettuce, staring across somebody.
If somebody went to dinner with the
reading the chicken palm dare order and
bread and you're just sitting there with
your fucking salad and the protein no
bigger than the size of
the palm of your hand.
They have the uniform version
of that low level of excitement.
Okay.
Um, I have no, I don't know shit
about the Astros' other than that,
they had an unbelievable year. So,
uh, I fucking love October baseball.
Um, my fucking Red Sox
Los, we deserve to lose.
What are you going to do? A, we'll
see what we do in the off season.
Congratulations to the Astros.
Definitely were the better team and a,
I missed all the Dodgers series and
I saw the highlights tonight of, uh,
of the cubs and nationals. Jesus Christ.
That fucking grand slam is brutal.
You know what's weird is the cubs lost
for so long. I still felt bad for him.
I forgot that they won the world
series last year, but I was just,
I'm so used to feeling bad for cubs fans.
I actually felt bad when that guy
hit the home run. And by the way,
can anybody explain?
And uh,
this it's always bugged me about Wrigley
field is that fucking fence that just
juts out that little basket,
you know,
that gives the warning track
power guy a fucking home run.
What are they going to take that thing
down? I don't understand that thing.
It hangs out into the field of play.
It's not a fucking hall.
It is a home run.
The little fence there.
What are we playing? Fucking tee
ball, take the God damn basket.
Whatever the fuck that is.
Um,
reminds me of way back in the day when
against the Yankees first the Orioles,
when that kid reached over and grabbed
the home run instantly became a fucking
hero with all Yankee fans who then I'll
then turn around and fucking call the
fucking red sox. I mean, the
Patriots cheaters, it's Hilarious,
but everybody does it. You
know what I mean? I mean,
look at this big story
out here in Hollywood.
The big scandal ha ve Weinstein,
right?
First of all, dude, I mean,
what a display of power to finish in a
potted plant and then have the nerve to
call the person the next day saying, hey,
you know, I had a great time. I mean,
that's out of your fucking mind and
I don't get these fucking people, uh,
where everything,
but I'm going to go to rehab.
How do you go to Rehab to stop you
for preventing a woman leaving a room,
taking your dick out and comment
on a firm? Do they have rehab?
I didn't know that. What are you
in there for? Oh, you know, I uh,
I fucking blocked an
exit and just on a plant.
Oh yeah, yeah, me too. Me Too. Well, I
guess we're going to be buddies here, Huh?
You know, and they just in this wing of
the rehab with this no potted plants,
they got buddies outside
the fucking window.
Tried to sneak fucking plants in forum.
That is the most bizarre fucking story.
But, um, that's not what I want to
talk about here. You know what I mean?
Where they fucking sitting there going
all I love when they send all all of men
in Hollywood kept silent.
It's like everybody did and they weren't
acting like Harvey Weinstein couldn't
ruin the career of a guy.
That guy up until four days ago could
take your career wadded up right in front
of you and throw it in the gutter and
you were done. You were fucking done.
You're talking about a guy,
whoever allegedly could block
a woman from leaving a room
and then coming on a planet and then
fucking does the follow up call.
Like they went to dinner and a
movie and they had a lovely time.
That's the level of power this guy had.
Human beings should not have
that level of power by the way.
Cause man or a woman, they, they, they
do not handle it well. Um, but anyways,
let's get back too far. It's like, you
know, being able to see both sides,
the fence house sports fans that just
like, you know, that's obviously holding.
And then if the holding called doesn't
it go against you? It's like, oh no,
no fucking great call,
great non call Fox News Day.
We're going off on fucking
Harvey Weinstein and all
Hollywood now underhanded
and Blahblahblahblahblah.
But when Trump was grabbing the pussies,
they got nothing, right?
And then fucking CNN,
it's the same fucking way Trump
grabs the fucking pussies.
They're all fucking over.
Harvey Weinstein does what he does.
This isn't a time to
fucking politicizes thing.
They're both so fucking full of shit.
And they're going to judge all
Hollywood on Harvey Weinstein. Right?
The same way the Liberals Judge
all Republicans on Donald Trump.
I don't know anybody. Uh, watch is
either one of those channels. However,
I will say this cause I don't
watch Fox News that often.
I don't really watch CNN, but I
will say at least CNN, it looks,
it looks professional. I'm not saying it
is all it is, but I'm not saying it's,
it's obviously not ridiculously
biased that they both are. But for,
what is Fox News looks like?
It looks like fucking Wsp k TV 38 back
in the day when they go in between
periods and their little bullshit sent.
I don't know. What about Fox News?
It's like they, they got to put more
money into it. Everybody looks sweaty,
you know, I don't understand
it. Um, but anyways,
Jesus fucking Christ.
Uh,
so now they're going back
into everybody's life.
They go back into somebody's eye. He
did this back in 2000. Here's my thing.
All these guys and now going to have
to apologize for all the shit they did
evidently back into the fucking 90.
So whatever my question is, is, uh,
when is the,
when is it going to even out a,
I would love to see some gold digging
whores come on and apologize and be like,
yeah, hey, sorry,
I took your house and add a couple of
kids with the Ed said that I loved you
when I really didn't. Uh,
I shouldn't have done that.
And then prevented you from seeing
those kids that you had with me.
That half looked like me and you now know
that I never really loved you. And uh,
I'm sorry for that and banging the
new guy in this house that you bought.
And now I'm also not
going to, uh, you know,
have my new boyfriend ever move in or
married me because then my payments from
you and the alimony will stop.
I want to apologize for that.
My behavior was completely unacceptable
just to balance it out. Listen,
if you knew that this podcast,
um, one of the mainstays of this
podcast is, and I'm a, I'm a,
I'm a contrarion cunt.
All right?
So if you're, if you're new
to it, you know, I don't know.
This first 11 minutes is what you
can expect for the rest of this. Um,
anyways, I am in Atlanta,
Georgia right now. Uh,
I got a, I got a small part
in a big movie. I mean,
that's my career. That's my,
that's my fucking wheelhouse.
I love it. You know,
all I want to do is paratroop in for a
couple of fucking days, have a good time,
you know, get to watch the real
fucking actors. Do the Goddamn thing.
I always feel like I won a contest when
I do a movie. You know what I mean? Like,
Hey, you want to be in a
movie? Oh boy. Oh boy do I. Um,
so I'm gonna be here for the next, uh,
the next couple of weeks, you know,
miss and my family like fucking
crazy. Uh, I'm hoping, uh,
trying to work something out where I
can bring them in so I don't lose my
fucking mind out here.
I'm not going to lie to you.
I was actually so fucking
lonely and depressed last night.
Um,
I mean,
obviously it's exciting to do a movie
just missing my family that I walked by a
liquor store and I saw this bottle of
booze in there in the window and I was
like, uh, am I going to buy
that and finish all of it?
And fortunately I walked past it and I
went down to the laughing skull comedy
club, uh, went up on stage, thank
you to them for putting me on stage.
And I went up there and I want to say
I kind hate my boss. It was a very,
a give and take, a lot
more. Whatever's worse,
but a lot more worse. A lot more give or
a lot more to, I don't know what it was,
but it, it was a rough one. Okay. Um,
but anyway,
so now I'm Outta here.
I gotta figure out what
the Fuck I'm going to do.
I went to trader Joe's about some
healthy fucking food. You know,
all this shit's healthy,
but they still have a frozen food aisles,
so I don't get that. You know what I
mean? They still have fucking cereal,
you know what I mean? That's that part
of a balanced breakfast. Is it cereal?
Can you even what, what the fuck is
cereal? I just thought about that.
Like what is in a cheerio
about these brand fucking things?
I don't know what they are
like,
can you make cereal? I bet
to some. Somebody on Youtube,
homemade cereal. I'm gonna look
that up. I, I've been, it'd be,
I'm going to go out on a limb and say,
I'm the first person we ever
fucking Google this home.
Fucking feds are going to knock on the
God damn door right now. Homemade cereal.
Does anybody likes cereal
enough to fucking do directions?
Okay. Preheat your oven to 275
degrees. I don't know about you,
but I'm already out. I get either
open a box and pour it and it's done.
Or I can go preheat my oven until 275
degrees from my friends around the world.
That's 135 degrees Celsius.
Um,
in a large bowl mix. Oats,
wheat germ, wheat germ.
What I'll is that in and we brand,
oh my God.
If you can actually take
the time to make cereal,
this is what you're going in a
medium bowl blend. Brown sugar,
vegetable oil,
honey and water mix and vanilla extract.
Is he making here? Cinnamon. Nutmeg.
It sounds like you're
making a pie and salt.
Beg for 45 minutes in a preheated oven
stirring every 15 minutes until lightly
brown. Hey Eddie, you're 20 minutes
fucking later than you usually.
Are you usually only an hour late for
work? Where the fuck you been? Oh,
you know what I'm saying?
All about with making breakfast.
What the fuck did you make?
Homemade cereal. Hey, Yeti.
Do me a favor. Why don't you fucking go
punch out and get the fuck out of here?
You're fired. How do you make corn
flakes flakes? Saudi make cocoa puffs.
They actually had this shit.
How to make cinnamon toast crunch caught
a couple whole wheat pastry flour.
Who has the fucking time to do this?
Quarter Cup of all purpose flour.
Baking Soda, cinnamon. All right.
Wait a fucking minute.
We're going to go this far right.
How do you spell Fritos?
Homemade fritos.
All right.
Hey De oven to 375 degrees.
Cut to pieces of parchment one the same
size is a beacon baking sheet and set
aside in a small bowl.
Whisk together the corn meal and the
salt place one sheet of parchment.
Am I going to do this?
Can you imagine if you fucking made
a homemade fritos and people like,
what the fuck? Where the fuck did you get
these freedom? I made it myself though.
Homemade.
Are you on house arrest?
Who the fuck has time to do
this shit fucking asshole.
You make it homemade, you know, how
did you make your own trans fat?
She a fucking psycho. Um, quarter thought.
Who the fuck would have thought that
you could do something like this?
It says a fucking great country.
Um, I've heard people make it.
Do you hear that fucking growl side?
What is that?
I shut off the fucking air con.
I fucking hate air conditioning.
It's so overused.
Air conditioning is like that person at
a party who just won't shut the fuck up,
you know?
Oh, you know what they said
that about, I was watching,
you know the B e t a wrap awards there,
hip hop awards
and um,
I'm watching all this shit.
And they had the guy from two live crew,
they were giving him like a lifetime
achievement award and it was fucking
hilarious. He was up there dressed
like he just got a doctorate
and then afterwards he does all his
music and it's all over me. So horny,
all that shit. I'm not saying I don't
like that fucking music, but I mean,
Jesus Christ, he had like a bow tie
on and his whole suit and everything,
it looked like a s a
fucking elder statesman. Um,
but anyways, uh, I dunno, I was
okay
talking to my wife about it.
I don't know shit about hip hop,
but this fucking thing where everybody
is drinking that shit, that lean,
whatever the hell it is,
and everybody sounds,
even if they're not fucking wasted,
they sound like they're waste
drives me up the wall. I just
listened to it. It's like, you know,
when you go to a party and there's
somebody way more fucked up than you were
just like, dude, I can't talk to you. I
got, how did I got to get out of this? Um,
that's what it sounded like. That one
dude lost all that fucking wait man. Okay.
I usually takes the shirt off when
he was fat, he took his shirt off.
Now he's skinny or,
and he has his clothes on,
which probably means he's still getting
the skin removed or whatever. You know,
it's funny. All the weight that he lost.
He still weighs more than all of them.
Migos
put together even with their jewelry on,
I'm sorry. I've just been, I, I'm I
my first day on the movies tomorrow,
so I've just been sitting here and
fucking watching TV and a waiting to work.
So I've just been watching
MMM.
Just been watching all
of this shit and uh,
listening to music and stuff.
Dude, I know, I'm like fucking, uh,
over 10 years late on this thing,
but I am an old guy is,
um, I've just been listening to the
first to Mars Volta albums and a,
I got to tell you, John Theodore is a
fucking genius drummer. That, what is it?
How do you say the Sarah Eyes? I don't
want to say any anything. V I s c.
E r a any drummers out there,
you gotta listen to that fucking song
and you've got to learn how to play it.
He can't be a drummer.
It listen to that and not want to
at least that open and drum groove.
I don't know what the fuck he's
doing on the breakdown in the end,
but it's one of the sickest fucking
drum grooves I've ever heard in my life.
And you listen to what the guitar is,
is doing.
Most people would have just played with
the guitar and the way he fucking plays
around it.
And one of my favorite things is does
not have the snare on two and four. It's,
and it's still just fucking
not only fucking rocks,
it propels this fucking song.
I think I've listened
to the song 200 times.
Okay.
And the last fucking week and it's still
giving me chills. It's fucking unreal.
And uh, my drum teacher a long time ago
told me to get into this band, Michigan.
And I listened to it and I, I just,
it was too advanced. I couldn't,
I couldn't hear what was, it was
just too much shit to be listened to.
But because I've been listening to
Mars Volta and they're crazy shit.
I actually went back cause I was scrolling
through looking for Mars Volta and I
and I had this much sugar album for
the longest time and I went back and
listened to it and I,
I think I'm finally starting to like,
I always knew it was amazing, but now
I actually am like fucking into it. Um,
I just keep listening to that first song.
I'm baby step in my way into it.
This music is way advanced for my fucking
limited fucking musical abilities.
But that first song
Stanger, s, e, n, g, h,
just the drumming on that, the whole
fucking thing is unbelievable. So, uh,
I've just been, that's what I've
been doing. I haven't been boozing.
I've been watching old twilight zones.
I've been listening to,
there's all this fucking music and uh,
I dunno,
I went out tonight till was cigar bar.
That's my one vice that I have left.
That's all I got left.
Um,
and it went out and ordered my fucking
club soda and a lime. I got to tell you,
the minute I actually felt, you know,
walk out, I'm not shit faced. It's Nice,
you know? Yeah. Bill, that'd
be boozed every fucking day.
People find that nice after a while.
I will. All right then. All right.
I haven't been able to watch
any of the hawk. He fucking,
I know the Bruins are one and two.
We got crushed by the avs tonight.
Six to three.
And I'm actually debating on Saturday
because I'm going out of my mind,
uh,
miss and my family,
I'm actually debating the Tennessee
volunteers have a home game.
I'm actually debating, it's a three hour
drive. I know they're not good this year,
but that's such a legendary stadium.
They are home.
I live on the other side of the country.
It's three hours.
I can drive up their scalp,
a fucking ticket,
watch him play the South Carolina
Gamecocks Nice sec matchup.
I get to fucking go to that state.
I think I'm going to do it.
What else am I gonna do?
Sit here alone in this fucking hotel room,
missing my Kiddo, you know? Um,
anyways, so let's get into the, uh,
I think I'm going to do it.
Fuck it. That'll be my 20th,
my 20th college football
team that I've seen.
I've seen some big ones though.
That'll be Mike by Fifth or sixth
SEC team that I've seen a home game.
I've seen Texas a and M, Lsu,
Alabama, Georgia, Florida,
and then Tennessee. I mean, as far as the,
the big ones I'd have left, I'd have
Auburn, Ole Miss, Mississippi state,
and fucking Arkansas,
you know,
no disrespect to, uh, uh,
Vanderbilt was who's left? Vanderbilt,
Kentucky and Missouri, Missouri. Like,
you know, I feel like the SCC is like,
they're rebound conference, you know,
they still want to be in the big 12,
but the fucking university of Texas came
up with their own, I dunno, their own.
Yes. Network their own and
whatever the fuck they did.
I don't understand why everybody else
just didn't do the same thing. Um,
but anyways, I think I'm going
to do it anyway. It's enough.
Enough with the fucking pablet here.
Oh, a little bit of advertising here.
All right. Uh, but don't do it
beyond ease me undies.
Bills all the fucking loan to do.
Dude
do brds me undies held
it up against my bone. Make it my
junk field. Really fucking Nice.
Uh,
get a steel column.
If you got some Lysol or some fucking
crabs down in your fucking under and you
know, maybe that's a way to
get rid of crabs. That's like,
that's how fucking nice to undies
are. It literally, it just makes them,
they fall asleep and they let go your
pubes and they fall right off down to t
socks. That's disgusting.
All right. Uh, me undies.
You know me undies makes the most
comfortable underwear in the world.
World world. If underwear isn't
your thing, you fucking animal.
We're excited to announce that
me undies socks are finally here.
Speaking of animals, by the
way, I'm calling her right now.
That Yankee Fan at the end of
the fucking Cleveland series,
when they cut to those two Yankee fans,
the guy on the left, when he was clapping,
somebody's going to turn that
into something. I mean, dude,
how, how unathletic are you
that you can't even clap
if you see when they teach like a
chimp on a clap of fucking chimpanzee,
clap better than this guy in
the fucking look on his face.
I don't know what was going on with
that guy. I hope he doesn't help.
He's not touched on some level then. I
feel bad. He did have front row seats.
You never know. Uh,
anyways, be ready for work,
play and everything else in between with
the new me undies, socks, me, undies,
socks are now available. Ah,
making your toes fill all nice.
There me undies.
Socks are spun from premium materials.
It's made me think of Rapunzel making
their socks the best you can get for your
feet.
Andy's will be the most comfortable pair
of underwear and now socks you'll ever
own. Jesus Christ. How the fuck
are you going to go to work?
If your balls and feet feel that good,
you're going to be nice.
You can be nice to everybody.
Uh, me undies will be the
most, they shouldn't give.
Sent a pair of those to
the fucking Grinch. Me.
Undies will be the most
comfortable pair of underwear.
No socks will ever own 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
They guarantee you will love your undies
and socks or your money back. Right now,
[inaudible] has an exclusive offer
just for our listeners and every other
fucking podcast they advertise on.
You get 20% off your first
order and free shipping.
Me undies is so sure you will
love their underwear and socks.
They will give you a 100% satisfaction
guarantee. Simply order a pair,
and if you don't love it,
get a full refund. Um,
to get your 20% off the best and softest
underwear and socks you will ever own
for free. Um, well free
shipping you'll ever own. Sorry,
free shipping and 100%
satisfaction guarantee.
You got to go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] that's [inaudible] dot
com slash part they're not free.
They're 20% off. Sorry. For some reason,
the way they put comma a comma
always fucks me up. All right,
next lift everybody.
Lyft knows that their drivers
are what keeps them moving. Well,
obviously you fucking drive people for
a living other than the car and the car
can't do shit without a driver.
Uh,
so they will do everything they can to
make sure that drivers are happy on every
trip.
Sorry.
Lyft is the ride sharing company that
believes in treating it's people better
that I love how all the shade that they're
throwing over at fucking Uber during
this lift begin believes that being a
ride sharing drivers should be fun if
you're having a good time.
So are the passengers well
don't have to good at time.
You fucking up my life in your
hands there. If it choosing raw,
I ride sharing company to drive for go
with a company that treats you better.
Lift lift was the first
offer in APP tipping.
When you drive for Lyft you keep 100% of
the tips are my stomach's growling here
being an actor can't eat late at night.
A 100% of the tips drivers will
be paid over 200 million in tips.
Since drivers have been paid over 200
million in tips since the feature was
first introduced,
express pay lets drivers get paid almost
instantly instead of waiting for weeks.
Lyft has taken the
guesswork out of pickups.
The new amp device uses color coding
to help passengers find the drivers.
You can earn hundreds of dollars
a week plus tips. What are it?
Won't dry boards? Never been easier
to give yourself a raise. Sorry,
I'm doing this one 13 in the morning here.
Now it's a simple formula.
Happy drivers mean happy passengers.
Maybe that's why nine out of every 10 Lyft
riders get a perfect five star rating.
So join the ride sharing company that
believes in treating its people better.
Go to lift.com/bird today and you
can get a $500 new driving bonus.
That's lyft.com/burr lyft.com/
[inaudible] spelled l,
y. F. T. It's a limited
time only terms do apply.
All right. What am I up
to here? 28 and change.
I got to kill another minute and a half.
Um,
actually if I do the drive
up to Knoxville,
Tennessee,
um,
I will pass through one of my favorite
and most one of the most underrated
cities in the United States,
Chattanooga, Tennessee.
I've only been there one time and I had
such a fucking great time. Great Food,
great bars,
just great people.
Just a great fucking great city.
Love that place.
And um, and Knoxville's another
place that had a great fucking time.
Everybody goes to Tennessee,
they all go to Nashville.
They want to go to the grand old
fucking Opry. They want to fucking,
I don't know what the fuck you'll go
see some live music and all that shit.
I'm telling you right now,
sorry.
Do not sleep on Chattanooga,
Tennessee. Do not avoid Knoxville diff.
Fucking great. I swear to God, if
I wasn't in this God damn business,
I could live in either one of those towns.
Um,
I'm a big fan of that state.
not that I'm shitting on fucking Georgia
here cause it's another good time. Uh,
speaking in which I guess
the College Hall of fame,
some sort of hall of fames out here.
I might go check that out down the street.
Um, but that is it, that that is a
podcast here. Oh Billy freckles here is,
I got to get my hate. I was asleep.
Um, and go do my fucking little
what I like to call acting
tomorrow. Uh, that is it. It,
was there anything else I wanted to talk
about my promoting anything coming up.
Oh yeah.
We added a third show and I'm in Austin
and Austin city limits now is all
excited that this is the same place
where I saw Stevie Ray Vaughan play.
But evidently that's a new one.
However,
it is the same place where I saw Iggy
pop with queen of the Queens of the stone
age performed.
So it is legendary and we'd be down
there with Dean del Rey and I'm trying to
find out if I can record.
Um,
cause my Madison Square Garden
recording did not work. Um,
I fucked up.
They just gave me the recording from the
board so I am loud as shit and you can
barely hear the crowd.
So oops.
I don't know if I'll ever get to do
Madison Square Garden against, so,
oh well I guess it's just a memory.
Um,
but I'm starting to think when I played
like these really cool venues like this,
that I'm just going to record audio.
I don't know what I'm going to do with it.
I might just start, you
know, putting out a random,
like fucking just on vinyl Assam Shit.
MMM.
You know,
I got to know the guys over there at third
man records that's also in Nashville.
Uh, Jack White's company. Those
guys treated me great. I did my, uh,
Carnegie Hall one with those guys,
so maybe who knows,
maybe I could do something with them.
MMM.
I Dunno.
I kinda like the idea that cause my act
changed so much and I have like a lot of
like topical shit. And I was
thinking like, what if I just,
yeah,
I don't know.
Just start recording all these sets and
then maybe I splice it together a bunch
of different ones. I Dunno,
we'll see what happens. But, uh,
it's never bad to have a good recording.
Right.
Am I just spit balling out loud you guys
as if this is fucking entertainment.
I have no idea. Um, all
right, that's it. Uh,
congratulations to Jaromir Jaeger.
You've got fucking signed with the Calgary
flames demands career continues and
um, I look forward to watching
them out there and shit.
I know I made all you guys yawn.
I apologize,
but I don't have time to do
this tomorrow. Uh, that's it.
You guys have a great day,
a wonderful weekend. And um,
I will talk to you on a Monday and a,
those of you new to this podcast,
we now do a greatest hits
from a Thursday gone by. Uh,
you can listen to some cool music if
you have any questions about who did the
music,
just a tweet at the mm podcast
at the podcast and I'm,
Andrew is really good about,
uh,
post in that type of shit to let you know
who it is cause he plays all the cool
music. Uh, you know, um, but um, I'm
way behind as you can tell. All right,
I'm just starting to get into Mars Volta.
Okay.
I'm getting into a band that people
are hoping is going to have a reunion.
I'm just getting it to them. Okay. All
right. Okay. That is it. Uh, all right.
Have a great weekend.
I'll talk to you later,
citizen.
So,
all right. Hair loss or sex loss bill,
I'm sure you've heard of Propecia.
Heard of it.
I used it.
I used it and when I ran out of it,
I just had that honest moment
with myself and I was just like,
there's no way. There's not going to be
a side effect. Okay. There's always just,
there's no way. There's just no way.
There's no way this thing, okay,
I'll save my hair but damage my liver.
You know,
what do I need more? You know, a full head
of hair or a functioning fucking liver.
You just, you know, you just got to bite
the bullet and turn it. Just turn old.
Just age gracefully. You know,
I try to keep my hair short.
I tried to offend as little people as
I go through the slow process of seeing
what my skull actually looks like.
He goes,
I have a lot of friends on it
that say it's sort of works.
Definitely slows down hair loss
by doing something. However,
apparently the drawbacks is no boner.
Oh,
is that? I don't know. I don't know
either way on that one. That's a,
that's some bar stuff. I think that that
can, that can happen to some people.
I have no fucking idea.
He said,
so do you choose hair to
get sex or choose no hair,
which might mean no sex.
Is this some sort of sick joke by the
pharmaceutical companies know you're,
you're fighting nature. Listen
Dude, I'll tell you right now.
All right, there's women out there
that think a shaved head is sexy.
Not all of them, but
there's enough. All right,
there's enough out there that you can
keep going out. Bang. And women, you know,
some women find a shaved head fucking
they lay like it turns him on.
So listen,
this is the great thing about women is
they could see beyond what you look like.
Okay? If you come in there and you got a
little swagger and you're funny and you
fucking, you know, shaved shows
confidence, dude, you're like, fuck it,
preemptive strike. You guys are
walking out on me. Well you know what,
I'm kicking you out the door
and you take out your clippers.
You know, I bust my head down a
few years ago. I fucking loved it.
And I took all the jokes.
When your kid's a patient,
if fucking make a wish but bubba button
to Peters out after a couple of weeks,
you know?
Yeah,
I dunno. I go back and forth.
I go back and forth. I mean,
I go literally from doing,
maybe I'll do the fucking hair transplant
to all the way back to all fucking
shape my head again. I have no idea, but
I gotta be honest with you, dude. It it,
it doesn't, the vibe you're bringing
is going to be way more. Listen,
do you really want to get with some
girl who's with you because you have a
fucking, a nice big cow lick
on top of your fucking head.
And if you didn't have it then she
wouldn't be with you. You know,
going bald is like driving
a piece of shit car.
It really keeps the horse away from you.
All these fucking idiots with full heads
of hair driving around flashy cars.
You see what happens to them?
What happened to Mel Gibson?
He should have just gone bald,
but he didn't.
He kept fighting it through and shit
up there. Drove around in a flashy car.
I had to give up my fucking leg or
tickets, you know, flipping out,
flipping up. You know what dude?
Yeah. Don't take those fucking drugs.
Those drugs are brand new and the side
effects that they're talking about,
I'm telling you is just to shit that
they're letting on to cover their ass is
that they said that there
was some side effects. Okay.
From what I've overheard bars,
the people on the FDA,
half of them used to work for these
pharmaceutical fucking company,
so they got the nuts running
the fucking nuthouse. All right,
and you're just going to be a good,
you're going to be a little lab rat if
you start taking that shit. All right?
So I would suggest not doing it.
Let nature take its fucking
course and do what I'm doing.
Wait for the cure and our
guarantee it at ain't gonna come.
So just fucking man up and go bald.
You fucking pussy gate door.
What I'm doing just slowly let it happen.
A year from now,
I'm going to have fucking hair plugs
and I'm going to be performing for
dictators for New Year's Eve.
Give niggers
be best friends with Beyonce.
I didn't see my itinerary either.
I didn't know who it was.
I literally use the same excuse
for performing for oil men.
Stop
sweating.
Uh, the past couple of weeks I've been
talking about the food down here in New
Orleans, saint help, delicious
slash unhealthy it is.
And how you can't find fucking
Kale. Excuse me. As a drink.
More cold water for my fucking scalded.
Tunc
mmm.
I actually bought a juicer this week to
somehow combat all the fried food that
I've been eating. And a, I started
drinking that shit that, that guy and uh,
uh, fat dead and kind of sick,
whatever the fuck is called.
Fat Sick and nearly dead.
Yeah.
Just sick, fatty with dead
fucking something, whatever. Um,
I've been drinking that
Shit, man. I got taste.
Something that's delicious
that only is delicious.
You crave it after awhile and uh,
yeah,
I think I dropped like four or
five pounds. Good pounds too.
You know the flabby once I was joking
on Twitter saying how I was in,
I wasn't buttoned down shirt shape
and I actually want to get into like,
I want to be in shitting down,
no shirt on shape.
I don't know what, I don't, Bill
Cosby did a bit on this, but he's,
so what the fuck happens
when you sit down?
You stand up and look sideways in the Mary
Lake Guy. You know what? That is a bad,
dare I say, it's kind of cue shows
that I like the occasional snack.
Right? And you sit there pitching it
yourself like you're in an old school,
special k commercial going on. Right?
That's not that bad. It's not that bad.
Then you just sit down and like three
handfuls of Shit just lands on your
thighs.
You know,
for the life of me, I can't.
What is, what happens?
The hip bones move up to your fucking
man tits and everything just gets blown
out. I have no idea. But sitting down
without a shirt on, you know, that's,
that's the truth moment of your fucking
physique that you're going to see all
day.
Okay?
Stop standing up. Suck in any
gut. All right? You want to see,
you want to see the damage you've done.
Maybe not ready for it.
All right?
This is like the ring. When you
looked at that fucking chick's face,
you judges opens up and you land
in a fucking walk in closet.
Oh my God. I don't know what happened
to me. I'm not even that bad of shape.
So I said, fuck this.
I got a juicer. And um,
I just did a quick gig up in Chicago,
came right back, this private thing. Um,
so I don't know. I ate halfway decent
up there. I did find a Vegan restaurant,
but then of course they had
had some Chicago Pizza. Um,
so now I came back and I had my little
fucking grilled cheese sandwich and
tomato soup.
So now my body is starting
to pull me back to the,
the bay,
the dark side.
And that's what I've really learned
about trying to stay in shape.
It's all about keeping your
brain out in front of your body,
keeping you fucking wits about you.
Like this shit.
It's like food, you know,
when they say food is a drug,
I didn't believe him, but I,
I'm totally convinced of it now.
It's like when you're eating bad,
when you just go on like a three month
bender have just eaten bad in your head.
Like, Oh God, I got to stop
on a fucking cheeseburger.
And you just keep going and then that
makes you want cookies and all that type
of shit.
It's the food equivalent to like locking
yourself in a Roman just freebasing for
three months. That's what you
doing. So when I try to do,
when I'm eating,
eating bad like this,
I just talked to a buddy of mine outside
of the business who's trying to lose
some fucking wait.
I was trying to tell him that like you
gotta keep your head out in front of it
and just go like, I want that,
but I'm going to eat this.
Even in,
in,
in that moment when you're looking at
that apple as opposed to that fucking
glorious, whatever
you're looking at, right?
Toasted roast beef and cheese with the
fucking pickles and the chips and all
that. The last thing your
body's like, that's fine.
Just what the fuck I want.
And you got to reach for that apple.
You got to fucking hit that,
that crack pipe instead.
And I'm telling you, the second you
get to three bites in, you're like,
oh thank God, thank God I did that. And
you find, cause the, from what I've,
what I've read,
the braid little I've read use your
body is it's actually craving nutrition.
You know?
That's why we eat Chinese food.
Like fucking 35 minutes later,
you're hungry again because your
body's still craving nutrition.
There wasn't like a fucking
ounce of it in that shit.
At the risk of getting sued by that
entire fucking continent of China.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Um,
okay.
So that's what I would say
if you could try to do,
that's what I'm trying to do as I'm
trying to keep my head out in front of us.
So I got that grilled cheese sandwich
and I got to tomato soup and I said,
all right, I gotta get back on
the fucking Green Gumbo here is,
I'm calling it because I'm in
New Orleans and uh, that's it.
I'm back on that shit for the last two
tomorrow morning and wake up and make
another one. Bingo. Bango
I'm trying to do two a day.
Jewson and then one day having
the fuck in, uh, you know,
a healthy dinner.
Yeah.
And then I go on the treadmill for
a half hour. There's no fucking way.
You're not going to drop weight.
All right, so there you go.
So stop doing those stupid ass fad diets.
EA.
It's the fucking cornflakes died.
All I do is he could lay eggs.
I can eat as much as I wanted.
That bullshit veggie eventually.
Okay.
You don't really, I think the really,
it really is, is not even like,
it's not even the fucking diet. It's
the, once you get to your weight,
what do you do then? You know,
once you get down to your weight,
if some point you're going
to be looking around,
it's like you got out of jail and
there's some ice cream right over there.
You were an adult. You don't have to
go, mom, can I have some ice cream?
Right? That's how you become
a fat fuck as an adult.
There's no one to say you
had enough cookies, so on,
you got enough boobs put on a condom.
It's all on you.
You gotta be your own fucking parent
until you get a lady and your life.
Then she starts fucking nagging at you.
Take your shoes are on there.
I get off the rug up.
Fuck you lady.
Where did you become so angry?
Um,
okay,
so that would be my advice when
you're just on, if right now,
if you'll listen to this shit
and you're on a bad fucking road,
I'm telling you one of these days in
the future, you're going to wake up,
you're going to be sitting
down on the side of your bed,
you're going to glance it to a mirror and
you're going to be like, what the fuck?
What have I done to myself?
You just stand up real quick.
You can try to suck it in and try
to deny the truth that you just saw.
Hear that?
That's the steam engine coming back
on the fucking racist genocide.
One Oh one.
MMM.
The fuck am I to,
yeah.
Just make yourself eat an apple
or just eat a fucking salad.
You gotta you gotta turn that
you've got to turn the boat around.
Yeah,
that's what I'm trying to do.
Okay.
I got to do what I fucking went back up
to like almost a buck 90 and now back
down to like the mid one seventies I got,
it's the fucking worst.
Just trying to lose like 15
pounds is the fucking worst.
I can't imagine people who got a, I
got to lose more than that. So, uh,
you know,
I don't know.
I don't know how this became more
of a weight loss podcast. Um,
but I think it's working though. This guy
actually sent me a letter. He said, uh,
podcast success story,
Dear Wilbur,
you sir are a god amongst men.
Ah, Jesus. I wish that was true.
He goes, I used to be a depressed
piece of shit. You're a,
your typical, the world is
against me. Nobody likes me.
Nobody wants me fucking moron.
That's who I was.
But your advice on stepping back and make
it fun of every negative annotation I
have. Is that a word? Did he write that?
Okay.
D type that correctly or
am I am boy annotation?
I Dunno not to make you depressed
again. I don't know how to spell. Um,
he goes, I have fucking change
my life. I'm 80 pounds lighter.
I got a great girl and I've gotten
two count them two promotions.
You're a comedian.
You're not obligated to be Oprah Maury,
but you still make a
difference. Thank you, sir,
for knocking me back into cohesion. Uh,
you probably make 20 times more than me.
I doubt that sir, with the
two big promotions there. Um,
but I know,
but I owe you a drink next time I see you.
If you're in Canada or being tamps you
stay classy, sir. Thou that's great.
Good for you sir. We'll get
ahead. He turned it around
somehow. My negative, whatever
the fuck my shaming, my fat shame,
my fear shame has been working.
Um,
all right, enough about that
shit. So that's what I'm
doing. I'm drinking the, I'm,
I'm doing that fat,
sick and nearly dead juicing thing and uh,
it's like all green
stuff. It's Kale, celery,
a couple of handfuls of
parsley, cucumber, Zucchini,
and then alignment to take
the bitterness out. And uh,
I get tell you it's fucking delicious.
I love it.
And um,
I dunno,
I think I'm going to incorporate
this in every couple of months.
Just go back to that.
Well just juice for like four or five
days just so I stay out in front of it
just so I don't have to have sit down
one day and have that fucking beach ball.
I've got a thing on my button down shirts.
It's the one, two third button down.
When that button starts to look like
it's doing the iron cross between both
sides of my, of my shirt. That's an,
I'm like guy, he fucking jerk off.
All right.
And then what happens is they lay off
the beer and then I just start slamming
whiskey.
Like that's my initial when I've,
we've begun our initial
defendant until our dieting is,
I go from drinking Pale Ales to whiskey.
I really am a freckled mess.
[inaudible]
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
October 12th,
2009 and uh,
I am in a fantastic fucking mood.
Isn't that nice? Isn't that nice?
When you run into somebody on a Monday
and they're in a great mood rather than
the usual country run into it
work. Hey Jerry, how you doing?
Oh,
you know the fucking week.
No girlfriend would be a bitch yo weekend.
Can't believe Patriots lose due
to food for tube. Rudy. Rudy,
most who's worried open.
Yeah.
Shut up. You think I give a fuck
about you? I was just saying hello.
I was being friendly because we
were walking in opposite directions.
Pass each other and our eyes happened
to meet. That's all I was saying.
No one gives a fuck about
your host stupid day.
So I'm in an awesome mood and I'm going
to tell you why because I've been on the
road for six of the last seven weeks
tightening up my act the way Bill Bella
checks going to tighten up that
patriots' defense over the year and we'll
challenge for a fucking title
sometime next year,
but it's still a good thing. I haven't
packed it in yet with the Patriots. No,
I've been on the road and I was on the
road for the last 10 straight days.
Everybody, do you have any
fucking idea what that's like?
Has any of you ever gone out there?
You've ever gone out to Disney world?
What a fuck do people go for it?
10 days. Oh my God. It went to Ahca Poco.
It was awesome. We sat on the beach,
we were tanning. We didn't do
anything. We dress like who was,
who was we? Just like
absolutely. Absolutely, totally.
100% who is,
we didn't pay for a drink.
I had no pubic hair.
I barely had a bikini bottom on.
I had this island guy put corn in my
hair and I did fucking things that would
explain the cows is on my knees,
but I'm not going to because it was
in a different country and it doesn't
fucking count.
Well, what I did was look at me with
all of fucking energy. You know what?
I thought I had a meeting this
morning at 10 in the morning.
It turns out it was fucking yesterday.
So I'm clean shaven and I am dressed,
dressed to impress for this
fucking podcast. And uh, anyways,
I've been on the road for the
last 10 fucking days. And, uh,
I finally got to sleep in my own bed,
saw my girl, I saw my dog, you know,
I came home.
I watch some sports yesterday,
even though fucking Red
Sox and the Patriots lost,
you know, good for the angels, by the way.
All the people out here in California,
man, good for you guys. You know,
I know what it's like when you
can never beat a team. Granted,
I wish you still couldn't beat us,
but I know what the fucking deal is.
I watched to pay a fucking red sox loose
to the Yankees for the first 80% of my
life. Well, first 36 years of my life
could not beat the sons of bitches.
So, uh, congratulations to you. I
hope you beat the Yankees and uh,
you know, I really hope you do. But the
fucking Yankees look really good too.
They really do.
Their $200 million team has just plugging
away against that $60 million fucking
Minnesota twins. That's right. Your can't.
Some bringing it up. But you know why?
Because none of the announcers due
to share as having a hell of a bat.
Juniors aren't Firstar Jesus Christ
has taken a lead off the third base.
He better watch out.
He's still got that robot.
It's not even fucking competition anymore.
You know,
and I know the red sox are part of
the fucking problem, but Jesus Christ,
Jesus Christ, rarely, um, anyways,
let's plow ahead. Good luck. Minnesota.
You really should be up two games to one
if you didn't fucking blow it, you know,
but what do you guys care?
How, what do you guys care?
You've got the mall of America.
You can go down there and ride the
Ferris wheel right across from the stride
rite outlet. Um, so anyways, yeah,
I've been on the fucking row for the
last 10 days and I swear to God, um,
I figured it out in the last three weeks.
I have done 22 sets of an hour or more,
and I was, my final night was Saturday
night at the Improv in Pittsburgh,
which, um, is really becoming one
of my favorite cities out there.
Uh, it's just, uh, it's
just a great sports city.
It's one of the greatest views when
he calls it the Fort Pitt tunnel.
I don't know where it is. A,
you always come through the
tunnel, right? You know, he,
after you drive down the
fucking roadway there, whatever,
when a comment come onto the airport
and get on the highway, there we go.
You know,
the only thing that sucks about
Pittsburgh is they're really big on having
whatever the numbers of lanes are.
When you get on the bridge,
there's one less lane. They're really into
that bottleneck thing. Um, three lanes,
it goes down to two, four goes down to
three. That type of ship when anyways,
when he go through the tunnel,
when you come out,
you think you're just going to be
coming, you know, up underground.
Like you don't like the Holland
tunnel on the Lincoln tunnel.
When you come into New York City,
feel like a fucking rat.
You just come up and you're
right at street level. But in,
in Pittsburgh you come through like this,
uh,
I don't know if it's big enough to say
it's a mountain to fucking hill and they
dug a tunnel right through it.
And as you come out,
right as you get to the other side, the
whole city is right out in front of you.
This panoramic view of
the whole city and look,
you look to the left is Heinz field
where the Steelers play and next to it is
that a,
the ballpark where the AAA pirates play
where the Yankees and red sox actually
have trained vultures circling the
stadium. And when anybody hits a triple,
we both dive bomb in to see
who can snatch the way first.
It's a tragedy man. Major League
baseball is a fucking tragedy.
You know. What do you think the red
sox are going to do this off season?
$120 million. All we
spent last year, one 25.
You think we're not going
to get back up to a buck 80?
Like we usually do better watch out.
Oh you little fucking teams around the
league were common. We got our checkbook.
Um, it's horrible. Anyways,
plowing ahead. Um, yeah,
the whole in that they have
like all these bridges,
all this great steelwork that,
you know,
people actually live in the town if they
didn't die when they were building them
falling off the bridge cause they had to
smoke weed because they were afraid of
heights but couldn't admit
it because they're a man. Um,
all those bridges are there. And uh, this
is nothing about Pittsburgh. Very, very,
very underrated delis. Whenever
you hear about great like Pastrami,
corned beef or whatever, you always hear,
you know, go to a New York, you know,
New York Deli,
oh I'll make you a fucking hero.
But Pittsburgh,
I don't know what's going on out there
but for some reason they have kept it a,
why doesn't that guy fee
air? He go there, you know,
and take a big fucking bite out of that
shit cause I'm telling you incredible,
incredible. A Deli meat. I
went to a, came in a day early.
I went to the Pittsburgh penguins verse,
the Phoenix Coyotes,
one of the worst hockey
games I've ever been to.
They didn't fucking show up cause they
were resting cause they had the flyers
the next night, let's just
go easy. They're bankrupt,
we'll just let them win tonight.
That's basically the game I went to.
But it was fun to go to the old
thing. So, uh, I'm just babbling.
I'm babbling like a fucking fat chick who
just got an engagement rank, you know,
that's what's going on here.
That was really mean and uncalled for.
Um,
so anyways,
this is what I have to talk,
you know what I want to do this week.
I want to take some time out to talk
to you guys about what it's like to fly
from fucking Pittsburgh to Los Angeles.
Basically,
there's one show in town and
the show's name is us air.
And um,
okay.
I went in, I mean you were Sarah's,
it's a fucking rinky dink. Caroline,
who's kidding, who, you know
what I mean? Like if they,
if they were in baseball, they would
be like the pod race, you know,
no offense to, you know what I
mean? That in an offensive way.
There's no comedy clubs in San Diego.
What am I really heartening, you know?
Um, this is what I did. I show
up and I go to check in, um,
and I'm bringing my bag along and
uh, I'm checking a bag. Basically.
You know how much they want for first
checked bag. Go ahead. I'll wait.
Take a guess. What'd you
say? 15 ah, higher. 2020.
You say their a guy in the back even more.
25 bucks for the first bag checked.
Now do they bring that up?
Is that anywhere on the Internet as
you're going to make you fucking die?
I didn't. I don't know who do I know
I fucking, I call my travel agent.
All I know is they don't fucking bring
it up until you get to the airport and
then you go to give it to bag and then
they go. That'll be $25. And they got you.
They got ya.
It's a total fucking shakedown.
And that's the exact song that went
through my head cause I was thinking,
why don't you just make this
part of the ticket? You know,
it's kind of like 1995
plus shipping and handling.
So you don't see that it really costs
like 27 bucks, then you'd be 27 bucks.
That's not worth that onion chopper thing.
If there's a one in the beginning,
I'll definitely fucking buy it.
Right?
That's what they're doing
to me and I'm tired of it.
Total fucking shake down those
fucking cops and I say to lay, I go,
you gotta be kidding me. It's 25 bucks for
the first thing. She goes, yeah, I know,
I know. She goes, well, it's only 20 if,
if you go on the Internet and it's like,
yeah, and then you don't have a job.
And she goes, I know I go, so why
would you tell me that? She goes,
to be honest with you, the people above
us say, we have to tell people that.
All right. And we also have to suggest
that they use the automated machines.
And I go, that's unbelievable.
She goes, yeah, and you know what?
The people above us get a commission
for the amount of people who use the
automated machines and
we don't get anything.
Do you realize how fucked up that is?
All you fucking people who argue with
me about those automated machines.
Do you see what they're doing?
They're pitting us against each other.
People's bad financial positions.
That lady behind the counter,
she wants to keep her job,
so she literally has to teach people
how to phase her out of a fucking job,
you know?
I Dunno. The whole time
I was in, now all I hear,
I kept hearing unilad ACDC song shakedown.
Nervous shake down off of a flick
of the switch. You know how it goes.
You don't. You don't know how.
You don't know how it goes.
You guys weren't fans of that shit.
Here it is. Here it is right here.
Yeah, it's $25 for the first bag. Yeah.
He didn't tell you because we knew you
wouldn't pick this fucking airline.
That's all I heard in my head.
Then I'm on the fucking flight and this
old lady goes, oh, I'm a little chilly.
Sweet Little Old Lady. All right,
could I have a blanket in the lit?
The stewardess said,
that'll be $7
that's what they should have.
That's the song that they should
have had this second phase,
close the cabin door.
It's fucking brutal.
$7 $7 for a blanket.
Everybody on us there.
But then somebody told me that's actually
because of the swine flu because of
the swine flu. And I was
like, wait a minute now,
didn't we put smallpox in blankets
and give them to the Indians?
You know?
So maybe there is something, I don't
know. I vaguely remember reading that,
that you can wipe out a whole group
of people if they're, if they're cold,
it's very easy to do.
You just put,
you just sneeze on some blankets and
you hand it to them and then they start
dropping like flies.
And the ones that survive run a casino
ronic casino when they cry about litter.
So see, there you go, people. Okay, now it
gets worse. So I'm on this fucking plane,
right?
It's 25 bucks.
MMM.
25 bucks for the first bag.
$7 for a blanket.
The people in my row was saying that
there's a rumor that are actually going to
start charging for the bathroom, which I
think is bullshit. There's fucking way.
We're not to that point are we?
Um, and then when we go to land,
this is the greatest fucking thing
ever. I go to land, I'm like, thank God,
thank God I have made it.
I am back here in La.
I'm going to sleep my own bed and
we see my baby and we see my dog.
Everything's going to be great.
I fucking standard down there waiting
for the bag that I paid $25 for.
That should come out of the fucking
thing on its own little pillow for that
amount of money. Right? I had
to wait half hour for my bag.
Still nothing, no announcement
from anybody, nothing.
So I finally walk into the
thing and I'm like, excuse me,
do you know what's going
on here? She goes, yeah,
we kind of Sunday we kind of have like
a skeleton crew. So I make a joke.
What do you got? Like one guy on
loading the plane. She goes, yeah,
one guy for 200 bags.
You know,
I don't flip out at those people behind
the counter because I know that their
job is to basically sit there and get
yelled at by people who don't understand
that they don't make the fucking
policy. Right. So I leave, alright,
half hour in,
another 20 minutes goes by,
I'm standing there for almost
a fucking hour, no bag,
and everybody's standing
around like zombies.
Occasionally somebody would be
fucking walking in there and uh,
I finally walked in there and
I was just like, alright, um,
I know you don't have anything
to do with this policy,
but do you have a form that I can fill
out so I can ask for my $25 back please?
And lays like, um, no, there's no
form for that. I have a number here.
And I go, how many people do you
have working right now on a Sunday?
And she's like, I don't know. I don't
have access to that information.
Um,
do you do this every Sunday?
Just so I know in the future when I go
to travel that I won't fly us Aaron on a
Sunday. Do you know? Do you do this
every Sunday? Yeah. I don't know.
I don't usually work Sundays.
Do you know what's going on with the bag?
Yeah. I don't know how to contact
the people. Every fucking thing.
I asked her, she couldn't give me
a fucking answer and I was like,
do you think this is a
smart way to run a business?
I mean,
I don't have a problem.
Where can you fucking morons?
So I go just gimme gimme gimme
I'm becoming that person.
I fucking complain all the time.
Right. Um, I'm gonna, I got the thing,
I'm going to get my $25 back.
I got to figure out how to do it.
I don't think I'm going to
be able to do it via email.
I think I need to get on the phone
and then I go, I want money back.
I'm sorry sir. We don't have for
refunds. I'm sorry. I know you're sorry.
You guys are always sorry, but none of
you guys can fucking help. All right.
I can't curse. So I realized
you're sorry. I'm sorry to,
is there someone above
you that I can speak to?
Well I would like to speak to them and
just keep going up and up and up and
become such a pain in the ass.
And the key is you don't curse cause if
you don't curse they can't hang up on
you. Well my buddies had a great
fucking line the other day.
He was on one of these
1-800-NUMBERS and he was,
and he was having the same
problem. He goes, yeah, I want to,
I want a refund and I'm
sorry we don't refunds. Um,
is there anything else I
can help you with? He goes,
anything else you can help me with?
You haven't helped me with anything yet.
You're fucking Twat.
And of course she hangs up cause
he said the f and the t word. Um,
so anyways, uh, I don't even know
what I'm talking about right now.
I think the only fucking way to get back
at these corporations is you have to be
like those little old ladies
who just won't go away.
And you really just have to complain
and just say that is completely
unacceptable. I mean, what the fuck?
Kind of an airline doesn't have enough
guys to unload their fucking airplane.
You know, I love too is such
a jam packed fucking airplane.
And I know it's a tough time. I don't
know. They're probably even losing money,
but those fucking assholes at the top
are still making it just as much money,
just as much money as they were.
I guarantee it. Those fucking CEO,
CEO douchebags never take any,
they never take a fucking pay cut.
They got me standard down there
for an extra fucking hour.
Did I say I was in a good mood this week?
I actually am in a good mood,
but um,
I'm more pissed off at the fucking people
who challenged me on those automated
things and all that.
You don't even realize you're leading
yourself and the rest of us down this
fucking path and that's what
it's going to be in the future.
There's going to be nobody there and
there's going to be one robo cop.
And if the second you start complaining,
they're going to somehow connect the
dots with you and the al Qaeda and you're
going to get shot. All
right. Maybe that's,
maybe that's a little bit of an
exaggeration, but you know what I mean.
Whatever happened to the customer is
always right. Fucking old lady next to me.
She was,
she put newspaper on her legs.
I don't fucking know. What are
you going to do? All right,
let's move on with the podcast. And if
you liked that song, nervous shakedown,
which I don't know why you wouldn't,
you know, why wouldn't you like that?
Why does that sound good?
Dat,
Dat, Dat, Dat, Dat, Dat, dat
that Abu [inaudible]. Um,
all right, let's get on with the
podcast. So if you knew my podcast, um,
most times I'm in a country mood and
sometimes I say I'm in a good mood and I
still sound a little bit cunty. Um, last
week a lot of people really enjoyed, um,
when Joe Derosa was a guest hosting
cohosting who's being Joe McMahon.
And,
uh,
we got a big debate over what was
less healthy doughnuts or pancakes.
And a,
I was on the pancake side and everybody
seemed to agree with me and one person
actually sent me a little linked to show
how donuts are made after they make the
dough and all that.
Evidently they fucking deep fry them
for like seven days before they even add
the jelly in the,
in the,
in the goo and the coconut and
the crap that they put on them.
And fucking Joe to Rosa is trying to
tell me that Bisquick some eggs and some
butter and a little bit
of Syrup is, is, is,
is worse than that and know
the Syrup Mai Tai. It's, it's,
it's damn close in order to like this is
where it's like pancakes or the red sox
and donuts to the Yankees,
you know,
it's basically the difference probably
between 180 million and 200 million.
Um, oh look at that. I got an
email from the ACDC official store.
I'm 41 let's see what they have to say.
Oh they have a limited
edition ACDC tee shirt
that's actually fucking cool.
They wrote ACDC on like a Marshall amp
preorder the ACDC backtracks two CD.
Oh Wow.
They getting fucking old.
My mother used to say that they never
fucking release shit. Rereleased material.
They don't like doing it.
Okay.
The ACDC backtracks amplifier tee shirt.
What is going on?
Let me get back to the podcast and a
fucking look at this later. All right.
We've got a lot of shit to get to.
Cause last week I shot the shit with
Joe to Rosa and I didn't get a chance to
answer a lot of questions or whatever.
One of one of the people
actually had a great solution.
Remember last member a couple of
weeks ago on a on, I read that, um,
I read that story where that dead guy
was flicking the ear of the boyfriend of
a, of his sister, you know,
and they were a little drunk.
They would come from the cubs game. I'll
do a little recap here. And the, the,
the boyfriend was driving,
telling the dude to stop and he kept
fucking doing it in and then the kid just
snapped and he turned around and punched
him in the face and knocked his teeth
out. So the brother of the sister, um,
says, now I have to kick the shit
out of that kid and it has to happen.
The kids been ducking me and I
know I'm going to do what? But, um,
I just need you to help me explain
it to my sister. Wide has to happen.
So I offered a, Oh yeah, that was
last week. That was last week. See,
10 days on the road, you don't even know
when the fuck it was. It was last week.
So me and Joe de Rosa tried to give
this guy some solutions and I hope he's
still listening this weekend. He
didn't get pissed off, but, uh,
this guy has got a great ear flicked
solution. All right. He says, Bill,
I have a great way to resolve the fight
between the two friends and last week's
podcast. Two words,
flare, chop. All right.
For all your raw, raw wrestling fans
out there originated by the nature boy,
ric flair.
You simply,
you simply wind up and backhand
the person in the chest.
My cousin, brother and I use it to
resolve all arguments between us.
The reason it's effective
is it hurts like a bitch,
but only for a short period of time.
It's hilarious for all that.
Watch it and leaves the raised
imprint on the person's chest.
After you flare chop someone
all malcontent melts away.
I think that's a fucking hilarious,
hilarious idea. So all you got to do,
explain to your sister what
the flare chop is and uh,
I think that's perfect because it's
not going to be anything permanent.
I think it's going to get away. A lot
of anger is going to get out. You can,
you guys can start over again and uh,
cause who's kidding? No. You know,
I'd rather have my ear flicked
and get my tooth knocked out,
but you were kind of being a cunt,
so this is a great way to resolve
it and it's fucking hilarious.
Maybe you can turn it into a funny youtube
video and I'll probably get a lot of
hits. So, uh, my hat is off to
that wonderful fucking solution.
They should give you one
of those judge shows.
I think you really got a really
got a knack for it. The flare chop,
the nature boy ric flair. All
right, here's something else.
Somebody sent me this week and um,
I dunno,
I didn't really fit into the advice.
It didn't really fit the questions,
but I thought it was a great point.
So this is kind of an op ed piece. Um,
all right. It says, dear bill,
this past week I attended game one of
the series between the Dodgers and the
cardinals. Uh, before the game started
there was of course the national anthem.
They gather, they gathered, uh,
let me move this closer to my
eyeballs so I can read this.
They gathered probably 50 to 75 or so
sailors from the u s navy locally based
and they hurled out this huge flag.
Um,
fast forward to about the fifth inning
when they are doing the cheesy jumbo tron
spotlight. And they put the troops up
on the screen. Everyone in the stadium,
cheers and applauds.
That's when I noticed that they had
these navy guy where they had these navy
guys seated. They were seated in the
very top section in the nosebleeds.
This is just bullshit to me.
We say we love our troops and
they have the greatest citizens,
yet we can't afford to upgrade them to
at least the outfield or even the second
level fuck the MLB for using the
troops as a way to show their corporate
patriotism and then sticking them
at the very top of the stadium.
Is it really that much to
ask for an organization such
as the MLB or the Dodgers?
Who am I?
Who am whomever the decision is up to
to lose just a little bit of money.
Um, on some seats. The right field
bleachers were not even sold out.
Fucking ungrateful, Fake
Patriotic Cunts. Um,
I don't know about you guys, but I
thought he made some great points there.
I've seen that a lot of times they do.
Whenever there's a large group of people,
be it the troops or some inner
city kids, they're the, you know,
they always fucking stick them all the
way up at the top of the stadium. Uh,
you know, that's, that's capitalism
for you. You would think though,
you know what I mean? You would think
with the troops the least they could do.
Yeah. I stick them on though. Yeah.
They'd stick them on the mezzanine level.
Okay.
You know what I mean? I mean, look a
team like the Yankees, I mean those,
those seats around Tuscon and know
those things are like 1500 a whack.
There's no fucking way he
could do that. Um, so yeah,
stick them on the middle level.
I think that's decent, right?
A lot of the shit around
the, uh, around home plate,
those are season tickets.
Maybe they could do that.
They could actually have
those corporate constant,
some of those rich bastards who have
season tickets give away their tickets for
one night.
Maybe they do a nice little switch.
That'd be a great little thing as a
thank you. You know, they switched seats,
they let him sit down there and then the
corporate guys could pat themselves on
the back of what great people they are
as a fucking trudge their way up to the
top and look down on all of us the way
they've always wanted to. All right.
Okay.
Now let's move on to the next section.
This is getting really choppy.
I'm trying to think of
anything interesting happen
and he, anything interesting.
That's something me and my
girlfriend always talk about.
You remember that bugs
bunny cartoon where a,
you know the monster that actually
had arms but she couldn't see him.
He wore the chuck Taylor high tops.
He was all brown and all the hair.
And you remember that time when bugs
bunny just sat them down and started doing
his nails and doing his hair.
Going mindset is such interesting people.
It must be so interesting to be a monster.
You remember that? Um, do you now?
I didn't think so. All right. What
happened? I just lost all momentum.
I was doing so fucking well. I don't
give a shit. I'm psyched to be on.
I'm really psyched to be home.
And if you have a pit bull,
you really have to watch out for their
head because it's like a fucking bowling
ball. And when they get excited,
they swing that thing around.
It's going to catch in your chops,
it's going to hit you in the throat and a,
you're gonna have to lay on the ground
for a minute and then they're going to
come up with that paintbrush sized fucking
tongue and practically drown you with
it. So, um, if you're
thinking about getting,
getting a pit bull when you come
home after not seeing it for 10 days,
you really,
you got to kind of,
okay,
I,
I come from behind and what I do is I
make sure I have my head away from its
head. Even if you get it to the
side, it's like a fucking alligator.
Just swings it around.
MMM.
I Dunno. I think he's a maniac. All right,
let's go. Okay. Interpreting dreams. Um,
this is like a new segment that I thought
was going to be great and it never
really took off. Uh, here's a dream
that somebody has. Okay, Bill,
last night I dreamt that there,
oh,
last night I had a dream that was
so damn weird on so many levels.
Basically I was back in the early
eighties. I was born in 1990.
Okay, so he's born in 1990 for yet,
for some reason he's in the 1980s.
I mean I might need some help
on this one. Um, and there were,
they were gangs all around where
I used to live in Reno, Nevada.
It was almost exactly like that movie,
the warriors. But I had never in my life
till today seen that movie.
I didn't really think much of it till I
watched a movie this morning and I swear
to fucking God that it was so
similar to the dream I had.
It weirded me out to the point that I'm
pretty sure I just failed a biology test
today at school because all I could
think about was the damn dream.
Just the fact that I basically
dream something that had
already been created and
then I had just heard they are making
a remake is pretty fucking strange.
Any thoughts?
Okay.
Um,
yeah,
I think you've been working out and you
really want to wear a vest with no shirt
underneath it.
And a,
you just grew up in a generation where
that's unacceptable on all fucking
levels, even during Halloween. So, uh,
in your dream, you were wishing that
you were born during a time when a,
where you could,
where you could wear a fucking leather
vest without a shirt underneath it.
You know, maybe join a gang, maybe sing
some doo-wop around a burning trashcan.
I think that's what your dream meant.
It means that you don't want to
think it is. You were born in 1990.
I bet in your past life you were
actually a member of a, of a, of a gang,
you know,
as opposed to some regular kid who just
goes to college out in fucking Reno and
is bored shitless with his life. Right.
So he jerks off to porn on the Internet.
Isn't anything, any of this, you know,
I'm gonna do is I'm going to parachute
out of this fucking business.
This is what I'm going to do right
now. Okay? I'm going to fuck him.
I'm going to do one of those.
What is the, what are those,
what are those fucking chicks who look
like men who tell you a future? You know,
they get a little snow globe in front
of them where they take the dandruff out
of it and all of a sudden they can
see your future. This is what they do.
They get a little, they get a
little information about you and uh,
next thing you know, they just start
piecing some shit together. There you go.
I should put on some gypsy scarf right
now. That's right. In your past life,
you were a member of a gang and uh,
you know, you got, you got fucking
stabbed to death and uh, he had plans,
he had plans to bring
all the gangs together.
That's what the fuck you wanted to do.
And you're the guy who gets shot by
fucking Cyrus. Was that his name?
That's what it is.
You wish you were born in a different
era as opposed to now where you live this
very safe life. You want to be
a road warrior and you can't,
what's the matter?
Was there some girl you wanted to talk
to but you didn't have the balls to?
Okay.
You know, so when your dreams, you're
trying to become like this hard ass,
I guess you weren't in a drain,
you weren't in a gang and your dream,
I don't fucking know. I Dunno if send
me more dreams, I'll get better at it.
You know what? Maybe why. That's why
that segment didn't take off. All right,
let's get back to something
a little more proven.
This is like doing standup right now.
That was like a new bit.
It bombed and now I'm going to go to a
proven joke that I've told 600 times and
make it sound brand new. All
right, here we go. Advice Bill.
Uh, I recently got dumped
by my girlfriend, um,
through behaving like an idiot
to be honest in her shoes.
I would have done the same thing with
a different set I would have given.
I would have given me a second chance for
the record. No, I didn't cheat on her.
Instead, I found myself getting quite
broody. I think that means depressed,
uh, with all the heaviness
that goes with that. Um,
who knew that that can happen to men too?
I certainly didn't.
What does broody mean? What does it
mean to be brooding? Isn't that what,
what's his face did and rumble fish,
Matt Dillon.
Isn't that how we got oh, you got
all his, his uh, his acting work,
they used to always say he does the
brooding good looks. So what happened you,
you'd be in the apartment
with your girlfriend,
she'd be trying to talk to you and you'd
be leaned up against one wall, you know,
one foot on the floor, the other one
up against the wall. And she'd be like,
what do you want for breakfast? And
then you just sorta look, you know,
you look to the side.
I Dunno.
Okay.
It's just doesn't feel right.
Did you have a cigarette pack
rolled up and your t shirt?
What the fuck is broody? I don't know
what that is. Anyway, see, she goes, um,
he goes, I believe I'm
through that madness now.
And yet while I was only with
her for about three months,
I Mercer companionship terribly. I think
he means he was depressed. Anyways,
he goes, I sent her some
flowers to say I was sorry,
but she says she doesn't
want to see or talk with me,
although she says she will contact me in
the future when some of the other heavy
shit she's going through
right now is over. Um,
I feel I owe the situation one last
roll of the dice at the very least.
Do you have any suggestions? Yeah. You
guys need to not be near each other.
All right. First of all, if you want
to call you back, don't call her.
All right?
Because you're going to sound even more
brooding is just standing there crying
with a bouquet of flowers or whatever.
Whatever the fuck you going through.
And then this whole thing was,
she says she'll contact you in the
future when some heavy shit she's going
through right now is over with. You
know, I'm thinking of that movie.
Barfly you guys both like alcoholics.
What does the heavy shit,
she's got to get through the
fucking 12 pound meat hammer.
She's going to be riding tonight.
I'm not trying to be a dick, but, um,
look, well, you got to do right now, okay?
If you were out sit there Bruning
and you were all depressed,
you're probably not coming across
as someone she wants to mate with.
Who's going to bring her
some strong offspring? Okay?
To get all discovery channel on you.
So what you gotta do is you got
to show her that you're a man.
So what you gotta do is just let her go.
All right?
It start going to the fucking gym.
All right? Getting eight hours sleep.
You start eating right? You start,
you can make yourself look good.
You make improvements in your own life.
So the next time she sees you,
if you run into where you
look, great. All right?
What was that fucking Rodney danger,
danger field thing.
What was that movie without doing
the Cyrano de Bergerac Shit?
Remember that Chico Telia
and the man remember that?
That's what you gotta do next
time she sees you. You're the,
you're fucking confident.
Nah, that's bad advice.
What are you gonna pretend to
be confident? I don't know.
I'm just saying you know what, to focus
on yourself. Get your own shit together.
You know, and don't wait for her to
call you. You know? So working out,
eating right,
getting some sleep.
Go do some shit you always wanted to
fucking do, you know, and go out to the,
you know,
go out to clubs,
start talking to girls who are quote
unquote way out of your league.
See what, see what the
fuck happens, you know?
But the last thing you to do right now,
I swear to God,
is to sit around thinking about that girl
or calling her or sending her flowers
and a box of chocolates and
all that shit because you know,
she needs a break from you, I
think. And granted, once again,
I give up this advice knowing that I,
I didn't really go to college. I did,
but it doesn't really count.
And I have no background
whatsoever and I know fucking read.
So you're on your own.
If you take my advice,
I take no responsibility for
this shit whatsoever. All right.
And not to mention there's a
zillion fucking checks out there.
Why don't you go join one
of those dating services?
That's a great fucking way to get laid.
You know,
someone was talking to me
about that the other day.
You know,
there's like two of them.
One of them's about really getting into
a relationship and the other one's just
about fucking join the one that's
just about fucking and uh, go by.
Go down a Bj's wholesale and
get some condoms and bang away.
Alright.
But the last thing you want to do is
to get all fucking depressed about this
shit and waste another couple months
of your life brooding. Alright.
Dust yourself off. Get back
in the game. All right. All
right, next one. Hey Bill. Uh,
I got an interesting,
uh, situation going on.
I've been really good friends with
this guy friend. I'll do this is a,
this is a fucking great question. I
don't even know if I can answer this one.
So I'm going to need some help.
All right. Uh, hey bill. I got a,
an interesting situation going on. I had
been really good friends with this guy,
friend of mine full for like four years.
We're super tight.
Talk all the time. Say I love you
regularly finish each other's sentences.
That sort of crap.
Well,
one day I call him and found out that
he had stopped mid hookup with a girl to
answer my phone call.
When I asked why,
he said it was because I was the most
important girl in the world to him right
in front of the girl he
was getting play from.
My question to you is,
does this do dig me or is he just
a great friend and if he does,
why has any ever made a move?
Ah,
wow.
Okay.
Oh right.
There we go.
It's not an original fucking question in
a way, but it is because this is what,
two dudes now? Yeah. Jesus Christ.
How the fuck do I answer
this one? Uh, yeah, dude.
There's something fucking going on there.
The way you write about it,
it sounds like you're in a relationship.
You guys are in a relationship.
It sounds like a,
yeah.
I don't know what his deal is.
Yeah,
he's definitely curious.
I can tell you that. Uh,
I dunno, I, I've never tried to
figure out if a dude like me,
but this is really
making me uncomfortable.
That's why I like this
fucking question. Um, yeah,
I think you got to figure out
what's going on, you know? But I,
I gotta be honest with you if this will,
yeah.
I'll give you the same
advice that if you were,
if this was like a woman and she
keeps acting like that around you,
but she's hooking up with some other guy
than I'd be like, fuck her, walk away.
So I'll give you the same advice. Fucked
his duty as an, you know, if he is gay,
he's not ready to admit it yet.
And what are you going to do?
Stand around like some fucking,
uh,
some fucking guy who stands around
fuck dead. Go down to a fiddle,
sticks, whatever, whatever the fuck
they was actually a gay bar called that.
I remember there was a standup Gig in
Boston. Someone of my friends did it.
It's called, it's called
fiddlesticks. Um, yeah. Fuck that.
Yeah, go down to the bar. Do what you guys
do. Work out. Get the fucking abs going.
Put on a tight shirt. Just don't
hook up with a creepy older guy.
That's something I noticed when
it living in New York and La,
there's always like a creepy older
guy with the young, younger gay dude.
Like he's teaching them how to be gay or
something and they're like gold, Drake,
dig and gay guys out there.
Cause I,
I really don't cause guys are visual
fucking people, you know what I mean?
So I, I don't know how the fuck that
goes down and I'll tell you right now,
I don't want to, so whatever do,
I don't know what your deal is.
Confront him or fucking
move on. Cause uh, you know,
if he actually is gay and he's still out
there banging and women, uh, you know,
when I'm telling you, you, you're only
on earth for a very short period of time.
Your time is valuable.
You got to put a value on it.
Just like that guy before you.
Okay. There chick fucking took off.
Now we stand in there walking
around trying to hand her flowers.
She's still giving him the Heisman and
then that's when you gotta be like,
that's when you, you got to get some
fucking self esteem and be like, look,
I'm better than this. I'm the shit.
I'm telling you the solutions,
you always go to the gym, you listen to
some fucking music. That's how I do it.
You know, if I can get some
sleep, you start looking good,
you feel good about yourself and then
you go out and you talk to somebody who
really,
you have no business talking to and they
shoot you down and you have a couple
more drinks and you start thinking about
the person that made you want to do
that the first place and you
go back into the depression,
but you wake up the next day and you do
it over again. It's six weeks people,
six weeks.
You've got to tough it up for six
fucking weeks and you'll get out of it.
So good luck to the both of you.
All right, next question. Hey Bill,
this is a hockey question.
Um,
it's another reason why I'm site to you
back on the road is now I can finally
actually watch some hockey games
ordering the NHL package today,
much to my girlfriend's Chagrin,
um, hockey question. Hey, bill,
you seem to be a knowledgeable
person when it comes to hockey,
so I figure, uh, it
would be best to ask you,
um,
being that I live in New Orleans where
there is no hint of an or of organized
hockey and very few televised game,
I am very limited on my knowledge of the
sport even though I love it. Basically,
I basically cheer for Detroit, the
Kings, the avalanche, the devils,
and the mighty ducks.
All right?
You can tell you don't know a
lot about hockey if you chew,
if you root for both the
red wings and the avalanche,
that's like rooting for the
buckeyes and the Wolverines,
the red sox and the Yankees, the
long horns and the sooners, you know,
the troops and the al Qaeda,
the different sides. Dude,
you've got to pick a side on that one.
Anyways, let's get to his question. Now.
My question is,
what is wrong with the mighty ducks?
Why are they not considered
a respectable team?
I went to a buddy's house to watch a
hockey game this weekend and was basically
booed.
That's funny to get booed in the living
room booed into oblivion because I was
wearing a duck's jersey in parentheses
because it's the only one I own.
I was told by him as well as the seven
other people president at the reason for
hating the ducks was,
has nothing to do with the way they play,
but rather it's the fact that
the ducks are not a real team.
Is this a general feeling
amongst real hockey fans? Uh,
or am I just dealing with
some bonehead friends?
Let me know and thanks in advance.
All right. This is the deal. Um,
I don't know how old you are,
but do you remember the mighty ducks
was a movie was a Disney movie starring
Emilio Estefan says Estefan as
however the fuck you say his name.
And it was a kid movie. It was
basically the bad news bears on ice,
which is was bay. I mean the
worst fucking collection of kids.
Emilio Estevez probably had relationship
problems and he learned a lot about
himself while working with the kids.
And then for some reason there's this
unbelievable hottie who's really into the
fucking kids and see something in him
that he didn't know happened and then they
hook up and then somewhere along the line
they have a big fight and then he has
to get her back. And meanwhile
there's some big hockey game. And uh,
I imagine the coach or the other team,
Emilio Estefan is already
fucking knows on some level.
And that dude always wins in life.
And now this is his chance.
You know what I bet to coach from the
other team is dating that hot girl and
then they hook up. Is that how it
works? Is that how the movie was?
I could never watch it cause by the time
it came out I was like fucking 25 years
old. Yes, I'm that fucking old. So
anyways, yeah, the team. So the movie was,
I evidently a big hit. They made like
two or three of them. And along the way,
Disney bought a hockey team and
because of the corporate mentality,
they named it the mighty ducks.
Okay.
That's the, the history of
that team. Now, the NHL,
the history of the NHL as it used to be,
six teams and six of the angriest,
most psychotic fucking cities in
North America fighting was legal.
You smashed, sticks over
people's heads. You know,
Teddy Green had to get a plate in his
fucking head. It's a maniac fucking sport.
And then they show up like, hi,
we're the, we're the mighty doc,
lace them up.
Fuckers.
It's already difficult when you have this
many teams because they really are out
of ferocious animals to name teams after.
So now they're kind of naming them
after different kinds of weather or
generalists, you know,
like, uh, the storm,
the thunder, the
lightning, the cold front,
they don't have a fucking,
you know what I mean?
Or they categorize the predators.
I still don't know what a thrasher is.
What does a thrasher,
that's a kind of metal speed metal, right.
Anyways, so anyways, that's why people,
they don't like to ducks because,
um,
hockey is like a rogue sport and um,
it's never been accepted, accepted
by the mainstream, nor will it ever.
And uh,
then all of a sudden they came
in with the mighty ducks and a,
they really left themselves wide open.
But the thing about they
got rid of the mighty,
so now that just called the ducks and the,
the funny thing about the ducks is
the kind of hockey that they play.
They play like a really
physical in your face.
Like I love the style of hockey that they
play and I even know they just traded
fucking Chris pronger. Um, you know,
I gotta admit I'm starting to like the
Philadelphia flyers because there's
something about them that
I can relate to in my life.
And that's the fact that
in the mid seventies,
they won two Stanley cups by beating
the shit out of people. Okay.
That's not what I'm relating to.
But they had an angle that was successful.
And since then they have failed
miserably with the whole,
we're going to beat the shit out of you
to win a Stanley Cup. But God damn it,
it doesn't stay,
have not diverted from that game plan
one iota since 1974 75 they are still
trying to, even though the
league has changed completely,
they are still trying to beat the
shit out of people. And you know,
they added Chris pronger cause they think
this is why we're going to be able to
compete against the fucking capitals
and the Pittsburgh Penguins.
And what do they do? They, they,
they fucking lose six to five and
then they have a big fight at the end.
And I relate to that because I have
certain things in my life that I've been
trying to solve with the exact same
approach. And I fail every fucking time,
but I for some reason can't
get out of this Rut. So, um,
I'm getting the NHL package
today and I'm telling you,
if you want to get into hockey, watch the
penguins, flyers, games all this year,
they're there. There's not
going to be one boring one. Um,
and a lot of people don't like when I talk
about sports, but I don't give a fuck.
I gotta tell you I'm
concerned about my Bruins.
I don't know why they trade Phil Kessel.
I don't get it.
Why you would trade a young guy who's
your number one goal scorer and you trade
him for draft picks. I could see if
he was 35 and he was past his prime,
then you're like, hey, we gotta get young.
But so many draft picks, they don't,
they turn out to be nothing.
And you actually had a young guy who
was scored like 39 fucking goals and he
missed some games last year.
Man. Stupid fucking stupid.
And I like it. I don't like it.
All right, so they got to do,
that's why they don't like the ducks.
So fuck them.
Just learn a little bit more about hockey
then you won't say things like, I'm a,
I like the red wings and the
avalanche. Uh, but good for you man.
Good for you. Like in hockey down there
in New Orleans. All right, next question.
Hey Bill. Um, I'm in a
little bit of a dilemma.
I'm 35 years old and I have a
30 year old. Oh, Jesus Christ.
I'm reading the one from last year. My,
all lot of that. I scrolled down too far.
I thought I had some questions here.
Oh, there's the questions. All right,
here's some questions and I'm
going to end the podcast here. Um,
oh, wait a second. Yeah. Here we go.
Questions Bill. If your
family, siblings, parents,
and close friends are turning into
zombies, um, then you could kill them.
I mean, like totally kill them because
if they are zombies, they would,
they would technically be dead
also. In addition to that, uh,
would you have to kill you?
Would you have to kill them in a special
way because they are special to you?
Like a quick death bullet to the head
or would you just take a baseball bat to
them? Would you look forward to it? Um,
I know I'd love it if someone I didn't
like became a Zombie so I could have a
legitimate excuse for killing them
and getting away with it. Yes.
Some people I'd love to take my time with.
Okay.
That's a fucked up question.
All right.
He's basically asking me if
my all my friends and loved
ones turned into zombies,
could it, would I kill
them? Um, all right.
In the old days when zombies could just
walk slowly, I would run away from them.
And unless cornered, like in the
Michael Jackson Thriller Villi Video,
obviously yes, I would kill them rather
than sitting there getting eaten alive.
Now with today's Zombie 2.0 uh,
where they can run and that type
of shit, uh, without a doubt, yes,
I would kill them because it
isn't them anymore. And, uh,
I want to live and what I do at quickly,
I try to do it quickly,
but if I didn't have anything, if I
only had something that would go slowly,
then I would use something
that would go slowly. You know,
I don't know. You know what? I was
actually on the road and I saw that,
that Zombie movie, what does that one,
uh, Zombie land or something like that.
And I don't know. It was cause I
wasn't in a crowded movie theater.
I was a little, little, little
disappointed, but I heard
this something out there.
This, this new ghost movie called like
photosynthesis or something paranormal.
Evidently it's supposed to be the scariest
movie of the last 10 years and I'm
going to go see it. Somebody fucking
ruins it for me. Um, so at that,
that is the podcast for this week.
Please try to avoid us air if you can.
American Airlines is also another
airline that that is also $25 a bag.
And um,
I'm going to complain and I would like
to encourage all of you because they
really puts you in this position where
you feel like there's nothing you can do.
I think that a regular customers
really need to get more vocal.
This is just my opinion.
I'm not getting preachy here,
but um,
I really see no end to these greedy cons.
Just taken another bite out of your
ass until we pushed back a little bit.
So, um, next time we get fucked
over, asked for a website,
send some emails, do whatever
the fuck you can. Um,
I dunno. I Dunno what the fuck to do. I'm
really, I'm really, I don't know what,
so what,
you know what I'm doing right now,
I'm going to thank everyone who came out
to see me over the last six weeks. Okay.
From,
from Stockholm to Boston to Philly,
all the people in a Addison
who came out to see me, um,
all the people at the stress factory in
New Jersey who've been coming out to see
me for years and in Pittsburgh,
which all of a sudden, man,
I mean that's a really hard ticket
for Comedians to sell out there.
I sold out two shows and the other two
shows where all the way to like literally
the last row and um,
you know,
it's seriously, man, no jokes here.
It's, it's, it's an unbelievable feeling.
You know,
I worked 17 years to get to this point
to actually have people like my comedy,
the way you guys do and to come
out to my shows is fucking awesome.
And I got to met.
There's always a little bit of panic.
Every time I walk into a
showroom where I'm like, fuck,
is this the week where
there everybody's over me?
And it goes back to 25
fucking people, you know? So,
uh, that's it. Thank you for keeping the
dream alive for another fucking week. And,
um, and I think, I think
that's it. And, uh,
I also want to thank,
uh,
Jim and Randy at Wd v e n a Pittsburgh
for hooking me up with the unbelievable
corned beef sandwiches. And let me
run my mouth on your great radio show,
the opiate Anthony show.
Uh,
who the fuck else I got to start thinking
those radio shows because those guys
really fucking really
helped me out. And, uh, um,
and also, um, I want to thank
everybody who came out for the,
I got a buddy of mine who's, who's, um,
he's really battling a
sickness right now. And, uh,
I went up and did a benefit of giggles,
which is a great comedy club if
you live up in the Boston area. Um,
my Clark Linny Clark's brother runs it
and we did this great benefit for this
comedian Kevin Knox,
just one of the great fucking comedians.
I'll tell you a quick story.
I started this business in 1992 and when
I did it was basically at the end of
the 1980s comedy boom.
It was almost like the
housing market or the, uh,
Internet bubble in that there was a bunch
of people making way more money than
they should have been and there had
to be a correction in the market.
So basically I started in 1992 and when
I was working during the first couple
years of my career,
I worked with a lot of guys who used to
be making way more money and used to be
headlining.
Um,
sort of the guys like the
B and c level headliners.
All right.
And I gotta tell you,
there was a number of them who I will
say we're not so nice to work with.
Basically, they tried to discourage
me from being a comedian. You know,
I'm not talking about the big guns.
The big guns who were in Boston still
were drawn and they were still doing well.
But there was like,
there was some B and c level guys that I
ran into and they would say, shit like,
you know,
you'd be there on like a Thursday or a
Wednesday night gig and they'd be like,
fucking 30 people in the crowd. 40
people and they, they'd be the gold.
Look at this shit man. You know, I'll
tell you men, two fucking years ago,
three years ago, there would have been
a line around the block, you know,
I'll tell you, man, if I was
your age, I wouldn't even
get into this shit. You know,
I quit right now, man, if I was your age,
if I could do this over again and never
would had done it yet, and I sorta guy,
he's to leave there with like a
gun in my mouth, you know. But um,
you know, there was this
one comic sky, Kevin Knox,
I used to go down to his show and he was
just a fucking great guy and he would
absolutely, you know, just, just a
fucking great guy. Totally encourage you.
Positive guy. Not a, not a jealous
bone, not an envious phone.
Competitive, none of that shit.
Just a fucking great dude.
And me and all my buddies used to go
down and he put us up on his show and I'm
not only was he a great guy,
I really learned to how to follow somebody
or attempt to follow somebody because
this guy was so fucking funny.
You know when he hosted a show,
we used to joke that
he didn't host a show.
He used to take breaks from killing
cause that's what he would do.
He'd go up and he would just be
killing and they'd be like, all right,
I'm going to bring up your next act.
And then you know,
he'd bring up a fucking 23 year old me
and I'd be happy to go up there and hang
on for dear life.
And it really helped me out when I went
down to New York and I had to go on
after like, you know, I go on after a
guy who had his own TV show and you know,
the nervousness of that when you
first start out being a comedian.
Um, and I was a much
better common cause, uh,
cause he gave me the opportunity to
be on a shows and stuff. And, uh,
so anyways,
we had a big benefit form
up in Boston and giggles comedy club and
it was a huge success. And uh, you know,
he's battling some shit right now. So
my prayers are going out to them. And a,
I want to thank my Clark for
having that great benefit.
Let me come on up being a part of it.
It really,
one of the great nights in my career
was just a fucking awesome night.
It was great to see all the, and
seen a long time. So, uh, that is it.
That is it for the podcast this week.
Um, thank you everybody for listening.
Please keep sending your questions. I
am off this week. I'm not doing shit.
And, uh, what do I got next?
I got coming up, I got the uh,
Improv in DC. Um, I ain't
know the fucking dates.
You know what, why don't I get
more organized? Improv in DC.
I know, actually I know one date that
I can actually hype right now I have,
I'm playing town hall in New York City,
which is a,
a, it's a huge date for me
to play a theater date in um,
New York City.
And that's going to be on,
what the fuck is it?
November six, 2009. All right, I'm going
to be a town hall in New York City.
Tickets are going fast,
everybody. All right.
Last I checked is only a
couple hundred left and uh,
I have all the information up on bill
[inaudible] dot com B you are are um,
if you never been to New York City, it's
a great excuse to go down there. Um,
you basically you want to be watching my
next standup special live that will be
taping the next month in San Francisco.
Uh,
cause I got to set or to down. And all
that got to do is just keep doing it.
So I really appreciate it if you
come out and support me. Okay,
there's a date I'll be playing the Improv
in Washington DC. Um, October 22nd,
23rd and 24th,
mmm.
Improv and Tempe, Arizona. I got
hilarity and Cleveland coming up,
giggles in Seattle. And then that's
it. And then I take my special.
So these shows are all very
important to me. Please come on out.
I'll be selling my DVDs afterwards.
Makes a great stocking stuffer
and plus you got that person.
It's just a great gift to get somebody.
You don't have to buy mine by
another comedian's fucking DVD,
but it's a great fucking thing,
you know, for that, that,
that person on your list
way. Just like, yeah, God,
do I gotta get this fucking
person something, you know,
20 bucks, bing, Bang, boom,
you're fucking done.
Throw it at them.
Make sure the corner hits him right
in the side of the fucking head.
Mary God Damn Christmas. Um, that is
that, that's a podcast for this week.
Once again,
thanks for everybody for listening.
And I will talk to you guys again next
Monday. Have a great week. All right, bye.
Awesome.