Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday morning
podcast. And I'm just checking in on you.
All right? I can't even tell you what a
great mood I was in seven minutes ago,
seven minutes ago. Everything was
fucking fine. And then what happens?
What happens in my whole
technology fucking world?
Just it just, you know,
Internet's not working.
I got to go into the one room in my house
where the Internet works for whatever
fucking reason. Uh, you
know, it's a cloudy day.
Uh, you gotta upgrade your fucking
something or other, you know,
all I wanted to see,
you know,
I found out that Liverpool lost the cup
final and I know what all you assholes
and doing the fuck do you find
out now? You know why? You know,
I just found out now because I
have American Internet. Okay.
Do you know how many pages I have to
scroll through to find fucking soccer
highlights and meet? It's after
the Germans scat films. Okay.
That's where the fuck it is in
this country. And by the way,
I found out that most solid guy
got his shoulder yank out by some
content, the other team. And,
and good luck trying to find a
video of the actual God damn play.
I swear to God,
I want to fucking find every content out
there that is acting like they have the
video.
Do you don't,
one of the websites I went to head
it had the silence of the crowd.
That was the video. I don't know. I
see that. I want to see the injury.
Fuck.
I want to sit there and look at some
fat cunt crying over his fish and chips.
I want to see what happened.
Cause this,
the picture that I saw looked
like that guy grabbed adi,
pulled the Kelly Olynyk you
fucking grabbed onto the
thing and fucking yanked it
out.
MMM.
Anyways, uh, I mean, what, what kind
of fucking world do you live in?
Okay,
we'll you're trying to get more money
off of advertising by pulling some shit
like that.
Swear to fucking God will get
legal. We'll have fun. Edge babbled.
We'll have them walking out of the
stadium with his fucking arm in a sling.
Hey, you got you got, you got the Zapruder
film. Oh yeah, we got it. You know,
what do they do?
They show somebody fucking with it.
They hand over their mouth. They don't
show the actual fucking assassination.
God, I was in such a good fucking
mood since such a great mood.
You know, I woke up, daughter woke
me up. Who's kidding? Who Right.
Made a breakfast as I always do.
We had a great time.
We sang the Itsy bitsy spider 5,000 times.
I was in a great mood and then for
whatever reason, my stupid recorder,
the metronome got turned on. I
did not turn that off. So, uh,
rather than relaxing and trying to
figure it out, I broke my headphones.
Can you believe this? This
all all unraveled. You don't,
my wife loved me seven minutes ago.
I'm turning 50 and I'm still behaving
like this. I just broke one of my toys,
like a goddamn toddler. Do you
guys realize that? That's you?
You're listening to a child?
Maybe that's why God had me go bald
because I was acting like a baby.
He wanted me to look like
one
big old baby,
a big old bearded baby.
I should be down in Coney island.
Right.
And they should just have me one of the
cages next to the bearded lady and just
have me trying to fucking figure out
something that involves any remote basic
technology. You know, look
at that big all angry baby.
He's 50 years old,
but you wouldn't know it.
Just watching me breaking
fucking headphones and recorders.
Ah God.
And I'd love to tell you that turned
50 is this profound thing and that I'm
going to change, but I swear
to God I'm not all going to be,
I'm going to be breaking my
walkers when I'm fucking 90.
Alma said 80 and then I bumped it up
to 90 cause I just said walkers. Um,
just no fucking way, you
know, speaking of which, um,
I'm back to working out to get yet
another time attempting with the shoulder.
Cause I,
I'm impatient,
I moved to up too quickly and
weight and I reactivate my shoulder.
I don't hurt it again, I just aggravate
it. But, uh, I really do miss,
I miss working out and lifting
weights and all that shit.
Get a little pump going, you know, so
I'm doing it with very lightweight,
like put it this way. This is
how light the dumbbells are. Uh,
my dumbbells are,
are like pink baby blue.
I have one pound. It's
a girls. I have, uh,
three pounds. It's a boy.
All right. Are those no,
I don't wait. No. Two
pound, two pounds or purple.
I got the purple rain to pounders
the, it's a girl, one pounder.
And then I got the, it's
a boy, five pounder,
and then I got a six pound
color. They're orange. All right.
It's like I'm living, I'm working
out with Fisher price weights here.
Um,
anyways,
but I got that TRX band and that thanks
kind of been saving me a little bit. Um,
it's weird. I can't, like,
I can't bring weighed up to
the side and up to this side,
w like much more than three pounds
is out reaggregate my shoulder.
But for some reason I could do 50 pushups.
MMM.
I don't know why I just told you that.
Cause now every person was even
remotely a personal trainer. You know,
they're gonna start giving me advice.
You can't bring up dogs
working out or uh, I don't
know. Something else.
How to shade your beaver. I don't, I don't
fucking off. You need three examples.
I'm sorry. I choked. I ran out of out
of thinks they're anyways, do you,
have you guys been watching the
Stanley Cup final? Not Finals,
the NBA finals start tonight,
but the standing Stanley Cup final,
the first two games in Las Vegas.
And I gotta tell you something I really
wanted to hate on the intro that the
vikings,
the Vikings thought the nights the Vegas
Knights had that game of Thrones shit
that they were doing. Uh, but
I get it. I get it. It's Vegas.
They got to put on a show.
They can't have strippers out
there cause there's kids there.
It was a kid friendly Vegas show.
I thought that shit that they were
doing on the ice was amazing. But, uh,
it was kind of funny how I remember
in the NBA when guys would dunk,
Aka black guys would dunk and
then they would do make that,
that motion across the neck. Like we just
slit your throat. And they were like,
that's too violet. That
A, is that a gang side?
They can't do that Eddie by right.
And then you turn on hockey.
It's a basically a bunch of white people
there out there dressed like nights.
They're not even miming
going across the neck.
They literally have a fucking
sword right across the neck.
Does all those kids there?
You know what I mean?
Maybe because he's dressed up like a
a night or something. Maybe, you know,
I have no fucking idea. But anyways,
uh, the games have been outstanding.
Uh,
it's really hard to root against
the Vegas Knights with that story,
whatever that GM or that coach said at
the beginning of the year than being an
expansion franchise.
He said to the players,
all of you are here for the same reasons.
Whoever you were just playing with tin
think you are worthy of being protected.
Something like that. And that's like the
beginning of all those fucking movies.
What, you know, they're going to
win the championship, you know,
sneak away from the Nazis like that
Sylvester Stallone movie where they played
soccer. Right. That's what the, how
this whole thing's playing out. But,
uh, I've become a capitals
fan just because, uh,
been hanging with Josh Adam
Meyers all these years,
so I got a root for his capitals.
Plus they've been waiting since 1974.
Who gives a shit? It's been great hockey.
I loved, uh, the shootout in game one.
Um,
as far as 10 goals being scored,
I was blown away by how fast uh,
Vegas was and just how relentless
there for check was. But, um,
and I did like that the,
uh, capitol stuck up for Tj,
Yoshi and knocked that one guy in
the nights on his fucking ass, uh,
which he got off easy by the way,
compared to what the fuck you guys
have been through and to a t j Oci.
They just decided that we're just going
to fucking go after this guy. Huh?
Is that what it is? Because he's getting
facewash slash boarded crosschecked end.
He finally fucking snapped and takes
a dump penalty. What's that guy? Well,
set needs to come and beat
the fuck out of somebody.
But I loved how the capitols in the
second game played a really physical game
and they slowed them down.
And um, and Jesus Christ,
that fucking safe.
That is the save of that might've saved.
Like if the capital's win the Stanley Cup,
he got us today, right there, that, that,
that fucking saved. They go,
they go back to Washington.
I'm going to go out on a limb here and
say really obvious stuff out there.
They got a big uphill climb to escape,
although the Cavalier's foot down o two
to the Celtics and came back at one four
out of five.
Oh God am I see when the red sox lost
to the mets and 86 we won the first two.
You realize that if you win,
the first to the other team has to have
to win four out of the next five and all
you gotta do is go two and three and
you're fucking blow it. Oh, it hurts.
Um, hats off to the Vegas crowd.
I got to give it up. You know,
the NHL chose so many wrong
cities throughout the years,
you know, to try to get excitement
going. You know, Carolina,
Phoenix, Atlanta, I mean, you know, Miami,
it just, you know, and I just was,
I was of that mindset of
what the fuck are they doing?
You know, why don't you just
put one in mobile, Alabama,
nobody gives a fuck about this shit.
You're going down into basketball
and football, country stock,
car racing in moon moon
shining. Well, you know,
I mean they,
they would rather stand along the
Appalachian trail and cheer on a hiker,
then go to a fucking hockey came south
of the Mason Dixon line. That was my,
my belief and my God, am I fucking
a, I'm quoting Paul and Scott,
that's mad.
Dabbin Jip.
Um, but I, I stand corrected
because I got to tell you something.
Fucking Nashville in Las Vegas,
the level that the fans are
going crazy in the stands,
that they're going more nuts
than anybody in the original six.
Granted we understand the game more so
we don't have to fucking scream and yell
like that,
but I think the Trifecta is going to be
Seattle as much as I trashed him earlier.
Those are great fans in Seattle.
They don't need any help to be
any louder than they already are.
But I will always contest the volume of
that football stadium cause I went to a
home game there and people were just
chatting before the game and I was like,
this is really fucking loud. And
people just talking normally. Um,
anyways, it was like that
fucking Metallica album would,
they made it like louder than 10.
The one that looked like a coffin in
a pussy on the, on the, on the, uh,
the album cover you had to like halfway
up and it was still blowing your
eardrums out. Did the owner of
the Seahawks produce that one
better? Um, anyways,
uh, I don't know. I'm just think that
that's going to be this research and,
and resurgence
after some missteps and some
of these cities by the NHL. And
I don't think that it will ever
quite go mainstream though. You know?
I actually watched game one at this
cigar butt. Oh look who's here.
The lovely Nia.
What's that?
Who's that from your agent when the
one of the batteries for her little uh,
toy going to come?
Yeah,
they are like watch batteries.
She has this little creepy little purple
monkey that she absolutely loves and it
just freaks me out.
It's like this.
It's something you'd seen a horror movie
right with that high pitched voice?
Yeah.
It's fucking head spinning around.
Stays on your finger.
Can you,
can you close the door near so she doesn't
hear all my feel filthy talking here.
Oh, bringing red. Bring a
red. Oh, it's the kid hour
she's coming in.
Oh,
the itsy bitsy spider went up the water
spot of saying this thousand times
today,
Dow came the rain and
washed the spider out. Hi.
Can you say hi?
Yeah. Yeah, go. Can you
say, can you say Dada?
Say Mama. Yes. Right.
You know where your bread's buttered.
Can you say Mama?
There you go.
Can you say baby
you go,
can you say thanks?
Can you say please?
Can you say dog?
What else should she,
she could say,
Hi Dad.
Nice. Very. Hi Mama.
Yeah,
that's right.
No love for Mama.
My favorite thing,
I love that I get the mornings
are mine, but with her. Ah,
that's right. I wake, I wake,
you wake me up a change a diaper.
If we give you your Baba, right. And then
I always make a breakfast. That's right.
Jitsu breakfast. And after
every bite she has to go. Yeah.
Yeah. Um, yeah.
What did you think about what the
capital's didn't game to how they, uh,
oh my God,
it was a real showing and saw you.
They got out there and they played
that game and I was like, whoa.
Can you say whoa? Wow. Yeah.
She likes you. The bubbles, those
little bubble things. She likes,
she blow the bubbles.
She likes to run into them and
break them with their face and go,
whoa. Bubbles. Right.
You like bubbles.
Um, all right, so nia, can you,
can you break down for the white audience?
What's going on with Drake and push your
tea? I actually listened to the song,
I'm like, all right. So, you know,
he knocked up a porn star, allegedly,
allegedly,
uh,
this isn't going to end with a gun battle,
is it? No, that is not. No, that's not,
a lot of those guys are, those days
are over by that. Oh, it is. Okay.
No more gangster. You shot me in my
live or you shot me. You shot me.
Like I, that guy drives me up
the wall. No push. See had,
I can't listen to Drake
that took shots at Drake.
Drake shout back,
Pusha t shot back and Pusha t shot back
in a way that was even more devastating
than Drake's. Do you ever listen to
white music when that happens? Uh,
white music when, what happens?
Uh, answer songs, whatever,
giving each other crap,
but whatever.
Do you know what the original one was
as far as I know, the original one?
Uh, well maybe it was the
Flintstones when they had bug music.
Bug Music. I can't stand
bug music. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He said, yeah. Yeah. You
remember that episode? They will.
They were trashing the Beatles
and the Beatles never answered it.
They were above. I'm
kidding. The, uh, the first,
the first one was a Neil young made
a song called southern man. Okay,
good. Tom Petty trashing
them? No, no, no, no, no, no.
Sweet Home Alabama. Okay.
Is An answer song. Okay.
It's all in the thing. I hope Neil
young will remember southern man.
Don't need them around anyhow. Sweet home,
Alabama, you know, and they, they never,
uh, they never shout at each
other anything. Wait, why
are you being an asshole?
Because you're like, wow. Yeah. Wow.
Heatedly that's impressive.
Why are you being an a hole?
I don't know what happened. Neil
young and who saying, all right,
I'm done with you.
Leonard Skinner,
lynching and skin.
And what is it?
You're always unit. Did you
hear her? She just talked to me.
That's the way she talks to it. Like wait,
staff people going out to eat with you.
It's just like, oh my God.
Telling you. Oh my gosh,
you get so upset when I say
that. Leave. Oh, I think, uh,
yeah. Jesus. What just
happened? What happened?
I'm glad I'm not on watch
because she just heat this
backup cause this was, yeah.
Oh,
I'm going to tease you out of that.
Bye.
Why?
All right. She gets so mad at
me when I bring that up. Um,
anyways. Yeah. I actually
listened to the song,
the Pusha t song so I could be informed
about what was going on and uh, you know,
I thought he brought up
a lot of points and a,
I don't know my answer song be like,
Ya. Yeah, I banged a porn star.
We got a kid and it's
costing me a lot of buddy.
Anyways, I still got enough of my own
Lamborghini. I Dunno what, what, what,
what do you say? What do I have no
idea? What am I talking about here? Why?
Why can somebody please send me the
video of this most solid guy getting a,
this, this cheap shot here. That is what
happened, right? Because I was thinking,
how the hell do you separate
your shoulder playing soccer?
You're not allowed to use your hands.
I would think like the one thing that
never happens is you don't have any
fingers, hand, wrists, any of that type
of stuff. Injuries in soccer, right.
Although with all the diving, I'm sure
you know, if you dove a little too hard,
maybe you could break your wrist. Why
do I trust soccer? I actually really,
really starting to enjoy it. I have no
idea why. You know, why I started off?
I was in a crabby mood. I just tease
my wife about the fact that she, um,
you know,
is less than cordial to wait staff.
You know what's funny is when she goes
into a restaurant, she becomes me,
which is she has expectations of people
and when they're not met she like,
you know,
gets a fucking attitude.
I'm not saying she starts throwing plates
or anything like that, but good Lord.
Um, anyways, uh,
let me read some of the advertising
here for this this week.
This is an offer Thursday,
isn't it? Hey. Hi. Hi.
Hi. Do you have any respect for the
fact that I'm doing a podcast right now?
No.
Cause I have to ask you something.
What are you going to be
leaving after your podcast? Oh,
I take an Uber to my appointment that I
was going to come back and take my car.
Because your car is blocking my,
okay. No, I can move it if
you want right now. Yeah.
Now I don't want to be talking
about this on the podcast.
This is not interesting to people
with that. Our driveway is so small.
I have to move my car so you can move.
Okay. Well, um,
oh, it is for reads. All right. I
got to read the advertising here.
When do you need me to do that now?
Or I get taken over and just, you
know, if you're going on a later,
I'll be able to take a car later.
Okay. Do that. Do that then.
All right. I'm almost done
with the pockets. All right.
Four sigmatic Nia. Sigmadek,
that was a big Nas album, right?
No,
sorry for Sig Sigmadek.
Four sigmatic mushroom coffee for Sig.
Oh my God.
He can be tripping.
Four sigmatic comes from Finland,
the same country that gave us Santa Claus.
Angry birds to go rask
and mushroom coffee.
Uh, also, uh, what's his face? Uh, um,
from Formula One,
the hell's his name.
They're not Nico Rosberg.
The guys who's driving their,
no felt Terry Botox.
Right?
Finnish people consume more coffee
per capita than any other country,
almost three times more than Americans,
you know,
and they don't seem to be out of
their minds when I've been over there.
They seem very clearly levelheaded people.
You'd think they'd be all wired
and shit during World War Two,
when there was a shortage of coffee,
the finish boiled mushrooms that
grow on trees to make coffee.
Mushroom coffee has half the
caffeine of regular coffee,
but it's twice as magical
al magical,
easy on the gut,
less acidic,
and you don't get the jittery
feeling you get from regular coffee.
I'm already ready to drink this stuff.
I love mushrooms.
The flavor is add your thoughts on
the flavor. Well, I haven't drank it,
so I'm going to say it's like hot and
mushrooms and definitely not as shrew.
Me As the mushroom you take on spring
break or a Coachella. All right,
so you don't start tripping.
This product is ideal for adult children.
Millennials that work and
hippies that smell good, uh,
called add depth.
So genic it gives you extra energy
without more caffeine or sugar.
I'm sold perfect for creativity.
Does it help you with technology helps
you when you need to get work done?
I can't believe I broke my headphones.
Think of it as supercharged instant coffee
comes in easy to use and carry single
serving packets.
Just add water perfect for travel
and when you're on the go cost,
just a dollar 50 per cup.
Get 15% off your first
purchase with the code bur bur.
Just go to four sigmatic.com/pat
and try it yourself. F, O, u, R s,
I g, m, a t I c.com/burr
and try for yourself. Hey,
maybe if you're trying to cut down
on coffee, you can drink this stuff.
Still be creative and not
be bouncing off the walls.
A stitch fix style.
Some of us have it,
some don't,
but it's just because the census,
but just because a sense of style seems
elusive for some doesn't mean it's
impossible to attain. Oh my God,
this feels like every eighties movie.
Is somebody going to get up?
Make A.
There's no time like the
present to discover the style.
You never knew your head and
you can with a little help.
Our friends at stitch fix stitch fix has
reinvented how we find in buy clothes.
I need to buy some shirts.
Maybe I should use this.
Just answer some basic
questions about your sizes.
Favorite styles and budget right from
your laptop, smartphone or tablet,
your personal stylist then springs
into action. Hand selection,
hand selecting five brand new
clothing items just for you.
I know,
I know.
Personal styles sounds like something
only the rich and famous can afford a
personal stylist, sorry, but you can to
stitch fix style stitch stitch fixes.
Styling fee is only 20 bucks which is
applied as a credit toward anything you
keep and since your personal style is
users only your preferences to pick your
clothes, you're still in complete control.
Once your items arrived, try him on,
only pay for what you keep a don't
like something, need another side,
just send the items back,
no questions asked and shipping
is always free on both ways.
Get your fixed whenever you want or
sign up to receive scheduled shipments.
The choice is yours. I love stitch fix.
Evidently, and I know you will too.
Call to action.
Hurry to stitch fix stitch
fix.com/burr to get started now,
keep all five items in your box and
you'll get 25% off your entire purchase.
That stitch fix.com s t I t,
C H F I s.com/berbee you are our
stitch fix.com/ [inaudible] all right.
Helux everybody he licks,
there's nobody on the planet like you.
No body does it better makes
me feel sad for the rest.
So why would you buy a mattress
built for everyone else? Uh,
working with the world's
leading sleep experts,
helic sleep developed a mattress that
customize to your specific height, weight,
and sleep preferences so you can have
the best sleep of your life at an
unbeatable price. Here's how it
works. Go to helix, sleep.com.
Fill out their two minutes sleep quiz
and they'll design your custom mattress.
They can even customize each
side for you and your partner
or your wife in 2018 and like sleep as
taken customized sleep to the next level
with helix pillows.
The all new pillows are fully adjustable.
My pill is adjustable. You just punch
it a couple of times. A fluff it up.
Are you advocating pillow,
domestic violence?
The all new pillows are fully adjustable
so you can achieve perfect comfort
regardless of sleep positions
or body type. He likes sleep,
has thousands of five star reviews.
Plus you can get a 100 nights
to try them out. Go to hell,
sleep.com/bar right now and you get
$125 towards your mattress order.
That's he likes sleep.com/burr for
up to $125 a few metrics hallux
slate.com/burp oh look what's left.
The only people that boto though
though we on ds beyond ease.
Where are the fucking whores? Doo,
Doo, Doo, Doo me undies beyond ease.
Your pregame was a fucking bore you
live in in Vegas with all that crack.
You came out with some nights and
the shit was whack. I'm sorry,
I never see a wack. It just
rubbed me undies. You've,
you've definitely heard
me talk about me undies.
You've heard me sing about me undies.
No more sweaty balls.
Be undies.
Brds
if you have sweaty balls
and you fall on the ice,
you're balls will stay,
but you will leave.
Then you have your scrotum on your
fucking sleeve. You know the fun,
comfy undies that feel as good as they
look to those of you who haven't tried
them yet.
Listen Up.
You can get incredible underwear
sent to your door with me undies.
You're going to have to leave the
fucking house for anything anymore.
Meaning no more hunting around for the
perfect pair at a crowded store and
eventually settling for good enough.
Me and these are made with sustainably
sourced material from beechwood trees.
Jesus like Budweiser, Beachwood
aged, uh, they're naturally soft.
Makes a fabric that won't sag or right up.
Trust me, once you get a put a pair on,
you'll get it.
Have you seen that patriotic fucking
beer that Budweiser is making?
I mean, how much money can
you make off of it? And it's,
it's w and then they had like the
name of a veteran on the side of it,
you know, it's like, dude, I was
already going to drink your beer. Okay.
I already support the troops.
You know,
I don't support what the fuck we're
doing over there in the Middle East.
So I can tell you that, uh, w which is far
as I can tell is slowly going bankrupt.
You know, I'm all for getting
these bastards, but can we,
can we get like a fucking more
cost effective way of doing it?
Can't you just drawn it up?
Me undies is so sure you'll love your
first pair that if you're not happy,
they do whatever they can to get you
into the right pair. And if they can't,
they can't keep them in, they'll
return, they'll refund you.
Okay?
So it's really is a risk free.
Try the best underwear ever.
Do you realize what a cheap, best you
have to be to order this underwear?
I'd be like, I didn't like them. And if
you keep them and get your money back,
if you're already part of the me, Andy's
family, I'm sorry, the Mandy's Fam.
Yolo, tell your friends about it
through their referral program.
This is like Scientology of underwear.
They'll get a discount and you'll get a
store credit. Wenwen still not sure. Well,
me undies has a deal for my listeners.
First Time purchasers get 20% off
their first pair of me undies and free
shipping.
That's 20% off,
plus free shipping and a guarantee that
you and your [inaudible] will be very
happy.
Get your butt over to [inaudible] dot
com a treat yourself to get 20% off your
first pair of free shipping and
100% satisfaction guarantee.
Go to [inaudible] dot com
slash [inaudible] that's
beyond these.com/bar mmm.
Yeah, I feel like the u s government
right now with the money, you know,
considering there's no
end in sight to this war,
there's really no exit strategy or any
of that shit and how much money it's
fucking costing.
They're kind of the ever see like one of
those talk shows where the husband's at
work or something and he finds out like
his wife ran up all this credit card
debt, you know. Then of course it's a talk
show so they still side with the woman.
Ah,
you need to work longer to
pay off all of her yoga pants.
That's my doctor Phil.
Um,
right now I'm copying and
pasting that wine advice, uh,
wine town advice to my wife too,
my wife.
Um, why did I give a shit about being
rude to the wait staff? You know, why?
Cause she always trashes
me and my behavior.
I'm going to use that in the future when
you start treating the people and in
and out burger a little nicer.
Maybe I will work on my attempt,
but you know what's so weird about ft?
Ft you flip up and then you calm down
and then you just looking at your broken
headphones on the floor.
It's just that sadness, you
know, why did I do that?
Where's the other piece of plastic
that used to hold this thing in? Um,
anyways, that's 31 minutes. I
wouldn't say it was inspired,
wasn't inspiring podcasting
today. It was kind of, you know,
I kind of fed off the energy of the
weather, which is a little bit Thad.
Um, I'm going to be running my hour
around La, wherever I can get up.
I'll be doing 10 minutes spots, 20
minutes, boy, fuck, I can do it.
Getting ready next week
for Dublin in London,
England. Um, some people would ask me,
why aren't you playing
more cities over there? Uh,
it's because I'm going over there
for my birthday. That's why.
And I'm doing two quick shows and um,
and then I'm going to just,
you know, turned 50, I guess.
I don't know what the fuck I'm doing,
but I'm definitely going to
come back and um, I dunno,
maybe next year or something like that.
I want to go back and do a,
a toy like I did the last time.
Um,
except I dunno, I just, you
know, I got the kid now,
so I don't know how long
I could go over there for.
And there is just something weird leaving
the country with your wife and kid.
You know, maybe I could bring
them along. Maybe I'll do that.
Maybe that's the fucking move. Maybe
I'll, I'll, I'll, I'll do it that way. Um,
you know what, I'm getting off the phone
and I'm talking to my agent right now.
How about look at that. It just worked
that out right in front of you guys. Uh,
that's how much thought
I put into my career.
I just talked to myself while
talking to you guys and there you go.
Look at my broken headphones.
I'm sorry, headphones.
Now I'm going to have to throw you out
because you know they don't make that
plastic piece there. It's going to end
up in the fucking ocean floating around.
They didn't even have to be out there.
I kept these things so long that they
like, like the shit was flaking off,
you know, that goes up and over
your head and people always be like,
you got something on
your head. It's like, oh,
it's just the spongy shit from my old
headphones. I'm sorry, old headphones.
You know,
this is like when somebody kills their
wife like fucking 50 years into the
marriage, you know, a fit of rage.
I feel really bad right now. Are you
comparing women to inanimate objects? Uh,
yes I am. All right, that's the podcast.
I have a great weekend. [inaudible]
can somebody please send me the video?
Dee Dee got a flip phone video of most
solid get in his fucking shoulder yanked
out. I just want to see if it's
his filthy as the pictures.
All right. That's it.
Have a wonderful day.
No.
Was
God Danton God and come
back.
I turned from black and
white
was from Gaza and smash.
Oh
mmm.
Here's something that I actually read
a quote from one of these magazines.
I guess evidently a Clint
Eastwood was hyping that movie.
Gran Gran Torino. I don't know
if you guys have seen that movie.
I'm sure you see any ads for it.
Where he basically is.
I get up late a lot and you
fucking person of another race.
I'm a white man and I represented my car
represents back when America was good
in the early seventies.
Um,
I guess when he was doing the
interview for that movie, uh,
he called I guess the current generation,
the pussy generation.
And at first it made me laugh
and I'm thinking like, yeah,
Clint Eastwood obviously has earned
the right to call people pussies.
And I'm thinking, wait a
minute, Cleese was, is an actor.
Okay. Who plays tough guys
who never loses a fight?
Rarely any of it. If he does lose a
fight in a movie, it's a fake fight.
So at the risk of making
second sack religious comment,
first trash and the Great Mickey Mantle,
uh,
now I'm going to go off to Clint Eastwood.
Unlike where has Clint Eastwood,
I want it. This is my question
for you guys this week.
Where's Queenie's would god off like
where's he earned the right that he's this
tough guy? Cause like he plays
a tough guy. I've known one.
Understand that with like actors, like I
remember like after nine, 11, like, um,
for some reason they wheeled out Tom Hanks
and like that was supposed to make me
feel relaxed as an American.
And I remember during that time I was
doing a joke on stage going and talking
about Tom Hanks saying he's done so many
army movies. He thinks he's a veteran.
You know what I mean? It's not like you
did army well, but he played an astronaut.
He was in saving private Ryan.
You know what I mean?
And like all of a sudden like he
becomes like a, all these guys,
like I said, you know, here's, here's
one for you. I got fucking, you know,
friends out here.
So we're doing the touristy shit out
here in La and I take them down to Mann's
Chinese theater or grooming's,
whatever the fuck they calling it now.
And they got those,
uh,
they got the hand prints in
the feet prints and the, uh,
footprints there in the, uh, the cement.
And I found John Wayne.
I swear to God,
John Wayne had the smallest
fucking feet I've ever seen him.
I couldn't believe it. This is the
Duke John Wayne. This is the guy.
Everyone's one.
Just thought if even breathed on you,
he fucking knock you in into next week.
This guy had like,
I think he went to fucking lady
gap to buy his cowboy boots.
He's fucking the smallest fucking things.
He could have fit both his
boots and his cowboy hat.
That's how small his fucking Fida.
If you ever go to La and you
go to Mann's Chinese theater,
it's on the right hand side.
He had tiny little ass feet,
you know, actors a fucking
annoying, you know what I mean? Sit.
Then they put on fucking leather jackets
and they play these bad asses and it's
just like, dude, you're a fucking, you're
an actor. Have you had any real fights,
Clint?
Somebody of a fucking rear engine.
The drive through at Burger King
and you got out and you settled.
The score maybe has, I don't
know what, but you know,
I don't know.
I don't know fucking,
it just fucking annoyed me
and moving on from that,
somebody actually sent me an email
that kind of ties into this, right?
I'm not saying clean is in a tough guy.
The guy's fucking ridiculous.
He's 80 years old. He's still
lifting weights, you know,
the way his eyes are squinted.
He definitely seems like
a bad ass, but you know,
I want to see his fight card. I want
to see his arrest record. You know,
maybe he was a juvenile delinquent
before he came up. I Dunno.
I haven't Wiki PD them yet.
Collide.
Explain.
Hey,
what's going on?
It's bill burr and it is the
Monday morning podcast for Monday,
May 31st, 2010. How the hell are you?
Happy Memorial Day. Let's start.
Let's, let's start with that.
Let's show a little bit of respect.
Okay. What are you doing right now?
Why don't you get off the
fucking Treadmill, Huh?
Stared at attention and
give a salute to the troops.
Seriously. Big shout out. Big shout out
half. What am I a hip hop Gj over here.
Big Guy. Big hello from America
to everybody over there and uh,
Iraq, Afghanistan. Where
else do we have troops?
Germany,
right.
Still got people over there just
in case they start acting up again.
You know them. That's what you get.
Germany starting a couple of world wars,
you know, I'm glad you did
it. I'm glad you did it.
It gave us a nice rain at the top
after you lost for the second time.
And then us and Russia,
we carved it up and stared at each other
for fucking 40 years going, oh yeah,
yeah. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. And
then we just like, all right,
fuck it. Yeah. And Russia just said,
forget it. I think my mom's calling me,
I got to go, but you know, fuck you.
Anyway. All right. And then they walk
away and then we're standing there like,
Holy Shit. You mean this
is all ours? I mean,
technically it's not ours, but
there's nobody stopping us. Right.
It's like Bo Jackson when he comes around
and all of a sudden he just sees 80
yards of fucking green. Okay. You know,
Kenny Easley ain't gonna Catch Ya,
even though he's got the fucking
right angle. It ain't happening.
That's what our corporations did.
They will like,
we are going to put a fucking best buy
and every God damn corner of this fucking
planet.
And we're starting in Iraq because as
far as I can tell on my map that looks
about the middle. Everybody go at that.
Huh? Show of hands. All right then.
Oh right dead.
Let's fucking rally the troops
is the best one out of all the songs.
No disrespect to the air force.
Army and navy.
Okay
Udo show us off trip Boli.
I'm a stupid fucking man.
Red Cans.
So I don't know where triple Lee is.
What a fuck is Tripoli?
That's an a fucking awesome name.
They really picked the right fucking city,
town or country. When they said
tripling. I know it's not a country.
Go Fuck Yourself.
Are you European snobs or listen to this
shit who think you're better, right?
Cause you had, you know more about
geography and your jeans are tighter.
You think you're impressing
me? You're not. All right.
Bunch of fuck ups. Really. Amy Winehouse,
that fucking Pete Doherty Douche
bag who's never done anything.
His big claim to fame is he looks like
paste stumbling down the fucking street
and you guys can't get enough of them
and you have the fucking balls to look at
us like we're a bunch of fat fucks.
All right,
stand down Europe.
This is our day.
Ah Shit. So anyways, I was actually
supposed to go over to Japan. Right.
A little fucking sucky. Now I wouldn't
do that. I would not do that. Um,
I was going to go over there to go
entertain the troops and I don't know what
the fuck's going on with that Gig was
supposed to be a nice three base. Bang,
Bang, boom. Right. I was
going to come in in a chopper.
I was going to do it up
just like an apocalypse.
Now I have a couple of chicks coming out.
These boots are made for walking
right tassels on their titties.
America throw some place
stations out into the crowd,
play a drum solo with some fucking
chop sticks, you know, little America.
That's what I was going to do
and I don't know what happened.
All of a sudden now it's like I'm playing
a rec room on a fucking Navy reserve
base in Rhode Island.
I don't know what happened to the tour,
but I was supposed to be going over there
and I was going to go over there and I
was going to give it my all and I was
going to hang for next thing, you know,
four or five days eating Sushi,
hanging out in Tokyo. You know,
just looking at a city like what if
all of New York look like Times Square?
I want to see it go to what? Go
to a Japanese garden. You don't,
you probably don't call it
a Japanese garden. When you
go over to Japan, you know,
kind of like when you go to Philadelphia,
you don't go,
can I get a Philly cheese steak? It's
like, dude, you're in Philly. Just say,
can I get a cheese steak?
All right, everything is a
Philly here. See that yogurt?
That's Philly yogurt.
How could with 30 oh play.
I don't give a fuck what it says.
All right,
you're in Philly. So all
this food is ours. Um, yeah,
so I guess you say I
want to go see a garden.
So I go see a garden and then be
like thought tie dyed by downside,
speak English, and then I'd be an asshole
American. Like you don't speak English.
Learn the fucking language.
You know
how fucking,
how bad would that be if you just
walk down the streets of Tokyo?
Just sort of yelling out to nobody in
general and just sorta over everybody's
head English.
All right.
I think I've been ignorant
enough on this podcast.
I right now you're probably wondering,
you're probably wondering going bill
last week according to the MM podcast.com
the one and only official fan page
of the Monday morning podcast.
For those of you who like to follow
along at home with every reference that I
make when I bring up youtube videos,
you want to at your fingertips.
When I mentioned old actors,
when I Talk About Yo play yogurt,
you want to look at the carton? Oh
yeah, that is what it looks like.
It's all up on the mmp.mm.
podcast.com.
All right, actually made a little
video there. Uh, let's see.
Like Archie bunker. Hey, I made a
little bit bit a little video there.
Edith eating bad. I made
a video for the uh, um,
it's a long story. You'll see I
got, we have an exclusive video.
It's not even up on youtube or maybe it
is. I Dunno. I don't handle that shit.
I just see the red light and I just
start talking to people cause I'm a
professional just like all of those band
members on fucking Lawrence Welk. Okay.
The light comes on.
I start doing whatever it is that
I do to pay the fucking rent.
I didn't know what I'm talking about.
But anyways,
I told you guys that I was going
to be interviewing the, uh,
the wonderfully talented
Nicholas Swartzman.
Is it Schwartzen or
swore Zin or Swartzman?
I think it's Swartzman with the Real
Nicholas Swartz. And please stand up.
Um,
Minnesota,
his own nick Swardson grandma's boy.
Don't mess with the Zohan Blades of glory.
All those fucking,
all those movies that fucking every
college kid and immature 41 year old,
soon to be 42 year old like
myself. Absolutely fucking
loves. I love those movies.
Okay. First of all, I didn't
even know. I didn't even,
somehow grandma's boy went under my radar.
I don't know what I was doing,
but I miss when that movie came out and
I started watching some clips on it.
It's fucking, it's funny as hell and I'm
going to rent it this week. So anyways,
I was supposed to, um, and
that's what I was doing.
I was ready for an inside the
actor's studio, you know, I was,
I was looking at his body of work and
all that Shit, getting ready, you know,
I wanted to have a good
interview. And then, uh, you know,
when you have everything all
planned out and then just, you know,
this is what happened. Okay.
I called Nicholas and uh,
and I said, you know, are we good for
today? He goes, yeah, no problem. Uh,
gimme and whatever. We're supposed
to meet in like an hour or something.
So I'm sitting there and my fucking,
you know,
my boxers play my guitar,
right. Doing what I do.
I'm trying to learn these fucking surf,
you know, that Surf Guitar, you know,
for those of you trying to learn guitar,
you know, try to learn to play by ear.
So then you're not like,
you know,
borderline retarded in an
instrumental kind of way.
Instrumental in an instrument
kind of way. So, uh, you know,
there's simple songs down
Aaron, Aaron, Aaron are
now now and I remember her married,
it's not one fucking string.
You can figure it out. You know,
you'll learn some courts. I'm fucking
doing that shit and I'm a girl goes up.
Okay.
Oh good to take the dog out.
So she walks down the street and just
like in life when tragedy strikes,
you have no idea it's coming.
All right.
I'm sitting there trying
to learn how to play,
waiting on a friend went in in a bed,
bed and
beauty you, you know, and knowing my
neighbors, having the window open,
not giving a fuck,
right?
I'm trying to slowly kill the old man
who lives down below me on a holiday
weekend.
I might add fucking three minutes goes by.
My girl is taking the dog around
the block. What could happen, right?
All of a sudden she comes in
opposite dawn. She looks look at me
and she's like, I just got bit by a dog
freaking out, and I was like, I
couldn't even fucking, I couldn't,
I couldn't process it.
I was like,
you just walked outside to go
take the dark for walking down.
You're bleeding on your leg. What?
What's, what's going on? She had a little,
was a nip.
Fortunately she didn't need stitches,
but now my whole day is in shambles.
It's like,
what the f what did you get bit by?
Was it a coyote? Was was, it was.
It was a dog. It was a dog. Okay.
Who's dog was it? I don't know. They,
they weren't around. There was some lady
there. She helped me. I all his shit.
The next thing you know,
I go from sitting in my underwear and
trying to learn some Bill Haley and the
comets next seen on walking up the street.
I fucking don't even have socks on him
walking up on my stupid old sneakers with
my feet squishing in my old new balance.
Right. Why am why you staring at me,
Neil and I talking about,
I'm telling the story as to why Nick
Schwartzen isn't on this podcast.
Come over here. Huh? What did I do?
What? Come here. What did I say?
What? Why didn't you go? Oh God,
no, I wasn't. I was trying
to act like you crying.
That's good.
Whoo.
That's making fun of me.
I'm not making fun of you fucking
told Nick a god. The a movie star.
I couldn't do the podcast.
I have to take my girl to get her
to get her up a little booster shot.
Well, I mean, what the fuck is, you
don't realize I'm recording right now.
I'm sorry. Yes, yes. He's, why don't you
go over on your laptop and go on Youtube?
He's clearly and more movies
than I've ever been in,
so I should probably shut up. All
right. This is ladies and gentlemen,
if you ever wanted to look up back
pedaling and the dictionary. Oh, sorry.
Sorry. I'm just explaining
this. All right. I thought
you were mocking me. I wasn't.
I was mocking the situation where you
just sit there and like nothing's going on
and I'll, you know, you
walked up to fucking take the
dog out. What could happen?
Remember I was sitting in my
underwears oh my leg ripped out.
Well yeah, not that chomped it Tom. Tom,
what you did was you broke up a rape in
progress. Yes, that's right. That's right.
This dog was trying to, you know, take
advantage of my dog's neck. Say Rape.
She tried to rape her and she
wasn't having it. And you know,
dogs can't hold pepper spray because
they don't have index fingers. Thumbs.
That's right. And so they bare teeth
and they go at it and a fight and said,
I was proud of her.
She's not one of those dogs.
Just let other dogs come up and have their
way. She's a fucking dime, not a slut.
She's not a slut. She's a dominant
female. She's not taking it. Right.
Well that's what I was,
that was a story I was telling.
Well will you draw a parallel to,
and so what happens to me earlier in the
day at the farmer's market when you get
to, I know it's not about me. Oh,
in the creepy homeless guy hit on you had
an awful day. I told him, you know, I,
you know this guy came up to me
and I was at the front, I'm sorry,
I'm going to see you're really just
taking this over. And he came out,
he was like, Yo, yeah I was, I was,
I was buying bread from the
farmer's market and this
guy comes up to me and he's
right in my ear, like all breathing on
my neck really close. And he's like, Yo,
can I get some bread or something.
Like
it was so awful. And I
was like, what is that?
Some new street slang for pussy. Yo,
let me get someone at brand sugar,
1972 slang salad. It was
terrible. And so I'm like, what?
And he got a mumbled something
and I'm like, all right,
you need to step off and whatever their
needs trades getting close to me again.
And I said,
if you don't get out of my face,
I'm going to punch you in the
fucking face. I was so pissed off.
Say face twice cause it
really kills your momentum.
If you don't get out of my face,
I'm going to punch you in
your face because you're in
my face with your face and
I'm not having that with your
face. No, I think I said,
if you don't get away from me,
I'm gonna Punch on your fucking face.
That's what I said.
If you don't get away from me,
I'm gonna Punch you in your fucking face.
And he was a Ho Ho you're not that pretty.
You're not that pretty in any
walkthrough. Hang on, hang on one second.
You just sounded like you
don't get out away from me.
I'm going to punch you
in the fucking face.
Do you remember the
cop and reservoir dogs?
One of the most underrated performances
ever in the bathroom with Tim Roth.
It's in there. I said, buddy,
I am going to shoot you in the face.
You know,
put your fucking hands in that dashboard,
that classic cop speak buddy.
That's what you just sounded like. All
right, so, so you almost got raped.
The dog almost got raped.
We both bared our teeth and fought off,
you know,
these fucking advances, you know what I'm
saying? So I write, go write the script.
It's going to be a nice lifetime movie.
Okay.
Taking over the podcast,
they want to hear about me.
That's what happened to Johnny Carson.
All of a sudden he led a couple of people,
guest host. Next thing you know, you're
playing golf. Wondering what happened.
Yeah. Beat it. All right. So
anyways, so that was the story.
Somebody tried to let some
person left the gate open, uh,
up to street. And uh, this
dog came out with another dog.
One was the lookout and the
other one fucking, you know,
came running up. You know,
probably there's a little pink dog.
He Dick and you know,
tried to mount my dog. You
know, I gotta tell you,
I got to respect the dog up to street
for its belief in itself that it could
rape a pit bull.
You know,
you know, when they make those movies
about the fucking, you know, the, uh, the,
the white guy from the suburbs who's
wrongly convicted, you know, and he,
and he goes, uh, he, he goes to prison.
You know, I just realized in those movies,
when it's the black guy
who wrongly goes to prison,
who's wrongly convicted
and goes to prison,
there's never any issues about
him getting raped. You know,
it's [inaudible] he's a black
guy. He'll fucking, you know,
kick the shit out of everybody in there,
you know,
and then dunk on the fucking warden
when they have the annual fucking warden
prison, fucking whatever game. Right.
But the white guy goes to jail.
It's always worried about
getting raped. So anyways, if,
because they've made that
movie so many God damn times,
and you couldn't make it any
better than Shawshank redemption.
But Tom Selleck made that movie.
Somebody else made them.
I came up with who the
fuck else made them. We,
Tom Selleck went to jail and he fucking,
you know,
he ended up running shit
and they respected his
intelligence and all in all this
fucking stupid white guy.
Shit that they do, right.
So I'm saying if you want
to write that movie, okay,
if you want to bring that genre back,
if you're sick of seeing to a boyfriend
and a girlfriend who are actually
secretly hit, men are spies. Okay?
If you're not tired of that genre yet,
when the fuck did that start, by the way,
was it Mr and Mrs. Smith and
they've made like 52 of 'em.
Ashton Kutcher has one coming
out with some other broad,
and they're standing back
to back with guns in the,
in the titles written in
like pink lipstick. Okay,
I'm digressing here, but
anyways, this is how you,
this is how you take that
one to the next level.
This is a tip for all you
Hollywood screenwriters out there.
This is how you fucking do it. You, uh,
you have the white guy not only be
able to handle himself in the prison,
but he rapes the toughest guy
in the prison. Basically the pit bull
version of, of, of a fucking human being,
whatever, the big, the big
fucking just jacked, you know,
you ever see a dude just so big? It's
like you look at the, he, he's like a,
you know, had an aluminum baseball
bat anywhere on his body that I hit.
He wouldn't even feel it,
you know, even his head,
it would be like three times he'd be like
banging them on the head as he slowly
turned around doing that. That
cheesy Bruce Bruce Willis. Look,
you know, Bruce Willis has one. Look,
once something's going to happen,
he makes his eyes a little wide.
He makes his eyebrows tents. One of
them goes up a little high and then he,
he makes his mouth like a little
round. Oh. And he turns around.
That's what he does. That's what
he did all through pulp fiction.
He did it in die hard. And, uh,
why am I shitting on Bruce Willis?
I like his movies. What am I trying to
talk? I'm trying to explain why. Uh,
Nick Swardson's not on the
podcast right now. So yeah,
I was playing guitar and trying
to learn some fucking, you know,
whatever the firing or the names of the
bands. I'm so new to the shit. Next scene.
I'm going up the fucking street and uh,
with Nia who's still bleeding.
Okay. I did try to, you know,
clean it up a little bit, but we
also have to figure out, you know,
if she's slowly getting Raby.
So long story short,
we get in the vicinity now we have to
start knocking on fucking doors to try to
figure out,
uh,
whose dog it was and I'm opening the
gates and the gates of creek and easy to
walk into these people's house.
We live on like one of those streets.
Reveries House looks like the
monsters, you know, so we, you know,
to a much lesser degree rather than the
gates being like, you know, 10 feet high,
they like sort of waist, chest height
depending on your height, you know,
so I'm walking in there worrying that
this rape his dog is going to attack me.
So I have this fucking stick
that has a ball on the end of it.
I look like a fucking wizard that
doesn't know how to walk with the cane.
You know,
I got it upside down.
I basically looked like some blue collared
guy who was wronged and he's about to
take the law in his own hands, but I'm
not going to get fucking bit right.
I got a weapon Memorial Day,
weekend, hand to hand combat.
I grabbed the shovel out of my pack,
so I'm walking up,
I ring the doorbell and I hear Oh, and
the other side, I'm like fucking great.
Right. And then this, you know, and then
I'm waiting for the sound of the feet.
Boom, boom, boom. Come walking up on the
hardwood floors. This lady ups door. Hi,
I'm Mike. Yeah, your uh, your girl.
Your dog just attacked my girlfriend
and then she does just, you know,
ah,
oh my God,
I'm 30 I thought thought
that fucking La Shit.
We get lazy by the end of the sentence
and you can't even finish the word.
Oh my God. That's my favorite.
You're what? My favorite.
Your your favorite?
Favorite. Favorite? Yeah.
Rit. Not Raw. That's my favorite. Anyways,
so she wasn't really like that. You know
what she was, it's, it's the way fucking,
I dunno,
I can't speak for other countries,
but the way this country is right now
where everybody is just so fucking sue
happy,
she can't even express concern or
like a sorrow or apology apologetic,
whatever that fucking word is and
whatever Tencent supposed to use that she
can't express it because
she's worried about a
fucking, you know, okay.
Incriminating herself.
Like we're just going to sue
the shit out of her because of,
cause my girlfriends got bit,
you know,
and all I'm trying to do is
find out if it has rabies.
And my girlfriend told me that the dog
was either black and white or brown and
black turned out it was brown
and black that she said,
and I couldn't remember
what the fuck she said.
And I knew that she had two dogs
and now I can't say to her the
black and white one. And then
she'd be like, I don't have one.
You have the wrong dog.
You just fucking,
a unencrypted hated me and that she
slams the fucking door. So anyway,
so I had to figure it out.
They had fucking rabies. Long
story short and you know,
and then I got to call nick
and say, Hey, you know,
remember how we were going
to do that three seconds ago.
Well since then my dog almost got raped
and my girlfriend got a chunk of her leg
taken out so she's got to go get
a tetanus shot. What happened?
Long story short was I cleaned up to
fucking cut, you know, little peroxide,
little bass to tracing.
I'd fucking covered the shit up and
then it went back up the street cause I
realized I didn't even get their names
and their phone numbers and crap.
And I know that the
doctor's going to be like,
well did you get proof that
it doesn't have rabies?
So I had to do that and the
next time I went up the street,
the husband was there and he was actually
cool as hell. He said, sorry about that.
Uh,
don't worry about it.
You know, I'll pay for the trip to the
hospital and that's all I wanted to hear.
You know, not trying to get a second
Prius out of a God damn nip on,
on the inside of a knee cap. I'm not
trying to do that, but I understand.
I understand why the fuck they did it.
But that's basically the reason why, um,
the reason why that uh, I Nicholas isn't
on it and this week I'm going to try,
I'm going to actually try to hook up and
do a very special version. You might,
you might get lucky.
It's either going to be next
Monday or maybe sometime this week.
You might get lucky. I
might do an extra one. Uh,
and if I am going to do an extra one,
just keep checking in with the uh,
the m podcast.com the second I figured
out that we are going to do what I will
let,
I will let you know the powers that
be know over on that page and uh,
they will put it up and you'll
have the inside fucking scoops.
So maybe you'll get something on a
Thursday or a Friday this week. Huh?
How much you guys love in life?
It's a short work week.
Well you got to do is Olympia way
through fucking Tuesday through Friday.
You might get an extra podcasts
with sliding into June here.
Good Times, good fucking ties. But
I was really looking forward to, uh,
I was actually watching a ton.
If you get a few guys for some reason
are familiar with Nica Swartz and you
really should just youtube some
of his stuff and then go out,
buy all his comedy DVDs
because like I said,
I'm not putting anybody on this podcast
that I don't think is a, you know,
is fucking hilarious.
And I was seriously watching his stuff
just fucking dying laughing by myself.
Even like the,
the quick little videos that he
makes, he's just, he's hilarious.
And I'm written a, that's your homework
assignment this week. Rent Grandma's boy.
So you're up to speed and a or any
of the other ones that he's in,
but grandma's boy, it seems
like he has the most lines
in it. And uh, I don't know.
He's got a bunch of movies coming out.
God dammit.
I had a fucking movie star coming on
despite what my girlfriend, thanks.
And I was just me sitting here
under my goddamn ceiling fan again.
So anyways. Yeah. So what
are you guys disappointed?
It's just me again. I understand
that. I think I'm fucking thrilled.
Thought I'd get a God damn
week off somebody else talk.
Somebody else talk for a while,
do some shit jokes. Um, anyways.
Anyways, oh, I got an email this week. Um,
remember the old Douche bag of
the week award. Remember that?
I haven't given one of
those out in a while. Um,
I got this really bizarre email from
somebody the other day. He said, uh,
it said,
hey man,
I sent you an email about a year ago
and it was something to the effect of,
fuck you, you really turned
into a pussy, et cetera.
I think though that I was wrong for
saying that I will continue listening to
your podcasts and look and looking
forward to any new shit you come out with.
Um, I wasn't thrilled with your
California dog loving bullshit. I mean,
we all love dogs, but we really
don't, don't all talk about it.
You know,
this is like one of these guys.
This is what fucking annoying
me about those emails. You know,
those people where they realize they're
wrong and then they apologize to you and
it starts off as,
as an apology and then you quickly
realize that it's really just an excuse to
start reiterating the shit that fucking
pissed you off to begin with. Hey, listen,
dude, uh, you know, can I talk to you
for a second? Yeah. Listen, man, I got,
I got, I don't know, I was in, I was in
a bad mood yesterday. I was, you know,
I've been dealing with flood of stuff,
a lot of personal stuff and I
just figured, you know, I just,
I just want to say sorry. You know, I, uh,
got a little out of line
yesterday and, um, uh, you know,
it was totally my fault and nothing
to do with you, you know, uh, just,
you know, you're doing that
faggy shit that I can't stand,
you know, acting like a,
it's like, wait a minute. Wait, wait,
wait. What? This is an appalling,
just stop right there. Just say
you fucking sorry. Don't, don't,
don't bring it around again
and start shitting on me.
So the guy's like, you know,
but fuck it. Everyone's entitled to
their own opinions, speech, et Cetera.
What the fuck ever.
I was think it's cool you actually write
people back now he's being nice to me
again. And you're also out
there. I actually liked
your material. Thanks again.
You know,
and you are really annoyed me about his
fucking email is that he wrote I'm back.
That was the name of the title.
Like I'm actually like, I fucking
like, he's the only guy
who shits on me and emails.
Like I've been sitting around going,
gee, whatever happened to that guy.
I don't even remember when
this fucking happened. Why not?
Why couldn't you just fucking come back
and start a listening to the podcast?
I don't give a shit what you're doing.
Any kid,
he told me to go fuck myself
and called me a pussy, you know?
Do you know how many of those I get?
The only one I remember was with
somebody gave me shit for supporting.
So take two for taking the side of
a celebrity you use like supporting
celebrities and what the fuck did he said?
Uh,
yeah.
Fuck you. Bye. Like he
was all done with me
and I just wrote back.
All right. Take it easy.
Okay.
I don't know. It just cracks me up
that people are so like, you know,
I'm the supposed to be the guy that
thinks the world is wrapped around them,
not you. Right? I mean, I,
these people make me feel better about
myself. It's fucking guys think like,
you know, yeah. Listen, I know
you're still fucking, uh, you know,
emotionally distraught about that time.
I told you,
go fuck yourself in November of 2006.
I don't remember that.
All right. Or if you've got
to apologize, just apologize.
Just sales guys kind of being a
cunt. Sorry about that. All right.
And then, and then just
fucking start listening again.
I don't need an Elisa and you
listen to your fucking explanations.
Douche bag of the week right
there. God bless you. Welcome
back, sir. Welcome back.
Okay. And you became part of the
podcast. Is that stroke your ego?
Okay.
Hope you get run over by that fire
truck at the end of the parade today.
I never understood the firetruck.
Is that because it's always during
the day and they don't have money for
fireworks or you couldn't
really see the fireworks?
So in the end they got to have those
poor fucking firemen in their raincoats
sweating their asses off.
Huh?
Sweating off that fucking hooker funk
that half of them have on their body,
those heroes.
That's one thing I've learned about
firemen and have to talking to the cops.
Firemen love hookers.
They love him.
You know,
I'm telling you right now,
half the time you see a fucking
fire truck going down the street.
Half the time they're going to get
hookers. So what they're doing,
I think they have all those extra seats.
Why do you think they have that?
That that fucking intense
look on their face. The site,
the site,
they're going to go get their dick sucked.
You know what was the last
time you even saw fire?
Every fucking three seconds. You see a
fire truck going down the Damn Street.
There's no fire. They're getting hookers.
But everybody comes down on the cops.
Happy Memorial Day everybody. I'm
winging this one. I'm winging this one.
I thought I was going to ask somebody
else talk for the entire fucking time. Um,
you know, in my, my youtube
research, everybody,
when I was sitting there in my lab coat,
my safety goggles doing
youtube research, um, you know,
lately we've been talking about,
you know,
bad covers and people actually started
sending me some covers that were bad,
but they actually thought were good.
Like there's some Ukrainian group
that does like this sort of a,
I don't know what it is, old school,
old school like European folk,
um, version of highway to hell. So
just search Ukrainian highway to hell,
you know,
the Malcolm and Angus parts or running
an accordion and Phil Rudd's part is
basically an empty suitcase
and somebody hitting a,
an empty water bottle against it and
somehow it's actually pretty bad ass,
pretty bad ass. Those
guys, like they really,
they bring a great energy
to it and I got a mid,
I kind of enjoyed it because you
would think it would be a train wreck.
So that's your first video to
watch Ukrainian highway to hell.
And um, anyway, so I was, I was
kind of looking up that, uh,
that some of that surf
guitar stuff and uh,
they all use those fender strats and
I got one of those this year and I was
never really a fan. I always like the
Gibson sound with a Marshall amp cause I,
you know, Zeplin ACDC, like that's
what I came up on. You know,
Joe Perry always had that 59 Les Paul,
he used,
you know the deal and um,
I dunno,
I was into the beach boys for like two
seconds and then they just annoyed the
shit out of me. Um, but I dunno just
trying to learn how to play guitar.
I graduate, you know, he
listened to a little blues.
It's funny when you go back and listen
to those old blues guys like Lightening
Hopkins is concerned,
you know,
called lightening cause he was so fast
and compared to how fast guys are today,
he's not that fast.
So you kind of go back to those guys
because you can at least figure out the
rhythm.
I've just explained if anybody out there
is trying to learn how to play guitar,
I'm really trying to
learn how to play by ear.
So I'm not like one of those Douche bags
you see on youtube where somebody shows
you how to play the guitar,
but then they still want the tabs,
you know what I mean? Um, so anyways,
so then I graduated to two other
Surf Guitar and like I said,
it's a lot of the thought of
the rips are all on one string.
But what I noticed in it
was a,
I came across this group called the
shadows and they got a song called Fbi and
you just have to see the
synchronized dancing,
the choreography that
they're doing. Um, you know,
you guys can keep sending
me the bad covers.
But a whole nother level of funny is
some of the bad choreography because
nowadays when you look at the
choreography that people do, it's like a,
I mean the, the, the dancers
nowadays are so good.
They'll have 20 people on stage and you're
watching them and they're all moving.
They're doing the exact same
move at the exact same time.
And back then in the 60s,
it was basically,
as long as you were doing
the same movement within
three seconds of the person
to either side of you, it was
considered a, it's considered,
I guess, decent. So
checkout, uh, search shadows,
FBI, this is some of the worst
choreography I've seen. And a,
if you want some bad,
heavy metal,
this is a whole nother genre and I
haven't even tip even even like tapped the
surface of this.
Look up Brittany Fox and Brittany's B R
I t and why Fox girls' school live and
just watched the first 10 seconds of
this stupid and back and forth that I
thought was fucking cool
as hell. I literally saw it
and I was like, oh my God,
this is, this is, uh, I
was like, oh my God. No.
I was like, I literally said, Oh my God,
I know a fucking ditzy girls have ruined
saying, oh my God. But it used to exist,
you know,
like when you saw a Zepplin fucking
burning back to the goddamn earth with
people on fire jumping out of it.
Oh, that was all the humanity. Um,
and then the last one isn't
even synchronized dancing.
But this is the main reason
why it took me so long.
And I never really got into Dave
Matthews was that stupid dance,
that White Guy, James Brown fucking
dance that Dave Matthews used to do.
Just search Dave Matthews dance.
And it's,
it's,
you know,
you really just want John Belushi to come
back from the dead and do that animal
house scene where he
smashes the guy's guitar,
except you really want them just hit
Dave right over his fucking head.
And the only reason why I ever got
in to listening to Dave Matthews was,
uh, their drummer. And
then I really liked,
there was a saxophone solo that I just
thought was the shit on one of their
earlier, uh, earlier ones. Other
than that, I just, I don't know,
I just haven't been into them. So, and you
know, if you, you know now, right there,
that's a lot of work. That's a lot of
shit to go look up. What? You know what?
Why don't you take the
express checkout line? Okay,
the automated checkout line and just
go to the [inaudible] podcast.com we'll
have all those fucking videos
right up there. You can watch them.
We'll have them in order the highway
to hell, right to Dave Matthews,
I mean very little times in life.
Do what would I ever be on the side
of a bully? But I swear to God,
if right in the middle of his dance,
if the stereotypical high school
football player walked up to him with his
jersey,
still on with two of his other meat,
had friends and they just stuffed him
into some locker that they brought on
stage and smashed his guitar.
You could hear me laughing from the back
of the fucking stadium that they were
playing. I would completely enjoy it and
I don't know what that says about me.
Oh,
we're 34 minutes in.
I want to give a shout out to
all the joggers on the treadmill.
You only got another word.
Another fucking 13 minutes left.
13 minutes left.
All right.
How smelly is the person next to you?
You know,
are you on a treadmill right now?
You know what I love is those,
those fucking people who don't even need
to do cardio and yet they still get on
the machines and they always get on
like that. That old school stair master,
you know people who just cheat.
They have like a magazine open and
they're reading and then they look,
they're like hunched over looking like
a question mark and that just sort of
moving their feet like flat,
flat, flat, flat, flat, flat,
flat. That it, it's like,
what are you,
what are you doing now?
You're trying to burn fat off of your
ankles. Is that all you're doing?
You're not doing anything you have
full makeup on. Maybe that's just La.
Do you know what time I was at the gym?
I'm actually going to go outside the
outside the bounds of this podcast.
I actually did. I'm going to, I'm
going to soar to name a name here.
I was on a, I was on the fucking,
the elliptical, you know,
cause I want to have a hip replacement
when I'm 55, I went to dual,
the fucking Earl Campbell special.
That's what the fuck I want. Right?
Actually I don't, I don't universe.
I don't. Okay. I've learned that.
Be careful what you say
your word is your wand. Um,
so I'm at the fucking
gym. All right. And uh,
there's this girl in front of me,
this beautiful girl,
but she's got tattoos all over
herself and I'm just calling.
Why the fuck did this gorgeous girl get
all those God damn tattoos right there.
Fucking sweatpants.
They're hanging down.
They can see about a 16th of
an inch of fucking ass crack.
And I'm just going like that
girl. I swear to God, if he,
if he just erased all those tattoos.
Okay.
And you put her in a address
that that showed off,
you know, the beauty of a
woman, but it wasn't trashy.
Like this girl is like a
classy, gorgeous woman. Right.
But she didn't know. She
said, you met sweating,
fucking sweat pants hanging
off her and everything,
and then like four days later
she's in the exact same one.
I'm fucking sitting there.
I'm doing the elliptical.
There she is against sweat pants hanging
off and just so happened I was done
before and I'm walking by or
cause I got to go, you know,
get the little fucking bottle of whatever
and spray down the machine I just used.
I looked at her and it was a, Oh,
this is such a Kathy Griffin moment.
I can't, I have Jesus. I,
you know, I can't tell.
I can't fucking name names that would,
that would ruin the podcast. All right,
I can't do that.
I'll fucking annoying is
that I couldn't do it.
Kathy Griffin has already ruined
the reputation of redheads.
No one's ever going to trust
us with his secret again.
She fucking hangs out with famous people,
right? And they're all going, oh wow.
Isn't this cool?
I'm hanging out with a fucking comedian.
And then she goes on TV
and rats out everything.
Then she picked her nose and I was like,
Oh my God,
Michael Landon just picked his
fucking nose. I know he's dead.
What the fuck? Right. So what am I going
to do? I'm going to do that on my podcast.
I can't do it. All right? I gave
you enough of a description.
It was a beautiful girl with way
too many tattoos. Figure it out,
you know?
Do you know any movie stars who are
beautiful with way too many tattoos?
You don't. All right, so now we're
out here. We're out of the movies.
Wasn't a musician. It's
a TV star. Beautiful.
Too many tattoos. There you go. You figure
what? Are you laughing at? Nia? Am I
totally giving it away? No, I'm not.
I don't name names.
She just said you're ridiculous.
The amateur thrill I get because I have
no idea if I'm making people laugh.
If you actually left knee,
I know that I'm not wasting my time here.
Yeah, I see that. I just
got an awe. Um, all right.
What am I reading here?
Uh, all right. He did.
Anybody notice last week when you watch
that? That sabbath fan going crazy.
How much he sounded like he
could do a dead on Sam Kinison.
I really thought that
that guy was awesome.
Somebody actually sent me a fucking
hilarious email going like, come on bill,
you think that that cause I said that
that guy is actually probably a parent
cause he's at that age and he was like,
dude,
you really think anybody's fucking
that guy. I mean look at him. And uh,
I would say this, if there was an even
amount of men and women on this planet,
I would say that he would be in trouble.
All right?
There would be a pussy shortage in his
life that would rival what the fuck we
went through in the early seventies with
the gas, with the, with the gas crunch.
All right. There was a long
fucking way to go. Um, but no,
fortunately there's three
women to every one guy.
So as a man,
if you're dating a loser chick or
someone who's just a total country,
you really have no excuse. But women, they
actually, they haven't excuse, you know,
when they say a good man is
hard to find a there. Right.
I would think a man would be hard to
find if this fucking, you know, you know,
three who host every fucking a hang
down there paying down over there,
you know. All right, let's read this
fucking question here on, you know what?
I don't want to do that. I don't wanna do
that. I don't want to do that just yet.
Beautiful woman,
not a movie star with a lot of tattoo.
It's not a musician.
She also does not own an ice cream
store. Okay. That's it. I'm done with it.
I'm done with the hints. Um, anyways,
and I'm not going to confirm or deny him
either, but I do know the answer. Huh?
You like,
I just went political.
That's one of the greatest
quotes I've ever heard.
Some lawyer for some fucking guy or
worked in Congress or whatever the fuck it
was, came walking out and
they go, they go, is it true
that blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah. And this guy
just looked at the camera. He goes,
I can neither confirm nor deny that I
can either. Oh, I fucked it up. He goes,
I can neither confirm nor deny that,
but I do know the answer.
And he walked away. All right,
put that one in your back pocket.
Next time you're in a fucking jam.
When the cops are asking you a question,
when your girlfriend and La, you're,
oh, you're cheating on me. You know,
give her that Bruce Willis.
Look from die hard.
Just look over your shoulder and then just
do that. Alec Baldwin sort of whisper.
I can neither confirm nor deny that,
but I do know the answer.
And then just sort of look off right
over a shoulder staring at something and
don't break a gaze and just walk
right by the side of her face.
And I'll tell you, you're, you're
completely mind fucked you.
You know your mind fucked her.
Okay.
And then run down to the corner and try
when the fucking fire trucks coming down
the street grabbed the side and jump on.
Go down the street.
Get yourself a blowjob. Celebrate
Memorial Day weekend. All right,
let's get into the
questions for this week. Um,
I want to remind me to talk
about the 1958 Oldsmobile 88.
That's my new fucking car, you know,
fuck it. You know what, I'm going to,
I'm going to put some pictures up there
and some of my favorite old cars and uh,
the Malibu,
the fucking Chevy impalas,
those early 60 Chevy and pile is
the Lincoln continental error.
JFK getting his brains blown out.
That fucking Eric Carr. The uh,
I have never been a big Oldsmobile guy.
Even like the muscle cars.
For me it was either the Mustang and
there was certain years of the uh,
certain years of the um,
the Camaro that I really liked.
Like as much as I liked
the late sixties one,
I think that 19 seventy's Camaro where
they got like death fucking sharp nose on
it is the meanest looking God damn car
and has got the corvette round brake
lights, the cars, the shit and
always seem like whenever, I don't,
cause it was a little bigger.
It always just seemed like the gear heads
always figure out how to put like some
fucking 700 cubic fucking whatever
the fuck. I don't know about engines.
They put a Goddamn jet engine in the
thing. Oh, and here's another thing too.
Jay Leno,
I'm fucking obsessed with
his car collection and I'm
always going on his website.
Jay Leno's garage or whatever.
We'll have the link on the
[inaudible] podcast.com. Um,
he has a fucking look up Jay Leno.
Here's another youtube video.
Look up Jay Leno tank car,
this fucking maniac.
But uh, uh, an engine,
he took it out of a tank,
never get dentally Chrysler or
dodge made it cause it's a Hemi,
but it's like a fucking 58 cylinder and
he made a hot rod out of it and open
wheel hot rod. The fucking car was like,
I swear to God, it's like 25 feet long.
It's longer than the 58 continental
right near one of the longest production
cars of all time. I was actually
talking to my dad about old cars.
He knows all about all cars.
You know he's do that.
When we were kids all the time be driving
down the street and we see a co they
care.
I'd be like,
dad is a 1955 Buick
special at a three 50 God,
there was a beautiful car. That's
what we always ended with. God.
That was a beautiful car.
Actually met him one time watching one
of those Dudley movies where he plays a
drunk and you know,
he drives his Rolls Royce and he comes
screeching in hammered and he rear ends
another car and my dad loves cars so much.
He's literally watching it and as,
as the dude is coming in
and the screeching in the
car and it's so clear he's
going to hit a fire hydrant or
whatever with that, that $5,000 grill,
remember that 16 candles, you can have
five grand and I've got five grand, right?
He comes flying.
My Dad is literally going making
that noise, you know, liquid.
Something precious is going to break
and it fuck he rear ends the car.
Then my dad's like, no. Why
did they have to do that?
I'm just sitting there laughing going,
dad,
it's probably a fake Royal
Rolls Royce, you know? And he
just goes, yes, but I know.
But whenever the fuck that means my
dad's hilarious and he and I and I,
whatever is in his DNA about
loving cars from the 50s,
forties and, and uh, the 60s, I got that.
I don't know what happened. I tapped
into that shit. But like I said,
I've never been an Oldsmobile guy,
but there is a fucking 1958 Oldsmobile
88 that this guy really did.
That is,
um,
it's gold and just those
front four headlights.
It's amazing because the Chevys went from,
from two headlights to,
for between 57 and 58.
I always hated that.
I hated how the Bel Air looked cause it
just ended up looking like a checker cab.
I like the 55 to 57 Bel air when
it had the single headlight.
And it wasn't just the classic, you know,
for Memorial Day American car designs.
How the fuck we went to that. And
I was actually thinking, you know,
I have a kid here,
you know,
am I really going to drive down the street
going Deta fucking 1987 Chevy Lumina.
God, that was a beautiful car. I'm not
even gonna know what the fuck it was.
Ford Astro, I'm not going to know
what it was. They all look the same,
but back then they had like,
it was like,
you know what I liked
about the cars back then.
I might be wrong here because this
is a, you know, like I said, I'm not,
I'm not a fucking mechanic obviously
and shit, but like back then,
the way they had things broken
down was, you know, nowadays like,
um,
I like how can I put this like it,
like Toyota,
we'll make everything from
uh, from a, uh, like a Prius,
low end car.
Like what?
I drive all the way up to a high
end car that'll still say Toyota.
I know they have Alexis and all that, but
Toyota, we'll make like a, like a 50,000,
$60,000 car and they'll make like
an 18,000, $20,000 car. And in all,
it's all under the brand name Toyota.
Well,
back in the day as far as my
understanding of it was Catholic.
They went Cadillac, Buick,
Oldsmobile, Plymouth,
Chevrolet and Chevy's
were like bottom end cars,
you know. And then if you drove up, it
was like the status was like, what? Uh,
what make you a drive?
And I believe,
at least that's the way I kind of
understand if you drove a Chevy,
you'll kind of a young guy,
you know,
I'm making your way up the ladder and
you go back to your high school reunion.
It'd be like, what? What's he driving?
Driving a Plymouth ag fucking shitty
was driving a Chevy and high school.
The fuck, how old is he? You know, but
if you, if you got up to, you know,
Buick and Oldsmobile you're doing are
right, but if you driving a Cadillac,
he will fucking run and shit.
And I think that work the same way with
like Chrysler where when Chrysler Desoto,
Plymouth and then dodge, I dunno, I just
met when I was in, when I was sitting,
I was in a bar in, uh, Colorado. And they
had this old school poster that said,
buy your wife a Chevy, which
is funny. It's like, Hey,
buy one of those low end cars
that'll shut her the fuck up.
It probably doesn't even
mean that tissue sound.
My chauvinistically mine took dead.
Anyways, let's, let's, uh, we'll, we'll,
we'll have a picture of
like, I'll say like, uh,
like three or four of my most favorite
American cars in celebration of a
memorial day weekend and all the troops,
you know, uh, you know what I mean?
I can barely handle being in Arizona.
I don't know how the fuck I
would ever survive. You know,
if I was ever going to go to war,
I should have gone to war back in
the day when we were, uh, well,
I guess we used to fight in the tropics.
Jesus Christ. That would have been,
you know, I probably could do they
let red heads into the fucking army.
You probably, that's is that,
can I get a deferment for having no
pigment? I've never seen an albino marine,
you know what I mean? Can I get,
that's like having flat feet.
I got a bad back. I'm a redhead. Where
are you going to stick me? All right.
You want to fucking have hand to hand
combat and Greenland. I'm there baby.
I'm fucking right there of a knife for
my teeth. I'll take out a polar bear.
I swear to God I won't.
Oh cower in my little fucking Igloo.
Crying someone else's going private Burke.
Get your shit together.
I don't want to go out there.
It's scary.
Nia,
I am killing with you this week.
I'm fucking funny today. See how
women, they always got to clarify it.
Why can't you just say your fucking
funny? I'm funny today. You know what?
That's why God made you so beautiful.
Lead coming in here with your
hair looking all glamorous.
I was really mad at you too.
I saw you come walking in here like
some old school movie star. See that?
See how I do that?
I insult him and then I quickly
compliment him and then I get the uh,
what do you have in your hand?
I am so why you like me
and women like the assholes
they do, right? Cause you know,
we know what the fuck. Wow.
Anyways, AH, whatever. I'm shit talking.
It's the holidays and be rubbing my balls.
Drinking a beer in a minute. Cause I'm
an American. You think I'm going to read,
I'm not that extra day. Going to
get dumber. That's what I'm doing.
And we'll be puking in a fucking BFI.
Been behind Dennis. All right, here we go.
Here's a question for a week, a
bill. Let me start by saying this.
This question stems from events
spanning over the last six years or so.
About six years ago at the age of 20,
I was about a year and a half into what
at the time seem to be a really great
relationship.
Coincidentally,
my job and money situation
was also doing really well.
Um,
so I decided instead of throwing my
money away on rent, I'd buy a house.
There you go. This guy's making
the moves. He's doing well in life.
It's buying a house. Everything's good.
So far, being that I always plan ahead.
I purchased a rather nice
house for a first home,
even though I thought, uh, he said,
even thought I knew it,
even though I knew it was a little too
much money and now I didn't decide I
didn't buy this to start a family or
for her. I just wanted a fucking house,
uh, in the year or so after the
relationship really went downhill,
mainly because I was working more in
spending less time and money on her.
Um, okay. Uh, long story short,
we split about two years later. Since
then, I've had many encounters with girls.
Okay. So let me, let me fix this
with my awful reading. All right.
Basically, this guy's dating a
girl. He's making good money.
He doesn't want to throw his
money down the toilet paying rent.
So he goes and he buys a house and then
now he's got a nut to fucking crack.
Every month he works a little bit more.
He's not spending time with his woman
and it goes downhill. Plus he's younger.
That's pretty normal except
the fact that he owns a house.
So now he's in this situation,
he's single.
He has this really nice house and this is
what's been happening since. All right.
Since then,
I've had many encounters with girls.
The one thing they have all had in common
is their hatred and animosity towards
my ex girlfriend and my house.
I've even heard them say things about
sleeping in a bed I bought with her or how
they don't like it that I did all
this with uh, with the other girl.
I've been dating a girl for about two
years now and she's the same way. Uh,
she even has problems with my dogs
because she says they were her dogs,
meaning the ex. My question is this,
why is it never good enough? Well,
if you're a fan of this podcast,
you've already asked that question,
but I think it's timeless. So I'm going
to, that's why I'm reading this again.
Am I suppose to start my life over every
time I want to begin a new relationship
or is it that girls really always
want to have what they can.
They cannot have half the country nowadays
are just waiting for some guy to put
them up in a house and take
care of everything. But when
you give him the chance,
the they bitch because they didn't
get to pick the fucking drapes.
Oh this guy's making some good points.
Knee, I'm going to need your help here.
He said, uh, I don't, uh, I don't get it.
I've done really well for myself
and I've done it on my own.
None of that had anything to do
with who I was dating at the time.
And I hate the feeling bad
because I'm trying to make,
because I'm trying to better
myself. What's your take? All right,
Nia, what did you say on
this? US? She summed it up
really well here. What do you,
what do you think about this guy? Just
to, just to reiterate, you know, the deal.
What, what, what is,
uh, what is his problem?
I think the problem is the kind of people
that he dates cause I don't think that
there mature enough.
So like let go of the past,
you know what I mean? It's like, of
course he stayed at other women of course.
You know what I mean? It's not,
yeah, but let me ask you this. If,
if when I met you already had a house,
right. And uh, it was, you know,
it had a little bit of the female touch
to it, you know what I mean? Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's not like you walked in and there was
just a coffee table and like fucking a
play station, you know, popcorn in
the cushions or whatever. Right.
I'm not saying this house looks like
that, but you know. Right. Yeah. No.
If it looked like, and I still had the
bed that I used to bang the other one.
I mean I'll say at least she can do,
dude, you can leave, switch out the bed.
You know what I mean? Bad though.
I thought. I think that's a little,
I think that's a little much, honestly.
What did the little much to still have it.
Yeah. He's going to buy it.
And you know how much better,
cause you don't have him buy a whole new
bed just cause he's slept with somebody
else and it ladies, can you see why
this is my girl? You're the shit. Yeah,
because I mean how many,
when you're dating somebody and you
have sex with them in their house,
chances are they've had sex with somebody
else in their bed before you anyway.
So now all of a sudden it's
like a big deal because no, he,
he needs to date some more mature girls.
But he's been dating someone for two
years. I don't know what he's been doing.
I thought you said he, I just
focus on saying the words, right.
Yeah. He says, you know what?
You know what this, this
house could be like the lock,
the lock, the door test in a Bronx
tale. Oh yeah, that's true. Yeah.
Like if they can't deal with it
and they start giving me shit,
you give him the heave Ho.
Exactly.
I think they should get the
heave Ho this is my house.
This is where I fuck you want in.
Not Quite.
So absolutely. But if
anything, he could, you know,
get some new sheets or something. You
know what? Oh obviously, yeah, bed,
bath and beyond. I'm thinking about some
new sheets. You want to help me pick out?
Some girl would love that. Love
it. Yeah. There you go. Yeah,
there you go. Yeah. And at what point
in the relationship should he do that?
You know, cause we don't like being tied
down. I want to send the wrong message.
I don't want to say that I love you,
but I want you to still bang me.
Like at what point?
I think when it's like official date,
like monogamous type thing is when
you can say, Hey, let's, you know.
Okay. All right. Really? You answered
the question, don't oversell it.
You answered it. It gets really annoying
that these girls would be like, my God,
I can't believe that you know,
this is already decorated and these are
her dogs and her house and I can tell
that there.
That's stupid.
That's really hard to say how la
girls say favorite athletic fabric.
That's going to be the podcast
for this week. So I guess,
so that's your answer right there on,
you know,
I'm not going to always defer those to
Nia, but I just think sometimes you're,
you're really asking me what
women are thinking and I,
I think I've done enough trashing
of women and, uh, shut up.
Um, I've done enough trash
enough. Um, and you know,
that's actually a serious
question here because still you,
you don't want to get to
that in a situation where,
I mean, you have to, I mean,
literally sell the house. What if it's a
bad fucking market just to appease her?
That's ridiculous. But, uh, I, I
would, I, you know something, yeah,
I would actually say that if they were
actually going to be getting married,
you know, if, if he take
it to that level and, uh,
there'll be a weird thing because when
you do get married and you want to pick
out a house, it's the house that for
both of you that you want to live in.
And you know, this houses out there
that I just don't get like that though.
You know that gingerbread looking
house sits up to fucking street.
Like you know if I met the girl of my
dreams and she lived in that house and
every day driving, Ugh, I
hate this fucking house.
You know all those ones that
look like the, the castles,
that employee but they're, they're just
the house so it looks stupid. You know,
Rapunzel let down your hair or
just sorta hop out that window.
No, I I do. I know, I respect
that but I'm saying I,
this is what I was saying like you know,
come on in and live here. I get that.
But then you know,
I'm sure he didn't buy a house
that's big enough to have like a,
like a big family. I don't
know if he does. I'm not know.
I'm just trying to kind of balance it out.
Allow what the fuck am I trying to do?
Nia,
are you going to be designated driver
because I'm going to get hammered today.
Why? I was designated
driver last time, last time,
last time.
Last time,
like fucking three weeks ago when we
were in Boston and you guys all got Hamad
is they say, oh yeah, but we're going
to somebody. We don't know these people.
We can't go get hammered.
I can, I'm going to,
you know what my mission is?
I'm going to make you look good today.
I'm gonna you're gonna people
are gonna feel bad for you.
We'll figure it out. Come on then I
send you those songs than I make up.
You know when I get drunk.
Yeah. Be Fun. No, we,
I'll be asleep halfway,
halfway through
with my mouth open,
looking like the asshole next to you
on a fucking transcontinental flight.
All right. That's it. Happy
Memorial Day to everybody. Sorry.
The Knicks Swartz and
things didn't work out.
I'm going to try to sneak in
an extra podcast this week. Um,
I'm going to figure this shit out. Okay.
I promised you a movie star. God dammit.
I'm going to bring you one and uh, that's
it. A Happy Memorial Day to everybody.
Have a nice safe,
happy holiday.
Get to where the fuck you going to be
at and just start Busan. All right.
Okay. Don't be that ass, so I'm fine.
I'm fine. You're not fine. All right.
Two Sec. You, you have grass
stains on your face. Okay.
You're not fine.
Have you been drinking today?
A couple Saad hanging off your
fucking left ear. All right,
everybody, that's it. Have a great
weekend and a happy holiday and,
uh, that's it. God bless the troops. Okay.
No, it was come direct
charge.
Charged
Yeah.