Hey, what's going on is bill burn.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday,
Monday morning podcast.
And I am just checking in on you.
Okay.
No bells,
no whistles on it this week.
I'm just checking in on you so you know
everything's going hope and you having a
nice week. I'm having a lovely
week. Um, been doing a bunch of,
a bunch of, uh, what do you call it?
Their promotion for F is for family that
comes out next Tuesday at midnight on
Netflix season to
10 episodes of the
Murphy family on Netflix.
Um, please tune in if you enjoy it.
Please continue to watch all 10.
If you enjoy all 10, please tell
your friends and have them watch it.
So then we could do a season three,
three, three. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. We'll see what happens. I um,
I know it's been such
a whirlwind of press.
What the fuck did I do
yesterday or two nights ago?
Okay.
How was that something? I wear
a sport coat. I do know that
I have absolutely no recollection
where I was two nights ago. Last night,
we went over to Netflix, this new
building they're taking over the world,
the new building and
Oh, I know what I did. I know what I did
there was for Emmy consideration,
they had it, they had the thing there.
And you sat there on a pen panel and
it was a Judd Apatow Chelsea handler.
Uh, the woman who created friends,
I gotta tell you right now,
if I created friends,
I would never come out of the house again.
I'd have so much goddamn money.
I would just be sitting in there
with the biggest drum kit ever.
And I'd have a fucking helicopter.
I don't know why, but yeah,
I'd be all fucking weird. I'd be like
growing my nail and I cutting my nails.
You know,
I beat Howard fucking huge
and it was me. And then the guy
from, uh, the Santa Clarita Diet,
that was pretty cool. You got to
sit there and every, I tell us
Zillow,
when you're creating your show,
what is it that you do when
you're creating the show?
MMM.
Okay.
Does any of this stuff in the show,
is it based on you?
Is it made up or is it something
else that we don't know altogether?
And he answered all the questions and uh,
you hope you get out of it unscathed,
which I think I did.
Sorry.
So what's funny was I actually wore
a sport coat and then Mike Price,
uh, cocreative efforts of family, the
Great Mike Price from the Simpson.
So I could not do f is
for family without him.
He was dressed casual to last
night when we went to the,
the new Netflix building. They're
taking over the world. Um,
yeah.
I said, I am not going to, I'd
said in Django, you know what,
I'm just going to wear a fucking button
down, blah blah. And as I pull in,
Mike Price has a jacket on. I got you.
What fucking jacket? No, I'm the bum.
So we were laughing about that and
everybody else had on a jacket.
So I just look like the, uh, the fucking
artist showing up. Like, hey man,
I just like roll out of bed
man. And Yeah. You know,
when everyone feel and I
just putting on me and um,
but we sat through two episodes,
the first two episodes.
It was a friendly though,
you know,
everybody pretty much in the crowd was
on the show and they will laugh and
having a good time. So I
hope you guys enjoy it. Um,
I was on rich Ising yesterday.
I don't know if he can go to some
rich i's and.net and watch it.
I had a great time, so thank
you to him. And uh, then I did,
Bill Simmons had a great time on that one.
Um,
and I got coming up next week.
I know I'm doing Craig Ferguson,
who's the greatest special I've
ever seen of doing his and uh,
there's something else. Somebody
look at my phone, I should,
I'm trying to promote these things
mmm.
Before I, uh, doing that
would probably be good. Right.
Rather than telling you after I did them.
I mean, that would make sense. Bill,
the whole thing about promotion is
let people know something's coming.
Not that it came and went.
Okay.
Oh, I know. I could actually,
I have a Gig for the California
Highway Patrol Booboo, but the two,
but that at the dead.
Oh yeah, I'm going to be on my best
behavior. You cannot know enough cops.
There's some great life advice.
You have no idea when you're going
to snap, you just walk into a bank,
you're going to make a
deposit. You just think, hey,
what if I just pulled my shirt up over
my head and passed them a note? You know,
you have no idea when for some
stupid fucking reason you do that.
And then unfortunate, hopefully when the
cop shows up, he's like, get out of crap.
I'll wait a bill. What are you
doing? Huh? All right. No. All right,
well I'll take care of this. Everything's
fine. There was no gun or a day.
It takes you outside. So what the fuck
you gotta get Outta here? Get outta here.
His son of a bitch,
you like dead.
And that right there is
called white privilege.
I don't know who's not white
or listens to that. You know,
he times I've gone in and robbed
the bank and it's, you know,
I've never been successful,
but I've never gone to jail for it.
It's because I am a white male, you know,
and I might get in trouble for this.
I might lose some of my privileges
if I let non. Why do you smell that?
I've actually on six,
maybe seven if you want to get technical.
First Time it was, I made a joke, but on
six, six and a half different occasions,
I made an attempt to rob a bank.
I was caught but knew the cop when they
will come in. Five out of six of those,
another time the guy was like, oh, you
look just like me and he let me go.
Those are all true stories. Um,
then you can add those to the,
to the non fake news in your life.
Um,
I flew a fucking helicopter this morning,
but getting back into it,
I'm up over 120 hours a,
my auto rotations are looking okay.
Last week they were fucking horrific.
Put the collective down,
fucking followed it. And I didn't go
aft cyclic and it was like, oh my God,
am I going to die?
Yeah,
getting good on the radio again.
I got this great fucking APP.
If you want to listen, if anybody else
there is into aviation of something,
I just,
you know,
cause you don't want to sound
like a fucking moron when
you're making your calls,
which uh, you know, I do on a regular
basis, there's an app called live a t c.
Dot net.
It's really cool.
And you just click and you can
listen to whatever airport you want.
I was listening, you know, when
my flight's taking off, you know,
I don't care about what does it,
magnetic deviation or whatever the
fuck it is from my cell phone or was it
magnetic something or there
retardation. I can't, I don't remember.
All I know is I'm going back and I'm
going through all my ground school again,
trying to remember all the Shit I'm
reading about fucking weather and uh,
I'm having a great time,
get myself back to where my skill level
was right before my lovely daughter was
born. And, um, I don't
know. I'm totally into it,
but the only thing I don't like about
those Robinson's is that the mass bumping
in the low Gi pushovers and uh,
someone was telling me today that they
had to have a fully articulated rotor
system. We didn't have to fucking deal
with that. And for those of you don't fly,
a mass bumping is basically
when the blades attack the mast
and break off the helicopter.
If they don't get bent and then slam into
the cockpit and cut your fucking legs
off or you right in half,
you know, that could happen.
So that happened on those bell helicopters
I guess that they had in Vietnam.
And, uh, you can't, you know, when
they would fly low to the ground,
they'd go up the hill and you know,
cause they was trying to stay at the tree
line so they wouldn't get shot at they
way up in the air and they would just
fly and they'd go up the hill and then
when they would dive down the backside,
that's the thing.
When you push forward
with the stick like that,
you're not supposed to do that in
a semi articulated rotor system.
What happens to the,
see if I can remember.
Basically what happens is the
main rotor is still spinning,
but it's no longer producing
lift with the helicopter. Right?
You've sort of been this low.
Gee thanks. So what happens is,
is if it goes counterclockwise,
you main rotor, your,
your rear tail rotor is going to
be on back behind you on the left.
And so you're,
it's still going to be compensating for
the torque that the main rotor is no
longer producing.
So it's going to push you over and
you're going to roll over to the right.
And what's fucked up is as
you roll over to the right,
the way to get out of
it is counterintuitive.
You would think that you would
move the stick left. You don't,
you move it slightly back after you go
aft to reload the main rotor to get back
underneath it. So when she's
fucking watching the ground
coming up on the right,
like I don't want to go there,
you will move the stick.
Like you want to do a backward
somersault rather than roll back up.
It's completely fucked up.
You got one chance to do it.
If you pull back too fast,
I think he chopped the tail off. So
there's that, which is why I don't fly.
If there's any sort of wind,
I don't fly.
But you know there's a
danger with anything that
you do if you're not risking,
are you really living?
Um,
I have to get on Instagram and I have
to become some sort of motivational
comedian. That's what I want to do. I
want to start giving you guys nausea,
eating fucking life lessons,
you know,
is I'm believing a gym
or a fucking juice bar.
What is with all these
fucking cops on the,
on Instagram acting like they're
trying to inspire you. It's you're not,
you tried to show me what
great shape you're it
Hashtag doing this one for you guys.
The fuck out of here.
Um, Instagram, horse, male
and female. All right,
so the Celtics, they won a
game. Holy Shit. Holy Shit.
So we have game five tonight,
which every Celtic fan knows that we
are basically eight quarters away.
If we can survive the next eight quarters,
we are eight.
No actually not eight quarters.
The next 11 quarters we are 11 quarters
away from Kelly Olynyk taking over this
fucking series and
getting us to the finals.
I know I say a Thomas' out.
I know they got fucking Lebron
Kevin Love.
They got all these mother
fuckers. I understand. Okay.
Do you know what Boston has?
We got hot,
so we always have never have
explosive speed. We have a strick,
no explosive newness with
all our draft players.
If he's got a quick first step and can
dunk where lag now pass that guy on.
Where can this guy do look like?
He's going to trip over his
own feet and he's white.
Gimme that guy you always happened.
And then we got the the like the,
the bruise and black dudes, but we just
never have those above the rim guys.
We just don't have explosive guys.
You know Isaiah has been, you know,
he's like five foot eight. So all
I'm saying, okay, but you know,
Crowder, he's going to get a say, you
know something. The younger kids though,
Brown Bradley, those guys, I love how
Bradley keeps trying to dunk on the Bronx.
He keeps missing the fucking rim.
No, that wouldn't, I liked that guy.
So anyways,
I don't know what I'm talking about.
All I know is the remaining Celtics,
just all you gotta do is get us to
the fourth quarter end game seven.
All right? And then the garden's
going to come alive. Kelly Kelly,
Kelly,
and he's going to hit a fucking zone
and I don't know what's going to happen.
He's going to be so in the zone.
He's not even gonna need a
headband anymore to keep his,
his locks out of his face and he's
just going to find, I don't know,
he's to start draining threes and that's
going to be all she wrote for the land.
Okay. Anybody want to put money on
it? I'll put money on it right now.
If we can somehow survive the next 11
quarters. Kelly, that was not a book.
Everybody thinks it's a fluke.
I'm telling you that man has ice water
in his faints Arctic fucking polar bear
swimming around in his fucking veins.
Microscopic ones.
I'm telling you the
thing is he's just bored.
He doesn't give a fuck about game five
one through four or even game six or even
the first fucking half. Actually
no, he had a good game game seven.
We just have to get to game seven and
the man that I've always been confused as
to why he was on the team.
I once again got hit with a
cold bucket of reality of bill.
You're just a stand up comic. You
don't know shit about sports led Danny.
Ange make the calls and
if Danny Ainge says,
Kelly Olynyk is the fucking man that
I am standard down you way Cleveland.
I know you're fucking nervous.
You are.
You are so scared that we are somehow
going to win game five and gave six
without Isaiah Thomas or Kelly Olynyk
gets dunked on and people go right around
up. You fucking wait man. We
get to game seven. It's over.
That man shows up to play.
All right. I'm an idiot. Anyways.
Carely carely um, let's uh,
let's move on to the, uh,
the predators. Holy Shit. Hey, anybody
in Montreal, the Montreal Canadian fans.
Did you notice that the guy that you
traded for, cause he was too flashy.
You know, you didn't like
his personality. PK Subaru,
it was really your front
office on this one,
but I'm going to play blame the fan base
yet another former Canadian leading a
team to the finals, leading a team
to the final level is my front door.
By the way, if you wonder what that beep
was, I didn't read the refrigerator open.
I'm so hoping that the predators
when the cup, because um, the Bruins,
we'll never catch the Montreal community
Canadians and the amount of Stanley
cups they have.
So all I can do is tease them about the
guys that they got rid of that then went
on to win cups elsewhere. Is
it petty? Oh, I think it's,
I think it's very petty. Who Do you
like tonight? Games. Seven Games.
Seven penguins. Penguins. Where's
the fucking, Otto was senators.
Where is that game? It was an an
Ottawa. If you're in Pittsburgh,
you want to go to the game,
you can probably just walk up to the
gate and buy a ticket. Kenosis this,
it's a transient city. You know, it's
a capitol. People don't give a shit.
They're from other places.
They're Calgary fans that live there.
Edmonton blue jackets.
They don't give a fuck.
They're not going to the Goddamn game.
Uh, what do you guys think? I actually,
for some fucked up reason,
I think,
I think auto was going
to win only because, um,
I dunno, the penguins have had a
little bit of gold tender issue there.
That's the only reason.
But that's all right.
I'm guessing the 10 seconds
that I paid attention.
Why do I talk about sports right now?
I'm too fucking busy running around
doing podcasts. Um, you know what?
I was so busy last week. I forgot
to read the, uh, the question.
So let me read this. Here's another person
giving me shit about bills. Fake News,
Delta Rant,
Billy fake fucking news.
I was listening to your podcasts from
last Monday as I was sitting on a Delta
flight heading to Los Angeles from Austin,
Texas was at,
pardon until that fucking story and one
of your readers brought up the Delta
Airlines incident where a
dad was threatened to get
kicked off and jailed if he
didn't stop complaining and fall in line.
As I was listening to your useless
fucking rant, still a huge fan.
I noticed how uninformed both you and
your reader, we're on the situation.
All right. Time out here. First of all,
if you guys are going to come at me
with uninformed and fake news, I,
you new to the podcast.
I don't really,
I just commented on for fucking series.
I've probably watched three minutes in.
My job is to make you laugh.
It's not to get facts.
What the fuck you think
you listen in to hear, sir?
I could have easily Google that and
figured out what I was talking about.
Don't come at me like use
some sorta Rhodes scholar.
Like I'm impressed that you're going
from Los Angeles to Austin, Texas.
Are you going to keep it weird name
when you get to Austin, Texas. Austin,
Texas is one of the most
overrated overpopulated
fucking cities and this goddamn
country. You know why cause La
concert like you keep moving there.
Who actually if you teach you
research you'd realize it.
I'm not from La [inaudible] from Austin.
He lets me tell you something buddy.
I don't give a fuck where you from.
The mere fact that you're dumb enough to
try to get fucking accurate information
from this podcast and you
think that I'm uninformed.
I used to do a radio show
called uninformed with with
better call Saul's star
breakout star Joe de Rosa,
the teen idol sensation sensation
from the now defunct
opie and Anthony Program.
That's what really broke up ob,
Anthony and Jimmy. It was the,
the sheer star power of Joe de
Rosa coming in once every 16 weeks.
They just all had to go their separate
ways because when they came back into the
studio, when they looked at one another,
all they can be reminded of was, was the,
the force of Joe to Rose's talent.
All right.
Do you want to look that one up there
and go on when your flight from La to
Austin? He said as I was listening
and Blah Blah Blah Blah. Um,
okay. I know. Okay. First
the seat that, that,
that the dad was bitching about being
sold to another passenger was actually his
18 year old son's seat. All
right, now where did you get this?
At delta.com cause they're not,
I don't trust these guys either.
I don't trust you either. How do I
know you're not fucking Eddie Delta,
son of a Ulysses Delta who
fucking started the airline, um,
who we put on an earlier flight by buying
a separate ticket instead of notifying
delta that he was changing his son
flight to an earlier flight. Doing this.
He thought he could magically have an
open seat to him for his who is under two
but that wasn't the case. Jesus, this
guy's spreading the seam and outer.
He's got an 18 year old and a toddler.
You go buddy, keep banging away.
You see when you decide to put your son,
I don't fucking go.
You see like you're fucking
talking down to me. You dumb cunt.
All you did was researching my
job, sir, is to make people laugh.
That's it. I, my job is not the fucking,
I don't have fucking time to figure
shit out. What am I still in school?
I got in this business to not have a job.
How am I going to sit here and
research your guy's fucking emails?
I don't care what your right to me,
unless it sounds totally ridiculous.
I'm going to treat him as long.
I've also flown a lot and I've noticed
that they don't give a fuck about you.
I remember one time I was on a flight
and they had the inner calm on,
so God damn loud. You needed like
earplugs and I said to the stores, I go,
is there any way you can turn that down
a little bit? And she just goes, no,
I'm sorry sir.
There's nothing we can do about it.
It's like you're telling me that they
installed an intercom system without a
volume knob and it was at full blast.
That's what you're telling me there.
Why are you being difficult?
I'm not being difficult.
All right with you fucking crooked toes.
All right.
You see when you decided to put your son
on an earlier flight by buying another
ticket while not telling Delta,
they assume that the,
the 18 year old son did not make it on
his original flight because he didn't
check in and they weren't notified that
the dad bought a completely separate
ticket. So they gave the seat away to a
standby passenger per standard protocol.
Also,
FAA regulation disallows a child under
two to sit in the standard seat without
the proper child seat and harness. So
there's another thing that dad got wrong.
You can't have a child
with a different name.
Sit in a seat that he sold to your 18
year old son. All right, fair enough.
Imagine all the,
the issues this would calls cause if we,
what if we allowed for anyone to use his,
any ticket that was issued
in someone else's name.
His mistake was that he didn't check in
and notify Delta and should have paid
the change fate to send his son on an
earlier flight with the same ticket and
then buy another ticket for his toddler
if he had the proper safety hardest for
the toddler. Uh, tickets are not
transferable to another passenger.
I'm not defending the flight attendant
who I thought said some things that were
inappropriate by threatening jail,
et cetera.
That's really what I was
commenting on, buddy. All right.
That they're sitting there acting like
he did something in the Pentagon. Um,
however the dad was completely wrong to
think he can somehow put his oldest son
on an earlier flight home and then
use as original ticket. What this guy,
he's got an 18 year old and a two year.
He's too busy fucking without a
condom to research all of this.
How about having a little empathy for him,
sir,
on your Los Angeles to Austin
flight fucking jackass.
What is the oldest sons? Um, which
is okay. Put it as okay. However,
the dad was completely wrong
to think he could sum up,
put his oldest son on an earlier flight
home and then use his original ticket,
which is in his oldest son's name.
How many times are you going to say the
same thing on the two year old toddler?
So he and she, because he or she could
sit in that seat of Delta Nuwella
just wanted to clear up your fake news
rant. You misinformed cons. Oh God.
Everything's fake news is
it's, it wasn't fake news, sir.
It was just me trying to make you fucking
laugh. Okay. That's all it was. Okay.
I'm glad you researched
and cleared all of that up.
Okay.
At the end of the day,
at the end of the day,
I'm just here to make you laugh. Okay.
So please people for the love of God.
All right. And stop acting like, you
know, I can't do what you just did.
Okay.
Girls stabs boyfriend and avoid jail
time because it was damaged her career.
Now what am I supposed to do here,
sir?
Am I really supposed to
fucking sit here and research?
This is if someone's going to go to jail
with the jokes that I do or should I
just take it at last so I can
get on with my fucking life?
Here's the deal. Why don't you got, why
don't you be the fucking the fact police.
All right, I'll do the rent the
next week. You can correct me.
That was my uninformed short. They
would gel to Rosa. We just pick a topic.
We'd go off on it, we'd be completely
wrong and then we'd bring an expert in.
That was literally the shell.
People would learn things and
there was laughs to be had.
All right girls stabs boyfriend and avoid
jail time because it would damage her
career. Hey there, Billy beats.
I'm sure a million people tweeted and
email you this article. Actually. No,
they didn't. Well, maybe they did. I don't
know. This girl stabbed her boyfriend,
but the judge agreed that any sentencing
would damage her future career in
medicine. Jesus Christ. Go Fuck Yourself.
All right, let me, let me read this here.
Go to the page. Oh, here we
go. Click here. Oh, this.
This is UK news. God knows this
probably happened in America.
I find the UK people love
to fucking did you see this?
That happened in your country. You
guys are all fat and stupid. All right,
here we go. Wow. Jesus.
Wow. I see what happens.
She's got this little
angel smirk on her face.
Aspiring surgeon Levina
Woodward admits attack,
but judge to first sentencing because
of her extraordinary talent. What?
He blew her back in his fucking chambers
and Oxford University studious
who's wider than my fucking legs.
Stabbed her boyfriend with a bread
knife. Okay. It's a bread knife.
May Not go to jail because it could
damage your prospects of a medical career.
Accord has heard,
well what sort of training and maybe she
could've stabbed them and sewed him up
real quick.
Aspiring hat surgeon.
Okay.
Levenia would-would 24 punched and stabbed
her boyfriend during an alcohol drug
fueled row at Christ church college.
This is an on the
guardian.com is this credible?
She so she's on drugs and she's drunk and
she punched and stabbed her boyfriend.
She admitted unlawfully wounding.
The Cambridge University who
she met on the dating app.
Tinder. All right, well not to blame
the victim, but what did he do?
You can do that with men.
What did he do? Judge Ian.
They're always named Ian over there.
Ian Pringle.
Nigel or Ian QC.
I'm sitting at Oxford Crown Court.
I was,
this is like the school court.
Is that what it is that she go to trial
at the fucking skull that's taking her
money?
I don't know.
Said he would take an exceptional course
and to first sentence for four months
hinting that Woodward would not
be jailed because of her talent.
It seems to me that this was a one off.
This was a one off drunk,
drugged up stabbing.
Is that what goes on in England? If you
go to Oxford, they give you one free pass.
As long as it's a bread
knife and not a steak knife.
A complete one off to
prevent this extraordinary,
extraordinary able young talent,
young lady,
lady from not following her long held
desire to enter the profession she wishes
to would be a sentence a what's B,
which would be a sentence
which would be too severe.
Then some fucking judge speak to enter
the profession she wishes to would be a
sentence which would be too severe.
He said that sounding fake.
That sounds like somebody's trying
to sound like a judge. What you did.
We'll never, I know leave you, but
it was pretty awful. Pretty awful.
That's an understatement. And normally
it would attract a custodial sentence.
She's going to be a janitor,
whether it's immediate or suspended.
He said Woodward, who
lives in Milan, Italy,
but the mother stabbed her then boyfriend
in the leg after punching him in the
face and it was below the waist.
So that's a misdemeanor, right?
She then hurled a laptop,
glass and jam jarred him during the
attack on the 30th of September last year,
the quarter she was in court
to hear the judge's comments.
The court was told that Christ's church
would allow her to return in October
because she is that bright and has had
articles published in medical journals.
Do do you realize that if this is true,
how fucked up this is
that then they have the,
the trap car that they drive down to
impoverished areas and they'd leave it on
with the keys in it and the door open.
Why don't you fucking help
somebody out down there?
You gotta be white as a ghost going to
fucking Oxford and they know they're
going to make a bunch of money off
your given a prescription drug someday.
Wow. All right. Anyways,
Woodward will be sentenced
on the 25th of September.
She was given a restraining order and
told to stay drug free and not to Rhea
friend. Hey, if you don't mind,
could you stay away from the person you
stabbed and lay off the fucking pills or
whatever the hell he said she had taken.
A spokesman for Christ shirt said,
I'm afraid that Christ church does
comment on the circumstances of individual
students. I'm a little
confused. If that was a,
I would think that that would
make it to real court. Not just,
she's a little thing to fucking lunatic,
but she's an animal in the rack. Huh?
Um, yeah. I mean that's
par for the course. I mean,
women do not pay the same fucking price.
You know,
white guys get away with shit that
black guys did. There's all fucking,
there's all different.
Before you do the crime,
you really should just do the
math and be like, what am I?
Oh,
what's up sweetheart?
She's coming in here and yeah, I can,
I can't be funny without cursing.
He can't bring my lovely daughter.
Is that my jot in there?
Um, am I watching her now?
Is that what's going on? No.
Oh, are you coming to hang out? Oh,
you want to be on the podcast? Hey,
listen to this shit. Some woman
punched, stabbed in through a laptop,
through a window in a drug
and alcohol fueled rage.
And they gave her a suspended sentence
because of her extraordinary talent in
the metal. Or pretend it could
damage her career in the future.
No, she stabbed her boyfriend in the leg.
Oh, get over here with a bread knife.
It was a bread knife. You know what
the fuck go around stabbing people.
He has a bread knife near Renee Hill. You
know you want to make a bumper sticker?
You know what? That's good. You can't
go around stabbing people. That's right.
You can't go around stabbing people
even if it's with a butter knife.
So what is it? They let her off.
Why? I'll show you what it is.
That's what it is. And the, oh, cause she
is wine. Yeah, he goes to Oxford. Yeah.
Okay. Damage her career.
Oh go fuck yourself.
Whether a little other little, a little
blondie white girl and a moto jacket
that says and is sitting in
this world. Yeah, exactly. Okay.
When she actually killed somebody.
Next time we'll see.
You can't kill someone with
a butter knife. She'll use,
I show you this fucking steak knife next.
She's crazy.
Is a butter knife a gateway to
a steak knife? I believe so.
I believe if you're willing
to pick up a butter,
neither willing to beg
them just about anything.
You conclude your case. Yeah. Can I,
can I hear your closing
arguments for this white lady?
If you were talking to the jury.
All right. You were in England. See,
we're in a powdered wig so it's even
more creepily white for you. Go ahead.
I have to wear the, I think
everybody has to wear one over there.
They're big into dress up over there. I'm
a king. I'm a queen. Who? I'm the duchess.
Okay, Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury, I know that.
What's her name? Uh, Levenia.
I know Luvenia Luvenia
Woodward looks innocent,
but you're staring into the eyes
of a psychopathic would be killer.
That's all I got, man. I thought you were
going to trash her mice wispy way fee.
Little white bitch break.
If I tried to hand her a nail file.
All right.
From an airline mechanic to complete with,
to compete with cheapo airlines
like southwest or jet blue,
the majors need to oversell seats.
In the case of passenger
misses their flight.
When passengers Miss Flights,
they essentially buy two seats for one,
the one they missed and the
one the airline rebook them on.
They do this to maximize
revenue per flight.
I'm against what United did because they
could have paid someone 1 million for
this seat and still not lost as
much as they did. Unfortunately,
entitled people want to pay for
an Uber and sit first class.
Uh,
it's hard to balance enough profit to
operate in eight three 21 cross country
keep prices low and still try to run
the airline like it did in the 70s.
Flying isn't as prestigious
as it used to be.
And everyone is looking for a way
to save a buck. Loved the show.
Go Fuck Yourself. All right, so
evidently passengers are, oh,
so I'm to blame.
Well,
let me ask what was going on in
the 70s that isn't going on now.
Is there a way more people flying?
Did you guys go after bottom feeders so
you have more airplanes so you have more
overhead?
I don't understand why it was so procedure
prestigious back in the Ron Burgundy
days and they treated you way better.
Now they just jam everybody,
you know,
in the back of the plane and try to put
the seats closer together so they can
get more rose. Did you
say Ron Burgundy? Yeah.
That's not a real person. No, but
that the era was like in the 70s.
Okay.
The Ron Burgundy Seventies.
What's a matter with them as a matter with
that man? Um, I would say, uh, I want it.
Why is that?
I,
this is really interesting to hear from
people who actually work in the field.
Like what happened?
Um,
what happened to the price of
fueled go up so high I don't get it.
Why would they just raised ticket prices?
Because on the average person
couldn't afford it. Well, good thing.
Get them the f out of there. Right? Wait,
sorry. I don't know why I came in
here. I'm really kind of checked out.
All right. Yeah. Well you got, we got it.
You've been dealing with the kid all day.
Who puked on me right
before I did this puke,
it was split up and it
was just a little bit,
you act like you're witnessing someone
getting executed in front of you.
Every time she spits up you're like,
oh my God. Like, oh that humanity.
I was sitting there and she was smiling
and out of nowhere she went that it just
fucking all came out and it's all warm.
It's like somebody poured clam
chowder on me and I was laying down,
so one of my shirt, my belt, my
pants, and it's just like, yeah,
I think I had the normal reaction
to somebody puking on you,
no matter how cute they are.
How cute are you? All right, let me,
let me, Oh wait, wait. What'd you do?
What'd you do?
Okay.
Price.
What did you do?
All right. I hope that wasn't a
bunch of silence here. Maybe it was,
maybe it wasn't. I don't know. Um,
I see someone wrote you something
about an article that I read. Oh,
my family's slaves article. Yeah. Yeah.
That was an intense article. I
want to, what does this person say?
Can you read the question? Yeah,
that's what I was going to do.
Can you not sit on the recorder again?
All right. My family slaves article. Hey,
Bilbo Baggins longtime listener.
First time email.
Um, I read an article written by
Alex Tos on, he's dead now. Okay.
That's shock me,
but didn't really necessarily
surprise me and I love your cultural,
a cultural perspective on it. Oh
my God, this is so fucking long.
And this article, this guy talks about
his family owned a slave for 50 years.
Even after immigrating to America,
they smuggled her with them and all that.
They treated her like shit,
never paying her,
forcing her to sleep on top of laundry.
I imagine it's the dirty laundry.
Why would you want to have somebody in
constantly beating her for the tiniest of
Eris?
Only when the writer grew up with an
American identity that he realized what
they were doing to the
poor woman wasn't right.
Did he and his sibling confront their
parents over this? Hey Mom, you know,
you've been thinking this
lady's sleeps on our clothes.
Guarding my teacher. That's not
right. As a guy of Chinese descent,
raised in the Americas,
raised in America.
I've witnessed poor people like
this firsthand. Growing up,
visiting family back in Hong Kong,
I'd see my cousin,
they're millennials by the way,
being tended to by a young Filipino girl,
no older than her twenties I never thought
much of this back then. Looking back,
it seems pretty fucked up.
I asked my mother about these kinds
of people and she simply said,
that's just the way things are.
These girls are poor.
They need to support their family,
and that's the only kind of shitty
employment that they can get.
Once my grandfather took me past city
hall and Hong Kong on a Sunday and I saw
hundreds of young Filipino girls just
sitting on the ground doing absolutely
nothing. I asked him,
what was that all about?
He said that Sunday was a day off and
they had nothing better to do than loiter.
They sent all their money
back home to their families,
so it's not like they could shop
or go to a restaurant or anything.
They ate and slept with their employers.
I never seen my grandfather turned his
nose up at a group of people like that,
but biff ever before my grandfather whose
parents were murdered by the Japanese
during World War Two. Oh Wow.
Yeah, I read about that shit.
The rape and Nan King every that they
fucking Japanese went off and had to walk
to the orphanage after finding out
Jesus Christ. I've had an easy life.
One of the kindest,
most empathetic old farts I know.
Loved randomly hugging white people.
He called them hellos because
that's what they'd say to him.
One of these people out.
Uh, here's the article.
I'm just curious what someone like
you raised with purely Western centric
ideologies would say about
something like this that, well,
I mean this country was kind
of built on that, so, um,
it was built on slavery. Yeah. I
can't really step away to, well,
we don't do it anymore. Um, but uh, yeah,
obviously I think it's,
it's right
three, I mean, not now, but
you should read the article.
It's, it's pretty powerful,
that whole thing,
because this woman was given to his
mother by her father and they're Filipino.
And that's just, yeah,
they would just like here,
this person is going to take care of you.
So she kept this woman throughout her
life and it became her children's care
keeper. Yeah. Cause she didn't
want to do any fucking work.
And then she moved to America and be like,
Oh my God,
I've got to take these kids out
for a Sunday. No, no. That's again,
that's just like the culture.
Like this person is your nanny and now
like you inherit them or something like
that. So it wasn't even as if she had,
it's this Bob part of their tradition.
I have to be not like all of that.
This guy grew up and then he realized
that this woman wasn't getting paid and
all this other stuff and he didn't realize
it until it dawned on him like she is
a slave.
And so he tried to make things better
for her in her later life after his
parents died and all this kind
of stuff. Back Rub. Yeah. No,
but by that time she, you
know, didn't know any other
lives. So she didn't really,
she wasn't like, yeah, I've been
waiting to go shopping at the mall.
Like this whole,
this is so fucking sad. That's
like one, it's like Dubai, Dubai,
they tell all those people and
east of there that, hey man,
come on here and to help us build
all these beautiful buildings.
You make all this money,
you'll get out of poverty.
Then they get them there and then they'd
take confiscate their passports and
that's just slave labor that builds
those fucking places. And then they, uh,
like the number one, the only way to get
out of it as they like commit suicide.
Right.
It's fucking brutal.
Then you watch your shows and the big
balloon tinted horse go over there to buy
a fucking bag. Not a
fan. Not Fan of Dubai,
not a fan of Dubai.
Why can't they be sinless like
the United States of America?
Uh, no, that's all horribly
depressing. And Ah,
I don't know what to tell you
about that as far as like,
I don't know how you'd do that
to somebody. They go in there,
goes to comedy right out
the window. Oh. Um, I wonder
why he, I'm just curious of
why this person asked. Like,
I'm curious what someone like you raised
with a purely wasn't centric ideologies
would say about something
like this. Again, it's like,
are you forgetting that this
is America that was built?
Yeah,
but I didn't grow up with that.
So what he wants to do is
get an outside perspective.
It's actually an intelligent thing that
you mean like, Hey, I'm not from here.
I grew up here, but you know, I
also have, you know, back there.
So what do you think about this? And Blah,
blah, blah. You know what I think, uh,
I think it's a terrible,
I'm going to go on a limb and say that.
That's fucking terrible.
I have so much more shit to read.
Renia you have to get out of
here cause you're just gonna.
You're gonna prolong it. Oh, I thought
you were only doing half an hour. Wait,
how'd that? We're ready to get going.
All right. Sorry. All right, real quick.
Let's let me, let me read this. Cool cars.
Hey, Billy Bruin balls. I'm a huge fan.
All you Ariana excited that you've
become an F1 and moto GP fan.
I followed both of your, these
incredible sports since the mid eighties.
If you haven't already
seen the documentary, uh,
center or Siena Johns Santa isn't,
I saw that actually did watch it.
I don't know perhaps his
name. No, you should.
It does a fantastic job of explaining
the myth around the great formula one
driver and his intense rivalry with
Mclaren teammate Alan Prost. Uh,
I know you're always
looking for cool website.
Here's the link to a really cool auto
auction website and it's a bring a
trailer.com. I'll check that
out. All right, here we go.
Here's some fucking advertisement before
we play a little music and then play a
greatest hits thing. All right. Five,
four mentioned the importance
of feeling good in your clothes.
All my God, when I walk around in jeans,
I want my fucking legs to feel great.
Looking good,
doesn't need to cost a fortune five
four club is revolutionizing the way men
shot, not the ladies. The way
the men do it. At five four club,
they found a way to make men under five
foot four looks stylish to tall women.
No.
At five four club,
they found a way to make great looking
clothes affordable for everyone else. Oh,
Jesus has his person,
his servant gonna make them sleeping on
top of the clothes before they sell them
together. Five four club also understands
that your time is extremely valuable.
Why wasted at the mall or wandering around
in the stores? Dude, I swear to God,
strip malls and malls.
Do you think in the future near do you
think they're going to exist anymore?
If more and more companies like this,
there's going to be no post office.
You won't go to the fucking
mall. Everything's going
to be a luxury high rise,
right? With indentured servants milling
around out front during a Sunday,
I dunno,
each month they send you a curated box
of two to three items that are handpicked
to match the current season in your style.
Five,
four club partners with cutting
edge designers and brands,
so you'll get the same quality as
top designer clothes for way less.
They'd been helping men with fashion for
over 15 years and shipped over 100,000
men every month.
Chris Paul and Mark Walberg
use five four club in five.
Four is featured in Gq,
vice and instyle among other publications.
Near a little look over. They didn't
believe that. Absolutely. Well,
and I'm on the way to the my Oscars.
You know,
someday I'm going to call the five four
club. They know what they're doing,
so if you don't,
that's okay.
Five four club will help you build
your wardrobe one month at a time.
Oh, Bardo me, undies, me. Andy's.
Everyone needs a slave, but do, do,
do beyond ease me undies work
until they're in the grave.
Your balls feel nice and soft because
they polished in with the underwear they
made in. That's fucking
evil. Bottom white.
It's part of my DNA. I'm really
sorry. All right. Mian he's,
hey bill.
What do you think about lifelong slavery
and somebody's dreams being crushed and
so crushed that they don't even have any
dreams and they don't want to do on a
Sunday?
I love to hear your Massachusetts
Western take on that discuss.
All right. Pride starts on the inside.
So celebrate yourself with me undies.
Mandy's makes the ultimate feel
good undies with free shipping,
right to your door. Satisfaction.
Guaranteed designed in La.
Every pair of me undies
is made with micro modal,
modal of fabric, three times
softer than cotton. There's soft,
stretchy undies come in. An ever
changing array of colors and patterns.
No matter what your style,
they've got something for you.
That's because we undies
believes and people feeling good.
And it all starts around your
balls and being themselves,
which is why me undies is putting
their money where their mouth is,
where their underwear is,
and where your balls dangled during pride
month for every special pair addition
for every pair of special
edition, celebrate undies. What?
Celebrate undies year. You buy during
pride. He's poor fucking bastards.
Every month they got to figure out a
way to make these things exciting. Uh,
me undies will donate $1 to
the Los Angeles LGBT center.
What does that long,
Long Gary Bateman technologies,
lesbian, gay, bisexual,
and transcontinental.
Sexuals people who trans,
who's transfer when they say that Trans
Trans loud transition on a flight across
the country.
What is their underwear look
like? Now? Wait a minute.
Did they have special underwear?
Huh?
Nasty pig underwear?
No. You know what it is?
It's like if you have a dick
and then eventually you're
not going to have a dick.
They offer the New Slowly Closing
Front pee hole right under.
Where can they do that?
Slowly closes up.
They call it the broods Jetta. Um, and if
the gold medal underwear
to Cathal on underwear, um,
as and as if you need another reason.
She's,
she liked it and it's, if you need
another reason to try me undies,
they're offering 20% off your first
pair and a satisfaction guarantee that
you'll love them or your money back.
Just visit our URL,
[inaudible] dot com slash head to me
undies.com and pick up a special pair
addition. Celebrate undies. I
just can't get to that sentence.
A special edition. Celebrate undies.
Celebrate. It's like capitalism.
I mean it's,
it's missing a word.
There's no comma said, don't go up
like you know what's going on. Um,
you'll not only get a discount
on some awesome Monday,
she'll be donating to an amazing cause.
Check out [inaudible]
dot com slash bird today.
You know what I realized when they
remove a dick, somebody has to take that,
put it in a bag and like walked down a
hall with it and put it in like a hazmat
thing.
Like where does that go?
Where do you,
where do all the cutoff
Dicsko long time passing.
You know that song? Where do the,
there was a Kingston trio long,
long time ago.
Where did bruise his penis go?
I Manson iconic peanuts that should
have gone to the Smithsonian Institute.
I think it was flopping left and right
as he fucking threw javelins and all that
stuff. Simply safe. Everybody did.
You just have a body part removed and
you want to put it somewhere safe.
Get as simply thing.
Protecting your home and family is
easy with simply safe home security.
Simply safe enters sensors,
motion sensors in glass break sensors.
Make your home a burglar's worst
nightmare or a biggest challenge.
If you're going to keep talking
shit. Um, can you install,
you can install the
system in under an hour.
Simply say's comes preprogrammed
to work out of the box.
Just plug in the base station and it'll
talk you through the whole process.
Seriously. Even someone who isn't the
slightest bit handy can install it.
That really means if you're a
dumb fuck like me, you can do it.
The entire system is wireless,
so there's no need to drill holes in your
walls or do any other permanent damage.
And once you're all set up,
simply safe makes it is just as easy
to stay protected month to month with
simply safe. There's no long
term contracts, no hidden fees.
It's just 1499 a month for 24 seven
professional monitoring and emergency
dispatch service. That's three times
less than what the other guys charge.
Go to simply safe,
burnt.com s.
I. M P, l, I. S. A. F. E. There's no why.
Simply simplized safe.com and get
10% off your home security system.
That's simple. I save.com
for 10% off. Hey,
simply safe.com s I, m p l, I, Sierra,
India, Mike, Papa, Lima, India, um,
legal zoom.com Jesus Christ.
One more
in order to successfully
run your business. Attention
to detail is so critical.
One contract,
one contract slip up and you are.
But now once contracts slip up or legal
misunderstanding can really set you
back.
Fortunately there's legal zoom.
You may already know that over a million
Americans have used legal zone to start
your business.
Start businesses.
But legal zoom service go well beyond
business formation. I'm sorry honey.
I know it's hard to listen
to me read out loud.
They built a nationwide
network of independent
attorneys who can provide legal
answers to the day to day questions
you have about your business.
Because let's face it,
things like trademarks,
employment laws and lease agreements
can get pretty complicated.
So don't waste your time,
your valuable time trying to wrap your
head around all of the fine print use
legal zoom for that. So you can focus
on growing your business. Instead,
you'll get the legal help you need
without being billed by the hour.
Since legal zoom isn't a law firm,
go to legalzoom.com today and be sure
to enter the code Berbee you are are in
the referral box for special savings
only@legalzoom.com are right.
That is the podcast for this month.
And um,
I get now for this, for this Thursday.
I'm all over the map here. Uh,
thank you for everybody riding in and I
like everybody writing in from aviation,
defending the, uh, the aviation land,
defending your side of it. That's good.
Fair and balanced. Uninformed Shit is
what I, that's what I'm all about. Um,
all right, that's the podcast.
Have a great weekend. Um,
I can't say the c Word I've said or other,
every other damn word here
for my daughter. My daughter.
Is that my dog in there?
Um, a, I can't say, hey sweetie,
give me a smile. Okay. Gay. There it is.
Do you know only Nia can make her laugh?
I'm bombing with my own daughter.
It's devastating. This is what I
do for a living. Um, all right.
Enjoy the song and enjoy a
greatest hits from a podcast.
Gone in a Thursday from a long time ago.
I'll see you on Monday.
Evan.
Let's read some of the, uh, the questions
here for this week or we got an update.
I love when there's an uptake.
Remember last week, the,
uh, the granny fucking war.
Remember that story? All right.
Here we got an update. Hey,
they're all Billy fucking water.
I got an update for you on this one. Uh,
the story has good news and bad news.
All right, so last, last week, for
those of you who didn't listen,
I'll give you a little recap. There
was some kid, uh, you know, he was,
he's basically, he's engaged,
he's getting married in six weeks,
so he's over his fiance's house as it
was future in laws house or fucking
parents. That's all I'm
trying to say, right?
So they're playing some card game and
evidently they're down to the final hand
and he has, uh, the cards
called granny water.
I don't know what the game is or whatever.
Some people sent me pictures of
the car at the game does exist,
but it's a really high point card
or whatever. And he was laying down,
ah, fuck, I'm yon and sorry, he
was laying down his card last.
I basically, when he laid it down, he was
going to do the old fucking right there.
Fred.
I won the game and uh,
he had the grantee water card and I guess
in the end of the game is probably the,
you get it, you hold onto it and
you played at a crucial point.
So everybody's sitting there as
everybody's laying the cards down,
waiting to see who's going to fucking
lay it down. So this kid fucking,
it's finally his turn, he lays
it down to be like, you know,
like hitting the last second three.
I just won.
And because he listens to the
podcast instead of saying,
I got the grantee water card,
he goes, he goes, look, he goes,
it's all fucking grant now. He
goes, it's granny fucking wall.
And just screamed it
to his in laws.
Okay, who never heard this guy curse
before and do not listen to this podcast.
So they just stared at him
like, what? What was that?
What is my daughter marrying?
Like he just completely screwed
the whole fucking thing up.
So he's asking me for advice. Should he
bring it up? Should he not bring it up?
All right, now you guys
are caught up. Here he go.
He says the story has
good news and bad news.
The good news is my fiance's parents
were super cool about the whole thing.
Um, I bit the bullet and
waited until we went over, uh,
for game night again last
night. I apologize. Of course.
And they said they initially just thought,
why are,
why are your electors fuck?
They initially thought it was really
odd for me to yell like that without
knowing, without them knowing the
context. But once it was explained,
my fiance texted them about it. It
was no big deal. It was a huge relief.
We played the game again and every
time someone played that card,
they did the whole granny water thing
minus the fucking in the middle.
Okay, cool. He goes, so my
embarrassment will be immortalized. Uh,
the bad news is that I mentioned that
you read the letter on the podcast.
Oh No. You know what, you're
one of those guys, dude,
you just like, you just like
stepping in shit. He goes naturally.
They wanted to listen to it.
I thought it wasn't a big deal because
they lived through the story and your
commentary was hilarious.
I warn them about the explicit nature of
your podcast and that there were plenty
of fucks throughout the fact that you
did the grantee water thing before it was
even brought up, uh, was perfect.
Everyone thought the story was hilarious.
That is until the p s
uh,
if you recall, I may or may have not
called Hillary Clinton a current,
uh, Jesus. That's right. You
did. He goes, yeah, I know.
I'm a dumb ass bill. My fiance just
turned to me and said, did you write that?
Uh,
he said,
my fiance turned to me and said,
did you write that with that look
on her face? I knew I was fucked.
So freckles. I did. The only
thing I could, I said, oh,
sorry about that. I didn't write
it. Bill's email screener. Guy Did.
Andrew did,
he picks the emails each week,
then writes the little opening line pawn
and then sometimes throws in a ps to
make them more entertaining when I,
why would you write this?
Cause if they listen to this, you're
fucked. Do you know what dude,
I have no sympathy for you. So here
we go. He goes, they bought it.
So we just listened to the rest and
we're laughing again by the end.
So I through Andrew under
the bus on that one.
I'm going to repeat my only good move
from the last story and just shut the fuck
up about it forever and the end all
is well thanks for reading it on the
podcast. It seemed to help
smooth it over. No worries.
Just tell them not to listen to
this one. He goes, by the way, um,
I just bought tickets to your show and
I'm not going to say where the show is in
case anybody is figuring
out what the fuck this is.
It's the week after my wedding and my
fiance slash wife by that point is coming
too. I'd love to meet you in person.
Thanks. And Go fuck yourself. Uh,
all right.
Well yeah,
I'll be hanging out after Iowa.
Just scream out. Oh, I
just said where it was.
How well you're fucked granny water
screaming out and I'll fucking say a,
all right,
now everybody's going to do that.
This he smiles all night.
Hey, what's up? This is
bill burr. For some reason,
the podcasts that I did on Memorial Day,
uh,
I dunno,
it hasn't been able to upload.
So now what I've done is I've turned it
into two parts because I think it's been,
I think it was too long.
So here is part one of the
54 minute Memorial Day,
Monday morning podcast at the end of
this one. You listened to part two,
Huh?
Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? It's Belper and it
is the Monday morning podcast for Monday,
May 25th,
2009 Happy Memorial Day to one
and all. Oh, you liked that.
Is that what are the most happiest
Kris kringle ways I've ever started.
A fucking podcast. Yeah. Happy
Memorial Day. And thank you to all the,
uh,
all the troops out there who are serving,
who have ever served at a,
yeah.
Get yourself a burger today or whatever
the fuck you supposed to do on this
holiday. What are you supposed to
do? He's supposed to go to a parade.
Isn't that what you're supposed to do?
You know, I'm not going to a parade.
I, uh, I'm not big on
parades. I don't like him.
I find them boring once I've
seen the first band, I get it.
All right. You're all basically
playing the same song.
It all sounds like the same song.
And I hate when a big fucking college
band starts playing top 40 hits.
Like it's going to sound
good. You know, like, oh,
that's the way Beyonce
should have done that song.
She should have had 58 guys on
a Tuba and 26 guys on trumpets.
I'll play in that fucking,
uh,
if you like a daddy bear to blurred
of egg on it with the fucking trauma,
you know,
28 fucking guys doing that shit and
then you're all fucking walking with the
same feet. Hey, we're all taking
a left at the same time. Ah,
go fuck yourselves. You know, I just
like the drum line. That's all I like.
Other than that, you
know, parade music sucks.
There's a couple of them. Bam,
Bam, Ba bum ba Ba ba bump Ba bump,
Eh, Eh, Eh, Eh,
fitbit pepper.
That's great.
And watch everybody prance around and
their red jackets with the gold buttons.
That's fine. I'm all over that, but
that's it. Once it's done. All right,
let's drink.
Now let's fucking fire up the grill.
I don't need to see another one of those
where bap bap, bap, bap,
bap, bap, bap, bap, bap, bap,
bap about Jesus Christ.
How many more counting on
index lady did, Joe? Man,
please welcome nick girls choir
with their little twiddle sticks.
Whenever the fuck Bhutan's
Eh,
Ooh, ha ha. You know, just standing there,
my big forehead just
burning in the fucking sun.
And what and what comes in the end?
It's either Santa Claus or a fire engine.
That's the end of the fucking paper.
Okay.
Oh those firemen sitting the truck
fresh after banging a hooker,
you know,
are stealing the cash and somebody's
buttoned down in a closet when there was a
fire in the basement.
You know,
I love talking shit about firemen
now cause I don't respect them.
I just love how they just
have this fucking Dudley do,
right? People love firemen.
They hate cops. They love firemen. You
know your house is on fire. They show up,
right?
You can't get stuck in a tree who comes
running down the street and a raincoat
with a fucking ladder. The
goddamn firemen, they get a call,
you know,
did not like cops polishing off a donut.
They stay fucking slide down that stripper
pole and they get it on the big red
for who the fuck doesn't
like a fire engine. You know,
I saw a fire engine fucking yesterday.
I was coming under the dog park with
my dog and there was like three of them
lined up and I guess they
were doing some CPR core.
I don't know what the fuck they would
do when they had one of the firemen,
you know he was, he was strapped down
to a Gurney. This isn't some gay shit.
They were like, fine, they will,
they will. They will learn it.
Some sort of procedure probably how to
move someone who has got a spinal cord
injury or whatever,
but they all the fire engines lined up
and I got to admit there's something,
there's a little kid and everybody's,
you get near a fire
engine is fucking great.
Big Red fire engine with all that
fucking chrome, you know? I mean,
who is a kid didn't want to be that guy
at the back of the fire engine driving
the thing down the fucking street.
You know what I mean?
That's what I'm going to do
someday when I get super famous.
That's the perk that I'm
calling in is I'm going to be,
I want to fucking drive that
thing down the street. You know,
they take you on a straightaway,
you realize how much
those fucking trucks cost.
Yeah. Well I don't either. I have
no fucking idea how much they cost.
They got to cost a lot.
Right. You know, dude,
you got to figure a fucking Winnebago. If
you get a nice one, cost you 150 grand.
Now what if you had a Winnebago that
could actually put out fires, you know,
or save someone with a spinal cord injury.
You know what I'm saying? Like that,
that would be, uh, that'd be at
least 200 grand. Right? You know,
I wonder if I can fucking
Google it right now.
You don't even realize today if you click
on f four, you get on your computer,
uh, at least on the Mac
book, you get the calculator,
you get the weather for the week,
you get a calendar and you get a clock,
you know?
I know that's basic computer shit.
That's something I do here on the podcast.
You don't, I'm not googling that shit. I,
there's gotta be a fireman or two
who fucking a listen to this podcast,
right? And I'm going to trash and
cops, by the way, either I'm not,
I'm just saying how everybody doesn't
like cops. Cause when cops show up,
you know,
either just got beat down by your husband
or you're getting a fucking speeding
ticket, you know, that's
when cops show up. You know,
firemen show up like a, you know, they
stick a ladder. It's like very romantic.
They put a ladder up to your bedroom
and they just take you away from it all.
You know what? Maybe
I'll start debt. Let's,
let's start a new segment on
this podcast where you actually,
you got to tell a bad story about a group
of people that only gets good press.
Like either fireman. What about the
troops? You know, straight up. Oh,
on Memorial Day straight across the board.
Support the troops.
Do you support the truth? You're a
judge. Support the troops. You know,
because I'm such a Cunt, I've actually
broken down supporting the troops.
You know,
th t I actually have so much free time
that I actually sat there and I was like,
really? I just have to straight
across the board, support the troops,
every single one of them.
You know, every single one,
like there's not one asshole in the navy
that even his fellow fucking people in
the navy can't fucking stand.
You know,
there's some current right now on a
fucking aircraft carrier who's just not
pulling his weight.
He's always fucking off and he know.
But he knows exactly when to fucking
pop to attention. When, when some,
when some officer comes by,
you know there's not one douche bag
in the navy dead is other navy buddies
aren't thinking it. Just push overboard.
Give me a fucking break. Okay,
so that I support the troops
but not the Douche bags.
How about that?
Um,
I'm actually going to make that into
a bumper sticker and I'll just have a
camouflage background so
no one will question it.
Where Lynn Miller and break it down here.
Where are you guys saying he supports
the truth? We're not the Douche bags.
I guess the Douche bags. Mostly the people
who don't support the troops. Now, dude,
the Douche bags and the guys
who are troops but happened
to be douche bags. Okay,
let's not speak in absolutes here.
Why the fuck would I say shit like that
on the God Memorial Day? You know what?
I support all the troops, even that
Douche bags today, but on any other day,
I don't. I don't. I, you know, I live in,
I live in the real world here. I'm or not.
I don't live in a real world.
Look at me.
I'm fucking sitting here with an orange
microphone talking shit to fucking
myself. I'm, I'm a realist. Okay.
You know what I mean? Look at, I
look at all, what's his face there,
George Bush. You know what I mean? I bet
people didn't think he was a Douche bag.
I bet he was a hot shit when he was in
the fucking national guard. You know,
taking weekends off when
he's supposed to be there.
He probably took you out on his boat now.
Now he didn't have a boat.
He lived in Texas, probably at a horse
or some shit. Isn't it amazing how that,
that guy just, he just fucking
disappeared. You know, I didn't,
I didn't agree with
George Bush's policies,
but there was just something about that
guy that I just really fucking related
to. You know what I mean? Like if I went,
if I stopped being president,
the amount of stress that has to
be involved with that fucking job,
I got to tell you something,
dude, today that job was over. I,
that's that.
Yet I'd like him.
You'd never see me again or the
very least I would take like a,
God, I, you'd have to, you'd have to
take at least five fucking years off.
I know they told stories about how
much that job ages you and if you don't
believe it, look at like younger pictures
of George Bush. Like how quickly you go.
Gray. Same thing happened to,
uh, to Bill Clinton. You know?
Or maybe they just stop using Grecian
formula because they got elected and I'm
like, well, I don't have to do this
fucking beauty parlor shit anyways.
I got the fucking job,
you know,
I'm taking my dick out,
bring in an intern.
One of the easiest impressions ever.
Build Little Bill Clinton for you.
You like that. And the end of this, I'll
do a Vinnie Barbarino actually, you know,
that's one of the things
that I wish I knew how to do.
I wish I knew how to do a impressions.
I wish, I wish I could do it.
I can more sorta imitate people
who I hang out with, but I,
I can't imitate famous people unless
somebody famous already does the
impression, then I can do an impression
of their impression. That's basically it.
You know, that's, that's I'm
sort of a hacky impression guy.
And a, and then if you do
something really obscure,
which I think I've talked to before in
this podcast, like yeah, Jay Moore's,
Collin Quinn, if you guys seen that, and
I'm going to cross promote right now,
not only j more,
but the opn Anthony show
go on youtube and a search.
Jay Mohr, opie and Anthony
and uh, he calls in,
he does a series of unbelievable fucking
impressions and the most amazing one is
he does Colin Quinn.
And if you know,
who the fuck does that guy?
Like I've known Collin Forever and I've
never noticed any like tick in the way
he talks and this guy, you
know what I mean? I just like,
one time I saw somebody do a,
the first person I saw do Tom
cruise the fuck show was I watching?
I was watching. It wasn't
30 rock. Excuse me.
How to clear my throat wasn't 30 rock.
What was that other show that,
that dude from friends was on that was
like 30 rock except they were taking it
seriously.
The fuck was that one
called like 60 degrees.
I can never remember these. I wasn't
there a number in it, you know,
to fuck Jesus Christ. We have to do is
sketch show, is that what it's called?
I know it was a drama,
but whatever.
But there was some kid in there who did
impressions and keeps fucking unreal.
He did a Ben Stiller and a,
uh,
an a Tom cruise that we're dead on and I,
I've scoured the internet
trying to find scoured. Is that,
is that really a fucking,
is that the right word?
Does not mean you got burned
now scalded is burned.
Scoured. That's not a
fucking word. Whatever.
I searched high and low near
and far all over the Internet.
I can't fucking find it,
but it's definitely worth,
it's definitely worth checking out and a,
and there you go.
I've talked myself into a corner.
I don't know what the fuck to say now.
I just realized that usually I just,
you know, I get a head of steam going,
this is how I do these podcasts.
I get a fucking head of steam going and
I just start running until I'm out of
breath and then I go back to the screen
and I read like questions or whatever.
But you know what? I'm not going
to read a question this week.
I'm going to start off with a,
a couple of stories about dogs.
All right.
One funny one in one feel good. One for
the Memorial Day holiday. All right,
here we go. Ah, this comes
from some fucking, dude.
I don't name names on this. All right.
I'm old school. All right. Uh, hey bill,
I have a dog story for you.
Uh,
whenever I visit my parents
who live at the Jersey shore,
I always take my dog who lives
with them to the beach. Uh,
personally, I love that
sentence. Listen to this.
Whenever I visit my parents
who live in the Jersey shore,
I always take my dog who lives
with them to the beach. Dude,
if your dog lives with your parents,
that's not your dog. All right?
That's like, you know,
that's like your bank.
You'd fucking knocked up your 16 year
old girlfriend and you left the baby with
your parents and they raised it.
You know,
you'll run to one of
those douchebags in a bar.
It fucking two in the
morning on a Wednesday starts
saying how he's got a kid.
Yeah. Went, see my kid for
Gurus takes out a picture of it,
you know, and it's like, dude, it's
fucking 2:00 AM on a Wednesday.
Shouldn't you be home with your
kid? Ah, I don't have a right now.
She's with my parents. Well then it's
not your fucking kid. All right? You're,
you're like a,
you're like,
it's brother sold a brother
who's like chuck on happy days.
Anybody remember that?
I mean,
people out there realize that Richie
Cunningham actually had an older brother
during the first season named chuck,
and he didn't know what
the fuck to do with them.
So they just had them go off to college
and then they just never used them again.
And then after a while,
they literally started just saying that
they get two kids and they never address
that kid anymore. You know? Ever again.
That's what your fucking dogs life,
sir. It's like chuck on happy days.
But anyways,
let's read the rest of this story because
this is actually a funny story. Uh,
my dog is 110 pound golden retriever,
who basically looks like a furry
[inaudible] with legs. God Damn it.
I can't fucking read.
So anyways,
so I had my dog at the beach and his
favorite thing to do at the beach is to go
in the water and swim after tennis balls.
Uh,
so one day I'm at the beach and this is
school trip of what seems to be a fourth
graders and fifth graders and they're
looking at see life in a jetty. Sarah,
I like how you wrote jetty. Like
everybody knows what the fuck a jetty is.
What does a jetty,
is that a little pool of water that
gathers during high tide and then remains
during low tide? Is that what
a jetty is? I don't know.
I know it's not a lagoon cause I
Gilligan's island. All right. Uh,
so a few of the kids came up to me and
asked me if it was okay if they could
play with my dog.
So I told him no problem.
And the kids are getting a kick out of
watching my dog run to the water and
fetched the tennis ball.
So one of the kids yells over to his
friend who's busy looking in the jetty.
He's like, hey dude, you got to come over
here and check out how cool this dog it.
At which point the kid and
the looking in the jetty says,
no way you guys are missing out. There's
a whole bunch of crustaceans over here.
So the kid who's standing next to me just
sort of turns it looks at me and goes,
what a faggot.
And I just burst out laughing because
I was thinking the exact same thing
as a fucking hilarious story right there.
People, I don't know if it went by you,
but that was a funny God
damn story. That's the funny
thing about being an adult.
If you're younger you,
I guess you think that you know you're
going to get mature and you're not going
to think that shit that you would
have thought in fourth grade.
And that's not what being an adult is.
Being adult is,
I guess still thinking the same
shit that a fourth grader thinks,
but you got to act like you're
not thinking. You know, like,
I'd like to think if I was there,
I would have said, uh, you know,
you shouldn't use that word. It's very
offensive, uh, blah, blah, blah, blah,
and gone down that politically correct
route. But I probably would have left too.
You know what I mean?
And that was just funny on a lot of
levels where the kid was being a little
pussy and the fact that a fourth grader
would say that and the fact that it's
coming out of a fourth graders
mouth, you know what I mean? I,
I would challenge one of those
politically correct people. You know,
I don't, I don't think, you know what?
I just talked myself into a fucking
corner again, I don't know what to say.
This is one of these deals.
You know what it is really people.
I just had a big argument. My girlfriend
and she's walking the dog right now.
I know she's coming back in
a half hour and she's worked.
She's going to come in and she's
not going to argue with me. Okay.
For you douchebags and think you're going
to get a little behind the scenes here
in my relationship,
but she's definitely going to give me
the silent treatment and as much as I'm
going to try to block her out,
it's a,
I'm not going to be able to do it
because her silence is just going to be
fucking washing over me,
you know? So whatever.
Um,
I had one of those arguments you have,
you have to have in a relationship every
once in awhile you got to blow the air
out of the pipes and uh,
that's what I did and I'm going
to be paying for it today.
So I hope your guys Memorial Day is
working out a little better than mine.
What do you think about that?
Okay,
and how about a little pat on the back
for me on a nice fucking holiday actually
doing this God damn podcast has
17 fucking free minutes so far.
I got to tell you I'm not doing 50
minutes. I know. I always say that,
but I'm not doing it this week. Okay?
I get shit to do. I got laundry going.
All right,
I've got a whole bunch of shit I got to
do before I can then go to a god damned
barbecue,
show off my pasty white legs and have a
burger because that's what the fuck I'm
doing. Um, so anyways, you know,
before I get too far down the road,
that is a new,
that is a new segment here.
Well you have to tell a bad story about
a group of people that just consistently
always gets good press and don't fucking
make one up either. Okay. If you,
if you have one, send one in. If you
don't, please don't waste my time.
People always try and do that.
Like I don't read a lot of the shit that
people send me cause it just, you know,
some of the revenge stories,
that's why I kind of stopped doing them
because they really got like ridiculous,
you know, they started getting like
James Bond ask and I'm like, dude,
the overhead of this revenge
is six figures. Okay.
This didn't happen. So anyways,
yeah. If he, if you knew, you know,
a nun who was being a
little cunty one day, uh,
who else gets good press? Kids
get great press, you know,
like they can do no wrong like they have,
they're not aware that they're
doing wrong, you know, I don't know.
If you don't hate kids on
some level, you're just not
being honest with yourself.
All right. Um, what do we got
here? Let's go with the, uh,
the questions for the week. All
right. Question number one, Bill.
If you had the choice to resurrect
either resurrect, either bond Scott,
Jimi Hendrix or John Bonam for one night,
who would you want to see in concert?
Uh,
you son of a bitch. That's a hard one. Um,
huge ACDC fan and I've always hated the
fact that I never got to see bond Scott,
but Jimi Hendrix, that would be
like being able to see fucking, uh,
I can't even say Jordan
cause I got to see him play.
I would tell you that story
when I saw Michael Jordan play,
I saw him in North Carolina and not
when he played with the tar heels.
This is a story for people who live in
North Carolina because I'm in the place
was not packed. I might've told this story
before. I can't even fucking remember.
I talk on my cell phone so much.
My brain is mush. Basically.
I was living in North
Carolina in 87, 88. And uh,
it was the year before
the Charlotte Hornets.
We're going to start in the NBA.
So to get people excited
about, uh, NBA hoop, you know,
cause obviously down there they got
tobacco road and all that fucking shit.
They're really big into college
ball to get people excited.
What they did was they had to scrimmages
at the Dean Dome at the University of
North Carolina.
And um,
what they did was they had a basically
two games and professional hoop,
like scrimmage hoop and each
team had a former tar heel on it.
And one of the Games was a,
the Chicago Bulls.
First I want to say the
Cleveland Cavaliers.
So you had Michael Jordan,
former tar heel,
and then you had Brad Doherty on
the Cavaliers. And, uh, so I've,
I've got to see Michael Jordan back when
he was skinny and he had hair and he,
and he only had one dunk. But
it was cool. It was so early.
I told this story before.
I remember that I told this story before.
It didn't I or did I tell it in a bar?
I can't fucking remember.
But I remember it was so
early in Jordan's career,
I was nudging my mom going to
watch that guy. That guy's good.
That guy's good.
Can you fucking believe that?
And then the other game
was the Los Angeles Lakers,
cause they had James Worthy,
former tar heel.
And I want to say they played the Seattle
Supersonics and it was a Sam Perkins,
but I can't fucking remember.
So if anybody from North
Carolina or if you can Google it,
and somehow it was in the dean dome.
I remember that. I do remember that.
And it wasn't nearly, it was, it
was probably three quarters full,
not even maybe 60% fucking full.
Um,
Jesus Christ. Can I get back
to the fucking questionnaire?
All right. Bon Scott,
Jimi Hendrix man or John Bonam.
Ah, fuck. You know, I couldn't, I
can't, I can't fucking answer that.
John Bonham Mobile,
Jimi Hendrix.
Well, if I'll tell you this, if I
was going to see, you know what,
I would have to flip a coin,
which doesn't even work out mathematically
cause there's three fucking people.
I'd have to throw a dart. All right,
I got to admit Bon Scott is out.
God dammit. I never
thought I'd say that. Okay.
But the thing about Jimmy
Hendrix and John Bonham is they,
they changed Jimi Hendrix changed fucking
what you thought was what you could do
on the guitar and John Bonham,
you know,
basically he brought rock
drumming into the modern era.
So fucking cunt. What
a question. All right,
now this is all I can tell you. I would
throw a dark between Jimmy Hendrickson,
John Bonham, and when I would see Jimi
Hendrix, it would be with band of Gypsies,
not with the experience.
All right? Cause that, uh,
that live album he has, we placed
machine gun and all that shit. Well,
boom, boom. Ba Da Ba da Ba da
Ba. Do Bad. That one with Bob,
was it budding miles on drums and uh,
Billy Cox,
whatever his fucking name is
on base that I would, I'd want,
that's what I want to,
I would want to see them on at that,
wherever they take that.
Was it in San Francisco at the Fillmore?
Remember that Shit.
And I would see John Bonham at a Royal
Albert Hall and I would be backstage and
I would be able to see his fucking based
from fourth to figure out what the fuck
he was doing.
Do you guys ever listen to old live albums
or you ever watch old concert footage
of how polite rock shows were?
Like the promoter would literally come
out and they would like announce the band.
Like on that Jimi Hendrix one,
it's really cool.
Like this promoter comes out and people
have this little polite applause,
applause and a the here, this
promoter going out, you know,
welcome to the Fillmore west tonight
we have a wonderful new band.
Ah, Babababa all this type of
shit. And then the background,
Jimmy's already playing,
he says,
and the fucking promoter
is talking over it.
It gives me chill in a second. He's done.
Then they just fucking go into the song.
You know?
Maybe because I'm old now,
I would love to go see a great band and
be able to sit down and just fucking
enjoy them as musicians. I hate the
fact that I have to fucking stand up,
you know?
And look around that Douche bag,
who puts his fucking
girlfriend on his shoulders?
You want to talk about a fucking
pussy whipped individual.
It's already bad enough that you
probably had to buy the fucking tickets.
You had to pay for parking. You're
already fucking whatever, two,
300 bucks in the hall. Yeah. You
know? And then on top of that,
you got to put your fucking chick on your
shoulders. Right. See, you're literally,
your spinal cord is crunching down so
she can get up there and make eyes over
there with the fucking lead singer and
possibly even flash your tits that she'll
then fucking blame on whatever
the weed was fucking laced with.
You're actually helping her to maybe
bang another guy at that point.
You know?
Because if the lead singer like sir,
he just gives the nod to the fucking,
the uh,
his go gather some pussy guy.
And then when he comes down there and he
taps your girlfriend on the shoulders,
says he wants to meet him, you
know, you sitting there going like,
you want to say no, you
can't do that. But you know,
you're never going to hear the end of
it because that was a dream to go see a
[inaudible] fucking a
Eddie fucking Douche bag,
whatever his fucking name is Eddie
vetter. Right. I, you know what,
I totally lost control of that story
because my washing machine just started
beeping to let me know that
the load of clothes has done.
This is what I'm doing with my fucking,
my memorial day.
I'll listen to the sirens.
It'd be funny if I could actually do this,
this podcast live and that was
a bunch of firemen coming over.
He had to kick my ass, you know,
and just to be traditional,
they didn't break down the door with
an ax. They actually put the ladder up,
fuse me,
Jesus
price is my house on fire.
Here it comes.
It would have that moment
and there it goes. Ah, right.
He's winding down. Okay, keep going.
Jesus Christ thought my place
was on fire there for a second.
Um, anyways, so that's what I would do.
I would pick between Jimmy
Hendrickson bond, Scott and I would,
I would throw a dart and uh,
I have to admit,
I think I would see Jimi Hendrix and
the end of it there, I made my decision.
I would see Jimi Dude.
That was a great fucking question.
That really was a great question.
Okay.
And here comes another God damn truck.
You know what?
This is some Douche bag on memorial
day already burned down their fucking
backyard with their,
with their Hibachi Jesus Christ.
There's the one where you
got to steer in the back.
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
This stopping on my street.
Yeah.
What would you do with the
middle of this fucking podcast?
All of a sudden somebody came
on while we're like a megaphone
Amri tangent. Ain't everybody
on the street dates to evacuate.
Okay.
Do you know that happened
to me when I was a kid?
Jesus Christ is for fucking fire
trucks right outside my window.
I feel like one of those guys,
I feel like Jimmy Olsen,
like I'm getting the scoop right now.
You know what?
Now I have to go over and
I have to investigate.
Let me bring my little fucking
podcast station over here. You know,
it'd be great if there was one right below
the window and I could actually stick
my head out with,
I actually wear headphones and I got this
microphone with the orange screen on it
and I just started talking like
it was the 1920s scares me sir.
What's going on down now?
Trying to get the scope.
Why can't I open my fucking windows?
You know what's funny?
You ever notice like whenever like some
fucking old lady twists or goddamn ankle,
like 17 firetrucks show up. It's
like, is it really necessary?
Okay,
why don't you put all the, the old lady
broke her fucking hip shit on one truck.
Dude,
there's no smoke.
There's nothing this for
fucking two fire trucks
for fire trucks. Oh my God.
Is that a why that is a woman.
I thought that was a guy. Jesus
Christ. Somebody just came walking by
looking like they weren't one of those,
you know,
those eighties bands that just uh,
they all just had like, then you know,
the one hit wonders but there was,
there was,
there was that whole scene like
they weren't like a Duran Duran.
They actually thought that they
were like artistic. What the,
what the fuck kind of bands were those?
They weren't, it wasn't like heavy metal.
It wasn't rock, um, new wave.
That's right.
I thought it was some guy dressed like
he was front and a new wave band and
ended up just being, I did, you know, you
know what girls like put their, their,
their pony tail,
you know,
and they wrap it around the front
and you can't fucking see it. Dude.
There's no sense of urgency. Now
they're backing the fire truck up. I,
this is one of these times when I just
wish I was old so I could go out there
and just start yelling at him.
You know about taxpayers money and Shit,
Dude, how fucked up is that?
I was making fun of firemen,
you know,
at the beginning of this podcast
and for fucking fire truck show up.
You don't want,
this is the thing,
I have to close the window because my
voice really carries and I say fuck a lot.
Not to mention the word cunt,
so I'm going to have to,
you know when they always leave
the fire engines running, you know?
Who Do you think pays for that
gas? Huh? We do see this is great.
This is the new segment right here.
I can trash fireman if there's a fire man.
Listen right now.
Is it a fire man or a fireman?
You know,
if one of you motherfuckers is listening
right now, can you answer that? Why?
When there's no smoke, there's no
fire. Why do 18 trucks show up?
You guys all just bored.
Are you trying to get away from that?
Get that the fat fuck down the firehouse?
Who's making the Chili? You know,
isn't that, isn't there like always
there was always a cook down there,
isn't there? He's got one of those
big mustaches. Yeah. Okay. Hey,
what do you make it today?
They have Freddy.
Oh, Megan. Mom. Make some
fucking Chile. Really?
You're gonna make some
you're famous fucking red hot
chili and then I'm going to
have had that in my mouth. Then I'm
not going to go fight a fucking fire.
You asshole.
I bought some Koolaid.
Now I'm fascinated.
Can you hear the rumble of those engines?
You know a lot of chicks like firemen.
They do. There's something about him.
You know, they rescue people. You know,
they got that rain coat sort of
perverted. It's like, you know,
they naked under there. Is he going to
show you to going to show me his hose?
There's a bunch of them walking
around in their fucking rain coats.
Okay.
Jesus Christ. You know
something? I got to admit,
you know what? I wouldn't, I
would walk out on my balcony.
I actually have a little fucking balcony
I could be standing on right now.
I could figure out what
the fuck's going on.
I can't even do the rest of this podcast.
This is ridiculous.
Was that really me talking? I just went
to some accent there. I usually say,
this is ridiculous. This is
ridiculous. Um, all right,
I'm going to try to fucking answer
the rest of these questions.
It's four fire trucks sit
outside and people walk
around. Is it a chemical spill?
All right.
That concludes part one.
And I have no idea why there's such a
huge echo on this. I'm using the, uh,
the recorder from my, my fucking
laptop, so that ends part one.
Now just go listen to part two just in
case you're a complete moron and you
didn't know that that's what you were
supposed to do. Okay. Hey, what's up?
This is bill burr and this is part two
of the Monday morning podcasts from May
25th, 2009. And for the life of me,
I don't know what that
fucking echo was all about.
Oh yeah. I started to tell a
story. Yeah. When I was a kid, uh,
this fucking guy's barn burned down and
evidently he ran this big business and
he had toxic toxic waste
and these big oil drums.
So evidently they went around to
every house in the neighborhood,
knocking on the door, telling everybody
to get the fuck out of their house.
And I don't know if they
forgot to go our house or what,
but we didn't know.
We didn't know.
So me and my brother went out to
do our paper routes in the morning.
That's how white my childhood was.
You know,
right after I had a piece of toast with
that little square piece of butter on it.
I went out
part of this complete breakfast
after I had my complete breakfast,
I went out to do my paper route and
there was all this smoke in the air and
there was nobody. We lived on a
busy street and there were no cars,
and there was just this firehose going
all the way up right down the middle of
the street. So we will let a wheel
like, oh wow, that's cool. Right?
We didn't give a fuck. So, uh,
I ride my bike down the street
to do my first customer,
which is in the direction of the fire.
So I drove down there on my bicycle and
there's a fireman standing there and
he's got, you know, the,
the fucking oxygen mask on.
And he literally looks at me and he
did literally the cartoon double take,
like Yeti editor, you
know, like what the F,
like he couldn't believe what he
was saying is all his smoking here.
Here I come up,
my little howdy doody face comes up to
street riding on my little bicycle and he
comes and he starts screaming at me
through that mass going like dark,
right?
Just dropping the F bomb and I'll
be like, ah, I have a paper route.
I had no idea.
So we ended up,
you know, maybe that's why my memory
sucks cause I sat there breathing in,
breathe in, all that shit.
Allegedly the guy who's who, uh,
whose barn it was started radio
shack. That was, that was the, uh,
that was the rumor. So anyways,
here we go. Ah, question number two.
Hey Bill, I want to know what you think
of old people going, going to the gym.
Every time I see this 60 year
old guy doing sit ups at the gym,
I felt sorry for him.
I work out so I can stay
healthy and live to see old age.
Once I see old age, it's
mission accomplished, right?
I think one, uh, when
I see these old people,
I think one of two things is going on.
Either he doesn't know he's old,
which is pathetic or he wants to grow
older, which is even more pathetic.
I mean,
how selfish can you be?
Do you want your family to
be wiping your ass at 90?
The big question is,
at what age will you stop working out?
I'm done at 50. I got
18 more years to go. Uh,
thanks for the podcast. Uh, they
helped my three hour daily commute.
Make it much easier. Well, thank
you sir. I'm glad you like them. Um,
don't you hate when somebody calls
you serve by the way, are ma'am.
Isn't that the worst the first day that
that fucking happens? You're just like,
Jesus, I really am old.
Okay. When am I going to stop
working out? Uh, I gotta admit,
Dude, I'm never going to stop working
out, but I won't be going to the gym.
Maybe I will be. You know what,
I, I've just, I just sort of,
I've adjusted my workouts to,
uh,
to with my age. Like I used
to, I used to, you know,
I used to throw the way to round
over there. Oh, right. And,
uh, you know, used to play full
court hoop running up and down,
but my body just can't take that.
I can still lift weights and shit.
I just get bored doing that. But,
uh, as I grow older, I, I, I,
I've told myself that I'm gradually
gonna Morph into yoga and [inaudible]
I just paused there. Wait for every
food you yogo you fucking gay, salty,
where you stretching yourself out.
You can give welcome banged in the air.
You could do,
guys are so fucking dumb, you know?
And there's just something about,
anytime you do something smart,
immediately it's considered feminine.
You know,
if you do something dumb here,
a man,
if you don't work out and he keeps
drinking red bear shove and half a fucking
cow's head into your colon, then
Dan, Dan, you're a guy. But yeah,
that's what I'm going to do it. And No,
I'm not going to, no, I'm never stuck.
I'm going to stop working.
I'm never gonna stop trying new things
and trying to learn shit because when you
do that shit, dude, you die. You Die.
And it's very easily to be 32 I've
done the math. You're 32 years old.
It's very easy to say that.
You know you're going to say
fuck it at 50 you're not dude,
because the 32 if you're still working
out, that means you still look good,
which means women are still
kind of checking you are,
but I'm telling you do it starts dropping
off when it starts fucking dropping
off. You know, you're like, Jesus Christ,
I don't even fucking look at me anymore.
And it's,
it's going to motivate you or you'll
just go into a depression and you will
spoon with that depression and you'll
eat yourself into an early grave before
you 50 so those are your options.
All right?
Okay.
Hang in that dual, keep working out.
You know, you want to come that,
do you want to come that Steph fat?
Fuck. You know what I'm saying?
We got that big bulge of fat right above
your Dick. You don't wanna be that guy.
You know, he just, you know,
you get that old person,
I'm going to die soon.
Smell. It's just bad.
You don't want you to want to be
that guy. All right? Uh, you know,
just out of curiosity,
I wonder who the oldest person is who
actually listens to this fucking podcast.
You know,
that's another thing.
I always want to stay up on
music and that type of shit.
I think that's easy to do when
you don't have children, but, uh,
I don't fucking know Phil, just shut up
and move on with the questions. All right.
Question number three, Bill.
I'm from Cleveland. Uh,
and I've rules really s and I'm
really psyched about the, uh,
Cavalier Orlando's Wednesday game.
It was amazing.
He had a bit dis pressing
at the same time.
Fortunately the Cavs lost one oh seven
one oh six dip deck a day the whole way
through.
Uh,
do you think what Brian will lead the
Cavaliers to victory against the magic and
who do you anticipate
to win the championship?
Um,
I have to admit,
I don't know shit about basketball and
I've started to watch now that the Bruins
and the Celtics are knocked out.
You know,
I wasn't really even watching the
Celtics, I'm just not in the hoop. And,
uh, I got to met, you
know, Cleveland, Orlando,
I don't think you could ask for a
better series out, but Lakers, Denver,
that series has sucked.
It's like neither team has won a game yet.
Denver blew the first game,
the Lakers blue,
the second game and Denver
blew the third game. And, um,
what's killing me is that I don't see
a dominant fucking team in the four
remaining teams. So I think this is
kind of, it's kind of a weak year.
I think Lebron is the shit and I
think that fucking superhero do dare.
What Howard for Orlando is,
is ridiculous and Colby is ridiculous.
And what's his face?
Carmelo Anthony is ridiculous
and everyone else is regular.
That's just regular standing around
watching those guys doing shit,
you know? There we go. That'll
get me a lot of fucking emails.
All these fucking hoop heads,
dude. Oh fuck. Can you say that?
Stood fucking good. Jamica
whatever. Fucking whatever.
Some black guy named his fucking regular.
He had,
he had 22 we won't see how many seats.
I don't give a fuck.
Pro Hoop is fucking boring.
The referees control the temple where the
game and the final three minutes takes
an hour. Fuck that game.
Okay, what does that,
what does that thing that,
that the commercial that they have,
when's the next time great will happen?
I'll tell you when the ref stops blowing
his fucking whistle. Every five seconds.
Do the second one team goes into the
penalty. Just kiss the rest of your day.
Goodbye.
It is the most boring fucking hundred
points you're ever going to see in your
life. Coby Bryan shooting the
front end of a one on one.
He's 38 and 39 from the line tonight.
39 38 39 let's fucking divide that by two.
That's fucking what? 1819 there'll be
night. There'd be his 20th fucking time.
He's gone to the line 20 fucking times
at that point. And Miss, oh no. 18 wait,
can you be 38 39 yeah, cause you could,
you could go for a three point play.
So whatever the guy's got on the line,
like fucking anywhere from
16 to 20 fucking times,
20 fucking times. They blown the
whistle with one fucking guy.
All right. I know 38 is a high number.
Okay. But there's nights where he's,
you know,
20th 22 from the line.
One Guy, one guy has the game 10 fucking
times. It's, it's, it's, it's the worst.
And I got to Mit, I think pro
football really gets boring. You know,
there's nothing worse than a pro
football game against two teams that are
mediocre.
It's just terrible.
And it's one of the written other reasons
why I love hockey because at the very
least have two teams suck. Maybe
there'll be a fight, you know,
any other sport.
If there's a fight that is the lead
fucking story on Sportcenter Holy Shit,
the benches emptied or this guy charged
the amount of fucking or whatever.
And hockey is whatever that
can happen in any game to God.
Great Sport.
If you like the movie Mad Max and
you don't like hockey and you're very
inconsistent human being. All right,
let's get on with computer tips. Uh,
we've been doing very basic computer tips,
helping people like myself,
a limp along. And uh, just to get
shit moving here, I have to admit,
this person brought in some computer
tips this week. One, two, three, four,
five of them and the first four
I knew. So a few guys, you know,
all you guys who are really into computer,
if you guys can,
can go to the next level here where
we can talk about preferences,
you know, where you know, they click on
the apple and then Click on preferences,
go into the applications. And, but
if you can break down that shit, um,
that would really help me out because I'm
really getting good at computers right
now or much better than I was because
of you guys, so I appreciate it.
So here's the, Oh God, my girlfriend's
back. Now it's going to get awkward.
It's going to get awkward. Um, all
right, here are some of the uh,
the questions here, question number,
uh, or some of the computer tips.
Computer tip number one.
Uh,
hold the apple command and
the letter x to cut. I mean,
people know this shit.
Apple Command and the letter C to copy
Apple Command and the letter V to paste.
And this is the one I didn't know.
Apple Command and the letter Z to undo.
I didn't know that one.
And that one.
Basically this guy so eloquently puts
when you just fucked up any document,
email or typing that you just did,
if you delete something by
accident and then hit the,
just hit apple z and you get it back.
Um,
and he goes,
God,
I know you have to know the f three
button to separate the screens. By now,
but I just want to make sure since that
shit is on the Mac, you know what dude,
I didn't know that one f three. You hit
that and that separates all your windows,
which in which point I
said what is that for do.
And that's when I found the calculator,
the date,
my forecast for the week and the time.
So that's pretty fucking cool.
I'll actually have to start the podcast
with that. So I won't know the dates but,
and for anyone,
you know,
I'm kind of being an arrogant
ass here cause I am a moron.
So if you don't know shit like that,
that apple command in the letter x,
uh, is basically when you just
highlight whatever you just did,
if you hit the command button and let her
ex that will just delete the sentence,
you know, apple, see that will copy it.
And then Apple v you paste it to somewhere
else. It's very easy to figure out.
But, um, I think at this point
and everybody's caught up.
So if you guys do computer tips, if you
want to take them to the next level,
that would be greatly appreciated and
all you fucking Douche bags out there who
are good at computer,
just Google good and so fucking basic.
This shit that you suck at and right.
Okay. Look at me getting all defensive.
All right,
you want to hear a heart warming dog
story and I'll end the podcast here and
actually I want,
I'm going to blow through some underrated
overrated because a lot of people sent
some shit in. Okay.
Heartwarming dog story. Uh Oh.
And also I got to have douche bag of
the week. I forgot about that one.
Heartwarming dog story. Uh,
all right, Bill. Uh, you
probably got a lot of emails.
We're going to Doug,
I have a dog that we found five years ago.
I was driving home after work and I saw
a yellow lab mix in the middle of the
road.
She was running across a busy street
with an e color on one of those things.
The vet's put on a dog and a,
I dunno, it's fucking dog has been
hectic. This is a really long stories.
So she's running across the
street and nobody was stopping.
She was really scared and confused,
running all over the street.
Everyone was honking their horns and
she was just running back and forth.
Not sure where to go. Basically, she was
freaking out. So I saw her in the middle,
in the mid section of the street
waiting to turn. When I saw her,
I call for her to come over,
which he did.
And I opened my car door
and yanked her in the car.
Dude, you got more balls than me. I
would definitely feel bad for the dog.
But I saw old yeller at the wrong
age and I've never just like jaws.
I saw jaws when I was young and I will
not go into the ocean and if there's a
fucking stray dog freaking out,
I'm not going to Yank it in my car
for fear of getting rabies. Um,
I quickly noticed she had a
surgical scar on her stomach.
This dog was scared and she had
the most desperate looking arise.
It really shook me.
So I brought her home and I put her in
the yard while I got our dogs put in
place where they wouldn't see each other.
Since I didn't know how
this dog would behave. See,
this guy really knows about dogs here.
I quickly found that she was
terrified and would not leave my site.
She would come over to me and sit on my
feet and follow me everywhere I went.
So we put her in a different room away
from our other dog and my wife and I got
a plan together to find her owner. Uh,
she was so sweet and terrified. Uh,
she must need to get back to her
house with her owners. Right.
So we put up signs and went around
to neighbor's house, house to house,
door to door to see if we could find
the owner. No luck. The next day,
my wife went to the nearest vet office
because we figured that's where she had a
surgery done. Well, they had never
seen him before, but said, uh, the vet,
the vet said he wanted to scan
her for a con, a microchip.
Turns out she had one and she
was from a no kill shelter.
So we called the shelter.
She was from turns out they kept her at
a veterinarian's house down the street,
but blah, blah, blah, blah. And uh,
they said that they would
come over and pick her up,
but by this time I was having second
thoughts. After only two days,
there are other dog had taken
tours of Wa as well. Um,
this dog loved me after only two days
and I can't explain it because my other
dog could care less about me.
Um, it's my wife's dog and I, um,
and don't get me wrong, I love
him, but this was different.
This dog somehow gotten in my heart.
See, this is what happened with Cleo.
I got the dog and half to two days. I
fucking love the dog. Um, so anyways,
the vet told us her story,
which was verified later on by the shelter
rep who came to approve us to adopt
her for a home.
It turns out she was given up.
I'm really fucking flake in here.
Turns up,
she was given up by everyone in
the families that adopted her.
She was adopted five times. Dude,
that's not a red light flashing.
Choose adopted five times and they
keep getting rid of her. Anyways,
over the issues,
developed some minor behavioral issues
such as digging and getting out of the
yard. She was placed
in when left alone. Um,
but whatever her name is Bella. And while
she was a pain in the ass at the time,
she is, as you said, what
I come home to. And uh,
basically the dude actually loves the
dog, the rest of the dog. And it says,
congrats on Cleo. What? Thank you. I
appreciate that. You know, I dunno,
there was something really cool,
I guess about rescuing a dog,
but there are a lot of, if you're a
realist, there's a lot of red flags there.
Dog have been adopted five
fucking times. Uh, you know,
I don't know. It's a great thing. God
bless you for your adopted dog. All right,
let's get on to Douche bag of the
week. Eric. His douche bag of the week.
Some reason this person sends me this
email right in the middle of my day.
Hey Bill, nice move.
Assuming I'm a female,
I guess I read one of
this, this person's, uh,
questions and I assumed that they were
a female, so they got all upset going.
Nice move. Assuming I'm a female,
since I never sign my name.
And when you read my comments on your
podcasts and always refer to me as a male,
it's just interesting how people will
determine if a person is male or female
without ever meeting them and
just reading what they write.
Why can't a woman writes something
about baseball or hockey? Uh,
say saying something true,
saying some true overrated shit
without being assumed. A male.
And uh,
this is after she,
the first email she wrote,
she wrote, Bill, fuck you.
And then I wrote, Hey Sweetie,
happy Monday to you. Okay.
So then she sends me this
other email, you know? Eh,
it's just really interesting how,
and people send emails
without ever meeting them.
They assume whether they're male or
female. So I just wrote back really,
you know, that's it. That's all that
deserved, really. You know what I mean?
First of all, sweetheart, I don't know if
you realize it, but in the subject area,
up top, it has your full
name, which is a female name.
And I don't know if you realize this,
but I get a ton of fucking emails
and I don't say people's names,
so I delete the names and
I just read them. Okay.
And at that point,
I don't know whether it's male or female,
it's not a fucking sexist thing.
You fucking psychopath.
I keep referring to my dog as a male
because I fucking always had male dogs.
My girlfriend keeps giving me shit. I go,
I got take 'em out. And she's like her,
you know? But it's not like, you know, I
wouldn't hire you if you had the right.
What a fucking, you're
a Douche bag. All right,
you're a big fucking Douche.
But you know,
you're such a big douchebag that literally
12 other Douche bags could climb in
your douche bag. That's how big a
fucking Douche bag you are. Okay?
I'm not assuming anything.
I get a ton of fucking emails.
And if somebody writes about hockey,
yeah,
I do assume that they're
fucking mail the same way.
If somebody wrote about
crocheting a fucking Afghan,
I would assume that they're a female.
I wouldn't be trying to insult the Rosey
Greer fucking guy who's into knitting.
Just generally speaking.
That's a fucking a,
that's a female thing to do.
All right?
Doesn't mean I don't respect you and your
vagina and your knowledge about hockey.
You know, do you know what from now on,
I'm just going to, I'm going to fucking a,
I'm going to say the gender of everybody.
All right?
Like here's an email from
someone who has a Dick. Uh,
just a quick notes in regards to the
caveman killer. Remember last week,
the serial killer thing,
uh,
using a sharpened stick as a
weapon and then burning it is a,
so there would be no evidence. Uh,
there's a bit of a problem here,
although it's genius and inventive
and inventive way to do it.
He would get caught. Um, when
the autopsy was performed,
they would come across the fibers, dirt
and residue left behind by said stick.
They would then do an analysis
on the residue to find out what,
what it was composed of and what type
of tree was used to make Swiss cheese of
the victim.
Now having that information,
the authorities would then plot out a
map of every single area within the state
or vicinity of the victim to narrowed
down where the stick could have come from.
They would then Jesus crisis as long.
They would then narrowed down that further
based on the composition of the dirt
in any traces of nutrients and figure
out exactly where the s what area the
stick came from.
A mass search would then take place
instead area and more likely they would be
able to pinpoint the spot where the earth
was disturbed or the branch that was
broken within a 24 to 48 window
concluding that this is the spot where the
weapon was obtained.
They would then probably find fibers
from the clothing of the perpetrator.
So they would match that.
Later after putting out a new
story with the evidence they had,
someone would come forward
saying they saw a car,
a person in their area that
seemed to be out of place,
sketchy sketch drawing
would be done and released.
The and the caveman killer
would be located in arrested.
Putting a nice tight bow on the case
would be their ability to match the dirt
from the spot where the weapon
was found in the, to the dirt,
found on the bottom of the shoes that
were in the garage of said caveman killer.
Further investigation in the vehicle
would find more traces of that dirt on the
floor mats from the shoes and on the seat
where the weapon was placed on the way
to the, uh, the offing. Sorry to say
Mister Cave, sorry to say Mister Caveman.
Game over.
Have Fun playing.
Hide the stick in prison over
the next 50 years to life.
Jesus Christ, he got to give it up
to that guy for breaking it down.
I know he's kind of a,
he was only semi-serious there.
He's talking about like those fucking
a and e murder things cause that's
literally how people get caught.
Like I saw one with this guy suffocated,
somebody with the,
with the trash bag and somehow they
figured it out that that's how they did it
and they were able to find the impression
of the woman's face in the bag.
It was one of the creepiest things ever.
And uh, but I got to tell you something,
you know,
I know you just half joking around,
but most of that shit's just
circumstantial evidence.
And if you don't have the weapon,
all you have is all that guys to say
what I like to go hiking in that area.
Yes, I hiked in that area. Yes,
my fibers were that, you know,
it's still all
circumstantial at that point.
If you have no priors
or anything like that,
that's a whole bunch of circumstantial
evidence. And I don't, you know,
if you get a good lawyer, you're going
to get off, you're going to get off. Um,
and I think that's it for the
Monday morning podcast this week.
Look at up to 54 minutes. It
happened again and I, you know, why?
Because the God damn fire trucks and I
didn't even get a chance to get to the
underrated overrated yet. Uh, but you
know, these things are really building up,
so I've got to blow through
these. Uh, okay. Overrated.
Driving fast.
Not many things make me angrier on the
road then when I'm driving 75 miles per
hour,
per hour and I'm getting tailgated
really is 75 not fucking fast enough.
Few people, you know,
something. I, you know, I,
that really annoys the shit out of me too.
Sometimes I'll bump it up to 80
and people are still riding my ass.
What the fuck? I can understand
and appreciate the need
to get somewhere quickly,
but is that,
that doesn't mean that wherever you need
to go is more important than my need to
arrive at my destination at one
fucking piece. Well that is true,
but you know something I got to argue for
the other guy here that if somebody is
riding your ass, you really should
get out of the way, you know? MMM.
I know. That's that whole guy
thing. Then he feel like a bitch,
you know?
So what do you got to do?
You've got to stop on the brakes
and be a fucking asshole. Um,
but really I got to admit though,
if you are doing 75 80 in the left lane,
somebody still riding
your ass. Uh, I dunno.
When you get a little older and more
relaxed, you don't give a fuck. You Do,
you do go over to the right
and like I do now and a path,
a one out of 40 times you do that,
you actually get to see the guy get a
speeding ticket a little further down the
road.
But the other 30 t nine times,
the other 39 times you feel like a bitch.
I got admit underrated, quiet time.
I remember when we used to have
quiet time in grade school.
I wish that was still around.
I work at a TV station and I
liked the guys I work with,
but sometimes I just need
everyone to shut the fuck up.
Do we have to be running our mouths
every goddamn second for the next eight
hours? Just sit there and do your
work for a bit. We'll talk later.
Jesus. You know what, dude? I
totally fucking relate to. Exactly.
Some people just don't like
fucking silence. You know,
they find it awkward and they
got to keep running their mouths.
Kind of like me for the last fucking
hour. Jesus Christ. All right.
Underrated TV show the
deadliest warrior on Spike TV.
Just look the shit up.
It pits two different warriors together
from different time errors and they see
who would win. Dude, that really
sounds like some nerdy fucking shit.
Isn't that like, who do you think
would win an alligator or a shark?
I don't know who either were
when Chewbacca or spark.
I don't get into that shit, but
you know what? God bless you sir.
There's people out there went to it. So
I guess, you know, go check it out. Uh,
real quick, uh, overrated women's
intuition. I've always heard educated,
intelligent women say that women's
intuition is always correct.
Sorry, you're wrong. If that were true,
why do women repeatedly date abusive?
Twisted guys?
Wouldn't their intuition
tell them that the guy,
what the guy is like yet another reason
of women patting themselves on the back
for no reason. All right,
sir. You know what?
Fuck that chick. Okay. Whoever
dumped you just fuck her man.
You know there's going to be
another good girl coming around.
Don't give into the bitterness.
Don't give into the bitterness
or maybe that's just from dating for
a while because there was a lot of,
there's a major part in me.
They really liked that email yet.
Another example of women patting
themselves on the back for no reason.
Jesus Christ. If that sentence doesn't
describe the Oprah Winfrey show,
I don't know. What does a great great
one. All right, here we go. Uh, in women,
if you're sitting there getting mad,
you can,
you can always fucking trash
guys cause I'll read them.
I'll definitely read them and I know
we deserve it. All right, number two,
Disney movies. Okay. I'm
35 years old now, but uh,
even as a kid,
I thought those a sugary shit.
Movies suck bloody balls.
All right dude.
Fucking wait and let me know how you
feel. Overrated. Interlocking lives.
Interlocking lives.
Movies like crash and fast food nation.
Get it. We're all connected.
This shit is getting old.
That movie crash was so fucking overrated.
So fucking,
and that's one of those movies
just cause it was about race.
People thought that it was saying
something. Uh, question number four,
the movie stir crazy. I love Richard
Pryor. He was one of the best ever.
But this movie is average.
His talent is pretty much
wasted on this film. Yeah,
I would have to say that. Is that the one
where they walk into the, into the jail,
you know, that's right.
Ah, we bad. We bed.
That's like the funniest part
of the movie and I dunno,
I would have to agree with you.
That's it though guys.
I'm actually coming up on a fucking hour
here. 59 minutes, 25 seconds. Listen,
that's the podcast.
You guys all have a great memorial day,
and I really should have made this one
short so you could actually enjoy your
memorial day, but you know what? You
got the whole week to listen to it.
And if you've listened to this on Tuesday,
that means you're back at
that fucking job you hate.
And I just killed an hour for you. So
God bless. All right. Have a great week.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible]
[inaudible].