Hey, what's going on? It's bill bird.
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday. Monday
morning podcast and, Huh?
Just checking in on.
Yeah,
just checking in to see how your week's
going and that type of shit. And uh,
you know,
we're doing this podcast.
It's usually just sold freckles
here talking by himself,
acting like a fucking maniac,
solving world problems by himself.
No one to debate it. So
it all makes sense. Um,
and every once in a while I have
a special guests, which I do.
I do have a special guest and my special
guests as promoted like a week ago,
whatever on my podcast is a
the one and only Dave Ilitch,
a drumming sensation,
teachers sensation,
human being sensation owner
of plenty of t shirts.
Dave, what's going on dude? Happy
to be here at brother. Yeah,
welcome to the podcast.
I told you before we started,
I made a major fuck up on my last podcast.
Yes.
I called the band the
specials. The smiths. Okay.
And oh boy. You know,
that is not good at all.
And that was going on and on about how
much I love this set and all that and I
fucked up and I want to
apologize to everybody that
actually met the lead singer
of the band and the guitarist and the
lead singer. That band, uh, said, uh,
he real quick, it was just like, oh,
I love the way you say the word cat.
You say it right. And I was just, and it
was like the greatest compliment ever.
Absolutely.
It's like when my buddy Joe to Rosa was
in Scotland in a bar at like four in the
morning. And some Scottish guy said too,
it was like, oh, you can fucking drink.
And he's just like,
it was like the greatest compliment ever.
So I got to apologize to
them. Okay. It's, it's,
it's my fault. The fucking music I
listened to in the 80s, you know,
I was into the fucking metal and all
these skater guys and everything up the
street. My brother hung out with, uh, you
know, stopped a mess and Oh, around ball.
And I'm like,
these guys aren't singing about the devil.
They're not wearing women's clothes.
I'm not listening to these guys. I mean,
I was, you know, I was very, I was
closed off back then, you know, so, um,
you know, so you saw
it, you saw it when I,
I've been taking lessons with you for
about what, a year and a half or so.
They can come in and Margaret and
all that man we get to right is,
it felt like 10
I went in there,
I came in there like the crypt keeper,
like I'll fucking
crunched over and shit, holding
the sticks, wrong forums,
everything all jacked up. And
I got to tell you like, um,
you're on here besides the fact
that you're a good friend of mine,
you're on here because you have a new,
uh,
a new drum instructional video route
called getting out of your own way. True.
Which I actually got to watch a lot of,
uh,
last night and it's all this stuff,
you know, that you've been teaching me,
which was I was basically
fighting the kit and yourself.
Yeah. I was like, yeah, it
was all crunched over. I was
holding the sticks wrong.
I was just playing uphill.
Nothing was at the right. And uh,
for the drummers out there
who listened to this podcast,
I cannot tell you like the stuff that
you showed me just getting me to sit up
straight, hold the sticks right
and have shit where I can hit it,
do to my body type.
Yeah.
It's made so much stuff that
used to be really difficult,
like borderline effortless now,
however,
I still suck because
at the end of the day,
no matter how much you
teach me to sit up straight,
I am still at the mercy of the talents
that I was blessed with. But um,
but I'm still,
you know,
yeah. But it's a whole different ball game
than when I first saw you man. I mean,
oh you work your ass off too.
It's like I can show you
show people how to do things,
but at the don't put in the work,
nothing's going to change. You know,
you work your ass off.
So
I'm a lunatic Dave. Yeah, I know.
I get into shit. That's my point.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
That's why I always stayed away from
hard drugs because I would have like,
I'd have like a fucking monogram
coke spoon. I would just be,
I would be a coke heads coke head.
I know if I did it. So I try to,
I try to send it into a positive areas.
So, uh, it's a good point.
Well, look, I gotta ask you,
I don't know if I've ever even talked
to this talk to you about this,
where it's just like,
so you grew up in northern California,
you said Hell or this Hella
Dad, I'm sure. Right? Yes.
I got made fun of a lot when I moved
to La Sacramento Kings Fan. Maybe
I didn't see the sharks
for hockey when I was,
oh fuck. I just realized, I
mean this fucking leather chair,
if this is gonna make a bunch of noise
when I'm moving around like that Benny
Hill sketch,
you'll see that one where he wore the
leather pants when the great sketches, no,
every time he had to deliver a line,
he would walk across the room and it was
just a sign of his leather pants and he
was sitting down crossing his legs and
then the other person would talk fucking
genius. I have to check it out.
Um, anyways. Um, so when you start,
what made you like want to play drums?
Like what got you started? What band?
Oh, what band? You know, I
don't know if there was a,
I mean I had a friend who was taking
drum lessons and I like slept over at his
house. I was like nine or
something. And he's like,
all my drum teachers coming over to
give me a lesson. And I was like, oh,
hang out and watch. And then I
was like, oh, this seems fun.
And then I sat down and I could just kind
of do it like it was you had that gift?
Yeah. It was like, oh, I
can kind of do this. And uh,
I'd never really had that experience
before, so I just immediately got hooked.
Uh,
and so I was like nine or 10.
So this is like 93 94.
Right. So this is like
God, I'm old when I was 25 and 26. Yeah,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
But this is like old dude.
But remember when we were sending
each other youtube clips about, uh,
um, I sent you that faith, no more clip
and you sent me the was a skid row.
Is that what it was? I don't remember.
Probably skewed. I love skid row.
It was that,
it was like SNL performances and yeah.
Oh my God.
Skid row on fucking SNL and it was like
the same year and it was like check out
the,
we were talking about the shift in music
like right around like 91 92 I think it
was.
And it was like how,
like right when grunge and all this
stuff was coming out and it was just like
hair metal to grunge was just like,
you were like, what the fuck they was.
It was abrupt. Yes. It was like a,
how a lot of divorces go down in la where
there's like the day after the prenup
expires, Bam, divorce papers. Thank,
that's the way the musical shift
was. But like as a kid, I was,
I at that point like, uh, what
year was that? When, when,
when think it was [inaudible]
91 [inaudible] 92 yeah. Yeah.
And that's good roll album. I
fucking love that album. Right.
And they were crushing. Crushing, yes.
Sebastian's voice was just like this one
of the great front men. Yes, absolutely.
Of all time.
And I had,
I didn't see that shift in music coming.
I think a way a lot of those bands didn't,
cause I remember when Nirvana came
out, I was like, what the fuck is this?
And I couldn't really even
hear how good a band they were.
And then that first video they had the
teen spirit when he was like doing like
uh, uh, basic solo and he was kind of
acting like he was doing the tap on Solo.
It was clearly making fun of all the guys
that I like. Totally. I was like, dude,
fuck these guys,
fuck this band.
And it wasn't until I saw
them on unplugged and I
got in Utero and everything
and I was just like, wow, this,
these guys are making like this is a
beautiful album night. And it took me,
but it took me like two and a half
years of of being like, wait a minute.
The 80s or over?
Yeah,
because I'm old now because you have
that shit juxtaposed right next to each
other and you're growing from spandex and
lipstick and straightened hair to like
flannel shirts and Glam thing
was only about three years. Okay.
It was right around 85,
86 everybody got the kick started dressing
like men again around 87 88 they had
a round table meeting and we're
like, look, stop blowing up the hair.
Let's go back to, let's try to get a limo,
Allman brothers here and a little less,
uh, grease, whatever the fuck
they were doing. But so yeah,
so that was the scene I was growing up
and when I started playing was what we're
talking about right now. So
you missed all, all this shit.
You would just, you know,
10 years old. I mean, I mean,
I definitely listened to a Shitload of
Phil Collins when I was like a little
Katie's Phil Collins or like, like the
later stuff that everyone makes fun of.
Well [inaudible] yeah,
I mean, you know, yeah.
I wasn't like listening
to that song specifically,
but like you're sure about that.
A little bearded 10 year old day dancing
around sue sue Tsuneo I did come out of
the wound with a beard by the way. Oh,
you did? Yeah. Just always been hearing.
It's what it is. That's why you went
to the drums. You were fucking animal.
That's true. I've heard that more than
once. Um, did you, uh, so then when, when,
when you, uh, when all
that grunge stuff came out,
was that just sort of music to you as
opposed to like being like all this is a
choice. You weren't old
enough to realize like, wow,
we just went from this to that? Not at
all. That's what I'm saying is like,
because that happened.
I remember listening to sir,
it's actually funny like
saying this, like, I listened
to it so much Phil Collins,
but I would hear like new wave stuff
or 80 stuff like tears for fears and be
like, oh, gross. And now I
love, love that stuff. Right.
But at the time it was like the
least cool shit ever. You know,
I went back to the eighties a
bunch of times going, oh wow,
this band was actually pretty
good. Yeah. Yeah. And it's,
and a lot of that stuff
is so like interesting and
esoteric and weird ways that
you check it out now.
And some of it's aged poorly,
but some of it's aged in
like a really cool way. Yeah.
I didn't like a lot of just the sound.
Yeah. Shit that came out in the 80s,
whatever that sound was,
I saw somebody sent me a video and you
know about how they came up with that,
that sound for the drums,
right.
That was the Phil Collins
[inaudible] sent me.
And that was just a complete accident
where there was a Mike on in this studio
and somebody played a Phil.
Yeah. And it was, yeah, it was,
it was in the control room or something
like that. Phil Collins was apparently,
there's various stories, but apparently
Phil Collins was playing drums on one,
a Peter Gabriel's solo albums and he
was trying out fills or whatever and
someone hit the talk back,
Mike. Uh, so if you, you know,
for people who haven't
recorded in a recording studio,
when you're in the control room,
you hit the talkback Mike and they,
you can then hear what the
person's saying, uh, or,
or if you're in the
studio or tracking drums,
you can't hear what anyone is
saying in the control room. Right.
So they have to hit a talk back Mike a
button so you can hear what's going on.
And basically they went to talk to Phil
and they hit the talk back Mike and he
played a drum fill over that and the,
the, the talkback might picked it.
I'm just got super blown out and
they were like, whoa, that was crazy.
It was like a complete accident.
And that's how that gated,
like Peter Gabriel was like, I liked
that sound. And then, which is probably,
I imagined a cool sound
initially and then it, it,
it was just overused and then,
and that's how everything happens now.
It's totally like in vogue again,
like everyone,
I mean it's sort of starting
to get overused now,
but it just went through a whole thing
over the past five years where that was
super hip again. Let's go on in my
business right now where they just, they,
I don't know what's they just rebooting
everything that I already watched that
just going the point through IMDP
to be like, is this guy still alive?
Do you think he wants to do a WHO's the
boss again and fucking now who's the
boss? Uh, I'm trying to think of
something more obscure than that. Um,
she's the sheriff. Is that a show that
wasn't show? Really no reason why.
I know that is because a friend of mine
was on it for a couple of episodes and
he said at one night and it was just like,
dude,
that's one of the great
fucking references. I don't
even know what that is.
That was a, uh, beautiful
woman who was on, um, Suzanne Somers.
Um, she started it and
evidently she was a sheriff.
She's the sheriff and she was just this
hottie who was the sheriff and everybody
had to listen to what
she did. It, you know,
I think it was for like people who were
into like dominatrix and like women tell
him that piece of shit and they're
under arrest. It was sort of something,
there was an underlying sexual thing.
Everything that was done back then,
you know, you can't do any of that now.
Now she'd be a fucking hero, you know,
whatever the fuck I,
whatever the, you know,
the pendulums completely
swung the other way now.
So every guy's a fucking taking his dick
out and peanut and on a plant blocking
a door. And women are all like fucking
Joan of arc. There's no middle ground,
there's no middle ground.
That's what it is.
We're going to go from not listening
to women to not vetting any of them and
then saying every fucking guy's a
complete piece of shit through some of the
shit that's coming. Like some of
these guys got friends of mine now.
It's like literally ex girlfriends
who are mad that they're famous now.
Totally just coming out, going like, oh,
lives get ruined. They're like, man,
I don't like you anymore if
I'm going to ruin your life.
I mean, well, the fact that
this, if, if, if there's gonna
be no due process, I mean,
who is safe? No one. It's crazy. Yeah.
I think it was emotionally abusive
and said, I haven't got it.
I've got emotionally abused and like
at least 85% of my relationships.
I spent the last fucking week in
my own fucking house on eggshells.
What? Back in a good place. But it's just
constantly, you know, emotional abuse.
I mean, women have the fucking
market cornered on that. This is,
this is a different podcast.
So anyways, that's a different
topic. So your, your, uh,
your, your, your, um, uh, instructional
videos. Yeah. You put it though,
first of all, you know, you're,
you're already ahead of 90% of people.
Just by the way it looks,
the quality of the way it's shot
because so much of it is just somebody,
you know, literally wearing
a Gopro, staring into a
mirror, why they play drums.
So you supposed to try to fucking
learn something out of that.
That's, well, that's exactly
why I made this thing. I mean,
I've been teaching for like
20 years and I work with,
you know, a lot of pros, a
lot of my contemporaries,
a lot of big name dudes who are out in
the real world touring with big bands. Um,
in addition to me touring and
recording and, um, I never, you know,
I always wanted to do
an instructional thing,
but with the way technology's evolved
with Instagram and youtube and everything,
like everyone's a quote unquote
teacher now. Yeah. So, um,
by the way,
there's,
so there's this inside thing that I
always see something and I think it's
fucking amazing. A drum thing and then I
send it to you and you're just like, eh.
You know what that reminds
me of is when I, you know,
it's when people come up to me
and then they just pick like some,
somebody super popular at the moment,
like, what do you think is so it's,
that person is really funny.
Huh? He got to be like, yeah.
I mean they're up there
talking and well Mike, yeah,
they're on stage doing things.
Yeah.
They're saying things that people
are really reacting with. Laughter.
You just have to say straight up facts.
Yeah, I know. I what I do, I just like,
I would never take down
another comment publicly,
but on the phone with my
friends or which it is,
we fucking eviscerate so many people and
then eventually it comes around to us
and then we just start trashing each
other and just laughing our ass off.
And then the end, everyone we trashed, we
just go, Hey God bless them. Bless them.
They're out there. That's what it's
all about. I do that same shit too.
I have text threads with friends
of mine where we do with the same,
same thing and were just as brutal to
work to each other and towards cells.
Do you know how many jokes
like back in the day when I,
when I was working in the comedy cellar
in New York, how many jokes I lost,
how many shirts I could never wear again.
And all of this cause we sit,
just sit there and like the guys used
to go down and they would watch you on
stage and they would be
staring at you with like the,
it would be Patrice rest his
soul. Oh Man. Uh, Voss Norton.
And they would just stand
in there in the doorway.
We could see and none of
the crowd could see him.
And you had to like totally commit
to your fucking act. Wow. And uh,
I remember Kevin Hart when
he first fucking came down
and he's like 20 years old
and they were doing that to him.
And I remember he didn't get rattled.
He did a little bit.
And then the first time and then he didn't
and we'll have to once he didn't get
rattled and I remember thinking like, wow
man, this kid is uh, he's got the force.
Wow. Yeah, because I was sitting there,
those guys were all my contemporary. Sure.
We were like 10 15 years older than
Kevin and these guys are my contemporary.
Then I could fall. I was like, Oh
God, they're going to stare at me.
And then you almost felt yucky.
Deliberately had to say something
to bomb or some shit like that.
So I don't know.
Do you guys ever do stuff like uh,
do you have a watch to go out and see,
see if like for a comedian to
watch a friend of yours bomb.
If not,
if it's like if the set means something,
but if they just stuck there and they
try a joke and they just eat shit,
it's one of the funniest things ever.
Like when you watch a
friend of yours play drums,
they go for a fill or something.
If they eat shit on it yet
it's totally different.
Just by the nature of what your doing.
So much of it is just throwing
shit against the wall and
seeing what sticks and
just being like, Hey, I
fucking try it like that.
I love Comedians and I respect
Canadians so much because you know,
I'll go around town and see you or other
builders go out one night and go to the
comedy store or something and someone
will walk up on stage with a slip.
I've seen you do this and a bunch of
other people like, oh yeah, just like, Oh,
I'm just working some shit out. Oh
yeah. You know, like subjects like Ah,
that didn't fucking work.
You know, and, and like that,
you can't do that with music.
Like people were there to see a show
and they botch something. It's like you,
you want to put up a bit about
the, uh, the jam section.
Isn't that what you guys call it?
When you look at each other then
you just wait and like there are,
there are like this, there's not a
different musical situations with this.
There's some bands go out like we're
planning exactly like the record. Sure.
And then there's other people, like if
we play it like the record one more time,
I'm going to blow my brains
out. Can we? Yeah, absolutely.
And there's certain situations where
you can jam and improvise and uh,
you know,
like I would do that
with the Mars Volta or like,
or like anti mass.
There would be certain sections or are
we just go way out into outer space for
half an hour. What was that like
when, when you got that Gig and,
and you had to follow?
It was crazy.
All of those amazing drummers
that were in the band,
all this shit that they came up with
and didn't even have some like something
ridiculously,
uh,
a short amount of time they have
to learn it and all that. Um,
basically,
uh,
I got the call to do it.
And um,
and Juan,
the bass player who,
who used to play bass in racer
x, by the way, for the last,
I heard of the band. I don't
know who they are. Okay.
I'm sure I'll fuck up their
name on the next podcast.
We'll talk about eighties in
spandex and feathered hair.
They're pretty deep into that scene.
But yeah,
so Juan came over to my studio
with a fellow Bass player.
This Guy Jonathan Hirschi,
really good buddy of mine now.
And John came over just
to watch me like so,
so Juan came over and we plugged in my
iPod and he's like, do you know this song?
You know? And I'm like, I don't know.
I've never played along to this stuff.
I just kind of like the first record.
So one's playing with me and John's just
sitting there like two feet in front of
me just staring at me, watching
me like, and then Jesus Christ.
Yeah, I know it's stressful and a, and I
never played the music. I was just like,
I kinda know this thing. Or you
know, just from being a fan of that.
What sort of prep did you do before then?
Nothing. It was like, Hey, I'm lying.
I'm in line at Starbucks when he called
me and then I had to go to a recording
session all day.
And then I was like,
I can meet you after I'm done with this
session at night. And then he was like,
okay. And like, you know what I mean?
How bad did you need that Mars Volta
Gig at that point, your career?
Was that something that was huge? Yeah,
it really put me on the map. I mean,
because of the lineage of dudes that
were in that band and how like the
reputation that band has. Um, I
mean I had done things before that,
but nothing of that level,
you know, so, um, it was huge.
So I had about two weeks,
you know,
to learn the music and it was a two
and a half hour set. Uh, you know?
Yeah. And what did you do? Shut it out.
Yeah, I charted everything out. Um,
how long does it take you to and when,
when like how true to the original,
like John Theater was shit. Well, yeah.
Well I'd love, I'd love John's playing.
I think he's amazing and I
think his parts are incredible.
I think that first record
is really a masterpiece.
So I wanted to do everything that I
could in the time that I had to play
everything. Note for note. Cause I
think that's really important with that.
It's like, it's like what situation
we're talking about earlier.
Like people go to see those songs off
that first record and they want it exactly
right.
Like I would want to see that.
So I went out of my way to get everything
totally note for note, which, you know,
it was easier and more difficult in
some certain circumstances. But, um,
there were other, you know, other songs
where it wasn't really important as much.
Um, so two and a half weeks
to get it together and, and,
and like how often were
you jamming with the band?
I didn't meet the band until I got to
Amsterdam and then we, I mean me and Omar,
the guitar player and won like got the
three of us jammed a little bit. Uh,
I went down to Mexico and the three of
us played through the arrangements and it
was like, he was like, yeah,
this is one. I was like, this
is fine. Like, you're fine.
But then I went to Amsterdam. How much
of a relief was it to hear that? Well,
we rehearsed everything without vocals,
which is difficult because I used vocals
to like sort of know where I am in the
song a lot.
Oh yeah, I've made that
mistake, I've done that.
So he was like,
dude,
you know, you don't even need to be
here. This is fine. It's all good.
And I was like, okay, great, but you're
still like freaking out, you know. So, uh,
I get to Amsterdam, meet the rest of
the band, then we run through the set.
And this is kind of funny cause I,
I wrote out all my charts
and I put an extra floor,
Tom on my left and like a crash cymbal
on my left, the left of the high hat.
And I just put my charts on the floor,
Tom, like hoping like no one would see,
you know.
Right.
And I get up halfway through and to
go to the bathroom and I came back,
it was all gone. Oh,
somebody took it. Yeah.
And I like look over it one and he's
like, dude, you don't need that shit.
You're good. And I was like, okay.
And then everything was fine.
We ran through the rent or the two and
a half hours because there's a lot of
visual cues I was going to sink. But
if, if they liked that, yeah. If,
if they,
if you went there and they weren't
during the first rehearsal wanting it,
note for note, that must
have been something a little
bit easier where it's like,
okay, these guys aren't going to
be like Nazis about this and this,
this going to be room for me to kind of,
yeah. Pull based on the situation based
on sort of where they were coming,
the situation they were coming out
of there were so like exhausted.
Um, so there were just
like, you know, this is,
this sounds like they were basically like,
we sound like a band again and it
sounds like a record. Oh, cool.
Which is great because I was did that
first gig. Yeah. What was, uh, that was,
um, it was in Oslo. Um, I love that.
Then those people, a great comedy fence.
Oh my God. I, some of my fucking lunatic,
some of my all time best friends are
from, are from Oslo. So many of them. Uh,
and so many amazing musicians
from there. It's insane. My first
really good show I ever had in
Europe was in Oslow. Really?
I don't know if it was them or
I just found it was just like,
just cause I was too much in my head.
[inaudible] and other places
like I'm in a different country.
Are they going to get this right?
I'm talking about shirts.
Do they have shirts yesterday dude,
they are wearing shirts. Oh Shit,
my timing is completely up. And I was
so fucking fed up with mediocre sets.
I think that when I was in
Oslo I just didn't give a fuck.
And then they were also
like picked up on it. No,
they were kind of maniacs where
they would like drinking and shit.
It's just like, ah, these are the
kinds of people I hang out with. Right.
And then just Kinda,
I felt comfortable and uh,
and then the rest of the tour.
And then I wanted to Stockholm
and all that and it just,
everything else I've just sort
of fell into place and saying,
oh just act like you're here, which
I've got here in Oslo. No, no, no.
Act like I'm in America. Oh Oh, oh Gotcha.
Cause then even if they don't get it,
you get to play the
arrogant American of like,
oh you should know everything about my
country and I should know nothing about
chores. And they almost want
you to say that cause you,
you feed into their stereotype of like,
yes they are self-involved conch and we're
better than they are and they love it.
Um,
I jumped around a lot.
No, that's okay. I get it. It's not like
I've never listened to this before. Yeah.
It's a shit show. So
yeah. So that first show,
yeah man, I was insanely
nervous. Um, but it went fine.
And then as soon as I was like halfway
through the show, I remember I was like,
yeah,
I'm feeling good luck.
I'm going to try and like put on a
little bit of a show here. Like visually.
Right.
Cause that's always very important to me.
Like there's nothing more boring than
seeing someone just up there just like
looking like they're doing their taxes.
That's me. That's how I look. Not Anymore.
A little bit better, but holy Shit. Oh we
got to talk about videotaping yourself.
Well, playing drums, which you
made me do and Oh my God. Yeah.
My self esteem has never been lower.
I've never looked worse doing anything
ever. Even my early standup tapes,
which I have on Vhs, which
I can't even watch. I don't
look as bad. Yeah. Cause you
word slouching. You know like, but you
won't. So you don't slide this, you know,
you don't slouch when you,
when you walk around and when you,
when you do stand up,
it's when you sit down.
No, but actually, you know
something, my posture is,
my posture I've learned from my shoulder
being fucked up is all my weight is on
my knees. And I've noticed a lot of
people do this. When they stand up,
they actually their,
their um,
their hips are forward and you're sort
of leaning back like standing like this
and what you're actually supposed to do.
You like to stand up totally
straight like this. Okay.
I feel like I'm puffing my chest out.
Acting like you like you want
to fucking fight. Yes. Uh,
especially coming from where I grew
up in such an angry crazy state isn't
outside of Boston.
Forget about Boston itself.
I was in the suburbs and
that shit was fucking nuts.
Stand up straight and then your knees
are just slightly bent and your arms had
just hanging down and your
shoulders are a little, you know,
I feel like their back but they're
not, that just lines up. Exactly.
This is what I have to
like learn how to do.
But this is exactly what I've said
to you and what I say to everyone,
especially all these big, big name working
pros is it's like if you're slouching,
that's your sort of normal goto setting
and you think that that's you sitting up
straight. Right. So that when you
sit up straight or stand up straight,
it feels like you're
puffing your chest out.
Cause that's that cognitive disconnect.
So he has to rewire everything.
So it's much more accurate.
So that's, that's the thing,
when I work on all this technique,
body mechanics stuff with people,
like that's why I tell them to videotape
themselves because you can't tell what
you actually look like. It's
brutal. It's brutal for everyone.
It's brutal for everyone, including
me. It's never, it never gets easier.
So when I started to talk about it,
yeah.
So when you were,
you started playing drums and everything,
I imagine you just sat down and grabbed
the sticks the way any other kid would
have. Like when did you start to
break down what you were doing?
Did you get hurt or did you just see a
video of some guy where he made it look
effortless?
Good question.
Uh,
I think when I started getting really
serious when I was like 14 or 15,
it was a matter of me
just constantly going,
how lazy can I possibly be?
Like,
how can I play all the stuff I
want to play and just be as like,
how, like how much, how can I continually
just make this easier on myself? Like,
why would I do this if I
could just do that instead?
Why do you think he thought that? I
don't know. Maybe I'm just lazy. No,
I was going to say that, but you're
not, you're, you're a driven guy. Sure.
I think I've just became obsessed
with like efficiency. Um,
not like for the sake of it in
and of itself, but to be like,
I can play in more or say more or do more,
the more efficient I am,
there's more I can do. It's more, I
can say the more it can emote that way.
Maybe it comes from, you
know, my dad collects cars.
Maybe it comes from growing up in that
culture of like talking about, you know,
how, you know, a difference between like
a Hemi and a wedge. Right. You know,
like the different having dual sparkplugs
versus single, like, I don't know.
I mean maybe it all sort
of mashed up together. Um,
I think it just,
I w you know,
if I wanted to play everything and
I realized from a young age probably
subconsciously like I need to
be as efficient as possible
so I'm not getting in
my own way so I can play this
stuff. I want to play. You know,
it's like the first time you heard
becoming, you know that Penn terra song,
first time I heard it I had to put
it on a cassette tape and put it in a
handheld recorder and slow the speed down.
Right.
I remember standing in my mom's kitchen
putting it up to my pump up to my ear,
slowing the speed down,
going what the fuck is going on right now?
Like having no clue how he could
possibly do that physically and then just
sitting there and breaking it down
and going, well that wouldn't work.
I still feel that way about a lot
of this stuff. Which by the way,
way man, you got to give a shout
out to Vinny. Good Lord Man.
That I was literally talking
about it texting with you.
Yup.
Cause talking on the phone.
Yeah. And I was just going like,
why is this guy so fucking good in,
in like two hours later you
sent me the texts that he had
passed away. Man, it's fucking
brutal. I know, man. I was really,
I haven't been that bummed out or I
haven't been like affected that much by
someone's death. Like who? I, I hadn't
really know him. I met him once, you know,
but I mean he was a real hero of mine and,
and to a lot of people,
uh, and he just had such a commitment
to an a very specific aesthetic.
Like he's like, this is the sound,
this is the feel, this is the vibe.
And like I'm 100% committed.
Like,
and the fact that they were doing,
when all the shit that I was talking
about that I was listening to that's just
face planted and then all this grunge
came out and they were just like, Nah,
we're going to keep doing this.
That's a great southern train kill. That's
the records of bow. As them being like,
fuck all these trends.
Like fuck this crunch shit.
Like we're going to stay true to our
metal roots and just keep doing this,
you know,
and like all that on that live record,
that live hundred and one proof
record like I love that dude.
Fill in some holes in between
Song Banter is incredible.
There's your for all your spoken pretty
blown after show recording for control.
Normal Ward Faulconer Obama nerve
ball shoot. I always love it.
That's pretty before can log in American
Harget Larry to strop from Auschwitz.
It's just like all this shit that you,
if you set it now you'd be my favorite
thing and I always talk about on this is
when he,
when when Vinny counts off broken.
It's like in the middle of Phil talking
like why are strong or knowledge called
on broker and I'm a look in the excess.
Yeah. The I'm having a good job.
That time is already playing and
it was just like, did they do that?
Cause that was fucking cool. Always
Vinnie. Like Oh God, shut up.
I want to drink.
I think it was part of it.
Yeah. I think he was probably just like,
fucking here we go. You know, like,
I love that.
That's such a great moment in that
record because you can tell they're just
fucking having fun dude.
And that's why that shit,
that's part of the reason why that shit
feels like never went to
go see them because I heard
the music and I had an idea
in my head what the crowd
was going to be like.
I'm going to get the shit
kicked out of me at this thing.
But that's one of the funny things.
I was just talking to a buddy of mine,
Jamie, who I've been giving
Skype lessons to in London.
It's an every week for years.
And he was telling me he went to
see the Bronx the other recently,
it's like, you know, pretty heavy
like punk rock band. And he said like,
he brought his wife and she was like,
they left.
They had a great time at the
show and like everyone, you know,
someone falls down in the pit,
someone picks him up.
Like everyone's looking out for
each other. And he said like,
they left the show and his wife was like,
or he said, I forget. They were like,
we felt more unsafe walking the streets.
Then you did it at the show,
like with all these dudes beating
the shit out of each other. Yeah.
It just sounded like when
I listened to their music,
this a bunch of guys that
were mad at their dad,
we're going to show up and then they were
going to take the childhood out on me.
I just, you know, and I had fucking
orange hair and it was just like,
I just didn't think it was going
to end well. So it's just like,
but that is one of my big
regrets that I didn't,
there was a number of those bands that
I didn't go out and go see because I was
just like, dude, I love this
music, but I'm going to go,
I'm going to get the fucking shit
kicked out of me. And you know,
I was also in my fucking,
my stupid single Bass
Drum Barnum d dope pedal.
The music didn't require it, Bill, I don't
care. He could do more with one foot.
Did this guy just saying all this shit
that other people and just completely
ignoring the, this entirely new, uh,
type of drumming and in all of these
pioneers who were just, it was like,
there was no roadmap on what to do
when I was listening to all these other
fucking guys who were just saying shit
that had already been said. And like,
and if basically if you could have
a foot is fastest bottom right,
then you were bought them. Something
like that mean it this way. My head was,
this is what I love doing when we're
doing lessons together and just shooting
the shit or whatever is,
is,
is that massive amount of carry over
between drumming and standup comedy.
I mean, it's huge. And that's
what's so fun about it. Difference.
It's the exact same fucking
thing of like, you know, uh,
the difference between a guy who change
comedy versus a guy who's just sort of,
you know,
doing comedy or if you're on stage,
like just reciting your act versus being
up there and having an idea and the
crowd reacts one way, which actually
affects how the show goes. And everything.
And um,
I used to be so envious of musicians that
could just sit down and play what they
could feel or react to
what another musician did.
And I just did not have that ability.
So when I got into stand up,
I remember like stand up. I had the same
feeling you had like when you got down,
when you sat it at a kid. When I first
time I remember when I went to a,
it was my second show is at
this place stitches comedy club,
which no longer exists.
And um,
I went in there for this open mic and I
remember just walking into all of these
open makers up at the bar,
all in different levels.
And I just remembered feeling like,
like, like for the first time,
like I was with a demographic of
people that like, I, I didn't know,
I was just like, yeah, these guys are
the same kind of fucking weird that I am,
this,
these Weirdos feel normal to me.
And it was the first time when
I went to stand up, you know,
even though I obviously had to learn
from all these people, there was, I,
I had like this feeling of, I know I
don't really know exactly where I'm going,
but I kind of know where I'm going.
Like I know that I,
I just have to do this a bunch of times
and what I feel in me is t his is like
that this is the right thing is
going to kind of come out. And uh,
so when I am in the, I'm trying to
think, one of the first guys I ever saw,
just a winger set.
I saw this Guy Frank Santa Rally and he
went up there and knowing what I know
now about comedy,
I think it was because the host brought
them up and they were playing this weird
music and she started doing this dump
dance and he did it with her and he had
this totally serious look on his face.
He was already killing before we
even took the mic and the mic stand.
But I think that little improv exercise
opened him up and he just went up there
and it was like he was just fucking
talking and I'd seen his act a bunch of
times and a then I remember thinking like,
oh he should be,
should do that again.
He should do like
everything was so precious.
She got to hang on to every
Friday thing you ever said.
And it wasn't like listen
to the musicians were the,
that whole those types of bands
where it's just like, yeah,
just how the song came out that night.
That was the mood we were in.
And I remember trying like
I tried to apply that.
Yeah.
Cause it's the exact same thing I have
people say it's still hard at what you do
cause you wake up when you're a baby
mama. Dot. Dot. You were already playing.
You're already talking.
I'm just talking into a microphone.
I have to learn how to speak.
Yeah, but use through sounds. Yeah,
but putting an instrument but you
being able to stand up and wing a set.
You have to be just funny. Inherently
funny. Obviously it takes work,
but you have to be a funny person to be
able to do that as opposed to someone
who has, all you do is when
it, if it doesn't work, you
just make fun of yourself.
It's the, it's the, it's like
literally, you know, if he can't dance,
you just learn a little two step and let
the woman do all the fucking work and
sane, it's over. It's the same fucking
thing. But go up there, you wing an idea.
If it doesn't either just make fun of
yourself or you blame the crowd. Yeah.
But that's like he's saying like, Oh yeah,
when I go to do a drum solo, it's like,
yeah, just kind of played the
Tom's a little bit and then
the symbol. No, it isn't.
That's what I'm saying. It isn't. Yeah.
So I'm saying the same thing to you.
It's not, it's not that
easy. Like, I mean, but that,
that, you know, I have, uh, you know, to,
to I teach who are like mainly Torin
guys put with like pop acts or whatever.
They're like, I can sit down
and play the shit out of a show,
like from start to finish nail everything.
But if I sit down and someone's like,
Hey, play a little bit like I
don't know what the fuck to do.
Like I can't just play by myself and
that's the same also type of a thing.
Someone has a routine or
bits of show put together,
they could kill it but then if they just
walk up and talk to somebody heckles
him and fucks up there.
Yeah,
I guess that's the exactly
the same in music and comedy.
Someone throws a fucking beer
bottle at you or whatever.
Yeah. People throw shit at you
guys. That does not happen.
I mean I've had shit thrown at me but
like usually to serve this you guys would
just be up there singing and for some
reason somebody just wants to throw a
bottle.
I don't know why.
In a lot of times it's like the band
is like the crowd is enjoying the show.
It's like they just want to connect with
you less. I hit him with the bottle,
like the plastic water
bottle I was drinking at my
fingerprints are on it and it
touched him. So, and then he
yelled at me. It was epic.
People are crazy. What, um,
what's the most fucked up
thing you ever saw in a show?
Cause you're the drummer, you
get to see that he'd be, he sad,
your lead singer go to crowd surf and
just sort of disappear in the crowd and
the people can't find them and you
guys are looking at each other like,
how are we going to end this song?
You know, one of the most brutal
things I ever saw, it was,
I wasn't involved. I was
just a spectator. But um,
I was seeing,
I think it was with some,
it was some Mike Patton band who's he
look Melvin's or Fanta Moss or he's in
that dead crust now, right? Yeah. I got
to see them in Bartow. Yeah. Yeah. Um,
I can't remember who it was. Um, anyway,
they brought up like a jelaby off road
to like sing a song and he went to go
like, this is maybe five, 10 years ago.
And he went to go like state
like stage dive or whatever.
And it's the first step he took.
He said that on some girl's face.
Oh No. Then just ate shit
like, like family guy fall,
how it's like one frame and then
your arms are behind your back. Oh
Shit.
And it was just like,
took him like 10 minutes to get back
on stage and it was just like, oh,
what is the band doing where they
just blank kept playing and you know,
it was just like, oh God.
Brutal. So what do you do?
Does the guitar player play a
Solo? Like how do you eat? I mean,
I think they just kept, you
know, patent was up there.
I think they just kept like going,
you know,
and he eventually made his way back on
stage or whatever, but it was just like,
boom. It was like, whoa.
Oh yeah. Um, I mean,
maybe you like for me playing,
there's a drum cam video on, on,
on Youtube. I think it's the first thing
you saw of me. The, the volt, the Goliath.
Oh yeah. And I didn't understand
your technique. I'm like,
this guy's fucking arms are
going to fall off. Yeah, yeah.
Cause I was going ape shit and go
nuts and hitting super hard and um,
or it looks like it's hitting hard.
Um,
and one thing Cedric he used to love to
do is he would just like take my crash
cymbals away from me.
Like,
so there's a part in that video
where he just takes my crash, uh,
and I only have two. So he takes
my crash and then like, you know,
like basically just jumps on it,
uh,
and like throws it up and down and then
takes the symbol often stomps on it,
and then takes the cymbal stand and
throws it over my head and almost hit it,
takes out the camera. And
I'm like, this is the,
this was the first time he'd
ever done this. So like,
did you know that he did shit? Like, no,
no, I mean, not really. I don't think so.
Did you think it was
because of your playing? No,
he was just like rock and rock and roll,
you know,
like my fucking self esteem.
It'd be like, he hates me,
I'm getting fired and then it'd
be getting mad at me like, dude,
a fucking trash my shit. Well, I
did get mad eventually. Um, uh,
and my company was like, what
the fuck? Um, but anyway, yeah,
cause he had to keep sending you shit.
Yeah. They were like, Shit, what the fuck?
We send you symbols to play knock to get
broken by the lead singer, you know? So,
uh, so yeah, this is the
first time he ever did it.
So you can see me like turning
around to my tech, like,
hey fucking give me another symbol and a
stand, like, come on dude. Like, and a,
and he's like, hold on a sec. You know,
and then, uh, and then he was just like,
I got to make sure and wait
until he's actually done.
I don't know how far he's going
to take this. Oh yeah, yeah, no,
they wait until he's out of that mood.
Yeah. And then he eventually, you know,
eventually brought another one
up and it was fine. But like, uh,
well not to get into the gossip, we, you
able to just kind of sit there and say,
hey buddy, I love being in the band man,
but I need my sympathy. I mean, it was,
I got to a certain point where I was
like, dude, like really? You know, like,
come on, cause he actually
plays drums too. I was like,
you know, you know how much,
you know, annoying that that would be
right. You know, he's like, Oh shit. Yeah,
you're right. Sorry man. Let's get
carried away. You know, I used to,
when I was five,
eight,
if I ever saw that on TV or if
I was in the crowd or whatever,
when I was a kid and I was
playing drums and everything,
I used to just be a tech to just give
it to me. Right, right. I need a simple,
totally need to sit there and
just break it in front of me.
It's just like I would have
loved to have had that. Yup.
Like when I ever watched like the
WHO or whatever. Yeah. And you know,
it's funny cause I don't know if they just
had like some piece of shit, you know,
the Japanese version of
the lesser or whatever.
Or if it was an actual one eat now,
like all those vintage instruments,
how much they're worth. Like I Pete
towns in his probably, you know, no,
my God,
probably seven figures and guitars.
Oh, at least. Yeah. Yeah. My Buddy,
my buddy Jerry plays with Dick Dale, you
know, and uh, he brings out this like,
I don't know what it is if it's like
an explorer or a Les Paul or something,
but it's like from the 50s and his amp
has also from the 50s and it's like that
shit's worth several hundred thousand
dollars and he tours with it.
It's crazy.
Well, yeah. And, and he's the guy
who did, who's to plays or frock,
but he plays like, Oh, right
handed guitar, lefty upside down.
It doesn't change the strings.
That sounds right to me. Yeah. He does
something super fucked up and weird. Yeah.
That's all that, that pulp fiction
song. Yup. That's it. Yeah. Okay.
Well where can people get this video?
They can go to my website,
[inaudible] dot com spell your name.
We're dumb dumb over here. L I, T,
c h, Dave [inaudible] dot com. And you
can just click on instructional course.
It'll pop up there and you
can get everything there.
It's just streaming and uh,
you know,
everybody does these sort of subscription
based courses now and then they just
take your money forever. Then I didn't
want to do that, so I'm like, you know,
you just pay for it once you stream
it forever, as long as you want.
I'm not going to charge your credit
card for seven years and you know,
like I don't want to do that. So, uh,
I've had a couple of those and
then you forget you have exactly.
Somebody is looking at your stuff going
like, dude, what the fuck is this dude?
I haven't tell you. I had, I had a
cell phone number for like 15 years.
Never used. Are you serious? Yeah. Like,
I was bitching to my wife
going like, uh, is that mine?
Oh, Siri, you know,
worse. Um, I was paying,
just seemed like a ton of money.
All of a sudden for my cell phone.
It just kept going up and up and up. I
said, I don't understand why I'm paying.
Why am I paying so much more than fuck?
It was going up to like fucking three,
400 bucks. Right. So she goes, let me
see it. And she looked at it. She goes,
all right, first of all, I think I had
three cell phone numbers. Why? Yeah,
she's looking at me. Yeah. Like,
like I got like fucking chicks on the
side and I'm like, no, I don't know.
We looked at up, all right, here's
what it was back in the day. Um,
when you were on the road,
you know,
you'd bring you your fucking
big thick laptop or whatever.
And all these hotel rooms were
charging anywhere from seven, 10,
$11 a day for the Internet.
So I went and I was working
places Tuesday through Sunday,
so it was like six times, you
know, 10, 11 bucks. It was like,
man with the tax has cost me
like $70 to be on the Internet.
So, uh, my buddy Robert
Kelly, right? He's like, dude,
you want to do a Gig?
He knows all the fucking technology goes.
Did you get the fucking, it's,
this was his hotspot thing.
So it had its own number.
You plugged it in to your computer
and blah, blah blah. Right.
So I tried to use it twice and it never
worked. Now says he's fucking digs,
never fucking work.
And I knew in the back of my head it's
like I gotta call these guys up and
cancel it or whatever. And I just, I just
never did. And I just forgot about it. Oh,
recently I actually founded, I still
have the thing. So that was one of them.
I forget what the other one was, but it
was like two things that were of that.
One was like a fax machine
number and the other one's like,
like all this outdated shit. So
she got, she got that taken off.
And then I think one time when I left
the country I switched my plan and they
didn't quite switch it back or something.
So now,
now it's down to like a buck 80 a month.
It was your,
was your mobile hotspot like the
size of this fridge? No, you know,
it was the size of a hockey puck.
I mean it was big,
was a big plastic thing and you just
had a, and you had to come up with a,
all this stuff that trips me up,
you know,
you got to come up with a password
and just like, oh, just a couple, two,
three of those hoops that I have to
jump through. But yeah, that's too much.
But I've been working on lately
though. Um, I remember seeing,
maybe I was watching one of the
interviews you did or whatever you said,
how you think everyone should have a
therapist if you just talk to somebody,
the world be a better place. Well, um,
I haven't gone to therapy
and like I finally, at one
point I was just going like,
dude, I'm always going to be fucked
up. I mean, I can sit here like, well,
I'm done talking about my childhood,
so I'm just going to be talking about
the dumb shit that happens every day.
I'm like, it was, it was Phil
started feeling a reality show,
but one on one reality show. But, um,
recently I've been really been working
on my not snapping over little things.
Uh,
and I,
I started to snap this morning for the
first time in like four days and it
actually felt a little
weird, but, um, I want,
I'm just gonna keep trying to do what I'm
doing with it and I keep talking about
it and loud, so I remember it
because, you know, it's like, Hey,
I'm going to go to the gym, you know,
and then that week you fucking crush it.
Next week you three quarters, he crushed
it. By a month later you've eating Oreos.
Sit on a couch. So what do
you, so what are you doing?
Like you just like breathe deeply years.
Like when you say Aye,
well, big thing is driving. Sure.
So when I get in the fucking car,
I just say like, uh, first of all, I
leave enough fucking time to get there.
I don't leave the utopia time.
This should take a half hour. Nope.
How dare these other people in front
of me have other plans in other lives.
So I leave plenty of time and then I,
it's just weird.
I drive slow, slow early. I'm probably
driving somebody nuts behind me.
I drive slower. I stop at yellow
lights. I let people go. I,
I chill out. I actually, uh, is another
thing. I swear to God, this is like,
they use this for premature ejaculation.
I'm actually using this.
I've listened to baseball.
He's day think I'll think about baseball.
I never understood that be,
if you don't want to fucking bus the nut.
I started thinking a fucking Carl
Yastrzemski now fucking get a hard dick
thinking about the fucking left field
or the red sox. And it's just confusing.
It's like, wait, am I
attracted to this guy? Um,
I just didn't feel like you were
present. Uh, sorry, I was busy.
I was thinking about fucking a
Jerry Remy. No, I put on like,
there's something about
smoking a cigar and listening,
listening to baseball on a radio.
It's like some old man shit and it's
slows life down. I don't know what it is.
So I uh,
I just have it on and they just have
a wonderful day for a ball game, man.
It's just crazy. The lineups, blah
blah blah blah blah. You know,
he's just extending is bratty of Aa
and you just sort of drift along.
And I just, and I just know and I
just, I don't have a hate saying this,
but you know that people always say like,
you know,
you got to give up like
expectations and shit. First of all,
I also like googled how to stop snapping
over little things in the first thing I
clicked on was this woman going,
did you ever hand is you have a blunt
in to say everything that I've done?
Like yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. So she goes,
here's four techniques and I'm reading
this shit and I am like five minutes into
reading this and before she says,
you know,
I've been doing this for like
a week and I'm like, what?
Literally started snapping.
Like you don't change in
a week. Okay, this is,
this is going to take me. I just turned
50 this will take, if I work my ass off,
this will take all of my fifties
to not to not do that.
That's why I was joking
with a buddy of mine,
why one of the most realest characters
ever in any movie was was private hawks
in police academy.
Remember she was always held mousy.
That black girl hang and then
the end she'd be like, no.
And I remember joking, you know every
movie she'd go back to being mousy again.
She had the exact same character arc and
it's just like when does she, you know,
in reality is is that's what it's like
to try to change yourself as a person,
as you have, you know, fucking up,
fuck it up it up for 90 minutes
and then whatever or whatever.
How much time the move goes by in the
movie and then you had that breakthrough
moment and you don't move dirt bag and
then the next day you know you're going
to fall back again or maybe two days
later or whatever. So yeah, but that's,
that's the, but when you, you know,
if you continued to do that work on
yourself where you fall back isn't as far
down the ladder as you were
before. You know what I'm
saying? Yeah, no, no, I, yeah,
believe me dude,
like I'm,
I am committed to this because it's going
to make my relationship with my wife
so much better. I'm telling you, dude,
if I could just stop snapping at
little shit, dude, she's got nothing.
He's got a real motivation.
She's got nothing. No,
because what I'm still doing,
this is something else that I'm going to,
I'm starting to let go of is the way
when you were in a relationship with a
woman,
like thinking the way a guy thinks you
think I'm going to do this and then it's
to then it's den.
She's going to be happy with me and
she'll be in a good mood and then I'll,
the egg shells go away. Right.
And what you realize is that,
that that's yeah, you're chasing a
a, that it's like a Ponzi scheme.
Like there's, there's no meaning having
expectations for your actions is, ah,
no,
I just like,
okay,
I'm just always going to win.
Neuer inherently just because I'm a man
and I'm not going to see things the way
she does because she's a woman
and touching that and what,
what she views as important
versus what I view as,
or she views is not a big deal. And I
think is a big deal is not going to Mesh.
Not because she's a bad
person or I'm a bad person,
it's just because we are
wired differently. And uh,
so I forget something happened
just this morning and I started to
get upset and I was just like, well,
why would I think that she would blah,
blah, blah. And it just fucking went away.
That's great.
So I kicked,
but I'm afraid of this because now I'm
filling in which to become this spineless
guy or hell, you know, sitting
there holding her purse.
You know what I talk about
the same shit I have with my,
with my therapist a bunch of times.
Uh,
because coming with not even necessarily
talking about that specific thing as a
human being,
but talking about that specific thing as
being the source of your creativity in
some way. Yeah. You know what I mean? Like
now there's, there, there is a thing
with comedians. What's a, if I get happy,
I won't be fun anymore.
Which is what musicians too.
It's a huge myth because I'll
tell you why. What happens is,
is like once you get everything
you want, you know, as far as like,
you found love and you have the kid and
your kid comes home is going. Dot, dot,
dot, dot. Big Smile students. The fucking
greatest, greatest fucking thing ever.
It's one of the few things in the
world that lives up to the hype, right?
Other than downloading your
fucking video, boom, Bam.
Cross promoting. Um, what uh,
what replaces all your angsty Lolita is
sort of sleeping on a futon and shit.
Is this new fear of that you're
now going to lose it all?
Like what if something happens?
Like I can't tell you since having a kid,
like any new scenario like, hey, I'm
going to go take her on the swing.
Like immediately this horror movie
that Steven King could not fuck with.
Oh, maybe that maybe he has kids
or something. That's how he writes.
But like the shit that goes through
your head about the possible stuff that
would happen. And always in the end I'm
either murdering a person or an animal,
one or the other.
Dude,
I've actually had fantasies of jumping
down on a cougars back in somehow I know
that UFC move where your choke it out
and I wrapped my legs around its belly so
it can't claw me.
And I sit there while I'm
eating a sandwich thinking
of all of this because my
wife said that she's going to like
just take her out in the backyard,
um, turns into a Joe Rogan episode. Yeah.
Yeah. So all of that. And then
like those fucking crazy thoughts,
we'll then we'll then fuel your,
um, your act hopefully. So. Um,
and he goes, well, I have to, I got to
read a little bit of advertising. Okay,
you want to see some comedy
here? Um, once again,
my apologies to the Special Smith.
I feel so fucking bad about that.
And I told,
I told the singer I'd throw a couple of
concent form and then I called his pant,
the smiths, and then I had all these
fucking mopey Morrissey people.
He left at Penn 30 years ago.
Man,
they're never getting backed
in other people freaking out.
Did they get back together? Like I
caused like this whole fucking thing.
I feel like such a f
by the way. You're, you're, you need to
film like a video of your Morrissey dance.
Oh, the Morrissey dance. Oh
yeah. Have you done that yet? No,
I got to get it down better. It's one
of my favorite things I've ever seen.
I don't dislike more soon.
I just made,
I like irritating people that are really
into shit. Like star wars fans. Oh,
I saw them. I saw one, I saw one
of the newer, newer star wars ones.
It was fucking great.
It was actually really good.
Now that it's not like a muppet movie.
There was two, like it was like,
it was like muppets with space
and then some bad self help.
You know, this guy's good. He's in
the league, his light sabers, blue
dude.
I think star wars is great,
but when people like make their
lives revolve around it, I just,
it's like there's so much other
shit out there in the world.
That's why people don't like baby
boomers because baby boomers,
like they just make so much about what
they grew up in and fucking all the stuff
they did.
If they just fucking just did what they
did and just shut the fuck up about it
and let them other generations
realize how cool they were,
they would have been fine. Um, all right.
I got to read a couple of these
things here. All right. Okay.
Bill stitch fix sent you
close while you were in Paris.
They're actually really normal and
wearable and much better than the other
clothing companies we've had. I probably
shouldn't read that out loud. All right.
This is going to be,
I guess these guys make really
normal wearable clothes. Okay.
Did you hear that? That was the
sound of money going out the door.
Stitch fix everybody a convenience
stitch fix understands that Louie,
even that much fucking copy this,
this. This is like that's a novel.
Stitch fix understands that
life gets busy. So tell,
tell them your sizes and your favorite
type of clothes and how you want to spend
and your personal stylists will pick
out clothing for you based on your
preferences. Try before buying. If an
item doesn't fit or you don't like it,
no worries.
Just send it back free of charge.
No clue what you did in those clothes.
They must have a giant washing
machine that it just goes in.
Some guy in a hazmat suit shows up style.
Some of us habits, some of the stone,
but just because a sense of style seems
elusive for some doesn't mean it's
impossible to entertain a,
there's no time like the
present to discovered the style.
You never knew your head with somebody
else's talent and you can with a little
help from our friends at stitch fix that.
It's not somebody else's town.
But this is reminding me of every bad
eighties movie where they do like a
makeover on you.
Um,
stitch fix has reinvented
how we find in buy clothes.
Just answer some basic
questions about your sizes.
Favorite styles and budget right from
your laptop, smartphone, a tablet,
your personal stylist
and springs into action.
Hand selecting five brand new clothes
I didn't for you. I know, I know.
Personal stylists sounds like something
only the rich and famous can afford,
but you can't.
To a stitch fix styling fee is only $20,
which is applied as a credit
toward anything you keep and sense.
Your personal stylist uses only PR
your preferences to pick your clothes.
You're still in complete control.
Once your item arrived,
try them on and only pay what you want
to keep. Don't like something neat,
normal size.
Just send the items back.
And this is why I don't think I'm supposed
to read all of this cause they just
keep repeating the same shit.
No questions asked.
And the shipping is always free both ways.
Get your fix whatever you want or sign
up to receive scheduled shipments.
The choice is yours. Um, I
love stitch Fitch. Fix Dave.
I didn't realize that. I guess I do
because they have normal wearable clothes.
I'm sure these are great. I'm sure
these are great and I know you will.
To call the action.
Hurry to stitch fix stitch
fix.com/bird he gets started now.
Keep all five items in your box and you'll
get 25 25% off your entire purchase.
That stitch fix.com/burr
a stitch fix.com/burr hey,
what do you think's going to happen? All
the strip malls and malls in the future.
Like what are we going to do with those?
Cause this is going to be no stores
like cause everybody's shopping from the
Internet online.
Even like they'll buy like
a vintage guitar without
even fucking tried it out me
and have it show up and realize
that it isn't in the guys in Japan.
There's nothing you can do about it.
He's got your money.
I remember I bought that. Well you know
that prince album that, that really, uh,
the one quests level was talks
about where it was just like it was,
I think it was just an all black album.
It's not available and he put it out in,
oh I dunno. Yeah, I bought it off some guy
in Japan. I didn't know what showed up.
It was like the fucking soundtrack
to chips and what am I going to do?
Call up paypal. They're
going to find them. Hey Man,
we're a web country in
the United States in a,
unless you returned that fucking
money for that record, we will,
we will do absolutely nothing because
you'll just change your name and become
somebody else. All right, policy
genius. If you have a car,
you have insurance, you have
car insurance. We should at
least if you have a home,
you should, you have home insurance. If
you're alive, shinny on life insurance,
four out of 10 people don't have life
insurance at all and it's not their fault.
It's life insurance fault.
Shopping for life insurance is
confusing and it takes forever. Hey,
insurance company,
don't totally blame yourself.
A lot of guys can't deal with their own
fucking mortality or they live alone and
who gives a shit if they diary.
So policy genius made it easy.
Policy Genius is the easy,
easy way to compare life insurance online.
It just five minutes.
You can compare quotes from the top
insurers to find the best policy for you.
And when you compare quotes, you've
saved money. It's that simple. In fact,
policy genius has helped over 4 million
people shop for insurance and placed
over $20 billion in coverage and they
don't just make life insurance easy.
They also compare disability insurance,
renter's insurance, health insurance,
one stop and Sharon stop here. If you
care about it, then they cover it. A,
if you've been putting off life insurance,
don't put it off any longer.
It's never been easier to buy and
rates already. 20 year, low policy,
genius.com the easy way to buy
life comparing buy life insurance.
I think I can tell you one of
the best things I ever did,
it was getting life insurance. Oh
yeah, I have it too. It's like the,
isn't it like a relief? My uncle works
for farmers and he was like, dude,
you got to get it. Like let me hook it
up. And it was super cheap. Yeah, breezy.
Yeah. When you're young. Yeah, I
didn't, when I was old they were like,
how old are you? He smokes cigars.
Occasionally we'll give you the old guy,
occasional fee. Here's supposed to say
no, no, I know. But now what they do,
they literally, they fucking,
they take your blood now,
right? I know. And they, yeah,
you so you can lie all you want. They're
going to find out what you're doing.
I say admit to more
shit that you're doing.
So they don't take your blood and
figured out what you're actually doing or
they're like, oh, it's not that bad
considering all this other shit.
And you've been doing whatever.
But I just liked the fact that when I
die that everybody's going to be taken
care of. And it's not going to be like,
you know, I've had buddies of mine die,
you know, unexpectedly, you know, my age,
it's unexpected and your
affairs are not an order.
And then it's the double whammy.
Yup. Where you know, it's the,
you're no longer there.
And then people are like,
how the fuck are we going to live?
How are we going to pay the rent and
take care of every? And that's sad,
but you know, it isn't sad. Is
that joy of your new drum video.
I see. I got out of that. Dude,
I'm so happy for you because for the
longest time I've been telling you with
your skills to utilize the internet,
get out there,
especially because you got something
to say and all that. And uh,
I am thrilled for you and I hope this
podcast can help blow up the video because
you're the fucking man. Because I
sucked at drums and I'm a comedian.
I've actually had people come
up to me and say, you know,
I've gotten to the point where people
come up to me. Yeah. That wasn't that bad.
And before it was bad,
it was definitely a dude.
That video where you were at
Dean's birthday was fucking
crushing. Uh, oh my God.
Dude, that was so much fun. Yeah.
Yeah. The fuck out of everything.
That's what it's all about, man.
You know. Oh yeah, that was,
yeah. I gotta be honest with you. Like
those, those fucking, all of those things.
When Krishna hooked me up
and I got the jams. Yeah.
A couple of those guys know those rice
stuff and slap, I mean, just like,
um,
those things are the biggest of anything
I've ever done in this business.
Um, those are the biggest, those have been
the play with fucking Nikki Sixx. Yeah.
Dude, that's fucking ridiculous.
Yeah. That's incredible. Yeah,
because I really didn't earn it.
That's what I,
cause I always feel like with stand up
as much as, you know, doing Letterman,
the HBO special dudes like that,
it's like I did the hell gigs.
Like I fucking earned it.
And the cracker barrel at three in
the morning and Nebraska or whatever.
But there's these drum and gigs. It's not
like I had to audition. It's just like,
oh, that guy's funny. I'll
play a song with them.
I'm sick of the guys in my band. Get up
their freckles. Let's see what you can do.
All right. That's the Thursday afternoon
podcasts. Very special guests. Davey,
let's thank you so much for coming on.
Finally get you on and thank
you for all the, uh, all the,
all the help you've given me over the
years. Dude, it's been my pleasure.
I've learned so much myself, dude.
And, and one more thing. Yeah.
I can't imagine you had a fucking student
more difficult than meet the fucking
teach. Oh, I definitely have believed in
that. Right? I don't say anything. Um,
but uh, uh, for everyone
who's listening to this,
if you want to go check out the course,
you can go to my website and
during checkout, if you type
in [inaudible], B, u, R, R,
you'll get 10% off off everything,
get look at debt.
And he's a guy who did not embrace
the Internet. Now you fucking,
you're doing it better than I am. I
love it. All right. That's the podcast.
Enjoy the music and then we'll have a
little a throwback Thursday afternoon
podcasts. Have a great weekend. Your
cuts and I'll see you on Monday.
Okay.
[inaudible]
what's going on?
It's Gilbert,
the Monday morning podcast from Monday,
June 28th,
2010 right off the bat.
You should be thinking,
you know what, Bill,
there's something weird with your voice.
Why does it sound like you're whispering?
Because I am fucking whispering.
You're fucking Douche bag.
Why don't you go with your gut?
You know, didn't you fucking brain
just tell you that I was whispering?
Did your parents beat you down mentally
that bad? That you literally question
what that fucking voice in in Saudi
was even saying. That's the voice.
It makes you fucking when you go on a
hike and if that little voice in he has
gone. Is there a mountain lion
staring at me? Yes, there is run.
All right.
Um,
I'm whispering because I'm doing this
fucking thing at eight 20 in the morning,
my girlfriend is sleeping
in the other room.
I take this fucking thing last night,
but for some reason I screwed up.
Okay.
And it didn't record 50 minutes.
I fucking did it and I was going to upload
it at midnight, just like last week.
Okay.
And just like last week,
I am once again Douche bag
of the week back to back,
just like the Lakers and my douchebag.
Two years in a fucking row,
uh, two weeks in a row, I should say
her two times in a row, whatever.
You know the analogy I'm trying to
let you guys know that I'm a
fucking idiot when it comes to this,
the past two weeks and kind of
try and trash the Lakers anyways,
but they don't give a fuck.
They got their rings right.
You know what a wonderful organization,
they actually had to switch their parade
route because they're stupid fans were
riding so much bunch of fucking animals.
Eric, Billy, ever going to let the
Lakers Celtics series go? You know what?
I don't think I'm gonna.
I'm reminded of it constantly.
Like I started watching World Cup soccer
and watching all those fucking people
flopping around on the ground.
Anytime anybody kicked it back of their
socks reminded me of watching Pau Gasol
play basketball, the
fucking flopping. Fag.
All right, let's not be this angry.
You can't be angry in whisper.
Ever seen that?
You've see a couple fight in public.
They do that angry whispering.
That's not what he said. You know,
Goddamn well what the fuck's on right
here? No kill. Shut the fuck up.
That's what I'm going to
be doing. So anyways, um,
I actually did the podcast
last night already and uh,
fighting through,
I was like sweating.
I was so god damn sick.
I did Vegas this weekend.
I performed at the Orleans casino.
Now few standup nerds out there or fee
fans of the podcast who listen every week
you read, you know that the
Orleans casino was the last place.
George Carlin did a stand
up before he died. So, uh,
I went there and I asked
them a ton of questions.
People who work there with totally cool.
Even one of the guys was actually telling
me how Carlin put together as hours of
material.
You know,
how he would come in and it would be
like an hour and 20 minutes and before a
special huge,
he'd watch them whittle it down and by
the end of the weekend it would be the
AEC an hour right on the nose.
Gave me chills listening to it and
also made me really feel like, uh,
I need to start working harder as a
fucking comedian. And, uh, someone,
they're also gave me a, a ticket stub
from his last show was fucking awesome,
but I made the mistake. I, um,
the Orleans Orleans casino is actually
off the strip. It's kind of cool.
So my hotel room at a view
of the entire Strip and, uh,
I would have been content to just stay
out there at the Orleans casino cause I
liked it. I liked the vibe. The
crowd was a little bit older as am I,
you know, so there wasn't a
lot of craziness going on.
It was just straight up,
let's booze, let's eat,
let's gamble. You know,
I wasn't a bunch of people fucking,
you know, in Alec, a Gaggle,
a chick screaming out the
sunroof of a fucking limb out.
You know, we got a lemma
beaches in Al, you know,
everybody tags everything
with bitch nowadays.
Is that from the Rick James Sketch?
I'm Rick James Bitch.
Then everything became bitch,
whatever long fucking story.
You know what I'm doing right now,
I'm looking at my laptop and
the screen saver just has all,
all the albums on my iTunes or all the
albums that don't really fucking exist.
The covers to the digital
singles that I downloaded.
I'm actually looking at one that
says Elvis speaking of Las Vegas.
And I came out to uh,
to LVC entire weekend.
I had to do it.
I came out to that song that's used to
be cute and now I realize that it's about
stocking someone you know,
has a fucking song go had in the kitchen,
had in the hall and gonna
do you any good it out?
It was one side something man.
The kids in start a team allowed
Hawes is good and Tamar us apart.
It's like really? Elvis does. Does
the woman have any say in that?
Okay,
I'm going to fuck and Zaha I'm Volvo.
But Elba.
Yeah. Stuck on you. Stuck on
you. You would think that, uh,
that with them, it's a guy in love.
But if you really listen to the lyrics,
it isn't,
it's a guy who can't accept the fact that
the relationship is over and her mind
and she wants to move on.
Okay.
Eh, you know, hey, he just
won't fucking leave her alone.
It keeps pressing his sweaty out of shape,
iconic stomach up against
her as he kisses her.
I mean,
that's what I got out of it,
but it was a great sign to come
out to nonetheless. So anyways,
you probably asking, hey
bill, you whisper douche.
How did you get sick?
I don't really know,
but I know who I'm going to blame it
on. How about that? I was fucking, uh,
like I said, I was content to stay
off the Strip at the Orleans casino,
you know, but I brought my girlfriend,
so you know what that means.
They want to do stuff.
Yeah,
that's counter this strip.
I heard they had some stores.
They are stewards on the strip.
Let's go to the Strip and go to the store
and see where to go to the stores and
the Strip a sweetie.
Sweetie,
do you want to go to the
stores on this strip? Okay.
No, of course. I don't. Why know?
Why would I want to do that?
If I had something I needed to buy, I
would go, but I doubt I don't want to go.
Yeah.
But I fucking learned.
I've learned to get through
the fucking relationship.
You got to say yes to some shit.
You don't want to fucking do.
So I go, yeah, yeah. Let's go to the
fucking stores on the Strip. Right.
So we fucking go out there and uh,
you know,
we go into all these fucking stores.
I noticed those really high end stores.
When you go into them,
they only have like 40
pieces is they call them.
You don't, it's very, it's now
like when you go into old navy
a, what's waist size area? We
got a hundred of that. You know,
we get a hundred every fucking size and
their stack from the floor up to the
goddamn ceiling.
And we got that ladder at fucking
slides right across the wall.
That's how much product we have in here.
And that's just the goddamn change.
And you know why?
Cause they're 30 bucks a whack,
but you go into those fucking high end
places and it stops being jeans and
dresses.
It starts being called pieces.
Yeah.
And all of a sudden there's like 28
things and there's a ton of space and
everybody in those stores,
it looks like Mike Myers and that
fucking sketchy used to do, you know,
re danced like the fucking German guy
who liked to get shit on sprocket or some
shit.
And I came out with the fuck name was
stressed all in black and he put his hands
on his hips and he only moved his legs.
Can you guys hear that person?
There's somebody giggling
like a maniac downstairs.
The person moved out downstairs,
not the old guy.
My apartment's over two
different apartments.
It's a little fucking spread out.
So anyways,
we start going to those God damn shops.
Long story short,
I got to actually admit a Louis
Vuitton when you go in there. Uh,
I really liked their luggage van.
That luggage is fucking insane.
Like it's handcrafted. Say No,
I lied that, you know, look
at that handcrafted. Yeah.
Some guy took a hammer and nails on the
inside, look at that craftsman ship,
you know,
and they have an old Louis Vuitton trunk
from like the early 19 hundreds and
it's still functional. You know, why?
Cause it was made by hand using great
materials. So I was like, you know what,
I liked his shit. I like,
it wasn't made by a machine.
It was made by a human being.
So I asked him the smallest
fucking piece of luggage they had,
which I guess would be considered
kind of like a jewelry box.
And I asked him how much it was
and they were like $4,000 and a,
I did the Eddie Murphy in Beverly
Hills Cop, you know, you know,
I just totally played it off like I
could afford it as that guy has. Great,
you know? Okay. Now.
Why don't you close up this handcrafted
thing and put it back up on the fucking
shelf?
I was actually pissed
afterwards for grant.
They fucking look me right in the eye
when they said four grand for gray.
You look at the fucking floor when you
throw a goddamn number up like that
should be ashamed of yourself
charging that much fucking money.
I don't understand.
Do you know how fucking rich you'd have
to be to buy a $4,000 fucking jewelry
box?
Okay,
Jesus Christ. Most people, their
jewelry isn't worth that much
and then where the fuck do you take it?
That's the thing about buying really
nice clothes and really nice stuff.
I got my legs crossed right now
and I'm swinging my foot around.
The fuck is wrong with me. She caught
myself on a really a feminist moment,
whatever I'm allowed on a um,
what? What the fuck are you going
to do? Like someone will like,
that's when you know you're rich.
When summer will mug you not
for what's in your luggage,
still just mug you for
your fucking luggage.
You know, when I go to do
the David Letterman program,
I go always go out and I
buy a nice God damn suit.
I always lose money
whenever I do that show,
but I'm not going out there looking
like a bum and I love the suits and I
wearing them. But the second you put them
on your freaking out like Oh my God, ah,
anything that you go to brush
up against you freak out
because it's an expensive God damn suit
as opposed to when you shop at old navy
in the gap,
you know the Anti Pussy
where that they sell.
I wouldn't give a shit if I was
walking through a fucking pig sty.
I mean I freak all my God
pig shit. Oh God. Okay.
I'm wearing gap jeans. I've never
wore gap jeans. I would never do that.
Do you know there was a
kid in my high school,
his nickname was the gap nerd
and he'd, he, he, he had no idea.
People use, no one said to his
face because he was a bigger guy,
but he always wore a gap jeans
and he wasn't even that big of a nerd,
but he always talked to shirts in
cause it was the 80s and a yeah,
they called them the gap nerd
and that was the end of his pussy getting
career. He had no idea, had no idea
she had to deal with his big six foot,
four inch fucking red corduroy gap jeans,
big stupid tag on the back gap.
It's like don't you notice that
everybody else's says Levi Strauss.
That's what you want to have on.
And then the couple of kids whose
dads have mafioso connections,
there's actually actually
have guests jeans, you know,
which in my world was chick
jeans back then. Um, anyways,
I'm getting off the fucking beaten
track. So anyways, so we will look,
we're going through all these,
these high end fucking stores.
I went into the Tom Ford store,
some of the most beautiful
suits have ever seen in my life.
Also some of the most expensive,
but you get caught up in it.
I was actually in there because Tom Ford,
his entire line is not just the line,
it's like a lifestyle and it's like
dead dull [inaudible] beer guy.
Stay thirsty. My friends, it's
like Steve McQueen man's man.
They had a fucking raw,
a cigar cutter cutter made
out of like a fucking,
I was going to say a rhino horn.
It wasn't,
it was an ox horn and
ox horn cigar cutter.
One of the most manliest
fucking things I've ever seen.
And I'm actually thinking about buying it.
I'm holding this fucking ox horn.
Yeah. Now they had a ram horn
cigarette lighter. I'm not even lying.
I'm not even joking. I'm actually
considering buying this fucking thing.
Fortunately I walked out of the store,
you know,
and by 10 minutes went by
and then I just kinda had like that
little fucking gut check moment there,
whatever. Kind of looking
at myself like, dude,
did you almost just by a fucking
[inaudible] Garth cutter.
Did you really? Almost too. Did you,
did you get that fucking caught up and
that bullshit? It's like, yeah, I did.
Couple of things kept snapping
me back into reality. Um,
I don't like my,
I don't like buying shit made out of
animals unless it's a leather jacket.
It's just a stupid cow
ate hamburgers anyways.
It'd be fucking hypocritical when
it fucking cows already dead.
Why don't we go to the native American
route and use up this whole fucking cow?
Yeah.
You know,
but I don't eat ox,
although I did go to a Mario Batali
restaurant one time and I got an oxtail
fucking stew or something. I can't
even remember what the fell it was,
but it was delicious. Um, but anyway,
since she's just no fucking need,
unless the ox was already
dead and you're like,
well we might as well sof,
it's fucking horns and turned
it into a cigar cutter.
Anyway, so we get out of that
thing and speaking of fucking cows,
yeah.
So I dunno, my girls like, let's go
get something to eat. And I said,
all right, there's a fucking
Mcdonald's right there. And she's like,
do you want to eat there? And Soda was
looking down at the ground, all sad,
you know, just doing that classic
female manipulation thing.
She knew I wanted to eat there.
I just said there's a Mcdonald's there.
And then why would she say,
do you want to eat there
and look down at the ground?
This question is for all the young male
listeners. If my whispering podcast,
why would a female do
that? Do, do, do, do,
do. I'll tell you why.
Because she doesn't want,
if not only does she not
want to fucking eat there,
she already has a place where
she wants to eat. She's our,
she's already had this
place that she's wanting,
wanting to eat it for probably a
month before you ever went to Vegas.
But she's not going to tell you about
it because if she tells you about it,
they'd give you time to do research on
it and find out how fucking expensive it
was. So she's like, do you want to
eat? And she looks down at the ground.
So immediately, despite the fact
that I know all this about females,
I take the bait. Why? Where
do you want to eat sweetheart?
Um, there's this burger place at
Mandalay bay. I heard it with Israeli.
Nice. Do you ever watch top chef? Uh,
only when you're watching it,
sweetheart. I don't like that show.
Fucking show is annoying. I hate when the
shift starts screaming at those people.
It's fucking foreign accent. He called
dead a fucking grilled cheese sandwich.
Get the fucker in my kitchen. Hey. Hey,
you think I'm fucking afraid of you?
You fucking Dosha. You got a fucking
problem with my grilled cheese sandwich.
You come up like a fucking
gentleman and you take me aside.
Don't fucking be screaming at me.
Why get these fucking knives in my hand?
Stick it right to your goddamn trachea
when you think about that. Huh?
I'll give you a fucking blow hole right
out the front of your fucking neck.
Get out of my goddamn face before I take
you by your fucking hair and Moshe face
into this pile of shrimp. Huh? That
I haven't taken the shells off.
So I'll give you a bunch of
little razor cuts. Sorry.
Could you actually smell there's
somebody there. You know,
I used to work in a restaurant where,
uh, I worked the mesquite grill.
I worked in a fancy restaurant called
the sable cafe and Cary North Carolina,
very short lived.
It was supposed to be five star dining
yet they had me working on a mesquite
grill.
Glassed in with a big chef hat is all
these fucking people will be looking at
me,
you know,
and I had to cook up all this
shit and I was done, you know,
burgers front bro Sheds
to chicken sandwiches,
whatever the fuck we will make
in the swordfish specials.
And then I turned around,
there was a little window and I'd hand
it to the fucking Metallica fan who I
worked with who had a stick his hair
up in the hat with his pre pubescent
fucking mustache even though he was 19
that was a funny thing about that job is
I'd be sitting there looking at all these
quote on quote elegant people in Cary,
North Carolina and then I'd look through
the little port hole where I would
stick the food through to give to
the fucking drug addicts on the lie.
I remember who, they had a guy back
there who was on a work release program.
Like at night he was in jail,
but it during the day he cooked
at this fucking restaurant.
This guy was a douchebag.
Okay.
And one time we went, we were on
our way to going out of business.
So at one time I was
literally the grill chef,
the busboy and a dishwasher.
Let's not even get involved in the amount
of fucking health code violations that
they're involved in there.
Cause I would,
I did not have time to wash my
fucking hands, put it that way.
Um,
so one day we were slammed,
I'm in back going, hey, we need
some more glasses. You know,
because we were running low on glasses
and the fucking Douche on the work
release program goes, well,
why don't we wash some Aha,
a novel idea,
you know,
like he's fucking intelligent
or something. Ah, a novel idea.
It was only because the guy was,
was in fucking prison that I
didn't say anything to him.
He had that sort of credibility. But
looking back, he was a fucking pussy.
God Damn Little Shit.
He wasn't even that tall.
And this is back in the day though,
when you weren't that tall and if you
weren't that tall, you weren't that tough.
You were tough for a little guy,
but you were still a little guy.
This is before Jujitsu had made
it to America. There was no UFC,
you know,
remember the first fucking UFC and hoists,
Gracie kept fighting all those big guys
and you think that he's about ready to
get punched in the chest and
the fucking face or whatever.
And then all of a sudden he grabbed
that little finger and bend it back and
whatever the fuck he was, he didn't know
what he was doing. It was like magic.
Okay.
He was like, oh, that little guy's
going to get the shit kicked out of him.
And the other guy would be like, I
ran a a ride or rhetoric. So, um,
yeah.
Isn't that hilarious?
There's nothing worse than taking shit
from somebody and you don't give him shit
back because you know why?
Because 23 fucking later years later,
it's still bugs Ya.
Okay,
you guys hit it. There's a,
there's a great one. If you
guys want it, you want to,
you want to, why the fuck is
the word I'm trying to say here?
If you want to participate in the podcast,
what's the law?
I want to find out what the longest like
who the oldest person is on my podcast.
What's the longest you've held
on to some shit. All right.
There's one that was from 1987
88 at least 22 fucking years ago.
It still bugs me every once in a while.
Just pop in my head.
Yeah.
Well, why don't we watch some
glasses are a novel idea.
Yeah.
Hey,
why don't we not live a life of fucking
crimes so we don't have to go to jail?
You fucking piece of shit.
You know the fuck did you do to get in
jail? You dumb fucking idiot. You do.
I bet you one of those guys who pulled
his shirt over his fucking head and try
to rob a seven 11 on a whim.
It was another thing before they
had really good security cameras,
so this asshole wasn't on
America's dumbest criminals.
I really fucking hate that guy.
Still to this day.
I remember I had a math
teacher one time and he goes,
he was asking questions and
he goes for number seven,
let's call on the dumbest kid in the room,
Bill Barr.
And it's still fucking bugs me.
That was like fucking 24 years ago.
You know what?
I think that that's what heaven is to me.
When I die,
I go to heaven and then there's just
the line of fucking people that gave me
shit throughout my life and I never
punched him in the face and they just come
one at a time and I blast them in the,
they say what they said to me then and
I blast them in the face and it doesn't
even hurt my hand cause it's heaven
and hell and I always fucking win.
Um, wow. It's a lot of anger,
isn't it? Okay, let's plow ahead.
So I go, all right sweetie, let's fucking
go up to the God damn Mandalay Bay.
I've never been there. So
anyways, like I said, it was,
it's run by one of the winners
of Hell's kitchen or some shit.
And when the reality is, is
what I'm not realizing is, um,
okay.
People who win that show.
Yeah.
I'm now really starting to believe like,
okay,
it's like last comic standing. You go to
go to the winner of last comic standing.
Oh, this guy, one last
comic standing and then you,
you're going to go see some open miker
who's got 10 fucking minutes and material.
I'm basing that on the first season.
I don't know who won the other fucking
seasons, but it's a reality show.
So I imagine it, it's,
it's a fucking, I dunno,
somebody with like a fucking Hula
hoop going around their head.
Somebody with some Soda Hook.
God knows that's how this business works.
You gotta have a hook,
you know,
if anything told me that it was,
uh,
looking at the people headlining and
Las Vegas. Yeah, that's not true.
There's actually some real
comedians out there. George Wallace.
I know Bobby Slayton worked
out there for a while.
There was real comics out there, but
the guys who make the big fucking bucks,
okay,
they just do shit. But yeah, buff puppets.
How the fuck is that
still entertaining in 2010
you know
like what I can't do ventriloquism
is that right?
Ventriloquism is that the right word?
You want to hear me talk without moving
my fucking lips? I can do that shit. Hey,
there they are. Dummy. What did
you do today? Yeah. Fuck you bill.
Your darker than I am. Isn't that funny?
Huh? The downy thing. You're fucking dumb.
Oh wait, I got to have a
stupid voice. Right? Take it
to another level. Hulu, who?
Who could fucking,
it's sold out shows at Caesars.
10 million a year entertainer of the year.
Bill Barr and fucking ham face.
Whatever the fuck you're
fucking puppet is.
Why is the fucking puppet always smarter?
Can't somebody switched that up?
I'd be arguing with my puppet. The second
the puppets started giving me shit.
Oh really?
You're so fucking smart.
What if I take my hand out
of your back now look at you.
He just fell on your wooden face,
didn't you? He had dumped. Fuck.
Then I turned on the crowd with the fuck
is wrong with you people. What is it?
The 1930s. She's we want, we,
what do you want me to do after they see
what's my fucking encore come out here.
I do the Goddamn Charleston.
Yeah.
Charleston. I could even say it.
All right. 25 whispering minutes in.
I'm actually starting to get a louder,
but you know what?
The Sun is a little higher in the sky.
And you liked that.
Did I sound like a native
American? Um, anyways, uh,
so let Jesus Christ,
let's get to the fucking Mandalay bay.
Okay.
So we go over to the man
late pay and oh yeah, that,
that's what I'm realizing that
I'm eating at an open mic.
Her's fucking restaurant. I didn't
even realize that until afterwards.
I eat the Burger. I got one of
the Coby beef burgers. All right.
Now let me say something
positive about Mandalay Bay, uh,
before I get out of that day,
had some fucking insane shows
coming up at their house of Blues.
All right.
Joe Rogan friend of this podcast and uh,
he had me on his podcast last week.
Joe Rogan is going to be performing
there on July 3rd at Mandalay bay.
At the House of Blues the day before the,
uh,
the big UFC fight you off shoe job,
your triple the wound.
Um,
do you have a seat that Joe Rogan video,
the buffer three 60.
You got to see that just a fucking
search that there's a fucking,
I don't know if it's a youtube
video or if it's just on his, uh,
website Joe rogan.net. But check that
one out. Really fucking funny video.
But anyways, he's playing there and
lamb of God, if you're into that,
a tolerable sort of death metal,
that guy's still sings in
that fucking, uh, you know,
Tom waits voice,
Tom Waits is really the father of death
metal if you listened to is the way that
guy sinks. Oh to Dow, Dow,
you know, or maybe Louis Armstrong,
I think it goes Louie Armstrong,
Tom Waits and then fucking death metal.
Dossie Drees of green red roses too.
Um, anyways, so that's a
good shit at Mandalay bay.
The bad shit is we go to
this fucking burger place,
I can't remember the name of it.
And we go in there and I,
I order a $16 and 50 cent fucking Coby
beef burger and they're talking about how
it's the greatest Goddamn
Burger. I'll, you know, the
highest quality fucking meat,
Yadda,
fucking Yada.
My girl orders want to 1615
1650 what is that? Kids,
that's 33 bucks plus fries plus drinks,
all that bullshit. You know, the
mob doesn't run Vegas anymore.
You can't go out and
get yourself a $2 stake.
The whole fucking place out there
now as a God damn, it's a fuck over.
So whatever costs me like 40 something
bucks, 50 bucks with the goddamn tip,
I eat it. You know, it
wasn't even that good.
Okay.
My girls like, how's your burger?
You know what I said? I said,
it's good just keeping the peace,
keeping the water nice and smooth.
Nice and fucking still on the horizon.
Okay.
So anyways,
I get back to my hotel.
My girl already tells me she doesn't feel
too good at that burger sitting in or
like a God damn boot. And I'm
like, you know what? I feel fine.
I get ready to do my show.
I earned my button down shirt,
put a little conditioner in my hair,
what's left of it,
shape it up a little and I head
downstairs to go work the Orleans casino,
the last place, Carlin ever the place
where the smothers brothers retired,
you know,
smothers brothers who
were so fucking edgy.
They actually lost their sketch show
during the Vietnam War. They did sign,
I forget what the sketch was,
but they had the balls to
say no to the network and do
a sketch that was actually criticizing
what the fuck we were doing over there.
And they lost the Goddamn show. You
know, I don't know about you guys,
but for me, that's lifetime
for respect. So anyways,
I walked down there and I'm going through
the Orleans casino and then all of a
sudden it just fucking hits me. Boom,
right in my stomach. Like some capsule,
some time release.
CIA,
you're going to shit your
pants fucking capsule goes off.
And I know there is no question that
whatever I just ate was not good for my
body.
And it was about to reject it one way or
the other without getting crude people,
when something goes into your stomach,
if it's coming out,
it only has two options.
All right.
Anyways,
I just thought of a really,
really bad joke for the fucking third one,
and I'm not going to say it,
but it involved stabbing yourself in the
stomach and you can fill in the blanks
on that one. All right. So anyways, um,
tell him he gotta be fucking do you
got to be shitting me? No Pun intended.
So I go in the back way,
the same way that Carlin used to go in
because I've already asked everybody
every fucking question. Literally so
much. I'm into Carlin. How did he leave?
Did he hang out now?
We'd say good night and he would go
right out the door and he'd be in the car
and he wasn't difficult to work with.
I guess he had arthritis at
the end of his life. And, uh,
the sound guy was saying one show,
he forgot to take the bottle caps off
the water bottles and he saw the car loan
was struggling with them and when he
got off because George, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry. And George just
like whack Matt. Al, come
on man. I don't give a shit.
Don't worry. Just walked out. I guess
he was a really great guy. So anyways,
I'm walking through this legendary door
and uh,
you know, and what's worse is like,
I know what's going to happen,
but I know it's not going to
happen for like another 15 minutes.
And coincidentally the fucking show starts
in 15 minutes and I'm going on first.
All right.
And this guy,
when you're backstage literally
says 20 minutes till showtime,
20 minutes till showtime.
He liked counts it down.
I never get nervous before shows,
but this guy counting down
the show is making me nervous.
15 minutes till showtime. Okay. And
it's starting to get worse and fuck it.
Get literally gets down to two minutes
before showtime and I'm questioning,
can I make it through a half set?
And I was like, you know what?
Fuck this.
The show can't start without me.
My opening music is Elvis Presley.
Anyways, the fuck do I care?
They can listen to that song.
I'm going robe, buffoon. He goes,
lose your long black hair
slam you four can fly.
You solve the fucking sink a
Ho, Ho Hoo. I don't give a shit.
And I said,
fuck it.
And I fucking ran into the bathroom
and I will spare you the details.
But you know, when something
either amazing hello,
uh, something amazing
happens. They make a statue.
If something horrific happens, a lot
of times they will preserve the area.
You know,
like Dealey Plaza.
Fuck a president gets
his brains blown out.
All of a sudden we can't change one blade,
a fucking grass.
Okay.
The horror that happened in that
fucking bathroom, ladies and gentlemen,
I never do shit jokes. They should
have retired that fucking bathroom.
That's it. They should've
just fucking, uh,
air sealed it and just
put a glass fucking door.
Two people could look in and,
and,
and realize why they closed that fucking
burger joint at the Mandalay bay.
And a, I got to met, dude. I
have, I haven't, this is Monday.
I'm finally back to normal.
So there you go.
There's my big shit story.
I had a burger over at the
fucking Mandalay bay and
it almost ruined my fucking
show over at the Orleans. So if you guys
saw me, anybody saw me Saturday night.
All right.
You want to talk about a professional
because I extra fucking killed on that
show.
If you knew what the fuck happened,
just know that the next time you go to
Vegas and you go to see Barry Manilow and
he's singing that song,
Mandy,
you sobbed and sobbed and then you stomped
there. But I still want to fuck you.
Oh Man.
D right.
Just know that he could have just
been shit in his fucking brains out.
Two minutes before he put on his ray on
fucking slacks with his horrific plastic
surgery is yanked back face.
I bet.
You know I was going to say
he need another face lift
if he fucking shit the way
I did before my show. But that's
actually not true. There's no strain.
There was no straining. Um,
anyways. All right, Bill.
Jesus Christ enough already.
So anyways,
one of the things I like to
do when I go out to Vegas,
I like to check out some of the acts
that are out there because Las Vegas is a
viable option for a standup comedian.
Um,
if things aren't going well
for you in, uh, in Hollywood,
but you're a huge draw as you
could actually go out there
like, uh, you know, some of the comedians
that are out there, I won't name names,
but they're making a
ridiculous amount of money,
you know, 3 million, four, five,
$7 million contracts,
okay.
For the year.
And you don't have to travel,
you don't have to go on the
road or nothing. And believe me,
I have thought about it.
I've thought about it. It's
like you fucking kidding me.
4 million. I'd stay out there
for a year. I just do it.
I get a fucking, I think I already
talked about this. I'd have a, a, a,
this is how I had a plan.
I was going to have a fucking of really?
Yeah.
Fucking slam and house that I would rent.
And then I would make the casino,
give me a car service and I would just
have him pick me up, drive me to the Gig,
walk right in the back door,
like Carlin do my show and walk.
That's probably why I did it.
I fucking walk right back out,
gave me the car and I get the
fuck out of there, you know,
that way I wouldn't get sick of the
casinos or any of that type of shit or at
least it would take longer.
But a summary One was telling me that
Celine Dion actually has it down and yes,
I am comparing myself to Celine Dion.
Cause sometimes,
I don't know if you guys notice
when I'm really feeling a joke,
I start punching myself in the chest.
Um,
her fucking music is horrific. She's like
the white version of Beyonce, you know,
where she's really successful.
I'd actually fucker,
but the sound of her voice makes me
want to just fucking kill myself,
you know? I mean, how hard is
Beyonce? But her voice is fucking,
it's beyond horrific. It's like,
it's unacceptable. It doesn't,
she sound like she's singing like two
octaves higher than she should be.
The worst is when you're in like a
restaurant and they just have it on.
It's sort of low volume and
the background and you're like,
is someone choking on their food?
Actually that wouldn't make sense
because that would mean that you could
actually get air out
if somebody sort of choking on their food.
Is there a an s and m
couple in the corner booth
and the dude is applying just
enough pressure. All right.
Whatever. Um, anyway,
she had it down the best.
Celine Dion like she would live,
she had a helicopter pick
her up at her fucking house.
She the land on top of the casino and I,
you guys don't understand how
much of a drain, the cysts,
any performer who's
listening to this is fucking,
it's got a fucking hard on at this
point. This is the ultimate. All right.
Other than just having a fucking evil
twin robot who always kills and just goes
out and does your shows,
you know,
and the fucking helicopter
would pick her up at the house,
Flyer over to the casino,
land on top of the casino,
and then she would just
go down, go out, sing,
punch yourself in the chest and then just
fucking get back on the helicopter and
ride back.
Do you realize that means she was doing
her vocal warmup in like her bathroom,
you know,
and like five seconds later or whatever
as she sat in her kitchen eating fucking
fruit loops or some shit, you
know, total, total, total, total,
total knee hit the fucking
sound of those helicopter
blades out doing that.
We'd be listening to the theme from Mash,
bad band and, and, and, and, and Eh,
you know,
maybe some of that music that they
listened to when like apocalypse now.
What are some of the music
that they listened to?
Was that the one at one of
those war movies where they
would listen to the doors?
This is the end.
Doodoodoo my only for Dan.
You probably wonder why, Bill, what
the fuck are you singing so much for
on your podcast this week?
I'll tell you why. Because, uh,
I went out to Vegas and uh,
I saw a group out there that was selling
out and it was frustrating to me how
much people like singers.
This group had the worst fucking name
of any group I've ever seen in my life.
I,
it was four people,
three guys and one girl,
all with like the fucking face lifts face
yanked back the fucking hair dyed all
well into their 50s except for
one of them who might've been 38.
And I thought they were an acapella group.
They're not,
they sing and they have a band there and
the name of the group was vocal soup,
vocal soup.
Is that not the most
disgusting fucking name
you've ever fucking heard who
came up with that vocal soup?
So I'm like, I have to go, I have
to go on youtube, look them up,
look up vocal soup and click
on vocal soup and concert
and I'm going to sing you some of
their lyrics. They sing vocals, sip,
Yay.
You take four cool voices and you make
them Ha and you give it everything you
get.
You get vocal soup.
How fucking gross is that?
It just makes you gag just to think
of it and the in the fucking lyrics,
they do nothing to try
to make it less gross.
There's actually a line in that.
Then they're stupid theme song that you
won't stop slurping till you're burping
up focal soup and the end of the video.
I Shit you not speaking of Shit,
which is the reoccurring
theme of this podcast,
they actually have an animated
bowl of soup that is shit Brown.
It looks like a bowl of fucking diarrhea.
I know it's gross but I have to
accurately describe it and they have notes
coming out of it with the steam.
Okay.
Vocal soup. Ah, it's fucking horrific.
Vocal soup and this is what killed
me is the one guy in the band,
the rocker is actually this
guy from the group foreigner
and it's just like, okay,
whatever. You know, I dunno.
Foreign is broke up right now and you had
a bad deal. Some behind the music shit.
You need money. A, I respect it,
but how the fuck did you
sign off on vocal soup?
Former person that was in
foreigner, you know, you don't,
you didn't, you didn't speak
up like, hey guys, you know,
I don't want a big league anybody,
you know?
Yeah.
But I, I wasn't a band that
not, not only sold out arenas,
not only had a number one record,
but I,
I want it to say we actually
had a pretty cool fucking name.
I think we can do better than vocal soup.
I mean,
I don't want to go the hacky route here
with like what movie the rube shoots.
What were the other options?
Throat Puke.
Ah,
fucking throat puke. Yay. Yay.
You won't stop yakking until you
fucking burping up stomach acid.
It's fucking horrific.
But of course they sell out,
they sell out and everybody loves him.
And I guess the piano player worked with
Frank Sinatra for 10 fucking years and
he also signed off on vocal soup.
Oh, it's just, I dunno,
but they sell out, you know, that's what
the fuck happens at Vegas. And it really,
you know, Vegas will really help you
understand this business as a performer.
Like why good things don't make it and
why shit makes it all you gotta do is
fucking go out there, you know, put
a fucking toilet seat on your head.
Toilet seat head. Yay. Yeah.
If you don't have a toilet and
you want to take fuck and shit,
I'm all right. I think that says I'm
running out of fucking steam here. Uh,
let's recommend some youtube videos here.
Um,
youtube video. I already told
you to check out Volkl soup. Oh,
it's just making me sick to my stomach
to continue to say that name a youtube
video. Look up. Best cry ever. MMM,
okay.
It's unbelievable. And then of course
you gotta hit the auto tune remix of it.
It really is the best.
Uh,
yeah,
one ever. But don't look at the
Popeye's chicken one. I hate when they,
people do those, that
racist Shit, you know? Um,
anyways, um, and then there's another one.
This is just an uncomfortable podcasts.
I talked to you about my bodily functions.
I brought up vocal soup and just
for the Trifecta of disgusting,
it's usually not, it's never been
this disgust. And this, this,
I'm going to nominate this one for the
most disgusting podcast of all time. Um,
and this is the cherry on top here
at the last youtube video, uh,
is chimp rapes frog.
It's really fucking,
I actually had to shut it off.
Okay.
I had to shut it off.
Um,
okay.
It started off as sort of
funny and then it's bizarre.
And then the people in the background
who were filming it are so fucking dumb
that you can't,
uh,
I dunno.
They just,
he just listened to him and you hear
that their parents and you know,
you realize why we shouldn't have
tried to stop the swine flu, swine flu.
I can't even talk. Sorry. I'm tying to
talk and type at the same time. And uh,
here's something new. Here's,
here's the fucking cool old car
of the week. Go on. Um,
go on youtube and look
up a Nash Metropolitan.
Now I'm sure people made fun of this
and you're gonna be like a course.
You like this car bill because
you drive a fucking Prius,
which you got to check this.
This car was a fucking bad ass car.
When they will make an all
these huge cars back in the day,
they made this little fucking
car. I don't know. Check it out.
Tell me what you think about it.
Some people like redid theirs. Um,
I know it's not a fucking Mclaren.
Don't be a cunt. Just check it out.
It's a cool fucking car.
Um, by uh, international,
I guess Nash and International
is somehow combined or something.
I don't what happened,
they became American motors.
I really should have looked that part up,
but that's a fucking cool car.
It's got three on the tree,
you know,
you know the old school cars where
you had like the a, you know, the, uh,
if it was an automatic, the
park neutral, reverse drive,
all that shit was right on
the steering column. But uh,
I think last time they made a car with,
if it was at,
it was a standard and you shifted up
there. They called it three on the tree.
And I had never even heard of that until
I was like fucking 25 years old because
those cars were long gone. But this thing,
three on the fucking tree, check it out.
A Nash Metropolitan.
And you know what that's going to be it
for the whispering podcast this week.
And maybe it was a good thing that I
whispered it because it was so fucking
disgusting. Let me, uh, let me hype
some of my gigs coming up here. Uh,
let me go to the official website of bill.
I'm going to be the next Gig I have.
I'm not working again until,
uh, I actually have, uh,
July 12th on my website,
but I have to change that.
I don't get to Montreal till the 13th
people. July 13th through the 17th.
I'm going to be in Montreal,
Canada.
Speaking of cities that riot
after they win or loose,
just like Los Angeles,
another sports town of fucking animals
who attack police officers and tip over
cars. Even if they fucking
win, win our loose.
Um, I'm going to be up at
the Montreal comedy festival,
the just for laughs festival.
I'm doing my new one hour of material.
So while you fucking frogs up there, who
want to pretend like you're from Paris,
I'm speaking to that
shit. Uh, I love the, uh,
my actually going to burn a job Burnett
show company. Fucking listeners do.
I have actually, you know what, my, uh,
the guy who actually set up my entire,
a podcast player told me a week ago,
okay.
That as of the beginning of this
month told me this a week ago,
I had 1 million,
3000 something downloads of my podcast.
Do you want to, do you fucking
understand that for a second?
Let's think about that for a second.
If I charged a dollar a podcast,
I wouldn't have to do this fucking
podcast anymore. That's actually bullshit.
First of all, people
wouldn't have, you know,
I know a lot of people go back
and they download all 150,
and if it was a buck a piece, they
wouldn't, but if I charged a dime a piece,
I would add 100 grant,
hundred fucking grant,
you know, that's almost as much
as vocal soup makes a night.
All right.
So anyways,
maybe I'll do that.
Maybe I'll charge like a fucking dime.
Cause if he didn't notice from the uh,
yeah,
from the story I was telling you about
working Vegas and not having to do the
road and that type of thing,
that's what happens to performance after
awhile is it's not the doing of the
show.
It's the fucking travel and you try to
figure out how the fuck I can get off the
road. Initially the road seems like
a cool, fun thing to do when it is.
But then as you get older and you've
been pretty much everywhere, uh,
you try to look for ways, what would
you guys do if I charge 10 cents now,
what would that be?
10 cents you guys were really going
to expose me for how dumb I am.
That means you can download the entire
podcast for 53 fucking years for 15
bucks.
Yeah.
You know?
Be $15.
Okay.
I'd have a hundred grand in my pocket.
Granted it would go down to like fucking
50 after the Goddamn government came
in. But you know what? You
know what that would do?
That would buy me a nude
fucking dodge challenger.
Okay.
The fucking top of the line, one with
the fucking stripe on it and shit. Um,
don't worry, I'm not, I'm
not going to charge a dime,
but what I am going to
do is I'm going to start,
I'm at the beginning of guilting
you guys into, to my new DVD, okay?
Just for the simple fact,
dad,
I don't charge for this
motherfucker. I am real. I am.
I am going to let you guys know that
I'm going to guilt you motherfuckers.
All right? Pay Forward. It's not a,
you can't just buy one of my DVDs.
You got to buy two,
one for yourself to show all your friends
and then you got to buy the second one
for somebody that you don't really like,
but you have to buy him a gift.
It's a great fucking gift.
You know your boss,
you if Canty fucking sister in law,
you know,
and you have to get him a gift cause they
get you a gift as that's a great gift
to get is my fucking DVD.
It's only fucking 20 bucks.
There you go.
You can't shut your face and watch
this guy trash women for an hour.
Um, that's it. Everybody. That's
a podcast for this week. I uh,
apologize that it was so fucking graphic.
I usually don't tell shit stories,
shit jokes, bodily feel fluid
stories. But uh, it happened.
What do you want from me?
But anyways,
I want to thank the Orleans casino for
having me. I had a fucking great time.
If you go out to Vegas, go to
the Orleans and casino, you know,
if you a little more mature and you don't
want to deal with those fucking whores
walking around.
Oh Hey,
I gotta I gotta give you guys the name
of this fucking thing. I actually,
I'm not one of these guys who
was into art really. Bill,
you just did a fucking shit joke
for fucking 45 minutes. If you guys,
next time you go out to Vegas,
go out to the Peter Lick. Um,
Gat Gallery, Peter Lik l. I.
K this guy takes pictures of,
of uh,
like beautiful scenes in nature and he
uses this camera from like the 1930s that
it literally takes a minute for the, the
camera to take a picture. And obviously,
I don't know shit about photography,
but I don't know what he does.
He opened something,
it's wide open and he hits it.
And because it takes so
long to take the picture,
it gets all these unbelievable colors.
It literally looks like
an HD TV picture and uh,
they stick you in these rooms and with
these dimmers and what they do is they
dim the lights down.
You,
it looks like the sun is going to,
I can't explain it,
but they have a gallery in Mandalay bay,
the Venetian and the, uh, that mall,
that covered mall there
at Caesar's palace.
Definitely check that out. If you
going out to Vegas, Peter Lik,
you know when you're done checking out
Joe Rogan at the House of Blues July 3rd,
go to the, uh, oh, you could do that.
Okay.
Go up there. Don't get a hamburger.
Checkout the Peter Lick, uh,
pictures and have them sit you down
in one of the,
in one of the rooms and have them dim
the fucking lights and check it out, man.
Peter Lik, man, it's the shit. All
right. That's it. I hope it was funny.
I hope it was a funny podcast.
I felt a little fucking hampered
by the fact I had to whisper here,
but,
uh,
what the hell did I do? Did I just shut
this fucking thing off? No, I didn't.
All right, you guys.
Everybody have a good week.
Alright.
Talk to you next week.
[inaudible].