Hey, what's going on? It's bill burn
is time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Just checking in on you. Just checking
in on you. How's your week going,
how you survive and how you survive in
the first couple of weeks here of fucking
the new America.
I wasted 90 minutes last night texting
with somebody on some big stupid fucking
political argument. I can't handle it
anymore. I can't handle people that,
you know, the thing I really
don't like the most about,
uh,
I dunno,
I hate people who say that I'm an
independent. I'm not this party. I'm not,
I'm an independent.
Do you know in California,
evidently according to the three minutes
of research that I did that if you
register you,
that's like you are actually registering
to the American independent party,
which is actually more conservative
than Republicans evidently.
Which is something I don't
understand about politics.
I just don't understand why
no means yes, yes means
no. Why? If there's a bill,
let's have safe drinking water
for children. All in favor. Yes.
And then like attached to
that is other shit like, Hey,
they can indefinitely detain
American citizens without a trial.
They'll tack that on to that. So then
when somebody else votes against it,
clean water for kids because of
that shit that's tacked onto it.
Then when they go to run, they go, this
guy doesn't want clean water for kids.
Can't a fucking and fucking give up.
I give up,
I poked my head out for a second
and I'm um, and that's it. Oh,
I'm putting my head back in the sand.
I'm going back to watching sports.
So Billy fuck head is going right
back where he belongs. You know,
Celtics finally beat the
raptors. Huge win it, goddammit.
Those capitals of Washington
or God damn it, they're good.
They fucking beat the broads. You
know, Marsha with another two goals,
racking it up. Uh, we actually Bruins
won three in a row. It was good.
It was like the strongest part of
our seasons so far. And um, anyway,
so I've been getting back
out there doing stand up.
Now that I've settled in being a
dad and all that type of stuff.
This is really like the
pre season of being a dead,
you know when your kid can't
move really without you.
It's once they start crawling,
that's like game.
That's the first game of the season.
But like early on right now,
I'm like in August trying to get the
roster down to the fucking whatever it is,
44 man roster or whatever
the hell I need because um,
I guess you can think this parenting thing
is pretty easy during the first three
months. You know, even though you're
not really fucking sleeping or anything,
just getting up and shit changing diapers.
But it's still not as bad as all these
pussy say this such fucking pussies dude,
you have no idea. Shut the fuck up.
We used to live in caves. You asshole.
You have no idea. You can't handle the
truth. Do you know I never saw that movie.
A few good men.
It just seemed too actory to me.
Everybody was real tense fucking faces,
you know,
delivering dialogue in
their military dress.
Did I ever tell you how much I can't
stand movies about fucking trials?
I was actually in what,
I didn't realize that,
but that one was different
because I was at it.
I just can't fucking watch
him after a while later.
Tell the jury,
put yourself in the place of the
defendant. Um, they're always like super,
super fucking dramatic.
Have you ever sat in on a real
trial you've ever been in one?
I actually sat in one,
uh,
buddy my became a lawyer and I came down
and I watched him try a case and it's,
it's not like obviously the way
they do it on TV or in movies,
but what was unbelievably compelling was
somebody's freedom was on the fucking
line. And that was what was riveting,
not what the fuck people were saying.
What they were saying was very like, you
know, I'd like to submit a exhibit a,
it's a,
the a the Chandeliers Hannah and
you just say the goals and um,
I actually watched somebody,
I don't know,
I think they got pulled over and there
was drugs in the car and there was some
sort of gun involved in shit.
And I was just sitting there.
I just couldn't get over the fact
looking at the defendant going like this.
That's not an actor.
That's like a real fucking person
as her is that if he did it,
that fucking guy's a lunatic.
He's driving around with drugs, he's got
a gun in the car. What the fuck is he?
This guy's a real life maniac,
or what if he's fucking innocent?
There was all of that shit and
then I was sort of looking around.
There was like nobody really there.
And I looked over in the corner,
there was this old lady sitting there
like knitting, sort of looking up,
listening, and she was like, no, no, no.
What the fuck? She was knitting, you know,
old lady,
she's just knitting.
So at the end I talked to my buddy and I
was just like, wow, man. That was like,
is it, I kind of feel guilty, but that was
like really entertaining. He goes, yeah,
you know, it's, it's real
shit. I said, you know,
I wouldn't be surprised if
like, do you have like, um,
court groupies to people just come down
and sit in on these trials just for the
entertainment value of it? And he goes,
yeah, that's what that old lady was doing.
A lot old people do it, you know,
during the day, you know, they,
they don't have air conditioning
or something. They come in,
they sit down and they just
listened to the trials. It's free.
You can go down and do it. And
um, there was something, uh,
I don't know, cause it's all, they're
old people you can't get too upset about.
But there was something kind
of gross about it. I mean,
I came down to watch my buddy.
I was proud of him and everything.
But then after a while,
how interesting it was and
how much I got into it,
I actually had this level of
guilt of like, you know, this,
this shouldn't be like a, I shouldn't
use this for entertainment purposes,
but I gotta tell you it was a fucking
great time sitting in on a trial.
If it's a good one, you know
there's drugs is a gun. I mean,
I want to see anybody get hurt,
but when they pull you over,
hey took a swing at the cop of,
that's a good, that's a good one.
That's a good episode to go
down, you know, so there you go.
That's real law and order
as opposed to a bullpup OPO,
right. Watching that shit. You can
actually go down the street for free.
You can be a cable. Can you get on,
you know, during the fucking cable,
if you have the, if you have the time, we
got the bay, if you got the fucking time,
you can just go down to court
and that can be your basic cable.
And just see last this week now,
no I didn't. But uh, you know,
did you see that fucking guy who uh,
went to jail for 10 years for vehicular
homicide or whatever the fuck Arama
whatever the fuck he go to jail for.
What do you go to jail for? Anyways?
So I've just been up to my
neck and all the baby, uh,
issues are probably changed like 9 million
diapers. And it was fucking Hilarious,
I found yesterday, right? My
wife's Nia just needed, she
just needed an hour sleep,
right? And women in the beginning,
and they're fucking doing everything.
All you have to do is change the diapers,
make an attempt to burp them or whatever,
but they got to just keep feeding
the kid breastfeeding, right?
So you start to feel like, you know,
guilty, like I'm not doing shit.
So I was just determined like,
I'm going to have this kid for like the
next hour, give her a great hour sleep.
And I was able to, hour and
15 minutes before the kid
was finally just like, look,
I need something. I need what
you don't have. All right,
I need to go downstairs. I need
a solo cup. And he did, you know,
I need a little a keg party here.
Right?
So I was just walking around with her
and I was singing all these songs and
everything. And then I actually,
for whatever fucking reason,
I started singing the Canadian
national anthem and it worked.
Yeah.
And I always forget, I always,
oh, Canada home and native land,
this barrier Drew Bay
we love and all I saw Mama,
man, there's probably washer
here, blah, blah blah, blah,
blah,
blah about eve harp,
harp harp who from far and
wide or card at RP at. Huh.
And he and the best part of our
God keep the Lad Gloria fee.
Right?
Fucking walking around
from room to room upstairs.
I sang the Canadian national anthem for
like a fucking half hour straight and
you're so fucking focused on keeping
your kid sleeping that the insanity of
that,
it doesn't hit you until afterwards
when you give you your baby back to your
wife and then you go upstairs to make
a sandwich and you're still singing the
song.
And if you can't stop doing it,
you know what's the name of
that movie with that guy?
Yeah,
that guy. A midnight express.
The guy traveling abroad
gets busted with the drugs.
Remember those fucking
lunatics that we're all in the,
and it would just sort of
marching in the same direction.
And he started walking in the other
direction that like freaked him out,
but they would just like these fucking,
the people just completely
lost his sanity. That's
what it felt like. You know,
we not just singing the national anthem
for a half hour straight is a fucking
insane thing to do.
Forget about it if it's not even your
country's national anthem. I mean,
I literally felt like a trader even
though that they're an ally of ours.
And I just feel like, you know, maybe
Donald Trump's going to call me.
They didn't give me a heated fucking
conversation, but what I just did,
maybe I'm going to get
deported. Um, anyway,
I'm not gonna get into that Shit fucking
90 minutes of my fucking life. Like,
it's so dumb and I know it's like I'm
literally going to make this person it
admit,
okay
or agree with me or anything, or I'm going
to step his way in. Agreed. It's just,
it's fucking pointless.
Um,
it actually affected my set last night.
Just spending 90 minutes in that fucking
never ending circle of Horse Shit.
And uh,
I gotta stop doing that.
I almost needed to come
home and meditate again.
I'm really getting into that shit. Just
clearing my head, not flipping out.
I think I flipped it.
I flipped out yesterday.
What fucking pissed me off yesterday.
I can't even remember. But I'm,
I'm getting, I'm getting way better
at it, you know. But anyways, um,
I want to thank uh, Conan O'brien,
Jimmy Kimmel, uh, Bill Simmons,
uh, everybody that Joe Rogan
podcast, Joe Rogan experience,
everybody that helped me promote
my special, my special outright.
Now it's doing great.
People are really enjoying it.
Thank you so much for watching it. Please,
uh, let other people know about it.
I am now, um, vigorously
trying to write my new hour,
um, and have some sort of life
outside of being a dad. Uh,
cause I don't want to bore you guys with
an hour long fucking thing about Islam.
Dad,
the same clown fucking floating around.
I'm not going to do that to you. All
right. Um, I already got some good shit.
I already got some shit that is good that
I'm going to be bring it towards you.
So, uh, I guess Obama, before he left,
he signed a, uh, Christmas bill
making alternative media illegal.
Okay.
This bill will criminalize criminalize
fake news propaganda on the web.
A key piece of legislation meant to
crack down on free speech and independent
media in Layman's terms,
the ACC will allow the government to
crack down with impunity against any media
outlet it deems is propaganda.
Uh,
the next piece of legislation will provide
substantial amounts of money to fund
counter propaganda to make sure the
government's approved stories drown out
alternative media and journalists
who questioned the status quo.
There you go. Isn't that great?
There's your hope everybody.
Oh,
what a cunt.
That's why I don't like Democrats that
they at least Republicans, you know, they,
they, they come out as cuts, you
know, there a cunt. You know,
they don't care about you. These fucking
assholes have the nerve to, well,
I guess the Republican's
sell it to the fucking dope.
So in the middle of nowhere,
okay,
we're going to make it great again.
All these people that think
it's going to be great again,
you're still going to fucking have your
face pressed up against a Walmart window
the day after thanksgiving.
You know,
the fact that you as an American have to
consider that fucking option is how as
hard as you fucking work is,
is ridiculous.
There's nothing that's dead is the thing
that nothing makes me more sad. Well,
I guess something else does,
but I can't think of it right now.
But that is a very sad moment every year
in America when you see people putting
their,
literally their own wellbeing at risk,
trying to find a fucking DVR recorder
for $3 before the next person is
[inaudible]. That's just a sad
fucking thing. Should be done.
People should have enough money to go
into a store like a fucking human being
and buy something that they don't need,
shouldn't they?
Speaking of which,
I got rid of some more shit.
MMM.
Uh,
I'm really fucking enjoying this stuff.
Just getting rid of all of the shit I
have to do what I gotta do it before my
kid starts walking or crawling.
You know what I mean?
Or maybe they make some sort of a little
playpen thing that you can put them in
right. Where they feel like they
have free reign but they don't,
you know what I mean?
Okay.
It's a very fucking governmental thing.
Make them feel like they're free,
but they're not.
How can I do that?
How can I apply the same things that
governments apply to my own child?
I got to figure out how to do that. Um,
and then they're moving around. Yeah.
You got to worry about what the,
what are they going to do and get again,
a childproof everything.
There's gotta be gates and
it's gotta be shitting outlets.
I'll tell you,
man,
that's a weird thing about
living with the baby.
It's just like you're living
with this thing that just,
it doesn't know anything but
you can't get upset by it,
you know?
Yeah.
Like we all have that friend
that's like a fucking moron.
And you could just be like, you can
just, if you can walk away from,
cause the end of the
day, you know, they can,
they can still go out and make
themselves a bowl of cereal.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus. But what are you talking about?
Oh, you know, I'm not getting any sleep.
What do you want from me? I don't
know what to say, you know, but
I'm actually kind of site,
we're not my,
my big thing is I just want her to be
able to start moving around so we could
start playing catch. All right. And uh,
if she doesn't want to play catch,
it's not going to be an option.
I won't have it. Oh, I will
make her hate the game of catch.
That's something that you got to
avoid, I guess as a parent. Right?
Like you have such hopes that
they're going to like what you like,
that you could actually make them
not only not like what you like,
but fucking hated and then hate you and
not call you unless it's on the fucking
holidays.
So hopefully she'll enjoy it.
I'll just sort of leave like,
you know,
okay.
I Dunno what baseball laying around.
Maybe she'll get into it,
throw it through fucking window. My
wife will get mad, but I won't care.
I look at that. I'm going
to be our, um, anyways.
All right, plowing ahead here.
Fuck. Was I going to talk about, um,
I'm trying to avoid politics and
fucking baby talk, but I mean,
I mean that's kind of my fucking life at
this point, right? How did this happen?
Um, where is it here?
Where's the time? Yeah.
What's going on in the
world? I have no idea. Oh,
I actually tried to look up some Google
news to see what's going on in the world.
Evidently Trump had a very
short phone call with Australia.
How the fuck do you get into a
fight with Australia is beyond me.
If this is even true, I have no fucking
idea. And then McCain called up and said,
hey man, like don't listen to him. We
still like you guys. This is very quick.
Uh, there's some guy who looks like a, um,
he looks, I don't know what he looks
like. He looks like a fucking magician.
He was going to speak at UC
Berkeley. Yeah. Annapolis,
I guess he's a big Donald Trump supporter
and he goes to UC Berkeley and all my
God, was there a protest? This guy's
a whore. Like he didn't know that.
What's going to happen?
Jesus fucking Christ. Um,
and then, uh, Beyonce
put out a really weird,
creepy picture saying
that she's having twins.
I actually looked at the picture and
kind of burst out laughing. I don't know.
It's some people you get so famous. Why
can't you just say you're having twins?
Well, why do you even have to
announce it? You know what I mean?
We're announcing to the world.
Um,
I mean, I guess I brought it
up. I don't know. I kind of did.
We should've done a photo shoot. What
is the hidden message? It'd be odd.
SES photo shoot.
Pregnancy photo.
There's a hidden message
she's wearing like a veil.
I mean,
I just don't under still kind
of a food as a photo shoot.
Why am I looking at this? Why? Um,
anyways.
All right.
So all Billy dead body's got to
hit the fucking treadmill today.
I got to start eating well. And, um, I
don't know what to think as far as like,
what you can eat, what you can't eat, you
know, people say avoid saturated fats.
And then I go on the Rogan
podcast and he goes, Nah man,
that was all bullshit that was put
out there by the sugar companies.
And I guess I could sit down and read
it, but I just don't. Uh, I don't,
I don't have the time, so I just
decided, well, you know what? Fuck it.
I'll have a stake in a lab
but with have a little,
a little garden salad and then I'll
be all right. And you know what,
I woke up this morning and I didn't
die of a heart attack, so there you go.
So I guess he's right.
So many try to avoid sugars as much as I
can and try to eat some Goddamn steaks.
The fuck is a button. Yeah. Sorry.
Every once in a while this I fuck
up with my recorder and I don't,
um, I don't record it on the right speed
and then it takes like nine years to
fucking upload anyways. Oh Hey, you
know what's going on? The super bowl,
it's the super bowl this weekend.
A little bread and circus for everybody.
The super bowl yet that,
that,
that way they could you do to do patriots
going for their unprecedented fifth
fucking oh Tom Brady going for
his fifth fucking ring. Actually,
we're also going for our fifth super
bowl title against the Falcons who are a
major problem. Like I said,
I'm going on the record.
I think it's going to be a classic if
you can get the falcons with four more
points. I liked that and
I also liked the under 59.
I like the fucking, because
everybody else was like, June,
it's going to be a fucking shoe kid.
You know, they start looking at those,
fuck this state.
I love looking at the stats of what
they did during the regular season.
It's like this isn't the regular season.
This is completely fucking different.
You know,
this guy throws her 500 fucking yards a
game against 90% of teams that aren't in
the fucking playoffs anymore. You've
got to adjust it all down. You know,
you gotta go negative,
negative, whatever statue. See,
you have to adjust it down because
each week you're going to play a better
fucking team, you know,
within, you know, the theory,
right? The theory says that. So,
um, I have no vibe whatsoever,
um, when it comes to this game, because
you know, according to the regular season,
the falcons do not have a good defense.
But according to what I've seen
in the playoffs against Seattle,
they have pass get dirty birds
up there in Washington, right?
And against the Green Bay packers,
whatever the fucking a packer is
loading trucks, whatever the hell it is,
putting cheese, right? Putting
cheese in your fucking caboose,
whatever it is they do
up there, you know, um,
the defense looks solid there.
And um,
I guess I was sitting there saying
the falcons have a great running back
everyday only. They have two running
backs that can get the fucking job done.
So I think this is going to be a,
and then the fact that
Matt Ryan also is mobile,
which means if he shut everything down,
that fucking red cunt can still do that
diagonal quarterback run where you run
right to the first down marker and
you're sitting at home as a fan gone. Ah,
right. And it keeps the drive
going after yet another third down.
I expect a lot of that and I think
it's going to come down to the wire.
That is my prediction.
It's going to go right down to the wire.
I hope the patriots come out on top.
And I predict myself a lot of times
during the game watching Matt Ryan run for
five or six yards as ice cream.
The fucking,
it's gonna drive me up the wall.
I fucking hate mobile quarterbacks
unless they're on my team,
which we've never had.
Okay.
Since Steve Brogan, see,
Rogan was considered mobile,
you know that naked bootleg he
did on Monday night football.
That was the highlight
of scrambling in the, uh,
60 years of fucking 50 years.
56 years of New England Patriot,
Boston Patriot fucking football.
That was it in like 1976 we had a,
we had a 50 yard naked bootleg on Monday
night football. And other than that,
it has just been, you know, drew Bledsoe.
I mean you could literally drew Bledsoe,
you could literally zoom in office chair
down the street fast and then that guy
could fucking run, you know, one of
those classic staples, piece of shit,
plastic fucking wheels.
Even with the pebbles on the street,
if you could fucking push that thing,
40 yards facet that drew could
run it. I'm telling you. And uh,
Brady is not fucking
mobile. So, um, you know,
you know what is great about not
being a mobile quarterback is you,
you really have to know how to throw them.
Yeah.
Cause I find what the Boval quarterbacks
then they, if they can really run,
they're never quite as good at throwing
the fucking ball. So what happens is,
is as they get older,
they get exposed when they have to kind
of stay in the pocket and just be like a
pocket passer. That's, that's, that's my
theory. That's completely not research.
So I think it's going to be a
real close one. And um, you know,
don't listen to all the fucking
analysts and then at the Patriots lose,
they're going to act like it was
this giant fucking upset, you know,
cause that's what ESPN does.
You know what I mean?
They fucking totally overhype it one way.
And then in the other way, then the, uh,
then they go,
where are we fair to the Falcons of Lana.
And they completely turned rich.
Eisen was another show that I did.
Colin cowherd Shell.
Thank you to everybody that helped me
run my fucking mouth and promote my
special. All right, let's do a little bit,
a couple of reads here and then I got to
go back down to fucking daddy daycare.
Do the diaper thing. All right. All set
up.
Are you hiring?
Do you know where to post your job to
find the best candidates? No, you don't.
That's why I have this
fucking read in front of me.
Posting your job in one place isn't
enough to find quality candidates.
If you want to find the perfect hire,
you need to post your job role
top job sites, and you know what?
Now you can with zip.com you can post
your jobs to 200 plus job sites including
social media networks like Facebook
and Twitter, all with a single click.
Find candidates in any city
or industry nationwide.
Just post once and watch your
qualified candidates roll into zip.
Easy to use interface, no juggling
emails or calls to your office.
Quickly screen candidates,
rate them and hire the right person fast.
Find out today why Ziprecruiter has
been used by fortune 500 100 what?
By fortune 100 companies and thousands
of small mediums and medium sized
businesses and right now my listeners
can post jobs on ZipRecruiter for free,
for free by going to ziprecruiter.com/bird
that's ziprecruiter.com/pat one more
time. Try It for free. It's it
the [inaudible] dot com slash
[inaudible] all right, lift.
You know about Lyft Rye, it's the
APP that gets you right in minutes,
man on demand 24 seven for
less than the cost of a cab.
Please include all of the following
points during your read. Well,
if you write it, I'll read
it. If you tried Lyft, you
know what I mean? With Lyft,
you just download the APP
request to driver and they
show up in three and a half
minutes on average.
That's really fast.
Every Lyft driver is fully vetted
through their 10 point safety standard,
including criminal and
DMV background checks.
You'll know you'll get around
quickly and safely, unlike that other
APP,
that other one
that rhymes with mover. Well you can
do, you can fucking, you can walk up.
You can fucking walk into that office
with a God damn bloody ax and they'd be
like, do you got a car?
Yeah, I got a van, man.
All right, you're hired. Lyft
drivers are rated after every ride,
so only the best stick around.
You don't have to worry about getting
into a filthy car was some creepy dude.
With Lyft, you can tip in the APP, which
obviously leads to happier drivers.
I mean, 910 Lyft rides getting a
perfect five. They're ready, boom, boom.
It's just a better all around experience.
Bigger isn't always better, Huh?
A tell that to a size queen lift
isn't the biggest ride sharing app,
but it's the fastest growing
and highest rated one.
I'm talking quality over quantity.
Thanks to lift.
You got an easy way to avoid drunk
driving. You never have to bum a ride.
He never have to worry about parking.
A lot of people are actually getting
rid of their cars and relying on Lyft to
get around and you know what?
Evidently I don't blame them.
Yeah.
Why would you say that? I don't feel,
I don't feel that. If you want to do I,
that's amazing. If you can do that shit,
but you know there's no more road trips,
you know, going out to the
desert, eating some fucking pot,
whatever these fucking kids
are doing. Okay. Right now,
Lyft is offering our listeners a
special deal. Get three free rides,
up to $10 each. That's an up to $30
value when you enter the Promo Code.
Bill Burgess,
download the free [inaudible] app today,
and Intro Promo Code Bill
per and the pay section.
You'll start with three free rides, up
to $10 each. That's up to a $30 value.
That's Promo Code Bill Burr,
enter Promo Code Bill Burr.
I just came up with the great
serial killer fucking movie idea.
All right,
this
is, this is how the guy gets his
victims. He just goes out to a bar.
He has a drink. He calls one
of those fucking, you know,
lifts or Uber's right. He just has
him drive it back to the house.
They pull up to the house.
He just bonks him over the fucking head,
brings him into his house. So whores
and then he has keeps the cars right.
He read,
doesn't gas monkey style.
He files down the engine number and all
that way. Puts a new engine in it. The,
the, the, the vin number and then
he takes some demeanor, right?
The auction.
He auctions off all the cars at these
dead Uber drivers and Lyft drivers maybe
not make him,
I don't think that they
would be interested in a
fucking Toyota Cressida um,
whatever he goes to, he goes
down to Clearwater, Florida.
There was some shitty cells up down there.
He makes his fucking money.
He takes that money. He uses it to
pay off his creepy fucking house.
Right. And uh, I dunno where he
goes from there. I don't know.
Maybe they did that on, what was
it? What was the name of that movie?
Not that movie. Um, Dexter,
they probably did that on Dexter
at some point. I mean, that,
that's show started off.
It was interesting.
Then after a while I just kind of left
it and then when I came back he wanted to
bang his sister and they were both all
right with it yet. Not all right with it,
you know? And I was just like, wow,
that is the definition of writing
yourself into a corner. All right. Oh,
look who's back. Everybody. Bodo too.
Mandy's me.
Andy.
He's riding around in
Uber. But dude, dude, dude
beyond ease me,
Andy,
something, something, some goober. Ah,
your balls won't stick to the guy's
fucking chair. You drive around,
you don't care. You might be a
serial killer, but who gives a fuck?
Your eyeballs feel nice and soft. Oh
yeah. I don't think this is my house.
Is that a lead pipe? All right. Mandy's.
Everybody picture a world where putting
on a new pair of underwear isn't just
fresh. You're stepping into a better
day. Think about it. Underwear,
it's the first thing you put on
in the last thing you take off.
Unless you Matthew mcconaughey,
why would you settle for anything less
than the best feeling underwear on the
planet? Please include the
following points during your read.
It's fucking here.
I'm going to read it.
Me undies focuses solely on producing the
most comfortable underwear you've ever
experienced. Uh, my friends,
I have friends at me undies.
What we never hang out and you never
call these people who claim to be.
My friends at [inaudible] sent me a
few pairs a while back and now I can't
imagine wearing anything else.
Of course I can.
I am right now I'm wearing cotton
once. Okay. You have no idea.
The length of the size of my
imagination beyond DC. All right.
And maybe if we actually were friends,
you wouldn't make claims like that.
It really makes each day that much better.
For the price of two cocktails me undies,
we'll deliver your new pair,
new favorite pair of underwear right
to your doorstep. A better day,
guaranteed tire mart tram on.
And if they aren't the most comfortable,
best feeling uneasy I need,
you've ever had their refund you and
let you keep your first pair for free.
Included in the price is to sweet touch.
Why do they say that it's in your crotch
area. This sweet touch of modal, modal,
a special fabric made with the best
in class raw materials that are
scientifically proven to be three times
softer than cotton. These Uber Cozy, Uber,
cozy undies are sold
exclusively exclusively on
the [inaudible] website where
you'll enjoy free standard
shipping in the US plus Canada. Uh,
actually you know something, if you
fucking killed your Uber driver, right?
They would be able to look at their phone
when they need to figure out where it
was the last call they made.
Then you come to the door like that
guy in silence of the lambs. All right.
Anyways,
and for a limited time,
everyone in my audience gets
20% off their first order. Uh,
but you have to go to our special URL,
[inaudible] dot com slash Burgh with
the [inaudible] better day guarantee.
You have nothing to lose.
So don't wait any longer.
Go to me undies.com/bar right
now for 20% off your first order.
That's [inaudible] dot com slash burp.
All right. How many fucking more?
Uh Oh Geez. Is there, we
got two more. I can't,
I can't subject you guys listen to me
read out loud this fucking long. Can I,
let's talk about some, let's keep fleshing
out this fucking movie. All right,
so then the cops show up,
you know,
and God knows I'll probably be
be playing the sidekick, right?
I got that role on lock.
You know,
I'd fucking show up and it
just be like, hey, yeah.
You mind if we asked you a
couple of questions? You know, a,
I noticed you have like a,
a,
you have like 15 late model cars out here.
What is it about a boring sedans that you,
an SUV is that you find so exciting,
you a car collector. You know,
the guy gradually invites me and then
he fucking hits me on the head and next
thing you know I'm down in that hole
with that fucking chick, you know,
was probably the same size as me.
So we got to play rock, paper,
scissors to figure out who's going
to stand on who's fucking shoulders.
You know what I mean?
That was such a great move when she got
the dog to come down there and she was
just like,
I will fucking snap this thinks neck.
Who was the actress that played in? She
was fine. I remember when I saw that,
I'm like that that woman is a star.
I thought she was fucking amazing in
that movie. Everybody talked about,
um, what's her face there
from taxi, you know,
and of course they talked about the other
guy who played the guy with the blue
dress like he had, he drove
an ice cream truck, you know,
and he had the guys live with, with
the fava beans, Sir Anthony Hopkins.
What is it about English people that
they think it's an honor to get knighted?
You know, I for the life of me. Why
the fuck do you show up to that shit?
What are the perks to being part of this
round table that never goes to battle?
Did they give you a fucking suit of armor?
You know,
I don't fucking, I don't understand
any of that shit a well bill,
when maybe he'll read up on
it. Well, you know what? Fuck
you. I'm gonna. Here we go.
Here we go. Let's see. Um,
what would you do?
What does it mean to be knighted?
Okay,
what are the parks?
These are the brakes.
Here we go. What perks of being
knighted by the Queen. Ah, here we go.
Um, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Oh,
this is just regular people talking.
So this would be even dumber
than the shit that I say,
as I observed in a response to a very
similar question on this subject.
I have read comments from people with
knighthoods suggesting that the biggest
advantage tends to be the
ability to get a table.
At a smart restaurant more easily and
usually to be offered a better table.
Okay.
That's it.
Other than that,
my only brush with the system is that the
husband of someone I used to work with
was knighted a few years ago
for his work in fiber optics.
Um, Jesus Christ, they let anybody in.
You wouldn't be able to read this on your
mobile phone without him and his team.
He is now Sir David and pain. He
remains a pleasant, modest man.
And I don't think his life has
been greatly changed by the title,
though his wife probably
quite likes being lady pain,
Laney, but both he and his wife
still need to work for a living.
So that's, that's what you
get, I guess you get a better
table at a restaurant. Uh,
I guess it still commands a certain
amount of respect in some circles,
but is increasingly less influential.
Well, what did it use to me?
Okay.
You know what it used to me, they used
to mean you could bang the kings fucking
right. You know, you
just take off your pants,
part of your suit of armor and he just
banging away, but he's, he just clanging.
You know,
you still got this shit on on top.
It sounds like a bunch of toasters
being beaten to death, you know?
But you know what?
I bet that that was an aphrodisiac back
in the day for those ladies with Dick
Chastity Belt, any sort of sound of
metal, they were so fucking repressed.
Is that true bill? I don't
fucking know. All right. Dollar
Shave club everybody. Ah,
Jesus. Urine animal. You need to shave
your back. You fucking all right.
Dollar Shave Club. Dollar Shave
Club always gives you a close,
smooth shave and you can't beat
the convenience of the price.
You don't have to choose between settling
for a cheap bag of disposables or
paying out the nose for a razor
with laser pointed at 17 blades.
It's awful. It's total fucking overkill.
You never needed more than two.
Two blades was the shit.
Once they went three or more,
you couldn't get that
shit underneath the nose.
And I got a cute little
button nose. Oh yes, I do.
The dollar shave club broke onto
the scene with the smarter choice.
Before Dollar Shave Club,
there was no middle ground.
It was either save money and get
a painful shave from a disposable,
like the ones that give
away for free at the gym,
which felt like shaving with a piece of
glass or you paid through the fuck knows
you paid a fortune for the latest shave
breakthrough you didn't need like a chin
detector or 17 more blades. Not
God. I got the hiccups. Now,
dollar Shave Club is the best of both
worlds. You ever seen a baby with hiccups?
It's fucking adorable. Uh, you get the
premium, the best premium shape, quality,
a disposable shape price. If you
haven't tried dollar shave club yet yet,
you're missing out. It's an amazing
shave at an affordable price.
There's no smarter choice on the market
and right now they're giving away a one
month trial of any of their new razors
for a dollar with free shipping.
And that's about it. After that,
it's just a few bucks a month.
There's no long term commitments,
no hidden fees. You get kicked,
fucking get it right.
Get one trial at get one free
trial or whatever dollars shape.
Get your online dollar trial.
Sorry it dollar shave club.com/bird
that's dollar shave club.com/bar in
mercifully, mercifully. This is the
last read and it's a nice quick one.
Legal Zoom, everybody. The
holiday hangover is gone,
right?
So are all your relatives and all those
fucking people you got to deal with.
You know, and everybody went their ironic
ugly fucking sweaters. It's all gone.
The New Year's does to settled. You've
broken all of your fucking resolutions,
so now you can finally get around to
doing the things that you've been putting
off for way too long.
Uh,
in legal zoom.com is
where to make it happen.
Whether you want to launch the business
of your dreams or you'd like to take
control of your family's
future with an estate plan,
legal questions should never stand in
the way. Well, thanks to legal zoom,
they don't the legal world.
It can be challenging without a doubt.
But that's exactly why legal zoom was
created over 15 years ago to provide you
with the tools and knowhow to wrap
up your legal needs with confidence.
You can even receive legal advice and
flat rates from legalzoom's network of
attorneys licensed in 48
states. They'll help you, uh,
with the right estate plan or answer any
questions you have about starting and
running your business or
without billing by the hour.
Since legalzoom isn't a law firm
right now, he should be like, Bill,
why aren't you trying
to make this copy funny?
It's because I need to do all of
this shit now cause I have a kid.
I'm getting life insurance. I'm getting
fucking, I'm getting it. You know what?
I'm getting my affairs in
order. Um, call to action.
Don't put it off any longer. You got
to do this guys, if you've got a kid,
you know, women, you got to do
this shit. You know what I mean?
It's always up to the guy to get the
fucking life insurance and all this shit.
Ladies, you got to do it too. What if you
die? We don't have any breasts verses.
What are we going to do?
Hurry to legal zoom.com now and scan.
Start getting your life in order today.
Plus get special savings when you enter
Promo Code [inaudible] at checkout legal
zoom.com. That's legal zoom.com.
All right, that's the podcast.
Have a great weekend. You can't, uh,
I hope this is his greatest Superbowl
as I think it's going to be.
May the best team win.
Congratulations to Atlanta for a year.
Help your team getting there
and all the fans in New England.
I hope it's going to be a great one.
Do Not Watch any pregame or post game.
Do what I do. Have some friends over.
Get the real golden taped the game.
Shut your phones off.
They'll look at a computer.
Let the gang get 90 minutes
out in front of you.
Then sit down and fast forward through
all the commercials to halftime.
Show all of the bullshit you'll catch
up with the rest of the world around.
Fucking, uh, I dunno, late third
quarter, early fourth quarter.
Then you can turn your fucking phone
on and you can read all your, uh,
your friends go on all day, dude, dude,
I called it and then see
how fucking wrong they are.
You can read it and you know,
rather than having to deal with them,
you probably should.
I mean personally I keep my phone off
for the whole game cause I don't want to
be distracted. It's the most
important game of the year. And uh,
we will see what happens.
We will know the next time you hear the
soothing sounds of my freckled voice.
Go fuck yourselves.
Have a great weekend.
Hey
silver, I don't know what the fuck
is going on with this g cast name.
This is the second time
I've baffled for 50 minutes.
I've done a hundred minutes
of podcasts this fucking week.
And every time I do along, I don't know.
I don't know if I'm talking too long.
I don't know what the fuck's going on.
But the only thing it seems
to be publishing is these
little snippets here when
I'm fucking pissed and it didn't
fucking work. So if you know,
what am I page? Usually I do one of these
every fucking weekend. It works. Alright,
there's other ones. Listen to those
ones. I don't know what's going on. I,
I don't know.
I don't fucking know what a God damn week.
Hey, what's going on? It's still, and
this is the Monday morning podcast,
I hope. And um, I don't
know what to do here.
Should I just keep babbling
because it seems that up.
I just go, you know, test
one, two, three cunt,
and then I hang up.
It doesn't have a fucking problem with,
uh, with, with just posting a short one.
But then when I babbled for like an hour,
at least this was last week.
I'm judging this entire
thing on last week.
So I want to take a leap of faith here
and I'm just going to do this God damn
podcast hoping that it's going
to save itself with that.
Hey, what's going on? It's bill bird.
It's the Monday morning
podcast for the week of, uh,
what the hell was it
February 1st February 2nd?
Is that what it is? I
don't know. Um, yeah.
What'd you guys think of the Superbowl?
Did you like it?
Did you think it was amazing?
You know, it was like,
it was like that movie stepbrothers.
I don't know if you saw it like
stepbrothers, the first fucking half hour,
40 minutes you're watching it going,
this might be the worst
fucking movie I've ever seen.
And then all of a sudden it just
became hilarious. And I was like, wow,
I think I got to own this on DVD.
That's what I felt like the
super bowl was like, you know,
first fucking, I dunno what,
three and a half quarters,
uh, whatever. Congratulations to
the Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh Steelers,
you sons of bitches,
the right back fucking out there.
Six championships. You guys rose
up from the ashes. You know,
you won your four in the 70s,
and then we didn't hear shit from you for
what, almost 20, 25 years or some shit.
And now you're right back out there.
They by the cowboys and 40 niners and
somehow you got three more championships
in the Patriots.
And I got to admit that bugs me.
I was pulling for the
cardinals just for the simple,
a simple fact that I didn't
want to be three behind you,
but you got to admit
you guys fucking won it.
I didn't think Ben Roethlisberger
had that in them. And uh,
Jesus Christ, why am I breaking down
the game? Like I'm on fucking ESPN.
Nobody gives a shit bill.
No one gives a fuck. Um,
so anyways,
last week I tried to do a podcast and uh,
I gotta admit I'm a little burned out
on these fucking things. You know,
last week it just really
took a lot out of me.
I'm not saying I don't enjoy doing them,
but I did two 50 minute fucking podcasts
and I went to hit save and the fucking
computer voice is just like, uh,
we having technical difficulties,
goodbye. And we just hang up just
like that. There wasn't even,
there wasn't even a, I'm sorry. You know,
if you have a problem, maybe you could,
you could, you know, dial
this number. It was just like,
we're having technical difficulties,
goodbye. And the way she says goodbye.
It was like, go fuck yourself, you know,
to 50 minute podcasts.
Do you know how my fucking left
ear was red for like three days?
Talking on the phone that fucking
long and I had nothing to show for it.
You know, my 14 listeners just,
just hanging in the balance,
waiting to hear the results
of the contest of who could,
can come up with an original.
I've got my fucking prostate tickled joke,
you know,
with a bill burr.
Why do I do this DVD hanging in
the balance and what do I get?
What do I get? I get some shitty
ass fucking computer voice goodbye.
Um,
who is that computer voice anyways?
You know what I mean?
I hope it's in an abusive relationship,
you know, and that's not even
advocating violence against women.
I'm advocating violence against that
female can computer fucking voice needs to
be slapped around by a God damn.
What is it an android?
Is that what happens nowadays?
You know,
this is what happened to you the other
day. Um, I went to the Superbowl party,
went to a Superbowl party and uh,
everything was going great. And, um,
I was feeling like the party was
enjoying me and my presence and a,
I don't know how it happened. Somehow
I just became that fucking guy again.
The Guy who was ruining the party,
somehow somebody brought up Bob
Dylan and I was just like, you know,
I've tried so hard to listen
to that guy, but I, I,
I kinda think he sucks, you know, I
can't understand what he's saying.
And even when I've looked at
his lyrics, like, you know,
I don't think that that deep
at a time they are changing,
you know, I don't mind, I don't
mind that tangled up in blue.
That's an all on its
own. He May, he would do.
And the hobbit even open a,
how would they even Alberta who
tangled up in blue, you know,
by doing a hacky fuck it,
I really am doing really well.
The hackiest impressions out
there other than Jim from taxi,
I'm doing a fucking bad Bob Dylan.
So I just said, you know, you know,
this is what I really didn't have an
opinion one way or the other about Bob
Dylan.
I kind of thought he was okay.
But I always read Rolling Stone
magazine Cause uh, you know,
I'm always going to airports and
it comes out every couple of weeks,
whatever the fuck it
does. So I always, uh,
I always pick it up and you know,
the,
the upper level management
of rolling stone, I mean,
I guess that from the 60s and in their
world, Bob Dylan can do no wrong.
And you know,
I dunno the guys on like his 85th album
and t still getting rave reviews and
rolling stones.
Just one of Bob's greatest
fucking work since his seventies,
eighth album. You know what I mean? I
don't know. Maybe I'm just a Douche.
So it started with that and
then Bruce Springsteen was the,
the halftime show and I just,
that's another guy I just look at and I,
I don't know what everybody's
so going crazy about,
you know, I'm just singing about
factories in New Jersey. I don't get it.
Him sliding on his knees into the camera
and doing that stupid yoga pose on that
strip pole when he started out and
doing the poison with the fucking guitar
around your back. I just, I don't get it.
And I at that point,
well only couple of beers in and
after saying that Bob Dylan Song,
I then said Bruce Springsteen sucked,
which then moved on to people getting
uh, you know, in a funny way, upset.
And next thing you know, I had three
people semi yelling at me going, well,
you know, you know, who would you have?
Who would you have for the halftime show?
Huh? Who would you have? And I couldn't
come up with anybody. So I just said,
you know what I'd have, I'd have a fucking
marching band the way they used to,
when only sports fans watch the
fucking show. And they worked,
they just showed you a football game and
they weren't trying to sell me the next
fucking Brittany Spears album.
How about that one? You know,
back in the day and those
racist white guys would, would,
would show up to the games
wearing a fucking short sleeve,
Michael Douglas falling down white button
up shirt with the black tie and those
Malcolm x, Vince Lombardi glasses
and a crew cut. All right.
That's the football I remember.
So then they started calling
me grant Grand Torino like
I was Clint Eastwood. Um,
has anybody seen that movie by the way?
You know, I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know if I want to watch Clint
for fucking an hour and a half going,
you know, get off my lawn. Hey,
you person of another race gate at a here.
That's a really weird movie. When you
think of the concept, like, you know,
what is the Grand Torino represent?
Like back when things were better,
when people had pride and there was more
racism or at least overt racism in this
country. Is that what the
message was? Well, I dunno, Bill,
why don't you go see the fucking
movie before you rip it apart? Well,
speaking of that, um, we do
a lot of, um, Jesus Christ.
I hope that this fucking
thing is recording right now
because I really feel like
a, this is going to be a decent podcast
here cause I've got a nice segue speaking
of a, of movie reviews, you know,
a lot of you guys have sent me move your
views about stuffs you liked and then
you've trashed movies that,
um,
that you haven't liked.
And I got to tell you something.
Somebody took the piss out of that.
I've never with a fuck is it?
Oh, you're such, oh, here
we go. I got it right here.
Somebody fucking did a review of Slumdog
millionaire and you have to like sort
of enjoy a movie and then you meet
somebody and they so rip it to shreds so
convincingly that you start thinking,
hey, maybe it did suck. You know,
I saw a, I saw Slumdog millionaire. I
took my girlfriend there with her mom.
She was in town and they loved it. Yeah.
You know, it's a chick flick or whatever.
But, uh, I walked away from it
thinking like a, you know, wow,
I should've been more of a romantic,
you know,
instead of the fucking asshole that I am.
That's what I got out of the movie.
But I thought, well, you know, I thought
it was a decent movie, but here's this.
But now that this dude fucking trashed it,
I don't know if I could ever watch it
again. Here is this guys. Okay. Overrated.
Slumdog millionaire. All right, buckle
up for this one. All right, here we go.
This is his review.
Imagine a Sally Struthers sponsor,
a child add meets faces of
death meets Forrest Gump.
Let me read that a little more
clearer. I apologize. In the worst,
imagine a Sally Struthers sponsors a
child add meets faces of death meets
Forrest Gump. The first 90 minutes,
first 90 minutes of of is a kid.
Kit's covered in shit,
sleeping on garbage blend in some child
prostitution in a guy running around
looking like the cover art on rage
against the machines. First record,
we see the kids mom get beat to death. Not
once, but at least three fucking times.
The movie is like transformers or any
other bombastic chase scene blow up flick.
But instead of Bruce Willis
fucking up cars, kids get abused,
abused to shock and awe.
The audience.
It also has more cliches
and a cop buddy flick,
the Indian guy works at
a call center in Mumbai,
Mumbai for cell phones and says shit like,
well,
we'll just live on love.
Am I butchering this?
And to top it off, fate and luck
make the Indian guy rich and happy.
Is that what they want us
to believe in these days?
Just let things happen to us
and we'll get by really the,
that overhype Turd got 10 Oscar
nominations that Godfather got 11 because
Slumdog millionaire has
poor people in India.
No one has the balls to stand up and
say it's just a glorified B movie.
The academy thinks they need to teach
the American public a lesson just like
they did with crash
and Brokeback mountain.
This snuff flick is not a meaningful
comment on the human condition either.
It's just another marketing con job.
And as,
as much so as Michael Bolton and as
much substance as a John Grisham novel,
Jesus Christ.
I think it's that last
paragraph that got me.
Um,
I got to agree with you on that.
The academy thinks they need
to teach America lesson.
I don't think that they need that.
I think the academy doesn't really hang
out with anybody other than the academy.
So whenever they see
a movie about tragedy,
about a group of people they
don't really know anything about,
they automatically say it's brilliant
because I'm gonna tell you something right
now.
I agree with you.
Crash sucked and will be fucking sucked.
It wasn't groundbreaking. There
was nothing going on. It was hacky.
It was, it was, the whole thing
was fucking stupid. And, uh,
when I saw Oprah going on TV going, oh
my God, this is such an important movie,
it's like, no, it is an Oprah.
It's not an important movie. Okay.
You don't know what the fuck you talking
about and you don't read all those
books that you recommend every
week. Okay? There's no fucking way.
You have time to have
your own fucking TV show,
your own fucking magazine and a weird
relationship with a cocker Spaniel and
read a 400 page fucking novel every week.
All right,
so you've got no credibility with me.
Okay. And that movie Brokeback mountain,
that was two gay guys fucking in a tent.
You know, it's basically a chick flick.
It's like, uh, I dunno. Grizzly
Adams meets Harvey milk.
No, that's not good. We
need something gay in there.
It's like the ice capades
meets, uh, a fistful of dollars
that gets shoved up your
host. Thank you. Um, no,
I gotta you know something I think, yeah.
Slum dog millionaire. I, it's actually,
I think it's a really good movie.
I actually should have done the whole
spoiler alert then cause I realized
halfway through that review,
he wasn't necessarily reviewing it as
he was just sort of telling you what
happens. Um, I should've
just read the last paragraph.
So I apologize to any, uh, chicks out
there who wanted to go see that movie.
It's definitely a good movie. Um,
you should go see it. How about that?
Does that make you feel better? Um,
but anyways, well, I don't know.
What do you guys think about this?
You know, that's another thing.
If you knew my podcast,
um,
I realized that I'm a fucking moron if
you haven't figured that out for yourself
yet. So I asked questions
like I asked, um,
I was kind of curious,
being an angry guy.
I had a question about
Asian culture where, um,
you know, I just don't see the
anger, you know what I mean? Like,
uh, I went, um, they got this
fucking skating rink out in Burbank,
some of the worst ice I've
ever skated on my life.
And I was talking a couple of weeks ago
how I was skating over there and it was
in the middle of the day,
cause I hate going to the fucking gym.
So I figured I'll just start skating
around Lego FHEG in the middle of the day.
There was no way for me to say I went ice
skating by myself in the middle of the
day and just not feel like the biggest
pansy ever. But I did it. Okay. Goddammit.
And I came home and I jerked off to some
heterosexual porn just to make sure I
was still okay. But anyways, um,
so I'm sitting there and skate
and skating around there,
skating around and just know that thing,
letting the momentum take me
where it wants to go. And, uh,
there was this group of Asian kids
there and the fucking two of them kept
falling down on the ice really fucking
hard and they never seem to get upset.
They always laughed and I was
just like, you know, really,
I can see the first couple of times you
feel silly that some girls there you
with Elap,
but at some point you gotta be like,
you got to start to realize that it's
killing your opportunity to get to hook up
and then don't you start getting mad.
But they never did.
So I asked the question
where is the anger?
So somebody wrote in and said,
Bill, I'm Japanese American,
but uh,
I and I have witnessed my fair share
of East Asian enigmas I think I have an
explanation for the ice
skating ass busting,
unyielding Asian persistence
for not phenomenon. Yeah.
Cause the dude just kept getting
up. He'd laugh, he get up,
he wouldn't even dust the
snow off the back of his head.
He just just kept going and he
was happy as hell. Was fascinated,
fascinated with that level of,
I dunno, denial or happiness.
But I want to have that look on my face
at some point in my life and I'm 40 my
life's half over. So anyway,
she goes, uh, as you know,
Asian people, especially men are
robots. I actually, I didn't know that.
Um,
they aren't programmed to show frustration
or anger after many failed attempts.
This is in large part why they can defy
the laws of physics in the fields of
gymnastics and can do martial arts
in the air and the lung rooftops.
All right, she's breaking my balls
here. Let me finish this. Ah, however,
even though they generally are void of
most emotions, especially in public,
Asians are weak to the layer of booze.
They get rosy cheek wasted
and nothing can sell either.
Alcohol induced getting this,
not even repeated ice to ask impact.
So my suspicion is that you witnessed
just that the mechanical persistence of
uncoordinated robots,
Aka Drunk Asians on ice.
You know, that would be a great, you know,
there'll be a great shelf
drunk Asians on ice that would,
that speaking of the Icecapades,
whoever thought that that
would come back around again.
Fucking drunk Asians on ice would
put the ice capades out of business,
kind of lazy UFC hurting wrestling
at this point. You know what I mean?
That would be the fucking UFC of ice.
Capades drunk Asians on ice.
Um, all right, so many ways you guys
want to get into the contest here.
I want to try to keep this
podcast a little bit shorter.
I'm already up to 17 minutes here.
I'm gonna try to keep it right around the
half hour mark because I'm afraid that,
you know, I'm using up too much
digital time here. So anyways,
as a most of you guys
know, um, I said I was 40,
so I got the physical and then I had
to get the old prostate fucking exam.
And, uh, I was, uh, I was
upset by it, you know,
because unlike heath ledger,
I wasn't in a tent.
I'm somebody who wasn't whispering sweet
nothings to me. And it was, it was very,
it was very fucking disturbing and a,
I wanted to talk about it on stage,
but so many comedians,
any comic,
you know who's had that
procedure done to them,
fucking has gone on stage and
talked about it. So I'm just like,
there's no way for me to talk about it.
Every joke has hackey so I asked my 14
listener fucking podcast audience if they
could come up with an a,
if they could come up with an
original prostate exam fucking joke,
they, um, I would do it on stage and
they would, they would win a fucking DVD.
So here are the finalists and you guys
are going to vote on these so I can keep
the whole interaction of this tremendous
podcasts going. All right, here is a,
here's number one,
entry number one,
trying to a given a range on an
original spin on the prostate exam.
Please forgive my reading out loud
because I really noticed on this one,
I'm just not getting any better at it.
And you know what's happens too,
is the second I start fucking it up,
I start panicking in my head just like
when I was in fourth grade and then I try
to rush to the end of
it. And uh, you know,
it just brings back bad memories.
I remember one time I read out loud in
the fourth grade and I got so fucking
nervous and I kept screwing up everything
that I just started reading faster and
faster. And when it was, you
know, cause I basically, I,
I figured out that everyone,
everyone was reading two paragraphs out
loud and I fucked up halfway through the
first sentence. So then I just [inaudible]
off to the next, the rest of it,
you know, thinking I got out of it
and at the end of it the teacher said,
I didn't understand one word. He said,
did anybody else understand them?
You know, I know. And
then nobody said anything.
And then she made me
fucking reread it again.
And by then my mouth was completely
dry, you know, and it was a,
I know it still affects me not like a
prostate exam, but it still affects me.
So let's get on with the content
there. All right. Prostate,
prostate joke number one.
Now I got admit,
I thought you guys were just
going to write quick little jokes,
but people were writing
colonists chunks on this shit.
So a fucking, I'm going to have to relive
my fourth grade nightmare here. Okay,
joke number one. All right. Keep
score at home so he can, you can,
you can vote for which one you
like. Here's number one, Bill.
You addressing the audience.
Okay,
well thank you for the direction and
didn't think I'd be turned around
addressing the curtain or a
fucking you in the green room.
Just talking to yourself.
All right, so everyone, um,
I went and got violated by my doctor
today. You've heard this story,
a horror story before
I got a prostate exam.
You've probably also heard the joke about
who the hell would ever want to grow
up and do shit like that on a daily basis?
Well,
what I want to know is what kind of a
person goes to school to learn how to
teach other people, more people, how
to do that shit on a daily basis.
What kind of fucking sadistic teacher?
What kind of say it as teachers,
other people,
the proper way to shove a
finger up someone else's ass.
They'd have to be a sadist.
I could imagine the prep professor
in the science practice lab with the,
the other dummies going, hey
Bobby, you being a little too soft.
You really need to shove
it up there. Good. And dig
around for that prostate. No,
no, no, no, no. Step aside, I'll
show you the proper technique.
Wait til they either screen or whimper
like a little kid. Then there's more,
I love this. This is more direction for
me. Walk to the other area of the stage.
The person really went all out. Uh, okay.
So evidently I walked to the other
side of the stage and evidently there's
another patient over there. At which
point I say, how are we doing over here,
George? You need to remember the lube
or you're going to get sued. Uh, oh,
I get it. The doctor wasn't using
any lube. Okay. Jesus Christ.
You're not wearing any gloves either.
George,
we've got to stop letting these
legacy students in fucking morons.
Uh, you could get a slip, serious blister
or shit on your finger or something.
Jesus Christ. Dude, you really
getting disgusting though. All right.
Here's the final bit. Now
class, most importantly,
you need to develop your emotionless.
You're emotionless. Face skills.
I'm serious.
You want an a in this class?
You better have a stone cold face after
you violate all the dummies. No laughing.
When they scream for mercy. I'm
serious. They have speakers with audios.
What? I'm serious. They have
speakers with audio screams,
custom fitted by me.
I'm serious. All right.
I don't get what the fuck that last
line means, but you know, there you go.
That's halfway decent. Do the whole doctor
thing, I guess. I Dunno, right? Number.
This is number two of the
colonists chunks and I apologize.
All right, that's joke number
one. Now with my skills,
I'm obviously only reading these ones,
so please keep score at home. All right?
You get to do a little American
idol thing here. All right. Uh,
all right, well the fuck are we. Ah, Bill,
I completely agree with you that there's
no real ground to break on the prostate
exam exam jokes, but want you,
but once you say free DVD,
my brain's shorts circus.
So below is my best attempt.
All right. My wife and I had been
together for 15 years. In that time,
I've gone to the doctor once,
she's probably gone 50 times that
John Wayne Act comes at a price.
There are procedures, there are procedures
for every one inch of a woman's body.
I lifts breast lifts,
Tummy Tucks,
someone with eight years of educations
that one of the finest schools on earth,
Spanish time figuring out how to inject
blowfish toxins into women's faces.
So they'd look younger
and it doesn't stop there.
Look at this using classic standup
jargon and it doesn't stop there. People,
what's the mammographic machine cost?
You know what cost a lot.
And what does it do? It crushes tits.
A cat scan machine cost a lot too,
but it can be used for anything. It's
a cat scan. Might be a little noisy,
a little scary if you have claustrophobia,
but it doesn't injure you.
A mammogram takes one of the most
sensitive parts of the human anatomy,
anatomy and it presses it until it
hurts. That's it. $1 million please.
But guys, gotta be tough. No doctor
visits unless something's falling off.
So what fantastic piece of
Jetson technology that we get,
we get some MIT created. Do we get
some MIT created imaging machine?
No. Uh, doctors index finger,
the same finger that he uses to
get the intention of a bad waiter.
That's the detective
equipment plus a rubber glove.
I grew up in the seventies and eighties.
I don't always remember
rubber gloves to you.
Back in the 60s when you'd see
a doctor smoking on TV shows.
Did they have gloves or do they just
have a bar of lava soap over on the side?
Think like a mechanic. Sorry,
I didn't shake your hand, ted.
Now doc rarely. That's okay. So those,
his prostate exam one, by the way,
I don't have anybody, you know,
you guys sent me your addresses,
but I saved all your emails. So, um,
next week when I announced the winner,
um, I do have your original email.
So any you fucking dirt bags out there
who can try to pretend to be these people.
I have all the original emails, so if you
win, please send me your address. Okay,
here's a couple more. Uh, well
I see this is number three.
That last one was number two and the
previous one was number one. Okay.
You guys, you guys all caught up. All
right, number three. Um, all right bill.
I see you got your ass
tickled the other day.
I don't know if anyone's
ever done this angle,
but you ever thought about one of
those ass tickling doctors being gay?
Not saying that he
enjoyed tickling your ass,
but more like the same way
if you're dating agendas,
your friends think stuff like,
ah man,
she must really know how to do some
freaky shit cause she's so flexible.
A gay guy would be like, hey, I'm dating
one of those. Ask tickling doctors.
And then as other gay
friends would be like, wow,
he must really know his way around an
asshole. I Dunno, that kind of sucked,
but give me a DVD. You know what, dude?
I don't think that did kind of suck.
I'm going to be a little Simon
here and say, ah, that, you know,
that wasn't that bad. That was actually,
you know what? That was pretty original.
Yeah. Why am I met? You guys fucking
decide I'm the goddamn comedian here.
You know what? Fuck you guys
right now. That one's in the lead.
So you guys put your pens down.
I just really killed a couple
of people's dreams there.
People sitting in their cubicles, you
know, people actually tell me that some,
some people out there that actually
listened to these podcasts to get through
airplane flights because I
make them so fucking long,
which means now there's possibly somebody
sitting on an airplane listening to
the podcast, which I think
is really cool. And, uh,
you know, I feel bad for you that
you're on a plane and uh, you know,
how ugly is the person sitting
next to you? By the way,
that's one thing that always annoys
me about when I get on a flight is,
I don't know if this
ever happens you guys,
but there's somebody good looking
ever sit next to you. You know, when,
when to fucking hot chicks fly across
the country because it's never on my
flight. Or when they in
shape guys, you know,
how can horrific looking people and I'd
say I'm helping anything. But you know,
if you're on a plane right now,
just pretend like you're turning around
to see if the bathroom's available and
just look at the people. Do it. I'll
wait. Good. Turn around. Look at him.
Look at him. Look at the, look at that
fat headed Jack. Big Fred Flintstone.
Look at fucking idiot
sleeping with his mouth open.
It's just horrific. You know what
it is? It's the private jets.
All good looking people flying.
Those little fucking private jets
just left all the ugly people in coach,
you know,
which is what I'm flying by the way.
I'm not trying to put myself above people.
Bill, can you get back to the
contest? Fine. I will. All right.
Entry number for bill.
You know the classic family dinner scene
where everyone is asking each other
things like how was work today?
Well,
there's really no fucking way you can
ask your dad or husband to give you a
legitimate response to that question
if they're approch tologist because in
reality he's been finger
and dudes all day and a,
you're trying to finish a potato salad.
You know what?
That was a funny line and I butchered it.
God dammit.
There's no way to legitimately ask a
proctologist that because he's been
figuring dudes all day and you're
trying to finish a potato south.
That my friend is a funny fucking line.
So all his answers have to
revolve around parking spots,
routes to work or maybe a
receptionist birthday cake. Also,
how scared of the other dudes
faces in the waiting room.
And that's to be similar to
the look soldiers gave each
other before stoning the
storming the beaches of
Normandy. Dude, you know what?
That's actually really true.
I couldn't look at anybody when I was in
there, and especially when I walked out,
when I walked out, I looked at the
floor, remember that? Remember that?
And the pope of Greenwich Village
and then you tell her she can't
say goodnight to nobody that way.
She got to look at the floor
when she walks out, Charlie.
That's what I was doing.
I looked out, I walked out looking
at the fucking floor. You know?
They know it's funny,
as the guys in the waiting
room technically could
have given me shit because
they still have the option of running out,
which is exactly what the fuck they
should've done. They should've ran out.
Just fucking hazed me all the way back
to the fucking elevator, Angie like that,
Angie like that. Your little
fucking Douche. All right. Um,
I think I got one more here.
You know what?
You guys can decide on these
fucking things. I'm not doing that.
That was Joe was number four. That was
joke number four. Pick up your pen.
That was number four. All right, here's
number five and this is this one.
This guy is actually,
you know what?
Those are the four you can choose from
and this guy here is going to win an
honorary DVD cause he didn't email me.
I was actually in Houston,
Texas and this fucking guy,
I was doing radio on location in some bar,
one of those fucking sports bars and
people are drinking beers and eating
chicken wings if fucking
10 in the morning. And I'm,
and I'm doing radio in there
and as I come walking out,
I don't know how this guy knew I was
coming out, but he timed it perfectly.
First of all, he knew where the fuck
I was. I came walking out in this car,
just pulls right up like
the FBI in good fellas,
you know, just pulls right up. He's like,
hey bill bar and I've got a little freaked
out. I'm like, Hey, what's going on?
He goes, hey, I got an I got an entry
for the prostate exam joke dude.
I'm in a parking lot in the middle of
fucking Houston outside some fucking dive
bar at 10 in the morning.
I'm not thinking about the podcast,
I'm thinking about going to Denny's
and this fucking guy pulls right up and
hands me two fucking
complete sheets of paper.
Prostate exam material is the heading.
I felt like I was cheating on a test.
You know this guy came back with all the
answers so I can only read half of this
cause I'm already at a half hour and I
want to make sure this thing gets posted.
So is the other one. Here's say
this is the honorary one. Uh, Bill,
I'm not sure how I'll be
able to cope with the day.
I have a prostate exam as it draws nearer.
Of course I realize that I'm eight
years away, but it freaks me out now.
Freaks me out now cause I'm going to be
a fucking mess when the time comes to
can I be a worst fucking out loud reader?
Whatever it is,
you never have to worry about
me being behind a podium.
Let me start this over again and
fucking relax here. It's all right Phil.
There's two pages of stuff. You only
have to read a half of it. Half of it.
You only have to read half of
it. Look at me. I'm flustered.
Bernoulli flustered on my own
podcast. All right, here we go, Bill.
I'm not sure how it be
able to cope with the day.
I have a prostate exam as it draws near.
Of course,
I realize that's about eight years away,
but if it freaks me out now, I'm going
to be a fucking mess when the time comes.
This all spawns from my homophobia and
lack of confidence in my own manhood.
Gotta love honesty in any joke.
I mean, what if I liked the ship?
I'll have to get divorced again.
My kids will have to ask why and
I'll have to tell my son, well,
I left your mom because
I liked the doctors.
Giant sausage fingers poking around
in my asshole and you know what?
It's just not fair to your mother.
Then I'll have to go into why it's
much worse to have enjoyed it during a
medical exam and the ethics involved
as opposed to just be an effect.
You know who I blame society and my God
damn older brother and it's not why you
think he made me watch the hand that
rocks the cradle when I was 15 before I
fully understood how sick that lady's
doctor was for slipping is rubber gloves
off before her exam and he fingered
the shit out of her Jesus Christ.
What kind of movie is that?
You know what I like about this guy?
He's really not soft peddling this joke.
He's really using brutal language here.
Anyways, getting back to the
movie, at first I was like,
why the fuck did they arrest that guy?
That was really fucking smooth.
Keep in mind I was 15 and thought anyway
at all to get my hands face or cock in
on or near a real pussy was
completely acceptable. Think about it.
When you're a kid,
societal rules and judgments don't apply.
If you see a kid shit,
you want it.
You just beat the shit out
of them and you take it,
you go to detention and Google
and who gives a shit? Right?
Of course I came to realize that those
types of things are fucked up and you
don't do that kind of shit.
But to get back to the subject,
when it came time to
learn about prostate exam,
my screwed up fucking head immediately
thought of that movie and I thought to
myself, fuck, what if I'm the guy who
is unlucky enough to get some sick,
perverted,
twisted doctor that wants to slip off
his rubber glove and get as rock off
Brock's off with his gay finger in my ass.
Not only will I have to process being
taken advantage of and violated,
I'm gonna have to reframe from beating
the shit out of the guy to avoid
prosecution.
And then I'm going to have to investigate
the guy and find out who else he
violated,
make a case against him and then go to
group therapy with a bunch of others.
Poor schmucks that got
fingered. All right, dude,
I can not read the rest of his men.
This is like fucking the
original count of Monte Cristo.
It's like 700 pages long.
All right there on the entries.
You tell me who had the best
one on of those first four,
this guy's going to get the honorary
mentioned cause he, you know,
that was actually really original
cause uh, I guess, you know,
I don't know. He fucking, they just,
all right, you want to hear my 2 cents?
I like this guy's angle.
The last guy I had just read because,
uh, I don't know. He made it really
personal and honest and even though,
you know, it was kind of homophobic, he
called himself out for being homophobic,
you know, and, uh, to me, honest with you,
I remember being a kid to
thinking like, you know, I,
I'd love to be a gynecologist.
You know, just being a kid,
you're a fucking pervert,
but you know what it is.
You forget that 80 year old women
also go to the gynecologist, you know,
so it's not a fun job.
So even if you were a gay guy,
you're just because you're a gay guy
doesn't mean you're like all gay guys.
You know what I'm saying?
What happens today?
Lou Grant comes walking in there
and you've got to check. Yes.
It's just really getting gross giving
you or something. You know, I learned,
this is why I don't do
sexual material on stage.
I don't know if you guys have
ever noticed that about me,
but I stay away from it
because I don't find,
I don't know if it's the Catholic guilt,
I just always feel crude, you know,
which is a funny realization that actually
make on this podcast after I had been
talking about prostate exams for
the last fucking two. So anyways,
um, I dunno, I think it's a
toss up between that last guy.
And I also like the guys who said,
what if the guy that that angle where
you know the gay guys going, Oh yeah,
I'm dating a a proctologist and then
the other gay guy friends are looking at
him like he's lucky. Like wow, he must
really know his way around an asshole.
That is such a fucking
valid point because he does.
And I would think that gay guys
would think that shit the same way.
If someone was dating a gymnast,
I'd be like, Jesus Christ,
you must be inventing sexual
positions, you know, so whatever,
whatever you guys send me in the ones
that you like, you gotta tell me why.
And uh, next week, uh, I'll do the big
giveaway. So everybody is that I read,
please send me Your fucking address and
uh, no one, me being a liberal, fuck,
I'll probably send you all DVDs because
I don't want anybody to feel left out.
Okay. So there you go. So how far
are we in here? We're at 37 minutes.
Then once again, this is really long.
Let me get to, uh, you know what,
I'm not going to get to the questions
this week just for the simple fact that
I'm afraid to step that knock on
a law that they're not going to,
you know, post this one.
So before I get Outta here,
I want to thank everybody I
didn't get a chance to last week.
I really want to thank everybody who
came up to see me and, uh, Houston,
Texas last week or two weeks ago,
uh,
I couldn't believe the amount of people
that showed out showed up as we sold out
a couple of shows and um,
they got a new club owner out there who
just really knows what the hell he's
doing. And I'm definitely
going to be back. And uh,
I'd like to thank Nicole for showing up.
Part of my fan club always
coming out to my gigs and a,
and that's it. And this week
I'm up in Boston. I got a,
I got the Wilbur theater on February 6th,
and then I got chickopee,
Massachusetts.
And if you live out in
western Massachusetts,
if you don't want to drive
all the way to Boston,
I'm going to be chickopee Massachusetts.
One of my favorite gigs.
I actually back in the day, I used to
open up the David Allen Greer there,
Bobby Collins,
all these big shots and now I'm there.
So I feel like a big shot. And plus
it's a Chinese fucking restaurant,
you know what I mean? How great is that?
I helped them. When you have stage lights,
I hope my face is just lit up by the
flames of the Pu Pu platter, you know,
and I can tell fucking ghost stories. So
those are my, that's my gig this weekend.
My next gigs I have, I have coming
up. I got a wife, guys in Ogden,
Utah on February 20th,
and then I'm taking a little bit of break
is going to be performing mostly out
here in the La area until uh,
March 26th to the 28th. I will be at, uh,
the house of comedy in East
St Louis, Missouri. So please
come out to see my show.
Thanks everybody for
listening to the podcast.
I really hope you guys get to hear this
one because I'm sick of fucking talking
and not having anybody here at all,
right? That's it. God bless you.
Congratulations to the Pittsburgh
Steelers. And how about those Bruins, Huh?
Beat the Canadians again. Can you
believe it? Can you fucking believe that?
All right.
That's it. Everybody have a
good week. I'll talk to you.
Yeah.
[inaudible].