Hey, what's going on is bill burn
is time for the Thursday afternoon,
just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Ah,
just checking in on you. Yes, I am.
How are you? What's going
on? How is your week going?
You realize it's July, man. The summer
is just, it's just with giveaway.
Do you know how fucking rained
out here yesterday in July?
It's unbelievable.
It never rains out here.
It never rains in California.
But boy don't they warn you it pours man.
It pulls. It just, it
just was this thunder and,
and there was rain and it just
poured down and I was like, Gee,
willikers you know,
I had a couple of shirts drying out on
the fucking porch there because, uh,
you know,
you can do that out here because it
never rains in February and that is it.
There's a little bit of June
gloom and you're like, Ooh, Ooh.
Is it no precipitation, blue
balls? That's all it is.
And yesterday it just was an
absolute downpour. And uh,
like 20 minutes later it was over and
everything was dried up and you would
never know what happened. You know, like
a perfect robbery, like a robbery gone.
Right. Nobody gets it. They get
in, we get up, we get the jewels.
Okay. Blonde. Um,
yeah.
Franco goes in with the others have been,
sorry,
I just combined three different movies,
two different movies,
some like that. I have no
fucking idea. All I know is
a, this is one of these days.
I forgot it was Thursday and I forgot I
had to do a podcast and I have some shit.
Ted Do
some shit to do.
All right.
I am going down to comic con today.
Can you believe that
Belper hater of all marvel
and DC fucking movies.
I don't hate him. I just, I they
do absolutely nothing for me.
You know,
I like the hulk. I'm an angry
fucker. I can relate to him.
Right? I've inhaled a cigar. I've
turned green before. You know,
I can't jump like that. A kid. I can't
crush cars the way he does, but I get it.
I like the hulk.
I liked the way he talks to,
okay,
you know how, how fucking stupid.
He basically talks like Tarzan,
which really made no sense if he was
raised by wolves or whatever the fuck was
going on there. How the fuck he
learned to how to speak English.
You know what I mean?
I can't tell if he was unbelievably
compromised in that relationship with Jane
or if it was a brilliant fucking thing,
cause he could just pretend he didn't
understand what she was saying. You know?
How long into that relationship do you
think before we looked at that little
chimpanzee just fucking rolled his eyes
like, you fucking believe this shit.
Okay, this, this,
this woman would be dead out here without
me at an edge and all she's doing is
bitch moaning and complaining.
All right, we'll live in a nature.
We're perfectly safe. Okay, I'm providing,
we don't have to pay any
taxes. There's like, no,
we're in fucking eating right now.
And they go, Jay, get, go, go, go.
Take a bite on the apple.
Okay.
You know that is one
thing that I've learned
as a 50 year old man. I'll tell you right
now guys, if you're out with the ladies,
okay. Save Your fucking money. Okay.
Do not spend money on women.
Okay?
Do it cause you want to,
but don't do it because you think
it's going to make them happy.
It will in the moment. But I
swear to God, I don't give a fuck.
You could literally buy a woman to
fucking space shuttle. All right?
And put our initials on the
side of it. Okay. And take her,
I dunno where the fuck you do
with the space shuttle. All right.
Whatever the take her to and from work.
I don't like thinning like this.
My hair is like hanging down.
Well,
we can't take off horizontally,
honey.
What am I just getting to work?
I swear to God you don't.
You'd literally be in the Doghouse
within fucking 24 hours of doing that one
stupid comment.
MMM.
It was actually joking with a buddy of
mine the other day. I was saying like,
you know, sentiment, if patching shit
up with your wife was deductible,
I wouldn't pay taxes for
the past three years.
That's all I'm ever doing.
You know?
I feel like the boss's son
who just keeps fucking up,
but for some reason he doesn't get
fired. You know what I mean? It's,
I have to like the 50th time you've done
something wrong that we could just like,
I, I really don't understand how, how did
I, how did I end up in this position? Um,
but that's neither here nor there.
Okay.
If you want to make up with your wife,
take her out for ice cream. Okay.
I'm telling you it's, it's romantic.
It, it gives him a sugar rush.
All right.
They feel like they're in some Tom Hanks
movie and it really doesn't cost that
much money.
You know,
if you can just keep your cool while
you fucking stand in line at the artisan
ice cream place that they want to go to
before you go up there and you order a
mint chocolate chip and they tell you
it's not in season with that happening in
San Francisco, remember that
story? It's not in season.
Then I'm going to cross the street to
the drug store and it came back with a
pint of it. You know, I should've walked
into their fucking ice cream place. Hey,
hey,
here's the deal view. If you want
to get adventurous with ice cream,
follow people under 40.
All right,
can you just want the
old school simple shit.
You follow old people because eventually
they're going to the pharmacy,
right? And that's where they have
chocolate, vanilla, strawberry
patch work,
chocolate chip.
How many flavors were there?
There was mint chocolate chip,
there was peppermint that was like, that
was fancy back then. Not now. It's like,
I don't even know what the fuck it is.
They got candy bars in there.
They got like a,
they have sugar and salt with a shot of
espresso and some sort of social justice
warrior thing written in
fucking a whip cream. You know,
I followed Joe Rogan is most
of the free world does, um,
on Instagram. And I saw this
whole thing about the okay sign.
How funny is that? According
to Joe Rogan, the okay side.
These people is a joke.
Tried to say that you can,
you can find white power in there
like this, which I don't know.
I see three fingers in it in a
zero. I see zero to three. I see 30.
I see, uh, uh, I dunno know if making
shadow puppets, maybe a rooster.
I don't see where the white power is
in it, but they tried to say that.
You could see in there,
I guess the p would be your forearm
up into the circle and then the three
fingers would be the
w, Oh fuck, I'm smart.
Or does that mean I'm racist,
racist, racist. So when he was,
they started it as a joke and then
dopes believed it and then actual,
even bigger dopes,
white supremacists started using it
and now it's actually going to get bad,
you know, which is so fucking
stupid. Like why would you ban that?
You know what I mean? That's
like banning, you know,
let's say it was actually race.
Would you ban somebody going Sieg Heil?
Why would you ban that? Let people do it
then. Then you know who the Nazis are,
right? If you don't let people do
it, then you're like, all right,
is this guy a Nazi or does he know
Jujitsu or was he just a fan of telephone?
Telly Savalas oh no, wait a
minute. That's all freckles.
He showed up to tell some shit jokes,
right? And then all of a sudden,
all the lines get blurred.
Okay.
Okay. You got to let corny
people have this signs.
You know how you doing Seth?
I'm okay.
You gotta let them do that and then
you got to let morons, you know,
fucking do this. SIEG Heil on. I hit
Lou's birthday on April 20th. All right,
well the hippies of behind him
smoking marijuana. Hey Man, like
Nazis, the mellow man, right?
You got to have all those people,
I think. I mean, you'd like to
have not have others, but I,
I really don't think I'll like banning
sides. I've always thought that was,
that was, uh, like I
guess wishful thinking
in my world. If you ban racial gestures
than people aren't racist anymore.
You don't need to fix
what's between their ears.
You just need to fix just stipulations.
When we come back,
Dr Phil will cure a heroin addict
within two commercial breaks.
Uh,
you ne to stop doing heroin and
you need to put on some weight.
You're right,
Dr Phil,
let me shake your hand and subtly steal
your wash so I can cop right behind your
fucking soundstage. Did I say cop?
Yes, I did. That's how old I am.
Uh, you know what's great about being a
parent besides everything is all the fun
fucking size. He gets stuck
in your head. You know, it's,
I'm talking to you guys about Neo
Nazis in my head. I'm singing pop,
pop, pop puppy dog past
a house. But no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no bro Bro. Bro, bro, bro, bro, Bro.
Up pop up pop. You know it was awesome.
Is My daughter sings along to it now?
Yeah,
she just goes pop, pop, pop,
pop. And then anytime they, they,
she just goes dog.
It's funny to parents.
Um, yeah, she's amazing.
Um, I, I get now why people
have like eight kids. I get it.
It's fucking amazing.
I mean if he can just get past being
tired and them eventually hating you
between the ages of about 11 and a,
I don't know,
depending on how much you
actually did do wrong,
it might be the rest of your life, but
usually it, I think it lasts to somewhere.
A mid college
I would think.
I don't know.
I've already thought about how I'm
going to handle their teenage years.
I'm just going to listen. I know, I
know. I'm cramping your style man,
but can you just go to lunch with your
old man? I swear to God. Here's the deal.
I like, I'll let you
walk in first. You know,
just in case some of your
friends are in there. All right.
And then if none of your
friends are in there,
then I'll come in like
the fucking elephant man.
And he will sit down just to have lunch
with me. And if any of friends show up,
you know?
Okay.
I mean, I don't know what to do at that
point. I guess I would walk out, you know,
how amazing is that?
Like,
as this little perfect big that
needs you on such a ridiculous level,
it almost makes you cry
within like 10 years.
He like treats you like the
fucking plague, you know?
I'm kind of excited for it,
for the whole fucking journey because
at the end of the day, I am a loner,
so I think I'll be able
to sub. No, I won't.
Okay.
What'd your own flesh and blood stone
say? Black on you. Um, all right.
I think we need to do some advertising
here. Don't I? At some point,
not all of them. Only 12 minutes in nearly
12 minutes. And you know what I did?
I tell you guys that I watched
the a moto GP from Germany. I uh,
I'm
from Germany and I saw a
fucking Mark Marquez fucking
run down Jorge low Lorenzo.
The, I just don't understand
the whole fucking tire thing.
These fucking guys,
whenever they use the soft tire,
they're always leading in the beginning
and then eventually the soft tires to
fucking soft, it starts to wear
down and then they're fucked.
You know?
I mean at this point,
the way Mark Marquez is winning,
why don't you just go, well,
what is mark going to use today?
The give ourselves a fighting chance
because as far as I know, Jorge, Luis,
Lorenzo, he fucking uh, he won a
championship three years ago. Right?
Mark has his one for the last five.
Let me look this up.
Moto g p Jambi almost.
Am I on the right
Internet? Okay, here we go.
Okay.
Oh God. They just let me know who.
Okay. How about Valentino Rossi? Huh?
Always making the podium.
That's a weird thing in racing that I
don't get how you get too old to do it.
I mean, as long as you are fucking,
especially race car driver,
as long as you have foot works,
can you press down on the gas?
I mean the engine has to go 200
miles an hour. You don't, right.
I mean it just kind of ride along.
All right. But I guess your reflexes,
your reflexes get, uh,
aren't as good. And then, um,
I dunno. You just stop winning.
It's crazy. All right. So basically,
okay,
first of all,
shout out to Spain because since 2010
a Spaniard as one at every year except
2011 when arguably the greatest
motorcycle name of all time.
Casey stoner.
One more time.
Casey stoner, one in 2011. All right,
Mark Marquez won it in 2017 2016 Jorge
Lorenzo won it in 2015 and then 2014 2013
was Mark Marquez,
Jorge Lorenzo was 2012 Casey stoner,
please report to the principal's office.
2011 and 2010 was Jorge Lorenzo.
And then the previous decade was the
Valentino Rossi show where that genius won
it seven times in nine years.
Honorable Mention to Casey and
2007 and also the last American,
the last Yank to win at 2006.
Nikki. Hey, what's going on?
Do you still riding the fucking
motorcycles kit Doty was crazy.
He was doing fucking wheelies
in the seventh grade.
And we also want in 2000
with Kenny Roberts Jr um,
Valentino Rossi won in 2001,
2002,
2003 2004 2005,
2008 and 2009 and he was
riding Hondas in the beginning,
2001, two and three. And
then the unthinkable,
he switched to Yamaha and everybody
thought it was an inferior product.
And not only did he fucking
went with them, he won four
times with Yamaha. Yamaha.
There you go. There's some
quick motorcycle history.
I don't know shit about it,
but somebody who watches this shit,
please explain to me why you
would ever run a race. Right?
Or race on the fucking soft tire.
The super soft. So whatever.
They always seem to blister
or just they shit the bed,
right when it counts.
It's like you lead the whole fucking race,
you know,
and then all of a sudden
with like 15 to 12 laps left,
all of a sudden somebody with a medium
tire or something like that just runs you
down.
You know,
the soft tire is sort of the, uh,
the heartthrob of the tire industry.
You know what I mean? Well, if you're
basing your whole life on your looks,
I mean you're, you're, you
know, you're going to have,
your career's going to be pro probably
shorter than a professional athletes
cause you're going to get old
and somebody else younger,
it's going to come along. But the
medium, I think the medium tires,
the way to go, it seems to be the wake
up way to go. I have no fucking idea,
but all I know is a,
I have to figure out a way next year
in April to get to that Goddamn Moto GP
race. But anyways, I didn't mention
why are you going to comic con bill?
Why are you going to Indianapolis Bill?
I'm going down the first time
I'm flying a helicopter down. Uh,
it's the first time I've flown since
May tope I remember how to do this shit.
I'm flying with an instructor.
Everybody relax.
So I'm flying down there and I am,
uh,
is it moderating hosting?
Um,
I'm sitting down for an hour in
front of a crowd of 6,000 people.
Yeah.
And I am hosting, uh,
what do you call it? The,
uh,
the cast of better call Saul.
I'm getting to interview all of those
people and I'm going to see Vince Gilligan
for the first time in a long time,
which can be great.
I'm going to thank him for giving
me an acting career and, uh,
and then afterwards,
uh,
some of the cast of breaking bad's going
to come out and then we're going to do
an hour with them.
And um,
yeah,
I dunno.
I don't know why I, this is one of
these gigs where I was like, yeah,
I'd to do that. And then the second I,
you know, the day comes and I'm like,
wait, what am I on my fucking,
what the fuck am I going to say?
But I know that everybody's got great
stories, so all I gotta do is just,
I just got to set people up.
I did this recently on another show
that escapes me. I have no fucking idea
what I am. I short term memories for Shit.
I have no idea. But anyways, it's
going to fly down to San Diego.
I'm going to a host,
both those things and I get to watch
the premiere of better call Saul.
You know what's better than that? Then
I come back, you know better call Saul,
one of my favorite actors
on television right now.
Joe To Rosa Smoking Joe to Rosa.
Oh by the way, by the way, you know.
Okay.
Very strong rumors,
very strong rumors that Belper and Joe
Rosa a back together in talks about
getting uninformed going again,
very strong rumors.
Remember when guns and roses was getting
back together and everybody isn't going
to happen.
Is it going to happen?
You know what?
Guess what?
Yeah,
I'm sitting down with old
fucking Joe to Rosa next week
to see if I can figure
out a way to get to,
to fit myself into is incredible busy
schedule as an actor yet to be nominated
for an Emmy.
But we all know it's inevitable.
I sound like a break in his balls, but
I think he's fucking great on that show.
And uh, I can't wait for
this season. And, um,
it is a beyond an honor that
Vince asked me to do this.
So I just hope I don't fuck
it up to be honest with you.
You don't.
Um,
and I also don't know how, how do
I get into this? I mean, can I,
can I talk about like how last season
ended without getting stampeded by 6,000
nerds? Go and see. Spoiler
alert man. All right,
everybody. Okay, here we
go. I got a little bit of a,
some advertising three here.
Um,
Hey, Nia is the OBL almost ready? Ah,
Shit. All right, I gotta get in there.
All right.
Okay.
Butcher box,
put your box delivers healthy 100% grass
fed and grass finished beef free range,
organic chicken and heritage breed pork.
The incredible quality of butcher box
means start with the commitment to raising
animals humanely and free of antibiotics
and hormones before you kill them.
Each box comes with at least
nine to 11 pounds of meat,
which is enough for 24 individual
size meals. Unless you're a fat fuck,
which probably you'll go
through that in three days.
You can choose from five different
box types. All beef, beef and chicken,
beef and mixed
box.
Custom box.
Okay.
Custom box lets you choose your own cuts.
Oh Man.
That's when you throw
it down at the grill.
That's when your eyes light up
like a kid in a candy store.
I get to pick my own guts.
Antibiotic slash hormone free.
No, we're not talking about bill
burr. We're talking about butcher box.
Put your box believes in a healthier
food system where everyone has access to
meets the way nature intended,
the way you used to be able to do it.
When you went hunting with a musket,
the only foreign object in that thing
was the little pellet that you shot into
its brain.
Nature intended free of antibiotics and
hormones and humanely raised on an open
pasture before they kill
him. Butcher, Buck selection,
butcher box.
Carefully cure rates to find a selection
and cuts and it makes it a breeze to
customize your own delivery.
Build your own box to get exactly what
you and your family love. By the way,
we're talking about butcher box, not
a robot. You can have sex with you.
Weirdo nerds.
Jude,
your delivery frequency with the custom
customizable subscription recipes are
available on butcher box websites and
videos are available to follow along on
butcher box youtube channel.
I'm going to tell you something
right now that heritage,
I cannot say enough
about the heritage pork.
Okay.
Heritage breed pork, it's, it's the
best pork chop I've ever made. It home,
delicious my mouth waters when I read
this, when I read this article. All right,
to receive free mated for life.
To think that while I was just on the
Jim Jeffrey show and he had the nerve to
say that America is not number one,
okay?
When you can actually
live in this country,
choose your own cuts of beef and win
Free Bacon for life plus $10 off your
order.
Go to butcher box.com click on the big
bacon banner on the homepage and use the
burpee you are are at checkout.
Go now. Limited time offer.
Please let Jim Jefferies know that he
is in the best country in the world
because you can win free bacon for life.
Um,
I did a show on a Tuesday and I have such
a great time with him. It's like, uh,
you know, he said this thing about
me said, he goes, some people,
people ask me about bill burr. I say
he's going to make a great 80 year old.
But the great thing about Jim is he's
a bit of a curmudgeon too, you know,
so we have to fucking chromogens
from different hemispheres,
the northern and southern hemisphere
and together we form a global force of
grumpiness. Um, I should
actually post the link to,
to that interview.
I had a great time when a show and uh,
I would like to do more often there.
I said it,
Postmates as usual,
your stomach and the rest of your
life are at war. You need to eat,
but you can't stop what
you're doing to deal with it.
And the only fast things that
deliver are not what you want.
Introducing Postmates,
the APP that adds a delivery option two,
your favorite restaurants. Imagine
anything you want to eat delivered.
You don't have to drive,
park or even talk to a f two the phone
talk on the phone to order Jesus Christ.
Just download the APP in order to 24
hours a day, 365 days, days a year.
You don't have to interact with anybody.
You can be completely naked doing this.
Just make sure you throw in a row before
the uh, the fucking guy gets there.
Or lady or person transgender.
I don't know what I'm
supposed to say these days.
Postmates will bring you what
you want within the hour.
You can even see where your
food is and track your driver.
Can we watch them to make sure
he's not eating some of your fries?
You forget to get eggs and milk,
no problem. Craving a tasty burger.
Check looking for the perfect bottle
of red wine or summer bare order up.
Oh,
that sounds delicious.
19 days into sobriety of fucking
summer Ale. Postmates is,
I only got 11 more days of this shit. 12
more days. Then I'm back on and August.
Postmates is your new longterm
munchies booty call for a limited time.
Postmates is giving you $100 of free
delivery credit for your first seven days
to start your free deliveries.
Download the APP today and use your code
burr 100 that's code bar 100 for $100
of free delivery credit for your
first seven days. Save the hassle,
man.
Get the food you love that Postmates
with code burr 100 unlike that,
I might steal that per 100. How did
the bird 100 thing come about? Well,
I stole it from Pa Postmates to make it
seem like I'm giving a hundred percent
effort to everything that I do. I'm like
p diddy without the effort. All right.
Huddle. Do you have eyes?
Sure. Most of us do.
Do not the do they not work
as well as they should? Yeah,
you should see the size of the
font that I'm reading here.
Do you like spending less money on
things than more money on things?
Yes.
I love how easy these questions are.
School is this easy? I would
have gone to Harvard. Uh,
do you know what the Internet is?
If yes,
then visit Hubble,
context.com Hubb Ellie
Hubble contacts.com.
That sounds like a nickname of wife
would give to her fat husband. Oh,
it's my humble. Uh, talk about how
when you started out in comedy,
all the other comics teased you
for your coke bottle. Glasses,
blind Billy, bad eyes. They call you
it not at your heart, toward your soul.
You seed with rage,
but deep down you knew they were right.
Yeah.
Well, is this copy here? I never
had. I've never had glasses.
Must say brutal and bill burr voice
at least twice per spot can be out of
context. Must not get mad at
Hubble for trying to be cute. Uh,
okay.
With Hubble,
you'll get a fresh pair of lenses
for every single day for s for less.
What? Fresh pair of lenses.
60 contexts for $33.
Do the math.
That's barely a dollar a day.
How often do you throw out contact lenses?
I've never been in this world.
Uh,
this is more affordable than other brands.
Go to Hubba contacts.com and get
your first two weeks for free.
They can send you to an optometrist if
you don't have a prescription featured in
vogue, Gq, tech crunch, Mashable,
and the billboard podcasts.
So do what I bill burr,
definitely 100% did.
And go to a Hubble context.com
to get your first two pairs.
First two weeks of lenses for free.
Uh,
that's 15 pairs of lenses for
free. I've never done this. Uh,
to summarize context.
Cheaper's good, easy,
humble Internet C, uh, make
sure to select my show.
Underscore Bill Burr, underscore
at checkout. That's Hubble Hubb,
Ellie contacts.com. All right, so
I guess they have cheek contexts.
All right.
Yet you can put it in your eyes.
Uh, I actually, I need
glasses, man. I do. And uh,
I'm just afraid that if I wear glasses,
it's going to make my eyes weaker.
It's kind of like, you know, given into
using a cane, except it's for your eyes.
I'm trying to tough it out. I'm 50 years
old and I still don't have glasses.
You know,
I'll tell you
I can't see shit, but I'm a good listener.
I'm all man. I'm a really good listener.
All right. I gotta get in there
and I got to go eat lunch.
Oh, sorry. Breakfast with
the, with the family. Um,
I almost just said I love you guys. I
don't even know why. Why would I say that?
This being a dad thing is really
making me soft. It's really,
it's kind of scaring me here. All
right, let's get back on track.
Have a great weekend. You con and
uh, I'll check in on you on, uh,
on Monday. I think. Is there
an f one race this weekend?
There wasn't one this past weekend. I
think that coming back. Ah, I can't wait.
That last race was my
favorite fucking race.
That I'd last two have been
my favorite race. And, um,
I'm going to go out on a limb and I'm
going to say a, a ridiculously focused,
slightly angry Lewis Hamilton.
He's going to put on a fucking display.
That's what I'm, that's, that's my guests.
Alright, you wanna see
something cool? Checkout Lewis
Hamilton's private jet. Ahh,
Ahh, I can't imagine that.
You know what I mean?
Just flying to every gig in that
fucking thing. Do you now not funny.
Would be.
Okay.
How would you show up with that grin on
your face that you know, like when those,
when when the the dive and rescue teams
find the fucking guy who drowned in the,
in the fucking those cave divers,
they would have that goofy smile on
their face because the last thing that
happens is your body
releases all that dopamine.
That's the look I would have on my
face if I had a private jet. You know,
by the way, there is no way
to fly private and make money.
There's just no way to fucking do it
unless you flew there and then did it
10,000 gigs in a row before you flew back.
I don't get how people fucking
do it and people go, Oh,
you build it into the contract.
It's like fuck it.
It's going to come out of your end. It's
going to come out of your rent. I mean,
I think if I was to fly from here to Utah,
it costs like 50 grant.
It's fucking ridiculous. That
50 it's fucking nuts. All right.
That's the podcast.
Enjoy the music and listen to and
enjoy another half hour of a Thursday
afternoon podcast for my Thursday
afternoon. God, by all look good.
Just came walking in all
shirtless with their beer belly.
How you doing buddy?
Is it me or does she just
keep getting better looking?
She does get better looking.
Can you say hi?
Can you say Mama,
can you say okay?
Can you say baby?
Okay.
Can you say dog?
You say Kat.
Can you say car? Can you say, wow?
He's saying, Whoa, whoa.
She slipped in both around.
Can you say keys? Key shoes. He
now she can almost say to civil war.
Can you say wallet?
The water. The water.
That's like the same thing.
Yeah. You got to pick like words that
begin with the letter that she knows.
I'm not trying to turn
him into a gold digger.
Okay.
Say Baby
baby laughing.
Crying, crying. Are you doing that?
Huh?
Angry sleeping.
All right. That's the podcast. God bless
Ya. Uh, I'll talk to you on my, yeah,
that's right. Check it out.
I'll see you on Monday.
From the first book, we get bashed into
the holder, not the half of the book.
Captain Aftermath of the project.
That's the way
I have a NASA,
but the one at the top came
after this shot. I'm like,
God,
Brooklyn.
See that all Kimberly,
that they send the true
gas where the police would
tell them what at New York City when they
paint murals and the and cash we trust
because it's getting a fabulous life.
Look Pretty. What a pity blunts is.
Still 50 cents.
3 cents is Tom and nick can't be
covered within says my presence felt.
My name is Callie from
the eternal refreshing.
We'll take shorthand from this conception.
Let me meditate.
Satish tray came to that conclusion
that most of these chapters let me
demonstrate. Walk in the streets.
It's like battling be with your body.
You must know karate it back to me
like a bitch or ready to be efficient.
Every year may be,
you can see your name in the column
where we certainly teach a reading and
talking about a new either mountain
tonight and neighbors like he went to cry.
It's like, who'd a thought, David? Hey,
what's going on? Go for Monday morning,
the July fucking 19th
2000 fucking 10 all right,
I'm going to pissed off fucking mood
because I'm not funny this week.
This is the third fucking time
I've started this Goddamn podcast.
They had a race. Two of
them got 12 minutes into the
first one and I just said,
fuck it. And I erased it and this one,
I got 24 fucking minutes in and I,
I just, I, I just erased it.
And rather than walking away and walking
down the Goddamn street and cleared my
fucking head,
I just hit stop and I hit a race and
then I just start the fucking thing again
thinking like, oh, maybe, maybe
this will work. Let me do a do over,
you know?
Okay.
Oh, actually, you know what it
is. I'm on the fucking road.
I went to Montreal and now I'm in New
York and I just, I want to go home.
I've had it. I don't want to sleep in
anymore of these fucking hotel rooms.
I don't want to order any more
fucking room service. I'm in New York.
Are you ordered a God damn fucking protein
salad with a fucking Capri Tse Salad?
Cause I thought they were
Mozzarella, Mozzarella sticks.
However the fuck you got.
Goddamn sons of bitches from Italy say it
fucking shows up.
So I ordered a salad and a fucking sal.
Do you know what it cost me? It cost
me fucking almost 50 bucks with the tip
because I'm staying in midtown midtown.
Therefore we can,
we can rape you. You want some fucking
advice. If you ever come to New York,
do not stay mid tab too. God goddamn
fucking. They deliver the fucking food.
The guy's wearing a goddamn ski mask.
Fucking pantyhose over his fucking face.
Sound believe. And then we send up
there the only set up some fucking,
you know guy who can't even speak
fucking English, right? So you know,
it's not his fault. You know, he
didn't come up with the Goddamn menu.
Poor bastard.
He's still has scurvy from floating over
on his goddamn luggage coming up here
at fucking dazed given me the God
damn s I can't fucking believe it.
Yeah.
You know, and if you've never stayed in
a fucking New York hotel room either,
this is how it works. It costs $400
for the night and you're like, wow,
this is going to be amazing though.
Right?
And you open the fucking door and what
happens? You take a step and a half,
you trip over the fucking bed,
you'll roll over the bed like that.
Dushant Starsky and Hutch Hutch going
right over the hood of his fucking Grand
Torino. And rather than coming up in a
cool way with your Adidas dragons on,
you do a face plant right into the
fucking wall. And if I have the second,
you're like, oh, wait a minute, wait
a minute. There's a ray of light.
I actually have two side by side windows.
Let's check out the view.
And all you see is a fucking
the brick building next to you.
Do you know? I can't even commit
suicide out of this fucking window.
That's how close the building is
next to me. Hang on a second. Yes.
Okay.
It's okay. Uh, come back later.
I'm doing the podcast. All right.
Thank you. And I call, I
assumed that she's a fan,
actually got a laugh out of her.
Um, but she had an accident.
I just said I'm doing the podcast.
She probably thinks that's some sort of
new dance or that I'm fucking my wife
and it's some sort of new weird position.
I'd love to open the door,
but we're doing the podcast. Um, anyways,
let's get back to killing myself.
Um,
if I were to jump out this
building and trying to kill him,
I wouldn't kill myself.
What,
what actually happened was I would
slide down between both buildings
excrutiatingly slow scraping the,
the fucking skin off of both ass
cheeks, the back of my head, my nose,
and the helmet of my Dick
and the top of my feet.
I would have my feet pointed down
like Greg Louganis, you know,
coming out of a fucking triple Lindy
gone right into the Olympic Pool.
How does he do it?
How does he not fucking create
a God damn splash? You're like,
that doesn't get enough credit.
That fucking Greg Louganis,
you know all he talk about his, how he
whacked his head and he had his fucking,
you know,
he was HIV positive and it got on the
diving board for the next Ukrainian dude
who came up there.
You know what about the fact that he
could basically jump off the Eiffel Tower
and somehow against the laws of
physics not have not have a splash.
I would put that guy up there
with the fucking Wayne Gretzky's,
the Michael Jordans. Okay. You know
what? I don't know enough about diving.
So I got a strike that,
but I,
I did see some shit this weeks with
someone was saying Koby Bryant had five
fucking rings. So if he gets one
next year, he gets number six,
then you have to say that he's on par
with Jordan as far as championships. Yes,
we can all do math.
But as far as him ever eclipsing
Michael Jordan, he never will.
And I'm gonna,
I'm gonna tell you this right now.
Not only will he never
eclipse Michael Jordan,
he's not even fucking close and know
what all you Laker fans are thinking,
but wait a minute, fucker. He's
doing the same fucking moves.
Yes he is. Yes he is. Physically,
he can do what Michael
Jordan can do. Yes, he can.
All right, but this is the
difference. Michael Jordan
created those fucking moves.
All right?
You can find a guitarist in your fucking
neighborhood who can play Voodoo child.
Does that mean they're as good as Jimi
Hendrix who wrote the fucking Song,
who is 20 years ahead of his fucking
any other guitarist on the planet?
Look, as great as Stevie Ray Vaughan is,
I love that guy to death. He can't touch,
he can't fucking touch Jimi Hendrix.
He can't.
Hendrix came up with that Shit and
then fucking Stevie ray modernized it,
but it was Jimmy Shit.
You know what I mean?
It's like a pilot take you learns how
to fly and then tries to compare himself
to Orville and Wilbur
Wright. Oh, they, they've,
they fucking flew only across the field
and flying across the whole country.
I'm 3000 miles better than the
people who invented flying.
All right. Now Colby, Bryan has the,
the I think has the athletic
gifts of Michael Jordan.
And if you had the two of them play each
other one on one at the height of their
powers, it would be the greatest
one on one game ever. All right.
But as far as the forward
thinking, the, the,
the athletic genius.
Coby Brian has not an inventor.
He isn't, he does have the drive.
He's got all that other shit,
but he doesn't have the ability to take
the game 20 years into the future where
he has no fucking pier.
There was no arguments when Jordan played,
there was no arguments about who the best
guy in the league was for the last 10
years of his career.
There was a, you know,
early on before he established
himself, you know, people, you know,
we're throwing other names in there.
But after you know,
fucking 89 there was no question
who the best player was.
And by fucking 92 93 he was without a
doubt the greatest basketball player of
all time. And he still is
Koby Bryant on the other hand,
his entire career, there's always
been, well what about this guy?
What about that guy you
know right now is Colby,
Lebron James? You know,
I still give it to Colby.
Colby is still uh,
beyond Lebron James,
but Lebron James is very close.
There was no one near Jordan.
I can't even explain it to you.
It's like when you talk to those
fucking Douche bags from the baby boom
generation,
those selfish Kuntz who hang their hat on,
they stopped the Vietnam War and
then became corporate douche bags.
Um, that's a big generalization
for you. Like they always say like,
no matter how much you
get into the Beatles,
you just can't wrap your head around
what it was like when they put out an
album, how far ahead they
were from everybody else.
It's the same thing with Richard Pryor
because what happens is as the years go
by,
everybody rips those,
those geniuses off and everybody gets
caught up to where the fuck they were.
And what usually happens
is if you're young,
you're watching the contemporary people
and then as you go back in time you go
back 30 years, you go all the way back to
prior and you see him do the black guy,
white guy thing and so many people have
ripped him off that that the genius of
what he does is, is a little
tainted. You know what I mean?
So that's like when people look at Colby
and that and they go back and they look
at Jordan,
they take for granted
what Kobe's doing now because it just
seems it just like that's what basketball
is now because Jordan showed,
showed them what was possible. You
understand what the fuck I'm saying here.
I'm sure Laker fans won't
fucking, they, they'll,
they'll argue it but they're
fucking morons anyways.
They're going to be like Jordan
is just as good as Jordan.
You know the same way.
They try to claim that they have fucking
16 championships or this other do.
She wrote me this week who tried
to say they have 18 this such,
there's just no way to
respect a Laker fan.
I just cause some, they're just
transplanted. Fucking does.
There's so few people from Los Angeles.
And what happens is people move out there,
you know,
Hollywood fucking phoneys and
then the Lakers, you know,
they always have some fucking
amazing team. There are a hell of,
they're an awesome franchise.
I think they've uh,
wait how many championships
they got since 1980 he won five.
Eight. They won nine. They're
better than the Yankees since 1980.
Better than the Canadians. They
had the franchise. All right.
This will all these fucking assholes go
out there and they see Jack Nicholas at
a fucking true fan.
Jack Nicholson.
What the fuck is wrong with me every
time I want to say Jack Nicholas,
I say Nicholson and vice a versa there.
God help me if they're ever
in the same fucking room,
really built when the fuck
would that happen. Huh?
When you do some corporate gig for some
people who actually did something with
their life and you go in there like a
dancing monkey and then afterwards try to
talk to them in the green room.
Is there clearly blowing you off?
Um, anyways, the fuck am I
talking about here? Yeah.
All those Douche bag Laker fans. You
know, I talked to one the other day like,
well dude, I'm die hard. I'm die hard.
And I found out he was from New York.
How the fuck do you go from being
a Knicks fan to being a Lakers fan?
I'll tell you why.
You become a fucking phony.
How do you leave New York and moved
to la? How do you do that? You know,
unless you're in show business. Which
was he? I think he was, I can't remember.
I drank so much just fucking week.
I'll of everybody's just amalgam.
Everybody's just a big, just
amalgamating, if that's even a word,
into just one big face
running their goddamn miles.
My own fucking lawyer is a Laker Fan.
Okay.
And we had that argument about the 16
championships and he just would not answer
my questions.
I got a real thrill out of it of being
a lawyer in a fucking argument because I
just kept hitting him with
that argument. You know? I go,
you go to the staples center. All right.
Now, you know, first of all, if you,
if you got to make a 16 championship
tee shirt, because the law,
the Laker,
the Laker franchise has 16 championships.
That is undebatable.
Okay?
But the Los Angeles Lakers have 11
the Minneapolis Lakers have five.
So when you make those 16
championship fucking tee shirts,
you got to say Minneapolis
slash Los Angeles. Okay?
Take the hint from the Laker franchise.
When you go to the staples center and
they don't have the Minneapolis banners up
there because those banners belonged to
the franchise slash the fans of fucking
Minnesota in Minneapolis the same way.
And I've made this fucking goddamn example
a zillion times and I'm going to keep
making it because every fucking week,
some Goddamn Laker Fan,
this is the last week I'm going to do
it because now people have sent me those
emails on purpose.
But like if the Lakers now moved
from Los Angeles to Las Vegas,
they win it next year for the franchise
is 17th Championship people in Los
Angeles. What would you do with somebody
from Vegas came walking up to you when?
What that 17 bitch,
we have 17 fucking NBA championships.
We are the New York Yankees of
fucking basketball. Would that,
would that make sense to you
if you saw Las Vegas Lakers?
17 championships and they will walk
it around, thrust in their chests out
the Boston Celtics have won 17
championships all in Boston. Okay,
that's it. And a few people in La, you're
still confused. Like I've said before,
just think how count,
how many times you've thrown a rock
through the wind storefront window of an
athlete's foot foot.
I can't even fucking talk this week.
How many times do you
burned down your city?
How many times you've
burned down the La area?
That's how many championships you have.
All right?
So stop padding you fucking resume.
Like all you can do out there.
You're a god Damn Pa and by the
time you type up your resume,
you fucking directed the movie fucking
phoneys who can't even show up to the
game on time. Um, all right,
well we go on. Hey, where the fuck
did we go from here? All right,
so how much time did that take
up? How much momentum. All right.
That was a good 14 fucking minutes.
Let me shut off this overhead light
made out of fucking piece of shit.
Plastic, 400 bucks a
night, fucking pricks. Um,
anyways, I am here in New York and, uh,
I did the Montreal comedy festival
this week. Uh, that was a big thrill,
you know,
that's why I drank so fucking much this
week and I just ran into a bunch of
comedians I haven't seen in a long,
long fucking time.
Um, you know, because everybody
I know fucking headlines now,
so we never get to work together anymore.
So just we're drinking and telling stories
and just laughing our fucking asses
off and I'll tell you,
it's a goddamn shame nobody filmed it.
Cause there's like nine
zillion documentaries out
there trying to capture the
backstage stand up fucking thing.
And uh,
I don't think they've ever done it.
And the only way you could ever do it
is if you'd have to do it like a reality
show.
Will You keep the cameras rolling
24,
seven.
And that way people gradually forget about
them because that's what they have to
do. They have to forget
that they're on camera.
So you actually hear the
fucking stories and the,
uh, I don't know if the level you have
to go to, to make another comedian laugh.
Um,
this put it this way,
this podcast is PG 13 compared to the
shit that we talk about. So anyways,
that's what I was doing. I was drinking
booze. I was having a great time up there.
Um, and I'm fucking wiped out. But um,
I'm actually taping this right
now on the 18th, Sunday the 18th,
and I'm doing the David Letterman program,
the late show tomorrow night.
I got my suit, I got to get my shoes
polished. I got my fucking cufflinks,
you know, nice fucking
shirt. And as always,
I know people are going to send me
emails. Dude, why did you wear is?
Why did you dress up for the
greatest fucking, you know,
talk show out there,
Bill,
I don't understand it. Everybody else
on the show is dress really nicely.
Why did you go on the show
and dress really nicely?
Why didn't you go out there and dress
like you were headlining the funny bone in
fucking Dayton, Ohio? Why did you dress
like you were in the Ed Sullivan Theater?
Do you guys realize you young punks that
that's the fucking same stage where the
Beatles came out and broke in the
United States. And if you'll watch him,
they were wearing suits.
Your dumb fucks really don't understand
that you show up to a Toga party.
If you wear a suit, you can give
somebody then when in Rome cunts,
when in Rome. Um, so anyways, this is
going to be my fifth appearance and uh,
I'm really excited. I
got a nice tight set. Um,
I am kind of making fun of mothers
right out of the gates. So, uh,
as always,
you know,
there's always a bit of awkwardness
before people realize that I look like a
puppet and then I'm harmless
and then I just write it,
write it right through.
And uh,
and then what's going to
happen is after the show,
I'm going to have the fucking euphoria
that I did it and I survived it.
And, uh, then I'm going to go out
and I'm gonna stay out too late
and then my alarm clock's going to go
off 20 minutes later and I'm going to be
in the worst fucking move ever.
I better have a window seat.
That's all I can tell you because if I
get woken up, if I get the aisle seat,
you know,
I hate how people wake you up on a plane.
When a stranger wakes you up.
Is there anything more creepier than
the touch of a stranger trying to not
disturb you from your sleep?
That little two fingered,
not quite a poke,
not quite a caress that they do into
your shoulder and then they speak in half
sentences. They don't just,
they don't just, you know,
you know, you know, it'd be
acceptable like a man demand, like a,
a back of the hand fucking on,
on the side of your leg
as intimate as that sound.
I'll give you the sound just like this.
Hey Man, I gotta get up. Use the bathroom.
I, so just like that, but for
some reason, because she just,
I don't know if it's because of nine
11. I don't know what, but people just,
they the two finger and then they,
and then they sort of
whisper a half a sentence.
They fuck you just feel this
creepy fucking pedophile touch.
It startles you. The exact
thing they don't want to do.
It's such a creepy touch.
It does startle you.
You fucking whip your head around
over to them and then it's some,
another man whispering I half a
sentence. Yeah. I just had to, yeah, I,
I just wanted to get,
can I just,
can you just what you fucking asshole
finished the God damn sentence and stop
fucking
finger raping me.
Whatever the hell you just did there.
That's the old shoulder finger
rape at 30,000 feet. Um,
which is actually a new phrase,
acceptable in the Webster's dictionary.
Can you believe that?
How many times I'm so sick of them
fucking bringing that up on talk shows.
Do you know that chillin is now an
acceptable word in the dictionary? Well,
do you know that everybody's using it?
You fucking idiot.
That's how they become words.
You can have words that everybody is
using and you're not going to put them in
the dictionary. Why are people so
fucking stuck up about that? Ooh,
good Chilean Knute mood
and be like, does any class
left you fucking doing Vegas?
People showing up and Hawaiian shorts
with flip flops and you can't put shelling
in the God damn dictionary. You know, keep
stopping these fucking plagues people.
And that's what you're going to have.
You're going to have a weaker
species of fucking human beings.
All right?
And they're going to use fucking slang
words and eventually you're going to have
to stick them in the dictionary
because you're gonna want to commute.
Be able to communicate to the people.
You always have to be able
to communicate to the people.
Because if you can't communicate to them,
then you can't give them the fucking lie.
You can't spend your own fucking story
of why we're all scampering around down
here as you sit in your fucking manner.
You know,
I've been dying to do a bit
about the kind of people I think
should have get the death penalty
and one of them is these fucking
bankers. I really believe, man,
if you shake up the economy like a
goddamn ant farm and you make fucking old
people have to eat al Po for the
last 18 years of their fucking life,
and I might just talking about five
or six of them. I'm talking about an,
you know, a large percentage
of an entire generation.
These fucking banker
cunts fucked over people.
Basically the generation
that won World War II,
it's unbelievable that even go to jail.
They don't even fucking go to jail.
I Dunno. I think they should
give all old people fucking,
they should just give them those paintball
guns and then they should just tell
him where the,
where the fucking rich people live,
the bankers and they should just go on
and just see every once in a while drive
by and shoot them and
they never get arrested.
That's what I think that they
should do. All right. Once again,
just like the last two podcasts.
This thing's starting to Peter
out right around 21 minutes.
52 seconds.
Can I be funny up until 22 seconds,
I got another four seconds to do it.
Three seconds. That's not going to happen.
Jesus.
This is the longest 15 minutes ever.
Fucking God damn judges popped out too.
I tell you guys that they said
that I grinded my teeth at night.
Like I didn't know that.
I didn't know that I was
an absolute psycho and had
angry dreams about murdering
people.
So they give me this fucking mouth guard
and I put the mouth guard on and now my
jaw just dislocates every once in a while
and I so don't like paperwork and shit
that I would never even consider sowing
them. Oh my God, this sucks and I've just
figured out how to pop it back in again.
All right, now it's out of alignment. Let
me see if, let me try to bite down. Yeah.
What the fuck? I feel like I had
a ball side of my fucking jaw.
Any dentists out there can
tell me why that happened?
I can't even, you know, you know why the
first time it happened, I can't leave.
I'm going to tell you this.
I can't tell you how the
time I dislocated my jaw was,
uh,
okay.
How do I tell it in a clean
way? I don't do sex jokes, but,
uh,
I was going down on a girl then I was
trying to fucking jam my tongue in there
and I think it, it pushed my lower
back. She was getting really into it,
you know, and I was younger, so I
didn't know how to make them come.
And she was getting close and I was so
fucking exhausted. I just went forward.
I was in the red zone and I was like,
we got a score here.
This fucking game is over.
And then when, uh, you know,
I came up out of the fucking,
what the fuck do you call it?
I don't know. The concubines.
I know some word with a see that began
there and I wasn't going to say can't I
came up out of there,
uh,
you know what that laminated face and a,
yeah,
I noticed it was difficult to bite down
and ever since then I had a problem.
I think it just ruined my lawsuit cause
if they'll listen to the podcast and
actually he admits on
the podcast on July 18th,
2010.
Yeah.
Then it was actually jamming his
tongue until Vagina in Laughlin,
Nevada.
There's no way to make that
up. It's fucking true. Ah,
Jesus Christ isn't aging.
Isn't it just funny how things
like that happen. Anyways,
Jesus Christ.
What a fucker thing to admit.
You can tell him flailing when I
started the fucking admit and that shit.
24 minutes. Here we go.
Okay, let's plow ahead.
I was watching ESPN today and um,
and of course, you know, as always,
you had four really intelligent people
on a panel who are all involved in a
debate that none of them
knew was even remotely true,
but they engaged in it anyways because
it would piss off a guy like me and make
me continue to watch so that I then
see the commercials so they can justify
their advertising so that those
four cock suckers can get paid.
I refuse to believe that Bob Ryan,
John Saunders,
though they're not dumb guys.
They're not.
But if you listen to what they're arguing,
it's the stupidest shit ever.
Basically because a tiger woods
hasn't won a major this year.
They're questioning whether he's ever
basically going to be able to put it back
together again.
Completely ignoring the fact that he got
busted for cheating almost 30 times on
his wife in front of the entire country,
and that he's going through a
divorce right now that you know,
she wants $700 million
and he's wants to give her 300 million.
They're in the process of
negotiating that. And also he's got,
he's going through a period in his life
where he realized that he fucked up his
whole marriage. You know, if
you guys, you know, not forget,
if you haven't fucked up relationship,
you haven't gone through relationship
that ends and you got to go through your
fucking town and everywhere you go
you got a memory of that person.
You sit in there welling
up in a Johnny rockets.
Would you like to get some French fries?
See a thing.
She loved French fries. We used to
share him, um, all that shit. So he,
you don't think he's going
through that on a worldwide basis,
traveled the world with that
woman and just be, you know,
when you fuck up to that level, you
always want to go back. You know,
you have to go through the
regret before you can move on.
So I'm sure he's sitting
there at the British open.
As much as he's trying to block it
out as much as he's a competitor,
there's no way as a human being few
not to be sitting here going, man,
this time last year my
life was so different.
Even though I didn't win it
last year when I came up on 18,
but she didn't play last year because
his knee was hurt for whatever the last
time he played it, you
know, um, or maybe did,
I don't fucking know.
He was coming up 18 and his
wife was sitting there with
their kid and he got the
hug and on the kiss and all that
type of shit and it's not there.
And he has to deal with that. And
this is a fucking guy that, you know,
he's a human being is such idiots.
The guy won a fucking tournament when
his knee was blown out and he was
screaming in pain after every God
damn shot. And he's still fucking one.
And they're going to question this
guy with a reconstructed knee.
You know, the guys in his early thirties,
they've already written them off.
Jack Nicholas won his final
fucking, uh, master's at like 45,
46 years of age. It's this, it's,
the whole debate was so fucking
beneath guys like Bob Ryan,
John Saunders, who was that? Who the guy
was. It was if you just sit there going,
you guys don't even believe this shit.
You just trying to cause controversy
because you have to fill up 24 fucking
hours. And that right there is why
I don't watch those shows, you know,
but you know,
unless I'm on the fucking road and
I've got nothing else to do and then it
completely fucking pisses me off.
Anyways,
let's plow ahead here.
Um,
here's a question I got this week,
um, from a listener. Um, Bill,
I have a question.
I had been dating a Filipina girl who
is too short to be seen with in public.
Geez. I mean, what, what a,
what a way to start the story.
I'm seeing a girl who I can't
be seen with in public. Okay.
This relationship has legs.
Um,
and the fact that I'm six foot
three doesn't help at all. I mean,
she is really small for foot five.
This is one of the great sentences
I've ever read. Listen to this.
Technically she's a midget.
So you would think people would kind of
leave us alone out of respect for her
shortness.
Sir. Do you realize that really short
people or little people want to be called
little people? They midget
is offensive. I learned that.
I didn't think it was,
I actually have that on my CD going.
It was never a racial slur.
You know,
midgets weren't dragged here from
another country and forced to do labor.
You're a midget.
What's wrong with that?
And evidently a PT Barnum came up with
it or something just to let you know,
cause I didn't know midget was offensive
either. Right. I knew it was offensive,
but I didn't understand why a midge is
like the name for a really tiny bug I
guess. So that's what they were
saying. They say when you like,
you were like as small as a little boy.
They were comparing it to a little
fucking insect, you know? And that goes,
the elephant man think I am not an
insect. I am a human being. Well,
it's the do with Mooc. It's um,
so technically she's a midget.
So you would think people would kind of
leave us alone out of respect for her
shortness.
But people's people stare
me down everywhere we go.
She's cute,
nice and sweet,
but I feel uncomfortable being
part of a side show all the time.
Do you think it's acceptable
for a tall man to date a tiny,
a tiny women, tiny woman is what you
mean? Do I think it's acceptable?
Yeah, it's totally acceptable.
Date with who you want to a date.
What's not?
What's not acceptable is dating someone
you're not comfortable being seen within
public?
Um,
I would work on not giving a fuck or
I would get out of the relationship
because,
uh,
I don't know how she hasn't
picked up on it already. But, uh,
if you're not comfortable with the
person you're dating, I mean, I mean,
I don't know if someone can walk down
the street with me and be comfortable
walking down the street with a fucking
redheaded freak. Um, I think that,
ah, you know, you could get
comfortable with her and when you,
when you walked down the street with the,
you don't have her like fucking,
you know,
what are those?
You don't have them. One of
those kiddie things, you know,
where she's sitting on you that
your chest like a fucking primate.
I guess we're all primates,
aren't we? You know,
in monkeys when the fucking monkey
just hangs on the other, you know,
wraps her arms around your back.
Yeah, I'm being a Dick Right now.
You ever in a fanny pack? See this? I'm
doing the exact fucking thing. Well,
you got to understand that's what people
are going to do. You got to understand.
If you're a different looking,
couple people are going to give you
shit and you just got to get beyond it.
You know, that's all I can say. I
shouldn't have made those jokes.
Cause now you're probably thinking
like see you being a cunt to,
I'm not being a condom.
Being a guy who is not even remotely
funny this fucking week trying to trudge
through 15 fucking minutes, 50
minutes of a podcast. All right?
So I have to make fun of everything. So,
uh, I dunno. She's adorable. She's nice.
If you think she's the one I
would, I would stay with her. Um,
if you don't think she's the one,
get out of it immediately because
even if she's not the one,
eventually you'll have feelings for.
And then when you break up with her,
you know, when you sat her on
the coffee table and say, look,
we have to have a talk.
I'm sorry dude, I'm on any
joke, any, any port in a storm,
I gotta fucking do it. And she starts
crying. You know, it's the worst.
That's why you know something. I'll
tell you right now. This is why like,
I love how it's unacceptable to break
up with somebody over the phone.
You know who came up with that is women
because they know how guilty they can
make us fucking feel
when they start crying.
They want to make us feel is,
it's a total vindictive fucking mood.
There's nothing wrong with breaking
up with somebody on the phone.
There's nothing wrong with like that
dude on sex in the city who wrote it on a
post it and stuck it to the TV.
I have a girlfriend.
I have seen some episodes of that show.
Um,
although I never get through the whole
one because I would always piss my girl
off cause anytime the hoary girl would
make us anything she said in the show was
always sexually related. And I told
you guys this before, need any lines?
She said after she said it,
I would just go cause she's a whore and
it would just piss my girl off to no one
until by the end of the show she was
doing it too. But anyways, I digressed.
Let's fucking, let's fucking just
plow ahead. There's nothing wrong
no matter what.
It's going to make him cry.
There's nothing wrong with breaking
up with someone through email.
There's nothing wrong with
doing it with the post it,
there's nothing wrong with doing it over
the phone in a way. There's actually,
it's a caring thing that they're doing.
It's like I care about you so much and
it would hurt me so much to see how much
I'm hurting you that I can't even deal
with watching how much I'm going to hurt
you. You know, and you're out.
It's a vindictive thing that
women want you eyeball to eyeball.
Watch you stand there and
watch you crush them by saying,
I don't want to be in a fucking
relationship with you anymore. You know,
it's fucking awful.
What I always do,
and you know back in the day when I
used to have to break up with somebody,
I used to just think
this, all right, dude,
it's, it's two hours of your
life. The first leg of it,
it's like the Tour de France, okay? We're
just trying to get to the mountains.
All right? The first two
hour fucking leg, all right?
She's going to cry. It's going to suck.
We have to stick to you fucking guns.
All right? Sit down. Just say,
and there's probably people out there
right now who need to get out of a
relationship and you just don't know how
to do it cause you're young. All right?
It's not going to get better.
You can't make yourself love the person.
You just have to fucking get out of it.
And this goes for the broads out
there too. He just have to go, look,
we need to talk. All right.
I don't know what's going on,
but I'm just not happy anymore,
you know? And you can use all the
hacky stuff. You're a great person,
but I'm just not, I'm not
feeling it. I'm just not.
And you know, that's, that's
a hold of her is to it.
Look at Murray, get nervous, just
picture of the girl crying, crying.
It's all there. You know, you're, it's not
fair to you. It's not fair to you. It's
so, what do you say? We care
can't work. And this is the thing,
they try to fucking,
they try to save it and you just have
to be like that dude in the first star
wars. Stay on target,
stay on target. Right.
Well, you know, I've, I've been
thinking things like that too.
I just think we don't see each
other enough big, you know?
And maybe that's what I've been avoiding.
You,
you can't say that can't be mean
and just be like, look, no. Um, um,
it's truly how I feel and
yeah, that's, it's just,
it's just how I feel.
And then just let them
a moat and let them go.
You know,
it's like deep sea fishing
when you get that line in,
the fucking thing takes off. We
got a bike, you gotta let it go.
You can't fucking clamp the thing
down and then snap the line.
You know, zen, she's free.
She's going to come back around and
attack the fucking boat, like in jaws.
You gotta let her go jump up out of the
water, flop around and get fucking tired,
you know, and, and uh, yeah, and you just,
you just, it's a two
hour fucking thing. Okay.
And all you have to do is just say how
you're feeling and then just let her
fucking run and start fucking crying
and go through all the emotions
she needs to, to, to get through.
And you just have to sit
there and stick to your guns.
All right? And then
comes, the hardest part
is, uh, if you're in her
apartment, that's a great thing.
So you can fucking leave.
It's worse if they do it in your apartment
because then you have to kick them
out. So yeah, that's how I feel. And, uh,
I need you to vacate the premises and
right as you say that you got to have your
friends step out,
dress like a bouncer with one of those
fucking cell ear ear piece. Thanks.
Okay.
Standing there like a bouncing,
you know when they stand with their
hands folded in front of him one hand
holding the wrist of the
other arm, you know, no,
you got to do it over to
her place and just say,
you know,
okay,
I'm not going to date anybody for a
while or whatever the fuck you guys say.
And I, I just, and if she says,
can I call you? You just, yeah,
you just say yes, yes you can.
And then decide whether you really
meant that or not later. But, uh,
and I dunno. And then you got,
I don't know, then you get,
you got to get it and then
he got to get away from him.
You got to get away from him. Um,
because if you keep coming back,
it just starts the pain over again.
And then also
on your level is you're going to have to
try to get over them even though you're
are over him,
but still now you're going to be alone.
You can have that panic attack.
Well, who am I going to be with?
What did I used to do when I was single?
How did I fill up all this fucking time?
Just ride it out. Just know it's going
to suck for six weeks. All right?
Six weeks later you're out.
Football season starts,
you know the smell of fall comes
through the fucking windows.
Okay?
You know?
Yeah,
buddy fucking brings over maybe a
couple of girls that were into sports.
You find another one.
God Damn. I look at her
and then you're a, you're on your fucking
way. It's spring again in the fall.
See, it has a happy ending. That's
how you fucking do it. Jesus Christ.
There was some advice for you.
How to fucking break up with somebody.
Do you guys have any stories about like
the worst way you were ever broken up
with or the best,
best way somebody ever broke up with you?
You know,
I broke up with someone one time
and then I bought her a hot dog
and it was weird. It was when I was a
little bit older and I just had a really,
it was just totally fucking honest. I
just had an honest talk and I said, look,
we're both, we're both couple
psychos. I mean, haven't you noticed?
I had you ever have that fucking
relationship where everything,
it just doesn't feel right
and then you freak out,
you have an argument and
then you've just fuck,
and then it feels right again.
And then it slowly starts going off
course again and then you have a big
argument and then you
fuck again right after it.
And I know I just finally hit me. It
was just like, yeah, well this is just,
this relationship isn't working, really
isn't working. And then what happens is,
is then we fuck. And it's
a lot of fun. It's just,
it's just based on sex. We're having a
really good time fucking before indicating
if I could try to be a gentleman here.
That's basically what we're doing.
But other than that, we don't
really enjoy each other's company.
You want a hot dog?
You know what it was,
was I did it early enough
in the relationship where
the woman's still actually
respected me and she
actually complimented me.
I mean it was a little more
involved than that. MMM.
But she actually called me. She
goes, you know what that was. Yeah,
that was a pretty good breakup.
I got to give it to you.
Then you walk me down to the train.
We waved goodbye as the
train slowly went away.
It was like the end of like a
fucking a film noir movie. What else?
Classic films. He played it for
her. You can play it for me.
Play it for me.
They're fucking black guy who doesn't
get any lines cause it's 1940.
[inaudible] math. I um, I was actually a,
the TV here in my walk in closet.
$400 a night fucking hotel.
Um, okay. I was actually watching
that Turner movie classics, man.
Jesus Christ. When I get on that
thing, forget about it. I was actually,
I watched you don't like the road movie.
The Buddy road movie.
I didn't realize this, the first ones,
the guys who invented that genre of movie,
um,
was um,
was it bing Crosby and fucking
Bob hope I had no idea.
And they will write as I had to
go out last night to watch, um,
to go run my set.
They had the third in their trilogy
and I forget of the buddy movies.
I think they did more after that, but
I guess this was the best one. And I,
I can't even remember the name of
the movie, but it, the, basically
the premise of the movie was that
they went to some fucking Arabian,
you know, back then there was no Middle
East. Everything was just Arabian,
whatever the fuck that meant.
Or does that mean like Arabic country?
I don't fucking know. But the whole thing
was they had to get out of something.
So Bing Crosby cells,
uh,
Bob Hope into slavery.
Like slavery was still funny back then.
I don't know what the fuck I'm saying.
All I know is I watched
the thing and bright,
the movie that I watched right before
that was a movie called zero hour and it
absolutely blew me away.
I'm sitting there watching this movie.
I came in in the middle of this,
this flick and there's a guy talking
about this guy who's got to try to land
this plane.
And the guy's name is Ted striker.
I'm going Ted striker.
That was the name of the guy in airplane
and it's literally the same movie.
And I finally fucking realize that that
was the movie that airplane was Perry
making a parody of,
um,
was a movie called zero hour that came
out in like the mid fifties for the life
of me.
I thought that they will make it fun.
You know those movie airport
airports, 76 airports, 77,
those ones with like George Kennedy,
I thought that they were making fun
of those movies and they weren't,
they basically almost did a frame
for frame remake of zero hour.
And, um, if you don't
want to watch the movie,
go on Youtube and watch
airplane versus zero hour,
you can't fucking believe
how similar. I mean,
all these subtle things.
They brings the kid up to the cockpit.
A Billy ever been up in a
cockpit before and he's like, no,
this is my first time
except in the real one.
The first one it drops off there, but
an airplane. Then the guy says, Billy,
you ever seen a grown man naked? They
added all that shit. So zero hour,
check out that movie. I'll give you
the youtube videos for the week.
Am I at least at 30 minutes? 44 minutes.
I somehow fucking did it again this week.
All right.
Youtube videos of the week.
Go check out a best have balls
of steel to jackass show from,
I dunno, over in England. And
uh, these guys are fucking great.
They're fucking,
they're just hilarious.
And they keep going to this Mcdonald's
gimme fall big macs gimme seven double
cheeseburgers and some fucking daddy
down. It's, and I know a ditty donuts are,
but they just keep going and
some fucking Dedi down. It's,
and it makes me laugh every time. And
I just butchered it. I'm telling you,
it's funny. And also for you animal
fans out there, watch eagle verse goat,
I guess in the wild.
This is how strong these eagles are.
They find little goats and they fly
down to them that goes fucking runaway.
The Eagles grab them,
pick them up,
just we'll grab one of their legs and
they drag him off the cliff and just drop
them.
That's how they kill him.
But they actually have the ability
to fly a little bit with them.
That's how strong they are.
And they wait til they are high enough
and then they just drop them and they
bounced down off the cliff like some
sort of x Gamer who lost his footing and
uh, the goat dies and then they
fly down and they fucking eat it.
And then you go. And I think that that's
going to be the podcast for this week.
Cause I, uh, I actually
have to go a New York,
I got to go do some shit. You
know, people don't go to New York,
just stay in the hotel rooms.
That's how we justify making him so
fucking small God damn. Cons. Hey,
let me, uh, let me hype some of the
Shit that I actually have coming up.
Um,
here's something that
actually fell out of the sky.
I have a gig coming up in Chicago.
All right,
and why isn't my fucking webpage
loading official site of Bill Burr,
Bill, burr.com, everybody, it'll
make you a better person. Um,
my next gig after I do Letterman
is on a Friday of this week,
July 23rd,
I'm a,
I'm working with Vince
Vaughn and Kevin James.
It's part of that Vince
Vaughn wild west tour.
We're doing the park West
Theater in Chicago, Illinois.
I have the link right on my website.
Um,
I'm just going to be doing
like 15 minutes, but it's
gonna be me, Vince Vaughn,
Kevin James, and uh, I forget who else,
but it's like just a ridiculously
star studded show. And I,
she definitely check it
out and bring your friends,
bring everybody you fucking can.
All the proceeds from,
uh, from the show will go to a,
the people who worked on the show,
the performers, all the proceeds
will actually go to the performers,
the performers, and we'll go
out and buy shiny shit with it.
So just want to thank all
you guys ahead of time.
After that,
on July 31st I'll be at the shoreline
amphitheater in mountain view,
California with like 10 other fucking
comedians doing something up there for a
radio program.
And a,
my next solo show though is going to
be at the comedy store in La Jolla,
California,
which is just north of San Diego.
So all you guys down to San Diego who
have always asked me when the fuck you
coming.
I'm coming on August 6th and August 7th.
All right. And the last thing
will be, I'm going to hype,
I'm Newport Yachting Center in Newport,
Rhode Island,
August 12th and the Hampton Beach
Casino and Hampton, New Hampshire,
Hampton Beach, New Hampshire on
August 13th. And I'm, by the way,
last week I did a little rant,
you know about the Lebron James,
you know,
being afraid of the big um,
big stage in New York and actually went
down to the comedy store and a fuck you,
I always forget the
pipe that the damn page,
the [inaudible] podcast.com.
All right, the m M podcast.com.
Go to that.
That's the official,
there's no other fan page for the Monday
morning podcast, the m m podcast.com.
All the references I've made.
I know I made a reference to something
fucking old a number of times in this
podcast.
He puts up all the references,
all the youtube videos will be there
so you can just click on them as I'm
talking about him. And um, anyways,
we actually filmed,
I did a different rant along the same
lines and they put it up on Barstool
sports.
It got a ton of fucking hits and uh,
touch her and, and Dave, is that the name
of the show? I'm such a Douche. How did I,
how did I fuck that up?
I just pan.
You don't want it is cause I
don't know how to read that.
Actually thought toucher was
too sure as I was like, is it,
is it too sure the guys on BCN
touch or enrich? There we go.
My brain isn't fucking awake.
I ain't have to look it up just for the
fucking record. What an, you know what?
I just tried to thank those guys and
I fucked up the name of this show.
Touch your enrich,
played it and then actually it let
me call in and Ha and hype my show.
So I'm feeling like I'm really becoming
Internet savvy because back in the day
I'd have to get on a plane for six fucking
hours, land, get up two hours later,
go into their studio,
half asleep and half is funny as I
usually am and try to hype my gigs.
I actually got a plug out a month
beforehand or three weeks before,
two weeks. I don't know what the date
is. Touch her and rich. Sorry about that.
Guys want an asshole. Um, anyways,
that's the podcast for this week.
I hope you guys enjoyed it. And, um,
I wanted to know was it easier to
download last week when I put it through
garage band because I was actually
able to make it a smaller audio file.
Did it download quicker?
Cause I think I'm going to try to do
it again this week because I know it
uploaded a lot quicker. Was
that interesting? You know what?
I think that's very fitting that I said
something that wasn't funny to end this
podcast because that's how it's felt.
I know I came out with a head of steam,
you know what I mean?
I came out guns a blazing,
kind of like a Peyton
manning football season.
Just lighten everybody up and then
right in the end when it really counts,
I shit the bed. Wow. Did I
really have to trash him?
I think I did. All right. You
guys have a great week and a,
if you're in the Chicago area, police
come out to the show. Um, and that is it.
Have a great weekend.
All
right,
cool.
Then they won't be there.
[inaudible] on a rooftop with us.
It could be your true click. It's a
random t. Just smoked food away. To me,
the entity within the industry without
a history of to live on my life,
expressing my liberty,
you got to be done properly.
My name is in the middle of the quality.
People follow me and number chassis here
will flow and assume I'm the real one
with deliveries like I'm suffering.