Norm minetta and I'm vice chairman of
the hill and Knowlton
infrastructure is so important is it's
directly linked to productivity
increases.
And there's been a tremendous amount of
productivity increase since the end of
World War II.
And that increased,
stopped,
maybe not stop,
but it slowed down about maybe 10,
12 years ago.
The there was still increasing,
but the rate of the increase of
flattened out.
But in the last,
I think five years or so,
85 to eight years,
productivity has gone down because of
congestion in urban areas.
And so my feeling is that here we are
competing in a global economic place and
we cannot allow,
and we can't afford to have our
productivity going down at a time when
we're competing in the economic a world
marketplace.
And so that's why we need this kind of
infusion of money into infrastructure.
Well,
the logical source in the past has been,
uh,
the gasoline tax or the fuel tax for a
diesel fuel or excise tax on batteries
and tires,
etc.
Now with the fuel efficiency of
automobiles going up,
uh,
the 18.4
cents,
federal gasoline tax just produces less
money into the highway trust fund.
So it's either going to be increased
gasoline taxes,
which for which there's a resistance or,
uh,
some other form of fuel tax,
maybe based on the odometer reading,
uh,
and uh,
but there's still going to be a gap from
what that generates and what the needs
are.
And my feeling is that public private
partnerships,
how to be used to fill that gap.
I think when you think about,
uh,
infrastructure,
it probably would a surround a what I
would think of maybe as employment.
What does it do in terms,
especially right now,
uh,
given the unemployment rate,
what is it do in terms of employment?
What does it do in terms of the
environment and what does it do in terms
of the economy as a whole?
And,
um,
and I think from there you can take
subsets of each of those broad areas and
come up with criteria that would be
applicable to any project that might be
funded so that you're looking for
efficiency and effectiveness of that
funding.
So then at the end of the day,
it's not just this question of,
Oh,
that's nice you spent $200 million on
that project,
but what did we get for that $200
million?
Seems to me that
there's been a lot of talk about a
return to more bipartisanship,
that the American people are tired of
the kind of constant bickering going on
back and forth between the Congress and
the executive branch,
and that,
uh,
there ought to be more,
um,
civility,
I guess,
in the relationship,
uh,
between the administration and the
Congress panned,
uh,
within the congress as well.
Yeah.