There is a rapid rise in the demand for
new skills.
In fact,
we see that at the individual levels and
we see this at aggregate levels.
Uh,
there's a growing gap between the
employment and labor market prospects of
people who are highly skilled and people
at the lower end of the skill spectrum
skills determine more and more how the
benefits of economic growth I shat in
society.
So success of companies today depends on
nothing more than on the talent pool
which they recruit.
70% of productivity gains have been bay
basically driven by improvements in the
skill base.
So there is a dramatically a rising
demand for better skilled people.
At the very same time we also see that
uh,
in some countries there are many
graduates unemployed on the street while
employers say they cannot find the
people with the skills they need.
So there is a emerging mismatch between
the kind of talent that is being
developed and the talent that is really
needed.
Tech.
One of the things that our data show us
that some of the scales that are easiest
to teach and easiest to test are also
the kind of skill set are easiest to
digitize,
automate and outsource.
Sort of.
That's a big challenge for,
for the Education Industry today to
think about,
you know,
what are they kind of 21st century
skills that will enable people.
You know,
in the past you could assume as a
teacher you will teach someone for the
lifetime.
You know what you learn in school.
It's going to last for many,
many years.
Today there's no longer the case today.
We need to educate people for jobs that
have not been created,
to use technologies that haven't been
invented to solve social and economic
problems that we don't have any idea I
want to arise.
This is sort of the fundamental
challenge for education and that
requires a very different caliber of
teachers,
teachers who are not just reproducing
sort of or educating the reproduction of
subject matter content,
but it help young people to extrapolate
from what they know to use and apply
their knowledge in novel situations.
In a nutshell,
the world economy no longer pays you for
what you know.
Google knows everything.
The world economy piece you for what you
can do with what you know in that
requires a very different caliber of
teachers,
a very different pedagogy.
21st century Podagra be a very different
relationship between teachers and
students.
Technology is part of this today.
It's hard to explain why you should
accept the teacher next door if you can
have access to the world's best
knowledge anymore.
We're seeing in an unbundling of
educational content,
educational delivery,
and accreditation with people anywhere
drawing on the world's best knowledge at
any time.
We are seeing governments putting
greater emphasis on evaluating outcomes
on quality assurance,
on setting standards,
and the business sector actually being a
lot more engaged in helping education
systems.
Figuring out,
you know,
where his labor demand evolving,
what are the kinds of skills that will
be there at a premium tomorrow.
The business sector playing a very
important role in as an education
provider,
engaging actively in the design and
delivery of instructional system,
providing educational and learning
opportunities for people in many,
many contexts.
At least we're seeing this in some
countries.
It's in others.
It's still a big challenge.