You know,
I,
I knew a guy
who was a bartender in Washington named
Steve Daley and I found myself covering
Wimbledon with him because I was a
sports writer for two years at the
Washington Post because that's the job
that they had open after my being a
police report.
And I said,
how did you get from being a bartender
to a columnist for the Chicago Tribune?
He said,
well,
I used to be a funny bartender and they,
you know,
the sports editors will come and they
said,
you ought to try writing a column.
And he did it and then he did it again.
He did it again and he got this job.
So what happens when you become a big
shot editor or a big shot columnists,
sooner or later,
people ask you questions like this.
What advice do you have for young
journalists?
And unfortunately,
if you're honest,
you have to say,
number one,
get real lucky,
but number two,
and maybe more important than number
one,
is to work like a nut.
To work really,
really hard and to learn as much as you
can and to hope that you have some
talent almost equal to or equal to your
sense of effort,
because I have to tell you,
as an editor,
what always impresses me are the people
who are obsessed,
people who are gifted perhaps,
but I'm obsessed and they can't even
imagine themselves doing anything other
than a political covering the political
campaign or writing about the war in
Iraq or Afghanistan or for that matter,
uh,
writing fiction at the level of an Alice
Munro or George Saunders or whoever you
happen to.
Like those people invariably do it all
the time.
And with a sense of passion and
obsession that makes them as successful
as they are.