Yeah,
well I was still in my parent's basement
busily making money,
doing our audio visual stuff and I had
an older brother at the time who was off
in medical school and he's extremely
bright guy doing both an md and a phd
program and his phd work was in
developing therapies for pediatric,
in fact,
neonatal,
uh,
cancer patients,
babies with leukemia,
and he was developing the drug therapies
for these neonates,
but they're so small,
they weigh a couple of pounds.
There was no practical equipment out
there for him to deliver his therapies.
So He'd show up in the basement on trips
home from med school and whine and
complain about his lack of equipment
designed for babies.
It wasn't surprising to me that there
isn't a lot of equipment for babies
because fortunately not a very large
piece of the medical population.
Unfortunately old people get sick.
Babies don't normally have that problem,
but I could sit in the basement and
imagine that I could build tiny,
tiny little drug delivery systems
essentially using a syringe,
for instance,
as a whole day supply of drug instead of
an ivy bottle.
So I built for my brothers some little
devices that use the syringe as the
reservoir and build some electronics and
control systems that would allow him to
program those things for drug delivery
for his research.
I think he was very proud of my stuff.
I certainly wasn't doing it as a
business.
I was helping my brother,
but he would take it to med schools with
him and he ended up doing a little time
at Harvard where he met a lot of doctors
up in Boston.
Then he ended up doing a residency at
Yale where he met a lot of the adult
docs and one of these docs at one point
said,
you know,
that little thing is so small,
it's great that it sits in an isolet
moving around with babies,
but it's so small you could slap it on
the belt or put it in the pocket of an
adult who could walk around getting
chronic therapy for things that might
dramatically improve their healthcare.
Like what?
How about insulin for diabetics?
So suddenly I took this core technology
that I developed for this very rare
disease that we owe,
lots of people will,
will never have to deal with pediatric
cancer,
and it would serve a very,
very broad population of people walking
around meeting I insulin to deal with
their diabetes.
And so we modified the pumps.
We moved out of the basement,
we started making lots of different,
uh,
pharmaceutical delivery systems,
ended up building an ice company around
that.
And uh,
and to this day,
we continue to build stuff for home
dialysis,
diabetes care.
We build lots of products related to
helping people get both better therapy
and live better,
live simultaneous.