This video is sponsored by honey,
the browser extension that gets you the
best prices on everything you buy
online.
Hey wise crack.
Jared here with our third and final
exploration of Christopher Nolan's weird
wild mind.
And our first installment,
we examined Nolan's idea of the self
charting the relationships between our
subjective perceptions and the notion of
objective reality.
Unfortunately,
our investigation's still came too late
to save poor teddy.
In the second installment,
we use no one's dark knight trilogy to
discuss the fragile dynamics of society
and the ways in which social norms are
tested and upended by symbols,
by desire,
and all too often by hoking Weirdos in
mass.
Good.
And now in our third act will attempt to
find some catharsis by looking to the
universe per response to the fragile
nature of humanity.
I want to know where we are.
So strap in because this is the final
installment of the philosophy of
Christopher Nolan.
Oh,
and we'll be answering your questions
for the first hour in the comments.
So we'll see you there.
And of course spoilers ahead.
Whereas no one's previous works focused
on the inevitable conflict inherent in
humanities.
Rational nature,
interstellar attempts to transcend these
burdens by looking to the broad expanses
of the universe and hopes of ridding us
from the social and physical restraints
explored in videos one and two of this
series.
By merging a sense of wide eyed wonder
with the thrilling advancements of
science,
Nolan Helps Cooper and us break free of
the expectations leveled against the
self and society from as early as it's
opening scenes.
Interstellar situates his protagonists
cooper as an ambitious innovator,
but also as a clear,
I'd advocate for science and reason with
facts and present your conclusion.
He's also a guy with a pretty healthy
skepticism of power and authority.
It's an old federal textbook.
We've replaced them with the corrected
versions,
correct,
but before the films adventure is done
with him,
Cooper will have to reconcile his data
driven beliefs with the mind expanding
unpredictability of the great beyond.
Although cooper is firmly committed to
his own sense of practicality,
is eventually forced to navigate the
fluid boundary between the real and the
Iran deal.
The latter of which is a concept
introduced by American philosopher
Nelson Goodman,
but what is the aerial exactly in his
work?
The ways of rope making good and
explored the notion of alternative world
versions at its most basic
interpretation.
This concept allowed for everything from
art to mathematics to be perceived and
understood in a variety of ways.
Take a look at this piece of art for
example,
and you might see a woman's face or a
goblet.
Both interpretations here are correct in
total,
but only one interpretation is correct
through one particular context at a
time,
and this in essence is the art of the
realities.
There are multiple ways to look at the
world and no one method is better in
every instance.
As such,
the way the film's mysterious beings
experienced the universe opens up a for
a new way to experience and know the
universe,
just not in the way we're used to with
you know,
time is a thing that passes in space.
Cooper is confronted with the real,
nothing abides by his conventional ideas
of time or even cause and effect.
Cooper as a man of science has some
difficulty adjusting to a new normal and
through that difficult adjustment,
no one is openly able to question me.
Physical,
spatial and chronological laws that we
and cooper,
how long the leave to be absolute
throughout much of interstellar hyman
space do not interact with us in a way
we might traditionally expect and
neither as it turns out,
does all American hero Matt Damon on a
new plane of existence in which even
time can be warped
gravity on that planet will slow our
clock compared to Earth's drastically.
Every hour we spend on that planet will
be seven years back on her.
What asks,
Nolan is left to ground us humans.
What lighthouse is there to help us
navigate,
to give us purpose and direction?
Thankfully,
interstellar not only poses this
question,
it provides an answer and that answer is
the one place technology cannot touch
human emotion.
Although the characters of interstellar
frequently doubt what is real and what
is trustworthy there snot filled,
tear drench deeply emotional experiences
provide them with the ballast focus and
resolve to see their adventure through
to the end and those components of
humanity or the very sorts of things.
Science alone can't provide.
In fact,
near the beginning of the film,
it's suggested the crash landing that
stalled Cooper's aviation career was the
result of his reliance on technology
alone.
We should ease Andrew.
I can see him case.
The only time I ever went down in the
machine was easy and at the wrong time.
Ultimately,
it's human connection and emotion and
capsulated in doctor brands.
Love for Dr Edmonds.
Love is the one thing we're capable of
perceiving that transcends dimensions of
time and space
that leads this crew to the habitable
planet they so desperately seek.
Now,
that's not to say the film is
anti-science far from it.
Instead,
it demonstrates something more complex
that science is necessary,
but by itself is an insufficient
condition for a journey of discovery.
Science alone can't solve our problems
of limited resources,
identity,
or societal violence.
In interstellar.
Science needs something more.
It needs emotion.
It needs love to fuel and guided.
It requires human subjectivities that
launches us beyond facts and figures and
shiny chrome.
They have access to infinite time and
space,
but they're not bound by anything.
They can find a specific place in time
we can communicate.
That's why I'm,
yeah,
and in that sense,
interstellar represents something of a
capstone in the Christopher Nolan
experience in the face of the questions
of identity that arrives from the self
and from society.
Interstellar responds by showing how
scientific advancements merged with the
intangibles of the human.
Provide us with the necessary thrust or
new frontiers and personal liberation.
If there's an answer here on earth,
it's back there somehow in that room.
Of course,
the technology exhibited an interstellar
is not up today's world.
It's instead rooted in speculative
fiction,
and that's where the film itself even
acts as an elegant marriage of science
and imagination.
It shows us worlds and innovations we've
never seen before with interstellar.
Christopher Nolan confronts us with the
power of hyper [inaudible] cinema,
image driven storytelling up an imagined
future that can influence and
emotionally fuel us in the present.
And that future urges us to make the
Iran real real,
even if we have to crawl to the
uncertainties of time and space to do
it.
At least we're fueled by love along the
way with interstellar,
no one presents new worlds and realities
that push us far from the violence,
self destructive climate of the dark
knight trilogy or Memento.
And in these new worlds,
no one offers us an optimistic glimpse
of our own possible future.
So why did he follow this story with
Dunkirk?
A film about the allied evacuation from
bloody war time conflict in 1940 the
short answer perhaps is that Dunkirk is
about our future too.
In both interstellar and Dunkirk.
Nolan unites his audience in celebrating
the indomitable spirit of the human.
The notion that man and woman is
essentially good.
The notion that each of us is built to
persevere.
This is evidenced in much of Christopher
Nolan's recent work,
including the dark knight rises.
When catwoman tells Batman she's bailing
and assures him she's no hero,
I'll open that tunnel.
Then I'm gone only to prove herself
wrong in the 11th hour,
how sweet interstellar furthers this
cheerful embrace of human decency and
capability by using love to push cooper
all the way to the end of his journey.
Cooper's own indomitable spirit,
powerfully fueled by the love for his
daughter proves enough to ensure his
success.
What could be a clear example of that
emotional potency that unflappable will
to persevere?
Then both the British referred to as the
dunkirk spirit,
a term that's been used to convey
solidarity since the days of that bloody
battle in World War II,
the dunkirk spirit is defined by a sense
of community,
a willingness by a group of people who
are in a bad situation to all help each
other.
The film invest a deep sense of communal
spirit,
a spirit best embodied in Mr.
Dawson.
Despite lacking any military technology.
This guy pilots is small boat into
violent conflict,
commits himself to saving the lives of
strangers and emerges victorious thanks
to the sheer power of will you have a
tender on?
Oh,
we have a job to do.
Mister Dawson's instrumentation is not
technical,
but internal.
The step beyond interstellar and the
purest possible connection between the
self society and the spiritual unknown,
much like Doctor Emilia brand and
interstellar,
Mr.
Dawson,
it's resolutely piloted by love,
but while Mr.
Dawson was unable to save his son,
he is in a sense still able to save the
conceptual image of his son with each
life.
Mr.
Dawson rescues during dunkirk escape.
How'd you know that stuff?
Anyway,
our son was running you loud.
I know she is,
and you know what?
That achievement might just be something
even more noble and significant in the
realm of the indomitable human spirit.
Dunkirk suggests sometimes the Iran deal
is more real than real.
Not only is this scene in the choices
the characters make,
but in the way the film is constructed.
Dunkirk is structured in such a way as
to reveal the purest distillation of
this communal concept.
I didn't want to tell the story in words
I didn't want people,
I didn't want the theatrical.
If people telling the audience why you
should care about,
I wanted to care about him just because
of the physical situation or they were
in
where many of Nolan's previous films
have been criticized for being too long
to dialogue heavy and expository dunkirk
hawks in and only 107 minutes offers
backstory for almost none of its
characters and really doesn't have much
interest in conversation.
In other words,
no one created a sense of solidarity
between the viewers and soldiers without
relying on the tools often used to draw
in audiences.
Essentially it plunks us here with every
bullet fired in with every ship
destroyed.
Dunkirk aims to access the psychological
concept of an affective empathy,
the ability not just to know or to
understand what someone is feeling,
but to feel that feeling before it
occurs in interviews about the
production of Dunkirk,
no one said his ambition was to create
virtual reality without the headset.
In other words,
a fully an effective experience for the
viewer,
whether Nolan's successfully reached
this goal is up to each individual
viewer to decide,
but the blending of science,
technology,
and imagination to create an immersive
sense of participation in the dunkirk
spirit.
Well,
that might just be Nolan's loudest call
to each of us to bind together in
shaping and perfecting the self,
society,
and future that we want.
No one's most recent film,
didn't just bring him a boatload of
Oscar nominations.
It also brought together the threads of
his earlier work,
ultimately illustrating the power of
love and the human spirit.
Christopher Nolan is one of the most
interesting filmmakers working today.
His movies aren't only visceral and
exciting,
but also extremely thoughtful,
a rare blend in today's Hollywood.
This is merely our interpretation of his
work,
but as with any mastercraftsman,
his work will continue to inspire new
thought for years to come.
Thanks for watching guys.
Hope you enjoyed our Christopher Nolan
trilogy.
These hey wise crack.
Want to save money without the extra
effort.
Add honey to your browser to get started
today.
Honey has a free browser extension that
searches the web for coupons and
discounts.
They can help you save money on your
online purchases.
Honey does all the legwork so you don't
have to spend time looking for coupon
codes.
With honey,
you always pay the lowest price for
everything you buy online.
Adding honey to your browser is easy.
It just takes two clicks and you only
have to do it once.
Go to join honey.com/wise
crack.
Click add honey and you're good to go.
Shop at your favorite stores online and
watch the savings pile up.
Here we are getting a sweet discount on
some treats from our new favorite store.
Dick's mail,
and of course we can't pass up on
restocking are delicious serial wall.
Luckily honey,
always test codes.
Make sure you're getting the cheapest
price,
so there's no reason not to add honey to
your browser today.
It's free.
Takes just two clicks to install and
we'll save you money.
So click the link below to add honey to
your browser for free or go to join
honey.com/wise
crack.
And as always,
thanks for watching guys.
He's.