Technologies,
the other field to you like to keep
control and I was just in South Africa
interestingly where there is an issue
now between local South Africans,
especially black ones who come from
typically a deck around where they
didn't have a lot of education and
blacks and Bob when refugees who have a
very good education and so they would
get a lot of the it jobs except that
they can't get working papers.
So you know,
whoever's got control of the resources
it's going to use whatever excuse they
can to keep other people out and it's
not,
it's not men going around specifically
keeping the women out.
But the,
the culture of the old boys club,
all these traditional things plus a,
if you like,
learned aversion to technology in
science,
especially among women and girls.
And so all these things.
Interesting.
Good role model
and just time,
uh,
there's a problem now with.
It's not just women,
it's men as well,
not being interested in good,
solid scientific,
technical,
mathematical education,
which is key for all of this.