That was the vision of literature for
six a all the time.
Uh,
I don't think I'm a very exceptional
case because simply in our daily life we
approached sex either as a pleasure or
as a tool,
uh,
for literature six,
that would say even I don't like very
much the term six.
I would say the physical relation,
right.
Then the physical relationship between,
I mean,
between two partners are in lethbridge
means much more because you need sex not
only for pleasure,
sometimes you need,
uh,
to,
to perform a physical relation with your
partner because you are scared or
because you are disparate or because you
are looking for intimacy or because you
want to be protected by a mother,
for example,
a order,
uh,
you would like to discover your partner
or to take control many things.
And this is a very rich human domain.
Accordingly,
it's a very rich,
uh,
later in the field.
I mean,
you cannot ignore sexual physical
relation.
Literature is many things more than just
the pleasure you see or you achieved the
pleasure through many,
many roads.
You see,
uh,
it is,
it is an art.
It is a way to express yourself.
It is even a way to discover the world.
It is a way to discover your partner.
I don't think that you know really your
partner without having sex with him or
with her.
You see,
because this is one,
it's a moment of truth.
You see,
and you could discover your feelings
after having the physical relation much
better than before.
You see what is left.
You see in the few seconds after the
pleasure,
the physical pleasure,
then you discover exactly how much you
feel for this person.
You see,
it's very,
very mysterious and reach moment and
accordingly.
It's a big challenge for a fixture.