I want to read a passage,
it's almost a monologue.
Um,
after the murder of this,
uh,
this kid in the lower east side.
Um,
the whole communities kind of turned
upside down looking for the shooters.
And um,
one of the people who didn't get the
message that he's not supposed to live
in the lower east side anymore is this
junkie who,
uh,
sees a crime,
a crime of opportunity and snatches a
bag in front of Schiller's and tries to
get away with it.
And a,
he gets grabbed by the bouncer and a
first thing he says in a panic is,
let me go and I'll tell you your shot,
that white kid.
And so they have to track him down in
the middle of the night to see the
catching detective.
Who's this guy,
Mattie Clark,
the,
the two cops in this scene,
or Mattie Clark.
And there's a guy named Iacono who's
another cop who basically lives in,
in the windowless bunk room,
has been for six months,
comes out every once in a while and a
toothbrush,
shower,
clogs,
and does police work and then goes back
into the bunk room.
So this is about three o'clock in the
morning and this is taking place in an
interview room in a seventh precinct.
The city less to Kaufman said one knee
crossed over the other,
a cuffed hand dangling languidly from
the restraint bar.
People are doing so well,
you know,
but you can't,
can't ask them for shit anymore.
It's never been so bad.
Maddie grunted and sympathy the balance.
I had told them that the first thing
this guy had said when he grabbed him
after the attempted purse snatching in
front of Berchmans was,
let me go and I'll tell you,
shot that white kid.
I swam man.
Less to said to Maddy for the 10th time
in the last half hour,
I just said that like in a panic,
like the first thing that came into my
head,
what's left in my head.
Unfortunately mattie believed him.
Lester yawned like ally and revealing
adults.
Steel Ball Pierce through his tone.
I a cone rouse from sleep for this you
owned in response,
but I'll tell you man,
I'm really worried about my girlfriend.
I gave her $100 to get me something.
You know,
get me well,
she said 15 minutes and left me standing
at three hours.
I had no idea where she went.
What happened to a 15 minutes?
I mean,
I never would've done that if she didn't
lead me to at like half the night
watching everybody come in and out of
that place for smokes drunk or drunk and
half the damn bags right on the
sidewalk.
Another titanic yawn.
The delta,
the tongue.
Pierce winking sucks.
I Cohen said strap for a partner.
Maddie had cajoled him out of the bunk
room with the promise of overtime and an
easy commute.
I mean,
I'm fucked,
I know it,
but can you just check your computer?
See if she's in the system.
I'm hoping she got college.
Nothing worse,
but what's her name?
Anita Castro or colony.
Elvis.
I colon rose and went to the screen on
Yolanda's desk.
Rich,
you get $100 Leicester Man.
He asked where he shifted then coughed
into his fist.
Oh Man.
You don't want to make extra work for
yourself with questions like that.
No,
seriously.
Maddie,
let it slide.
Nothing I cold called out.
You.
Did you check Brooklyn?
No,
just Manhattan.
Could you check Brooklyn?
She scores on south second south third.
No one scores in Manhattan anymore.
My Net and is dead.
You guys took care of that Lester.
He crossed his knees.
A slice of grimy red,
long John Peeking out between his Pale
blue ankle and the cuff of his jeans.
I mean,
what the hell happened to us?
She was going to take me to the
hospital.
I have fluid in my lungs.
That's no problem.
We'll get someone to take you as soon as
we're finished.
Nothing.
I called and called out.
She got a third name.
She's not in the system,
Huh?
Jesus.
What do you think happened to her?
He asked Meti and me here.
This is a felony to right?
Not necessarily.
It depends how you say what you say.
You know visa vi,
sincerity.
Remorse.
I am remorseful.
I didn't miss.
I didn't threaten.
I didn't see anything.
What's a terroristic?
Alright,
just capture that and your statement.
In fact,
if you want,
we can even write your statement for
you,
but less than,
what can I tell you that you haven't
heard a million times before?
You help us.
We help you take this could go down as a
pet law.
I just,
I don't even want to pick the fucking
thing up off the sidewalk.
I don't even think anybody was going to
notice when that big black guy started
running after me.
I was like,
he had taken and didn't even get to open
a damn thing.
I have no idea what was in.
Now obviously I'm not a pro at this now.
Now don't get down on yourself.
I Cohen said from Yolanda's desk,
you know,
I got to say right now we're pretty much
eating out of garbage cans.
Me and Anita would,
a few years ago we had a store with like
$200,000
Oh yeah,
Matt,
he's turned to you and what kind of
store?
It was like a punk boutique.
No kidding.
Can I have a cigarette?
Geez,
I got to get to the emergency room.
All right.
Mandy clapped his hands.
Here we go.
One time offer the hell would the guys
who shot that kid just give us a stickup
team.
Just some names.
Anybody you know works the hood.
They check out.
Not only do you get a pass here,
but we take you to the Er,
get you squared away.
Then we go look for your girl.
A stickup team.
Let's just shrugged.
Recrossed crossed his legs,
looked away.
You know,
she used to use Carmen Lopez.
That was like a professional name at
this one place out in Massapequa.
She's a bod dance exotic.
Very good,
very popular.
Had a regular schedule like to see you.
And she could go to the houses summit
and embargo 30 $40 but she's four months
pregnant now.
So resting is Brown.
The curve is freehand.
I Dunno.
Maybe it's time to go upstate.
It's getting too hard out here.
You know,
that's it.