About a decade ago I realized that if we
were going to go to Mars with people,
it'd be really expensive.
And so I thought to myself,
what activities have human cultures
engaged in in the past that were as
expensive as what it might be to go to
Mars and what motivated them to spend
that money?
I was going to fill a whole book,
motivations to do great things,
great expensive things,
and then I find the uh,
the task,
I'd find the activity that more most
closely resembled what it would be to go
to Mars in the 21st century.
I said,
oh,
is that what that culture did with their
population?
Is that how they raised the money?
And that's how they convinced the people
I was going to fill a whole book of
this.
It'd be a nice little reference catalog,
but how to get something done in modern
times in conducting that exercise,
what I found is that there only three
drivers,
not more,
not less,
three drivers that account for the most
expensive,
ambitious projects humans have ever
undertaken.
One of them is the praise of deity or
royalty.
That's what got you.
Got You.
The pyramids.
They're basically expensive tombstones,
so it got the cathedral and Church
building of Europe.
That was a period where huge fractions
of of societal investment went into
those activities.
There's less of that today,
so that's not really a useful driver to
think about how we might transform the
21st century.
Another driver is war.
Nobody wants to die.
That gets you the Great Wall of China.
That gets you the Manhattan project
where we built the bond that gets you
the Apollo project.
Okay.
Another driver,
this search for economic return,
nobody wants to die.
Nobody wants to die.
Poor.
The search for economic return.
That's what is responsible for the
Columbus oranges,
the Magellan voyage,
Lewis and Clark,
figuring out what is beyond that
frontier in hugely expensive enterprise
is conducted by government.
So if we're going to go to Mars and if
war is not the driver did you could,
it could easily become the driver.
If,
if we'd be getting another space race
with someone,
we view as a military adversary,
wonder who that might be.
Okay.
But if peaceful heads prevail,
then war is not the driver available to
you.
Let's check our list.
Well,
kings and gods are not sufficient in
modern times to undergo heavy projects
such as that.
What's left the promise of economic
return.
You can go into space,
transform society changed the Zeitgeists
of your culture.
Turn everyone into people who embrace
and value science,
technology,
engineering,
and math,
the stem fields,
whether or not people go into space or
serve the space industry,
they will have the sensitivity to those
fields to stimulate unending innovation
in the technology and the technological
fields.
And is that innovation in the 21st
century that will drive tomorrow's
economies?
Any frontier in space now involves
biologists were looking for life.
Chemist,
geologists,
physicists,
mechanical engineering,
electrical engineers,
uh,
aerospace engineer's astrophysicist.
All the traditional sciences and
engineering frontiers are captured in
any ambitious goal to explore space.
We can recapture those times and
reinvent America.
We've already invented American once
before.
It's ripe.
It's ready,
and it's willing,
I think,
to be invented again.