There's a couple of guys,
uh,
for,
from,
from New York named Jozy Altidore,
he plays on the Olympic team,
plays for a full national team.
Uh,
he's a big guy.
I've gone up against them a few times
and he's,
he's,
he's young in his decision making,
but,
uh,
you can see all the tools are there.
He's,
he's very humble.
He's very willing to take advice.
He wants to learn.
And so I think he's definitely a kid to
watch.
Most people in soccer circles do know
who he is.
So for all those people that maybe are
on the fringes,
this is definitely a kid to watch.
Freddy Adu has been a guy who's been
well documented.
Uh,
he left the league last year to join one
of the top clubs in Portugal and I think
it's been a great move for him.
He hasn't been playing a lot,
but it's like I couldn't think of
anything better because now he's got to
earn it.
He's in an environment where they don't
care if he's already or do or not.
They see 20 freddy a dues,
you know,
all the time.
They probably have 20,
30 dudes on their team or they've been
stars and now he's going to have to make
the adjustment where he's,
uh,
you know,
not the number one guy and there's not
everybody telling him he's the best day
in and day out and so he doesn't have to
work for it.
So now I'm excited for him.
I think,
uh,
during this they just had the Olympic
qualifying tournament,
where are our boys qualified for the
Olympics?
And I thought he played very,
very well.
Uh,
there's another two kids,
one's named Marissa do,
he plays up in Toronto,
went to Maryland,
he was rookie of the year last year.
He's very good.
He's got a lot of the tools.
I think the guy's a deer.
We can be running whatever distance and
I don't think the guy sweats,
you know,
it's just,
I don't really think that's fair really.
But he is a specimen.
He's got a very good soccer,
but he needs another guy's very humble.
Uh,
he gets it.
And,
uh,
you know,
I think he's gonna be a very important
part of our net full national team for a
long time.
And then we have another kid named Sasha
[inaudible].
He played for Chivas,
uh,
grew up in California.
Uh,
it's got a lot of personality,
but that comes out on the field and I
think that kind of blend of being
technical,
but also having a little bit of that
flare a lends itself to our program very
well because I think that having those
kinds of kids,
those are few and far between.