In the entire universe.
The two greatest scientific mysteries
are,
first of all,
the origin of the universe itself.
And second of all,
the origin of intelligence,
believe it or not,
sitting on our shoulders,
is the most complex object that mother
nature has created in the known
universe.
You have to go at least 24 trillion
miles to the nearest star defined a
planet that may have life and may have
intelligence,
and yet our brain only consumes about
2030 watts of power and yet it
performance calculations better than any
large supercomputer.
So it's a mystery.
How is the brain wired up?
And if we can figure that out,
what can we do with it to enhance our
mental capabilities?
When you look at the brain and all the
parts of the brain,
they don't seem to make any sense at
all.
The visual part of the brain is way in
the back.
For example,
why is the brain constructed the way it
is?
It's just nothing but an accident of
evolution.
Well,
one way to look at it is through
evolution.
That is the back of the brain is the
sole call reptilian brain.
The most ancient primitive part of their
brain,
their governance,
balanced,
territoriality,
mating,
and so they're very back of the brain is
also the kind of brand that you find in
reptiles and when I was a child,
I would go to the Science Museum and
look at the snake sometimes and they
would stare back at me and I would
wonder,
what are they thinking about?
Well,
I think no,
I know what they're thinking about was
is this person lunch?
Then we have the center part of the
brain going forward and that's a so
called monkey brain,
the Mammalian brain,
the brain of emotions,
the brain of social hierarchies.
Then finally the front of the brain is
the human brain,
especially the prefrontal cortex.
This is where rational thinking is and
when he asked his self a question,
where am I anyway,
the answer is right behind your
forehead.
That's where you really are.
Well,
I have a theory of consciousness which
tries to wrap it all up together.
There have been about 20,000
or so papers written about consciousness
and no consensus,
never in the history of science have so
many people devoted so much time to
produce.
So little well,
I'm a physicist.
And when we physicists look at a
mysterious object,
the first day we tried to do is to
create a model,
a model of this object in space,
and then we hit the play button and run
it forward in time.
This is how Newton was able to come up
with a theory of gravity.
This is how Einstein came up with
relativity.
So I tried to use this in terms of the
human brain and evolution.
So what I'm saying is I have a new
theory of consciousness based on
evolution.
And that is consciousness is the number
of feedback loops required to create a
model of your position in space with
relationship to other organisms.
And finally in relationship to time.
So think of the consciousness of a
thermostat.
I believe that even a lowly thermostat
has one unit of consciousness that is,
it senses the temperature around it.
And then we have a flower.
A flower has maybe,
maybe 10 units of consciousness.
It has to understand,
uh,
the temperature,
the weather,
humidity where gravity is pointing.
And then finally we go to the reptilian
brain,
which are called level one.
Consciousness.
And reptiles basically have a very good
understanding of their position in
space,
especially cause they have to lunch out
and grab prey.
Then we have level two consciousness,
the monkey consciousness,
the consciousness of emotions,
social hierarchies.
Where are we in relationship to the
tribe?
And then where are we as humans,
as humans?
We are in at level three,
we run simulations into the future.
Animals apparently don't do this.
They don't plan to hibernate.
They don't plan the next day's agenda.
They have no conception of tomorrow to
the best of our ability.
But that's what our brain does.
Our brain is a prediction machine.
And so when we look at the evolution
from the reptilian brain,
the mammalian brain,
to the prefrontal Cortex,
we realized that it's the process of
understanding our position and space
with respect to others.
That is emotions.
And finally,
running simulations into the future.