Silicon Valley has been a strong
intellectual resource to us in putting
together I innovation agenda.
In fact,
our discussions began at Stanford
University and when we put the
innovation agenda together,
it became clear that a energy security
was it competitiveness issue.
It's not only a national security issue
for our country and an economic issue,
it's a competitiveness issue.
So right from the start,
as we put the innovation agenda
together,
silicon valley was there from the start
and on energy.
Of course,
the green momentum that is a,
a springing forth from Silicon Valley.
Is there an important.
Because if we're going to succeed with
our new green economy and with our,
our,
um,
addressing climate crisis and energy
security,
we have to have the marketplace,
uh,
lead the way.
So when we see Silicon Valley with all
the invention and ingenuity and
discovery plus all of the venture
capital flowing toward that,
we know that we can be successful.