I'm Anne Marie slaughter and I am the
dean of the Woodrow Wilson School of
Public and international affairs at
Princeton.
United States has to operate on two
tracks in the world.
One is addressing the crises that were
already in the wars that were already in
a,
the mistakes we've made.
So closing Guantanamo,
signing back up to the Geneva
Conventions for all Americans.
That's one agenda.
And that agenda is right there and it's
on the president's desk and he,
you know,
he has to deal with it and the global
financial crisis on top of that.
So that's one track and the president
has to be addressing those issues.
But at the same time there has to be a
longer term plan just like in a
corporation where you are investing for
the future where the president says,
all right,
you know,
over the next two years,
five years,
10 years,
20 years.
Here's our,
my vision of how America is going to
operate in the global economy,
in a global polity and increasingly
global society.
We are going to exploit the connections
we've already got.
We're going to build them.
We are going to understand that our
immigrants in many ways are our greatest
assets.
We are going to lead in a different way.
Where as I talked about strategic
leadership,
we're going to understand that partners
are terrific.
You know,
we want partners in every region and we
want those partners to take the lead
where they can.
Now they're going to be places where
only we can do it and then we have to be
there.
But it's a vision of the United States
at the center of a global web connected,
uh,
taking in the best ideas from all over
the world,
but sending them out whether those are
ideas on foreign policy or on innovation
and products or on green technology,
which ought to be a huge part of what
we're doing.
It's a vision of the United States that
says,
you know,
we're reinventing ourselves as a great
power.
One more time.
We started as a weak power.
We rose,
but we weren't really an imperial power.
We were a new kind of superpower in the
20th century.
We created all these institutions.
We actually cooperated with most other
nations around the world.
Now we're going to invent ourselves
again,
and we're going to invent ourselves for
a networked world.
We're going to keep our army.
We do need our military,
and we do have the ability to send
troops around the world,
but we're going to understand that that
is a small part of the game and probably
a diminishing part of the game in terms
of the utility of military force,
and we just like where the country that
invented the Internet,
we're going to invent how you lead in a
completely network
[inaudible].
Yeah.