Hip Hop's been dying or dead every
single year since it's inception,
so along with its eight of the top eight
downloads last week,
I feel it's not dead.
It's still got a tremendous influence in
American pop culture is still a great
brand building community in the world.
They have all kinds of,
uh,
inspiration and influence for American
mainstream.
They made the president by shifting a
race,
a race dialogue.
They,
they run DMC got MTV.
There was no black people at all except
Michael Jackson and he,
they,
they were,
they had ahead and changed a lot in
America and where people see each other
and Jay is not dead files.
I can tell this last.
Ll Cool J's on the number one show.
Ice T is not dead.
He's 45.
I'm 51.
I got new businesses that are hip hop
related and they're growing.
I don't feel hip hop is dead.
I don't feel that any good signs that
would say that.
I guess young people do download cricket
and then people would,
might buy a Whitney Houston record or
something,
but that's just what they do.
Hip Hop is being consumed as much now as
ever,
and that's an important statement and it
has as much effect or the American
mainstream culture now as ever,
and that's another good statement.
So it's hard to predict the death of a
culture,
a cultural phenomenon that's transformed
America in so many ways.