It's hard to give money away.
Sometimes that's the worst thing it
could do,
but I mean,
I would look to say the gates
foundation,
which now has 60 billions of dollars to
give away,
how are they doing it?
And I think they're going about it
rather wisely.
I mean they have put processes in place
and objectives in place and they're
targeting certain things in certain
parts of the world that would appear to
be at first some of the lowest hanging
fruit.
Some of the things that,
uh,
need to be done that might have the
greatest leverage for us to move forward
looking at things like population growth
and demec disease,
a corruption and try to apply it in a
ways that the money gets handed to
people who are responsible for it,
uh,
using techniques that seem to be proven
to be effective.
Hundreds of billions of dollars have
already been wasted.
Get people giving money away.
But at the same time,
when people say aid doesn't work,
I mean,
that's really not true because a lot of
a's does work.
You can just look at some of the money
that's been spent on recently for
eliminating simple things like malaria
and other diseases and there's been a
lot of ways too,
uh,
how effectively do that.
And certainly we should learn from that.
And there's plenty of smart people
working on exactly this and there are,
there would be ways to give away
$100,000,000,000,
although I'm sure you wouldn't do it all
in a,
you wouldn't do it all at once.