I think there has to be some evolution
to the curriculum.
Um,
but I'm,
I'm fairly old fashioned and then I,
you know,
I like to teach basic math skills and I
feel that in order to really master
skills,
you have to practice them.
Uh,
so,
um,
I may not be the most innovative teacher
in America,
but,
um,
mmm.
I think,
you know,
I keep coming back to the standards that
we have.
Every teacher has his or her own skills
and,
um,
preferences in terms of how to teach.
But I think,
you know,
we,
we have to make sure that we,
we learned the basics.
Um,
and,
um,
you know,
I,
one of the things I believe that happens
in education is that we,
we tend to latch onto the latest reform
idea.
Uh,
I,
I would call it the reform do shore.
And I would suggest most of these reform
movements that we have,
we've tried before they're recycled with
a new name slapped on them.
Okay.
So I'm not a big fan of new reform ideas
and thinking that those reform efforts
are silver bullets.
I just don't think this happens.
Um,
instead,
I believe that it's the teacher who
makes the difference.
So if it's a question of a program,
she's a person.
To me,
it's the person that is far more
important than the program.
The.