My name is Graham Hill,
founder of tree hugger and Interactive
Planet Green.
From,
from here we all but now we're in
Montreal and in the woods.
Uh,
I think it's very much shaped sort of
where I,
where I ended up.
So my parents were hippies and really
the community around there and my
parents' friends were largely people
sort of getting back to the land.
And so I lived in a log house and
learned a lot about sort of conservation
and nature from my child.
My parents certainly did help it vary a
bit.
They're very green in the own way.
My mother is a vegetarian,
has been for many,
many years and I certainly remember many
lessons of conservation from my father
in a more general sense.
My stepfather was very inspirational and
that he just helped me believe in myself
and just believed that I could do
whatever I wanted to do and that I was a
special person.
And so he was very influential and then
some,
certainly some great teachers along the
way.
My,
my childhood,
uh,
later on it was more books,
I guess I used to read fiction back
then.
So he was sort of different.
Um,
I don't even know if I can remember.
I mean,
I read it,
I read,
I certainly was a very much a bookworm.
I loved reading.
Um,
I don't think they inspired me in the
same,
same way.
I mean maybe it's our creativity later
on was more more books like a Gandhi.
I found very inspiring.
The,
his is a biography or autobiography and
certainly books regarding green
regarding evolution,
like a beak of the finch by Jonathan
Wiener,
natural capitalism,
uh,
by the 11th
and Paul Hawkin both very inspirational.
Pardon me from my parents,
certainly.
So I think I was always somewhat
conscious of it,
but really it was only a.
So I was vegetarian for quite a long
time.
I've certainly lived in terms of live
with less sometimes due to finances.
I think it really was,
it was,
it was sort of later on though is the
sort of mid,
mid twenties to late twenties.
I really started thinking about and
reading about it and,
and,
and getting more concerned about how I
lived and what
back I might have with the businesses
that I might create.
I always thought I'd be an adventure and
I think that's,
that's what I became.
And
I,
I still,
I'm a creator.
I like to,
I like to build things and I think that
that basically is what an adventure is.
I do some products,
I do some media.
Yeah,
you know,
I could do various things,
but really ultimately I'm an inventor.