Here,
he essentially,
his innovation was to recognize from the
start that the campaign is just really a
bad reality show and he made it a,
a,
a good reality show.
Now that's not saying that qualitatively
he was a good person.
I'm just saying that he knew how to make
good television.
He knew he knew how to attract the
eyeballs.
It's entertainment.
If you think about the,
the,
the financial incentives of everybody
who's on the bus or on the campaign
plane,
you have the candidates who are funded
by a,
you know,
a very small group of ultra powerful
commercial donors.
And then you have the press and they're,
they're,
they're basically funded by advertising
dollars.
And so there's this.
Somewhere along the line there was a
synergy between,
um,
the person who was the most entertaining
on the one hand and who was able to
satisfy the donor class.
And the other hand,
if you find that sweet spot in the
middle of those two phenomena,
that's usually where you were going to
get your candidate a is someone who is a
little bit entertaining and also a
little bit more flexible as a result of
that at the,
at the outset of the campaign,
uh,
especially,
he was able to attract mountains and,
you know,
billions of dollars,
probably a free coverage,
um,
at a period of the race when other
candidates have to buy their own
publicity.
And he made it into a kind of a genuine
revolt,
a where his voters perceive themselves
as to kind of be aggrieved victims of a
conspiracy of elites that were
represented by all the,
you know,
the donors,
the press,
uh,
the two parties.
And he managed to get past a lot of the,
the kind of the bulwarks that we usually
had thrown up in the past to keep him.
People like that out.
Like for instance,
um,
normally when a candidate slips up and
make some mistake,
uh,
I'll,
Howard Dean when he made his scream or
Gary Hart when it got busted with the
monkey business photo,
uh,
you know,
we typically used to descend upon a
candidate,
a reporter I know used to call it the
seal of death,
um,
where,
you know,
we would kind of swirl around a
candidate with negative attention and
that would really be it,
you know,
a few hundred times and they would show,
a damning clip and the person would just
exit the scene.
Uh,
there'd be humiliating public apology
and then a few a drop in the polls and a
few weeks later you wouldn't hear from
that candidate again.
That didn't happen this time,
this,
the trump managed to survive countless
scandals like that.
And every time everybody expected him to
go down in the polls,
he went up in the polls.
And I think a lot of people in,
in our profession,
we're,
we're kind of flummoxed by that.
They,
he was sort of defined the usual laws of
gravity and we just didn't know what to
do about it.