Roy at the present time,
our senses are inadequate to do the
things you mentioned.
However,
with the addition of technology,
it is very easy to imagine a time in the
future when we would have super senses.
For example,
our eyeball can only see red,
green and blue,
the primary colors,
but animals can see different colors.
Bees,
for example,
can see ultra violet radiation.
That's how the law clumped in the sun
when it's raining and it's cloudy,
you think that bees would starve to
death because they don't know where the
flower patches wrong.
They log onto the sun and in under
ultraviolet radiation bees can see the
sun.
So for us,
however,
we can't see infrared,
we can't see ultraviolet.
However,
it is possible that one day we'll have
contact lenses,
contact lenses with full internet
capability.
So we will blink and we will be online
and these contact lenses could be
sensitive to infrared or ultraviolet
radiation,
in which case we could see radiation
that is invisible to us already.
It's possible to get the x ray vision of
Superman.
If you think of Superman comics,
you think,
no way.
You can't have x Ray Vision.
You have half a photographic film behind
the person.
You would have to shine,
photograph,
shine,
x-rays,
develop the film to get the x Ray.
You're the person.
You can't do that with an eyeball.
It turns out we can.
There's something called backscattered
rays,
which gives you x Ray Vision.
Allah Superman,
almost indistinguishable from the x ray
vision of superman comics.
Here's how you do it.
You Get a light bulb that emits x Ray
radiation that floods the room,
the x rays bounce off the walls.
Then you put on special goggles or
lenses which are sensitive to x,
x rays.
Hit the wall,
go behind the person's back,
go through the person and into your
goggles.
That's how you do it.
Without photographic film,
let's call back scattered x rays.
It already exists,
and in fact,
because of the nine 11 attack,
there's been a rush,
a rush to put backscattered x rays in
airports at the present time.
In fact,
it's already causing civil liberties
lawsuits because some people don't want
their privacy invaded.
They don't want a superman to look at
them with their x ray vision.
So,
and even telepathy,
we have certain forms of telepathy even
today by putting Mri Scans and he eeg
scans onto our brainwaves.
So we can actually appear now into the
fabric of our own thoughts.
It's rather primitive.
However,
we have a dictionary,
a dictionary of objects like dogs,
cats,
houses,
and brain patterns.
So by looking at a person's brain
pattern through an Mri,
you can actually tell if the person is
looking at a dog or a cat that exists
today.
In the future,
our vocabulary of maybe 20 pictures may
be increased to a few thousand.
And at that point,
that's beginning to look like real
telepathy.