This video is sponsored by Nord Vpn.
Hey,
wise crack jared here.
And today we're talking about one of the
funniest and weirdest shows on
television Atlanta.
What makes Atlanta so thought provoking
is that it's simultaneously one of the
most realistic and one of the most
surreal shows on television.
It's this seemingly contradictory
combination that makes the show one of
the most interesting and hilarious shows
on the air.
So welcome to this wise crack edition on
the philosophy of Atlanta spoilers
ahead.
And a lucky if you're watching this
one's for you buddy.
But first a quick breakdown for the
uninitiated.
Atlanta has a simple premise earn a
princeton dropout,
needs to find a way to make some money.
So it links up with this cousin Alfred
Aka Paper Boi and becomes his manager.
All the while he tries to balance his
relationship with the mother of his
daughter Van and becomes friends with
Alfred's roommate darious.
But this simple premise is deceiving as
the show which Creator Donald Glover
described as twin peaks with rappers,
pushes the boundaries of reality to
insane links for both comedic and
dramatic effect.
And it accomplishes this by using both
surrealism and realism.
Let's begin by defining our terms.
Realism is any set of restrictions to a
creative work which demand that it
adhere to the dominant assumptions about
what is and isn't possible.
Realism presents the world with minimal
interference from the perspective of the
artist.
One of the best examples of contemporary
realism is the work of British filmmaker
Ken Loach.
We'll use this as films to presents the
gritty reality of British life without
any sugarcoating his most recent film,
I,
Daniel Blake tells the story of a man
struggling to stay financially afloat in
the brutal bureaucracy of the British
welfare state,
and unlike the typical Hollywood tale of
overcoming poverty,
Daniel Blake dies alone in a bathroom
stall before receiving justice.
Unlike this harsh realism,
surrealism pushes beyond the limits of
reality.
If Ken loach uses the camera to show the
world precisely as it is someone like
David Lynch uses it to create something
which exceeds our logical expectation.
Now,
it's also worth noting that most comedic
television is neither realistic nor
surrealist,
but simply fiction with no real claim to
authenticity.
This is why it doesn't matter that the
Manhattan of Seinfeld is just a
soundstage in Los Angeles or that Kevin
James could be married to three
different beautiful women into different
CBS shows.
Now that we're clear on the basics,
let's get into the nitty gritty of
surrealism with the Oji surrealists
Andre Norton,
who is to surrealism.
What guy theory is to donkey sauce and
percent.
Robert Barton was a French writer
working in the early 20th century who
viewed surrealism as both an artistic
and political tool.
One of the ways in which Proton
described surrealism is a psychic
automatism and its bigger state by week
one proposal to express the actual
functioning of thought.
Have you haven't had your daily
microdose of Lsd yet?
Put Burton is saying is that surrealism
uses art to express what's really going
on at both the personal and social
level.
Surrealist art might confuse us at
first,
but on the other side of this confusion,
we can see the world in a new light.
So how do you take an art form that
aspires to exceed reality and combine it
with an art form that takes the exact
opposite approach.
While let's find out first on realism.
Atlanta makes a deliberate effort to
portray life in Atlanta accurately,
especially for people struggling like
earth.
It removes the fictionalized glamour of
say a rap video and instead gives us the
sometimes not so pleasant reality behind
the facade.
Take paper voice apartment while the
network originally wanted him to live
somewhere that would fit the stereotype
of a rapper's house.
The show puts him in a pretty standard
Atlanta apartment building or someone
like paper boy would actually live or
redmond
got my eye and then boys right here,
you know we are in on the floor or watch
tv at the same time,
he also is usually profusely sweating
because Atlanta is king hot and anyone
who had portrayed otherwise with makeup
is a liar.
Meanwhile,
earn lives in a storage unit and works a
series of odd jobs while trying to make
it as a manager when they're in need of
sustenance.
Paper Boi and dairy is don't just get
wings from an anonymous restaurant.
They go to Atlanta institution Jr
crickets and ordered lemon pepper,
wet wigs,
a regional staple not available outside
the six seven eight and 404 area codes
major
and then couple of joints.
These cocktail sauce on snap lemon
pepper wings.
This commitment to realism makes the
city of Atlanta a character in the show.
This stands in stark contrast to
surrealism.
While it's realism is important,
Atlanta's embrace of surrealism has
produced its most memorable moments,
whether it's been the Tele Sandwich guy
on the bus
symptom,
not the way things necessarily the ship
black student wearing white facing
class,
a strip club Dj speaking to earn.
You'll just look at it Tipa what are you
going my man,
I said Chip Hook with that green jacket
out.
Whack ass cold.
Cool g shirt
or most things.
Darious does the careful.
It's very,
very cold.
Atlanta's world is full of seemingly
nonsensical characters and events.
Atlanta often blends the surreal and the
real together in the same scene,
including the one we just discussed
after being told that the chef hooked
him up.
We see a magical glow coming from the
wings showing the viewers from outside
Atlanta precisely how magical and
revered these wings are.
But often the use of surrealism can ask
us to rethink what we take for granted.
And the season one episode,
nobody beats the biebs paper.
Boys playing a celebrity basketball game
with the son of Justin Timberlake and
Post Malone Justin Bieber.
Well,
the idea of paper Boi dunking on Bieber
is perfect enough on its own.
The real twist comes when we see Justin
Bieber and he's well black.
The deal,
this is a clear subversion of our
expectation and while this surreal,
this casting might seem confusing,
it creates some wonderful comedic
moments.
Get a Buddha,
others because Brian's out.
Cool.
But what's most important is that
besides being black,
Atlanta,
Justin bieber acts just like the real
justin bieber.
He treats reporters and fans like acts
like a spoiled Brat has a huge entourage
and can't fathom the idea of anyone
getting more attention than him.
After acting like an asshole for much of
the episode,
beaver holds a press conference where he
apologizes for his behavior with the new
song
thing that bieber actually did in real
life.
Yeah.
This surreal take on beavers very real
behavior leaves the audience with a
crucial question,
namely what his behavior be perceived
differently.
If he were black,
black beaver would please Burton as he's
used,
not just for surreal humor.
The forces,
the audience to rethink their
assumptions about reality.
In this case,
does our culture forgive white
celebrities for bad behavior of while
holding celebrities of color to a
different standard and even weirder
example of surrealism takes place in the
same episode while paper Boi and earn
are busy at the celebrity basketball
game,
darious heads is local gun range to let
off some stress,
but his range mates get pissed when they
noticed.
Dairies says target poster isn't a human
outline,
but instead a picture of a dog,
this raises the question,
who would shoot a dog target shoot dogs.
We're not your second.
But then we're forced to consider,
well,
why would I shoot a human?
I mean that's weird,
right?
I mean,
look at that one.
This is way too specific.
It's also a potential nod to white
people's over the top obsession with
their dogs,
which nobody a wise crack from late to,
nope,
not,
not even a little bit.
I did not know people like dogs this
month.
I use of realism that is quite literally
hard to see.
Takes place in episode eight of season
one in which earned darious and paper
boy are outside the club after strong
arming the club owner to get paid.
Just getting their money was a surreal
endeavor in itself,
but things get even weirder once they
hit the parking lot.
In case you don't know what you just saw
that was an invisible car speeding
through the parking lot,
leaving bodies in its weight.
Is this meant to be a commentary on the
absurd ways that celebrities use their
money to flex on everyone else?
Maybe could it be highlighting the way
in which we have become so desensitized
to violence that the only way to make it
stand out is to use an invisible car
possibly.
Or is this Atlanta at its most twin
peaks,
and we shouldn't look for meaning at all
either way.
It's a good reminder that surrealism
doesn't always have to mean something as
often.
It's used to undermine and confuse our
rational impulse to project meaning onto
everything.
Nice condo.
The flip side of this,
meaningless surrealism can be seen in
one of the most uncomfortable moments of
season one,
the juneteenth party,
in case you're not up on your history.
Juneteenth is the holiday that
celebrates the abolition of slavery in
Texas and in general,
the emancipation of slaves throughout
the confederacy at the party,
the husband of the host gives earn an
impromptu lecture on the importance of
visiting Africa.
That was a pilgrimage needed to pay my
respects.
Ask for forgiveness.
One,
you know,
right?
I don't,
I really don't like you.
You've never been to Africa.
No.
You gotta go.
It's your motherland.
What are you thinking
and predicts his ancestors via his
facial features,
Congo,
Ivory Coast,
southeastern,
ben to region.
I don't know this spooky thing called
slavery happened and my entire ethnic
identity was her race.
And to ensure that he is the platonic
form of that white guy.
He let it performs a poem about the
horrors of slavery.
Jim Crow has the name of a man,
but is it
ghost?
I am a man,
but Jim Crow is haunting me liking that
movie poltergeist.
That's right.
The only white guy at the party
celebrating the end of slavery performs
a poem about slavery from the
perspective of a black man,
let me slave ships
and to add salt to the rim of this Super
Awkward Margarita.
The parties bar offers fun cocktails
named after the horrors of slavery.
I have to plantation master poison
and we couldn't talk about surrealism
and Atlanta without covering the most.
Talked about episodes of season one b a
n the entire episode takes place during
a fictional talk show where paper boys
being grilled by a feminist sociologist
for his lyric
rap is tickets coming home to roost.
My life is messed up.
Y'All did?
Okay.
That's black news.
You can look that up.
Well your news is problematic.
This,
that ain't my fault.
The crown jewel of this episode is a
black teenager from Atlanta.
That self identifies as a 30 year old
white man from Denver.
Hey,
excuse me.
What Ipa?
Do you have one tack?
Hey,
did you see game of thrones last night?
This came on the heels of the cultural
show.
That was Rachel Dolezal and the ensuing
debates about trans racial identity
while the notion of a white person self
identifying as black led to genuine
debate and consideration.
Atlanta asks us to consider how we feel
about the issue when it's a black teen
self identifying as a white man and
paper voice responses.
One that much of the audience likely
resonates with.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
This is dumb.
This is dumb
and this might be the ultimate genius of
Atlanta as unlike other shows that have
used surreal elements to take us further
away from reality.
Atlanta uses surrealism to bring our
back to reality by using the surreal to
disrupt the habitual way we look at and
think about certain topics we can
reconsider them altogether.
We see this in Clark County and his
hybrid music video slash commercial for
you who uh,
blacks on the base.
Like this seemingly surreal example of a
famous rapper making a song about an
artificial chocolate beverage exposes
something that's an actually going on.
I Eve,
much of art produced in our day and age
is really just thinly veiled
advertising.
We don't really need
good.
This example resonates with the
influence of Marxism one Burton as he
surreal moment leads to a sociopolitical
critique.
This use of surrealism for social
critique is what keeps Atlanta in the
spirit of protons work in both seasons.
Surrealism is used to reflect on
everything from inequality to cultural
appropriation.
Boy,
they before Christie grab go
and it refuses to let the viewer turn
off their TV without confronting
something real and urgent about society.
This might be the most unique
contribution Atlanta has made to
contemporary television in the same way
that an employee's surrealism without
veering into absurdity.
It also provides cultural commentary
without coming off as preachy.
Hi,
I'm Brandon Tartikoff,
chairman of NBC entertainment and I've
got a hit idea for the new fall season.
Don't do drugs.
There's no hope when dope
and it's this commitment to pushing the
boundaries of surrealism that gives us
one of the most insane moments of
television in recent memory.
Gotcha.
Okay.
Before we go,
it's worth mentioning the aims of
Bhutan,
surrealism in relation to Atlanta,
creator Donald Glover's,
musical alter ego,
childish Gambino as Britain makes clear
the aim of surrealism is not simply to
create a new form of culture,
it's to use art to change culture can
revealing its true structure.
The baton,
the world is only very relatively into
with thought meaning that much of what
we perceive isn't a true indicator of
the way the world really is.
We can see this in this is America.
We're surreal elements are used to make
a scaling political critique of the
State of affairs in Contemporary America
and if this video is any indication it
seems like glover and his creative
circle,
we'll be continuing to push the limits
of a new black surrealism for the
foreseeable future and as always,
thanks for watching guys.
These that guys,
what can also be surreal is finding out
your computer has been secretly hacked,
which is why most people use Vpn to
protect their web surfing.
We could have used one back in the early
days of wise crack when we were actually
hacked to get back our channel.
We literally had to pay off some hackers
in,
you know,
my life could have been like if I had
kept that bid coin to keep hackers out.
We could have used Nord vpn with
unlimited bandwidth and double data
encryption.
You can surf privately and securely from
anywhere in the world compatible with
windows Macko,
s Ios and androids.
Nord Vpn is a great way to start taking
your Internet surfing seriously.
Start protecting your internet
experience today with 77% off a three
year plan by using code wise crack at
Nord,
vpn.com/wise
crack don't get hacked.
It's really not fun to grab the steel
head to Nord vpn.com/wise
crack or just hit the link in the
description.
What show do you want us to dive into
next?
Hit us up in the comments and as always,
peace.