There's one way to be rational.
There are many ways to be irrational.
We could be irrational by getting
confused,
not taking actions,
being myopic,
vindictive,
emotional,
you name it.
There's lots of ways to be wrong.
And because of that,
there's not one way to fix it.
But one interesting way to try and
inject some rationality is to think from
an outsider's perspective.
So here's what happens when you think
about your own life,
you're trapped within your own
perspective,
your tribe within your own emotions and
feelings and so on.
But if you give advice to somebody else,
all the sudden you're not trapped within
that emotional,
um,
combination,
mishmash,
complexity.
And you can give advice that is more
forward looking and not so specific to
the emotions.
So one idea is to basically ask people
for advice.
So if you're falling in love with some,
some person,
a good advice is to go to your mother
and say,
mother,
what do you think about the longterm
compatibility of that person?
You're infatuated,
right?
When you're infatuated,
you're not able to see things three
down,
three months down the road.
You're saying,
I'm infatuated.
I'll stay in fragile forever.
This will never go away.
Your mother being an outsider is not
infatuated.
And she could probably look at things
like longterm compatibility and so on,
eh,
but there's other ways to do it,
which is not to be advisors to other
people,
but to be advisors for ourselves.
So for example,
in one experiment,
Eh,
we asked people,
we said,
look,
you went to your doctor,
they gave you this diagnosis.
You know that the thing that the doctor
recommended is much more expensive and
there are other things that will be much
cheaper.
Eh?
Would you go for a second opinion?
And people say,
no,
my doctor recommended it.
How could I not take their advice?
How could I say?
Can you please refer me for a second
opinion?
Then we asked another group,
we said,
here's the situation.
If this happened to your friend,
would you recommend that they go for a
second opinion?
People said,
absolutely.
How could you not go for a second
opinion?
So one idea is to try and get ourselves
from an outside perspective.
You look at the situation and then you
say to yourself,
if this was about somebody else,
some of the I love and care about,
and they,
when this situation,
what would,
why,
what would I advise them?
And you would realize that often your
advice will be different and often a
more rational,
useful perspective.