Yeah,
well it's always been a,
the big breakthroughs and transportation
has always been propulsion,
you know,
however you're gonna how you're going to
get the vehicle going from,
from the ground transportation side,
you know,
horse and buggies gave way to a steam
engines,
locomotives,
to,
uh,
the first practical small gasoline
engine and the cars first cars,
a steam ships,
sailing ships,
gave way to steam ships,
gave away to diesel and nuclear powered
vessels.
The,
uh,
the airplane started out as these tiny
little engine's turning propellors to a
turbo props and modern propeller
airplanes to the jet engine,
advent of the jet engine,
turbo jets,
and then two turbo fans,
which were efficient enough to allow,
you know,
the air transportation system as it is
today to develop same as rockets.
Rockets have remained fundamentally
unchanged except for a few exceptions,
uh,
for the last almost 50 years.
And so,
uh,
for there to be a fundamental shift in,
in rocketry and getting into space,
there almost has to be a breakthrough
and propulsion either and how to bring
the price down or how to more
efficiently get people up into space.
And that's,
as we talked about earlier,
the key barrier is the expensive a
rocket.
It's a matter of getting enough energy
to get off of the planet and into lower
earth orbit.
You know,
it takes,
takes a fixed amount of energy to do
that per massive payload.
And so that part is fixed.
But how you do that,
how do you get the energy,
how do you extract it from the chemical
propulsion you're using or if you're
coming up with a whole new way of doing
it,
um,
you know,
the neatest thing about research and
science is that we don't necessarily
know what's going to come down the pike.
You know,
we think we know what we're working on.
Oftentimes discoveries are made when
you're trying to discover something
else,
you know,
you end up accidentally discovering a
different thing.
And so one of those things might happen
then enable us to have more efficient
rockets.
I,
it's hard for me to,
to kind of guess what that might be.