Taking shots for anybody who may have
been in a position of where he's just
one vote.
Granted the bigger vote getter,
the biggest voter on the FMC is that,
you know,
we all were sitting in a world again
where we thought certain things were
going to happen and not happen.
And clearly when you Monday morning
quarterback somebody might say,
well,
we should have raised rates a little
more quickly and made money a little
less cheap and I would be one of those
that would say that today.
But when you sat there were making those
decisions,
I'm not sure that coming out of the 2000
tech bust and going through,
you know,
nine slash 11 and then having the Iraq
war come up in the Afghan war that,
that you wouldn't have had a bit of a
conservative view towards how rapidly
you do that.
Uh,
so clearly in hindsight you'd say,
yes,
we should have made money less cheap.
But again,
I think to blame the Federal Reserve for
what human beings are doing individually
is,
is a bit of a stretch.
You know,
one thing we've done in our company that
is a direct reaction to this is that we
actually have written into our equity
and bonus plans now,
we just did it this year that if there
is a material misstatement or financials
is that we're going to recapture from
the executives the money we just gave
because I thought it was just horrible
what happened,
not because of any of the right to
collect it,
but these guys walked away when their
firms went and had a lot of suffering.
I don't want that to happen on my watch.
Doesn't mean we can't make mistakes,
but I think you're going to start see
compensation plans also alter,
but that's a free market force that
wasn't imposed by any government is
boards will do that.
Our board was very receptive to it.
You happen to have a management team
that wanted to do it and they saw
something in the news they didn't like
and they change things.
So through a combination of changes from
the Federal Reserve combination of state
implementing laws,
I think we'll get some of this behind
us.
And I also think that what's remarkable
is to think that you could have a war,
you could have nine slash 11,
you could have all these things happen
where the global economy is still able
to absorb it.
And until very recently,
main street wasn't suffering like Wall
Street was.
So our economy is still very robust and
I think it'll still end up being,
even with this tremendous impact.
Um,
it'll take awhile,
but I still think we're in.
We're going to end up in a good place at
the end of the day.