Globalization today is not just the
spread of product and ideas and money
and even people around the world.
It's also about the arrangements that
are made by companies to start operating
in new countries,
to open up new factories and plants and
service operations.
When companies do those things,
they typically need middlemen to help
them enter those new markets,
and those middlemen can have a variety
of different occupations.
You need translators.
You need lawyers who can help you to
adapt to a new legal system.
You need accountants because there are
always new accounting systems and
regulations to you need fixers who can
help you to find locations for your new
operation,
help you to deal with local officials.
You need a whole variety of people who
are middlemen because they operate
between the foreign company that's
coming in and all of the domestic
actors,
whether they be governments or companies
or citizens groups on the ground.
This is truly important for
globalization.
Now,
where do these middlemen get their
return?
Well,
they usually get paid a fee up front
because the company is entering the new
market saying,
Hey,
there is some value to our being here
and we're willing to pay a small
percentage of that value to the people
who help us to open our operation and
that small percentage is what the
middlemen received.
They get that upfront payment.
If you're a middle man,
this is fantastic because you can help
one company to open an operation in a
new country and then you can help
another company and another and each
time you're going to get that little
percentage of the total value of that
company's engagement with that new
country.
Now,
middlemen have lots of opportunities
here.
They can specialize in a sector.
You could work only with companies in
oil and gas industries.
They could specialize in a country.
You can say,
we're going to be the law firm for any
American company that wants to enter
Ghana,
for example.
There are many ways that they could
structure their business and economists
have found that they are able to get
this significant upfront payment.
You could say,
well,
isn't this damaging?
Doesn't this take money away from the
company and from the people on the
ground who might have benefit who
might've benefited from the company's
operations there?
Well,
not really because there had to be some
sort of opening up the gates to allow
these companies to come in and this is
what the middle men provide in the
longterm.
It's good for the economies on both
sides.