I believe in the power of images.
I think,
uh,
I wouldn't be a photographer.
I didn't believe in the power of images.
I think there's an immediacy to an image
that obviously text or writing doesn't
have.
They both are incredibly powerful tools,
but they hit you at different moments.
So an image that can speak to people
really can bring them to that place or
transport them to that moment of pain or
that moment of urgency or whatever that
emotion is I'm trying to convey in that
image.
I think that an image has the ability to
take the viewer there immediately
because sometimes,
uh,
I feel like a hunter,
like I feel like I walk into a scene and
I kind of look,
the first thing I do is look at the
light and I figure out where is light
interesting.
Whereas the light source and where is it
falling?
And then I look at the expressions on
people and their faces and I'm trying to
think about what is the story I'm trying
to tell or what is the story that's
being conveyed to me?
And then I have to look for details.
I'm looking for sort of anything that
might be interesting or might sort of
convey a message and I often kind of
circle around that seen several times,
so I'll look at it from the front,
from the side,
from the back.
I'll go around it a few times and see
how the light changes.
If it's backlit,
if I'm shooting straight on and then
often I'll shoot the hell out of it.
I mean I'll shoot it every which way I
can.
I'm kind of very unconventional and how
I learned to compose pictures,
it was really trial and error.
So for me,
uh,
I'm often trying to fit a certain amount
of information into a frame.
I'm trying to tell a story with each
picture.
So that has a lot to do with how I
compose a picture and then I'm trying to
make it beautiful.
Not only even if it's a horrible scene
I'm trying to,
to sort of bring the viewer in and make
them interested.
So I don't want to take something and
make it so horrendous or,
or capture it in such a way that the
first thing they do is turn the page.
I want to engage the viewer.