Talking with them doesn't mean not
having sanctions on them.
We would continue to have sanctions the
way we do now.
It's just a question of making progress
while those sanctions are in place.
We had sanctions on Iraq for a long
time.
We didn't make a great deal of progress
in dismantling the well.
We claim,
or George Bush claim that we didn't make
any progress in dismantling the weapons
of mass destruction program,
which was why he claimed we had to go
back in again.
So sanctions alone don't do much.
When we asked earlier about hard and
soft power,
I said it's a whole combination of
things that have to happen
simultaneously.
Well,
this is an example.