We humans live on earth that we all know
and we can look up at the stars there,
stars that are close to us and our stars
that are further away belonging to other
galaxies and the stars that are
extremely far away belonging to
extremely far away galaxies.
Now for about a century.
We know that we see that far away.
Galaxies which are islands of billions
of stars,
far away.
Galaxies seemed to move away from us.
We see that the light that reaches us
coming from those galaxies is what they,
what the scientists called red shifted
meaning something has been stretched in
between those galaxies and us.
What has been stretched is the distance
that separates us from those galaxies.
As time goes by,
all the distances in space stretch,
they expand.
That's what we call the expansion of the
universe.
It is not actually that those faraway
stars or get x,
he's moved away from us.
It is the distance itself that
increases.
There is more space and time in between
them now than there was before.
Just to make that point clear,
that's when you,
when you are from on earth and look at
the stars,
the expansion of the universe makes all
the far away galaxies look as if they
were moving away,
but if you imagined that you were living
somewhere else in another galaxy far
away and the universe from there,
all the stars and galaxies that are far
away would again be moving away from
you.
To summarize,
the expansion of the universe means that
distances increase with time.
That's not something that is completely
crazy to understand.
If you imagine that the universe started
with the big bang,
meaning that everything we can see in
outer space right now was condensed in a
very much smaller volume a long time
ago.
Then somehow some energy got released
and everything expended.
Okay,
do you universe group,
but if you think about that carefully,
what that means is that somehow this
expansion,
these blow up,
this big bang thing should slow down
with time.
When you have an explosion on earth,
the objects that are thrown away,
they slow down because there is friction
because there is something happening.
Objects don't keep moving in flying
forever.
They slow down in the universe.
It should be the same.
In some sense,
gravity should keep things from moving
too far away from one another.
If is enough gravity.
For instance,
the expansions should slow down after a
while,
but there you go.
In 1998,
uh,
astronomers discovered that it is
actually the other way around in space
looking at far away galaxies,
they,
they realized that the expansion,
the rate of expansion is accelerating.
So there is a forest pushing away.
The faraway galaxy is faster and faster
with time,
and that's something that gravity can
not explain.
Gravity pulls things back towards one
another.
And this accelerated expansion means
that there is another force before that
has been called dark energy.
This discovery of dark energy,
of the accelerated expansion of our
universe did change something already in
the way we picture the future of our
universe for a long time since we know
of the Big Bang,
there were basically two possibilities
for the future of our universe.
The first one is that there is so much
matter in that that despite the
expansion,
gravity would work like some kind of
rubber band and would bring everything
back into what we call a big crunch,
that the everything will be pulled,
two words each other at some stage,
and the expansion would go the other way
around and we would have the the precise
opposite as the big bang,
which was called the big crunch.
The discovery of the accelerated
expansion kind of ruled that possibility
out in the sense that gravity will never
be strong enough to pull things back
into a big crunch.
We are the.
We are more into a scenario in which our
universe will keep expanding,
will keep being getting bigger and
bigger forever.
That is what we can expect as of today
for the future of our universe.