Well,
the question is,
if we're entering a new golden age of
space exploration,
what is the main bottleneck that we
face?
The main bottleneck has to do with life
support and the human.
You see,
we've already said robots.
Tomorrow's,
we've already said objects the size of a
bus to the planet Mars,
but now we're talking about humans which
require an whole support network and so
we have to realize that things that we
don't even consider it all with robots
become central and a bottleneck for
humans.
Humans have to live in an environment
where there's radiation,
where this loneliness,
where the journey could take two years,
where temperatures are below freezing,
where the atmosphere of pressure is only
one percent.
The atmospheric pressure on the planet
earth and eventually we want to create a
base there.
We're not going to go there just to
plant the fly and come back and crow
about it.
No,
we want a self sustaining a plant,
a base on Mars that could support
people.
This means it has to be done in several
steps.
The first step would be to create a base
on Mars with power solar power.
Can provide the energy and lava tubes
underground lava tubes,
might be able to provide caves by which
astronauts could live and create the
first outpost underground.
That's the way it was done in the movie.
Two thousand one.
The moon base on the moon in that movie
was underground providing a natural
barrier to radiation and then once you
have the base set up,
you have to begin the process of
creating a self sustaining agriculture
there.
I mean,
what are you going to eat on Mars?
You can order a hamburger because
everything has to be shipped from the
planet earth.
You want to create an agriculture and
this means genetic engineering.
This means creating genetically modified
algae and plants that can consume the
rich carbon dioxide atmosphere,
live in a very cold environment and
thrive.
Then we have to create mining
operations.
We have to mine the ice ice can provide
oxygen for breathing water,
for drinking and hydrogen for rocket
fuel,
and so we have to begin a mining
operation so that we have the materials
to build cities,
materials to build bases,
oxygen to breathe,
water to drink and hydrogen for rocket
fuel.
Then the last step in the process,
and this will take maybe another 100
years,
is to send satellites,
satellites orbiting around Mars to begin
the process of melting the polar
icecaps.
This is called space solar power.
We have the blueprints already.
The problem is cost,
but the costs are dropping for sending
payloads into artists space
dramatically,
and so people are,
once again dusting off these old plans
to create satellites around the earth
satellites around Mars that can beam
energy and begin the process of melting
the ice caps.
Now,
once you raise the temperature of Mars
by about six degrees,
is the temperature of Mars rises 60
degrees.
It becomes auto catalytic.
It takes off,
it becomes self feeding because the more
heat you have on Mars,
the more carbon dioxide you loft into
the atmosphere,
which creates more greenhouse effect,
which allowed you to melt even more ice
to raise the temperature even more so
you have a positive feedback loop.
The question is,
can we reach six degrees?
That's the key point.
If we can raise the surface temperature
of Mars by six degrees,
we can create this artificial spiral by
which it feeds on itself and we can
begin the process of terraforming.
Mars is there.
Remember,
robots don't need terraforming.
Humans do,
and so to make more suitable for humans,
that's going to be the big problem.