Good evening,
my name is looking.
My daughter and ever struggled,
ballsy,
so I'm sorry if I sound weird or look
weird,
but my question to you was on cold
fusion,
was it something that actually had
married or was it something that the
scientific community legitimately had
reasons for abandoning your thoughts
please.
Low key,
low key,
low key.
You don't look that weird to us,
sir.
He looked fine about cold fusion,
so here was the idea.
There's a guy who really had the first
patent on television was the mythic.
This was really his name,
Phylo Farnsworth,
and it is said he told people that he
had the idea for television by plowing
his uncle's potato field as a as a kid
and he looked at the way the the furrows
went across the field and inferred.
That would be a way to make a moving
picture.
That same guy got it in his head that he
could make neutrons do whatever he
wanted,
like he had this one success and he got
it in his head that he could influence
neutrons and he created a device which
he called a phaser and that that word
has later been used to describe a
rotating vectors in electrical and light
waves and a heatwaves.
But,
uh,
this thing was going to enable neutrons
to fuse together at room temperature.
He was not able to do it.
I mean this.
In order to do that,
as far as we can tell right now,
you need the gravity of a star,
which we have at our nearby star,
the sun.
And people have speculated that you
could also contain fusion.
Not speculated that's an exaggerated,
that's a I'm shortchanging us.
People have shown that you could contain
fusion in May,
in a magnetic field,
a very,
very strong magnetic field,
but no one has been able to build a
magnetic field powered by the fusion
reaction.
That makes the fusion reaction makes
enough power to,
to establish the magnetic field is
strong enough to hold it so that
everyone,
in my experience growing up,
it's always 40 years from now when this
will be done.
But,
uh,
recently,
an aircraft company,
I guess it was Mcdonald Douglas claimed
or yeah,
Mcdonald's claimed that they'd be able
to make fusion happen at room
temperature.
I'm very skeptical because they look at
what happens in nature with these stars,
but it's so far cold fusion was a myth.
Now then about 25 years ago,
1988,
1990 scientists at a,
at a university in the State of Utah
here in the US,
thought they had established cold
fusion,
that they had established a magnetic
field powered by the energy of the
fusion that would contain the reaction,
but they didn't.
They had the thermometer in the wrong
place on their lab equipment.
And,
uh,
I cite this as an example of journalists
who were not scientifically literate
enough to question this.
This result was published.
Results are announced result and they
just let the thing,
the journalists let the things spiral
out of control to the point where the
story to the point where somebody like
you 25 years later is asking essentially
the same question,
can we have fusion at room temperature?
So as far as we know,
no.
However,
it is reasonable that you will be alive
when people really do figure it out.
It's exciting.
It's a very.
It's a great question.