The reason why we have a much better
handle on crime now is because we have
trained the police to be police.
That social workers,
it's not their job,
not educated.
It's not their job to a degree,
not even role models.
They have to be like Sergeant Joe Friday
out there.
They won't have time to sit down and
have a cup of coffee and Nashawn what's
taking place because we have turned the
police department into a reactive
agency.
They're not proactive.
So they're racing around going from one
nine one one call to another nine one
one call.
Now that's not the kind of policing I
like,
but that's just the way it is.
So if the cops are going to be
responsive,
they can't always sit down and try to
figure out who's right,
who's wrong.
So their job is lock everyone up,
take them into the WHO Scow,
the cop shop,
and the judge.
Figure it out at arraignment.
Who should it be released?
Who should be incarcerated,
who should be given bail,
who should be remanded to jail?
That's good policing when you have
limited resource and what the
recessionary times where in and no
longer any stimulus money to keep cops
on the payroll with less cops in enables
you to do more.
So I think that's why at this point was
still able to keep the crime down
significantly in a time of recession.
But we can only hold out for so much
time as we have less and less police and
more and more people taking advantage of
the criminal opportunities that are
before them.
Absolutely.
The better educated you are,
it just means you have an opportunity to
become a more well healed criminal
command,
white collar criminal with a number two
pencil and rip off everybody by going to
Wall Street where the banks are too big
to fail and then we bail you out.
So instead of doing triple life without
parole,
for sticking a gun in somebody's back
and Robin on a $25 you'll rob them for
$25 million.
But you know something,
at least you can read the Wall Street
Journal,
right?
Isn't that an advantage in life now?
In reality,
it's the basic ability to take care of
yourself and for those that you have
responsibilities of.
So learning what life is about now
nowadays the pension is to have you or
an an academic diploma.
Most people that I've ever met,
including myself,
cause I don't have a diploma,
I got kicked out of high school and not
going to qualify for an academic
diploma.
They're not going to go on to college.
They're not going to get a bs or
whatever that is or an fact magnet
coombe loudly cause some of them are
going to major in having a 44 magnum in
their hand.
So they need to be taught skills.
It's called technical high school.
It's called in middle school.
Finding out if their adaptability is in
the academic world or it's that their
thoracic and that they like to work with
their hands and they'd like to learn a
trade and then giving them the
opportunity to do what it is that they
decided to do.
Even charter schools nowadays,
it's not full charter schools is the
answer.
You know,
it's more focused.
It's more disciplined and gives the
child a better opportunity in the belly
of the beast.
It's not one charter school in America
that's devoted to teaching technical
skills.
So is everybody going to be a white
collar workers?
Everybody is going to be a go to Wall
Street and become a thief and a
financial institution or a bank.
And then tell us how they should reward
themselves with a bonus because they
worked so hard.
Robbing US morning,
noon and night with derivatives and
subprime mortgages and giving out loans
to people who have no income,
no jobs,
no credit.
I know that's wrong.
You know that trump,
but hey,
they're smarter than us.
Got Brighter than us.
They went to Harvard,
they went to Yale and went to the London
School of Economics.
They went to wharton,
the business school.
Ooh,
far tall.
All of them send them to get more lock
'em up.
That's right.
Since we're clearing amount of
terrorists,
I'll kind of nut nate's right and tally
mine wanting,
but he's,
why don't we put all the white collar
criminals over there and get Mo..