The high roll in style that's portrayed
on television is basically a dream,
meaning that if you have a dream,
it can happen,
it could come true and in a way it's
good for kids to see that.
Um,
but a lot of times I feel like art,
if you tell it the high rollers,
I think the story should start from the
rags to riches because when you do that,
then it's a sense and it makes sense.
But the idea of just flossing,
you know,
hundreds and millions of dollars and
then jumping on a plane and then a boat
and the kids really think that,
you know,
it's your boat.
Um,
what I've learned,
because let me tell you something.
This is what I've learned through my
years.
The people with the real money don't do
any of that stuff.
Nine Times out of 10 they're in a room.
You won't even know who they are unless
you hear people talking about them.
So the thing about it is when you've
seen all this high rolling in you,
like,
I'm going to tell you what a ty Cohen
said,
tycoon has billions of dollars.
The tycoon said,
why clef?
You know what's funny about you guys?
Y'All want to be us and we want to be
young and that's the best way to explain
it.
You know what I'm saying?