I mean,
it depends on who you are,
you know,
it's like,
it's also shouldn't be a stressful
thing,
you know,
it's like,
it could mean that you take your family,
uh,
instead of,
you know,
to,
uh,
the price chopper,
you take your family to the farmer's
market once a week and you do,
you know,
it's a more expensive there.
So you do some,
some intelligent shopping and you'll
cook a little bit more at home.
And uh,
you know,
you,
when you're at the farmers market,
you're asking the farmer,
you know,
how is this pork raised and how is,
what,
what soil did this carrot growing and
what kind of carrot is at and all of
that.
And maybe,
you know,
he has three different kinds of carrots
that he's growing and,
and you come back the next season and
there's different carrots again.
And so all of this becomes educational
and,
and inspiring.
And,
and,
and because of that more delicious.
I mean,
I think that's,
you know,
that's,
that's one point that's,
that sometimes gets lost in all this is
that,
you know,
as chefs,
one of the great assets that we have are
these,
these front of house staff.
He's waiters to an end myself to,
to,
to tell stories about what we're doing.
You know,
where this food is coming from.
without the story.
You lead to a lot of that,
this association you were talking about
before,
you know,
it's the story that separates the small
family farmer and even the midsize
Pharma from the big food chain because
all along the food chain,
you know,
from seed to farmer to trucker to
distributor to marketplace.
Price is the determining factor.
But when you have a story from a small
family farm about a carat and about the
soil it's growing in and what that
farmers,
grandfather grew in that same soil.
If you have a quick narrative like that,
you have something that's so unique and,
and so,
uh,
infectious to people who want this kind
of food and it informs their appetite.
Literally.