You have an APP,
I mean there is actually,
you know,
if you're like a zillion ar,
you can take a trip to outer space and
into the international space station.
They're also all these sort of,
you know,
suborbital flights you can take.
Um,
it's,
you know,
to the tune of $35 million and up.
So it's not a mass industry at this
plane.
It's still kind of a niche.
Um,
yeah,
I think we will,
I'm not sure if it's 25 years out or
maybe a little bit longer.
Um,
you know,
Richard Branson is doing some amazing
things.
He's putting a big bet on it.
Um,
I think the appeal is there.
I think it's going to become,
you know,
it's going to be a pretty rarefied group
of people who get to do it.
Um,
but it's just such a nifty idea to be
floating above,
above,
you know,
above the earth and,
um,
and,
and seeing the curvature of the earth
and seeing the stars above you.
I,
you know,
I'd love to do that.
Um,
I do more of a Middle East.
Absolutely.
Um,
you know,
places like Oman and Yemen Oman's been
pretty stable for a long time,
but Yemen has been a little,
unless less stable,
I think that's going to come up.
I think Iran is it as an emerging
destination.
Um,
you know,
our political relationship with the Ron,
it's terrible right now,
but,
um,
you know,
there were a lot of Europeans going
there,
a lot of other Asians going there,
and it's magnificent country with a lot
to offer.
Um,
same with Pakistan.
You know,
I want to go to Pakistan right now
because it seems too edgy and Vol tile.
But I think as hopefully as things
stabilize and situations improve their,
um,
you know,
there's some,
some fantastic things to see that I
think Americans be interested in seeing.