Yes,
track jared here today were dawning our
trench coats as we talk about what went
wrong with the final installment of the
rather tragic Matrix trilogy,
the Matrix revolutions.
We could talk about the flat characters,
unclear motivations and structural
cluster,
but perhaps the most important thing to
address is the fact that,
well,
the movie just doesn't make much sense
or to put it more generously.
It has some colossal narrative gaps.
We basically can't make sense of the
plot without some pretty massive
interpretive leads.
Here are our top three burning
questions.
One,
how the hell does neil have powers
outside the matrix to?
Does Neil make his own choices or is he
just a pawn of larger forces?
And three,
is neil supposed to be Jesus again,
and how does this religious imagery fit
into the story given how much thought
went into these films?
It can't be that the witch house,
he's just dropped the narrative.
Ballz oily,
right?
So if the answer is don't lie in the
narrative,
perhaps they lie in the philosophies
that inspired the film's,
woken with his wife's cry condition on
the Matrix revolutions,
what went wrong,
and of course spoilers ahead in case you
don't read.
Watch the trilogy every few weeks.
Here's a recap in the matrix.
Neo wakes up from a simulated reality to
discover machines control the world,
and he is the one prophesized to save
humans from their metal photos,
digital ass kicking in suits in
reloaded.
These dreams are dashed when we
discovered that neos not special,
the prophecy was part of the machine
scheme.
All the log and the film ends with him
gaining insane powers,
but also in a coma.
In revolutions,
neo awakes from his coma and cooperates
with the machines to beat agent Smith
and a fight to the death saving humans
and maybe machines from lives of
servitude.
So how does neo have power in the real
world?
The only explanation in the film were
given is this.
Tell me how I separated my mind from my
body without checking it.
Tell me how I stopped for sentinels.
My thinking.
Tell me just what the hell is happening
to me?
The power extends beyond this world all
the way back to where it came from,
where the source,
and that's great you felt when you touch
those sentence
and then in the end of the Matrix video
game,
we get
touched.
The source separated.
It's mine.
These are basically non explanations
since they don't,
you know,
actually explain anything.
There are also fan theories.
Maybe there's a matrix within a matrix
or maybe Neil's wirelessly connected to
the source.
Dial up is very nineties,
but none of these are really textually
supported.
Instead we think these mysterious powers
have something to do with French
philosophers.
John Beaudry,
art in the Matrix,
the witch house keys referenced
boatyards several times.
Welcome to the desert,
the real,
the desert of the characterizes beaudry
arts critique of the postmodern era
where meaning and reality are replaced
by ear representations for Baudrillard.
The term similar locker described signs
that have no relation to the real but
pretend to like a painting that looks
like a polaroid photo of a Unicorn on
instagram.
When these fake copies without originals
get together,
they form simulations,
and when simulations hookup,
they replace reality.
With the virtual,
the web of media we're plugged into all
day.
What's worse?
There's no easy exit from the virtual.
You can't tell it isn't real,
because who even remembers what reality
is when the virtual becomes more real
than reality itself.
We enter hyperreality where technologies
and simulations control meaning not
humans like a desert wasteland.
Reality is emptied of meaning for
humans.
The problem is the witch house keys took
this a bit,
but literally they show technology that
controls meaning by literally enslaving
humans.
Meanwhile,
the real is a literal desert or more
like more door meets Manhattan,
and the Matrix is not just simulated
ideas and technologies,
but a physical network into which humans
are literally plugged.
Even bogart himself criticized the witch
house skis saying they took the
hypothesis of the virtual for an
irrefutable fact and transformed it into
a visible phantasm,
but it is precisely that we can no
longer employ categories of the real in
order to discuss the characteristics of
the virtual.
That's French for they've done for
Baudrillard.
There are no red pills and blue pills or
external reference points from which you
can distinguish the real from the fake
if you could.
One could easily choose the real as neo
and others do,
so laying one final bit of smack
boatyard insisted.
What would be interesting is to show
what happens when these two worlds
collide.
It seems the which house keys not only
took boatyards words to heart,
they plotted a pretty wild course
correction in the sequels.
They attempt to merge the real and the
virtual by giving neo powers.
In the quote real world,
we start the trilogy thinking of Neo as
real and the matrix and its programs as
fake,
but as the matrix revolution seems to
imply were wrong.
Neo doesn't just plug into the virtual,
he can't unplug from it.
The virtual is inside of him.
When he kills the sentinels or
experiences the train station in a coma,
we see a more complex idea of the
virtual that is not the opposite of the
real,
but a layer of the real or interwoven
and confused with it that neocon tap
into.
This may also explain how Smith entered
the real world.
When Smith clones himself onto Bain,
the real becomes virtual,
the virtual becomes real,
and the distinction between mind and
body collapses.
This idea of the real world as virtual
can also explain why neo can see the
world as energy pulses as if it's a
virtual.
Here,
the witch house keys borrow from the old
archetype of the blind seer.
Someone who through seeing less actually
understands more odin even plucked out
his own eye to gain knowledge,
although it's probably not what boatyard
had in mind.
Neil's blindness helps him literally see
a fundamental truth about the
relationship between the real and the
virtual,
namely that they aren't as separate as
he thought.
Finally,
Baudrillard helps explain what's
happening in that train station.
The weird limbo space between the real
and the virtual.
Here neo discovers programs who want to
escape the so called real world where
they're forced to carry out their
programming and attempt to hide in the
matrix from the perspective of humans,
the Matrix as a deceptive false space
that steals their agency,
but for the programs,
the matrix is a liberatory space where
they can be their true selves.
If you're a digital entity,
maybe the virtual world is the real
world.
This is perhaps why at the very end,
the Oracle is ambiguous in her plea to
the architect.
What about the others?
What others come on and say,
I'm fiercely.
They will be freed.
Is she referring to the humans or
machines?
Could be both,
but for the machines getting out might
mean getting in and for the humans,
vice versa.
This brings us to the conflict between
choice and determinism,
which if you remember from our matrix
reloaded video,
they never shut up about
causality.
Action,
reaction,
cause and effect.
Everything begins with choice.
No wrong.
Inevitable is literally the last word
neo ever speak.
That's right,
right after he says,
yeah,
wait,
choose what to keep fighting something
else.
Be Clear,
man,
and whatever choice he refers to isn't
even up to neo or AC,
just the product of larger fates and
factors.
How does this fit in with the oracles
apparent omniscience?
Is it some mutation in his programming
or purpose that drives agent Smith to
start a clone war?
Is it chance or does he reveal that
programs have the capacity for choice
and free will?
Let's see if we can use some philosophy
of free will,
determinism and fatalism to make sense
of this show.
Most of us experience ourselves as
making choices.
We write geeky videos on Friday nights
because like neo week shoes to and not
because we don't have friends for
aristotle.
This is because humans are rational
animals.
Our reason helps us to make choices and
differentiates us from other animals and
technology to call something a choice.
One must be able to act otherwise and
not be driven by mere instinct or
programming,
and most of us probably agree with David
Hume,
that the ability to act or not act
according to our own desires and reason
is the basis of human freedom.
Neo morpheus and the rest of the gang
certainly agree and they're cheesed off
because humans are being treated well
like machines with their minds and
bodies totally controlled while plugged
into the matrix.
They don't seem to have the capacity to
act otherwise,
and of course the arc of the whole
series bends toward gaining freedom,
but of course it's not that simple.
Neo and friends don't realize that
freedom of choice is actually part of
the matrix itself.
In perhaps the most cryptic conversation
in cinema history,
the architect reveals earlier versions
of the Matrix didn't work because even
though the world was perfect for humans,
they were being forced
choice.
Choice,
but choice is so essential.
Humans value to it even over perfect
happiness.
Do you know that the first matrix was
designed to be a perfect human,
the world or suffered every.
Everyone would be happy and it was a
disaster.
No one would accept the program.
Entire crops were lost.
The current matrix only works because it
accounts for the human need to choose.
I'll be at a paradoxical choice to give
up their freedom.
As I was saying,
she stumbled upon a solution whereby
nearly 99 percent of all tests subjects
accepted the program as long as they
were given a choice,
even if they were only aware of the
choice at an unconscious level.
Hey,
wait,
doesn't this look similar to boatyards
claim that we prefer and willingly give
up control of meaning to the virtual?
Yes,
it does.
Gerrit.
Anyway,
this produces anomalies in the heart of
the system.
Neo and his five predecessors.
Human choice means there are some
aspects of the architect's plan that
can't be predicted.
Enter Neil,
who chooses to save trinity instead of
reloading the Matrix,
freewill one,
determinism zero,
but does neo really make a choice?
There are several reasons to wonder.
First it looks like neo chooses to give.
The architects play a big middle finger
and runoff the safe trinity,
but for Aristotle and Aquinas,
the passions like love,
anger,
jealousy,
or the Kryptonite of choice and free
will.
They're no more than animal impulses.
The architect also isn't buying it.
Maybe it's because he doesn't understand
choice.
You and I may not be able to see beyond
our own choices,
but that man can't see past any choice
or it's because he thinks neos returned
to trinity is just the result of another
causal law.
Love
already I can see the chain reaction,
the chemical precursors that signal the
onset of an emotion signed specifically
to overwhelm logic and reason
or as a wise crack favorite puts it what
people call love.
It's just a chemical reaction to compels
animals to breed.
It's possible that neos just responding
to basic evolutionary programming,
what the architect refers to as a
chemical reaction.
Colonel Sanders incarnate believed that
everything is mechanistic.
The matrix fellow programs and even
humans don't have choice but operate
unphysical,
logical and mathematical laws of
causation.
This version of determinism dates back
to ancient philosophers like Democritus,
loose ipis and others you might confuse
for diseases who began noting the
physical was not random,
but governed by strict causal laws.
Determinist buzz kills that.
They are always claimed the appearance
of choice is just part of the system.
Once the architect notices the human
need to at least feel like they're
making choices,
even though they'd be plugged in like so
many light brights,
no matter what,
he just adds choice to his determinist
calculations.
Then the whole function of the one is to
control the narrative of choice and
resistance in a way that suits the
machines.
They're stuck in a cycle.
Every time you think you're escaping the
system.
Nope.
Xy on rises.
The one appears.
He meets the architect.
The one chooses most.
Everyone dies.
The Matrix reloads xy on the one weird
conversation,
choice death,
reload,
rinse and repeat until neo,
but even if we buy,
but it's love with a capital l,
not just chemicals that made him exit
door number two or do whatever he's
referring to here.
There are still reasons to be suspicious
that it was ancient human choice for
medieval theologian and 40 year old
Virgin Thomas Aquinas choices.
Not Enough.
It's our freewill that makes us
sensitive to which goals are best or
most moral and allows us to be held
responsible for our choices is neos will
free.
Well,
one very powerful old lady and something
called fatalism makes that unlikely and
don't worry about fatalism is like
determinism with a heaping spoonful of
the supernatural.
Let's focused on physical laws,
fatalist claim events are destined to
occur because the gods,
the fate,
or even our own character and
compulsion's directly caused them to and
if by gods they mean a bearded math
program,
a cookie baking profit and a self
replicating Lord l Ron,
then we're inclined to agree over the
course of the films,
the Oracle's been very busy.
She's the one behind the prophecy and if
we're to believe the prophecy is just a
mechanization to met out the anomaly and
guide him to the source,
then that would mean she's tricking neo
and his pals into almost every one of
their decisions.
Even when she pretends it's his choice
through a fatalist lens.
It almost seems like she and the
architect are pulling all the strings
and the whole series is just a game of
chess between the two of them made a
very dangerous game.
Then again,
the witch house keys leave us wondering,
does the Oracle really make her own
choices or is she just a product of fate
and determinism to by aristotle and
Aquinas is definitions.
It seems she does make choices.
I made a choice and that choice,
she makes the choice to save Sati and
let agent Smith turned her into a clown,
but she also says she made these choices
to fulfill her purpose.
What's your purpose to balance?
She also says they had to happen to
happen.
I'm sure it couldn't be here like you
remember
me,
but it wasn't meant to be
so maybe she isn't making choices,
so if neo isn't making his own choices
and the oracle might not be either than
is anyone.
This movie is freaking impossible.
Maybe agent Smith,
as his name suggests,
is the only real being with agency in
the film.
When he's killed by neo,
he refuses to return to the source to be
destroyed.
I knew the route,
so I understood what I was supposed.
It's a choice similar to the one neo
makes,
right?
No,
by his own account.
Smith as a diehard fatalist and he
doesn't see this as a matter of will,
but part of a grander plan.
We're not here because we're here
because we're not free.
There's no skipping,
no denying purpose,
because as we both know without purpose,
we would not exist
and he's pretty sure his purpose is
still to kill neo.
Ultimately.
Agent Smith believes freedom.
Truth,
peace and love are just illusions and
fantasies as meaningless as the matrix
itself.
There's a freedom or peace but love
illusions.
Mr Anderson,
vagaries of perception,
temporary constructs of a feeble human
intellect,
trying just Berkeley to justify an
existence that is without meaning or
purpose in all of them as artificial as
the matrix.
Really programming and fate are real and
because they're not programmed,
human lives are empty,
but just when determinism and fate
appear to have kicked us out of choice,
we're reminded that will for freedom.
Peace and love means something for both
humans and programs.
I love my doctor very much.
I just have never program speak of see
human emotion now,
etc.
But methods is the connection.
The word implies
love.
It is not just an illusion or some
chemical Bs.
It's a powerful and meaningful
connection and so his freedom or the
freedom to do otherwise sati doesn't
have a purpose.
I find it to be the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen,
like where we are from.
that is not enough.
Every program that is created must have
a purpose.
If it does not,
it is deleted,
but her life is still worth living and
she should be free to live it.
Neo realizes that just as humans can
exercise their freewill,
some programs can't either.
Maybe This is what makes neo realize
that it isn't just humanity that needs
saving from this war.
If we really want to talk about choice,
there must be choice for everyone.
Then again,
before we can put our neck braces away,
we're in for more whiplash because it's
the oracle who sent sati and her family
here at this exact time for this
revelation about freedom,
what choice to help you to guy neil
high and it makes it again seem like
she's controlling everything.
After all thIs and all the films chit
chat about choice.
It's not that neo or anyone else for
that matter actually makes one.
If nobody is making choices,
that is neil,
even the real protagonist.
Is it the oracle?
Are we even supposed to care as if there
aren't enough unexplained plot points?
Revolutions ends with some confusing
religious imagery.
What exactly is this glowing jacked in
jesus supposed to show us?
Maybe we can explain this in terms of
choice versus fate,
but also faith from the beginning.
Neo is a quasi religious figure who
helps save humans from their ignorance
and enslavement in the matrix.
He's basically straight out of the
gnostic gospels which talk about a
savior who is the ultimate guide to the
nature of reality.
This group of religious,
mostly christian heretics in the early
ce claimed that humans perceive the
material world in darkness,
sleep night and blindness and must be
saved through waking knowledge,
light,
etc.
Sound familiar?
Neil basically spends half the trilogy
just waking up.
When neo sacrIfices himself,
he enables true knowledge of reality and
peace between machines and humans,
but it's not determinism that gets him
this far.
It's faith.
He has faith in his purpose and in the
possibility of peace even when he
doesn't have a clue what he's doing,
but beyond that,
I don't know
even the faith of the other characters
play a big role in turning the tide of
the war.
So
while we can't explain how neo raises
the dead or how the blind can see,
that kind of seems like part of the
point.
Maybe the religious imagery is the last
word on the whole determinism business.
Some things exist beyond reason.
Clarity or calculations,
maybe part of what makes us human is
this capacity for faith in peace,
in goodness,
and something beyond ourselves.
So far,
we've tried to fill some plot holes by
exploring the witch house keys,
philosophy,
faves,
but perhaps the answer to our question
has been lying in a small detail all
along.
The oracles earrings.
Maybe many of the inexplicably
happenings in revolutions are there to
prove some sort of uni and yankee point
that it's not about winning,
but balance.
the philosophy of yin and yang found in
taoism and confucianism is present in
the films,
not only in jewelry,
but in themes like balance cycles and
dichotomies.
According to chinese philosopher joe,
he yin represents a dark condensing
force and is associated with metal fire
and the material world.
Yang is associated with light expanding
forces,
water,
earth,
ci or energy forces in life flows.
Notice that in revolutions the real
world is full of machines and bodies and
is literally dark and on fire while the
virtual world is of the mind or things
are light and well not on fire,
but getting yang are not dichotomies.
they stand for opposite,
but connected forces like a light and
dark side of the same hill.
So why do asian smith,
neo both have unexplained powers and
obsess over each other because they are
yin and yang,
light and dark sides of the same
anomaly.
what is he?
He's.
You could be so good.
The equation trying to balance itself
out
instead of confusing the real and the
virtual allah baudrillard,
yin and yang,
help explain how the real and the
virtual are two sides of the same coin
and both are important for achieving
peace between machines and humans.
Was neo making his own choices or was he
determined by larger fates like the
architect and the oracle who are also a
bit uni and yaggie we'll never really
know,
but in revolutions,
choice and fate are a bit yin and yang.
Equally important aspects of the human
experience.
Is the matrix really a religious
allegory bringing credence to the
prophecy or did the oracle make the
whole thing up to win a game of wits
against the architect?
Again,
we'll never know,
but maybe that's deliberate.
Both faith and faith are important
aspects of making meaning for programs
and humans,
and maybe we're being too meta here,
but it seems revolutions even combines
eastern and western philosophy as two
important parts of the philosophical
story.
So to summarIze what went wrong?
Well,
we've spent over 20 minutes
philosophizing about these films and
still have no idea what exactly
happened,
but maybe that's the point.
The film seems committed to being beyond
sense.
If they told us everything or flawlessly
implemented each philosophy,
wouldn't they just undermine their whole
point at some things are beyond
reasoning calculation and that's okay.
Or maybe we're giving the which house
keys.
Too much credit.
Either way,
despite their flaws,
we won't be unplugging from these
stories time soon.
Thanks for watching.
WIse crack.
We love making videos for y'all and it's
your support that keeps us going.
So another way to support us is by
becoming a patron patrons.
Get immediate access to exclusive patron
only releases including special podcast.
Our new video on the movie it and a
sneak peek of our upcoming wisecrack
addition on the philosophy of mr.
Robot,
and another new thing we're trying out
is a podcast format called wisecrack
addition extra.
You guys are always asking us about
behind the scenes stuff like what is the
research process look like?
What is the writing process look like?
What does it take to make these videos?
Well,
now I'm holding our long conversations
with the writers,
researchers,
and directors of these videos to help
you give you guys extra content.
If you want to think more about these
properties.
So if you guys are matrix philosophy
freaks,
I just recorded an exclusive interview
with the writer and researcher.
This video you're watching right now,
you'll get access to the podcast and
everything else on our patrion page.
Plus we're working on more exclusives
each month.
Once we reach our big milestone will be
able to branch out even further.
Look,
there are tons of movies and tv shows
out there that we'd love to cover,
but the reality of running a youtube
channel is that you have to focus on
stuff that's super popular in order to
keep the lights on.
So by helping us reach our nexT
milestone will be able to make deeper
track videos on topics.
You guys request the time,
stuff like whiplash,
dr twin peaks fargo and tons more,
and as a patriot,
you'll get exclusive access to these
videos months before anyone else.
So click here or use the link in the
description to visit our patrion page
and become a patron.
And if you're hungry for more matrix
content before you go,
check out our matrix playlist here.
Thanks again for thE love y'all.
Peace.