This video is brought to you by
skillshare.
Hey wisecrack jared again and today
we're taking a look at the show that
tears to ask the question,
how much body horror can we
realistically animate in 22 minutes?
I'm talking about Netflix is devilishly
good anime offering devil man cry baby.
While you may know it by its reputation
as that show with lots of incredibly
violent humping cartoon boobs and
incredibly violent cartoon boobs.
Domain crybaby has some deep things to
say about metaphysics,
the media and even international
relations.
So welcome with his wives crack
condition on the philosophy of devil man
crybaby has always spoilers ahead.
And by the way,
we never get it right whether you guys
want dubs or sub.
So we literally flipped a coin in
Atlanta,
did on dubs,
so be happy.
But before we get into the recap though,
I just want you all to know we're
working hard to put together an animate
podcast.
It's in very early stages,
but a lot of our best video ideas start
from podcasts discussions.
So subscribe to our channel wise cast.
You get a closer look into our creative
process.
Anyway.
Onto the recap.
Akira,
a teenage boy known for crying over
almost anything is living with the Maki
Mora family while his parents traveled
the world providing free medical care
when he tries to save his crush.
Slash.
Housemate Mickey Mckee,
Maura from what looks like a gang,
Aki raise interrupted by his trigger.
Happy adoptive brother and childhood
friend Rio.
Recently back in Japan.
After a research project in South
America,
Rio tells Akira what he learned abroad,
namely that devils are real and that
they are possessing human beings trying
to collect proof of his theories.
Rio Takes Acura to a drug fueled sex
party called Sabbath,
where his bloody rampage actually
succeeds in summoning a group of demons,
one of whom tries to possess Acura.
That demon Ayman fails to take over
Akira completely.
Acura gains the strength and power of a
devil,
but he's still in control of his mind
and body.
You're a man who possesses both the body
of a devil as well as the heart of a
human devil.
Man,
while Rio and occupy initially planned
to use his powers to fight the devils,
the show gradually reveals that there's
more to Rio's plan when the demon thread
is revealed to the Public Rio gains.
Immense influence with world leaders
turns on OC Euro and promotes policies
which encouraged the murder of not only
devils,
but millions of human beings.
This all comes to a head in the big
reveal.
You seen him say,
Yup.
Followed by a massive human devil,
devil,
man battle culminating in the end of the
world.
So how did we get from a bad night at
the club to the fricking apocalypse?
Well,
the answer has to do with two distinct
but related concepts,
moral panics and threat construction.
Sociologists,
Stanley Cohen,
argues that mass media constructs a
moral panic directed at certain groups
of people by portraying their behavior
as deviant society labels these people a
threat which justifies excessive social
control and policing over the quote
demonized as he puts it.
The media informs us about right and
wrong about the boundaries beyond which
one should not venture and about the
shapes that the devil can assume.
Devil may cry.
Baby references a few well known moral
panics.
For instance,
local news falsely identifies the young
rappers as members of a gang.
The mistake and their resemblance to be
constructed.
Stereotype of violent youth nearly gets
them shot by police even as they try to
cooperate with the officers.
The show also references the archetypal
moral panic which hunts for her almost
supernatural speed.
Miki is known to the media as up is
reach of track and field.
As a result,
the mob calls her a witch.
She's an outsider before killing her and
burning her body.
More to the point though is reos use of
mass media to create a moral panic over
devils after triggering code has
transformation at the track meet and
causing a massacre.
Rio uses his live stream too,
so fear and mistrust among the general
population,
demons exist.
That could be one right next to you
taking advantage of his academic title.
Rio claims to be merely a reporter of
the facts.
In fact,
he uses multiple media outlets including
social media and traditional
broadcasting to promote as much fear,
paranoia,
and violence as possible
in this battle.
Huggins,
I'm sure that we will win.
Once again.
As the end of the world draws closer,
Satan slash Rio encourages more and more
violence by expanding the definition of
devils to include anyone deviating from
the social norm.
He falsely implies that deviant behavior
is a proven indicator of the potential
to turn into a devil.
So you're saying that anyone
dissatisfied with society can
potentially turn into a demon?
That's correct.
So then in order for us to defeat the
demons,
we must eradicate them before they
become demons.
He pulls off the same feet at the
international level.
Through our process.
Scholars call the red construction.
Certain camps of foreign policy
theorists argue that many international
trends positive by national leaders are
largely constructed.
That is issues become threats when
people in positions of power define them
as such,
like creating a moral panic.
Threat.
Construction involves identifying some
other,
whether it be another country and
organization,
et Cetera,
and defining its otherness as a danger.
The other is portrayed as not merely a
physical threat,
but a threat to the very identity of a
domestic state political scientist.
David Campbell explains that in the
process of threat construction,
the other becomes the barbarian who
stands in opposition to the quote
civilized self.
Following this model,
Rio manipulates inherent weaknesses in
US foreign policy to start world war
three beginning a nuclear conflict which
wipes human life from existence.
Rio takes part in a high level
government discussion about how to
handle the threat posed by the devils.
By this point,
we're leaders have bought into reos
logic completely and have become
distrustful of one another.
We must be careful of the movements of
neighboring countries.
There's information that they've already
been taken over by the demons.
In response to the situation,
the u s government reflexively
identifies a Russia as a quote,
geography of evil,
a term coined by Campbell and declares
the devil.
Possessions are the product of a Russian
bioweapon.
The U s department of National Defense
closed its borders in response to the
possibility of demons being rushes
biological weapons
in devil man crybaby,
the u s and Russia respond to the
devil's much as real world governments
respond to terrorism because the threat
is barbaric and a threat to
civilization.
No measure is too extreme to stop them
including nuclear war.
No,
I like this.
The minute sure threatens our cow.
The show explores the dangers of
throwing up artificial boundaries
between groups.
The bloodshed and heartbreak that fills
up the last few episodes are a direct
result of the public's willingness to
buy into rios us versus them mentality.
Maybe you can run faster than people
because you're a demon.
You think you're better than the
Japanese.
This preoccupation with boundaries is
also reflected in the show's exploration
of what's called dual list metaphysics.
So what does that mean?
Doulas and posits that reality is binary
or oppositional in nature,
composed of two eternally clashing
irreconcilable forces such as good and
evil.
One of the classic examples of the list
philosophy is the ancient religion of
Manichaean as religious scholar Todd
calder explains according to Manichaean
dualism,
the universe is the product of an
ongoing battle between good and evil
substances,
which are in a constant battle for
supremacy.
At first glance,
the show appears full of binary
oppositions,
which will never be resolved.
For instance,
Rio is distinguished from AH,
era by his inability to shed tears,
which serves as a visual cue for the
ability to feel emotion.
Why would I cry?
I'm not sad it was going to die.
Anyway,
the show also sets up a sharp divide
between fear based violence and the
Maki.
Morris Christian passivism,
one of the people who was following
Jesus pulled out his sword,
attack the soldier and cut off his ear.
So then Jesus said to him,
put away your sword and return it to the
sheath.
Rio is a doulas to the core.
He describes Devil's as fundamentally
lacking in the human capacity to feel
devils have existed on earth since long
before humans.
They are ferocious,
extremely savage and have no emotions.
What's more?
The show takes that Manichaean idea of a
battle between good and evil substances
very literally real first discovers the
existence of devils when the corpse of
his formerly possessed professor is
revealed to wait twice the size it was
when he was alive.
This possession,
in other words was not only spiritual
but physical.
A case of two bodies,
one good and the other evil fighting for
the same space.
The show emphasizes the material
dimensions of this battle between good
and evil.
Whenever a devil successfully takes over
a human host,
often ripping apart their body in the
process over time,
however,
devil man crybaby winds up turning this
dualistic model completely on its head.
The show reveals the socially
constructed nature of the dichotomies
many of his characters take for granted
and argues that reality is far too
complex to be put in terms of black and
white.
As panic over the devil's thread reaches
its tipping point.
The show blurs the line between good and
evil.
One of the more obvious examples is
Akira,
who by his very nature challenges reos,
dualistic model of the world.
In one person,
he combines devil and human good and
evil.
We see this when Auc euro in his devil
man form stands between an angry lynch
mob and its targets and offers up his
life for theirs.
Why Chili Java?
If you're going to kill someone,
just chill van stead,
defying the angry and fearful humans
expectations.
By contrast,
we see an example of supposedly good
humans resorting to evil when the mob
dismembers and Burns Mucky,
mucky Maura for her public supportive
Akira and other devilment devil man
crybaby also loves to play around with
dichotomies surrounding gender and sex.
The show regularly hints at an ambiguous
Lee Queer relationship between hockey
era and Rio.
Aqua remains invested in his ability to
openly display emotion even after being
mocked for it as a child,
what the heck is crying?
Even though he's a boy?
And in his final form,
Satan embodies both male and female sex
characteristics,
but perhaps most interesting is the way
the show blurs.
The line between devils stand ins for
the outcasts and scapegoats of society
and the humans they're supposed to be so
different from Mr Machimura eventually
finds his wife and their son,
Toro in a refugee camp.
Unfortunately for him,
it isn't the reunion he'd hoped for.
Toro now possessed by the devil can't
control his own hunger any longer.
His father arrives to find him in his
demonic form,
eating his own mother.
Mr Machimura tries to fall back on these
socially constructed dichotomy between
devils and humans to reduce Tarro twin
evil creature and make some sense of the
horror confronting him.
God are no longer my sweet son.
This is for your Oh God,
but in the end he can't help but see his
human son in the devil's crying eyes,
please don't show.
Dot.
The show also provides plenty of
evidence to exhibit that contrary to
Rio's claim that devils are incapable of
emotion.
They're actually quite capable of
feeling love for each other and in some
cases for humans in the episode,
Beautiful Siren,
a cure.
It gets into what can only be described
as a deadly sex battle with styrene,
the former lover of acuras devil.
Amen.
In the first round of their fight,
Acura and nearly kills siren,
but as she lies bleeding out,
her partner came,
comes to her aid,
offering new give up his life so that
she can merge with his body and live
long enough to kill devil man site
bloodied.
You won't be able to fall.
Came sacrifice even causes siren to cry.
Most impressive of all is the change
that comes over Satan himself.
As a result of his experiences with
Akira,
having revealed his true form to Akira,
Satan admits that he made the merging
between him and Ayman possible so that
Okoro would be able to survive the
apocalypse and live with him forever.
Oh,
a Kiddo.
Let's live in the new world together.
I made you merge with the champion.
Amen.
For that very reason.
What's more when Satan Kills Aki era
during their battle,
he came up the devils experiences grief
for the first time and cries over era
his body.
He's awfully
by pointing out fluidity where we would
expect to find hard boundaries.
Dell man crybaby asks us to think hard
about the labels we apply to others and
the potential consequences of black and
white thinking.
The show puts forward some tough
questions.
Who benefits from media scapegoating and
to what ends?
To what extent does rhetoric play a role
in the identification of threats and
what are the dangers of being too ready
to draw lines between self and other and
in a world where categories as basic as
good and evil are the product of
manipulation and deliberate
construction?
What is the right thing to do as Mikko
and her blended human devil man form
puts it,
what does it mean to be a human?
What does it mean to be guide?
If you're going to die,
hurry up what is right
and as always he's
and wise crack.
We're all about philosophy,
jokes and the rule of threes,
but when the clock strikes five,
everyone's got their own silos.
I draw pictures of dogs wearing Tuxedos
or people on the Internet.
Yo,
two words,
bro.
I'm going to make bongs out of fruit.
Rollups money.
I run a website that lets me keep track
of every single bed bug in Los Angeles.
It's my calling.
No matter what you're involved in,
skill shares,
the best way to launch your side Hustle
with over 20,000
classes.
Skillshare connects you with tutorials
and everything from creating a business
model to investing how tubes.
So head on over to s,
k,
l.
Dot.
S.
H slash wise crack tend to get two
months of premium for free.
The first 500 wives cracked fans to sign
up will get two months of skill share
free.
So click here or at the link in the
description.