This video is brought to you by
skillshare,
the first 500 people to sign up with the
link in the description.
We'll get a two month free trial.
Greetings and welcome to earthlink
cinema.
I am your host Garrick's wormy Lloyd.
This week's artifact is the exorcist
starring the lady who was in like 10
minutes of requiem for a dream,
and the guy who was in like 10 seconds
of Star Wars,
episode seven,
the force wakes up.
The film follows female human Chris who
has a male name and her female daughter,
Reagan who has a Republican name.
Chris is an actress even though that has
basically nothing to do with the plot of
the movie.
Her daughter Reagan plays a game of
spooky monopoly,
which I guess is the inciting incident,
but the film isn't exactly clear on
that.
She starts acting like a millennial,
being irritable,
anything saying swear words and pissing
all over everything.
She sees Chris Shuttles in thousands of
doctors to test Reagan,
which she can afford because she's a
famous actress,
but the doctors can't find anything
physically wrong with her other than her
inability to transverse beyond the third
dimension and affliction that was common
in the Milky Way Galaxy before we
developed a vaccine one night.
Reagan takes it too far when she does
the whole don't tell mom the
babysitter's dead routine.
Deceased was killed and then pushed your
daughter's window.
So Chris decides it's time to give up on
modern medicine and start having a
little fun with it.
She goes on a romantic stroll with
father charisse across dressing mystic
to see if he can do that thing from the
title.
Forget about exorcism.
He isn't sure if Reagan is really
possessed by a demon,
so he asks her and she says,
after that all he has to do is
procrastinate for a little while longer
and then like a crunchwrap supreme,
he's good to go.
Unfortunately,
the bureaucrats at corporate determined
Charisse is too much of a sexy hothead
to perform the ceremony by himself,
so they fly in a ringer named Marin and
bump caris down to first alternate.
The two priests start vigorously
exercising Reagan,
who luckily has been content to just sit
in her bedroom the whole time instead of
making any attempt to leave or cause
havoc or do anything at all.
Demon Reagan responds by giving a gentle
razzing,
which causes him to get the vapor so
marin kicks him out so he can go it
alone,
maverick style,
but the real maverick thing to do is die
immediately,
which brings charisse back to times
square one all out of ideas.
He asks the demon to possess him instead
it and
the demon is so damn agreeable.
It just does it with no hesitation.
Then charisse jumps out the window to
his death.
Seems like it could just float away and
find someone else.
I don't really know how demons work.
The exorcist is a contemplation on
religions place.
In the 20th century of Earth's
existence.
The film was released during a time when
religious obedience on the decline and
the 19 seventies sexual revolution was
on an incline since that provides more
torque and the opening of the film,
we meet Father Marin,
uncovering doodads on an ancient burial
site signifying that spiritual beliefs
have been buried in favor of modern
fidget spinners.
Chris and Reagan are products of their
time ignoring religion,
even though it circles around them like
an annoyingly persistent Hulu.
Do you have any religious beliefs?
No.
What about your daughter know why
Chris Casually takes the Lord Son's name
in vain,
daughter on her birthday for Christ and
besides football.
Obviously the only significance of
Sunday is that she doesn't have to work
on a Sunday this year.
Thus when Reagan's problem start to
manifest,
everybody looks to secular explanations
such as her absentee father.
You mentioned her father and separation
and scientific causes like cte.
The film explores the area between
science and religion,
also known as homeroom father Charisse,
who's religious training was overlaid by
years of med school in Boston,
well near Boston,
initially considered the idea of
exorcism to be antiquated.
It just doesn't happen anymore on this.
Since when?
Since we learned about mental illness,
paranoia,
schizophrenia,
all those things they taught me at
Harvard.
His experience with his mother's
dementia predisposes him towards
psychiatric explanations for Reagan's
Tomfoolery only water.
Furthermore,
the demon pretends to be hurt by tap
water,
tap water,
which reinforces charisse has doubts
about the demonic properties of
fluoride.
In contrast to Caris,
the developed Father Marin acts with the
conviction that are racist,
grandpa set in his ways.
When Kara starts to explain Reagan's
case,
Marin stops him because of his extensive
experience with highlander.
I think it might be helpful if I gave
you some background on the different
personalities were begun as a benefit so
far,
I'd say that seem to be three.
She's convinced that
Harris ultimately accepts the true
nature of Reagan's possession.
The message being that religion
maintains its relevance in the modern
world since both religion and the modern
world are equally absurd.
Through Keris is journey.
The film explores the reason for evils
existence and area of study called
theodicy.
The film specifically espouses the
Iranian model not to be confused with
the Iranian model or the training model.
St Aaron has believed that to achieve
moral perfection,
a human must suffer evil and possess the
freewill to choose goodness instead,
even though it's boring.
Under this explanation,
Reagan's possession doesn't indicate the
absence of God,
but rather serves as a test of faith to
those around her,
especially that babysitter she killed
Father Charisse is alienated from God
because of his mother's condition and as
burdens as a psychiatrist and the demon
attacks these pressure points like a
Swedish massage.
Zeus in the end,
Charisse confronts his evil head on by
performing a Christ like sacrifice,
thus demonstrating is reunification with
God.
Similarly,
when Reagan kisses a preceptor,
she is cured.
The film suggests that the ordeal may
bring her to faith as well.
It also suggests she is in for a
lifetime of barking up the wrong dick.
Earthling cinema.
I'm Garrick's formula.
The power of space compels you.
Hey,
wisecrack guarantees intern.
Jared here,
you guys often ask us what sort of
applications we use to make our videos
and how we learn to use them.
Like a lot of youtubers,
a bunch of us here at wise crack are
self taught.
Luckily these days you can learn just
about anything online.
If you're wanting to jump into a project
or learn a new skill,
but weren't sure where or how to begin
skillshare can help get you started.
Skillshare is an online learning
community with over 17,000
professional and easy to understand
classes in design,
photography,
business,
and more.
Whether you're already a creator or
you're looking to become one,
you'll find likeminded people with steps
and advice on how to take your ideas to
the next level.
You can take classes on everything from
how to light for portrait photography to
the basics of three d printing to how to
make fresh pasta,
and if you've got a skill that you'd
like to share with the community,
you can teach a class as well.
A premium membership starts at just 10
bucks a month to get you unlimited
access to the full range of courses,
but the first 500 people to click the
link in the description will receive two
month free trial to skillshare and all
of its resources.
So head over to [inaudible] dot s,
h slash earthlink to to begin your two
month free trial and get learning.
You can download their mobile app and
take classes no matter where you are.
We can't wait to see what y'all create
and if you ever want to miss something
that we create,
don't forget to subscribe and ring that
bell.
Thanks for watching guys.
Catch you all next time.