This video is sponsored by Intel and the
upcoming vr film Pale Blue Dot.
Stay tuned after this video to learn
more about Pale blue dot.
Hey,
wise crack corporeal.
Jared here on the set of earthling
cinema,
so we just saw star wars,
the last Jedi and seems like it's pretty
divisive.
While the critics seem to love it,
it's one of the least liked star wars
movies by audience reviews and the wise
crack team is similarly divided,
but regardless of whether you loved it
or hated it,
it's hard to deny that the movie took
some big interesting risks.
It deliberately plays with our
expectations of what a star wars movie
is.
Rethinks the eternal battle between
light and dark and questions.
The efficacy of heroics.
Welcome is wisecrack quick take on the
last Jedi and for the love of God,
spoilers ahead.
If you haven't seen it,
go watch it and come back the last July
puts forth two major ideas.
One,
let go of the past.
Kill it.
If you have to end to.
Don't be a hero.
Preserve the light.
So let's break down the first one.
Should we let the past die?
Raise whole reason for seeking out luke,
in addition to getting him to join,
the resistance is to get answers about
her powers and her parents.
Rose holds onto a family heirloom that's
reminder of her deceased sister and
Leah.
After the murder of Han Solo is
struggling to hold onto the memory of
her son.
Other characters try to outright reject
their past.
Luke renounces.
The Jetta convinced that the force is
about balance,
not a bunch of dudes with laser sticks
convinced that they're the arbiters of
that ballads,
even decides to burn the temple,
and the foundational texts within luke
also rejects his legacy.
The legends of Luke Skywalker rose is
compelled to part with her past by
giving away her precious family.
Ambulant Kylo Ren is killing off the
memory of Ben Solo and he also urges
rate to forget about who her parents are
or his own lineage and join him in a
galaxy.
We're home.
Planets have a tendency to get blowed
up.
It's not bad advice,
but ultimately the film projects this
message reasserting the importance of
embracing the past.
Even though Lucan Yoda burned down the
Gi temple,
turns out Ray has those foundational
texts still safely stashed in her
belongings.
Luca firms,
he won't be the last Jedi,
and rose eventually gets her pendant
back,
but most importantly,
luke revives the legend of Luke
Skywalker when he confronts Kylo Ren,
but more on that later,
now onto the next lesson.
Don't be a hero preserved the light or
more specifically,
if being a hero means yelling,
Leroy Jenkins in the face of
insurmountable odds,
then don't do that.
This is embodied by Poe who disobeyed
his orders and gets a bunch of people
killed and taking down a dreadnought and
Finn who goes on a suicide mission to
destroy the battering Ram Canon.
The whole point of this is to say,
when things are so dismal,
the battle can't be about winning.
The best we can do is preserve the
light.
This is decidedly a different attitude
than other star wars films which
characterize the day being saved by Jed.
I'm hopping and swings and blowing stuff
up,
but with Vice Admiral,
oh,
skepticism of Po,
the last jet,
I takes a new approach.
Fin suicide charges interrupted by roads
who tells them that at this stage it's
not about defeating the enemy so much as
protecting what you love,
except that's exactly what Finn was
trying to do and after admonishing po
for the entire film,
Vice Admiral,
Oh,
saves the transport ships by sacrificing
herself and ramming the first order
cruiser more or less what Finn tried,
but in space.
So what the hell?
Star Wars.
By the way,
if you want to hear more of that kind of
fan rage,
check out our last episode of our movie
podcast.
Show me the meaning.
It's available wherever you get your
podcasts.
Anyway,
it's in Luke's arc in which we see these
two themes of the past and heroism
collide in a really interesting way.
Most of the movies shows luke
incessantly refusing to get off his ass
and join.
The rebellion is even confronted with
the exact same call to adventure as
episode four,
which he also initially refused,
but this time he refuses for like two
hours precedent joining up with the
cause like he did an episode four.
He does something else.
He projects his image to the rebel
holdout echoing roses,
words he's not here to defeat the enemy,
but to preserve the light by saving his
sister and stalling the first order.
He projects his image and dies from the
tremendous energy the feet requires,
but why didn't he just go in person and
kill Kylo or at the very least,
let Kylo strike him down all our ob one,
because the galaxy doesn't need a hero.
They need a symbol.
While layers call for assistance fell on
deaf ears.
The final scene of the film details poor
exploited children of Canto bight
retelling the story of Luke skywalker
surviving the impossible barrage of
fire.
This is where Luke comes to accept his
legacy and his past.
This revitalized legends of Luke
Skywalker will inspire more people to
join the resistance.
Then layers cries for help.
Luke Skywalker as a symbol will do more
for the resistance.
Then Luke Skywalker,
the man ever could.
There's another reason I find this
really interesting.
The original star wars was heavily
inspired by Classic Westerns with its
ensemble of outlaws and the lawlessness
of open space,
and in that tradition,
Johnson takes an idea that we see in
classic Westerns like the man who shot
liberty valance and Fort Apache in both
films and undeserving character is
enshrined in legend for the greater good
of the West and the man who shot liberty
balance the false narrative that the
idealistic ransom stoddard killed the
seemingly unkillable liberty valance
brings order to the west and in Fort
Apache,
the lie that captain Thursday died,
a noble hero enables the US military to
continue its duty.
He must have been a great name,
great.
Norman died more gallantly.
Luke skywalker may not have been the
hero people thought he was,
but belie created around his epic last
stand.
We'll go on to spark the next wave of
resistance in a quote that equally
describes all three movies.
A reporter in the man who shot liberty
balance,
proclaims,
and the legend becomes fact.
Print the legend the last July even uses
the western tropes of a retired
Gunslinger,
hesitant to enter back into the world of
violence.
Now,
if you'll allow us to get Meta for a
second,
there's another way of thinking about
all this.
The force awakens in dealing with its
own past decided to make a more or less
scene for scene remake,
a new hope,
but unlike Jj Abrams,
writer,
director Ryan Johnson,
did something much different.
Johnson took the fundamental building
blocks of star wars for saw audience
expectations and deliberately subverted
them every step of the way.
In many ways,
the last jet is similar to the empire
strikes back a wannabe jet.
I traveled to an isolated planet to be
trained,
ignores their masters advice,
then finds out who their parents are,
even swapped out billy dee Williams for
Bco del Toro,
betrayal and all.
However,
in the last jet,
I are mentor refuses to help and raise.
Parents aren't legendary Jetta.
I bought junkers who sold her for booze,
money and snow just dies with no fleshed
out backstory.
When I first saw the gaping dark hole in
the last jet,
I was like,
oh,
this looks familiar,
but unlike Luke,
Rey finds nothing there.
It was a deliberate misdirect.
And finally,
and I'm still a little unsure about
this,
the powdery white base is pretty much
the same as hoth,
but covered in salt instead of snow.
I was a little confused as to be very
deliberate proclamation that the white
powder was salt.
But here's what I've got salting the
earth.
In ancient history,
salting land was a way to curse the land
and prevent anything from being built on
top of it as salt is toxic to crops is
Johnson salting the earth of Star Wars
Lore.
By redefining the resistance and what it
means to be a hero.
Also,
unlike the original trilogy which finds
its heroes and princesses and people
with quote unquote noble blood,
the last Jedi Knight does a lot of work
to move away from this narrative.
Our heroes are fin,
a janitor rose,
a pipe mechanic,
and ray,
who we learn is not the descendant of a
powerful family lineage like the
Skywalker's but junkers.
And unlike the rest of the film,
which seemingly argues for preserving
the past,
the last gi is moving away from the
narrative model that defined its
predecessors.
So what do you think wise crack was the
last jet,
a cinematic masterpiece or a medic
laurian dumpster fire also will be doing
an ama for the first hour of this video
gets released.
We'll have a pinned comment or you can
ask us about star wars,
how we work,
my favorite Korean barbecue restaurant.
My dog would eat or anything else you
want to know?
As always,
thank you so much for watching guys
piece the last shit.
I's amazing story wouldn't have been
possible without the technology needed
to power it.
In that same vein,
Intel is paving the way for emotional
stories in virtual reality dedicated to
innovation and technology and content.
Intel is supporting the vr film Pale
Blue Dot,
allowing audiences to explore their way
through deep space where earth is just a
speck in the cosmos.
Inspired by the iconic Pale blue dot
photograph.
The film brings other worlds to life
with visual effects,
sound design,
and an original score under the
direction of indie filmmaker Eliza
mcnitt.
The film is part of Intel's commitment
to empower vr filmmakers and as huge
Scifi nerds.
We love this.
While the film premieres in early 2018,
you can catch every episode of the
making of the Pale blue dot,
the behind the scenes miniseries right
now.
The series offers key snapshots of
beignets journey with her fellow
filmmakers.
In this new medium,
we learned firsthand what it takes to
create a vr experience and how to
immersive you were in a story when the
audience has control over what they see
a wisecrack.
We're constantly analyzing the ways we
experience stories and we couldn't be
more excited to see how vr filmmaking
shapes the way stories are told.
Check out the entire behind the scenes
series of the making of Pale blue.by
clicking here or on the link in the
description.
Thanks to Intel for sponsoring this
video,
and if you haven't already,
be sure to subscribe and ring that bell
so you can catch all the great videos
we've got on the way.
Catch y'all next time.
Peace.