Oh,
hi mark.
Hi Mark.
Greetings and welcome to earthling
cinema.
I'm your host Garrick's worm.
You Lloyd.
This week's artifact is the room
written,
directed,
and starring.
My time traveling.
God's son,
Tommy Wiser.
The film follows human banker Johnny,
who despite everything about him is
taken seriously by his friends.
I was so happy.
I have you as my best friend and I love
Lisa so much.
He lives with the apple of his eyeball,
Lisa,
and they are madly in love for two
scenes,
tired of Johnny's esophagus disorder.
Lisa cheats on him with his bff,
forelle mark,
last name unknown.
In fact,
Lisa so done with Johnny's smoking hot
bod.
She gets him drunk to frame him for
domestic abuse.
Johnny naturally denies this to no one
in particular.
It's both.
Did Not hit her.
Did Not.
Oh,
hi mark.
And makes his home phone where?
Wire at an evacuation from the womb
party.
Mark and Lisa are caught swapping DNA
orally.
Why are you doing this?
To save the relationship,
Johnny announces that Lisa is more
pregnant than a dramatic pause.
We're expecting.
Lisa,
of course,
denies this.
There is no baby.
Johnny Imitates a horse and market tax
him before he can lay an egg
heartbroken.
Johnny locks himself in an indoor Porta
potty,
the phone rats on Lisa and they agree to
a bitter breakup.
Get Out,
get out,
get out of my life completely done with
earth females.
Johnny sucks.
A glock.
The room is a tale of duplicity and the
follies of love and trust to things I
know little about the film takes many
cues from classic dramas such as rebel
Wilson Without a cause and the streetcar
named desire.
Part one,
the latter of which provided sematic
inspiration for the room,
which was oh,
acknowledges with a little wink in the
cold.
Open Streetcar Concerns Blanche Dubai,
a formerly wealthy female who tries to
hide her past but winds up in Arkham
asylum when her fantasy world crumbles
just like blanche.
The characters in the room live
duplicitous often under the influence of
c,
two,
h six zero.
A wasted.
I love you,
Darling.
Lisa pretends to be a devoted lover,
but in reality is only using johnny for
his sweet bitcoin.
Mark pretends to be a loyal friend when
he's actually in bed with Lisa fucking
suggesting the soullessness that comes
with living a lie.
Almost all the characters deliver their
performances in a robotic fashion.
Oh,
hey.
How you doing?
Yeah,
I'm very busy.
What's going on?
That is to say with a battery of their
butts.
You're right.
The computer business is too
competitive.
The film accentuates this effect by
juxtaposing these lifeless characters
with the visceral energy of Chris r
Kelly,
although he's a criminal,
he's the only character who is honest
about who he is and therefore he's the
only one who appears high on life and
crack what is just as in streetcar,
the room centers around a domestic
location,
Johnnie's apartment.
The titular Tommy [inaudible] the room
by concentrating the action on the home.
The film focuses on the relationships
that form the sort of conflict.
The room takes a skeptical view of these
interpersonal,
intra human connections.
Johnny appears to have a ton of friends
on facebook,
but in actuality they're just liking his
status is out of boredom anymore.
He's not worth it.
The visual Motif of a foot sphere and
capsulates the film's pessimistic view
of friendship,
although intended for comradery,
it causes injury to two characters on
your mat come up.
The message is clear.
Friendship can hurt and mostly happens
in alleyways.
Similarly,
early in the film,
the color red symbolizes love and sex in
the city and everything from Lisa's red
dress to these red candles,
to the roses in the bedroom to this ball
gag at the end of the film.
However,
when Johnny rips up,
the red dress shoots himself and dies in
an ocean of blood,
also known as hitting the Johnny.
The colors,
meaning is transformed to reflect the
eventual outcome of some relationships
and all of humanity in its emotional
climax and sexual climax.
The film breaks the fourth wall.
When denny uses wise,
those real first name,
johnny plays brilliantly turning the
camera on the audience.
The film forces us to question whether
we are deluding ourselves.
I mean this film won an Oscar,
right?
Didn't it?
I mean,
crashed.
Did
for earthlink.
Cinema.
I'm Gareth Lloyd.
Ha Bye.
Hey guys.
Garrett is interned.
Jared here,
wanted to let you know about our new
channel wise,
cast wise cast is our new channel where
post video live streams of all of our
podcasts,
including our rick and Morty podcast,
the squash and our weekly movie podcast.
Show me the meaning where we dive deep
into your favorite film.
I recommend checking out our video on
inception,
where we chatted with our in science,
was Helen about the nature of dreams
here.
To check out our new channel and be sure
to hit the subscribe button and ring
that bell.
You can listen to all of our podcasts,
including a new westworld one on itunes,
spotify,
soundcloud.
You get the idea.
Well,
that's it for today.
I'm off to eat a big ass burrito.
Thanks y'all.
Peace.