Hey wise crack.
Jared here.
Today we're breaking down everyone's
favorite insomniac,
his soap salesman bff,
and they're super,
super secret underground club for due to
like to beat each other senseless.
That's right.
We're talking about that thing you're
not supposed to talk about.
For most fight club is about chiseled
men who like to knock each other's teeth
out and destroy private property to
escape the monotony of consumer culture.
But there's something about fight club
we often overlook is tyler durden really
the suave savior.
We thought he was welcome to this
wisecrack condition on the philosophy of
fight club.
And as always,
spoilers ahead.
Fight club begins with our nameless
protagonist slash narrator as he tries
to beat insomnia and complete his life.
One Ikea Shelf at a time.
Yes.
Like to order the Eric Carle dust
ruffles
is doctor suggests he see real pain at a
testicular cancer support group.
And our narrator finally finds the key
to sleep crying his eyes out.
But another faker,
Marla singer ruins it,
flaunting her lack of balls to are now
again sleepless narrator.
Testicular cancer should be no contest,
I think.
Well,
I have one more right to me though than
you.
You still have your balls off,
gets put on hold.
When the narrator's apartment blows up,
destroying his perfectly manicured
lifestyle and forcing him to live with
one tyler durden,
he and tyler share some drinks.
Go on wild in Xeni Adventures and
convince lots of people to beat the crap
out of each other.
Also domestic terrorism,
but we'll get to that.
The most overt theme in Fight Club is
the drudgery of consumer capitalism.
Our narrator lives a tiny life of
tedium,
working a job he hates throughout the
film.
He looks half asleep staring,
absent,
mindedly into space,
unable to feel anything.
At one point the narrator tells us
when you have insomnia,
you're never really asleep and you're
never really awake
as he watches an infomercial suggesting
that he's not only half conscious
because of insomnia,
but also consumerism,
but more importantly by club shows a
world of what sociologists call
rationalization.
Rationalization in this sense isn't
quite using rationality in the way you
might think,
but using a certain kind of rationality
to organize society.
Essentially rationalization favors
efficiency over tradition,
custom or individual desires.
So for example,
instead of getting your pies made with
love from the nice little bigger down
the street,
you get them from a factory where
they're made on a cold dead assembly
line.
Modern social life is pretty much
dominated by rationalization.
It's organized to accommodate large
numbers of people in the most efficient
way possible.
Everything in the narrator's life is
designed for a specific purpose.
Mass produced and unrelentingly
predictable down to his bosses tie.
It must've been Tuesday he was wearing
this cornflower blue tie,
even calls his own home,
a condo on the 15th floor of a filing
cabinet for widows and young
professionals describing
his existence as nothing more than an
efficient way to store and organize
things.
Fight Club shows us that efficiency has
its downsides,
especially in a world where efficient
means efficiently consuming to the point
where as Tyler durden says,
things you own end up owning you.
The narrator describes everything as
being a
copy of a copy of a copy.
Consumer products and consumers are
indistinguishable from each other.
The drive this point home director David
Fincher,
even put a starbucks cup in almost every
scene of the film for philosophers,
Theodore Adorno and Max Horkheimer.
This trend of indistinguishable
commodities is a direct result of
rationalization according to them.
Everything we're sold comes from a
standardized menu of constructs all
designed to be as cost effective as
possible while promoting fake
differences.
Consider the Dubé,
which may or may not be different than a
comforter.
I don't know.
I tried to read about it.
Gava
no want a DJ is blank.
Just blank.
Why don't guys like you and I know what
the phase this essential to our survival
in the hunter gatherer sense of the
word.
No.
What are we going to consumers,
right?
Some good marketing might make the
things we buy seem different from each
other,
but in reality they're all pretty much
the same.
Hobbies of copies of copies.
This commodification of all things makes
life pretty dull and also kind of
fascist for Adorno and Horkheimer and
for the characters in fight club,
living in a rationalized world can have
a dehumanizing effect.
Turning everyone into lonely,
alienated drones at the behest of
consumer capitalism,
living life,
just following orders if you will,
flown around the country on business
trips.
The narrator describes the isolation
that comes with a single serving
lifestyle.
Everything is small and disposable.
Even the people he meets,
it's the people I meet on each flight.
They're single serving friends between
takeoff and landing.
We have our time together.
That's all we get.
After getting in a car accident.
He muses about the dehumanizing effect
of his own work.
I'd never been in a car accident.
This must've been when all those people
felt like before I filed them statistics
in my reports.
So how do we cope with a single serving
lifestyle?
One might be tempted to say,
get a hobby,
bro,
but for Adorno and Horkheimer amusement,
under modern day,
capitalism has just become a
prolongation of work.
Hobbies and entertainment serve to
rejuvenate us so we can go back to work
the next day.
But those same things that keep us sane
in our off hours are still determined by
the system.
This makes amusement the after images of
the work process itself.
In other words,
if we are working,
we're buying mass produced stuff to help
us feel better about the fact that we
have to go to work again.
The next day.
I'd flip through catalogs and wonder
what kind of dining set defines me as a
person
or we get the fat sucked out of us,
which was caused by our own decadent
lifestyle.
You were selling rich women,
their own fat asses back to them.
The narrator's way of coping is still
just an extension of living as a
consumer in a rationalized world.
I had it all.
I had that's there.
That was a very decent wardrobe.
That was very respectable.
I was close to being complete
during the winter as far as directly
comparing this kind of mass consumption
to fascism for him,
the mechanism of rationalization that
causes people to blindly throw their
money at big companies like starbucks is
the same mechanism that causes people to
throw themselves at Fascist ideology.
Much like the citizens of a fascist
state mobilize under a totalitarian
dictator.
Modern society has mobilized under
capitalism.
It isn't until his apartment
mysteriously blows up that the narrator
finds a new way to resist
rationalization after losing all his
precious Ikea furniture.
He trades in elite and capitalism for a
place in tyler.
Durden is crumbling mansion on paper
street paper streets is the exact
opposite of his former apartment,
while the other one was small,
efficient and well decorated.
Paper Street is needlessly large,
disorganized and dirty.
If his apartment was rational,
paper street is irrational.
In his new home,
he joins tyler durden and his fight
against consumer culture.
Tyler,
the charming,
charismatic leader of Fight Club
champions a resistance against
oppressive consumerism,
offering the narrator and escape in a
way to reclaim his identity.
But what does escaping rationalization
have to do with punching people in the
face?
Tyler's resistance takes things a bit
further than your run of the mill
critique of capitalism.
He frames consumerism as an assault on
masculinity.
The men in fight club basically fear
that society is turning them into women.
They feel degraded by their jobs.
The narrator,
in this sense is the perfect image of an
emasculated consumer.
He's weak and goes to support groups
where he hugs people and cries,
you know,
girl stuff at the testicular cancer
support groups.
Some of them have literally become
emasculated.
One of the participants laments,
he's been cuckolded as his wife has had
the child they could never have had with
a new man.
She had her first child last week,
a girl with her new husband.
The film really drives this symbolism
home with the character of Bob.
Once a bodybuilder,
bob literally loses his balls to
testicular cancer and gross bitch tits
as a result of hormone therapy.
There's still men.
Yes.
Where I'm at man is what we are.
His loss of masculinity results in a
stranger from his family.
Any fields completely dehumanized?
No.
I'm Baker up,
divorced my two grandkids.
What do you mean return?
My phone calls.
The narrator and Tyler also discussed
their absentee fathers wondering what
the role of being raised by women has
played in their lives.
We're a generation of men raised by
women.
I'm wondering if another woman is really
the answer.
We name
and Tyler tells the narrator,
Oh man,
it couldn't be worse.
Woman could cut off your penis,
wave sleeping,
toss out the window of a moving car.
Seriously,
this whole movie is about losing your
balls and or Dick.
Given the emasculation of modern
consumer society,
Fight Club is appealing because it
allows members to express themselves by
acting in a way they can't in everyday
life being really,
really violent,
which is something they associate with
being men with a capital m.
Masculinity through aggression provides
a way for the men to cope with their
girly day jobs and domestic consumer
behavior.
But while Tyler durden laments the fake
kind of masculinity sold to us by
Hollywood,
he sells them another kind of manliness.
The second half of fight club is all
about how tyler durden has taken all the
things.
Project mayhem is supposed to rebel
against,
repackaged it and sold it to his
project.
Mayhem stooges,
the members of fight club just become
copies of copies of each other.
They shaved their heads,
called each other magnet.
They even lose their names in project
mayhem.
We have no names rebelling against the
system that's made them faceless drones.
They become well,
faceless drones and rumor,
all that stuff about losing your balls.
Well,
testicles under the reign of tyler
aren't fairing much better either.
The movie gives us an early glimpse of
what's to come as tyler durden just
repeatedly punches this guy in the Dick
Project.
Mayhem later threatens to cuts
everyone's balls off
publicly state that there isn't a
wunderground or these guys are going to
take your balls.
Even its own founder.
You said if anyone ever interferes with
project mayhem even you,
we got to get his balls for Bob and the
narrator fight club has simply replace
the support groups in their lives and
they chat about their fight club.
Days like one might talk about their
weekly support groups.
Schedules
go Tuesdays and Thursdays.
I go Saturday,
tyler acts like a strong father figure
for the narrator and the rest of Project
Bay Ham.
I will carry you kicking and screaming
and in the end you will think of me but
like the narrator's he father,
he left when I was like six years old.
I had this other woman had kids and he
like did this every six years.
He goes to a new city and starts a new
family
franchise.
Pilar abandoned him.
The most devoted members of fight club
are put through intense hazing to become
members of project mayhem before they
can join.
Perspective members have to stand
outside the paper street mansion for
three days without food or shelter and
her verbally and physically abused.
Those who tough it out are allowed
inside the house and Become Part of a
well oiled machine that blows up
computer stores to horizons politicians
and since corporate sculptures rolling
into coffee shops.
As Tyler's movement gains momentum,
it transforms from an afterschool
activity into a fascist cult that might
just be as bad as the capitalism they
rebelled against in the first place.
You are not,
we're not beautiful,
no place for the same decaying organic
matter and everything else.
Time was built himself in army.
We are the all singing,
all dancing wrap up the world.
We are all hard to say pop magic
mayhem operates through strict rules and
systematic efficiency.
Even rely on capital to run properly and
fund their activities by making and
selling soap out of human fat stolen
from a liposuction clinic.
The difference is now instead of
reporting to the demands of their
corporate bosses,
members report to their patriarchal
authoritarian leader,
tyler durden.
Sooner or later we all became what tyler
wanted us to be.
Chapters began springing up all over the
United States.
The narrator even calls them franchises.
Tyler had been busy setting up
franchises all over the country
the entire time.
Project mayhem has been plotting toward
a master plan,
blowing up the officers of the credit
card companies.
The narrator discovers this plan and
also discovers that he and tyler durden
are the same person.
Is that a pretty accurate description?
I've got relationship tyler.
We have just lost cabin pressure.
Tyler durden was the manly virile
compliment to the narrator's emasculated
helplessness,
and if we recall when the narrator says
early on that
and suddenly I realized that all of
this,
the gun,
the bombs,
the revolution that's got something to
do with a girl named Marla sings
probably means that his spiral into
psychosis began when he needed to create
an alter ego to be with her.
You were looking for a way to change
your life.
Could not do this on your own,
all the ways you wish you could be.
That's me.
Look like you want to look like you want
to look.
I'm smart,
capable,
and most importantly,
I'm free and all the ways that you are
not,
he's able to get rid of durden by
shooting himself in the face,
but the damage is already done.
The buildings collapsed supposedly to
reset societies debt,
although I'm not sure how that actually
works.
Just like tyler and the narrator are two
sides of the same person for Adorno and
Horkheimer.
Fascism and capitalism are two sides of
the same coin.
They argued that both fascism and
capitalism see human beings as numbers
instead of individuals.
Alienated objects to be used and
control.
So what do you guys think?
What's worse?
So coming to the lower of Ikea catalogs
and coffee chains,
or following the orders of a fascist
soap salesman offering promises of
humanity.
Let us know what you think in the
comments or don't.
But if you want to hear more about what
we think about movies,
checkout our new movie podcast called,
show me the meaning in it.
We're breaking down some of the best and
worst movies ever made,
but we've got a bunch more planned for
you guys and we want to hear what you
want to hear.
So send us suggestions on which movies
to break down next@moviesatwisecrack.co.
Click here or at the link in the
description to subscribe to show me the
meaning on apple podcasts,
Google play,
stitcher,
or wherever else you get your podcasts.
Thanks again guys.
Catch you all next time.
Peace.