Hey,
wise,
crack,
fleshy,
jared again,
and today we're breaking down season
three,
episode nine of Rick and Morty,
the abcs of Beth.
This episode is one of my favorites,
not only because it develops Beth in
some interesting ways,
but because it builds on a theme from
way back in another season.
Three favorite pick on that idea,
the importance of choice.
Welcome this wise crack quick take on
the abcs of Beth.
First,
a quick recap.
The father of Beth's adolescent friend,
Tommy.
It's about to be put to death for
eating.
His son that's soon realizes her
childhood fantasy of fruit.
De Leon was not some mechanism to cope
with her friend's death,
but a very real place built by rick to
keep her sociopathic tendencies out of
his way.
Also,
Tommy has built a kingdom on incest and
cannibalism.
I suppose you're wondering,
how do I sustain myself?
Oh boy,
we aren't.
Meanwhile,
Jerry has a new alien girlfriend,
Kiarra and things are moving fast.
Does your planet have shorter days
because you guys are moving kind of
fast?
No,
Jerry decides to break up with her,
but isn't able to take responsibility
for his decision and blames his kid
after kid tries to murder morning in
summer for allegedly causing the
breakup.
Jerry finally owns up to his actions in
the abcs of Beth,
the A and b plots parallel each other.
We have Beth Cherry and even greg
unwilling to take responsibility for
their choices.
Beth refuses to acknowledge sentencing
Tommy to a life of humping teletubby.
Tommy,
I'm sorry.
You think you deserve an apology.
And Rick Denies Building for Upi land to
avoid being emotionally available to his
daughter.
I'm sorry.
You think you deserve an apology?
Whereas Jerry refuses to take
responsibility for ending his toxic
relationship with Kiarra.
So what does all this have to do with
pickle rick?
Well,
this
and I think it's because the only truly
unapproachable concept for you is that
it's your mind within your control.
You chose to come here.
You chose to talk to belittle my
vocation just as you chose to become a
pickle.
Each of us gets to choose.
As we've mentioned before,
this season is playing a lot with the
ideas of agency freedom and most
importantly choice as Dr Wong noted in
brick managing the stone.
Morty is angry at his father for having
no agency standing in the driveway.
Talking about company can either tell
her you want to stay married or get on
with your life,
but whatever you do,
stop being a baby in pickle.
Rick.
Rick literally gives up his freedom by
becoming a pickle and elaborate ruse to
avoid therapy in the Rick Landis mixup.
We see what happens when ricks give up
their freedom and of course in the world
early conspiracy.
One of my favorite moments in the season
is this advice to jerry,
but there comes a time in every man's
life when he must choose the foundation
on which his legacy will be built.
What of compromise one of blood in our
pickle.
Quick take.
We talked about how some of the ideas
represented their mirror.
John Paul Sartre,
idea of bad faith for a very quick
refresher.
Bad faith is when we negate the radical
freedom we are afforded in our ability
to make choices.
In a sense,
we choose not to choose after she
realizes she's no different than God.
I'm my father.
Beth has an identity crisis to head.
I'm out of excuses to not be who I am.
So who am I?
What do I do?
So how do to Sanchez is cursed with
intelligence,
find meaning and an uncaring world.
Am I evil?
Worse?
You're smart when you know nothing
matters.
The Universe is yours and I've never met
a universe that was into it.
Rick's conversation reflects on some
upstarts points for sorry.
The whole problem of our existence
starts with the fact that there is no
inherent meaning and departing from
Sarta bit.
Any attempt to draw meaning from the
universe will be met with cosmic
indifference.
You know,
smart people get a chance to climb on
top,
take reality for a ride,
but it'll never stop trying to throw you
and eventually it will.
There's no other way off for rick.
Those smart enough get to take reality
for a ride before they too are
inevitably thrown off.
Or in other words,
they can indulge in whatever they
desire,
but when reality catches up with them,
well,
we've seen it before with rick best
feels trapped by her family and her
arguably ironic attachment to abc,
to bachelor's.
She readily denies her own freedom and
thus the choices available to her with
the facts of her existence can't do
that.
The kids,
jerry my job and as much as I hate to
admit it,
ABC's the Bachelor Rick Solution isn't
to free her necessarily,
but to give her a choice can make a
clone of you a perfect instance of view
with all your memories and exact copy in
every way and 11,
provide for the kids.
Do your job and consume broadcast
network reality TV on the same allegedly
ironic level as you.
You could be gone a day,
a week or the rest of your life with
zero consequences.
The moment you decided to come back,
I flipped a switch and the clumps job is
done.
It feels no pain,
regrets nothing,
and has zero chance of going blade
runner.
The important thing here is rick doesn't
argue that she should do this,
but says then stay and luxuriate in a
life you can finally know you've chosen
my secret bonuses,
that no matter what you choose,
you're finally going to chill the fuck
out.
In other words,
it's not whether she takes rick up on
the clone or not,
but the fact that she makes a choice
that matters.
The prospect of the clone confronts Beth
with her absolute freedom and just by
putting her in this crossroads,
rick is prompting her to choose her
identity.
So no matter what she chooses,
the choice brings resolved or her
identity crisis.
So maybe Rick has learned something from
Dr Wong afterall.
We can split hairs on reddit forums for
hours on whether or not Beth decided to
take rick's offer,
but it doesn't really matter whether or
not Beth abandoned her family.
It's the fact that she chose that will
ultimately help her find meaning.
So what about evil?
Jerry?
He claims he is an evil but just a
tower.
Meanwhile,
rick tells Beth,
she's not evil,
just smart,
but are we to believe rick or is this
for intelligence used to justify
sickness?
To quote Dr Wall after all,
Rick built a magical play place for his
sociopathic child just to avoid dealing
with her inherited problems.
To hear us address these questions and
more checkout are rick and Morty podcast
launch or breaking down every episode of
this season of Rick and morty.
So click on the link in the description
to get your squash on.
Thanks for watching everybody piece.