A wise crack,
live action.
Jared here these days,
social media means everything we do ends
up on permanent record.
Just being on the Internet is a
minefield and there's no survival guide
for handling.
We're not the only ones worrying about
it either.
As the newest episode of Southpark
tackles these ideas head on.
So let's get into this quick take on
season 21 episode three holiday special.
And as always,
spoilers ahead if you've been listening
to our ourself park podcast,
respect our authortalk,
you know that we've been fascinated by
the fact that this season has been more
focused on people's reaction to world
events rather than the events
themselves.
This has never been more clear than in
this past episode.
Holiday Special Randy's quest for social
justice hits a lot of ideas right on the
nose,
but it also raises some really
interesting questions.
First,
a quick recap.
Randy caught up and yet a nother wave of
activism gets Columbus State canceled,
which means no more day off school,
but that's still not enough for south
park's most vocal father.
He sets off to tear down a statue of
Columbus,
takes a crap and Columbus circle and
berate the residents of Columbus,
Ohio.
You're an intolerant pig.
Oh,
you're not.
You just choose to live in a city named
for ethnic cleansing is activism keeps
escalating until the kids discover a
treasure trove of instagram.
Pictures depicting randy in Columbus
play.
After that,
randy goes to great lengths,
including falsifying a DNA test in the
randy way possible to inoculate himself
against criticism by presenting himself
as a native American,
I.
E.
A descendant of Columbus.
These victims.
In the end,
randy finds out that he's just an
average white dude of European descent,
but with more than average amount of
neanderthal DNA,
a fact he spins into his own story of
victim hood.
The earth wasn't big enough for the
Andrew.
Thoughts to your ancestors.
Just got rid of them up after all those
brutal homo sapiens for race
neanderthals from the face of the earth.
So what does Randy's quest tell us about
the world we live in?
Well more than you might think and to
explain why we're turning to something
that we talked about in one of our
walking dead videos.
The pen off the con,
the panopticon is an idea originally
created by philosopher Jeremy Bentham.
It's a prison where a single guard in a
tower can watch all the inmates at once.
The prisoners can't tell if they're
being watched,
so they have to always be on their best
behavior.
But postmodern theorists,
Michel Foucault,
thought it was a perfect metaphor for
how society controls that citizens,
because we never know when our actions
might result in punishment.
We try our best to follow the rules,
which means we'd become controlled by
those rules even when no one enforces
them.
We even internalize those rules and
systems,
so we don't know if we're acting because
of our beliefs or because of that
systemic control and fear of punishment.
Unfortunately for Randy,
social media has become a kind of real
life panopticon don't post that.
Everything we do exist on the Internet
for forever and because of that,
we all have to be careful with what we
do and what we say online.
Randy feels this in a very real way.
When the kids discover his prior
predilection for Columbus because he's
always being watched,
randy has internalized his fear of
punishment and his desire to live up to
social ideals as a means of creating
social capital.
You guys found those pictures online.
It's only a matter of time before
everyone else does.
People won't care about what I do now.
They'll just see me as a thoughtless
indigenous son of a bitch.
In other words,
as a perpetual band wagoner,
randy needs to be a guy who protest
Columbus because that's what he thinks
society wants from him,
but with the advent of the Internet,
he's constantly terrified of what his
peers might uncover about his past.
Once the points Sharon,
soon they're going to become an
afternoon.
With social media,
our culture is evolving faster than
ever,
but it's also becoming or judgmental
mistakes made in the past are looked at
through the lens of the present.
Just because he's suddenly not cool now
doesn't mean I'm going to be the scape
goat.
This goes for both Columbus who
definitely did horrible things and
randy,
who's just kind of an idiot.
It's only now when everyone's being so
indigenous to me that I realized how
indigenous I've been acting all along.
Randy tries to explain that he's changed
that what he did in the past shouldn't
matter.
Look,
I was younger,
we were all young.
There was another time you have to
understand it was 2013 two bad for
randy.
There's no codified statue of
limitations on bad behavior.
Randy gets caught acting in the past
with ways not entirely kosher with the
present.
He can't be an advocate for a cause.
If he's seen as disingenuous and sends,
Randy defines himself by his project of
the week.
He can't afford to let that happen and
because social media judges all action,
we often fetishize purity when it comes
to social issues.
Yeah.
How I'm from New York,
I drive around a big circle that
celebrates a guy who murdered native
Americans.
Luckily for Randy,
he stumbles across the commercial for
appears to be a perfect solution.
DNA in me.
Wouldn't you like to know the story of
you?
What makes you you?
The DNA testing program lets people
claim affinity with marginalized groups.
I'm on cell part,
northern Asian and even some Kurdish.
I'm a victim of oppression.
Even if they aren't apparently a part of
them DNA and be showed I was 8% Navajo,
nobody making fun of me.
Now are my people who are victims.
The ability to claim victim hood enables
people to stake out a moral high ground
and make themselves immune from
criticism.
Are you in health?
Yes,
I'm in.
Now the irony of this is a course that
most people who need a DNA test to find
out if they're victims of oppression
probably are not oppressed.
I'm 13% victim.
I'm 21% victim to protect himself from
potential fallout.
Randy pays a native American to make out
with him in order to guarantee he'll end
up with the DNA of an indigenous person.
In doing this,
randy demonstrates and indifference
toward the feelings of the native
American man who ends up falling in love
with him.
I have never felt so alive and tone and
even managers to recreate the misdeeds
of Columbus all over again.
You get off my land,
you'll pay.
This all adds up to show that randy's
political aspirations are ultimately
selfish.
He's so desperate to claim victim hood
and so utterly ill informed about pretty
much everything that he leans on his
2.8%
neanderthal DNA.
They claim that his people were erased
from history.
Yeah,
sure.
Everyone gang up on the neanderthal
visited.
Funny again,
Randy's bizarre behavior raises
something important.
How do we decide when people can claim
victim hood?
That's not to minimize the suffering of
anyone,
but how do we distinguish between people
who are legitimately effected by a
legacy of oppression and this guy,
I used to get in trouble for always
using the n word,
but with DNA and me,
I found out that I'm 2.1%
black morning Steve,
stop.
Where's the line?
How close do you need to be on the
family tree for oppression to be passed
down?
Certainly a thousand years is too much,
but what about a hundred years or 50
years?
Even five.
It's a complicated debate,
but we know exactly what randy thinks
even tens of thousands of years is fair
game.
All these ideas add up to one compelling
20 minute critique of how we approach
politics in the age of social media.
Questions of how we deal with our public
lives being saved online,
how we treat past mistakes and how we
understand victimhood in our hyper aware
era are ones that we need to answer and
South Park knows that until we resolve
all of that,
there'll be a whole lot of misguided
randy's running around and causing
chaos.
That's what the show is ultimately
saying.
We need to figure out how we talk to
each other about history and complicated
ideas of culture or else we'll just be
crossing wires,
making messes and in public places.
The 21st season of south park wants us
to think how we handle an increasingly
complicated world that demands faster
and less nuanced reactions.
You have to Overdo it in today's
society,
Stan,
you can't be nuanced and subtle anymore
else.
Critics go,
wow,
what was the point of that?
The show doesn't have answers though and
neither do we,
but the first step is asking questions.
If you want to hear these questions
explored further,
check out our south park podcast.
Respect darth Dorota,
exploring every new episode of the show.
You can find links to the podcast in the
description below,
and you can subscribe by searching for
South Park wisecrack wherever you get
your podcasts.
Thanks for watching guys.
Peace.