One of the things that's happened in
business,
I think,
is that to the pursuit of shareholder
value,
we've lost raison d'etre,
Blair shepherd,
the Fuqua School of business,
Duke University.
If you get your resume dettra right,
it's not in conflict with making money,
it just,
it just frames how you do it right,
so that you do it in a way which is,
is more likely to sustain itself over
time and more likely to contribute to
society and larger sense.
Now it turns out you fail fast when
you've lost your resin data.
So Arthur Anderson,
right the year before Arthur Anderson
was put out of business.
It was the number one company for most
business schools in the world.
Students wanting to go there.
Why?
Because they made a lot of money.
They were really professionally while
developed.
It was a spectacular firm to work for,
but they forgot their resident Natura,
which was to ensure fairness,
honesty in the marketplace,
right?
Was to make sure that the numbers that
were produced were numbers we could
believe as soon as they forgot that they
failed overnight.
Enron failed overnight.
Um,
financial services firms fail overnight.
Why?
Because whole bunch of reasons didn't
have the right risk controls in place.
They,
uh,
they forgot that,
that their brand matter,
they forgot that the franchise manner,
but at one level you could look at it
and say they forgot the resin data.
Right?
And,
and so all I'm saying when I sort of say
there's a moral side of business is
something that's straightforward,
which is remember why you're in business
and predicate every decision you make on
that as well as whether you're gonna
make money and it turns out if you do
those two things together,
you will sustainably make money.
Forget the one you'll go out of business
overnight.
Forget the other,
you go to business because you won't
have the cash to support the business
right now.
What they need to do is fix what's
broken and invent the future,
right?
But as they come out of it,
the question of what's the mental model
you should have for how you manage the
success?
There is no question that what you need
to do is innovate and call at the same
time always what occurs,
unfortunately,
as,
as we get wealthy,
we forget to call.
And so what has to happen then as you
call in the worst of times,
which means layoffs because if you call
in good times,
you can actually repurpose physical
plant,
you can give people,
you can train people to put them in new
jobs.
So if you,
if you do it when you're wealthy,
you can actually absorb the consequences
of calling,
but if you wait to bed to do your
calling,
you're actually just gonna devastate
both yourself as a firm in your employee
base and your customer base.
And so I think the issue is be
disciplined at the same time you're
being creative,
right?
Um,
and,
and if he can be discipline at the same
time you're being creative,
you will prepare yourself for the next
downturn because you'll be trim right
where others won't be.
And,
uh,
and you'll just,
you'll just survive better through a
difficult time.