Talking to the general public around the
country is that most people don't have a
very high level of scientific literacy.
People seem to be afraid of science and
certainly people seem to be afraid of
mathematics.
And I think that's such a shame because
I don't think it's as hard as people
seem to think it is.
Um,
you know,
people have this idea that if you're not
brilliant like Einstein,
you can't be a scientist.
And that's just a myth.
I mean,
he was the one out of a million
scientists,
but there were 999,999
other scientists who are not as
brilliant but to just do great science
as well.
And so a lot of the work that I do is to
try to dispel these myths about science
being on Arcane Hartfield and math being
in comprehensible.
I just said,
you know what,
we need to know math to be a good
scientist,
but math is a language and we need to
learn the language because that's the
language of science.
And you know,
if I go to Sweden or Ethiopia,
I can't speak that language.
And that doesn't mean I can't live in
that country and function.
I need to learn the language.
It's the same with science and math.
You need to learn the language first and
then you can work in those fields.
But it's not mysterious and arcane.
It's a way of looking at the world in a
way of exploring the world and trying to
make sense of the world.
So I,
I really,
uh,
I,
it disappoints me that people are so
frightened of science and frightened the
math.
I think the only way we'll have a sea
change and people's appreciation of
science,
technology,
engineering,
math is through a broad effort,
partially part of the government.
Partially the work of scientists like me
who communicate to the public,
partially the parents of young kids not
propagating myths about science is hard.
And,
Oh,
I never did well in math.
You know,
you don't need to do that.
Yeah.
It's got to be a joint effort on
everybody's part.
People need to realize that the world is
changing.
It's a very different world than it was
2030 years ago.
And we have to be aware of that as a
culture,
as a society,
and recognize that the rest of the world
is moving on and moving on pretty
quickly.
And if we want to maintain the level of
comfort in our culture and society that
we've become accustomed to,
we have to really get in there and we
have to educate our kids and bring them
up to speed with commensurate with
what's going on in the other countries.
And I worry that that's not right.