Well,
my main job is twice a year to cover the
collections each season,
the fall and spring season,
so we've just had the New York shows
this fall for spring clothing that will
be in the stores for spring 2009.
This weekend I will leave to go to Milan
and I will spend a week.
They're looking at the clothes from the
Italian designers and then that will be
followed by a little weakened
adventists,
which would be lovely and then onto a,
which is a break and then onto Paris for
a week of shows there.
So those are the two main large blocks
of time where I'm literally sitting in
what the fashion engine,
what I would consider to be,
what the world would consider trade
shows and they're the fashions fashion
shows that are called the collections
for ready to wear those clothes that you
will see at various department stores
and boutiques all around the country and
all around the world as well as online.
That is followed by then a period where
I come back from the fashion collections
and make some pretty strong decisions on
what trends I like.
What I've seen,
um,
how I've amassed all this large grouping
of plethora of clothes that are kind of
bombarded me and everyone for about a
month,
um,
make sense of it all and group them into
stories,
into themes and the things that I think
will be relevant for my publication and
for things that I think will be fun to
photograph and shoot.
And from there I developed the idea,
think about what kind of imagery I'd
like those ideas to be and think about
the photography,
the models,
and how I'm going to actually really
produce that idea.
So it becomes an eight page,
10 page story in the spring issue of New
York magazine.