This video is sponsored by squarespace.
Whether you need a domain,
website or online store,
make it with squarespace.
Hey,
wise crack.
Jared here.
For those of you following ourself,
park podcast,
respect or authortalk.
You know,
we've been reflecting on how this season
is focused more on people's reaction to
our modern cultural cluster rather than
the actual events themselves.
Well,
this week the show commented on people's
reaction to something very close to our
hearts.
South Park itself.
It makes me feel old saying this,
but many of you may not remember a
little movie called South Park,
bigger,
longer,
and uncut because it's almost 20 years
old.
This episode artfully echoes the movie,
but this time things are a little
different.
Is southpark showing signs of a moral
crisis?
Well,
let's find out for those of you who
aren't caught up on this season,
kyle falls for carbons,
girlfriend,
Heidi.
But after a brief flirtation,
Heidi cakes,
kyle to the curb,
returns to Cartman sweaty,
stubby,
armed embrace,
it starts to match her bloated bow right
down to his trademark.
Assholery Jag,
a special needs science fair.
No thanks.
Let's start the discussion with Heidi
and Hartman brawling in the hallway
while goes to break up the fight and of
course everyone hates that he ruined the
fun.
Shut up,
Kai.
You sound like your mom.
From that point on,
kyle is the butt of a thousand jokes and
tell.
He thinks he's figured out what's caused
such a culture of meanness at school.
His former favorite show,
terrence and fill up those two Canadians
have kept on farting into old age and
have even tooted their way into a brand
new netflix original series.
The new show is a hit,
but kyle hates it because having been a
metaphorically farted on in school,
he finds himself sympathizing with the
people getting farted on in the show for
the first time.
I feel kind of bad for the person being
farted on rather than letting those
loose bowel loonies continue poisoning
the hearts and minds of children.
Heile takes a stand.
You're organizes an activist group
called millennials against Canada.
His protest leads him to shutting down
the show and eventually it goes all the
way to the president.
Garrison tells kyle to stop the protest,
but he won't and kyle eventually gets
garrison literally turned on drew's.
I've got a little chubb by the idea of
Nuking Canada.
Now with that plot.
Sounds familiar.
Congratulations.
You like us,
have watched a lot of south park.
Turns out those jokes about kyle being
like his mom were just empty insults.
Kyle's protest mirrors the behavior of
his mother in south park bigger,
long for an uncut,
just as Sheila created mothers against
Candida to protest the obscenity of the
terrance and Philip movie.
Hile has created millennials against
Canada to protest terrence and Phillips
and new Netflix show.
The parallels are more than just
conceptual.
They lift entire scenes from the movie.
We can't believe that a movie was some
foul language would piss you off summer
please.
Can I finish?
Okay,
I bet that's how you know.
How can I bet?
Because you were all waste on it
yourself.
Please.
Can I finish?
All right.
I finished
on one level.
This is south way of playfully comparing
millennial hostility toward offensive
media to the parents of the 90s who
blamed issues like drug use and
columbine on everything from heavy metal
to south park.
But there's something else going on
here.
The South Park movie features a movie
within a movie,
terrorists and Philip asses a fire.
It was a metal stand in for the South
Park movie itself.
Just as Kyle and company,
we're witnessing a cruder r rated
version of an already obscene TV show.
We the audience were similarly consuming
a cruder r rated version of an already
obscene TV show while parents were
protesting southpark in real life.
Parents in the movie protested terrence
and Philip.
The Canadian duo has always been a riff
on how people who've never watched south
park characterize the show is nothing
but Barton poop jokes.
The thinking is South Park is far from
terrance and fill up these days.
South Park has gotten increasingly
topical and specific over the years with
the occasional returned to their roots.
Alexa,
add big hairy baths.
Do My shopping list.
Okay.
I've added big hairy balls to your
shopping list.
That means that old tariffs and Philip,
despite sharing initials with South Park
Creator Trey Parker,
aren't a perfect parallel to the show
itself,
but the idea that both shows are objects
of both love and scorn in their
respective universes holds up.
So with carrots and Philip acids have
higher.
Matt and Trey were asking us to go along
with them as they wonder about their
place in the cultural landscape where
they to blame back then,
their answer was a resounding no.
Now,
in the turbulent times of 2017 they're
doing it again,
but this time the answer up to whether
or not they're implicated in society's
ills is not so clear.
Once Kyle realizes that the person
getting farted on has feelings too,
he finds the show cruel and offensive.
On one hand,
Kyle's growing distance from terrance
and Philip is a commentary on how
millennials new found awareness has
rendered old school south park humor no
longer relevant,
which leaves Matt and Trey Feeling as
old as terrorists and Philip look,
on the other hand,
this is the beginning of the show's
attempt at self evaluation.
Heile takes his concern to the new vice
principal,
strong woman.
There's a culture at the school and they
didn't break his meanness and I believe
now it comes from a Canadian TV show.
All the boys watch it.
I did too.
We all laugh while they fart innocent
people's heads.
The thing is,
I never felt for the person being farted
on until now.
There's no shortage of things,
pieces that suggests that south park may
have fostered this culture of meanness,
but strong woman disagrees.
You want to blame farts?
That seems kind of ridiculous,
doesn't it?
I mean,
it's a slippery slope when we start
pointing the finger for our own
shortcomings.
She's making a very salient point here,
one that we can dig deeper into by
again,
returning to bigger,
longer and uncut as the war with Canada
rages.
Kyle runs into his mother.
She says it was all for him,
but kyle doesn't see it that way.
I,
I'm doing very important
things,
but you never took the time to talk to
me.
Whenever I get in trouble,
you'll go up and blame everybody else.
But I'm the one to blame here with me.
Sheila has started an entire wars that
she could avoid confronting the fact
that she was simply a bad parent who
didn't pay attention to what her child
needed,
just like his mom.
Kyle brings about horrible things,
not because of his principles,
but because of his self absorbed
motivations.
What do you like what I want to world?
We've mapped,
it doesn't come at someone else's
expense where people can live freely
without fear.
Think farted on.
I want a world we want ridiculed for
Teigen out a world where nice girl that
I liked is it turned into another Eric,
you're kyle admits the real reason for
his actions,
the shortcomings he was trying to hide.
So if Sheila was protesting the terrans
and Philip movie to cover her own
failings as a parent,
and Kyle is doing it to hide his
feelings of having lost Heidi to
Cartman,
what does that say about South Park?
The show since kyle is so often the
voice of the show,
I've been thinking,
how did shamelessness get to this?
Did it start with that people on
scooters or did the bar get lowered way
before that?
And then I started thinking maybe it was
us,
I don't know,
but maybe somehow we lower the bar a
long time ago and now we're all sitting
here in this.
Think of it all.
Well maybe it's this,
maybe kyle sadness at losing Heidi who
has basically turned into a female
version of cartman antisemitism in all
mirrors,
Matt and trey sadness at creating a show
that may have spawned a few real life
Cartman's they've always prided
themselves on making fun of everyone
equally,
but now do they just come off like out
of touch old people farting on
minorities?
Yeah.
Now just to be clear,
I love South Park and hate censorship.
Put this critical look in the mirror
also reflects the show's identity crisis
after a failed attempt at full on
satirical serialization.
We're now in the midst of a season full
of ups and downs and a mix of tones.
The episodes range from terrance and
Philip's style fart jokes to failed
political satires two successful ones
and episodes that don't make a lot of
sense.
Should they be a political show?
Don't even want to,
can he still be funny if people are now
concerned that people are farting on
half feelings,
are we truly in a post funny era of
satire knowing that Matt and Trey find a
lot of 2017 to be miserable just like
the rest of us.
It's interesting that unlike bigger,
longer and uncut they aren't giving
themselves a free pass.
Now we don't know how that evaluation is
going to play out,
but the episode ends on a real
cliffhanger.
What comes after the bombs land on
Canada?
Well we'll just have to twiddle our
fingers until the season finale.
So what do you think wise crack.
Do you think the show is getting Maudlin
in its old age looking back on its past
like a bleary-eyed former football state
champion or do Matt and Trey just not
give it?
Maybe we're overthinking it either way.
Let us know what you think and as always
peace.
Thanks for watching wise crack.
One thing you can never overthink is
your website.
Whether you're hoping to show off your
art or start a new business.
Look no further,
Ben squarespace.
You can start your free trial today and
get 10% off your first purchase when you
use the offer code quick takes
squarespace makes it easy to get an
exciting professional looking website in
minutes with their designer templates
and an all in one platform.
You don't need to know a thing about
coding to create something beautiful.
So head to squarespace.com
for a free trial and when you're ready
to launch your site,
go to squarespace.com/quick
takes and use the offer code quick takes
to save 10% off your first purchase of a
website or domain.
Thanks to squarespace for sponsoring
this video.
Well,
that's all for me.
Don't forget to subscribe if you haven't
already and ring that bell.
Catch you all next time.
Peace.