This video is sponsored by him.
Your go to resource for all things.
Men's health checkout for Hims Dot com
slash wise,
crack to find affordable medical grade
products,
treat hair loss,
acne Ed and other fun stuff.
Yeah,
a wise crack.
Disembody.
Jared again here to ask you a question.
Why are a repetitive Sitcom intro and an
Ode to British Children's television?
Two of the most disturbing things on
youtube besides the obvious,
is there a reason that this or this is
more unsettling than say a dude who
murders you in your dreams instead of
cheap jump scares.
Too many cooks and don't hug me.
I'm scared into a kind of existential
horror,
but two different ends.
So if you've ever pondered the eternal
question of whether you'd rather be
stuck in a song that never ends or an
acid induced muppet nightmare,
then this is the video for you.
Welcome this wise crack condition on too
many cooks versus don't hug me.
I'm scared.
And I guess spoilers ahead.
For those of you who don't know,
here's a quick recap.
Too many cooks begins like the opening
credits of most 80 sitcoms,
like full house,
different strokes or my two dads,
and then just keeps going.
As the jingle repeats,
the opening credits mutate and begin to
resemble things ranging from Gi Joe to
Battlestar Galactica and it keeps going
and going and going,
and a serial killer shows up and look.
If you haven't seen it,
go watch it.
It's so good.
Don't hug me.
I'm scared as a six episode web series
that resembles British children's
television shows like the teletubbies,
but each episode quickly descends into
terrifying psychological torture,
complete with cultish fees.
This embezzlement and uncomfortable
amounts of raw meat,
although they don't seem terribly
similar,
both utilize a special nightmare sauce
that really gets under our skin that
sauce king with nostalgia in too many
cooks.
The aesthetic of the comforting TV
families of the eighties and nineties
are quite literally murdered while in.
Don't hug me,
I'm scared.
Our childhood mentors are inverted into
orwellian despots,
but what makes this worse than say,
watching nightmare.
On Elm Street,
you see nostalgia offers three
psychological benefits.
It acts as a repository for positive
feelings,
a contributor to self esteem,
and as a method of social connectivity
because who hasn't read all 52 ways,
you know you're a nineties kid,
since nostalgia makes us feel so good,
disrupting it can really mess with your
head according to one school of thought
called terror management theory,
nostalgia can be a handy way to combat
the terror of our mortal existence,
no longer able to take comfort in God or
an afterlife.
Our secular age has put more emphasis on
other kinds of immortality,
like having kids,
making your mark on the world,
having a national identity or having
your Dick cast and plaster.
This is where nostalgia comes in.
At 2006,
study found nostalgia helps to provide
meaning in our lives by allowing us to
relive idealized memories of our past in
order to feel better about the future,
but unlike some media that shamelessly
parrots nostalgia to give us the warm
and fuzzies.
Too many cooks and don't hug me.
I'm scared.
Using this to log references to draw us
in and then give us a good old fashioned
mind rather than dressing up like
ghostbusters.
Too many cooks and don't hug me.
I'm scared over.
Identify with these references to the
point of absurdity.
They use the sappy intro music.
Too many cooks dated retro graphics and
simple puppets with bright colors to
pull you into a nostalgic state and then
under my so when everything goes to
hell,
they're literally ruining your childhood
and not like the last jet I did.
The nostalgic fuel,
good memories that pacify you on your
meaningless trudge toward death are now
being murdered both metaphorically and
literally,
but while both these properties utilize
this subversion of nostalgia,
it's how and why they subverted that
sets them apart to understand what sets
too many cooks apart from.
Don't hug me,
I'm scared.
We need to look at the Early Twentieth
Century Theater Practitioner,
Bertolt Brecht,
Brecht rejected realism and theater.
Arguing that because film was so much
better at it,
why even bother theater doesn't have the
endless takes multiple locations,
camera angles,
and perfectly mixed audio that puts you
in the moment the way cinema does.
Theater requires a lot of suspension of
disbelief and audience imagination,
so breck developed what he called epic
theater.
Epic theater sought to disrupt the
audience performer relationship where
traditional drama expected an audience
to be sad when the protagonist is sad,
frightened when he or she is frightened
and so on.
Brecht wanted an audience to view the
performance more critically and
dispassionately.
To do that,
he used a technique called distantiation
or the alienation effect.
For instance,
he would show the workings of their
performance on stage to reveal its
falseness in his play,
mother courage and her children.
Costume changes happen on stage.
Props and scenery are brought on and off
during dialog and placards are held up
to explain the action.
Also,
the audience can't escape the awareness
that they were watching a play and thus
are able to judge the characters more
critically.
Old birdie basically patented our
culture's favorite thing,
breaking the fourth wall like Brecht.
Too many cooks draws our attention to
its own falseness.
Characters run between sets that are
stocked by their Chiron's.
The audio and video are disrupted and
whatever.
This is another characteristic.
Too many cooks shares with Brecht is
repetition.
In almost every Brecht play,
there is a form of repeated dance
movement,
gesture or phrase,
even in the music.
Consider the Alabama sauce,
which you might recognize.
It's an awesome song by the doors.
Well,
Brecht wrote the lyrics.
Rhythm and instrumentation are highly
repetitive and the harmony uses a lot of
dissonance to achieve the general
feeling of creepiness on bestows upon
the listener,
and if you two are creeped out by the
song,
then congrats,
Brex alienation effect work.
The more you repeat something,
the more likely you are to look at or to
listen to it critically.
Seeing it a different way like have you
ever repeated a word until it sounds
like gibberish?
Just like saying,
pigeon pigeon,
pigeon,
pigeon for a minute straight,
we'll make the word pigeon sound
extremely weird.
Hearing the phrase,
too many cooks over and over throughout
and 11 minute video will remove any and
all meaning the phrase too many cooks
ever had,
but were Brecht would often use this
distancing effect to explain an
injustice or challenge or prejudice.
Too many cooks has a much more
nihilistic view of the whole thing.
Every component of popular entertainment
is distance and robbed of meaning.
For instance,
the repetitiveness of the phrase,
too many cooks spoil the broth seems to
parallel the repetition of other Sitcom
catchphrases like,
hey,
even as more and more unsettling
elements are introduced,
the repetition renders it all
meaningless and uses this opportunity to
show how interchangeable at all is as
our characters get murdered are greasy.
Serial killer begins to inhabit the
generic and interchangeable tropes and
aesthetics of television.
By deconstructing these old shows in
this graphic way too many cooks up ends.
Any attempt at terror management through
our nostalgic love of he-man married
with children or buck rogers by
revealing them to be empty,
easily replicated junk all for a joke
and a great one at that.
Don't hug me,
I'm scared.
Use this a lot of these same techniques
of distantiation to like breaking the
fourth wall by rotating a digital image
of their set and repeating camera moves
and dialogue over and over.
I wonder what will happen,
but
don't hug me.
I'm scared.
Has more in common with a different type
of pop culture deconstruction.
Whereas too many cooks is deconstruction
for its own sake.
Don't hug me.
Subverts nostalgia too.
Not only criticized children's
television,
but to offer a way forward,
but how exactly.
Well,
first we need to talk about something
that sounds really boring.
The British television act of 1954,
which allowed commercial television
networks to compete with the publicly
owned BBC.
Following the television act,
a new commercial channel called
Independent Television was created in
1955.
A fact not lost on.
Don't hug me.
I'm scared in the Erie fundraising
campaign.
Trailers,
a violent bear monster demands money
from the audience using a ransom video
conspicuously timestamp as 1955.
With this in mind,
the reason for deconstructing children's
television becomes a bit clearer.
Subtle clues,
take jabs at the very idea of children's
television for profit or even profit in
general throughout it's six episodes.
The three main characters,
red guy,
duck and yellow guy are terrorized by
different guest teachers,
like a notebook that explains
creativity.
What's your favorite ice is being
creative,
a clock that explains time.
Time is a tool you can put on the wall
or wherever it on your wrist.
The past is far behind us.
The future doesn't exist.
Nap Ap,
that explains love for some reason.
Together we get understanding
on the surface.
This seems like any episode of Barney or
whatever kids watch these days,
but as the fourth wall starts to
dissolve,
everything gets weird.
Herder is trippy and even profound.
One could argue that this bat,
it insanity and the unexpected guys have
a kids show is been to expose the
authoritarian and consumerists messages
using a method known as culture jamming
culture.
Jamming is a tactic used by anti
consumer as groups to subvert the
dominant narrative and iconography of
our era,
mainstream media advertisements and so
on.
This means revealing the message that is
quote,
really behind popular media and
advertising and injecting their own
meaning to serve their agenda.
I think of the coke billboard that says
love,
but someone spray painted profit
underneath it,
or a Mcdonald's billboard modified to
read.
I'm loving diabetes or anything banks
he's ever done or vermin supreme,
a man who wears a boot on his head and
wants to mandate brushing your teeth by
law all to mark our political process.
This election year,
vote early,
vote often.
I remember a vote for me,
vermin supreme.
It was about completely thrown away.
This method of deconstructing a well
known institution like children's
television by jamming it with another
more graphic image highlights the
disparity between wholesome edutainment
for kids and the excesses of profit
driven media that the television act
introduced throughout the series.
The teachers in every episode explain
what something is or means,
but start to suggest better ways of
doing things.
Could you're not thinking creatively
correct.
The main characters.
It's not by name.
If you can do it.
Oh,
they did,
and punish them if they do or say what
the teachers see as the wrong thing.
Wanting to be creative.
Don't use green.
That's not a creative color.
One.
Eat fancy foods.
Sorry.
They'll clog up your body.
Ten feet.
Foods are very rude.
I must leave through the cat flap.
While these choices of excluding green
or choosing a computer over a globe to
learn may seem inane and meaningless at
first,
they slowly begin to reveal what is at
stake.
These saccharin notion of a child's TV
mentor is jammed to reveal the dangers
of letting media teacher child in the
harsh realities of the commercial age
and the touch of authoritarianism that
is inherent to it all attempts to
question their teachers are always shut
down.
It doesn't make sense.
Let me just.
A construct of human perception and
illusion created by.
Furthermore,
the danger of empty platitudes about
love devolve into a cult.
His name is
age.
They can't get loud.
Optimism about technology is juxtaposed
with some clockwork orange in the
computer episode.
What you do with a computer seems to be
dancing graphs and more importantly,
style as in,
you know,
buying clothes.
Wow.
The last few episodes even seemed to
drop hints that this is all a plan to
sell oats to kids.
Our computer teacher asks the puppets a
series of questions like it's for a
focus group and on the question of what
do you like to eat?
Our beloved computer shows us another
picture of oats.
In the next episode,
Our teacher tells us the merits of plain
foods and more oats are seen next to the
healthy juice.
This gives.
Don't hug me.
I'm scared.
A much more moral message than too many
cooks while too many cooks literally
self destructs the message of,
don't hug me.
I'm scared.
Instead,
alternate methods of childhood
education.
Try managing your terror with that.
Just like almost everything else in pop
culture right now.
Too many cooks and don't hug me.
I'm scared.
Recognize how we use nostalgia as a
safety blanket and then soak that
blanket in blood and rip a few holes in,
but while too many cooks says that's
because this kind of nostalgic is a lie
and ultimately useless.
Don't hug me.
I'm scared.
Ruins our childhood because it loves us.
It wants you to challenge the lessons
you've learned instead of blindly
obeying that comforting kids.
Show voice.
So do me a favor.
Don't listen to these smooth voice of
video host and think for yourself.
All right,
thanks for watching a wise crack piece
and a huge thanks to hymns for
sponsoring this video.
If you're like me,
you only go to the doctor every other
decade.
In fact,
18 to 40 year old men are less likely
than any other group to visit a doctor
or a pharmacy.
Luckily Hims is your one stop solution
for potentially awkward men's health
issues.
Yeah,
I'm talking about going bald acne and
yeah,
I'm going to say it.
Penis problems,
it happens basically all the things you
try to hide on tinder,
but these conditions are as normal as
they are treatable and hymns takes your
privacy seriously through hims.
You'll get personalized recommendations
from medical grade products,
from real doctors and with the doctors.
Awesome virtual visits online.
You never have to get off the couch or
turn off your ps four.
While I've been blessed with a full head
of very thick hair,
at least for now,
you don't have to lose yours and because
hymns offers generic equivalents to name
brand prescriptions and ships direct,
you're getting major savings.
Hims is offering wisecrack viewers a
full month trial of their comprehensive
haircut up to a $67 value for just five
bucks a head do for him [inaudible] dot
com slash wise crack or click the link
below to get your discount today and
while you're checking that out,
here's an artist rendering of what I'd
look like bald.
It's not pretty thanks to hims.