This episode is brought to you by wix.
What's up guys?
Jared here and today we're talking about
these surprising headscratcher have a
season finale for South Park season 22,
the final two episodes unfulfilled and
bike parade or the first and probably
only time you'll see the show quoting
the communist manifesto,
and from their very essence,
the oppressed worker will eventually
strike back at those capitalists who
controlled the means of production.
We have nothing to lose,
but our chains so have matt stone and
Trey Parker turned against big business
like the Denisons of South Park.
Well,
let's find out in this wisecrack
addition on the finale of South Park
season 22 and obviously spoilers ahead,
but before we get started,
I want to give a quick shout out to our
sponsors over at wix.
Wix is the easiest way to create awesome
professional websites.
As I mentioned in an earlier video,
I'm trying to make some side money doing
voiceover work.
So let me show you how I created my
professional site with voice samples.
So here when to create a website for
myself and you can see they have a whole
bunch of options.
So a business now,
designer photography.
Now I want to build a portfolio and CV
and yeah,
I pretty much suck at computers.
It turns out there's already a template
for voiceover artists.
I picked a style and within minutes I
was dragging and dropping my audio files
and Bam,
done.
Now I have a site I can send to
potential clients and it looks good.
So if you're looking to up your game
before 2019,
go to wix.com/wise
crack or click the link in the
description to start making your free
website today and now back to the show.
All right guys.
First,
a quick recap in unfulfilled and Amazon
fulfillment center comes to town where a
workplace accident crushes.
A guy named Josh and surviving organs
are crammed in a box.
The box opens.
I spill out and guide his box.
Oregon's agitate for working class
rebellion,
causing Amazon's employees to go on
strike.
Meanwhile,
the kids want to flex at the bike parade
to get girls,
but can't deck out their bikes without
their Amazon packages.
Then in bike parade mall workers tried
to break the strike and anyone willing
to help Jeff Bezos gets their orders
fulfilled.
Once Kenny's newfound socialist beliefs
ruined their plans for the parade.
Yeah,
I can do the bike.
Why not?
Commodity fetishism the boys try to get
it canceled.
Meanwhile,
Randy struggling.
We'd business gets a boost from everyone
jones for their Amazon packages stoned
in content.
The citizens of South Park realized
they'd rather keep their tegrity than
suck [inaudible] to figure out what Matt
and Trey are saying about the economy.
We have to start with this intro montage
of the Amazon fulfillment center.
You load 16 tons a day,
older and deeper in debt.
The song playing 16 tons has a million
covers,
but the original was written by Merle
Travis about the life of coal miners in
Kentucky.
The song highlights the troubles of
living in company hounds.
A common practice that faded out in the
middle of the 20th century.
Company towns were places where a single
employer dominated economic life,
sometimes companies would open a factory
and literally build the housing schools
and hospitals for its employees,
but more importantly,
companies would pay their employees with
their own version of vbox bucks that
were only redeemable at company owned
businesses.
What resulted was functionally slavery
with extra steps workers could never
move because all their savings were
useless outside of the company store dot
or don't check out on MCOs,
go
to the company stone and running up a
debt at the company store would further
obligate you to stay until you paid it
off.
So it South Park Calling Amazon a modern
day company town.
Sure Amazon isn't paying people in prime
box and there's no debt slavery either,
but Amazon does seem to infiltrate every
aspect of south park life.
Once you got on tap,
Amazon,
Amazon light and Amazon Ipa,
but especially in episode 10,
we see that the primary motivation for
working at Amazon is to buy your kids
more stuff from Amazon.
Mr Stacia's motivation for going back to
work is to have his orders fulfilled for
butters,
peacock bike and like the Merle Travis
Song,
your paycheck has a way of ending up
right back into the company store,
loading up forklift,
getting paper cuts from boxes,
and for what a measly paycheck.
They just barely covers our online
purchases
and while the people of south part in
theory could take their real dollars to
some other businesses to show hints at
how big business coming to town can
create eight,
not so free market.
When the boys try to find supplies to
protest the bike parade,
all the other businesses have gone
under.
When the Amazon fulfillment center open
to everything else went out of business.
A similar dynamic happens not just with
Amazon,
but Walmart were low paid employees only
had enough money to shop at Walmart.
You get a discount working here 10
percent.
That means the baguettes or even better,
ensuring the destruction of local
businesses driving more people to work
at Walmart and.
Well,
you get it.
This problem seems encapsulated by Jeff
Bezos is term consumer worker
Lauren,
between classes,
customers and workers.
At us,
all I've done is create the new class,
the consumer worker
doubling down on the same sense of
resignation that pervades the season.
People support a company they don't even
like because they feel they don't have
any choice.
I want to quit working for Amazon.
I want to join my friends and striking,
but I know that you have to have your
stuff to be happy.
This hopelessness is also a nod to the
real life bidding war to host Amazon
second headquarters.
As you probably know,
Matt stone and Trey Parker are
libertarians,
and the last two episodes seem to
further a criticism of government
involvement in the market,
specifically the way business minded
politicians get in bed with giant
corporations to create a grotesque
version of the free market.
If the workers are selling their soul to
the company,
store towns and governments are selling
their soul to Jeff Bezos is throbbing.
We had a deal.
You told me this town would be the
perfect place for one of our fulfillment
centers.
The creation of jobs holds local
governments functionally hostage to
their whims.
Perhaps you should no longer be a prime
member,
and while,
yes,
Amazon fulfillment centers are a good
example,
you could easily replace Amazon with any
sports stadium or manufacturer seeking
tax breaks that forced local governments
into a race to the bottom and deals that
leave them another day,
older and deeper in debt.
In short,
the show criticizes the imbalance of
power between companies like Amazon and
local communities and their workers.
Amazon dehumanizes the strikers when
their status is downgraded from rhyme to
Amazon.
USD.
A choice as in me and Josh does humanity
is exactly what gets him killed when
Amazon labels is death.
Human error.
So is there any escape from this
nightmare?
Well,
sort of as randy bemoans the strike
messing up his business,
customers start lining up at his door.
Hey,
are you selling weed?
Uh,
yeah.
My wife is going nuts not getting her
packages.
I told her I find her some Kush local
competition soon forces randy to
optimize convenience by delivering weed
to people's homes.
Starting an APP.
We haven't happened out and even a
membership program,
we're just making sure folks are aware.
In other words,
he becomes the Amazon over week.
So what is South Park trying to say
here?
Well,
on the one hand,
that integrity in business usually
doesn't mean going all the way back to
the gnomes episode of season two.
We see that small business can be just
as evil and exploitative as big bad
horror books.
We're just using those boys for our
benefit.
They have no idea what they're saying,
but kids are great to get people on our
side and 20 years later South Park's
message hasn't deviated much.
You know what they got?
They got these days.
You mean the things that almost killed
us on Halloween?
Yeah.
I remember.
Why do we use scooters to get directly
to the customers?
Those things that were once devoid of
tegrity are now the vehicles with which
he sells tegrity wheat and of course the
episode ends with this.
You come in giant online retailer near
you complain all you want about hotbox,
Walmart or Amazon.
They're just going to get replaced by
something equally sinister because at
the end of the day,
if I don't get my gamecube adapter for
smash brothers by Wednesday,
I swear to God,
I'm burning this to the ground.
What's interesting is that the strikers
and our Marxist in a box are casting a
pretty sympathetic light.
Sure.
Jeff Bezos has this to say about Josh.
See how the box ridiculous commercialism
in order to try and feel better about
itself,
a sentiment of resentment echoed by the
boys as they try to cancel the bike
grade to obscure their own failure.
We're never going to win the bike ride,
but if we get a canceled,
then everybody loses.
But as what the rest of the season,
the message seems to be resignation.
Strikers are encouraged to cross picket
lines to appease their materialistic
children.
Others kids on bikes,
and maybe
you won't get off your ass and work.
Dad
and Josh gets ripped open by a mob of
gift hungry kids.
Jeff Bezos,
as Josh says,
it makes too many useful things
resulting in too many useless people,
but it seems we can't resist.
You need your Amazon prime shows in your
music and your books and your things
delivered to your door like little
presents to yourself.
In true south park fashion are only
savior is a fake one,
a fake claim to authenticity in the form
of integrity that ends up just being
repackaged and sold by a huge online
retailer.
Even though it's a functional Amazon,
we're reminded
you don't want to be elite because the
elites gotten old integrity.
Even our anti consumers to send is just
a regular part of the business cycle.
It's not that integrity save south park,
but the cynical interest of randy
packets tegrity,
I got more money now because integrity,
that's because I figured out how to get
tired.
Everyone was once supposed to be a
counter.
Cultural rejection of modern life
becomes a symbol for the commodification
of dissent.
The bike parade,
which was once a pond and Jeff Bezos,
the scheme to break the strike is now
sponsored by tegrity.
We'd citywalk and Taco South Park to
seems content to bask in cynical
tegrity.
As the boys tried to cancel the bike
parade,
it becomes clear that the parade is a
metaphor for the show and its marketing
campaign.
Hashtag cancer South Park,
we demand you canceled the bike parade.
It is an added touch with progressive
day.
Everything out there is getting
canceled,
but when it comes to us,
we just can't do it.
I mean,
are we supposed to just keep going?
Just go on making total assets of
ourselves,
just that south park was promoting
itself with a half serious critique of
itself.
The show is content to continue basking
in the business of selling television
ads where they have serious critique of
consumers.
Now,
if you really want to stick it to the
man,
I recommend you try wicks.
There's no better way to discover the
true joy of an alienated labor.
Then by designing your own website,
a specter is haunting your future,
the specter of not having a website,
so go to [inaudible] dot com slash wise.
Crack to sign up today.
The only thing you have to lose is your
chains,
and as always nice.