This video is brought to you by
blackwoods.
Stick around till the end of the video
for a preview.
What's up guys?
Jared here,
as I briefly alluded to in our last
south park video,
I've been playing a lot of red dead
redemption two lately and at the risk of
sounding hyperbolic,
it's nothing less than a milestone in
the art of gaming.
Now,
I could spend the entirety of this video
geeking out about the detail,
the story of the performances,
but that's not what I want to talk about
today because surprise,
I want to talk about philosophy.
In fact,
there's one mission in the game that
builds its entire trajectory around too
philosophical ideas and not only is it
quite clever,
but it builds off the critique of early
American values that the franchise is so
famous for versus America.
You can always cut a deal.
So welcome to this test Vlog format on
red dead redemption.
Two we might do a bigger wisecrack
condition that focuses on the entirety
of the game,
but I haven't even finished it yet.
In the meantime,
I know you guys like hearing about our
process,
so consider this a little window into
how we think about things.
Let us know what you think about it.
This new format in the comments and very
insignificant spoilers ahead.
Seriously,
it just doesn't matter.
Starting early in chapter four,
you can go on a three part stranger
mission called idealism and pragmatism
for beginners.
So yeah,
you can probably see why we're breaking
down this mission.
It comically explores the basic tenants
of idealism and pragmatism,
but it's in its exploration of
pragmatism,
a uniquely American philosophy that we
get to see that classic rock star
sarcasm as they take American values
down a peg.
And the first part of the mission we're
introduced to mayor Lemieux,
the pragmatist and his assistant John
mark the idealist.
The Mayor Informs Arthur that he
recently bought a collection of classic
paintings to hang in a new museum.
He plans to open,
but turns out he's been conned.
The sleazy art dealer painted them
himself,
but that's no biggie for Limu.
The problem solver who will display them
anyway,
these are good paintings.
I can't make the difference.
And I'm French,
but an expert by the name of professor
shift occur is on his way to evaluate
the paintings and make public their
fraudulence.
So Mayor Lemieux Hires Arthur to
intimidate professor shift occur so that
he changes his professional opinion and
deems the paintings real shift occur
initially.
Resist.
Bud Arthur's fist are quite convincing.
Okay.
So what does this have to do with either
philosophy?
Well,
in this part of the mission,
we most clearly see an interesting
exploration of pragmatism originating in
the 1870s pregnant tism isn't American
philosophy primarily developed by
Charles Pierce?
William James and John Dewey pragmatists
vary in their specific philosophies,
but one tendency among them all is their
willingness to settle metaphysical and
scientific debates according to the
practical consequences of ideas.
So basically they emphasize that which
useful to advance human understanding of
the world.
More importantly,
this stands in contrast with those who
sought out universal truths with reason
allowed German idealists like a manual
con.
So on the one level we see the mayor
ever the pragmatist deciding to beat the
shit out of a man.
So long as it's useful.
And John Mark the idealist holding moral
principles as universal truths,
not unlike our boy caught fire nuts is
never right.
But there's another reading of this
scenario that perhaps incidentally
comments on how pragmatism deals with
our understanding of reality.
Pragmatists don't look towards universal
truths and stress that human ideas about
reality are likely wrong.
So because humans are fallible,
some pragmatic thinkers favor ideas that
are the most useful for a pragmatist
like John Dewey.
Scientific hypotheses are great because
they're useful.
And even if they're not 100% right,
we can fumble around with them to
acquire more scientific knowledge,
which allows us to concoct better
theories.
The same for dewey should be true of
philosophical ideas.
Rather than search for some capital t
truth,
one should instead search for an idea
that may be useful to humanity and its
advancement of knowledge.
So here we see another layer to the
joke.
The mayor hires Arthur to beat the shit
out of a guy until he admits that a fake
painting is real.
Now,
although this isn't exactly what the
pragmatist we're talking about,
they're making a blunt if reductive joke
about pragmatism.
Sure.
The paintings aren't real per se,
but the idea that they are real has its
use in the advancement of public
education and culture.
So who cares if they're fraudulent
vapor?
Going to look at those pains and love
them.
So you're helping me
as William James said in his work,
pragmatism,
a new name for some old ways of
thinking.
The true is the name for whatever proves
itself to be good in the way of belief
and good too for definite assignable
reasons.
This idea of partial truths also comes
up later.
I'm worried that he's going to open his
mouth and say things that aren't true to
those vulgar puritans at the newspaper.
Well perhaps true,
but not the whole truth.
Now I don't think anyone at rock star is
reading John Dewey and if you are,
please send me an email.
But this take on pragmatism as it's more
commonly understood by non philosophers
is in line with red dead cynical take on
the value systems that propelled the
west at the turn of the century.
Pragmatism is darkly cast as an ideology
that more or less justifies selfish,
cynical behavior.
Education is the most wonderful thing.
It'll raise us higher and higher.
Make civics and ethics lesser work of a
dirty minded pragmatists like me and the
calling of higher,
better men here,
hey,
in part two of the mission,
we see this distinction between the
dirty pragmatism of the mayor and John
Marks.
Idealism.
When the mayor hires you to once again
intimidate a man into funding the
library,
Arthur does what he does best and the
newspaper man gives in and libraries are
good things,
right?
Look at these beautiful books.
This is magnificent.
We'll bring this city back to life.
If it kills me,
I didn't probably shower,
so if it requires a little bit of nasty
business to get something done,
it's worth it,
right?
Such pragmatic justifications for pretty
gnarly shit are all over both games,
including the essential conflict of the
first game,
threatened John's family in order to get
him to do what they want,
killed the remaining members of the
gang.
In the third and final part of the
mission,
we see a final standoff between these
two ideas systems.
When John Mark Turns on the mayor for
his seeming lack of principals will
strive to improve the city's moral
backbone by any means available to us
who we are then reasoning.
Yes.
Yes,
yes.
Within my reason because it's better to
get something done than nothing at all.
Like you said,
Tony,
uh,
Tony corrupted lemieux how I long for
the luxury to have principles such as
you,
but I must actually do things.
So there you have it.
A little taste of philosophy in what is
undoubtedly a top contender for game of
the year.
So what do you guys think?
Is this exploration of pragmatism
relevant in more areas than just this
one mission?
What does know what you think and hope
you guys enjoyed this new blog format.
And as I already mentioned,
I'm super impressed with the story of
red dead too.
So if you guys were looking for more
engaging stories to listen to all your
hunting,
legendary animals are trying to find
those rare herbs.
You gotta check out blackwood.
It's a narrative podcast about our group
of friends investigating their small
towns,
urban legend,
the Blackwood bug man.
It's kind of like vhs or Blair witch
project meets stranger things with it's
found footage,
audio style.
Each episode leaves you wanting more,
so if you're interested,
you can head to [inaudible] dot fm slash
wise or find blackwood anywhere you
would get your podcast.
As always,
thanks for watching guys.
Peace.
If you still need convincing,
checkout this preview for the series.
Five years ago,
three teenagers from the small town of
Blackwood,
Connecticut started an investigation
into a local legend.
We are officially recording within
weeks.
Their names would be added to a long
list of tragedies in town.
Everything you're about to hear,
it was recorded by them.
All of it.
You can kick against his thickly scaled
body scratch at his bulging red eyes,
but you won't escape the Blackwood bug
man.
Welcome to the Blackwood podcast.