What's up guys,
jared here on the set of one of our
other projects,
so infinity war is finally out.
We saw it and wanted to try something
new,
whereas we usually dive into the themes,
ideologies,
and subtexts of these films to gain a
better appreciation for them today.
We're going to use these elements to
propose some educated predictions of
what will happen in a vendors for so
welcome to this wise crack quick take on
infinity war,
part one.
Spoilers ahead for part one,
and if we're flattering ourselves,
part two.
Also a huge things to digital sputnik
for supplying us with their gear to make
these quick takes and all of our other
shoots look pretty awesome.
They make it so easy to just throw up
some lights and shoot.
So thanks again to digital sputnik for
making lighting fun for us.
Now on with the quick take,
the central question of infinity war is
whether the value of an individual life
can be weighed against the greater good
throughout the film.
Characters are posed with the conundrum
should they sacrifice a loved one for
the greater good at the films climax
scarlet,
which attempts to kill vision for lover
in order to destroy the mind stone.
Similarly,
quill reluctantly tries to shoot
Gomorrah,
his lover only for his blast to turn
into bubbles and later thanos throws her
off the altar on for me or as a
sacrifice to earn the soul stone.
This is one of moral philosophies all
time.
Classic debates,
one that we've talked about before,
utilitarian,
consequentialism versus deontology.
To briefly summarize,
utilitarian.
Consequentialism defines actions as
ethical if they achieve a positive
outcome for them.
Most people,
no matter what one must do to achieve
those ends.
Deontology on the other hand,
is a duty based ethic that suggests that
no outcomes can justify heinous things
like murder.
I'm going to neutralize a lot of threats
before they even happen.
That's punishment usually came after the
crime,
scarlet witch,
star,
Lord,
and then I was all ultimately make their
moral decisions based on consequences
instead of duties.
For everyone that's not a rip off of
dark side.
This greater good is fairly
straightforward.
Do anything to stop Vanos from gathering
all the infinity mcgovern's.
It's basically trolley problem,
the movie you are arriving a trolley
when the brakes fail and on the track
ahead of you are five workman that you
will run over.
Now you can steer to another track,
but on that track is one person you
would kill instead of the five.
The mad titans understanding of good is
a universe in perfect balance,
firstly,
balance between life and death and
secondly balanced between humans and
resources.
This second one echoes the economic
philosophies of Thomas Robert Malthus
who suggested that when you have finite
resources,
you therefore have an ideal population
size and when you exceed that population
size,
poverty and starvation increase,
but ultimately the film is critical of
anyone who tries to use math to measure
the word of some lives against others,
these sacrifices and never actually
succeed in bringing about the greater
good.
Their actions are at best few tile and
at worst maximally evil star,
Lord and scarlet witch is attempts to
sacrifice their loved ones are thwarted
by Thanos and fall apart.
In a matter of moments.
We see this critique again when at the
beginning Dr.
strange says he won't hesitate to let
Tony or Peter die to protect the
timestamp.
This changes when at the end he reneged
and trades the time stone for Tony's
life in recognition of a higher moral
duty.
This is best articulated in captain
America is constant refrain.
We don't trade lives basically,
if you ever want to know what the film's
regard as right look no further than the
mcu is moral exemplar.
Steve Rogers.
So what does the films moral perspective
tell us about what will happen in
avengers four.
To answer that,
let's take a look at the comic run that
inspired infinity war even more than
Jim's Darwin's Infinity Gauntlet mini
series.
We're talking of course about Jonathan
Hickman's epic marble run that weaves
its way through fantastic for future
foundation of vendors,
new avengers,
infinity,
and secret wars.
This is the run that it introduced the
coal obsidian outriders and the battle
of will conda from the film's finale,
but most importantly,
infinitely wars.
Moral philosophy is ripped right from
Hickman.
If you thought the stakes were high in
this movie,
check this.
An infinite number of parallel universes
were colliding together at the point of
earth threatening to annihilate their
trillions of inhabitants.
The only way to prevent this was to
destroy one of the Earth's along with
the billions of people living on it,
or to put it another way,
killing millions to say it was the
ultimate trolley problem with all of
existence tied to the tracks and heroes
like iron man and Black Panther forced
to grapple with whether or not to pull
the lever in a moment of truth for all
involved to child walks right up to the
moral line before refusing to cross it.
I know I should.
I know I must,
but it's wrong.
We were damned the very day we thought
it was for men to decide things such as
this as always,
it's captain America who most clearly
champions duty based morality that like
roar shack is utterly uncompromising.
Even in the face of Armageddon,
I don't let people die because it's the
lesser of two evils or expedient or
because it serves the greater good.
I don't compare the act against
something else.
I see someone who needs help and I help.
I don't measure people's lives.
I saved them,
but perhaps the ultimate exemplar of
duty based doing what is right,
ethics and Hickman's work is Mr.
fantastic himself,
Reed Richards,
and it's his arch that will be most
telling for how avengers four will
conclude in secret wars Dr.
Doom like fantasies with the infinity
gauntlet has become for all intensive
purposes,
God,
but he's not defeated by force or a
clever plan,
but by recognition that reed is a
genuinely,
morally superior man who would have been
at being God.
This is Hickman's main thesis and one we
think will play out in avengers for one,
ought not way lives and calculate how to
achieve the greatest good,
but instead merely act according to
one's duty.
So here are our predictions for avengers
for one fan.
I won't be able to enjoy that sunset at
the end of the movie quite as much as he
had hoped.
His regret over Gomorrah's death will
convince him that a single life can have
irreducible worth even one way against a
world in which everyone enjoys peace and
plenty,
which obviously they won't.
It was still a stupid,
stupid,
stupid plan,
so fantas will neither be forced nor
tricked into giving up the gauntlet.
It's too hard to punch or trick God.
No Fan Osu like doom in Hickman.
Secret wars will become convinced by our
heroes that his convictions were wrong,
that he doesn't deserve to be God,
and he will forfeit his power freely to
the one who will convince Dan will be
Tony Stark.
Since the first iron man movie stark has
been the defacto protagonist of the
franchise more than any other character,
he's had the most dynamic character arcs
from narcissistic to self sacrificial
and avengers,
one to the antagonist mired in
consequentialist ethics and civil war to
realizing his ultimate failure and
infinity war.
He will achieve the greatest redemption
in the end.
Firstly,
by coming around to caps,
duty-bound way of seeing the world,
and secondly,
by being the one to defeat fan owes more
than any other character.
Tony has made the most improvement and
is in need of the most improvements.
Still he'll go from someone too selfish
to handle a relationship to someone so
noble as to wield the power of a god
with integrity.
We're guessing that starks conversation
with pepper about his dream of her being
pregnant will propel this final growth
in his character,
but we're not quite sure as to how
lastly,
Stephen strange his decision not to
sacrifice Tony's life to save the time.
Stone will prove the crux around which
stark success and therefore the
salvation of the universe will resolve.
But importantly it won't be because
strange saw that that was the only way
to achieve that one in 14 million
future,
but for no other reason.
Then it was the right thing to do as an
Hickman's work.
It will be explicit that doing the right
thing for no other reason than because
it's right will lead our heroes to
salvation.
And if you want to hear more of our
predictions of what's coming in avengers
for,
be sure to check out the infinity war
episode of our movie podcast.
Show me the meeting.
We're actually recording it today so it
might be up in a day or two,
but to check in,
click the link in the description or
find our podcast on itunes,
stitcher,
soundcloud,
or on our Youtube Channel Wise Cas.
Also,
this is our first attempt to use
philosophy for prediction rather than
reflection.
So if you like it and want to see more,
let us know.
And as always,
thanks for watching guys.
Piece.