Wise,
crack real life.
Jared here,
I know you got used to only rick and
morty quick takes,
but the biggest show on earth just
wrapped its seventh season and man,
there were some amazing moments.
The Jamie Tyrian Reunion,
incredible battles,
lady [inaudible] Lennon's death scene.
Aria murdering the phrase the Zombie
Dragon going ham.
Plenty of awesome stuff.
But to be honest,
in our humble opinion,
the show just doesn't feel as a magical
anymore.
And of course we had to ask ourselves
why.
Game of thrones,
by virtue of adapting George Rr Martin
is revolutionary series got us all
hooked by refusing to play by the rules
of the fantasy genre or even normal tv.
It took turns.
We never saw coming killed characters we
were sure would be around for the end
game and turn the tropes of the fantasy
genre inside out.
It was that willingness to show the ugly
side of the Lords and ladies that made
us fall in love.
These days it's feeling a little eagles
rescue the boys from Mount Doom.
Why?
Maybe it's because game of thrones set
up the unique specific rules for its
world.
Made promises about what we could expect
or not expect.
And now that it's time to pay off those
ideas,
well it just feels like a different
show.
So let's talk about whether or not
dineros and friends have lost their edge
in today's quick take on game of thrones
season seven and as always,
spoilers ahead before we can explain
what's going on with theme of thrones,
we need to talk about story structure,
react structure to be specific.
Even if you've never heard that phrase
before,
you've seen it in action because almost
every story in the world follows it.
Without getting too much into detail,
we can describe three x structure like
this.
In Act one the major players in central
conflicts are introduced in act two
events complicate those conflicts.
And finally in act three of these
conflicts are resolved.
These categories are used to describe
parts of a story.
So while they may seem like arbitrary
cutoff points,
they are indicative of patterns we see
in almost every story.
So let's take that basic structure and
apply it to game of thrones.
Act One is the first two seasons we meet
the lannisters.
The starks Denaris and the whole gang.
We learned about the iron throne and how
everybody wants it.
We even see the white walkers the first
that culminates with each side taking
positions and making their moves.
Act Two is the war itself.
We see the costs.
Rob As the red wedding,
Stan is burning his daughter,
joffrey getting poisoned all with the
undead threat looming in the background.
These days we're firmly enact three John
and Danny are preparing to face off with
the white walkers.
While CRC is going crazy,
trying to hang onto her new found power.
The show pretty much nailed acts one and
two not only did they establish
characters in conflict,
they did so in a creative way that
challenged our expectations after season
one who really thought we'd all grow a
soft spot for Jamie lannister.
The thing is all these twists and turns
set us up to expect an ending that would
follow the same unpredictable pattern.
Sounds weird.
I know,
but that's what made it so great and
season seven that's turning into a bit
of a challenge.
So let's see how it happened.
The show.
May Two major promises early on.
First,
it was a dedication to breaking down the
attractiveness of the fantasy world.
It's not all gowns and gallantry.
Instead,
it showed us the dark underbelly and
cruelty that infects every inch of
Westerns.
The nights aren't paragons of justice.
They're rapists and murderers.
The beautiful prince isn't kind.
He's a spoiled monster.
Honor doesn't help you reach new
heights.
It puts you in jail.
Magic isn't something friendly.
It involves sacrifices and shadow
monsters,
but good guys who fight for justice
don't always win.
In fact,
they usually die because everyone else
is playing dirty.
The landslide Gwen of your style,
forbidden love between a knight and his
Queen in Game of thrones,
that's incest.
This is the show that killed robb stark
who would be the hero in any other
fantasy story at his uncle's Dang
wedding,
a double subversions.
Since rob was living out the narrative
of love overcoming all,
only it did the lannisters cutoff Ned's
head because he was too loyal.
They shoved a kid out a window for
seeing something he shouldn't have.
These moments were more than just cool
Vitsa TV.
There were signals that game of thrones
was not business as usual.
That brings us to the second major
promise.
The show promised us that actions would
have consequences.
We see this in episode one.
A man shirks is nightwatch duties and
ned decapitating,
no questions asked.
That's the world of the show.
Nothing comes without a cost and even
the greatest victories can have
ramifications.
The characters never expected.
There's a storytelling value at play
here.
It means that everything matters.
That's why this is the show that
launched a million conspiracy theories
for several seasons.
Consequences where the law of the land,
for example,
why is no one mad at Cersi for blowing
up the CEP and killing Marjorie Tyrrell?
Someone we know was hugely popular.
Do they just not know?
Maybe it's because they're mad at CRC or
afraid of her,
but these folks seem like they're doing
just fine.
We can also see this and how the show
handles travel.
These days.
The logistics push the limits of
plausibility.
For instance,
Dendri turns into Usain Bolt and sends a
raven at a speed far greater than an
unladen swallow,
which crosses Westeros a continent
described as the size of South America
to Generis who flies her dragon's back
across the continent all before the
magnificent seven can even get frost in
their beards.
See,
it's not just that fast travel strains
credulity.
It actively harms the dramatic action of
the show when travel stops being a
factor.
So does the danger of traveling.
One huge element of the travel times in
thrones Burley storytelling is the
implication that something could go
wrong on any trip.
Bandon,
Stoneman,
slavers,
whatever that risk means that we can
imagine a huge number of possible
outcomes,
but in fast travel world,
that's not really on the table.
All of that nuance,
the repercussions,
the sense that anything can happen any
moment is now gone.
It got traded for expedited plotting and
well,
it's a trade that makes sense.
There were only 13 episodes left when
the season started,
but it's changed.
The nature of the show.
Game of thrones was so interesting for
the first five seasons in change because
it was decidedly not your daddy's
fantasy story.
Now,
this is something that any parent could
recognize.
All the tired and familiar tropes that
game of thrones was deconstructing are
back in full force on ambiguous evil
Quebec on killable chosen ones.
Check Dsx,
Mokena rescues and check,
check,
check.
This isn't a show heading in new
different directions.
This is a show that is checking third
act boxes.
That's not necessarily a bad thing,
but it's checking them in a way that
defies the narrative framework.
We spent five years internalizing even
the finale,
which was pretty dang good,
showed off all these problems.
As the season came to a close,
we got clear sides,
something game of thrones has been
reluctant to offer us.
Now all the characters we like are on
one side.
There's no room for ethical ambiguity.
So why is this happening?
Well,
it goes back to that three act
structure.
Thousands of years of storytelling
indicate that to create a satisfying
narrative,
the show needs to have all the work that
Danny,
John and others have put into change.
The world actually pay off.
Unfortunately,
that's how all fantasy stories and the
good guys always win against incredible
odds.
The subversion doesn't work anymore when
it comes to the end game.
Even the craziest brand is the night
king type ending doesn't really subvert
anything and ending where this was all
inevitable because of magic or time
travel undermines the theme of agency in
the show and it's just another fantasy
trope for the show to fall back on.
Unfortunately,
it seems the show can't get to the
ending it wants while still disrupting
the fantasy narrative space from the
beginning.
Game of thrones has told us that we're
getting a different kind of fantasy
story,
but this past season it felt more like
Lord of the rings than the Sopranos and
honestly it's a bit disappointing.
Look at the end of the day,
it's still a good show,
but it's an action fantasy story and
that's not what they promised us.
Thanks for watching guys piece.
If you're looking for more wisecrack
quick takes on the latest stuff,
be sure to check out our rick and Morty
podcasts,
the squatch where we break down every
single new episode.
And if you're looking for more game of
thrones stuff,
be sure to check out our other videos
here and you could find all this and the
description to catch all next time.
Peace.