This video is brought to you by
squarespace.
Whether you need a domain,
website or online store,
make it with squarespace.
Hey wisecrack jared here.
It all started when someone at the
office said,
jared,
got to watch the boss baby.
So I did.
And then perhaps reluctantly we covered
it on our movie podcast.
Show me the meaning and yes,
shameless plug.
Check it out using the link in the
description and let me tell you
something odd happens to you when you
spend hours thinking about the boss
baby.
Soon it became a semi ironic obsession.
And then after it got nominated for an
Oscar,
we said we have to do a video on the
boss' pain.
So we're going to do something a little
different today.
It's not that the boss baby is a
deliberate and nuanced exploration of
childhood psychology,
it's more holy.
This movie accidentally shows us how the
way we currently think about love is not
only ruining us but our future children.
So if you thought the tide pod challenge
was bad for kids,
strap in for this wise crack condition
on the boss baby.
And as always,
and if you care,
spoilers ahead.
Let's start with a recap.
Tim is living a perfect childhood with
his family.
It's nothing but imaginary ventures and
expensively licensed lullabies,
blackbird singing in the dead of night
until the baby shows up.
Suddenly Tim's parents need to spread
the love around and tim finds himself
struggling with not being the center of
attention.
Tim Learns that this is no ordinary
baby.
It's an Oscar nominated boss baby.
It can talk,
hold meetings and eat solid food.
At first,
tim tries to expose the babies bossy
ways,
making a be suited baby Mike Freak is
Paris out enough that they,
I don't know,
throw the baby away or something,
but the boss baby isn't going out like
that and outwit him at every turn.
Tim Learns the baby is only around to
foil puppy Co's,
mysterious new puppy that threatens to
make babies obsolete somehow.
So he agrees to help.
Tim and the Oscar nominated boss baby
sneak into puppy code to conduct some
corporate espionage.
They're madcap adventure goes off the
rails and they end up in Las Vegas
saving their parents from a rocket ship.
With the help of a tidal wave of
puppies.
It's weird.
So what's the movie really about?
Well,
the short answer is easy.
La La,
la,
la La.
No,
it's about love.
Tim wants his parents love the boss.
Baby wants to win the market.
Share of love back from those Gosh Dang
puppies and the villain wants to steal
love away from babies.
No one will ever want a baby,
ever,
ever.
It all comes back to love.
In the end.
Tim and the boss baby have a delightful
reunion when they realize that love is
not a finite resource.
There's enough for everyone.
Now that's a nice message and all.
But anyone who's ever had a high school
crush knows we don't always get the love
we want.
Now I know.
Who Cares?
A silly kids movie has a reductive view.
Love.
So what?
Well,
this view on love isn't just simplistic.
Some might call it dangerous,
like known Weirdo and everyone's second
favorite psychoanalyst Jacques Lacan.
One of the cons fundamental ideas is the
idea of lack.
In short,
Lacan says that we spend our lives
looking for meaning unity and peace,
but those aren't real things.
We're never going to find them,
and the desperate search for them is
what makes people neurotic.
We developed social and psychological
disorders to cope with the fact that
despite how badly we want life to be
perfect,
it never will be and it's this lack that
defines tim struggle in the film curl
ICAN.
It all starts with a childhood trauma
called the mirror stage.
When we're babies,
we don't really know what the hell is
going on around us,
but everything is awesome.
We're fed,
we're taking care of and it's all good,
but eventually we see ourselves in a
mirror and realized we're not part of a
comfy,
cozy world,
but just one little being in a giant
world,
that realization hurts.
It's when we realize we're on our own.
We see this phenomenon play out in boss
baby too.
I'll be,
it's a little differently.
Tim is naive to the fact that the world
doesn't cater to his every need until
the boss baby shows up and he is
traumatized.
Suddenly the world isn't all about Tim,
is parents only have a finite amount of
love to give.
Moms.
Dad don't even know you.
They love me.
Oh yeah.
Do the math kid.
There's only so much love to go around.
It's like these beats you used to have
all your parents love all their time,
all their attention.
You had all the beads,
but then I came along.
Babies take up a lot of time.
They need a lot of attention.
They get all of you obviously didn't go
to business school.
This theory that there isn't enough love
for everyone is the foundation of every
Oscar nominated choice.
The boss baby makes tim tries to live
with the baby,
but he can't.
It can sucks,
so he tries to expose him so his parents
will get rid of them.
No dice even jumps over a train and
sneaks onto an elvis themed flight to
Vegas,
all to make this baby go away.
Why?
Because the baby interrupted his notion
of how love works.
Life was good.
Life was perfect,
but as I drifted off to sleep,
something my parents said got me
thinking,
where do babies come from?
No matter how much,
this feeling of having your ideal
reality shattered may suck.
It's an essential stage of human
development.
However,
instead of having tim move past this
difficult stage,
the film doubles down on his childish
fantasy,
suggesting that love is in fact
infinite.
Tim writes a letter to the boss,
baby sing that there's plenty of love
for both of them as long as they have
each other.
It's heartwarming,
but for Lacan,
desire for love,
for anything else is insatiable because
the world will never be perfect.
It's the inevitable outcome of lack will
never have the flawless complete life we
want.
So we focused on specific things as
objects of desires or an individual
problems as the source of our suffering.
In other words,
Tim's idea that love can or should be,
infinite is a fantasy,
and boy does tim love fantasy.
Throughout the movie,
we see him creating fantasies to
represent the world around him.
He uses those fantasies to entertain
himself,
to show his feelings and to grapple with
how love works.
In the end,
we learned the whole movie is just a
story adult him is relaying to his
daughter to prepare her for a sibling on
the way to story Daddy.
Well Sweetie,
that's how I remember it,
but you know what?
I found out what there's plenty of love
for everyone.
Lacan might say.
This poses a few issues by creating this
bizarre narrative about a ruthless
corporate baby who threatens to close on
all the market share of love in his
family unit.
Tim Is essentially demonizing his little
brother.
The deal with the fact that love is not
in fact intranet,
but whether finite or not,
we're always going to want more and
we'll never get all the love we want.
This targeting of a single cause for all
our problems is something that Lacanian
scholars and also regular people refer
to as scapegoating.
In the case of the family,
we developed neuroses,
a cope with the feelings of isolation
that start with the mirror stage or we
fabricate a story about a giant
corporation of babies.
The justify hating her little brother.
We see the same thing happened with the
villain.
Francis Francis formerly super colossal
big fat boss baby.
He becomes an evil psychopath and tries
to steal love from all babies because
his fantasy of staying a baby forever is
taken away from him and he blames all
other babies.
This is what happens when we expect a
perfect world and don't get what we
want.
We act like babies but not necessarily
the Oscar nominated con and then Tim
does quite possibly the most
irresponsible thing ever.
He passes his fantasy and all the
neurotic baggage that comes with it on
to his daughter.
Inundating your daughter with the idea
that your basic desires will always be
fulfilled is well not great.
That will probably lead to some issues
down the line like whatever happened to
this kid,
like get out of my face and make no
money.
What are you wearing?
So
what's the deal?
Is it just that love is another one of
the many things we're programmed to want
but doom to never get enough of not so
fast.
The con might say there is in fact a
secret way around the problem of love
and fantasy and it's also hidden in the
Oscar nominated story of the boss baby.
What the movie's ending gets right is
that the love between the brothers is
the healthiest relationship we see in
the movie,
but that's not because love is infinite.
Instead,
it's because love depends on showing us
how much we're missing.
You don't even know what it's like to be
part of a fair and you don't know what
it's like to have a job.
Lacan famously referred to love as to
give.
What one does not have.
When we love someone,
we reflect their lack back to them.
We show them what they are missing and
for Lacan that confrontation with LACC
is far more psychologically curative
than covering over our desires with
fantasies and scapegoats.
If we accept that definition of love,
it's hard to argue that the brothers
don't live up to it from the very
beginning.
Their position not just as opposites but
as complimentary.
Boss baby is practical,
but tim is a dreamer.
The boss baby writes memos.
Tim Takes Action.
Tim has experienced love and values it
immensely.
Boss baby has never been loved and isn't
too worried about it.
I may look like a baby,
but I was born all grown up,
never had someone to love you.
Well,
you can't miss what you never had.
They each cover the other's flaws and
reflect them back to each other in a way
that helps them both grow and save the
day.
It's the boss baby's motivational skills
that keep tim on the bike once he loses
the training wheels.
The path to success is not a straight
line templeton,
but rather a wild ride and it's Tim's
imagination that allows them to defeat
Francis Francis in the end by showing
the other what they're missing and
embodying those values,
they help each other grow into more well
rounded and healthy individuals per
lacan.
Love isn't meant to fill in the gaps we
fill in our lives,
the attempt to make life perfect.
It's exactly what leads to neurosis and
pathology and all kinds of other messy
things.
Instead,
love shows us what we're missing and
makes it okay because we see what is
missing in someone else.
Maybe it seems like we're going a little
overboard on a movie about a baby who is
somehow paradoxically a boss.
But this is an important lesson.
Real life is full of disappointment and
few if any things live up to the world
we imagine,
but that's no reason to get depressed.
Oh you need to do is realize that things
aren't going to be perfect.
Not everyone gets nominated for an Oscar
and once you see that imperfection
reflected in the world around you,
it's really not so bad.
Thanks wise crack.
And before you go,
want to be a real boss,
you squarespace to design your next
website.
It's so easy up baby can do it.
Use the offer code wise crack to get 10%
off your first purchase of a website or
domain today.
Don't know how to code,
not a problem.
Squarespace's all in one platform and
gorgeous designer templates.
Make it a cinch to build an eye catching
website for your project or business.
And with award winning 24 seven customer
support help is never more than a phone
call away and on over to squarespace.com
for your free trial.
And when you're ready to launch,
go to squarespace.com/wise
crack and use the offer code wise crack
to save 10% off your first purchase of a
website or domain.
Thanks for watching guys.
Remember to hit the subscribe button and
ring that bell catch all next time.
Peace.