This video is brought to you by
squarespace,
whether you need a domain,
website,
or online store,
make it with squarespace.
Hey guys,
jared here and today we're diving back
into black mirror.
The fourth season of this modern
twilight zone just dropped on Netflix
and with it some truly thought provoking
episodes including a loving homage to
star trek and Apache helicopter parents,
and they rather utopian alternative to
tinder in the wake of season three super
popular San Junipero.
The show has traded it's trademark
pessimism for a slightly more positive
tone,
injecting a measure of justice and
happiness previously unseen in the
series,
but it's in the season finale where the
show does something drastically
different.
Black Museum not only provides the high
concept technological nightmare that
we've come to expect,
but reflects on the legacy and function
of the show.
As a whole,
black museum asks,
what is even the purpose of Black
Mirror?
Welcome this wise crack quick take on
the philosophy of black museum and
obviously spoilers ahead.
The episode follows a young woman named
niche as she's given a private tour by
proprietor Rolo Haynes of the eponymous
black museum,
a tourist trap that houses a collection
of authentic criminological artifacts.
Viewers will be sure to spot a number of
prominent props from past episodes,
including the DNA analyzer from USS
Callister,
the parental control pad from Archangel
be bloody bathtub from crocodile,
and even the strange symbol mark ski
masks from White Bear.
These are more than just Easter eggs.
There are visual clues to the viewer
that Black Museum is a Meta textual
reflection of the show itself.
The artifacts that contain serve as a
physical representation of the episodes
they appeared in,
and even the name black museum is
deliberately evocative of the show's
title Black Mirror like the holiday
special white Christmas black museum is
an anthology within an anthology with
three separate subplots loosely
connected by Rolo Haynes is narration
and utilizing this same methodology
structure.
Black Museum is mirroring the format of
black mirror,
but if the exhibits in the background
represent past episodes,
what do the three new gadgets,
Dr Dawson's lymphatic diagnoser,
the monkey stuff with Carrie's
consciousness and Clayton Lee's
holographic holding cell represent each
item is an interface for human
consciousness,
a more direct means of what television
and social media already do today.
These fictional items represent the
different ways our current technology
both connects and disconnects us as a
society.
Dustin's implant connects him and his
patients signaling their sensations to
him via the hairnet.
Looking headgear.
The upload which inserts carries mind
into the backseat of Jack's brain,
allows her to see and feel as he does
and the thin string separating Clayton's
consciousness from the museum.
Visitors creates emotional distance akin
to the distance between fictionalized
characters and desensitize audiences.
Dawson subplot comments on media's
ability to let us empathize with
characters and experience thrills
without any physical ramifications.
Imagine if you could feel exactly what a
patient feels minus the physical
consequences.
Jack and Carrie story reflects media's
ability to turn us into voyeurs.
Clayton story reflects on the guilt free
gratification we get from consuming
violence in media.
In all of these cases,
technology allows individuals to
experience things vicariously like
hitchhiker,
like a passenger,
vicarious sensations.
She sees what you see,
she feels what you feel.
This episode dramatizes what all fiction
generally does and what Black Mirror as
a television program does.
Specifically all fiction is delivered to
us via a medium in the case of black
mirror through television.
Television itself is enroll those words,
a receiver for human experiences and one
that often,
as Rolo says,
offers no privacy for him,
no agency for her with a particularly
compelling show like Black Mirror.
We become increasingly invested and
share in the same sense of joy in San
Junipero as Kelly and Yorkie the same
indignation as being in 15 million
merits and the same initial prejudices
and gradual awakening as stripe in men
against fire.
For philosopher Martha Nussbaum.
This kind of connection is emblematic of
narratives,
roles in one's moral development.
Narratives according to Nussbaum free us
from the parochial confines over our own
lives and place us in a position both
like and unlike our own like in that we
are emotionally involved with the
characters,
active with them and aware of our
incompleteness,
unlike in that we're free of certain
sources of distortion that frequently
impede our real life deliberations.
For example,
take a character like being in 15
million merits.
His love for abby might remind us of our
own lives,
but unlike being we're not sent on a
downward spiral when that love is lost,
yet we can still experience it from a
distance.
Black Museum,
however,
explores the danger of this distancing
effect through Dr Dawson subplot and
it's here that the episode looks at the
potentially desensitizing nature of the
series owned violent imagery,
more pain.
He felt pleasure,
God
in a series which premiered with the
prime minister of Britain.
A pig.
Maintaining that same sense of shock
requires increasingly more shocking
scenes.
Bus,
they need to surprise audiences in shut
up and dance.
By revealing that the protagonist they'd
been rooting for had been into Kiddie
porn,
only to
be topped in the subsequent season in
crocodile.
As we experienced an average human being
transitioned from innocence to
infanticide because a baby per rolo.
As the show progressed,
our relationship with pain had shifted.
We're not merely desensitized to the
violence on screen.
We take a twisted kind of pleasure in
the discomfort it inflicts upon us.
See,
it's like eating chilis,
your climate eyes fast.
First Time we had a Jalapeno that you
spat it out too hot,
persevere,
and it becomes addictive,
but black museum is ultimately not
apologetic for engaging in such extreme
emotions,
arguing through its third subplot that
the show is not empty.
Sensationalism,
but rather has a purpose motivating it
in the main exhibit of Black Museum.
We see what remains of Clayton Lee,
the alleged murderer who is arrested.
Execution had been alluded to throughout
the episode like carrying the Monkey.
His consciousness continues on even
after the exploration of his physical
body.
I'll be at this time as a self aware
hologram.
As the museum's grand attraction
visitors are invited to pull the switch
themselves,
not merely inflicting real torture on
this Lee,
but in the process creating a sentience
souvenir that eternally experiences the
moment of execution.
It was beautiful juicing him out.
Subconscious session,
snapshot of Clayton,
not a recording,
a true copy of his mind perpetually
experiencing that,
but stuck
forever in that one.
Perfect.
Similar to white Christmas in which the
cookie of Joe is confined to a virtual
cabin for what he experiences as
hundreds of thousands of years.
It's the punishment made perpetual that
most offenders,
our innate sense of proportionality,
even if he committed the crime,
no finite offense could merit infinite
punishment.
As such,
the show forces us to empathize with one
character who may be a murderer and
another absolutely guilty of
manslaughter and a child on Christmas.
We don't merely feel bad for them from
the safe distance of our side of the
screen.
We feel their pain with them.
Likewise,
we feel a sense of vindication when our
audience surrogate niche revealed to be
Clayton's daughter and carrying her
mother inside her head,
enact retribution against Rolo.
It's not just that niche seeing the
suffering of her father or hearing the
story of Kerry engender empathy in her.
It's that such empathy then motivated
her to moral action.
This is black museum state went about
how Black Mirror sees itself and its
purpose.
It's not desensitizing spectacle and
empty entertainment.
It's not even a cautionary tale about
the dangers of technology after all,
the same mind sharing method which
caused Jack so much.
Grief is shown as being beneficial to
niche and her mother rather black mirror
sees itself as serving the same role as
a long line of literature and science
fiction shows which connect us
emotionally to their characters in order
to engender empathy and in turn,
encourage us to enact justice in the
episode arc.
Angel Art empathetic attachment to the
constantly surveilled.
Sarah is supposed to incite us against
similar big mother surveillance systems
pervading our lives or in the episode
metal head.
Our investment in Bella survival against
what is essentially Boston dynamics is
big dog invites us to scrutinize the
militarization of autonomous machines in
all these cases,
black communities able to raise our
concerns for these societal issues as
effectively as it does only because it
first causes us to care for the
characters it's crafted.
Black Museum is the whole of the show.
Black Mirror distilled down to a single
episode preserving the same content,
the same format,
and most importantly the same purpose to
see ourselves reflected in the black
mirror that is our television screen or
smartphone.
Engaging empathetically with the
characters were connected to buy that
screen and by doing so,
expanding our moral imagination and
motivating us towards justice.
Thanks for watching guys.
Hope you enjoyed season four and as
always,
piece,
but of course internet technology
doesn't have to be a harbinger of doom.
Just ask the folks over at squarespace
the place to go when you want to build a
stunning website and wisecrack fans can
go to squarespace today to start their
free trial and get 10 percent off their
first purchase when they use the offer
code quicktakes squarespace.
Makes it easy for you to transfer your
old domain or to create a new one with
designer templates housed in a user
friendly all in one platform.
Got Artwork or services to sell
squarespace,
makes it simple to set up and manage an
online store and they'll help you
maintain your website with award
winning.
Twenty four slash seven customer
support.
So you go to squarespace.com
for a free trial and when you're ready
to launch your site,
go to squarespace.com/quick
takes and use the offer code quick takes
to save 10 percent off your first
purchase of a website or domain.
That's all the time we've got.
Thanks to squarespace for sponsoring
this video and if you haven't already,
be sure to subscribe and ring that bell
catch next time.
Peace.