Hey guys,
Helen again,
so I know we've talked about rick and
morty have bought,
but well,
jared has been lamenting the lack of
meaning in our asshole universe.
I thought it was time to give science a
chance to shine light on everyone's
favorite negligent grandpa and his,
uh,
talented career savvy son in law.
When do we need food?
When we're hungry.
Specifically,
I wanted to see what psychology had to
say about a problem we've all been
asking ourselves,
is rick destined to be miserable because
of his intelligence?
And if so,
is it better to be a jerry?
If you asked 19th century author
Theodore dust way up ski,
he would probably say no as he famously
puts it in the idiot.
It is better to be unhappy and know the
worst than to be happy in a fool's
paradise.
Dostoevsky statement seems quite apt and
describing the dynamic between Jerry and
rick.
Rick's despondency is driven by his
knowledge that nothing matters.
While a fool's paradise might as well
just be Jerry burry,
Visha Maillian simulation.
Yes.
You just sold the apples campaign.
Who just sold the apples campaign?
Pluto or the titanic.
Oh,
look,
it's the line for the bow,
so it's Dostoevsky,
right?
We'll break it down in this wise crack
addition on the psychology of Rick and
morty and being smart make you miserable
and as always,
spoilers ahead for being the smartest
man in the universe.
Rick,
surprisingly relatable as cocreator Dan
harmon puts it.
When you're standing in line at that
bank,
sometimes you always feel like none of
these people understand what a hurry I'm
in,
how much crap I have to do today,
what I'm up against.
We've all been rick,
and as much as it sucks to admit,
a lot of us can also probably identify
with his self loathing and self
destructive behavior.
Maybe I hate myself.
Maybe I think I deserved to die.
I,
I don't.
I don't know.
Rick is practically omnipotent with the
power to invent,
transform,
and destroy his way into getting
whatever he wants.
Yet despite all that power,
he's miserable.
On the other hand,
there's Jerry who's a little bit dumb
and a lot of bit discombobulated.
Jerry operates best when he doesn't have
to think too much because when he does,
he generally makes things worse,
but even when he's down in the deepest
of dumps,
he doesn't seem to suffer to the same
degree that rick does.
Jerry may not have street smarts or be
able to hold down a job,
but he's also not hitting the bottle or
questioning his place in the universe
and his barber.
Happiness seems low,
so is it better to be a rick or a jerry?
First?
Let's look at Rick.
His inner turmoil leaks out in some
subtle and not so subtle ways like his
famous catchphrase 40.
Do you know what?
Oh,
that's just stupid nonsense.
Catchphrase.
It's not nonsense at all in my people's
tongue.
It means I am in great pain.
Please help me
and obviously that way to real suicide
attempt in season two,
but is it because he's smart?
The stereotype of the tortured genius is
so deeply into pop culture that we
should wonder whether it's overblown
Hollywood bullshit,
the roster of famous folks from history
who have suffered from crushing
depression and the attention given to
the brilliance madness link by the media
almost makes it seem like depression is
a prerequisite to success,
but there are obviously plenty of
brilliant people who didn't suffer from
mental illness or were otherwise normal.
They just aren't to sensational.
Right?
Listicles about as say,
a guy who fell in love with a pigeon,
so is it true?
Does being a genius or even just pretty
smart make you destined for misery?
Well,
maybe one study as 3,700
Mensa members or people who were so
proud of their Iq scores that they
joined an organization to brag about it
if they were currently dealing with
mental illness more than a third said
they were depressed.
To put that in context,
that's five times the national average.
If you rounded up 100 Mensa members and
100 regular people,
about six to seven of those regular
people would probably be depressed.
Well,
more than 30 of the MENSA members would
be a few caveats.
The mensa members were asked to self
report on their own wellbeing here,
of those who reported feeling depressed,
roughly 10 percent didn't have a doctor
telling them they actually had
depression.
As anyone who spends way too much time
googling symptoms knows the art of self
diagnosis is far from perfect.
Plus are these medicines representative
of all smart people?
Probably not.
Still,
there might be a biological basis for
why highly intelligent people are prone
to depression.
Her pinsky who random mensa study
asserted the people with Iqs of 130 plus
have hyper brands.
That is,
they can comprehend the world's
problems,
uncertainties and possibilities more
easily than people with non-hyper
brains.
The whole hyper brain idea was based on
the work of psychiatrist Dr.
Kasim Years Dubroski,
who noticed his exceptionally smart
patients had a tendency to overly
contemplate everything,
especially the bad stuff.
At times.
They also seem to experience deeper
depression compared to the
intellectually average.
These traits were part of a group of
characteristics that he called over
excitability.
He didn't see it as a bad thing.
Instead,
he thought it was predictive of the
potential for being able to achieve the
most ideal version of oneself.
In 1972,
he wrote one who manifests several forms
of over excitability,
sees reality in a different,
stronger,
and more excitable manner.
Debraski said that overexcited abilities
come and five flavors,
excessive energy or nervousness,
deep appreciation for things like art or
music being extremely curious or having
an active mind,
having a vivid imagination,
and finally extreme and complex
emotional experiences.
Rick is a textbook example of all of
these things.
He still slaying aliens on the rig at 70
years old freestyles award winning
tracks on a whim you gotta to use with
me.
Okay.
Maybe that's not appreciation,
but still can be just a tiny bit over
analytical.
I can prove it mathematically is capable
of thinking up and inventing entire
worlds and has seriously complicated
feelings for his family.
While it hasn't been tested,
some psychologists believe that people
who think this way are more prone to
what's called existential depression.
It's exactly what it sounds like.
Feelings of hopelessness that come from
wondering whether life is ultimately
meaningless.
Dr James Webb,
a psychologist who studies gifted kids
notes the well existential depression
can happen to anybody following a
crisis.
It's more likely to happen spontaneously
to people whose intelligence is above
average.
Rick never comes out and says he's
crushed beneath the weight of a futile
existence,
but he certainly comes close.
You know,
smart people get a chance to climb on
top,
take reality for a ride,
but it'll never stop trying to throw
you.
Eventually it will.
There's no other way off.
On top of that,
he's bored senseless,
virtually nothing in our own mundane
world impresses him,
but his intellectual prowess and
imagination enable him to find temporary
reprieve from boredom by way of his
portal,
gun aided adventures.
Oh,
and alcohol.
Contrast this with Jerry.
Jerry possesses none of the traits,
psychologist associated with hyper
brain,
unless you count getting super stoked
about rare coins.
There's little r two.
D Two is where the George Washington
should be done.
Mobile Games or the titanic,
so does that mean he's inherently
happier,
but before we get there,
real life.
Helen,
here for a second.
I want to take a minute to talk about
this video spots or better help,
which is an online counseling service
for those of you who saw our booth
Burnham video,
you know jared gave him a girl and he
dug it knowing I like many people might
be able to benefit from talking to
someone on a regular basis.
He suggested I give them a try too,
so I did stick around to the end of the
video to hear more about my experience.
And in the meantime,
go to [inaudible] dot com slash wise,
correct.
One to learn more.
Now,
back to Jerry.
Okay,
so does Jerry's daringness mean he's
happier news,
but it's complicated.
Well,
some studies may suggest that being
smart makes you more likely to be
depressed.
Others suggests that intelligence gives
you the ability to unlock a lot of
amazing doors in life that will make you
healthier and sometimes happier.
Specifically money as pretty much all of
the studies on Iq and depression point
out being smart is associated with
greater wealth and therefore better
health.
Oh,
sometimes it gets hard to distinguish
what causes what?
Among the zillions of criticisms of Iq
tests is the kids who come from well off
families are more likely to be tested in
the first place.
That being said,
the relationship between achievement,
money,
and intelligence throws a wrench in the
idea that genius equals misery.
In some studies,
having a higher Iq has actually been
associated with greater happiness.
One study looked at more than 6,800
people and found that I was positively
correlated with well self reported.
Happiness genius has long been
associated with eccentricities and few
geniuses,
fictional or otherwise can live up to
the centricity of Rick Sanchez.
It's safe to say rick has a tendency to
overwhelm people with his intensity.
Some researchers have said this is a
hallmark of people with high Iq,
but these eccentricities may freak out.
The normal minded people around them
leaving our geniuses socially isolated.
Trying to roll with the normies requires
minimizing that intensity which can lead
to a so called crisis of self,
where conformity makes people feel lost
and confused about who they really are.
One could argue that Rick's in a
perpetual crisis of self on earth.
He's forever an oddball and while that
doesn't seem to concern him too much,
it does mean he asked to compromise his
nature for the sake of his relationship
with his family,
like when he finally shows up to
therapy,
I have no doubt that you would be bored
senseless by therapy the same way on
board when I brushed my teeth and wipe
my ass,
because the thing about repairing,
maintaining and cleaning is it's not an
adventure.
Yeah.
Just because jerry isn't an eccentric
genius,
doesn't mean he doesn't have his own
problems fitting in.
He's seriously lacking in social skills.
Very stop networking.
We're in space survival skills.
I'm not proud to share this,
but the truth is I just kept crawling
and kept working or skills of any kind.
Really.
He's most successful in a career where
he doesn't even know what he does.
Our Ya the Galactic Federation taking
over Earth's best thing that's ever
happened in his family.
I just got my six promotion this week
and I still don't know what I do and is
otherwise so utterly incompetent that he
has to beg his kids for money.
Oh God.
Todd,
please don't just need a few hundred
dollars to get through them on.
I have some interviews coming up.
Something's going to come through.
I can see it.
Ultimately,
as Rick points out after the worldly
Durley fiasco,
the only reason Jerry's able to get by
is because everyone feels sorry for him.
You act like prey,
but you're a predator.
You use pity to lure in your victim how
you survive.
Rick gets his way by intimidating.
People fall.
Jerry relies on their mercy,
so let's recap.
Some research suggests that the hyper
brains of highly intelligent people make
them more prone to depression mainly
because they see the world in a
different way and are more intense than
your average homosapien,
which is kind of a turnoff to the
average joes,
but at the same time,
the fact that they can leverage their
smarts for high paying jobs that enable
them to avoid the stresses of poverty
and afford better healthcare means that
as a group,
they're more likely to be happier.
Overall.
To our original question,
is it really better to know the worst
and be unhappy than to be happy in a
fool's paradise?
To be a rick rather than a jerry
research says,
well,
that's a subjective asked question and
frankly,
psychology doesn't have a concrete
answer.
Thanks psychology.
I went to school for you,
but for limited evidence that is out
there,
so just that while you may be less
likely to suffer from existential
depression as a jerry,
you're more likely to live a better life
overall as a rick,
but which would you rather be?
Wisecrack.
Drop us a line in the comments below and
thanks for watching.
All right guys,
thanks for sitting around.
So this video was sponsored by the
online counseling service,
better health.
We've talked about them before and they
wound up sponsoring this video to better
help.
Takes an inventory of what you're
looking for in therapy and then they
match you with a licensed counselor
within 24 hours.
I'm a full time journalist who
freelances for companies like wisecrack
on the side,
so it's really hard for me to commit to
a set time for therapy every week.
My therapist was extremely patient and
totally understood my crazy schedule.
Plus she was really accessible and
responsive.
One of the best parts about it is that
you don't have to talk to your therapist
over video conferencing if you don't
want to,
or if you just don't have time,
you can reach out to them over the phone
or through messaging or through live
chat and you can get ahold of them while
you were in your garage or your bed or
wherever,
and it's all completely confidential.
We all know we should make mental health
a priority,
but getting over the stigma or just
finding the time can be super
challenging.
So if you've been thinking about talking
to a therapist,
consider checking out better health and
better health.com/wise,
crack one or click the link in the
description below.
Thanks so much for watching and see you
next time.