Hey guys,
Helen here,
wisecracks resident science nerd.
Well,
14 year old.
Jared was waiting in line seven hours
early for the matrix reloaded.
I was playing with my star wars action
figures,
acting out weird love triangles between
on Django and Princess Leia and trying
to convince my family that my home
planet was actually older on,
so I decided to flex my star wars
geekery for this discussion of Disney's
latest installment in the star wars
cinematic universe solo.
The movie fills in the backstory of our
favorite smuggler,
turned hero showing us how a young Han
transforms into the legendary Han Solo,
sort of given that the other films have
been massive cash cows solo was expected
to do pretty well even considering the
last jet I backlash and potential
franchise fatigue,
but solo flopped.
It's on track to be the first
unprofitable star wars film ever.
They should surprise you for one reason.
Everything about this movie is designed
to be marketable and give you the warm
fuzzies,
so what went wrong?
Let's take a look in this wisecrack
addition on how even psychology couldn't
sell solo thanks to our sponsor,
brilliant.org
for making this video possible,
and as always,
spoilers solo kicks off sometime around
the year 13 bb,
why that's 30 to 64 on the lawful
calendar and ends roughly 10 years
before rogue one and a new hope.
The movie follows aspiring pilot and
[inaudible] to be Han as he goes from a
bright eyed romantic to an outlaw who
shoots first.
Alright,
along the way,
he picks up a level below 190 year old
Wiki,
a notorious techno sexual smuggler,
and the Millennium Falcon doesn't quite
pull off the Kessel run in less than 12
parsecs unless you round down.
Here's Solos,
fundamental strategy,
make us nostalgic for the good old days
of star wars by cramming in as many
Easter eggs and nods to the past our
wars as possible.
There's the golden dice,
the planet Solutia Viper droids,
mandalorian armor,
Jabba the Hutt boss,
the bounty hunter,
Colo crawfish,
and of course darth Maul,
and that's just scratching the surface.
The movie is one Easter Egg.
After the next pulling references,
not only from the films but also from
the novelizations,
the video games and the animated series,
the reference to Rsa,
Lando skies from return of the Jedi and
cure is impressive.
Command of terrorist Khasi are great
ways to make fans who know two
generations worth of star wars lore feel
like they have a special connection to
the film,
but despite the outstanding fan service
and some great deep cuts,
the movie falls short because nostalgia
alone can't propel a film and might even
get in the way.
Well,
I can't read Disney's mind.
The reason they relied on all this
nostalgia seems pretty obvious.
Marketers use nostalgia to sell stuff
all the time and it's no different in
movies.
Just look at the force awakens.
Besides bringing back the actual
characters and actors from the original
trilogy,
the film paid homage to its predecessors
in the form of things like trash
compactors,
pod racing,
flags,
and even that Werewolf alien thing from
the Mos.
Cantina neuroscience has a possible
explanation for why this trick can be
super effective.
It involves the brain's reward system.
Some imaging studies have shown that the
parts of the brain tied to feelings like
pleasure,
motivation and euphoria are activated
when you're experiencing a stalled jet,
so for long time star wars fans,
seeing things like Han's dice and
hearing the sound of the ethereal
fighters or like a jump to hyperspace
for the feel good pathways in your
brain,
which is exactly what Disney wants to
happen because then you'll keep coming
back for more or buy some solo dice
cufflinks and a tee shirt,
but nostalgia.
Marketing aside,
these Easter eggs do something else in
the case of humor.
Being on the receiving end of an inside
joke makes us feel more affiliation with
the jokester and makes them seem more
socially desirable.
I understood that reference and
according to the encryption theory of
humor,
jokes are funny,
not just because of their superficial
content,
but because they broadcast shared
knowledge between the person and their
audience.
So if you caught yourself laughing in
the scene where is losing it over being
beaten at Gerrick or the one where he's
holding up the guard severed arms.
The writers did their job from a
psychology standpoint.
The fact that Disney shares your inside
knowledge that peoples' arms off makes
you feel like they get it.
Droid don't pull people's arms out of
their sockets when they lose,
but here's where solo lands itself in
trouble.
Plenty of movies have inside jokes and
references will also giving us well
developed characters,
but in the process of doubling down on
the stall did Easter eggs.
Disney fails to give us a legit origin
story.
Solos.
Fundamental problem is that Alden
Ehrenreich has to convince us.
He's Harrison Ford's Han Solo from the
very start.
He's got the arrogance,
the wisecracks,
the hustle hard,
supposed to transition is basically 75
percent complete right from the
beginning,
so by the time he shoots back at the
end,
it doesn't seem like much of a change.
He's been acting like Harrison Ford the
whole time.
The film makes gestures of a
transformation,
but they seem halfhearted when cram
between 8,000
other nostalgia triggers as a result for
a film that promises to showcase a
development of one of the most beloved
characters and Saifai history.
It feels more like a buzzfeed top 10
list of Han Solo Trivia,
even significant plot points like the
way Han gets his last name meets Lando
or winds the Millennium Falcon.
Feel like Easter eggs take Han's
relationship with chewy Han's,
only known him for a couple of minutes
before the relationship has the same
dynamic as it does throughout the rest
of the saga.
Normally we'd expect this kind of
connection to develop and mature over
time,
but because Disney's top priority was to
trigger nostalgia and familiarity rather
than the truly show development,
it ends up feeling shallow.
The movie gets it out of the way and
moves onto the next bit of Trivia.
The point of an origin story is to show
us how a character we know and love
comes to be who they are.
For Batman Begins Shows Bruce Wayne
mastering his fears to become the
legendary dark night.
Bruce starts out as a troubled,
angsty,
scared youth at the beginning and by the
end he's disciplined and unafraid.
Dr.
strange starts off as a self centered
surgeon who only believes in cold
rationality and ends the film as a self
sacrificial mystic.
But to be honest,
I kind of get it when you're recasting
such an iconic role,
you can stuck between a rock and a hard
place.
If Hans antiques at the beginning seemed
completely different than Harrison Ford,
the audience wouldn't believe they were
watching Han Solo.
But if you have him act like Ford Solo
from the beginning,
you sacrifice a convincing arc for
familiarity.
If we were to try to give the fillmore
credit,
we might say that the arc is Han going
from an aspiring scoundrel to an
idealist when he decides to hand over
the hyper fuel to the budding
resistance.
But isn't that the exact same arc from a
new foe?
At worst,
the film has no work and at best it's a
retread of episode four.
That's not to say solo doesn't have
moments of fun,
but that's really the best thing you
could say about it and hey,
if that's what you're looking for,
it's a good time.
But in our opinion,
Disney could have done better by
delivering an intriguing character
rather than relying on Cipa Pilsen a
soldier in the form of endless Easter
eggs.
But that's our take.
Leave us yours in the comments below.
On the other hand,
if you'd rather work hard for your
dopamine hits,
see if you can solve this riddle.
If I were to tell you that the combined
area of the blue triangles is 25 and the
five red squares are identical,
what does the area of the entire shape
pull out some scrap paper if you need
it.
This brainteaser comes from
brilliant.org.
The site that helps you deeply
understand math and science.
Perfect for numbers people,
regular people and Mon Calamari,
like if you're into neuroscience like I
am,
they've got a great module and
artificial neural networks which are
like real neural networks,
but our official,
they've also got an awesome section on
engineering,
which is something that kind of makes me
want to go back to school one more time
to become an engineer.
The checkout brilliant to
brilliant.org/wise
crack and sign up for free.
The first 200 people to click the link
will also get 20 percent off the annual
premium subscription.
By clicking the link,
you can also get access to the solution.
So what should we look at the science of
next?
Drop me a line in the comments till next
time Helen.
Apt.
And may the force be with you.