This video is sponsored by loot crate,
the monthly subscription service for
epic Geek and Gamer items and pop
culture gear.
More on Luke crate at the end of the
video.
[inaudible]
Hey,
wisecrack jared here.
If you've been listening to our self
park podcast,
respect our authortalk.
You know,
we've been low key obsessed with a
really interesting problem south park is
facing this year.
How do you make social satire when
reality is already so absurd and
interviews?
Matt and Trey have noted that liberals
and conservatives frequently praise the
same episodes.
Each thinking of the show has secretly
sided with them.
Then after season 20 was all been
railroaded by the 2016 election.
Oh Jeez.
This doesn't look very fun.
They made a new valve.
Avoid trump related narratives.
We don't want to be CNN.
They told the independent,
but with divisive politics dominating
our national discourse.
Can a show that prides itself on not
taking sides continue to stay relevant
judging by their latest episode,
which manages to take a stance without
resorting to partisan talking points?
The answer is absolute.
In fact,
this episode is one of my favorite
indictments of trump on television and
quite possibly one of the most nuanced.
Of course,
that's not to say they have anything
uplifting to say because if there's any
one consistent message this season,
it's that well,
we're all to death.
Let's make this country great again.
Welcome this wise crack quick take on
South Park's doubling down and as always
spoilers ahead.
But first a quick recap.
Heidi once again tries to end things
with Eric probably for something petty.
Cogni or foreign pushed me in front of a
car.
As always,
he ugly cries and emotionally blackmail,
sir and just staying with him after
watching cartman continue to abuse.
Heidi Kyle makes it his duty to rescue
her.
It is our problem and eventually
realizes he's fallen for her.
Meanwhile,
Paul Ryan,
Mitch Mcconnell and Mike Pence try to
stand up to the president,
but garrison gives them a little taste
of his signature.
Can people to death.
Hope you brought some condoms after some
illicit courtship Heidi dumps cartman
gets with Kyle and carbon vows to take
revenge on his least favorite too.
Things seem to be looking up for Heidi
until her friends make her feel like
forever dating carbon in the first
place.
All the,
I told you,
so's make Heidi feel hurt and resentful,
causing her to double down on carbon.
Who presumably gives her an offscreen
lecture about the merits of
antisemitism.
It's hard to know for that.
People are always trying to get ahead
covered in blankets and bruises.
Pence,
Ryan and Mcconnell commemorate
garrison's first anniversary.
Yes.
As president and garrison reassures them
that the next three years will be even
worse.
What's so brilliant about this episode
is how the A and b plots parallel each
other.
The main gist is just as Heidi is in an
abusive relationship with Cartman,
so two are trump supporters in an
abusive relationship with trump.
The parallel is hinted at early in the
episode through subtly coded language.
Kyle wondering why Heidi staying with
Cartman asks,
she's still supporting him.
She loves him,
I guess,
but he clearly sucks.
Really sucks.
Whatever was going on
here are his wording is deliberately
identical to be stock language.
Critics used to question why trump
voters continue to support him.
Kyle.
Then straight up ask tidy what the deal
is and here's where the parallel falls
perfectly into place.
It turns out Heidi Hartmann,
like president garrison are about to
celebrate their one year
bursary.
I know you and Carmen have an
anniversary coming up and I just
wondering,
you've known him.
How do you think he's doing?
Has a boyfriend?
Kyle presses the point,
again,
using language perfectly suited to
trumps.
Some of us are thinking that maybe he's
not super qualified to be with you
here.
Kyle was pretty clearly playing the role
of a liberal reporter interviewing a
trump supporter.
One of the things about carbon that you
find remotely redeeming this approach
does not prove very tactful and Heidi
doubles down on Cartman.
Great.
You don't know what Eric's like when
we're alone.
He's actually really good to me.
Later in the episode we see the exact
same exchange in a more familiar
context.
Speaker Ryan,
it's the anniversary of the president
being elected.
How do you think he's doing well?
What do you mean he's great?
We're doing great.
A lot of people judge him and just see
the negative.
People don't know how great the
president can be behind closed doors.
The irony becomes layered when just as
kyle uses political polling lingo to
talk about Cartman Paul Ryan starts
using language associated with domestic
abuse to protect trump
and is that semen on your black art?
Oh Nah,
I tripped on a tornado.
That's just,
that's thrown up.
Come
later.
Heidi finally admits to kyle that she
may have made a mistake here.
Again,
her description of falling for cartman
sounds like the description reporters
use to explain how the white working
class voter fail for trump.
Before we started going out,
he was in a really bad place.
I felt pushed away by society.
Famous guy came along who told me all
the things I wanted to hear it.
We'll just wait with it.
Does that make me a bad person
here?
Kyle helpfully points out how cartman
like trump constantly plays the victim
to when sympathy.
No run.
We see ourselves as the victim
sometimes,
but carbon sees himself as the victim
all the time.
Meanwhile,
Heidis essentially the perfect stand in
for the regretful trump voter who really
doesn't want to admit he was wrong.
I don't know how I'm going to face
people with funding and we give up.
This culminates in a beautiful montage
that essentially sums up the episode
eight dejected.
Heidi evaluates her relationship and the
took her job's dudes cry watching trump
on TV.
The message is clear.
Heidi represents the white working class
voter who is struggling to accept that
banking on trump was a mistake,
but a glimmer of hope appears for both
Heidi and the Republican leadership
respectively.
A healthy relationship with kyle and
garrison's dismal poll numbers.
We'll republican leaders and high he be
able to escape their cycles of abuse,
not so as garrison says,
see,
I know something about societal
psychology that you three turd balls
down,
everything's gonna be fine.
What is garrison talking about first to
preface,
something unique about South Park is the
nuanced way it critiques liberals.
Whereas due to the general liberal
politics of Hollywood,
most satirical shows tend to mock
conservatives.
That trend has been particularly true in
the past year when snl and others
doubled down on trump theme lampoon or
of course these shows are unlikely to
resonate with even a vaguely regretful
trump voter.
This climate is part of what has made
Matt and Trey reluctant to constantly
take easy shots at trump or his
supporters this season,
which brings us to the dinner with Heidi
and her pouch who bombard her with an
array of smug jokes about cartman's
racism and sociopathic tendencies.
Ultimately all these antiques do is put
Heidi on the defensive,
making her feel stupid.
Matt and Trey seem to be critiquing the
way Hollywood has essentially declared
open season on trump and his supporters.
This is most clearly expressed through.
Kyle will often acts as the metal voice
of reason for the show.
You guys shouldn't criticize her so much
for going with carton.
Why not?
You're in Kirby's non verbal person
trust yet he carved as much as any of
you,
but just give her some space.
You know,
you can't keep saying we told you sell
it because if you make her feel dumb,
she just doubles down and tries to prove
towards south and it wasn't done.
Here are the show
professors unambiguous disdain for
trunk,
but seems to be urging the liberal media
to be less condescending toward trump
voters.
Less eager to feel smug and say,
I told you so.
The girls should have heated kyle's
warning because their comments during
dinner made Heidi run right back to
carbon.
I think maybe I am just stupid and I
don't know what I want and it ends up
partying.
People.
No,
you need to know something.
None of this is your fault
at this moment and isolated,
insecure Heidi is prime to believe
whatever radical,
bigoted garbage carbon wants to serve
up,
presumably like the voters she's come to
represent and a surprisingly well
quaffed kyle is in for a surprise.
Just as trump has convinced his base to
blame the left for everything that goes
wrong with his presidency.
Carmen is convinced Heidi to make kyle
her well,
Jewish scape goat.
You can't help it.
It's how you were raised,
what you were tying.
My heritage is Irish,
so I'm prone to being moody and your
heritage.
You know,
you can be a little sneaky sometimes and
not even realize it.
Now a word on this episode's treatment
of antisemitism.
Of course,
Jew jokes have been carbons,
bread and butter since before Kenny's
first death.
Yeah.
Hi.
Okay.
Yeah,
you'll have that by got Kobe fat.
This episode felt a little different.
Hardy's final speech to kyle is pretty
shocking.
It's not loaded with the usual overt
punchlines.
All we get is kyle looking pretty
devastating.
Dude,
did she just call me a dirty Jew?
South Park's mockery of antisemites has
never looked so dark,
which may be the shows way
of acknowledging how fundamentally
different Hartman's character sounds
since the rise of the alt right has
southpark consciously graduated from
goofy,
childish bigotry to genuinely ugly
bigotry.
It seems like it.
In the meanwhile,
things are worse than ever.
Heidi is now completely controlled by
Cartman and the Republicans and the
nation are going to get with an even
bigger strap on.
Things are looking pretty bleak,
but what do you guys think?
We'll regretful trump voters be shamed
right back into his voting base or even
worse.
Is there any hope for Heidi Paul Ryan or
any of us?
Let us know what you think in the
comments.
And if you love to hate cartman or just
love South Park,
checkout loot crate for less than 20
bucks a month.
Loot crate sends you geek and Gamer
collectibles and apparel right to your
door.
It's the best place to go for monthly
swag from your favorite franchises like
southpark and when you enter the code
wise crack you'll get 10% off a new
subscription.
The November loot crate team is unite
2.0
celebrating all the stuff we can do
better when we work together.
It's packed full of items from overwatch
power rangers DC and more.
You won't want to miss this crate.
You only have until the 19th at 9:00
PM Pacific time to sign up and receive
this unite 2.0
crate.
So don't wait to join the team and get
10% off with the code wise crack.
Click here or check out the link in the
description to head over to [inaudible]
dot com slash wise crack to nab those
exclusive items from those powerful
franchise.
Thanks to loot crate for sponsoring this
video and as always,
catch you all next time.
Peace.