This video is sponsored by skillshare.
Stick around to find out how you can get
three months of skillshare for just
ninety nine cents a wise crack.
Jared here,
it may be the new year,
but we've still got a massive hangover
from 2017 final blockbuster,
right?
A film that left us cross eyed and
confused.
Netflix spent $90,
million dollars combining two of our
favorite things,
the dystopian fantasy and the buddy cop
and left us with the world's most
expensive WTF.
We've been scratching our heads trying
to figure out how such an awesome
concept.
Think rush hour too.
If the deathly hallows or lethal weapon
of the rings ended up feeling as biggest
show as David Ayers last movie.
Sorry,
I couldn't help it.
Like other fantasy films,
it seems to be using it's imaginary
setting to tell a compelling story while
also illuminating truths about our
society.
However,
both its plot and any potential
underlying meaning become completely
muddled by the films.
Poor world-building,
lousy character development and ill
suited metaphors about American racial
politics.
So let's find out what happened in this
week's [inaudible] condition on bright,
what went wrong,
and if you liked this sort of thing,
there's more where this came from in our
movie podcast.
Show me the meaning,
links in the description,
and be sure to check it out.
And as always,
major,
minor and vaguely judgmental spoilers
ahead.
Headscratcher number one,
building the world.
Every time you see a film,
you're asked to take a leap of faith and
accept some kind of proposition that
loving parents occasionally leave their
youngest child behind when they go on
vacation or that Keanu reeves is the
most bad ass assassin ever.
But when you're watching a fantasy that
plays with gravity,
object permanence or the entertainment
potential of a piece of furniture,
filmmakers have to convince you to take
a mountain everest size leap off a peak
of disbelief and land with their
characters in a distant galaxy,
middle earth or a far away distant land
inside a wardrobe.
A good script gets the audience to buy
into its world by explaining the rules
of that world coherently and concisely
and getting the heck on with the story.
Think of how effective Lord of the rings
is in briefing the audience on the
history of middle Earth's most sought
after jewelry
with the forging of the great rings.
Three were given to the elks,
seven to the dwarf loads,
and nine,
nine rings were gifted to the race of
men,
but they will,
all of them to see for another ring was
made.
I'm mastering to control all others.
One ring to rule them all
with an origin story clocking in at six
minutes.
That film situates US firmly in this
complex world for it even leaner
example,
consider star wars epic rolling title
card that introduces you to an
intergalactic space war in the time it
takes to unwrap a candy bar.
Both films Orient the audience quickly
and then they're off to the races.
Brights,
origin story.
On the other hand,
it's just plain messy to voltage and
sloppy,
repetitive yet in complete fragments,
but before we analyze the world building
strategies,
a brief overview of the mythology behind
bright 2000 years ago,
something gnarly went down with a dark
Lord.
All your excited with him except this
one ORC Gerard,
who somehow united the nine races
together and who are the nine races.
While it's not exactly clear,
we've got the elves,
humans or fairies and for the eagle eyed
viewers,
but anyway,
they managed to take down the dark lord
except oops.
Ease ready to come back and all his
demons,
Elvis need to do is bring three ones
together.
Watch out though.
Only a bright can hold a one which
creates complications still.
Even if the dark Ford does rise,
he can be stopped with magic.
That whole subplot never comes to
fruition though.
Probably to be saved for the recently
greenlit sequel that will hopefully come
with some clarification now.
It's totally understandable that the
minds behind Brian wanted to veer away
from the dramatically narrated storybook
style opener of Lord of the rings.
It's not exactly the freshest turf in
the screen writing world or it would be
understandable if bright hadn't started
out with an equally cheesy but less
eloquent quote.
That sounds like it came out of a 10
year old's dungeons and dragons game.
From there,
they have an opening sequence of
cringeworthy tagging.
You would think with $90,000,000
they can afford to hire a decent la
graffiti artists.
Through this we learned there's
interspecies upheaval,
police brutality and lizard people
roaming the streets.
You know,
it's pretty rude to tease the existence
of Lizard people and not the liver,
but I digress.
These shots of the street explained some
atmospheric aspects of the film's world,
but we're still missing the cold hard
facts.
For instance,
who is the dark lord and what did he do
and why are all the social media
influencers,
elves.
We weren't the only people scratching
our heads either after fans expressed
widespread confusion as to what the heck
was going on with all this dark lord
stuff.
Netflix released what amounted to a two
minute instruction manual for the film
and it's we're given a few thousand
years of magical history with factual
nuggets like Jurek was hailed as the
first,
but if Dirac saved everyone,
why do people hate orange so damn much?
And how did this world social order come
about?
This video feels more like a hastily
concocted admission of guilt that this
film was confusing as hell.
Another world building issue is the way
the film conveys the limited information
it does tell the audience which brings
us to a fundamental screen writing rule
showing versus telling.
Showing is when a film conveys
information through characters.
Actions telling is when characters chat
about the events of the world,
the narrative equivalent of an Intel
briefing for the audience,
and boy is bright a telephone for route.
The film characters regularly serve as
embedded narrators,
a strategy that swallows the action and
create stiff,
unrealistic dialogue.
For instance,
the award for worst line in the film
goes to wards daughter in this cringy.
Everybody hates please.
Okay,
we get it.
Another prime example comes from ward
early on.
Hey,
look,
I got to do to my car.
The whole world is watching.
All right.
I didn't ask for it.
I don't want it,
but I don't get a vote.
First of all,
this speech is stupendously heavy
handed.
Nobody talks like this.
Secondly,
these facts can be shown in a natural
way through the narrative.
In fact,
Ward makes it pretty clear he'd rather
be done by a ferry than right to work
alongside Jacoby,
so I'm in a phase where he just shut up.
Don't say anything,
just draw out a word.
Still.
The winner for the most forest proxy
narrator has to be the smelly sword.
Wielding bum who goes from trying to
Samurai,
a crowd of people to calmly relaying the
entire world's backstory without even a
shower break.
Nine races shoulder to shoulder to give
you the world you neglect the.
Now,
the dark one returned to reclaim our
carts.
Then as the feds interrogate him,
he gives a plotting explanation of the
shield of light in Fernie wands.
The dark Lord Layla Tika,
and write this scene is a boring and b
doesn't make sense unless you assume
federal agents in charge of magic crime
are Asfa confused by the rules of their
world as we are.
This strategy continues throughout the
film wants to and ward,
find the magic one and call for backup
for skeezy.
Cops show up and give us another forced
lecture on how magic works.
That's magic right there.
That's whatever you want.
You want a million dollars,
10 million,
you want to be taller or shorter,
make it bigger.
You want to go back in time and marry
the girl who didn't blow you on prom
night.
That's how you do it right there.
They continue to narrate the plot as it.
The audience would be absolutely
flummoxed by the concept of dirty cops,
so it's thrilling.
Two cops die tonight.
It's clearly done for the audience's
sake and it's Corny as hell.
The scripts spooned feeds us.
Huge plot points and small details
alike.
Like when Ward Jacobian Tika are fleeing
the Mexican gang and ward yells,
windows up.
Bulletproof.
Is he patronizing Jacoby or the audience
who even knows just for fun,
they remind us.
Needless Exposition,
head.
Sometimes this tire,
some exposition manages to somehow be
both forced and and complete.
For instance,
Jacoby gives a snooze inducing and
scattered explanation of his orchid idle
Jeruk chemos who changed the world.
Okay.
And
they raised their place to him.
He was flooded in that very moment.
Okay,
so Dirac was a former farmer who was.
Wait,
what was that?
Flooded
in that very moment.
Okay.
Seriously,
what is the deal with this flooding
thing?
He's out.
He's like a finger that got cut off the
hand.
He's dead to us.
Jacoby who is not flooded explains that.
It's a sign of honor in the community.
What you did tonight.
That's what it takes for an org to get
blooded,
an active,
great bravery.
So are we supposed to think that all
these other orcs are brave except
Jacoby,
the one who professionally puts his life
in harm's way and what does blooding
even mean?
Jacoby sad dental situation as compared
to his brother and it's definitely tooth
related.
We finally get a peek at this blooding
ritual at the end of the film after
Jacoby Saves Ward and the same orcs who
only half an hour ago killed him slip
their palms because apparently clan
loyalty means never having to say you're
sorry.
Hey,
least that's showing,
not telling.
So Goldstar.
If only we understood what the heck is
going on or how this crowd of orcs knew
that Jacobi had just committed an act of
bravery.
Is there some kind of work bat signal?
Are they just following Jacoby all
night,
waiting to shed blood,
which would magically give jacoby the
perfect or smile on the bright side.
The next day.
Jacoby does appear to be teething on his
new fangs moving onto head scratcher.
Number two,
hero Shamiro.
Whether you're writing about outer space
downtown Baltimore or a wizarding school
in an English castle,
the first ingredient of a good story is
a hero or two or three in bright.
We have ward and Jacoby and neither will
undergo significant character
development over the course of the film.
Ward begins the film as a snarky
dickhead.
Well,
if you in a box,
I'll probably be like more song
and ends the film as a snarky dickhead
dog.
Now you blooded,
Huh?
Jacoby begins as a toothless,
insecure guy who can't stand up for
himself.
Hold.
Can you make a shootout?
Awkward.
Sorry.
And ends.
The film has a slightly tooth guy who
ward still treats like a tattooed
forrest gump thing.
The nice federal agents.
Thank you.
Beyond that,
for a film centered on an unlikely
friendship,
their relationship also seems pretty
stagnant.
At best,
it could be said that ward learns to
tolerate Jacobi and not narc on him,
which is pretty bleak as far as buddy
films go.
It's not surprising.
They never changed because they never
really had character journeys to begin
with.
He number one rule in making a
compelling hero according to Aaron
Sorkin,
is that somebody's gotta want something.
Something's got to be standing in the
way of getting it.
You do that and you have a seat.
Eventually you'll have a movie to
Westley wants Princess Buttercup,
Ferris bueller wants to cut class and
party and so on and bright,
not so much or doesn't appear to
actively want anything except maybe to
lose Jacoby as his partner and keep his
job without being a corrupt asshole.
That said he doesn't pursue those goals
in any meaningful way.
Jacoby does want to be blooded,
but as explained earlier,
we don't really understand what the heck
being blooded is or what it means for
him as a character.
Does he have to submit the clan loyalty
to hang out with those Miami orcs?
I mean,
they seemed fun.
While a,
what makes a hero initially compelling
the heroes choices or what makes it
characters stay compelling,
apparently Dustin Hoffman won't even
sign onto a movie unless his character
has no less than 40 points of choice in
the script.
Rather than 40 points of choice,
our main guy's face approximately 40
points of coincidence that saved their
butts.
Such a coincidence is called a deus ex
machina or a person or thing that
appears suddenly and provides a
contrived solution to and apparently
insoluble difficulty.
Most notable among these is the one in
one instance,
the wan solves the inconvenience of
Jacoby dying in another awards,
totally random status as a bright turns,
what would have been an act of suicide
into a semi heroic,
a 100 percent coincidental fee.
Now for a head scratcher.
Number three,
when a metaphor is a train wreck,
bright is littered with unsubtle
metaphors comparing interspecies
discrimination with real world racial
discrimination.
Even chance the rapper are called the
metaphor a little shallow.
We more than a little degree,
but before we take a deep dive into the
meanings at play,
we want to give the following.
Disclaimer,
yes,
this is a fictional world in which nine
races coexist with varying levels of
friction.
Maybe the filmmakers had no intention of
it being read as a precise metaphor for
American racial politics.
Problem is the movie practically begs
you to draw this comparison.
Where's the diversity hire you ride
with?
First off,
it's a film about cops set in La,
a city that was home to one of the
country's most violent race riots ever.
One which was specifically ignited by
police violence towards black folks.
Bright,
very deliberately draws comparisons
between orcs and black Americans in ways
that are too obvious to ignore from the
graffiti to the urban street,
wear visual adaptations of black culture
about their marginalized by other races
in society and face victimization at the
hands of the police in truly
sophisticated symbolism.
The films that just the cops would
definitely kill the hooded or
and the troops are coming up.
Humans with gone looking for new.
Who shot a cop.
You pick that kid had a chance
just for fun.
One ORC tells Jacoby your buddies,
so happy to say he's got an ORC friend.
Not knowing that ward very dramatically
doesn't do friends.
You don't want me as a friend.
Oh Jeez,
dude,
save it for your art therapist.
That metaphor is referenced most
disturbingly when Jacoby is hung by a
rope during a fight scene with an Elf.
I don't need to spell out why.
Putting a character that has been
signified as black in this situation is
more than a little messed up.
Oh,
and one very important distinction
between ORCS and black Americans.
ORCS apparently caused their oppression
or at least their great,
great,
great grand daddies did when they
decided to side with the dark Lord Lord,
a long time ago,
and navient paid for it ever since.
Needless to say,
real racial prejudice does not work that
way.
I eat black Americans have zero sins to
pay for.
When you're making a metaphor about
race,
it's important to be very,
very precise because there's a real
danger that an ill conceived metaphor
can muddle an already complicated
conversation to understand why.
Let's examine the cognitive function of
metaphors in there.
Influential book metaphors.
We live by scholars,
George Lakoff and Mark Johnson explained
that metaphors are vital to human beings
understanding of the world around us.
That's because metaphors are a way of
taking a human's understanding of a
simple,
often physically tangible concept and
transferring that understanding onto
another poor,
complicated concept,
often one hidden from our senses or
difficult to explain,
play golf and Johnson.
Are you then when we make a metaphor,
say,
comparing madness to love.
We're not just momentarily linking to
ideas.
We're also transferring an extensive
array of our cognitive associations
about what constitutes madness onto
love.
As a result,
a human struggling to write a Valentine
card can explain why they have
butterflies in their belly.
As a result,
metaphors may create realities for us,
especially social realities leading us
to view the metaphor as being true.
So in this case,
lovers be cray.
So what does all this have to do with
fictional orcs?
When a film like bright unsubtly evokes
a metaphor that transfers the viewer's
understanding of the inhuman orcs onto
black Americans,
they inherently invite the possibility
that viewers will transfer all their
cognitive associations about what
constitutes orcs,
a race of homogenous,
inarticulate,
tattooed gangsters onto that of the
extremely complex and most importantly,
human group of black Americans.
It's not like bright is going to
radically harm race relations,
but this practice does place it
somewhere in an ugly history of American
cinema comparing people of color to
inhuman creatures.
Before we go further into this,
it's important to address the colorblind
elephant in the room.
Bright depicts a world where a black man
of wards status can exist seemingly
without facing bigotry or to quote
chance the rapper.
Racism has gone because we hate ORC.
Now that's messed up more so even when
you couple it with wards,
treatment of marginalized creatures,
all of which have OIC treatment of black
Americans by police officers.
Whether he's saying very lives don't
matter today or watching a bunch of orcs
get beat up.
Then asking Jacoby Your Cup first.
It just feels odd in a country where
violence against black men by police
officers remains heartbreakingly common
depicting a black cop this way just
feels way,
way off the mark wards.
Character seems to be there to both
protect the film against charges of
racism because how can a movie be racist
when it shows a black man as equal and
even getting to be racist himself and
make a backwards argument about how far
black America has come through an
individual representation of a black man
who's made it and earned respect.
Now back to the specifics of the films
depiction of Orcs,
which makes it even more.
While Jacoby is an honorable guy with a
working moral compass.
His depiction is not particularly
flattering for starters,
and there's no easy way to say this.
Jacoby is not the sharpest,
most painfully obvious near the end of
the film would Jacobi cannot stop
spilling incriminating evidence to the
two federal agents turn turned around,
just rocked the film.
Doesn't make it better when ward tells
his daughter.
All of the races are different.
While there is something to be said for
respecting ethnic and cultural
differences,
wards comments seemed to suggest the
existence of actual biological racial
differences to have mad,
Huh?
Excuse me.
Her,
the
detective.
How many dogs play pro basketball?
None.
They're slow.
They're heavy.
That's why half the NFL defensive lines.
It's not racist to physics.
Yes,
they're fictional characters who are
literally have different species,
but the metaphor is still evokes black
Americans and it feels plain weird.
That coupled with Jacoby's clear
inability to match words,
intellect which falls into the trap of
evoking hundreds of years of junk,
racist biology that tried to excuse
racism on the grounds that people of
color were intellectually inferior.
At the same time giving orcs,
they super strong sense of smell gives
them an animalistic quality.
That again makes the metaphor super
ugly,
particularly when you consider the
hundreds of years of white Americans
treating black Americans like sub human
beings as lakoff and Johnson explained
what is it?
Issue is not the truth or falsity of a
metaphor,
but the perceptions and inferences that
follow from it and the actions that are
sanctioned by it.
Metaphors like the one in bright in
comparing people of color to in human
beings are up even if they had good
intentions and as lake often Johnson
explained,
we define our reality in terms of
metaphors and then proceed to act though
it makes some superficial points about
tolerance and encourages the audience to
empathize with Jacoby's experience of
marginalization,
abusive friendships and kick me signs.
Brights overarching metaphor is just
plain sloppy brights.
Let us down,
but given our world of inevitable
sequels,
prequels,
three goals and squeak walls,
we suspect elves and orcs.
We'll be duking it out on your favorite
streaming platform for years to come and
we're not mad at it.
Netflix has a cool concept to work with
and in case you haven't heard a
disgusting amount of dough to throw at
it.
So here's to hoping the cql gives us
something special.
Thanks for watching.
Everybody pays.
Wise practice with the new year upon us.
There's never been a better time to set
some resolutions and pick up some new
skills,
so head on over to skillshare to get
started.
Skill shares and online learning
community where for less than $10 a
month,
you can access expert lead courses in
just about any field you can think of.
Want to learn the basic screen writing
techniques that might have saved will
Smith's character arc or pick up the
design principles that may have given
the orcs a bit more of an interesting
look.
Skill shares got you covered,
more than 18,000
courses and everything from writing to
photography,
business,
entrepreneurship and more and through
the end of January,
you can get your first three months of
Skillshare,
Ford,
and ninety nine cents.
Just follow the link in the description
to l dot ssh slash wise,
crack 99 and get your discount today.
Don't be shy.
Let us know about all the cool things
you learn and as always,
be sure to subscribe and ring that bell
so you won't miss what you've got coming
next.
We've got episodes on American psycho,
Captain America,
civil war,
and tons more on the way.
You won't want to miss it as always,
catch you all next time.