This episode is brought to you by Wix to
easily build your own website for free,
had to wix.com/wise
crack.
Hey guys,
Michael here are some known in the
office,
the bad boy of 19th century Danish
philosophy scholarship.
You probably already know two of the
things we love rambling about most it
wisecrack are superheroes and
philosophy.
So today we're going to take a look at
two films that are full of superheroes
and big philosophical questions.
The incredibles and incredibles.
Two since the release of the incredibles
films,
there has been much digital ink spill
over its philosophical themes with much
of it pulling around.
One idea,
namely that the incredibles is making an
argument for objectivism,
a philosophical theory developed by
novelists.
I N rant advocates for this reading
point to the emphasis on the
exceptionalism of the supers and the
implied critique of Egalitarian Society
has evidence and while we see where
they're coming from,
if the time comes,
you'll know what to do,
it's in your blood.
We also think they're wrong.
While there is undoubtedly some
objective is colored to the films.
They're true philosophical importance is
the way in which they consider the
question of power from the moral
responsibility of having superpowers to
fans going insane due to a desire for
power to the power and influence of the
media.
These films posed questions that are as
pertinent now as they were in 2004 and
this time we agree with you.
Kanye,
welcome to this wisecrack addition on
the philosophy of the incredibles and of
course spoilers ahead.
But before we get to that,
uh,
Mr incredible size,
thank you to our sponsor.
Weeks gives you the superpower to make
beautiful,
robust websites.
You don't have to get bitten by a
radioactive web designer anymore.
Thank God with utility belt that
includes custom domains,
enhanced security,
and infinite design possibilities.
Wix equips you to crank out websites in
a snap,
doesn't wipe out half the universe.
Best part is,
it's absolutely free to get started.
More in that at the end of the video.
And now back to the fantastic four,
I mean the incredibles.
First.
A quick recap in the first movie,
Mr.
Incredible scorned.
Former fan buddy wants to be a soup,
but since he's a normie he decides to
use technology to kill them all.
Instead taking on the villainous
persona.
I am here buddy plans to use Mr
incredible to optimize his own personal
death machine.
The Omni drove once perfected.
He plans to defeat it in public so that
society will see him as a hero and
eventually he can sell his technology as
a product so that everyone can become
super.
And as we all know,
everyone super,
no one will be Mr.
Incredible fuels,
neutered and aimless as a result of the
superhero relocation program.
But what are you waiting for?
Yeah,
I mean two kid and secretly returns to
the superhero game to curb and impending
midlife crisis.
He even questions the point of the
egalitarian spirit of dashes elementary
school.
It's not a graduation is moving from the
fourth grade to the fifth grade
ceremony.
It's psychotic.
They keep creating new ways to celebrate
mediocrity.
But if someone is genuinely exceptional,
then you bob.
But he eventually comes full circle as
he realizes that his power isn't just
for feeling like a bad ass.
But instead makes him responsible for
the good of society.
In this parable about power,
we see that great power unchecked by
great responsibility leads to very bad
things.
Incredibles two continues this
exploration of power,
but shifts the focus to the considerable
influence of two media moguls,
prestige,
a no,
not those media moguls.
These ones,
the brother Winston devore is a lifelong
superhero fan who wants to use his media
influence and his seemingly endless
piles of money to repair the supers,
broken public image and change the laws
so that they are legal again,
while his sister Evelyn wants to use set
it influenced to mind control supers
into doing horrible things,
thus ruining their public image and
ensuring that people don't put faith in
them ever again.
All right,
so in order to discern why the film has
been read through the lens of
Objectivism,
we need to first figure out what in the
hell is objective isn't the basic
tenants of Randy and objectivism are
one.
The ability of human reason to gain
objective knowledge of reality to the
moral aim of human life is to seek
personal happiness.
Three man's being is heroic in nature
and for that free market,
deregulated capitalism is the socio
economic system most suitable for this
happy heroism.
So basically the philosophy of Ron
Swanson,
this man is a failure.
He is not up to snuff.
His business was failing and you're
bailing it out.
This is a bailout and I don't like it.
We might usually associate heroism with
those who use their powers to help
others,
but for rand,
a captain of industry is a better
example as they're the ones who make the
world better simply by willing their own
power and proving their superiority.
Randy and super heroes don't wear capes
but rather neatly press suits with
Italian shoes and gold plated cufflinks.
Now,
according to a whole bunch of writers,
this is just the sort of philosophy we
find in the incredibles.
Normal Society represents the
meaningless egalitarianism,
which tells us that everyone is special
and that it's bad to be exceptional.
The supers represent randy and heroes
frustrated by society's obsession with
fairness and equality.
Only when they are able to don their
mask and tights.
Are they able to will their own power
and find happiness in their own
strength.
But rather than advocating for
objectivism,
these films shine a light on the types
of problems that come from this
inherently selfish philosophy.
Through the failures of both [inaudible]
and Evelyn,
they explore a number of interesting
philosophical ideas and relationship to
power and responsibility.
If anything,
the films may be an exploration of what
happens when keeping it rand goes wrong.
So let's start by taking a look at the
first film.
As we mentioned,
many of the incredibles as objectivist
proponent's point to the characters
frustrations with the inhibition of
their exceptional nature.
Bob Can't use his powers to stop muggins
and instead professionally ruined the
lives of old ladies.
Then there's dash who can't try out for
sports less t go all USAIN bolt on his
classmates
generally set her powers are nothing to
be shutting down.
Our parents made us special.
Everyone is special dash,
which is another way of saying no.
Yes.
And while we see how examples of
people's exceptional nature being
suppressed by society can be read as
objectivist,
it ignores some clues to the contrary.
First of all,
the insurance companies sucks,
and Mr Incredibles boss is a monster who
only cares about profit.
Tell me how you're keeping ensure a care
in the black.
Help me how that's possible,
but you were writing checks for every
Harry hard luck and Sally Tom Story that
gives you a phone call.
This of course,
makes him an ideal candidate for a randy
and hero,
but there's no evidence that he's
anywhere close to a sympathetic
character.
I'm that happy Bob,
not happy.
Most importantly,
this reading ignores Bob's moral
journey,
which can be best understood with the
help of the Greek philosopher aristotle,
who's super power was getting millions
of undergrads to read his boring books
for thousands of years.
When bob first shoves his middle aged
body back into a suit and gets back into
the game,
he does indeed exemplify the type of
selfish exceptionalism that rand lauded
as heroic.
He starts to care more about his secret
superhero missions than he does his own
family.
Selfishly prioritizing his own power and
the pleasure it brings.
So if you stop the movie after half an
hour,
then shore.
Mr Incredible is an objectivist and the
whole movie is one big o to iron rand's
philosophy,
but for those of us who finish the
movie,
we see that Mr incredible is simply
beginning of moral journey in which he
learns about the true purpose of having
great power.
In his lectures on ethics,
aristotle tells us what it means to live
a moral and happy life,
but before giving us the answers,
he warns us of some of the common
temptations that keep us from true
happiness,
namely pleasure,
money,
and power.
Coincidentally,
all of these are essential components of
objective is happiness.
Much like trying to understand bitcoin.
Aristotle thinks our moral journey
should consist of an endless pursuit
without a steaming end.
After all pleasurable activities
eventually get boring.
Money is only for other stuff and never
really makes us happy.
And power is often dependent on factors
outside our control.
Mr Incredible seems to fall into a
devil's threeway of moral temptation as
is super secret superhero activities.
Bring him pleasure,
make him feel powerful and throw some
extra o's in his bank account along the
way,
like a good randy in hero in this false
happiness.
He's experiencing pleasure from his own
power,
which is sort of like masturbating you a
picture of yourself and according to a a
friend of mine,
you can't come back from that.
Now of course,
Mr incredible is only drawn back into
his super self via the trickery of his
old fan buddy now acting as syndrome and
while buddy wanted nothing more than to
be mister incredibles faithful sidekick
when he was younger,
this fixation on power has turned his
fandom and a near psychotic obsession
after all,
I am your biggest fan buddy has
structured his happiness and his moral
goals around this pursuit of power.
He wants power so badly that it needs to
destroy the supers to prove to himself
and the world that he has an ultimate
source of power and this does not end
well as at one point buddy doesn't seem
to give a crap when Mr incredible almost
kills his assistant Mirage.
That sounds a little dark for you.
Now go ahead.
If she was an objectivist before this
encounter,
she's throwing out her copy of atlas
shrugged afterwards.
On the flip side,
when Mr Incredibles pursuit of personal
power puts his family in harm's way,
he realizes that his power is only moral
when it's actively used in the service
of others.
I'm not strong.
I'm strong enough and this will make you
strong.
Goodness.
No,
it's what they see is some sort of work.
Alec camp use you again,
whether these others be as family or the
innocent citizens of Metro Hill.
This stands in stark contrast with
rands.
Insistence that one's personal happiness
leads to the greatest good,
I swear by my life and my love of it,
but I will never live for the sake of
whatever law nor ask another to live,
and it's this that distinguishes buddy
from Mr.
Incredible.
An incredible too.
It seems as if a couple of objectivist
captains of industry might just be the
saviors of supers everywhere.
As the second film finds the incredibles
both broke and without government
protection.
These two hyper capitalist Winston and
Evelyn Endeavor are set to make
everything better with their financial
resources and media influence.
For a moment,
it seems that the powers of industry
might just save the day.
And Randy,
in terms the devore siblings are titans
of industry ready to get what they want.
I.
E fulfill their own happiness via the
most powerful force in modern society.
The media as a childhood superhero nerd
all grown up.
Winston wants to use his media influence
to literally change the law so that he
can get what he wants,
which is a world full of cool
superheroes to idolize.
And though Evelyn might initially seem
on board with their brothers plans,
she intends to use her tech empire to
make sure that supers go extinct as she
has spent her entire life blaming them
for the loss of her father.
It's revealed in the film that when
burglars broke into their home,
Evelyn and Winston's father waited on
two supers to save him,
but they never showed up and he was
murdered for Evelyn.
Her father's reliance on the supers is
indicative of an inability to take
responsibility for one's own life and
actions.
It's sort of like how all of us who grew
up with spellcheck can't spell calendar
or definitely to save our lives.
Evelyn's desire for self reliance is
very random,
but it's not so kosher that she wants to
stifle the exceptionalism of others.
But while all of these shiny titans of
industry are spending billions to get
what they want,
the villain screen slaver exposes the
dark power of screens.
This resentment of superheroes and their
broader effect on society leads Evelyn
to create screen slaver whose mission is
expressed in a strikingly poignant
manifesto.
Superheroes are part of your brain lists
desired or replace true experience with
simulation.
You don't talk,
you watch talk shows to watch shows,
travel relationships,
risks,
every meaningful experience packaged and
to watch it at a distance.
If much of this sounds eerily true of
our contemporary relationship to
technology,
it's because it is.
Before we know that Evelyn is screen
slaver.
She has a conversation about the ills of
the modern era with Helen in which Helen
agrees with her.
Which of us has the greater influence
which side of Mary you asking the
believer or the cynic cynic would say
selling is more important because the
best sellers have the most buyers.
It doesn't matter what you're selling.
It only matters what people buy.
Now,
while I disciple of rand might argue
that our present digital age has led to
a capitalist utopia in which the right
algorithms can lead to massive wealth
for the exceptional few.
The Moody's explore the effect that this
entertainment driven media has on our
humanity.
To better understand this,
we can turn to 19th century Danish
philosopher Soren Kierkegaard,
who at times was the screen slaver of
his day.
Kierkegaard was worried that the modern
media,
which at that point was the dawn of
print media,
was creating a world devoid of passion
in which reading about the interesting
lives of others was thought to be
equivalent to living an interesting
life,
oneself and align.
That makes me relatively convinced that
he had access to time travel and spent
an afternoon reading sponsored content
on instagram.
Kierkegaard said about his own age that
while they revolutionary age is an age
of action,
the present age is an age of
advertisement and publicity.
Nothing happens,
but there is instantly publicity about
it for both screen slaver and
Kierkegaard,
the media distorts our relationship to
powerful people as rather than lead us
to imitating them in our own lives and
activities,
we settle and become mere spectators.
Kierkegaard was worried that this would
make 19th century Europe devoid of
passion and individuality.
Of course,
this doesn't end well for Evelyn and
eventually the superheroes all come
together and use their collective power
for good.
Both stopping Evelyn's plan and in the
process restoring the world's faith in
the goodness of superheroes.
Notably Winston is pushed to action
during the final act,
not just using his massive resources to
change the world for the better,
but by actually risking his own life to
save the lives of others.
Just like in the first film,
we see that true heroics isn't just
flexing one's power.
It's about doing the right thing at the
right time.
A pull.
One more example from aristotle.
He thought that justice was completed
virtue as true justice is working for
the good of another.
And in this way,
both films show that True Heroes Exhibit
this type of justice as their power is
at its most virtuous when it's used in
service of others.
And we have a final critique of randy
and thought in violence.
Final words during Evelyn's arrest.
Well,
I'm sorry,
she's rich and we'll probably get no
more than a slap on the wrist because at
the end of the day,
Metro Ville is like our own world.
And access to wealth is the ultimate
superpower.
And while Randy and objectivist would
enthusiastically agreed,
violet is pointing out the fundamental
injustice in this type of system.
So there you have it.
What some see as a pair of films at the
Randy and slams are in fact asking
crucial questions about power,
responsibility,
and the forces in our world that have
power over our attention and
imagination.
And just in case you still need to hold
onto some sort of objective truth.
Just listen to what Mr incredible has to
say about math.
Why would they change math?
Math is math is math.
Or if not,
share your own truth with the world by
creating a free website with wix.
Click here to get started.
Building an easy professional looking
website right here.
Thanks for watching guys.
Peace.