Was having a baby this week on thought
nosebleeds,
straight clown and with it by Stephen
King movies.
Gabs bad of me.
No,
you better recognize it's this big ass
book.
Always jumping across two time periods,
but since town like that will be a bit.
I'm going to land on your chronological
age.
Nineteen 57 and it's random balls in the
town of Derry man.
One little shorty George playing with a
paper boat made by his older brother
bill so that both flow into the storm
drain where man,
they got some weird crackheads and
dairy.
Anyway,
George tried to snatch that boat back
from the cloud.
Spray rip him off.
He did three months go by and the boy
named Ben Rolling back to the crib when
hold up that same red nose,
Hayden,
the clown ass.
If you want to grab a balloon and chill
and Ben's tempted,
but he say,
Nah,
I'm straight and the cloud to a damn
mommy and ben like books.
The bench on a duck,
a thug name,
Henry bowers,
and it's cooler gangbangers by laying
low in the barons where you become tight
with homies who also getting their ass
whooped by Henry George older bro.
Bill and his cat,
Ben,
Bill and Addie got already in a dam with
some other young bloods name Richie and
stands rob by.
Turns out most of them is seeing I clown
on the.
So as a girl named beverly and a brother
named Mike together,
all these cats make up the loser's club
and Reggie thinking it's got to be the
ghost and all these little kids and
dairy eventually that recognize the
cloud shacked up in the sewers and
change shape you to some glamour.
Apparently the only way to end that fool
is my busting a mad lib flow of jokes
and rentals while buying on edge tongue.
Oh,
it's called the ritual of June and yeah,
man,
it sounds pretty freaking.
What I like it.
My show loses his daddy's collection of
all those photos.
Now what do you know that clown all up
in those crusty stills,
man,
this dude older than,
Oh damn.
I'm trying to bust out the photo and be
all like break because I'm coming for
you.
Oh,
I don't like this clown man.
Slow the losers.
Do the logical thing and get so high and
tripped balls imagining it crash on
earth.
No,
it's a years ago later it gets even
wider.
When he shape shifts into the moon and
start conversation with Henry bowers,
he slides a blade and say,
Yo daddy and that girl,
beverly got to grow so Shank Papa
bowers.
Get out here.
We get the jump on Bev and while she's
struggling to just watch it go down
without even doing nothing but bev don't
play man.
She kicks him right in the nuts and
bells that go hook up with the losers.
Bill starts getting crunk about how all
the adults don't give a fuck about
what's happening to the kids and dairy,
so data side,
they got to be the ones to pull up on
that beast.
So they grew up and head down to the
sewers.
Thing is Harry and his posse creeping up
from behind,
but it ain't long before it goes cold to
Henry's boys and Henry gets lost for
hours.
I have to record it with an inhaler and
some choice words.
The losers roll up on edge layer and
bill gets his ass lost in some kind of a
void.
And if you think this Jan was trippy
before,
peep this it out.
A giant turtle who created the universe
say,
Yo,
if you really want to kill it,
you best are laying down that tube.
So bill stopped flowing,
bite down on the monster's tongue and it
scurry away like a little low bitch
Lillo clown bitch.
After that,
the losers can't find their way out of
the tunnels.
But beverly got an idea.
Hey Boys,
drop your draws and fuck me.
Wait what?
These kids are only 11 stephen man.
So after the assembly line and a freak,
nasty oof the losers find their way out
of the sewers.
They all swear that if the creature
ain't dead,
they got to come back and put it in the
ground no matter what.
And as for Henry,
that full gets tossed in a loony bin and
tastes the fall for all of its murders.
Dan,
27 years later,
the children started disappearing and
dairy again and might get suspicious.
So he hollered at his old crew and say,
get your ass over here.
And bloods and his back.
So all the losers hustled back to dairy
except stand who get so wigged out,
he slipped his damn risks.
Meanwhile,
Henry get a visit from it who tell them,
it's time to bust out of the house to
get revenge on those losers,
the cloud being a real dick,
making the losers relive all kinds of
nasty mess from their childhood.
And if that ain't enough,
babs asshole hobby.
And Bill's wife come to town on the
bouncy.
Later,
Henry Bowers,
Shane's Mike at the library,
but he's still kicking with a little
help from it.
Henry,
head over to the hotel,
the ghost,
the losers.
But Eddie keeping clutch.
And Merck's Henry the way most gangsters
do it with a bottle of perrier.
Oh,
classic.
I begin word that might get racked it.
Mind control.
Bev's husband and snatch bills.
Woman.
The losers are all like,
no fucking around man.
Time to end this food.
I have to send more crazy.
The losers drop in at it's digs,
feel.
Richie and abby started laying down the
ritual,
a head up into that void and it chops
addys Damn Arma.
He dead.
What a monster started crawling away.
Been bused.
Everyone zags and bill crushes.
Ed's hard like a jake.
Now that it's finally dead.
They grabbed bill's wife and chunk out
of the tunnel.
No Gang Bang required this time.
Oh,
the losers go their separate ways and
slowly started the good.
What the hell just happened?
Bill's wife all whacked out in the head
from all the crazy she saw,
but after bill gives her a ride with his
goofy ass childhood bike.
She snaps right out of it,
but still don't remember what went down.
You might be thinking,
why would a gnarly beast like it set up
shop in a hub like dairy?
Well,
this ain't the innocent small town.
It seemed like,
oh,
that leave it to beaver.
They got a dog side brewing under it.
People who are crooked,
violent,
racist,
and don't give a damn about what's
happening to these little kids.
See,
it acted like a mirror of the crooked
ass.
People in dairy just picked this quote
of homies jabbering about the monster.
The one glimpse I called him,
it looked like he had a winchester board
action and it wasn't until later that I
figured out I must have thought of that
because that's what I thought he had a
remington because that was what he had
and when I asked Jimmy about it,
he said that guy was shooting the nose
spray field just like this.
Funny,
Huh?
Hey brotha.
Remember the monster packing the same
piece?
There were packing weapon.
That the clown is a reflection of all
the raw violence inside the heart.
Autumn Hood,
rats.
Matter of fact,
ain't no mistake that it roll around
decked out.
Lack of clown cars,
just like a clown.
The people of dairy seemed nice to the
kids on the outside,
but on the inside it's all flows back.
Clown wouldn't even exist if it weren't
for dairies.
Dark deeds.
See it is only able to hit the scene
when a horrible event go down like child
abuse on murder.
It's like a gnarly cycle where the
messed up things the dairy folk do
inspires it to terrorize the people,
which then encourages the people to do
even more wax because this cycle just
keeps going and going.
It's been chilling in dairy for a long
ass time.
It's become a part of dairy,
something as much a part of the town is
the stand pipe or the Canal Abassi Park
or the library.
Oh,
it's not a matter of our geography.
Somehow it's gotten inside this whole
cycle.
Jam Go even deeper because there'd be
circular imagery all up in this huge ass
book.
The kids struggled back to this hood
roots when they returned to dairy as
adults to lay a whip on the monster
beverly replaced or abusive daddy was an
abusive husband.
The only way they're able to beat it in
the end,
it's about throwing back to the mental
of that childhood and flats in their
imagination.
They even recognize that past events
happening all over again,
like when big boy band pink,
some bz reading the same story she read
back in the day,
am I supposed to believe that's just
coincidence because I don't.
There's something really stable in the
past and present together here or I'm
only imagining it.
The losers always form a circle at
important points.
Like when they promised a wreck it if he
dad shows his face and Debbie again,
when adults try to remember what went
down back then and even when everybody
gathers around a tab,
beverly,
that Ah,
nevermind man,
I can't say that she's the only like 11,
maybe all this cycle job.
Just preaching a greater point about
evil just like it.
Evil been around since the beginning of
time,
but it's only one humans arrived that it
started to take shape.
It says humans keep doing dark deeds
over and over again at been thriving for
centuries.
So maybe that's King's message evil only
because for real,
when humans are allowed to take control
of bus and got all my nasty qualities
like greed,
jealousy,
and violence,
it's always been here since the
beginning of time,
since before there were men anywhere it
was here.
Then sleeping,
maybe waiting for the ice to melt,
waiting for the people to come out.
Thanks for telling me and my library
today,
y'all and y'all.
One more thing before you go,
because we've got big news and Shit.
We've launched an audio series.
Notes get lit and each episode I dive
into list of the trellis riders,
characters,
plots,
themes,
and more all from the world of
literature.
So if you like what your boy dot suite
does here with notes,
check out it's available on itunes and
all these bots you find podcast.
And as always we've got lots more videos
on the way.
So click here to go to our channel page
and if you haven't already,
make sure to subscribe while you're
there.
Your star players face.