A wise crack,
jared here today,
we're diving deep into the world of
metal gear solid now because doing a
full scale philosophy of would be an
arsenal gear scale undertaking.
We decided to focus on something else
today,
the enigmatic nature of its Creator
Studio Jima.
Not only will we be talking about the
underlying themes of the games,
but also how Kajima has inserted himself
into these games in an unprecedented
way.
Nowadays.
It's not uncommon to have a small indie
game tell a personal story from its
creator,
but it is uncommon to see that happen
with a big budget cinematic thriller
like metal gear solid.
These games aren't just a collection of
stories about solid snake in big boss.
They're also about co Gima and his place
in video gaming at the time.
In a funny way,
life imitates art.
Here you have a narrative arc going from
upbeat poppy spy adventures to
Nihilistic,
Anti American cynicism as coaching his
relationship with Konami Sour,
but now with those shackles fried,
he's off to make whatever weird thing
this is,
but before Koji,
Miss Games became gut punching,
self critical studies.
They started off as a Kurt Russell,
rip off welcome to this wise crack
edition on co Gima and metal gear solid,
but before we get into it,
we wanted to give a shout out to our
sponsor,
audible,
who enabled us to finally dive into the
crazy world of metal gear.
We're going to get into this in a hot
second,
but Winco Jima created the world with
metal gear solid.
It was actually inspired by Richard
Dawkins,
the selfish gene.
I call him Dickie Dee because we're
tight.
You can learn about the very ideas that
inspired him to Yoko Gina's work while
still playing his games,
but I'll get more into that later to
listen to the selfish gene yourself had
to audible.com/wise
crack or just text wise,
crack to 500,
$500 and check it out and get yourself a
free 30 day trial.
Audible has a ridiculous number of
titles to expand your mind and you can
listen to their library anywhere.
I mean anywhere with a full audible
membership.
You can get one free audio book a month
that you can keep forever even if you
cancel.
That's audible.com/wise,
crack or pull out your phone and text
wise,
crack to 500,
500.
Thanks to audible.
Oh,
and watch out.
Major spoilers ahead.
The seventies were a decade when
visionary American directors were making
masterpiece after masterpiece with
directors getting top billing,
discreet,
artistically mature works.
A whole generation of kids grew up
wanting to make their mark on the world
through movies and video.
Kojima was right there among them,
but as fate would have it,
gaming would be the outlet for Cucina to
express his cinematic ambitions.
The first two metal gear games are full
of references to coaching was favorite
action movies.
The whole concept of self gameplay was
inspired by these sneaking scenes of the
great escape.
One of the bosses,
a duo of unstoppable cyborgs.
We're straight up terminators originally
called Arnold's and snakes.
Codename was ripped directly from
Russell's character in escape from New
York.
I'm not a snake who gene was earlier
works.
Police knots and snatcher were
respectively animate up Japanese takes
on lethal weapon and blade runner,
but it was the advent of three d gaming
in the late nineties that gave Kajima a
truly cinematic canvas to work with.
Suddenly,
video games needed cinematography and
performances,
so Kajima made snake even more of a Kurt
Russell rip off.
My name is Pliska.
The solid snake of metal gear solid was
so close to snake skin that years later
the film's rights holders actually
wanted to sue until John Carpenter
stopped them,
but beyond his obvious love for movies,
you can also see a kind of optimism and
metal gear solid what I understand,
but why metal gear,
the nuclear age ended with the turn of
the millennium writing a spy adventure
in the late nineties,
shortly after the Cold War has snake
saying things like this.
Russia today has enough.
They're struggling between freedom and
order,
and with that struggle,
a new spirit of nationalism is born
given the enormous economic decline
Russia faced after the Cold War.
Snakes,
words might sound naive today,
but they fit right into an upbeat
feeling of peace and prosperity for the
West.
Complete with a villain,
frustrated over a world,
gone soft off,
throwing the launch this weapon and get
a billion dollars.
We'll be able to bring chaos and back to
this world soft.
This is metal gear solid at its most
optimistic,
but it's all downhill from here.
In December of 1999,
the Ria filed a lawsuit against napster.
Cocina thought the idea of the US
government controlling how people shared
music was great fodder for his paranoid
cyberpunk spy fiction,
so in metal gear solid to our villains
are the patriots,
a secret network of conspirators who
have a chokehold on the US government,
the media and the minds of the people.
This country is shaped and controlled as
the Patriot seat fit.
The people are shown what they want to
believe,
what you call it.
Government is actually a weld stage
production aimed at satisfying the
public,
which includes you,
the player
colonel.
I just remembered something that I've
never met you in person,
not once.
If you fell for all the bait and switch
tricks packed into games writing now,
yes,
in the sql games,
it's revealed that the patriots are
actually robot ai satellites made for
comic relief sidekicks from the Prequel
Games,
but importantly they're based on
something much more real.
We are formless.
We are very disciplined and morality
that Americans invoke so often.
The Patriots are the concept of memes
personified.
We started with genetic engineering and
in the end we succeeded in digitizing
life itself,
but there are
are things not covered by genetic
information.
What do you mean?
Human Memories ID culture,
history,
metal gear,
solid one references Richard Dawkins'
book,
the selfish gene in which he coined the
term the beams means our cultural ideas
that replicate and spread from people to
people similar to gene's tunes,
catchphrases and ideas are all means
also means or means,
so as the language you're thinking in
right now,
which means the perspective that you
understand reality,
which is all made out of meat.
The are these psychological
homogenization of culture.
They aren't globalization,
they or why other countries are wearing
America's blue jeans and listening to
their poppies,
Perko Jima.
They are yet Japanese game developer can
succeed at making very Japanese games
for Americans based on American action
movies.
All the movie references that Cocina
included in these games are memes as the
games themselves,
the end of metal gear solid to has all
the characters reflecting on the meaning
of life and it's said to reflect co
Gina's anxieties about his own work as
well.
Life isn't just about passing on your
genes.
We can leave behind much more than just
DNA through speech and music,
literature and movies.
What we've seen heard,
felt anger,
joy and sorrow.
These are the things I will pass on.
Countless interviews at the time
revealed that metal gear,
solid tube was supposed to be coaching
was last metal gear games before handing
it off to a new team.
In a sense go Jima was trying to pass on
his mean,
yeah,
well listen,
what I do,
I'm going to quit,
but was so unsatisfied with what they
were cooking up for.
Mail gear solid three that he decided to
step back in and directed himself.
So in true [inaudible] fashion metal
gear solid three is full of even more
Kajima means the game takes place on
[inaudible] first birthday,
August 24th,
19,
64,
and includes multiple movie references,
especially early sixties.
James Bond and hitchcock flicks.
Go was personal.
Philosophies are once again present,
but this time there's a decidedly more
nihilistic slant from a character called
the boss.
Light is,
but a farewell gift from the darkness to
those on their way to die.
The bosses message of breaking down the
world's political barriers
is there such a thing as an absolute
timeless anymore.
There is no such thing and never has
been,
and the reason is that our enemies are
human beings like us.
There can only be our enemies in
relative terms.
The world must be made whole
is gradually warped and perverted until
it turns our hero into a villain.
The big boss of the earlier two d games
who was warmongering for the sake of
giving mercenaries,
a purpose in life.
It's a bleak view of the world that
comes to fruition in metal gear.
Solid four ever respect that face in
your mirror.
The first world becomes obsessed with
war and the third world is their
battlefield.
In the Games universe,
wars had become cold financial
strategies in real life,
so had metal gear,
solid games under Konami.
This was the second time code.
Jima was roped into continuing metal
gear solid after wanting to back out
with attempts at franchises like zone of
the vendors and Bach tie failing to
capture mainstream attention the same
way.
So metal gear solid four was explicitly
designed to end it all for real.
This time,
the gameplay acquiesced to the first
person shooter modes and fully
controllable cameras demanded by
reviewers and the story gave in to the
fans most burning questions while the
cutscenes fulfilled comas,
lifelong desire to make films,
no other metal gear,
maybe even no other game has cut scenes
that go on as long as the and the grand
irony of it all is that this is both be
closest and furthest.
Kajima came to making actual movies.
Metal gear,
solid four had plenty of live action
video put Kajima,
didn't direct write or produce it.
These intro commercials were outsourced
to an American studio.
Meanwhile,
questions from metal gear,
solid food that were never meant to be
answered are answered to the Wilderness
and results
on site.
Destroy Katie with a nuclear strike.
The Patriots network will be mine and
then I'll build my haven.
A melodramatic costume party.
Story ends with the hero and villain
beating the dead horse of their conflict
for 20 minutes and solid snake is now
old snake.
There's definitely an undercurrent of
self hatred running through this game,
especially with the knowledge that Koji
human wanted to run away from its
development and originally planned in
ending where were arrested and executed,
which came from the fact that fans sent
him death threats if it wasn't made,
but despite could was protests and metal
gear solid four is conclusive narrative.
He still couldn't get out.
Konami was demanding more and more of
these games and they were to be made by
no one else.
A rocky relationship between Kajima and
his employer started boiling up in 2009
with him joking in an interview that if
fans Richard Right the CEO of Konami and
tell him that [inaudible] doesn't have
to make metal gear anymore,
it might be easier for him to stop.
Go.
Jean was only nonmetal gear project
after four was a minor production role
in Castlevania lords of shadow,
but then it was right back to snake and
now metal.
Here's plot had to become more
convoluted and provocative to keep up
with its own standard.
Obviously they're bringing in state of
the art,
weaponry and equipment by the shipload.
Where'd they get that kind of cash?
I fear maybe involved the CIA.
Peace walkers fiction tested the idea of
nuclear deterrence.
Wait,
he's launching a new.
To prove that is perfect.
Current works.
His words to prove that if someone
attacks us,
we will strike back a situation that
mirrored the mutually assured
destruction of coaching was creative
work against Konami's tight control of
it.
This t rated portable entry still had to
explore the gritty.
He'll turn of big boss and the route
code human took was her boss to idolize
Che Guevara.
Jay never managed to numb himself pain.
That's why people loved him and why he
died.
A figure whose popularity to his western
audience is polarizing to say the least.
Four years later,
the Anti American sentiments of the
series new protagonists are taken the
extreme ground zeroes to explain to him
a very thinly veiled Guantanamo Bay were
supporting characters are subjected to
horrific sexual humiliation and torture.
A year after that,
metal gear solid five,
the phantom pain pain's the US
intelligence community as an out of
control evil conducting experiments on
third world refugees while also rubbing
the u.
s is known as hard in their real life
support the Afghan Mujahideen.
Four years ago,
the Soviets invaded Afghanistan.
Muslims are fighting back with Western
support
and desire president mobile.
Second set go.
You're not selling them US military
hardware.
Would you ever read about Napster in
ninth,
99 to make the Patriots and it's just as
likely that news breaking out about Apu
Grip Guantanamo and Edward Snowden
inspired this new version of an American
illuminati cipher.
These stories were being told in spite
of and perhaps in response to coach
edema,
not exactly having a great working
relationship with neo liberal corporate
capitalism.
When rumors of a rivalry between Cocina
and Konami came to light,
so did stories of his bosses actively
sabotaging his projects.
Eventually shipping metal gear solid
five in two parts with an incomplete
ending,
believe it or not,
the first edition of Moby Dick,
a novel frequently referenced,
and metal gear solid five was also
released without it's ending chapter.
The parallels between moby Dick and
metal gear solid five are rampant venom
code named Ahab is an amputee naval
captain hell bent on revenge.
Who commands a vessel called the peak
was just like the Aa happened in the
book,
but
this connection to the male of the
classic is also reflected by the
players' response to the game.
Like Ahab the player is relentlessly
chasing after a white whale.
They'll never best a feeling of
completeness at the end of finishing
this game.
It's a feeling so pervasive that entire
fan communities have sprung up over
refusing to believe that the game is
over.
Similarly,
in Melville's book,
the eponymous white whale is seen as a
representation of being a hollowness of
the universe,
the thought of annihilation or the
meaningless prize of a life spent
seeking meaning in metal gear.
Solid five players can seek meaning by
completing a story arc that ends halfway
through with the second half of the
story asking,
but never answering the question of what
happens after a hero defeats the
villain.
Players can instead seek meaning in the
Games multiplayer missions which
developed a kind of whaling economy of
their own or they can find meaning by
going for a completion score.
That of course has them fruitlessly
chasing after rare animals,
but no matter how you play,
no matter which ending you go for the
Games,
tone remains melancholy,
lonely,
and a anti climactic.
There's no epic final boss fight.
Each ending is intended to leave the
player feeling unfulfilled and wanting
the player feels a literal phantom pain
which leads us in our own opinion,
at least to believe that could Jima was
his own,
Captain Ahab with his own obsession to
defy the typically cold corporate
tradition of game design and create his
own art on his own terms if he's been
wanting to get crazy and make something
different than at least his story can
have a happy ending for now because
Norman reedus waking up naked on the
beach after giving birth to a magic goes
baby is a premise of a story where we
truly don't know what to expect and also
something that could have never been
done under the thumb of Konami.
So is this life imitating art or were
these just insightful predictions bound
to come true?
Either way,
color us stoke to checkout.
Death stranding.
Kajima is truly one of those
interesting.
Ah,
tours in gaming.
And as always,
thanks for watching guys.
Piece.
Thanks for watching.
Wise crack in case you missed it.
We recently released a video on the
philosophy of assassin's creed road
remastered.
We got the chance to go back and play
the game with fresh eyes,
which left us wondering if we'd been
playing the bad guys all along.
Be sure to check out that video by
clicking here and we've got tons of
other exciting stuff on the way,
including episodes on one punch,
man,
the cloverfield paradox,
and the last Jedi,
so be sure to subscribe and ring that
bell so you don't miss out.
Alright,
wisecrack catchall next time.
Peace.