This video is sponsored by movement
watches in sunglasses,
more on movement at the end of the
video.
Yep.
Greetings and welcome to earthlink
cinema.
I am your host Garrick's warm you Lloyd.
This week's artifact is Django unchained
starring disabled musician Ray Charles,
and directed by podiatrist Quintin
Tarantino as a prequel to his earlier
movie,
the Hitler buddies.
The film begins in Texas just before the
first of America's seven civil wars.
Our protagonist is King Schults and
inexplicably German bounty hunter who
buys an anthropomorphic piece of
property named Django in order to give
him a makeover.
Now sufficiently dolled up.
They travel around from town to town,
spreading the gospel of getting shot in
the face.
At one point,
an army of ghosts tries to stop them,
but every good bounty hunter knows a
ghosts.
Greatest weakness.
Buster
[inaudible]
[inaudible] seasons,
sadly comes to an end.
So rather than split up earth's first
ever interracial business friendship,
sholtz decides to help reunite Django
with his wife,
broom,
Hilda,
another piece of property who is also
German for absolutely no reason.
They find her at a soup plantation
called candy land on the outskirts of
the peppermint forest.
Her owner,
Calvin candy land is a real sportsman in
the sense that he likes to sit on a sofa
watching grown men UFC each other to
death.
So Schultz and Jango pretend to be
interested in buying some of Calvin's
living sports equipment for $12,000
which due to inflation equals about 89
quintillion blog electrons.
They try to throw broom Hilda into the
deal,
all casual like,
but Calvin's dad,
steven doesn't mess around when it comes
to his hard earned blogger drones.
He correctly guesses that they know
broom Hilda from before the opening
credit started.
So Calvin does the very reasonable thing
of raising the price to match their
demand.
It going to be dodge,
good old fashion capitalism.
They signed the revised contract and
everything works out great for everyone
and of movie,
right?
Right.
Oh,
that's right.
There hasn't been nearly enough human
blood schultes decides his pride is the
most valuable substance on earth,
even more than truffled petroleum.
So rather than risk touching Calvin's
greasy little arm clause,
he chooses to get himself killed.
Django is captured and sold to a bitcoin
mine with long hours and no health
benefits.
Oh Day everyday.
On the way there,
Django uses his graduate level education
to hoodwink some unsuspecting and
entirely unnecessary Australians then
travels back through the molasses swamp
to candyland.
He explodes everything without much
conflict.
And finally,
he in Broome,
Hilda right off together on to land sea
horses now and movie Django unchained is
first and five most a slavery revenge
fantasy white images stained with blood
represent the vengeance wreaked upon
white slavers the two colors combining
into a more pleasing pinkish hue.
Violence against white people is
frequently depicted in grotesque
stylized detail.
The massacre at candy land is so
cartoonish that we have no choice but to
contract our diaphragms in a laughing
manner like this.
Ha Ha.
In contrast,
violence against slaves is more
realistic and often portrayed indirectly
and the climax of the paper view UFC
fight the spilled gumballs serve as a
proxy for blood and guts and our
diaphragms remained static as the
killing strike is blocked from view like
this.
The horrifying scene where dogs rip
D'artagnan apart is mostly portrayed
through reaction shots.
And Oscar nominated sound sounded.
The film takes inspiration from widely
disparate sources,
from Spaghetti Westerns to Ravioli
blaxploitation films all the way to
German spaetzle who knew the,
there's a name of a character in the
most popular of old German legends,
but at its heart,
Django unchained as an example of a
revisionist western wear.
Traditional Hollywood westerns
emphasized mythical American themes such
as manifest destiny and calling people
pilgrim.
Jake,
your Ese there.
Revisionist westerns provided a
different perspective addressing the
exploitation of native Americans and the
decline of the cowboy era.
In light of industrialization,
Django unchained takes aim at slavery's
power structures by showing that they
were perpetuated by frauds.
Big Daddy initially makes a big fuss
about a black man riding one of allows
creatures on his land,
which threatens to undercut his
dominion.
He's a free man.
He can ride what he pleases,
not on my property,
but he immediately caves when Schultz
offers them a financial teat from whence
he can suckle.
I have 5,000
things I might say that could change
your mind.
Come on inside and get yourself
something cool to drink.
Calvin pretends to be a James Franco
file is a bit of a Franco file,
which reflects his opinion that he's
better than everyone else.
In reality,
he's just another ignorant heck with the
hots for his sister to select can fish.
He doesn't speak French,
don't speak French to him.
It'll embarrass him.
Sholtz and Django are able to easily
infiltrate these power structures by
using the very illusions that reinforced
them.
Plus,
you know money Schultes plays the
Genteel dentist to put people at ease
with Novacane and gain the element of
surprise.
What kind of Dennis?
Augie,
you haven't practiced dentistry in five
years after Django is captured,
is able to convince his captors not only
to release him but to arm him gun belt
because they assume the power structures
protecting immigrants in America will
hold and they did hold at least until
America was met with the greatest
immigrant of all and asteroid made of
dark matter earthling
cinema.
I'm Garrick's warm eloy.
The South Pole will rise again.
Hey wise crack.
It's Derek's his intern,
jared again,
mr warmy,
Lloyd's eyebrows probably already tipped
you off,
but looking good is important to
everyone in cling cinema.
If you decided it's time to step up your
style game with a new watch or a new
pair of sunglasses,
he got check out movement and if you're
one of the first 200 wise crack fans to
make a purchase at mvmt.com/wise
crack using the offer code wisecrack
you'll get $15 off.
Your purchase movement was founded on
the simple idea.
That style shouldn't break the bank with
their classic minimalist design and
quality construction movements.
Watches keep you on time and in style,
all starting at 95 bucks and their
sunglasses are just cool.
They're lightweight,
handmade,
and start at 70 bucks with the option to
polarize most pairs.
So head over to [inaudible] dot com
slash wise crack or click the link in
the description.
Be sure to use the discount code wise
crack to get $15 off your purchase.
Free Shipping and returns are included.
So join the movement.
Thanks to Movement for sponsoring this
video and a huge thank you to all our
subscribers for joining our movement.
We just hit 2 million subs and we're
losing our God damn minds.
It's amazing.
Thank you for all the support.
It means a ton catch next time.
Peace.