This video is sponsored by loot crate,
the monthly subscription service for
epic Geek gamer items and pop culture
gear,
more on loot crate at the end of the
video.
Hey,
wise crack.
Not a pickle.
Jared here and today we're breaking down
the season finale of rick and morty.
Season three in this season,
especially rick and Morty,
continues to flump the meaninglessness
of our existence.
Nobody gets it.
Nothing you think matters matters.
This is special.
This,
this is happening infinite times across
infinite realities.
Every time the show's teased us with an
authentic moment of love or motion,
it's ripped it right out from Andress.
My grandpa was my hero.
Your mom wouldn't have accepted me if I
came home without you and your sister.
So now you know the real reason I
rescued you.
I just took over the family.
Morning.
This leaves an interesting challenge for
creating a TV show.
How do you have characters grow when
there is no meaning?
Well,
let's show it gives us a novel solution
that's a little better than just
spiraling deeper into nihilism
guarantee.
You're going to die if you touch me and
there's no afterlife.
Everything just goes black,
don't do it,
and that growth isn't from the titular
protagonist,
but the matriarch of the Smith family
wasn't list wisecrack quick take on the
rick and morty and of course spoilers
ahead.
Okay,
so first a quick recap.
Rick and morty are called in to help the
president with some x files,
shenanigans,
but soon for of helping out the leader
of the free world.
Rick and the president began an ever
escalating Dick waving contest,
the to unleash their vast arsenals
against each other before rick has a
more pressing matter to attend to Jerry
out.
The more interesting subplot,
however,
is best fresh off the events of episode
nine.
Beth begins to question whether or not
she had taken rick's offer to be
replaced by a clone and if she in fact
is the clone to settle the matter.
She seeks the help of Jerry who
recreates one of their first dates and
rekindles their love,
but still worried she's gone.
Blade runner,
Beth,
runs off to the woods with the family or
rick shows up to kill Jerry and convince
her that she's not a clone.
And our last quick take,
we talked about rick informing Beth of
what her intelligence actually means,
my evil worse.
You're smart when you know nothing
matters.
The Universe is yours and I've never met
a universe that was into it.
Rick's answer to all this,
of course,
as we know,
is don't think about it.
Faced with this,
Beth has given radical freedom to choose
her destiny.
In this freedom brings her solace about
her choice to stay with or leave her
family,
regardless of which choice she makes.
I don't know if I can do it.
Then stay and luxuriate in a life you
can finally know you've chosen my secret
bonuses,
that no matter what you choose,
you're finally going to chill the Scout.
But this episode seems to suggest that
she chose to stay.
Matthew crazy bitch.
You're my daughter.
And as a new found sense of happiness,
she's being a better mother to summer
sort of.
I just put it on for finding now.
I can't buy it.
Oh,
come on.
You look great.
You're only young ones.
Just promise if the results are too
strong,
you'll use protection.
Finally loves Jerry and has brought her
family back together.
Real family.
Now,
in many ways things will be like season
one,
but for some it may seem kind of weird
that she suddenly rekindled her love
with the helpless parasite.
That is Jerry.
We could apply some of the philosophical
themes we've identified in earlier quick
takes here like starts bad faith and
radical freedom,
alienation versus agency,
but I'm going to propose something a
little new to explain why Beth
reconnects with Jerry and her overall
paradigm shift.
I'm more Fati the cure for common
nihilism.
Now,
what really made me think of this is
this moment,
my memory is of hating that night,
but now reliving at all I can feel is
how lucky I am to be loved by such a
simple,
honest,
simple man.
This isn't the woman you married,
Jerry Beth worried she's the clone must
now confront and question her past.
Not only is she still thinking about
rick's original proposition,
the ability to flee her past,
but as a possible clone or those
memories even her own and what does that
mean for her future or her happiness are
more fati.
Is a Latin phrase that spreading each
meister use that means love of fate.
A more [inaudible] is the affirmation of
life being what Nietzsche called a yes
sayer.
Not to be confused with the pervasive
corporate.
Yes ma'am,
and it's tied to a thought experiment.
Many refer to as eternal recurrence to
simplify.
Imagine a demon shows up and says he's
going to groundhog day your whole life.
You get thrown into existential despair
because you have to infinitely relive
questionable life moments like the
popularity of smash mouth and frosting
your tips and middle school,
or do you to paraphrase Nietzsche,
high five,
the demon and say you've never heard of
anything more defined to want to relive
everything that's happened in your life
for eternity.
The good,
the bad,
and everything in between is the
ultimate affirmation of life.
It's a more foggy and it's part of
Nietzsche's grand plan to escape the
crushing nihilism of existence.
Given Beth's existential crisis and
proclivity for rick like disillusionment
causing intelligence.
Beth has to confront her past.
I came to you for help and now I'm
insulting your intelligence and look,
we're intelligence gets you and with
Jerry,
she gets to relive a small part of it.
I just thought it lips don't sweat and
yes,
you may have hated her life the first
time around,
including her date with Jerry.
This time around,
she'll be that Nietzschean yes,
saving,
but I don't think Beth is rewriting the
past either.
Just didn't deny the years of misery she
has endured a more Fati isn't about some
kind of.
Everything is a blessing in disguise,
but it's more about not to shun the ugly
aspects of our lives as she tells Jerry,
she's no longer the woman he married and
sure Jerry may be an idiot,
but maybe simplicity is what a person
with a family history of using
intelligence to justify sickness needs.
We see another amore fati moment when
Beth.
Thanks.
Rick has come to retire.
Her.
I guess I was her,
which makes me related to her,
but I don't relate to her.
She left her family and me,
which means I relate to them.
Brushing aside the blade runner,
remiss of it all.
Beth is also functionally saying yes,
a version of Beth have chosen to leave,
but I will embrace being left with my
family rather than dwell on what could
have been and if you let me extrapolate
a bit.
While there may be infinite universes
where rick and Beth has made infinitely
different choices,
she wants to stay in this one.
As Nietzsche says,
my formula for greatness is a more fati
that one wants nothing to be different,
not in the future,
not in the past,
not for all eternity.
While meat,
you didn't necessarily philosophize
about infinite realities,
he did write about the impossible task
of knowing oneself.
I'm out of excuses to not be who I am.
So who am I?
What do I do?
Beth doesn't know who she is,
but desperately wants to.
For Niki,
the logic of why we actually do anything
is impenetrable,
and if we want to apply this Nietzschean
framing to rick,
we the fans almost never know what
actually drives him.
Why would you do that for me?
I don't know.
Maybe you matter so little that I like
you or maybe it makes you matter.
Maybe I love you,
so while Beth confront about whether or
not she chose to be cloned or whether or
not any of it matters in the infinite
versions of herself,
Nietzsche would say it really doesn't
matter.
All we can do is love our faith and that
seems to be the choice that Beth is
made.
And to me,
this is really interesting because while
the show is often portrayed,
rick as a kind of Nietzschean,
Uber Manch at war with the meaningless
cosmos,
there is no god in your face,
but rick and uh,
quite an uber menschy way doesn't really
create his own new meaning as much as he
just kind of dicks around in the most
self destructive way possible.
Beth,
on the other hand,
when faced with the meaninglessness of
the cosmos finds happiness,
and that's pretty Uber Menschy.
If you asked me now,
if you're like me and don't know what to
do with yourself,
now that you have to wait probably for
ever for season four,
consider checking out our wisecrack
podcasts,
the squash where we broke down every
episode of season three.
Over the break,
we'll be breaking down older episodes,
engaging a lot more with your questions
and trying desperately to interview
anyone who works on the show and thanks
to loot crate for sponsoring this video
for less than 20 bucks a month.
Loot crate sends you a geek and Gamer,
collectibles and apparel right to your
door.
It's the best place to go for monthly
swag from your favorite franchises.
And when you enter the code wise crack,
you'll get 10 percent off a new
subscription.
Just say it.
And the October loot crate theme is
mythical.
It's packed full of items from stranger
things,
marvel,
buffy,
and ghostbusters.
So you won't want to miss out on this
crate.
So click here or go to the link in the
description to head the loot
crate.com/wise,
crack to nap.
Those exclusive items from those epic
franchises you have only until the 19th
at 9:00
PM Pacific to sign up and receive this
mythical crate.
So don't wait.
Thanks to loot crate for sponsoring this
video.
I'm off to go fill the rick and morty
void in my life with some carbs.
Piece guys.