Hey guys,
jared again.
Today we're talking about your favorite
ocelot enthusiasts.
Mallory Archer and his crew of snarky
foul mouth spies,
Jesus Christ.
Archer is sustained.
Eight seasons worth of comedy would be
occasional drastic reboot.
So what we form a cartel,
how hard could it be?
So what makes archer work?
What's its secret sauce?
How does watching it feel like a
familiar experience?
Even as the show takes absurd leaps that
would probably kill off any other show.
Archer succeeds by inverting rules,
characters and narrative tropes of the
spies genre while using sound and
language gags to build a unique arsenal
of humor that explores deeper
character's psychology.
Oh,
it's Mrs J.
Welcome
this wise crack addition on archer,
and as always spoilers ahead,
it should be no surprise that archer
borrows plenty of the magic elements
from James Bond and slash or hello,
but these gags are more than just a
shallow nod to double o seven bond films
regularly pit.
The freewheeling titular stood against
these stuffy,
boring rule makers best exemplified by
him.
To understand why this is important,
we have to look at what was going on in
America during the meteoric rise of the
James Bond series.
According to sociologists,
Thomas Andre,
this time period was a crisis of
masculinity in which the male desire for
autonomy and independence was displaced
by pressure to sell out for a desk job
with a 401k,
leaving many a man feeling like an
alienated but conforming employee of a
large corporate bureaucracy.
Spy Thrillers emerged as the perfect
form of escapism with the character of
James Bond,
exemplifying the ideals of independence
agency and individualism that were
otherwise the lacking in the day to day
life of most American men.
Bonds,
characterization as a chronic
rulebreaker who relied on his charisma
and sheer guts to succeed made him the
perfect hero for the time.
Unfortunately,
be bond style.
Secret agent is a complete fiction.
Reportedly.
After viewing a James Bond film,
CIA officers would ask questions like,
why wasn't bond required to prepare an
expense report throughout the series?
Archer takes this question and milks the
humor of the unglamorous espionage
bureaucracy.
For all it's worth.
Forgot the balance in my God damn cow
date of employment or
mindless paperwork occupies a central
role on the show.
Frequently threatening archers ability
to live his best spy life.
You turned in an expense report from
Berlin with the German desk,
says you've never checked in Berlin.
Too busy to chose.
Yeah,
the show contrast the fantastical action
sequences with the Monday and ease of
office life to amazing comic effect
beneficiary on my company life
insurance.
Even when archer does escape the
bureaucratic ramifications of his
actions,
it's only because of his boss,
mom mallory's forgiveness.
Later in the series when the agency
becomes a private investigation firm,
Cyril is the only one eligible for a Pi
license.
As a result,
archer has to suffer the indignity of
working for the figures agency.
While a character like Cyril prospers in
the world of espionage,
bureaucracy,
archers,
swashbuckling,
antics are usually counterproductive.
I don't see what could possibly go wrong
and a quick note on Cyril,
whereas some might associate paper
pushers like him with emasculated
stooges.
Cyril is instead addicted to sex.
Hello?
Hello,
hello.
And hypersexualized.
I think I need a spanking.
Archers.
The ultimate James Bond parody,
it's all about machismo,
exemplifying the qualities he's best
known for,
and then taking them to their logical
unromantic conclusion like bond archer
is wild and untamed,
using drinking,
fighting womanizing cars,
and guns to affirm his manliness.
You want to see who's a big boy grow up.
The decades bond films have fetishize
the latest,
sexiest car.
Aston Martin sponsored 12 of the 24 bond
movies usually offering promotional
deals to let fan boys live out their
dream of buying a bond car.
On the other hand,
archers car is a birthday gift from his
mother,
presented to him as if it's his super
sweet 16.
Oh my God.
Adding to the adolescent field,
the car gives archer and embarrassing
erection.
Oh God.
He's got an erection.
The show mocks the way that bonds
hypermasculinity was and still is used
to sell products like cars and beer to
men who want to embody the same
qualities,
challenges,
special agent addition brought to you by
dodge,
then go for the best of times.
Archers car may be a marker of his
manliness,
but it's one that's on loan from Mommy
who confiscates it.
Days later,
again,
be supposed masculine power of archer is
yanked away by his more powerful mother.
James Bond is one of cinemas,
most famous eductors.
Similarly,
archer is hypersexual,
constantly hiring sex workers,
sleeping with every office.
Mate.
Would you please come in this dirty
toilet stall and have sex with me and
propositioning every woman with a
beating pulse and some without.
Could you close your eyes?
I kind of feel like I'm banging tail
lights on a country road.
Of course,
while bond sexual prowess is legendary,
archers is less than that.
Oh,
you finished.
All right.
Maybe try.
Well,
I weights by the way,
makes one of us,
and while bond sex life come seemingly
without physical consequences.
Archer frequently comes down with stds
and has to pay for abortions.
Oh,
pay for other health effects of the bond
in lifestyle are also taken to a logical
extreme.
Wild James Bond is known to enjoy his
liquor.
Archers.
Substance use is super human.
At one point,
he literally chugged germicide.
His drinking appears to play at least
some role in him getting these Feminine
Disease of Breast Cancer and a history
of alcoholism,
you know,
I mean,
I drink socially,
but
I didn't have breakfast,
hardly the stuff of a double o playboy
before archer undergoes chemo.
He has some of his sperm frozen later
on.
Lot of secretly uses that sperm to
become pregnant and have his baby
without his permission or even his
knowledge for the oblivious archer.
Even becoming a father somehow plays out
as a twisted form of emasculation cancer
isn't the only health ramifications of
archer secret agent lifestyle.
There's also tonight is a hearing loss
caused by too many damn guns going off
all the time.
Either James Bond is always wearing
earplugs or his craters.
Ignore the pesky realities of inner ear
damage.
At one point,
archer and his crew even solidify
tonight,
us as the show's pet cause attending an
annual fundraiser for the American
Tinnitus Association.
Once again,
archer subverts the bulletproof James
Bond and fantasy by dragging archer into
the bleakest realities of his mortal
body.
But is there something more to archers?
Hearing loss communication scholar.
Ian,
I think so in his essay,
archer,
a spy parody for the ears dot argues
that archers tonight is is more than an
ongoing gag.
It's actually an important aspect of the
show's preoccupation with sound and
language which are both used to generate
laughs and to provide deeper insights
into character psychology to prove this
doc conducted a study in which he
watched every episode of archers,
third and fourth seasons,
and counted the number of linguistic or
sound specific references including
language jokes like puns,
foreign language references or loud
gunfire followed by the high pitched
ringing of archers.
Tinnitus dot found that such references
occurred on average 10 times per episode
in the third season and 11 times in the
fourth,
which comes out to approximately once
every two minutes just as mundane office
politics serve as a humorous contrast to
the life threatening action sequences.
The show's language jokes are often
employed at the most inopportune
moments.
Don't take special interest in one of
the shows.
Simplest ongoing gags.
Bada Bada
archers.
Frequent act of calling out loudly to
Elana even when she is nearby is more
than just a simple annoyance.
It's reminiscent of a baby calling out
for its mother,
which for Archer probably never quite
gave him the comfort he needed.
I don't feel good.
What the hell?
Essentially archers increasingly louder
appeals to signal his inability to
control his demand for attention.
Eventually other characters adopt the
same gag.
Pam,
based on the growing frequency of these
appeals for attention,
Nga says clearly it is very important in
this show for characters to be heard.
However,
it also seems to be important that they
not be hurt too quickly by the listener
bringing up the rooms of power,
demand control,
and psychological repression.
For instance,
take archers,
classic phrasing,
joke.
Don't you want to freshen up after your
long ride raising mother?
This is a classic use of what Freud
called Double Entendre in which the joke
depends quite specially on the sexual
meaning,
even though the words have an
alternative,
nonsexual meaning.
Freud thought that these sorts of jokes
were way to release some of the nervous
energy that comes from repressing sexual
or aggressive desires.
That's particularly significant when
archers aiming the joke at his mother
for whom he has more than an inkling of
an oedipal complex clone of me,
dead gives you know just half of one,
but beyond that,
when archer says phrasing,
he's essentially choosing to
miscommunicate and willfully
misinterpreting the speaker's words.
Thus derailing the conversation by
choosing to only hear the sexual
innuendo.
Archer often ensures that the person
won't be hurt at all.
I guess I'm a bad listener.
The tech,
they quickly becomes one of archers.
Favorite ways of hijacking a
conversation.
As language tends to do phrasing spreads
as the other characters start adopting
it.
Thank you for coming so quickly.
In fact,
the joke eventually become so ubiquitous
that it actually circles back and falls
out of fashion like Yolo or on fleek.
Archers,
anxiety over the plummeting popularity
of his favorite joke only confirms how
important these attention grabbing
antiques are to his identity.
The world's image of a perfect man
reduced to a manchild phrasing isn't the
only way to avoid hearing what a
character usually his mother is really
saying.
Take the running gag about archers,
voicemail messages which become
increasingly elaborate ruses to trick
his mother into thinking she's actually
speaking to him.
Sterling Sterling listened very
voicemail as a result.
Mallory has entire conversations with is
prerecorded voice before realizing she's
been duped here.
Archer is taking great pleasure in the
power he's able to wield in a
conversation with his mother.
This voice message gag is archers
hilarious.
If juvenile means of temporarily
reclaiming some power momentarily
undermining mallory's dominance over
him.
I'm trying to just as archer has trouble
bending to the will of Isis.
As human resource department,
you often find themselves struggling
with the rules of language.
I learned that flammable and inflammable
mean the same thing.
Both restraints prevent archer from
living the bad ass spy narrative he
envisions for himself.
One such example occurs in the three
part series,
heart of archness.
When Archer has declared himself king of
the pirates,
he attempts to address his subjects
through his translator slash slave noah.
Okay,
pirates.
Hey,
take a knee.
That won't translate.
It's like last week when you said,
lend me your ears,
and they were like,
damn it.
I can't do idiom.
Sorry.
Shut up.
Archer attempts to convey his message
without these idioms,
but quickly finds it impossible.
Oh,
I never realized how much we rely on
idiot.
You'll win this round here.
Archer shapes against the rules of
language just like he chafes against the
rules of bureaucracy,
but even when he's not dealing with
inconvenient language gaps,
archer still has trouble expressing
himself.
No,
I still got that stemer.
While James Bond is well known for his
pithy,
one liners.
Archer is not so gifted between his
legs.
Frequently regretting his failure to
come up with the perfect witty line.
Wait,
wait,
I got something for this.
Hush puppies.
Oh Damn.
That's better.
Again.
Archer parodies bond by turning his
funny offhanded Innuendos into a chore
in which Archer Still Comes up.
Short operation,
something about I rescue,
Ilana,
and she begs me to take her back so then
you don't commit suicide.
Swear to God.
I had something at other times.
Archers language isolates him,
particularly when he's attempting to
connect with others over his favorite
obscure cultural references.
I would prefer not to Bartleby the
scrivener.
Anybody?
Not a big Melville crowd here,
Huh?
While he's constantly grasping to be
heard and to impress through his brain,
he call outs,
he rarely receives any affirmation.
Why am I William Sapphire?
It's always disappointing to have your
thoughtful cultural references fall flat
and not even the greatest spy in this
fictional cartoon land is immune to the
shame.
Read a book,
archers chock full of fantastical fight
sequences,
wildly ambitious spy missions and
unnecessarily complicated weapons
technology,
but much of the show's humor,
rest in the linguistic communications
between the characters I honestly have
no response to that is lingering.
Adolescent sense of being an outsider
formed over and impressive 15 years
spent at boarding school are perfectly
expressed and his over enthusiasm for
coining group slang and his wildly
obscure pop culture references that
inevitably fall flat.
Most of all,
archer embodies the perennial secret
agent struggle born out of the 19
fifties,
masculine anxiety about being cogs in
the corporate machine,
but what do you guys think?
Will Sterling Archer ever learned to
listen?
Will there ever be a joke?
Good enough to replace phrasing?
Let us know in the comments and as
always,
thanks for watching guys.
Thanks for watching wise crack.
If archers got you itching for more
great animated content,
get your fix over at verve.
That's VRV and if you act soon,
you can get 30 days free to check out
all the shows and channels they've got
to offer.
Verve is a mega service that gives you
unlimited access to awesome channels
like curiosity,
stream,
drama,
fever and enemy favorites like crunchy
roll and funimation where they recently
added dubbed episodes of Dragon Ball
Super.
Not only will you be able to instantly
catch great anime like my hero,
academia,
black clover burrito and food wars,
but you'll also be able to watch on the
go without an Internet connection.
If you think that sounds great,
verbal wants to give wisecrack fans 30
days of free hd ad free viewing for all
13 of their channels.
If you sign up before the end of
December,
when you order for of premium,
you get everything that includes
shutter,
where you could get your horror fix with
a bunch of scary series as well as
exclusives like harmon quest,
bravest warriors,
and be and puppy cat,
so head over to [inaudible] dot co slash
wise crack or click the link in the
description.
Do you get your 30 free days of birth
premium before the offer ends?
This month you can get it on your
desktop,
on their mobile APP,
Roku or playstation or xbox.
Thanks for sponsoring this video and
we've got tons of great stuff on the
way,
including videos on deadpool and up,
so if you haven't already,
be sure to subscribe.
All right,
catch you all next time.
Peace.