This video is brought to you by
skillshare,
the first 500 people to sign up with the
link in the description.
We'll get a two month free trial.
Hey,
why is cracked jared again?
Today we're talking about an insanely
popular Halloween horror series
guaranteed to make you barf up all your
candy corn.
No,
not the Emoji movie we're talking saw
since 2004.
The torture porn he franchise has been
locking up morally dubious characters in
all kinds of gruesome steel contraptions
and inventing creative new places to
hide the keys.
The creepy puppet master of the saw
franchise is Jigsaw and boy does he love
playing games,
and by playing games we mean locking
unconscious people inside Dank
warehouses and giving them 60 seconds to
choose between certain death self
mutilation or if they're lucky,
this embellishing a stranger.
When people talk about saw,
they tend to focus on jigsaws impressive
body counts,
but just as you can pick through a pit
of heroin syringes to find the hidden
key,
you can sift through this villains
deadly traps to find the grander meaning
of his game.
Welcome this wisecrack edition on the
philosophy of Saul,
and as always spoilers ahead.
The philosophy of saw all comes down to
jigsaws.
Motivation is torturous.
Games are opportunities for his victims
to repent for their sins and ostensibly
to transform into better human beings.
They survive his tests and the odds are
not quite ever in their favor.
He believes they'll emerge with a new
found ability to appreciate life.
So basically if Tony Robbins had a baby
with Satan,
in a sense,
jigsaw embodies a kind of extremist
Christian morality.
But before we get there,
we first needed to get into the
headspace of John Kramer.
Alias the jigsaw killer.
Once upon a time,
John was a perfectly nice civil engineer
who loved hanging out with his pregnant
wife,
Jill,
who owned a drug Rehab Clinic.
Then one of Joel's tweaked out patients,
Cecil Adam's robs her clinic
accidentally injuring Jill in the
process.
She suffers a miscarriage and John Falls
into a deep depression.
A short while after he's diagnosed with
a brain tumor and terminal cancer,
he plummets further into depression and
its relationship with jill quickly
deteriorates.
Girl boy,
boy,
girl,
boy gets cold,
pregnant girl loses baby boy,
turns into a serial killer
and instead of joining tinder or
something,
Joe continues to entangle herself and
her booze drama.
After an all around year,
John Tries to kill himself by driving
off a cliff.
Miraculously,
he survived the crash and emerges
totally sure of his new calling,
dispensing morality,
one torture device at a time.
It's a moment that I decided to end my
life,
started me and my work and brought
meaning to it,
and I was determined to spend the rest
of my days testing the fabric of human
nature as John cooked up a fresh coat of
morality to match his new mission in
life.
He seems to have been inspired by an
unlikely source early Christian
philosophy.
Specifically,
it's views on suffering.
According to early Christian tradition,
God is good in everything he created is
good,
and nobody really questioned that until
one day and an early Christian stubbed
his toe and discovered suffering and was
like,
this sucks,
WTF God.
Once a bunch of Christian theologians
started stubbing their toes,
they realized they needed to rationalize
how an all good God could have created
such suffering.
They theorized that suffering had to be
the fault of no good,
lousy humans.
Here's what they figured.
When Adam ate that apple from the tree
of knowledge does committing the
original sin.
He's separated dumb,
evil humans from the pure perfect God
who apparently doesn't like it.
When humans eat a fresh healthy snack
from then on,
sinful humans would need to suffer and
repent if they wanted to be reunited
with God.
Suffering then is the result of our own
sins and an expression of the pain.
We feel over our separation from God in
this way.
Traditional Christianity justified
suffering as the fault of the sinner,
not of God.
Crisis averted.
Similarly,
Jigsaw thinks his victims deserve the
suffering that they endure in his traps.
He helpfully reminds each victim of the
sins they've committed to get there and
he doesn't hold back.
As Jigsaw sees at his victims are
enslaved by their past and morality,
not his industrial strength,
torture devices.
Much like theologians believe humanity
had been trapped by Adam and Eve's
original sin fittingly.
The saw series has a few atoms of its
own.
In sophomore we learned that drug
addicts,
Cecil Adams,
is responsible for Jill's miscarriage.
His original sin is a catalyst for
John's transformation into jigsaw.
Additionally,
in the first film Adam stand height,
a photographer who spends his day spying
on people becomes one of jigsaws
targets.
His professional quest for CD knowledge
mirrors that of Adam's desire to eat
from the tree,
so Kramer's view on human suffering
shares a similar origin story to that
have early Christians,
which hey could mean that watching some
movies qualifies as attending church.
However,
John Kramer also shares a common thread
with Christian theorist and father of
existentialism,
Soren Kierkegaard,
who sees suffering as a critical part of
personal and spiritual growth.
For context,
much like Kramer Kicker Guard had his
share of luck.
He had a lifelong physical deformity.
He watched his mother,
brothers and sisters die at a young age.
It became totally convinced that he was
going to die at age 33 light Kramer.
He also broke up with the love of his
life,
his then fiance regime,
yet continue to pine after her for the
rest of his days.
Basically the two of them could have
shared stories over whiskey.
They also both believe that suffering
purifies the sufferer,
teaches them to appreciate life and
forces them to take responsibility for
their actions.
You might prefer your life without a
generous dose of suffering,
but here are the guy out here regard,
believed that an individual must pass
through three distinct phases to become
his or her true self.
First,
the aesthetic driven by central
pleasures and lacking any morality.
Seconds,
the ethical driven by morality and
belief in individual responsibility and
third,
the religious driven by faith in God.
So how do you go from being a lowly
drunk aesthete to an upstanding ethical
guy?
Well,
you can always try out one of jigsaws
torture machines.
That's right.
According to Kierkegaard,
suffering is key to moving up to the
next stage of human development.
Here could guard was mostly talking
about spiritual and existential
suffering,
not being caught in a torture device or
worse.
Having people spoiled game of thrones
still jigsaws machines can be understood
as a test for each of his victims who
are typically aesthetes driven by
desires for sex,
drugs,
or money.
His testes present his victims with an
ethical quandary that usually forced
them to make a painful decision.
This matches the way cuter guard
explains the journey from being an
aesthetic to ethical being first,
the ethical life makes the suffer,
suffer even more than before.
Drawing him out of the frying pan and
into the fire so that he really has
something to scream about and only then
does it help him,
but how exactly does suffering help you
become more ethical?
According to Kierkegaard,
suffering forces a human to reflect on
their situation.
If only to think,
oh,
this sucks,
that moment of reflection summons the
first doubt,
which regard describes as the thought?
Why is this happening to me?
Can it not be otherwise?
Or to put more simply what's going on?
That little WTF moment generates the
immediate desire to change your
circumstance.
Desire opens a person up to a character
guard,
calls ethical self.
Understanding suffering is growth
inducing because it turns these single
individual over to himself completely at
its most successful.
This suffering can force a person to
repent for past sins,
take responsibility for his guilt and
choose to seek his own survival,
but more on that later as you progress
up the ladder of development,
a piece of your old false self dies,
much like the old Taylor swift
because she's dead.
Judging from his own interpretation of
his car crash,
John Kramer agrees that a different
person crawled out of the wreckage.
For Kierkegaard,
the ultimate goal of spiritual suffering
is to completely kill off your flawed
false self in order to make room for
your recreation it into a better truer
self.
Kramer demands this of his most fervent
follower,
Amanda,
when she agrees to live by his ethical
code,
every cell in your body,
there is no turning back.
Amanda sits in a prayer like position
listening deeply.
Diehard Saul fans called is seen
Amanda's baptism,
which is fitting when you consider how
baptism relates to suffering,
just as Jesus rose from the dead to
redeem humanity.
Human beings are baptized and
spiritually cleanse Christian tradition.
Also see suffering as a mechanism for
spiritual cleansing.
Jigsaw frequently references this
concept of rebirth,
whether he's chatting with his favorite
disciple or welcoming a new victim into
one of his traps.
Welcome to your rebirth tonight.
I give you the opportunity to face your
upside.
Jigsaw even loses his kidnapping Virgin
v during a literal celebration of
rebirth,
the Chinese New Year celebration because
it's the year of the pig.
Kramer even picks up his sweet trademark
pig mask at the event.
Trigger guard and Jigsaw have a few
other important ideas and common
specifically.
They both value personal responsibility.
Kierkegaard writes that the first
indispensable step of becoming a real
man isn't getting strange new body hair,
but by becoming a responsible individual
before God,
Kramer demands the same from his victim
and what's the key to taking
responsibility,
making a choice,
Kramer Spurs his victims into life.
Affirming action
seems to me that two of your sons,
impending death is causing you to
forgive his sins,
to wipe the slate clean.
Why is it that you're willing to do
that?
When a life is at stake
in the moment of making a choice?
Kick regard believed that a man becomes
himself.
Similarly,
Kramer is adamant that his victims
choose their actions even ending each of
his games with this Yoda like refrain.
He also maintains that the individual is
responsible for the outcome of their
decision within the confines of the
game.
I've never murdered anyone in my life.
The decisions are up to them.
While many horror films offer an
ultimate salvation
saw,
does not offer any kind of hope for a
better tomorrow.
Instead,
it seems to critique this extreme
version of traditional Christian
morality.
Throughout the series Kramer's
positioned as a god like figure monk or
even martyr,
he dresses in a long black hooded cape
acquires flocks of disciples and
performed baptisms.
You also maintains the quality of
omniscience.
He's always watching his victims through
camera monitors or people's,
so jigsaw may be a godlike figure,
but he's a seriously failed one.
His attempt to establish a moral order
does not bring about meaningful change
that kramer professes.
It will.
For starters,
most of his victims failed their tests.
They crumble under pressure or can't
withstand the pain.
Those who do pass are frequently
traumatized.
You want to know the best thing that
happened to me after having to cut off
my own,
our handicap parking at the mall.
Further revealing the full extent of
jigsaws failure is this ill fated quest
for the right apprentice.
Each of his contenders twists his
philosophy while jigsaw creates games
that are truly winnable.
If you follow the rules,
you can choose to preserve your life as
long as you're willing to part with say
your left arm.
His mentees on the other hand,
create rig games that are unwinnable
death traps.
Blowing up Jake's last game was to get
out.
Why was the door well to his disciples?
Just used the games to get revenge on
people they don't like.
Eventually they all end up trapping and
killing one another.
Adam,
jealousy to them,
the point of the Games is punishment
rather than renewal.
So much for Jigsaw is legacy.
The characters in the Sol films
frequently remind the audience that this
is a seriously flawed moral code.
You said you wanted to talk then you
said you wanted to play a game.
You're talking,
but it means nothing just before her
death.
Amanda Denounces Him.
Nobody is going.
Lastly,
because Jigsaw is presented as a god
like figure,
you would expect that his justice be
dispensed fairly,
but it's not.
He's the villain of the series and his
morality lessons frequently sacrifice
innocent human lives.
Similarly,
you'd expect his death to result in
salvation or redemption,
but instead he dies after offering one
of his victims,
Jeff,
the opportunity to forgive him instead
get violently killed.
Scraper,
even Kramer's own death is the result of
one of his tests,
ultimate failures,
and he didn't even get to eat a tasty,
delicious apple so much for finding
spiritual rebirth and a reverse bear
trap.
Still plenty with seem to find value in
less intensive experiences of suffering.
Just look at marathon runners or
competitive hotdog eaters.
So when it comes to self improvement,
is it no pain,
no gain,
or will human suffering be eliminated?
Once we invent the perfect dual purpose
food delivery and TV streaming APP?
Let us know what you think in the
comments.
Thanks for watching guys.
Thanks for watching.
Wise crack.
We love making videos for y'all and you
guys often asked what programs we used
to do it and how we learn to use them.
Like many youtubers,
a bunch of us at wise crack are self
taught and these days you can learn just
about anything online ever wanted to
start a project or learn a new skill,
but weren't sure where or how to begin.
Well,
skillshare has got your back.
Skillshare is an online learning
community with over 17,000
professional and easy to understand
classes in design,
photography,
business,
and much more.
Whether you're already a creator or
you're looking to learn how to become
one,
you'll find likeminded people with steps
and advice on how to take your ideas to
the next level.
You can take classes on everything from
how to design an effective logo to the
basics of three d printing.
To the proper way to chop vegetables,
and if you've got some skills you'd like
to share with the community,
you can teach your own class.
A premium membership starts at just $10
a month to get you unlimited access to
the full range of courses,
but the first 500 people to click the
link in the description will receive a
two month free trial to skillshare and
all its resources,
so head over to sk l dot ssh slash wise
crack too.
To begin your two month free trial and
get learning,
you can download their mobile app and
take classes no matter where you are.
We can't wait to see what y'all create
and don't forget to subscribe and ring
that bell to keep up with what we're
creating.
Thanks for watching guys.
Catch you all next time.