This video is sponsored by skillshare.
The first thousand people to sign up
with the link in the description.
We'll get their first two months for
just 99 cents.
Yep.
Greetings and welcome to earthling
cinema.
I am your host Garrick's where ameloid
this week's artifact is it based on the
novel by the sovereign of intellectual
property,
King Stephen and storing the cutest
scars guardian of the galaxy.
The film takes place in an alternate
reality where earth children rode bikes
everywhere known as the ats.
Our sort of protagonist is build in Bro,
who despite his name breaks the first
rule of bro Code.
When he lets an unemployed artists eat
his brother,
a year passes and bill's still butthurt
about his dead brother.
He's dead.
So his loser friends search the septic
tank with them only to find it more
barren than my first wife.
A local Hussey named Bev short for
beverage joins the crew to up the
diversity and the boy,
his blood pressure and a stranger things
start happening.
The kids make a shocking discovery.
The only haunted looking house in town
is haunted and it's where it lifts.
Turns out the artist is actually a
bogert named pennywise who's preferred
Pronoun is it dad?
When pennywise totally screws with their
analog powerpoint,
the kids try plan a walk into it's trap
house.
Since Bev probably took all their plan B
and after successfully stabbing its
head,
they disband for no reason.
That is until pennywise teen naps Bev to
show her his latest installation bill
and Co's save her cause they hate modern
art and take turns punching it even
though they could have done that at
literally any time.
Pennywise goes down the pipes back to
the mushroom kingdom and the most
rocking summer ever ends like all
rocking summers with a blood oath.
At its core,
it is about battling fear and is not at
all about child orgies.
Pennywise lives in the sewers beneath
dairy surface reflecting the
subconscious nature of its attacks and
how hard it is to find a good one
bedroom fame.
Psychopaths,
siggy fraudster would call this
amalgamation of subconscious concerns
into one representative token
condensation.
I call it Dad Dad.
Ed's fear of disease is baked into this
dude with Eczema.
The painting in Stan's father's office
represents the pressure on stand to
learn how to read the Rabbi's son Ken
finishes on Taurine.
The bloody scene in beverages bathroom
reflects her insecurities about her
changing body as is quickly losing
carbonation.
The film explores the conditions under
which fear and evil may flourish.
Pennywise finds a comfortable home in
dairy because the adults are indifferent
to the town's problems like the high
murder rate,
constant amber alerts or the lurking
killer childhood obesity.
By feigning ignorance to these issues,
the adults enable it just as they allow
bullying and racism to do its thing.
The film suggests that being alone
renders one more vulnerable to fear and
to spending an entire day naked on the
couch throughout the film.
It attacks victims one on one cause it's
not really into group stuff.
The antidote to indifference in
isolation is friendship.
Okay?
It's a 64,000
be the losers are only able to defeat it
by facing it together and sharing their
emotional burdens,
even though all they had to do was hit
it with a stick.
When Bev decides to go.
All Terri Shiavo.
It's Ben's gesture of friendship that
snaps her out of it.
A classic true love's first base,
like many kings,
steven ips.
It is about coming of age to legally
bone.
The film as an allegory for the
transition from childhood to young
adulthood,
also known as the hood.
In the beginning.
The characters are helpless.
Children controlled by their overbearing
parents and the beliefs who terrorize
them,
you're trap.
They are painfully aware of
characteristics that make them
different.
For Billy,
it's his oral,
your hair.
For Ben,
it's everything except his personality.
And for Mike it's being the only black
character in the movie.
But as the children unify and battled
the monster,
they learn to assert power over their
own lives.
Graduating from helpless children to
helpless teens,
despite its uplifting message.
The film makes it clear that evil,
much like herpes can never be eradicated
without a ray gun,
just as pennywise will inevitably wake
up in 27 years.
This stuff seems to happen every other
27 years.
Evil such as racism and abuse will
eventually rise up and get a hit movie
too.
And it did in the 2075 box office.
Hit racism and abuse.
Save Christmas,
earthlink cinema.
I'm Garrick's learning what goes up.
Must come clown.
If
there's anything we get asked time and
time again,
it's jared.
How can you still be Gareth's as intern
after all this time and it's actually a
funny story.
Late last year,
Garrick's promoted me to graphic
designer,
just white,
having no experience whatsoever.
Attempting to airbrushes eyebrows.
I failed miserably even though I could
have used skillshare,
the online learning community with
thousands of classes,
the final product was a nightmare and
knowing garrick's you can probably guess
what happened next.
I was fired,
lost my salary and was forced to sleep
on the streets and he used Napkins to
survive.
That is until I got a premium membership
on skillshare and unlimited access to
college grade courses on skills that
would allow me to get hired back and
sent the subscription has less than $10
a month.
I took all the courses I would need
dynamic brand identity,
fundamentals of dslr photography and
mastering logo design.
Armed with all these skills.
I ask Eric for my job back,
and he overwhelmingly said no.
So I grovel to my hands,
went numb,
and he reluctantly hired me back as an
intern.
So don't make the same mistakes I did
and sign up for skill share at s.
K.
L.
Dot.
S.
H.
Slash.
Earthlink,
six the first thousand people to use the
promo link in the description.
We'll get their first two months for
just 99 cents,
which is less than a mcdouble.
So come on already,
give them your money.