Have you ever won some asshole who needs
a haircut here?
We just got back from deadpool two and
one of the shares.
Some thoughts.
Is it funny?
Yes.
Is it the same thing as deadpool one
except replace romance with family also?
Yes,
but there's one particular scene we
wanted to talk about it just for for
Logan,
but deadpool two spoils logan pretty
much immediately,
so consider yourself warned.
At the beginning of the film,
deadpool holds a music box of Wolverine
from the end of Logan.
It depicts him impaled upon a tree.
After defeating x 24,
he laments that Logan has stolen his
fire,
so to make it right,
dead pool will also die.
Deadpool's Hugh Jackman obsession is
well documented,
but in deadpool two,
it takes on a new layer of relevance.
One can view the entire film as one
giant joke at Logan's expense.
So welcome to this wise crack quick take
on deadpool two,
and of course spoilers ahead,
but first,
quick shout out to Wix for sponsoring.
This video weeks gives you the
superpower to make websites quickly and
easily.
That don't look like my Zenga page,
circa 1999.
They've got a solution for every need.
Whether you want to embed a video of
yourself eating a bucket of peanut
butter with a wooden spoon or create a
suave business side that can help you
get a job.
Wix is where it's at.
No matter what you do,
wix makes sure your website is safe and
secure while offering you a design
toolbox.
You can make websites that don't look
cookie cutter,
no disrespect to cookies.
It's legit.
Free to sign up at [inaudible] dot com
slash go slash wise crack,
and whether you're a novice,
one of those hot shot web designer
people,
or a guy who just makes videos on the
Internet,
it's super easy to get started.
Thanks to wix again and now back to
violence,
cynicism and fourth wall breaks.
So first a quick recap.
Deadpool two follows the MERC with a
mouth as he's going through a bit of an
emo phase.
His plans to start a family with Vanessa
Goto when she gets murdered by some bad
guys after trying to kill himself,
he's brought on as an x men trainee.
Where he encounters a rotund young
firestarter named Russell,
tired of being abused by his boarding
school staff.
Russell starts lashing out.
Deadpool decides to dish out some
vigilante justice on his abusers,
so he,
along with Russell,
end up in Buton prison with power
inhibiting collars.
Deadpool breaks free when the time
traveling cable infiltrates the prison
to assassinate Russell.
Why?
Because it grows up to be a pretty big
who kills cables,
wife and child.
After playing some cat and mouse russell
for sakes,
deadpool to join up with the juggernaut
and kill his school master causing
deadpool and cable to team up as part of
their deal.
Deadpool gets to try to stop Russell
from killing his schoolmaster.
Thus breaking the chain of events that
turns him into key.
We voldemort if not cable,
gets to kill him.
When you put the two film side by side,
deadpool two is a lot like logan.
Besides the healing factor,
both films follow two mutants,
trying to help younger mutants being
hunted down by guys.
It's also worth noting that both of
these bad guys have robo arms slash
hands.
Both films also have an adult child
relationship.
Where the child is kind of a mirror for
the protagonist,
Wade Wilson had a crappy family life
which makes him empathetic to the
orphans Russell,
who's only father figure conducts cruel
experiments on him.
As a result,
he realizes Russell's and is beyond the
child's choice and thus he deserves a
chance.
Similarly,
Logan sympathizes with Laura because she
like him,
was engineered as a killing machine.
Both our heroes Die Sorta to save said
child.
So here's the thing in logan and his
sacrifice has a particular meaning,
one that we've covered before Logan and
not set aside his violent past.
No matter how hard he tries,
he tries to spare laura the violent life
he had,
but can only do so by reluctantly
becoming one last time.
The animal like Wolverine Logan and his
Wolverine Fur Sona die so that Laura may
live.
This may sound a lot like Vanessa's
line.
Give us a chance to be better than you
used to be about how children give
people the opportunity to make better
versions of themselves and on the
surface,
this is kind of happening,
at least in a,
did poorly in way deadpool.
Who has a violent past like wolverine
does not want Russell to get that
initial taste of murder because it will
set him down a dark path.
Now,
does deadpool want Russell to avoid
being a jaded hitman for higher?
Well,
not exactly.
He has to make sure Russell doesn't kill
his school master,
but he seems to have no problem doing
the killing himself.
I mean,
this is deadpool.
After all,
at the end of the film,
we think deadpool has turned a new leaf
and decided to spare the school master
and perhaps take colossus words to heart
from early in the film that he's not
judge,
jury and executioner,
and with deadpool sparing of him,
Hey,
it's progress,
but it was all a stall tactic so that
depender could make like daisy Buchanan
and commit some light vehicular
manslaughter.
Just like the end of deadpool one.
Wade is still not.
Colossus is image of heroics,
but perhaps this comparison works on
another level.
It Logan is about sparing a younger
generation,
the violence of their elders.
Then deadpool two maybe about spearing a
younger generation,
the cynicism of their elders.
The idea that deadpool is cynical is
pretty captain obvious,
inhabits all the tropes of a superhero
wild,
mocking them.
He shamelessly advertises but does so in
a self deprecating style that makes it
palatable.
In one instance,
Tequila ads had poorly plaster deadpool
faces on them that we're an actual
partnership.
He also,
above all else,
refuses to take anything seriously
including his own torture.
If deadpool,
the character is so cynical,
so willing to trivialize everything,
perhaps it's because he never really had
a family.
This negative part of his character
manifests itself and heightens the
conflict when he belittles Russell
within earshot and claims not to care
about him,
and if this ill fitting role model has
also abandoned Russell,
why should Russell think anyone could
love him?
At the end of the film,
deadpool approaches Russell and embraces
him to try to stop his pyromania spree,
but Russell doesn't buy it,
and why should he?
All the adults in his life have been
assholes.
The implication is because Russell
doesn't trust anyone because he's never
had a family.
He is without hope,
but when cable tries to shoot him dead,
pool takes the void proving to Russell
that someone cares.
Not only does this mean he doesn't have
to grow up and killed hundreds of
people,
but that he should allow himself to
trust others.
Logan died so that Laura could give up
violence and have a good life with her.
New x family and deadpool died so
russell could give up cynicism and
embrace his new x family.
Logan will never not be violent and
deadpool will never not be cynical,
but that doesn't mean we can't try to
help the children.
But again,
this movie is a kind of extended joke on
Logan.
Although deadpool has healed the
cynicism of Russell,
the film still takes the opposite
approach rather than a sad heartfelt
ending.
Deadpool doesn't actually die,
and the bait and switch with deadpool
sparing the school master as a ruse to
let dope hinder kill him.
It's just proof of this cynicism.
So where we expect progress,
we find none.
And if we had any doubts,
the after credit scenes show deadpool
making the entire first act irrelevant.
And also shooting the old deadpool in
the head,
so although deadpool may have saved
Russell from these cynical belief in not
being able to trust anyone,
the franchise itself is still as cynical
as ever.
And I'm sure commercials like this and
this will never go away,
but what do I know?
I'm just some asshole with a youtube
channel.
Seriously,
go,
go read a book,
or hey,
make a website with your own thoughts by
clicking here.
Also,
we're going to be talking about deadpool
two on our podcast.
Show me the meaning,
so subscribe to our channel or check
out,
show me the meaning on Itunes,
stitcher,
soundcloud,
or wherever you guys get your podcast.
And as always,
thanks for watching guys.
Piece.