This video is sponsored by Skillshare,
the first thousand people to sign up
with the link in the description.
We'll get their first two months for
just ninety nine cents.
The
greetings and welcome to earthlink
cinema.
I am your host,
Garrick's wormy Lloyd.
This week's artifact is the Truman show,
starring stand up,
turned,
impressionist turned comedic,
actor turned dramatic actor,
turned comedic,
actor turned nihilist.
There's no meaning dynamics slim carry.
The film follows lovable human male
Truman,
burbank who knows a thing or two about
sensible sweaters.
What he doesn't know is that he's
actually on a reality show because who
needs writers line his town was a movie
set.
His town is a movie set and keeping with
Hollywood tradition.
Everyone is fake.
Freaking up.
This freak show is tortured artist,
khristopher tortured because he wears a
bra to ensure truman doesn't get any
crazy ideas like swimming.
He makes Truman's dad drink too much.
Flash forward to the college years
season where Truman falls for a sexy
librarian,
actress,
and after some flirtatious running,
she tells him those three little words
every guy wants to hear.
Everything's alive before Truman can
say,
yeah,
I love you too.
Production intervenes and whisks her
away to the h,
two o company Fiji inconsolable beyond
words.
Truman marries the next person he sees,
but Truman can't get her out of his
hand,
so khristopher tries.
Bird Manningham.
Then it only makes things worse.
I'm not really sure how it could have
helped.
Truman starts noticing that his dead dad
looks a lot like the town's only
homeless guy and more alarmingly that
someone has canceled his Sirius xm
before you can say blah,
blah,
blah.
He Truman skipping town until
Khristopher pulls the old.
There's been a nuclear explosion,
so this one road is closed trick and
like all my family road trips,
it ends in divorce.
So Truman does his best Saddam
impression and hides when the network
can't find him.
They start a human hunt cut transmission
and air reruns of technical
difficulties.
Khristopher loses a ship,
but immediately finds Truman on it.
He makes it rain if you catch my drift.
Since HBO still holds the rights to
violent death,
they stopped the storm and Truman breaks
the fourth wall.
Truman tries to punch his way through
for a hot sec,
but gives up and goes for the fire exit
instead,
but khristopher has another trick up his
sleeve,
namely a Samsung Galaxy note.
He fires up the PA system that's been
there the whole time.
I can hear you and asks Truman back for
six more seasons in a movie,
but Truman's agents are sharks and
that's just the nature of the Biz.
The Truman show begs the question,
to what extent are recovered by some
unseen,
all powerful force,
otherwise known as Disney's the force
for Truman.
It's the latter.
A state referred to as the illogical
determinism,
but why you got to put a label on
things.
Every aspect of Truman's life,
from what he eats and where's is
controlled by Khristopher.
In fact,
Christopher's name is a variation on
Christ as in Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
Christ.
Through most of the film,
Truman struggles to free himself from
the system and make his own choices,
only to find offers flashmob poised and
ready to dance.
The film frames this age old debate in a
20th century context,
when most human lives were controlled by
the media,
instead of the chips inside their
brains,
Truman is literally owned by a studio
well until the right to revert back to
marvel has last name.
Burbank is a nod to the California and
city where the Warner Bros used to do
keg stands.
As we watch truman get ushered from
product to product by subtle
advertising.
We can't help but notice the same
attempts by the media to groom our
decisions.
That is a beer,
not that I would ever tell you to buy.
Kill Mo's eyebrow wax on sale.
Now for 6,000
Garba trons.
I just wouldn't.
Truman's journey to discover the truth
resembles the thought experiment,
the allegory of the cave by plate.
Oh,
Spaghetti.
The experiment imagines humans chained
to a wall only knowing shadows,
more popularly known as a sex dungeon.
Truman's worldview is similarly
constrained,
is cave is sea haven.
The actors are his shadows and his hair
is just perfect.
Plato's oppose that.
Once a prisoner ditched the cave,
he would prefer the outside world to the
dark.
Khristopher disagrees,
I think what distresses you said,
ultimately Truman prefers his cell,
but as the film climaxes Truman calls
him a liar,
liar.
His perseverance to retire from Showbiz
is reminiscent of Captain Ahab's classic
struggle with moby penis symbolically
representing the struggle between
mankind and God,
the novel ends and a good old fashion
drowning,
whereas Truman's ends and breathing the
final frames suggests that humans had
the will to control their own destiny,
which was true until president and Kylie
Jenner found out about it.
Birth link cinema.
I'm Garrick's Romeo void and in case I
don't see you.
Good afternoon,
good solstice and didn't
egg wise crack.
Garrett has intern,
jared again.
It took a lot of highly skilled people
to make the Truman show or reality
writers,
editors,
designers,
and more all working together to keep
Truman in the dark.
Writing,
editing,
filming.
These things aren't easy,
but there is a way you can start to get
good at them.
If you want to become your own Truman
show,
puppet master,
then checkout skillshare.
Just please don't use your new talents
to spy on people for entertainment.
We certainly wouldn't want to do that.
Skill shares and online learning
platform where you can access more than
18,000
courses and accounting in a wide variety
of subjects with skillshare,
you get to take part in classes designed
and led by experts in fields ranging
from design to business,
technology and everything in between.
For all you cinephiles out there that
even have a whole section of their
website dedicated exclusively to classes
on filmmaking.
Premium membership gives you unlimited
access to thousands of in depth classes
that will help you master your favorite
hobbies and promote your awesome work
and with annual subscriptions starting
at less than $10 per month.
Skillshare is one of the most affordable
learning platforms on the web,
and if you're looking to save even more,
the first thousand people to sign up at
[inaudible] dot ssh slash earthlink five
or at the Lincoln description will get
their first two months of skillshare for
just ninety nine cents.
Click here or follow the link below to
try it out.
We've got lots more great stuff on the
way,
including new videos on saw the wolf of
Wall Street and the bee movie,
so be sure to subscribe and ring that
bell to keep up with all our freshest
content.
Good afternoon,
good evening and goodnight piece.