Hey everyone,
meet boat jared here,
season three,
episode seven of Rick and Morty is one
of the darkest and densest of the
season.
In less than half an hour,
the episode managed to build a rich,
complex and utterly dismal political
world,
only for the show to summarily dismiss
it.
Still not curious about what might've
happened at that crazy senate up place,
not at all,
Laurie.
That place will never have any bearing
over our lives ever again,
but in that short time,
the rick lantis mix up paints a really
interesting picture of modern politics
specifically as it pertains to hope,
resistance and revolution.
Welcome this wise crack quick take on
the ric Lantis Mixup,
and you guessed it,
spoilers ahead,
but before we get into that,
I want to thank quid for sponsoring this
video quite as a really cool app that
allows you to collect stickers,
cards,
and toys for free.
Featuring a bunch of the shows we love
here at wise crack breaking bad
adventure time,
Bob's Burgers,
Star Trek,
and most importantly,
rick and morty.
Think of it like opening up packs of
baseball cards.
I've actually been collecting rick and
morty stickers for about a month now and
it's actually amazing how quick they are
to add new stickers.
Pretty much the day after a new episode
is released,
they have new gifts and stickers that
you can send to your friends over taxed
or slap onto images in your camera roll.
My favorite is the mailman from
[inaudible] that says,
mom,
man,
check out the description below for a
link to grab the APP for free.
It's available on Ios and android.
I'm on there as jared.
See One 37.
Last time we did this for a 600.
Have you added me as a friend and we had
some cool chats and trades with some of
you.
So Adam,
he is a friend and trade me all your
Miseq swag.
Thanks a bunch.
Back to the show.
So a quick recap,
rick and morty go on an adventure to
Atlantis,
but don't worry.
That actually doesn't matter.
Instead we're thrown into the citadel of
Rick's as they rebuild after the
catastrophic events of the shank.
Redemption,
democratic elections are being held for
the first time in the wake of the
disillusion of the council districts.
Hold on,
hold on.
The world building in this episode is
freaking amazing,
especially in how it cleverly mirrors
our current political climate from a
news organization that's only one end
away from CNN that trivializes descent
in order to maintain the status quo.
Anyway,
so yeah,
the suspect says the citadels ally built
on lies,
and some others,
I say appreciate the life you have
because it can always be worse
to an intercity devastated by drugs and
guns to a hogwarts that teaches the
disenfranchised mortise to accept their
lot in life.
This is a great adventure.
This is definitely one of the harder
narratives to follow and certainly more
complex than your traditional episode.
So I want to lay out the many subplots
as follows.
Evil morty comes to power on a platform
of unity and change before revealing his
grander and more totalitarian intentions
in an illusion to training day,
a fresh out of the academy police,
rick has to join a crooked cop,
morty,
and confront the corrupt underbelly of
the citadel where he is forced to
confront his ideals and abandoned them.
It seems reminiscent of the ending of La
confidential.
We're an idealistic cop,
has to break the rules and kill his
superior undermining the same justice
system he fought.
He was protecting a group of orphaned
morty.
Set off for an adventure.
I'll last stand by me before sending
their hopes and dreams into the literal
trash,
garbage dump.
Stand back.
Hey,
rick is passed over for a promotion and
realizes he's wasted his life on an
assembly line.
He revolts,
but his triumph is quickly ruined by the
powers that be.
In all of these cases,
we see any kind of political or personal
optimism for change,
crushed by a cruel and indifferent
reality.
This episode really builds off the
themes that we talked about earlier in
Rick Man,
sing the stone,
specifically alienation or the way
modern society is strange as us from the
world and our peers making us all dead
inside.
In the case of rick man seeing the
stone,
the creature comforts of society turn
the exciting world of the apocalypse
into a domestic nightmare.
Now we see many versions of the smartest
man in the universe reduced to the
drudgery of modern life and mixed in.
We see signs of a deeply divided
society.
The number of displaced mortise is
soaring woolrich rick.
Satisfaction levels are plummeting and
the divide between the two groups has
never been whiter.
Saw that one real quick,
but as evil morty suggests,
this is a distraction.
Sentidos problem.
Isn't homeless mortise or outraged
drinks?
The citadels problem is the rick and
morty is feeding on the citadels deck.
The real divide,
the rich versus the working class.
I don't see a divide between Rick's and
mortise.
The division IC is between the bricks
and mortars that liked the citadel
divided and the rest of us.
What's interesting is
that despite the apparent ruling class
of Rick's,
everyone is a big thing.
Some of alienation told us we were
special because we were rick,
but they stripped us of everything that
made us unique.
That doesn't sound like brick work.
You didn't come to the citadel to be a
plumber.
Did you?
Even the cops are like into just workers
on the assembly line of Justice.
We know how you feel.
We're working just like you,
but our assembly line is justice,
but in addition to being victims of
those individuals in power,
the rics are also victims of an
impenetrable system,
and here's where my favorite part of the
whole app
episode comes in.
His name is simple rick,
but he's no dummy.
He realized long ago that the greatest
thing he'd ever create was his daughter.
We captured that moment.
We run it on a loop through simple
rick's mind and the chemical that makes
his brains to create goes into every
simple rick simple wafers,
wafer cookie,
come home to the impossible flavor of
your own completion.
Come home to simple rick's.
This gets at a really smart question
tackled by a lot of different
philosophers,
but I'll summarize the issue as this is
our escape from the alienation of modern
life.
Just strengthening the foundations of
the system that drives that alienation.
Simple follows what I'll call beat Ron
Swanson trope someone who fights are
fast paced world by slowing down,
working with their hands and spending
time with the family and a world that
crams us into cubicles and hunches.
US over assembly lines are only respect
is the simple life running away from the
urban clamor,
living off the land,
learning a trade like woodworking,
reconnecting with your family,
et Cetera.
Not surprisingly,
this kind of idea gained prevalence as
the world was industrialized and
subsequently corporatized.
We saw the rise of organizations like
the boy scouts and the establishment of
national parks where you could practice
not being crammed in a city,
but it could be argued that this escaped
the simple life.
Whether in the form of nature or family
or woodworking is not in fact retreating
from the system,
but an essential part of its
functioning.
We can view these simple rick wafers
brand as a kind of fantasy that
reinforces the system rick show up for
work because they know they can go home
and allegedly unplugged from the system
with the distilled essence of
simplicity.
Even though this unplugging comes in
commodity form,
one that requires you know,
money that you have to work for at an
assembly line,
and we've all seen enough cereal
commercials to know that advertisers
love selling us a kind of pure,
wholesome family who actually eats meals
together without screaming at each
other.
Sociologists,
George Ritter says that our enchantment
and disenchantment from the modern world
are not so easy to distinguish from each
other.
He says they exist and a reciprocal
relationship.
In other words,
the fantasy of unplugging with some
simple rick wafers further entrenches
you in the very system you want to
unplug from,
but it gets even more devious.
As one rick decides he's had enough and
engages in an actual act of rebellion,
killing his boss and trying to get a
portal gun to actually escape the
system,
but instead of affecting change,
his rebellion is commodified in the form
of the simple rick.
Freedom wafers selects come home to the
unique flavor of shattering the grand
illusion.
He endlessly lives the joy of rebellion.
While the system distills this joy in a
consumable form,
freedom from the system in traps you in
the system.
Richard goes onto say that fantasies
drop people into the new means of
consumption and those fantasies can be
rationalized in order to further draw
people in,
and this for me makes this the darkest
episode of the season.
Yet the message seems to be in the
terrifying political reality that is
2017.
The best we can hope for is the illusion
of making a difference.
If you don't believe me,
remember the orphan mortise plot.
They go on a coming of age adventure
trying to escape their terrible orphan
existence and their bondage to some
future rick,
but the wish portal turns out to be a
garbage portal.
The system turns wishes into literal
trash,
slick morty sacrifices himself to wish
for a better world and it happens sort
of holy crap.
Slicks wish came true.
I don't think we're meant to believe
that his sacrifice magically made things
better,
especially because the change promised
was just a ploy by evil.
Morty.
The subplot has no actual bearing on the
overall narrative.
It only seems to exist for the riders to
show us the naive ideas of these
children that slick morty sacrifice
could have changed something.
Nothing they did mattered,
but they get to believe it did just like
are revolting rick.
So what do we make of evil?
He sold a kind of class consciousness to
the rics and mores of the citadel that
bricks and mortar,
you should join together to make a
better world against the ruling elite,
but with the brutal purge of his
political opponents.
It seems like this was nothing more than
lip service as a means to power,
but hey,
could we really expect any kind of real
progress from this show?
There's just so much going on in this
episode that we haven't touched on.
Like is there some connection between
this Latin phrase on the chalkboard and
evil mortise view of how society
functions will discuss this as well as
dive into the shows commentary on the
media,
state violence,
and who really controls the government
on the squatch wise cracks,
rick and Morty podcast,
check it out on itunes,
stitcher,
Google play,
or wherever you get your podcasts.
The link is in the description and don't
forget to subscribe.
Well,
beloved dub wl piece.