Hey wisecrack jared here,
and we've got a special quick take to
prime you guys for the release of blade
runner 2049.
As you might guess,
we're big fans of the original blade
runner and are super excited to see how
the sql not only continues the plot,
but develops the themes that made the
original so legendary to wet our
appetite.
Even more crunchy roll has a first look
on a 15 minute blade runner,
animate directed by cowboy bebop.
Mega director Shin is Watson Nabi that
bridges the original and the sequel,
and it's actually really good.
Not only does it carry on the same
visual style and the Neos,
Anwar pitch black tone,
but it reflects on many of the same
themes and symbols present in the
original.
So big thanks to crunch roll role for
giving us an exclusive sneak peek at the
short and making this video possible.
Blade runner is a really dense,
profound film full of symbols that also
make an appearance in blackout 2022.
So let's unpack how these symbols give
us a better understanding of what it
means to be human and perhaps derive a
sense of what we can expect from blade
runner.
Twenty,
49.
Welcome to this wisecrack quick take on
blade runner and blackout 20 slash 22
and heads up.
This discussion will spoil some key plot
points of the anime.
So if you want to watch it right now for
free,
had you crunchy roll.com/wise
crack.
So let's get to first a quick recap of
blackout 2022 to replicants Trixie and
ag go on a mission to destroy a database
that holds a registry of all replicants
on earth.
One of the primary themes of the
original is interrogating the line
between human and Automaton,
both blade runner and blackout 20.
To explore this dynamic using three key
symbols,
the eye,
the doll,
and the dove.
Number one on the original blade runner
places,
significant emphasis on eyes.
The void contest examines eyes to detect
if someone is a replicant or not.
Roy and Leon meet the designer of their
own eyes,
and Roy even kills his own maker by
giving him an extreme bits of Iq
puncture.
Similarly in blackout,
the characters right eyes are coated
with a mark,
identifying them as replicants Bi is
also relevant and how replicants and
humans define themselves through images
and symbols.
For example,
the replicant Leon is obsessed with
finding photos because these visual
symbols reinforced the idea that he has
a history proof of having existed.
There's actually a pretty interesting
postmodern commentary here.
Many philosophers,
including wisecrack favorite genre,
beaudry yard,
have discussed how all of us now think
of our past as a series of images,
photo albums,
instagram,
facebook,
photos,
et cetera.
Our Past,
like the replicants,
has just become a series of photos,
symbols,
or video images.
Similarly,
the main drive of the protagonists in
blackout to destroy a database registry
that lists them as replicants.
By removing these signs that defined
them as not human,
they are destroying the one thing,
separating them from humanity.
Number two,
the dol in blade runner,
Chris,
a pleasure model,
just like trixie disguises herself.
It's a doll amongst other nonsense toys,
while in blackout 20 slash 22,
trixie carries a stuffed doll.
In both cases,
the dol indicates how humans distinguish
themselves from replicants.
They're largely considered to be doll
like lifeless Automaton,
but why?
Philosopher David Hume argues that the
only thing that distinguishes us from
dolls is our experience.
He says that mankind is nothing but a
bundle or collection of different
perceptions.
This bundle theory says that all we are
is just a collection of experiences and
memories held together in a sack of
meat,
and this is how we define ourselves as
human,
but as the film points out replicants to
find themselves in the same way,
even though her memories are
artificially implanted,
Rachel is convinced of her own humanity
and even carries a photo of herself as a
child.
Implanted or not.
If you have memories,
what's the difference?
Utilizing their experience,
both trixie and Chris Challenged,
they're prescribed faked shedding this
idea of the doll and asserting their
humanity.
This is why trixie leaves her doll
behind as she goes into ass whooping.
So who is to say they're just lifeless
dolls?
Number three,
the dump,
the final symbol has caused so much
debate since the release of the original
blade runner and its appearance in 20
slash 22 makes it all the more
significant in the original movie Roy,
he gives his famous speech while holding
a dove and releases it just as he
expires.
Similarly in 2022,
trixie observes a dub as she sails
through the air before coming to a
crashing end herself because of how
briefly the doves are seen and
importantly when they are seeing,
it's easy to interpret them in a number
of ways as a symbol of life departing or
alternatively as life continuing or even
as just another Automaton,
as blade runner suggests,
most organic animals no longer exist if
you like our own
sort official.
Of course it is.
However,
our favorite interpretation of the dove
is that it represents a certain kind of
freedom.
The sort of freedom the characters yearn
for can be found in what soren
kierkegaard refers to as despair.
Kierkegaard defines despair is the
tension between life and are inevitable
death and the search for meaning they're
in.
While for Keaker Guard,
this was solved by aligning yourself
with God for the replicants,
no heaven or hell before us.
This world is all gone,
so like a lot of people living in are
more secular age.
We free ourselves from this tension or
despair by being conscious of that
understanding and defining ourself,
which is exactly the replicants do.
Roy spends the film fighting this
tension by searching for more life
beyond his four year expiration date and
tell when he feels his body beginning to
degrade and his end is near.
He chooses to fight his programming as a
combat model and spares deckerd.
He then delivers this speech that brings
tears to the eyes of nerds everywhere.
Oh,
the moment will be lost in time,
like tears,
right,
referring to the bundle of experiences
that he has seen throughout his life.
Perhaps this indicates that he has
finally defied his programming by
defining himself and thus is free of his
existential despair,
even if he didn't get more life.
Unlike in the original movie,
Trixie and Iggy are seeking the power to
allow them to define themselves by
destroying the registry that the humans
use to define them as replicants.
In doing this,
we see trixie breakaway from her
programming as a pleasure doll and
become a backflipping baptist,
thus liberating herself from her
predetermined role.
In both cases,
freedom must be fought for and claimed.
If a 15 minute prologue by the same
studio can pack all this sexy stuff than
20,
$49.
Sounds pretty promising and we didn't
even get into the whole is decorative
replicant debate,
but that's going to have to wait for
another time.
For now,
be sure to see blackout 20 slash 22 for
free@crunchyroll.com
slash wise crack.
And if you want to watch an ad free
signup for a free 30 day trial on us and
while you're there,
be sure to check out other great anime
like my hero academia,
dragon ball super,
and cowboy bebop.
So big thanks to crunchy roll for making
this video possible and giving us a
sneak peek at Watanabe's.
New anime catchall.
Next time guys,
peace.