This video supported by our friends over
at Cheddar.
Hey,
wise crack jared here.
Unless you're living in a galaxy far,
far away,
you've probably heard about the recent
star wars backlash.
Some fans hated last I so much they
issued an anti Disney manifesto,
run an actress off instagram,
are crowdfunding for a remake and have
claimed credit for Solos failure at the
box office.
There were even rumors that Kathleen
Kennedy v President of Lucas films would
retire early,
possibly influenced by twitter.
This may seem like a bunch of fanboys
throwing tantrums or Russian bots.
And while both of those may be partly
true,
I can't help but think there's something
way deeper going on here.
So join us as we try to use philosophy
to explain the current crisis of the
Star Wars Universe and some minor last
jet.
I spoilers ahead.
Also for any of our fans that live in
la,
we're going to be hosting a live
Halloween show on October 26 with our
movie podcast crew and Adam Kovac from
fun house.
So check out the invite and the link to
tickets in the description.
But first a quick recap of what people
hate about the new star wars.
While there's some rather unpleasant
threads of criticism on the Internet,
some people hate the new star wars for a
reason.
That director Ryan Johnson is pretty
overt about subverting the Canon or as
he likes to call it,
killing the past
raised parents aren't skywalkers or
[inaudible] or some other great family,
but nobody's,
despite the constant mystery box teasing
in the force awakens,
we get no storied rise of snuck or
reveal that he's Mace Windu or
something,
just an unceremonious death and then
there's luke.
We're supposed to believe this wholesome
hero who once saw the light in the
darkest of villains is now throwing
light sabers off cliffs and almost
killing his child nephew.
That just didn't seem right with Disney.
Now putting all of their extended
universe movies on hold and New Star
Wars spinoffs getting universally panned
by fans.
It seems like the world of star wars is
in crisis.
What's happening with star wars is not
so different from a problem often faced
by social systems or what political
philosopher Juergen Habermas calls a
legitimation crisis,
I.
E.
N existential crisis that threatens the
foundation of a social system.
Social Systems are made of three
subparts,
the governmental,
the socio cultural,
and the economic.
They all interact and in some ways these
three systems map onto the system of
star wars fandom.
Let's start with the government side.
See,
the system needs some kind of story or
idea to give it legitimacy.
Governments do this through different
means.
Monarchies claim their legitimacy is
derived from God.
Democracies through election by the
people,
constitutional governments through well
constitutions.
Even dictators claim legitimacy in one
way or another.
Some by they represent the will of the
people.
Other things help to making sure your
citizens are warm and fed or the
economic does wonders to make them ask
fewer questions about how or why your
allowed to be in.
So what happens when this is called into
question?
What happens when the people no longer
feel a system is upholding its values or
that those values are antiquated and
useless?
What if people feel betrayed when a huge
corporation takes over their beloved
franchise only to birth what some
consider to be an unholy abomination.
When this happens,
people stop obeying and start rebelling.
Think about countries whose populations
take to the streets when they suspect
that their new leaders rig the election
and therefore aren't legitimate.
If we use this as a metaphor for star
wars,
a lot of things start to make sense.
Lucas was basically the divinely
ordained monarch of the Star Wars
Universe,
which consisted not just at the six
films he made,
but also a ton of spinoffs in the form
of video games,
board games,
cartoons and tie in novels.
They got the royal seal of approval from
Lucasfilm,
so maybe it's more like a constitutional
monarchy,
but his legitimacy also came from the
fact that he,
you know,
created it all together with Lucas Star
Wars fans helped create a fully
functioning social system with shared
practices,
beliefs,
values,
and agreed upon rules of operation.
That's what harbor might call the socio
cultural side of this system.
Habermas calls this kind of socially
cohesive system.
Laytonsville a life world.
And the Jed,
I could Laban Svelte with the best of
them.
The general meaning of Star Wars,
the values it represents,
the characters that is develop,
the stories it tells and the themes that
define it were originally laid out by
Lucas and we're more or less agreed upon
within the community.
Okay,
maybe you hate George Jar book.
You got over it.
Lucas's word was still star wars law.
Even if you didn't exactly like it,
they need a medical rank like all life
worlds.
This star wars universe also helped
create a sense of individual identity
when people use these values and beliefs
to make meaning of their lives.
That is until 2012 when Disney bought
Lucas films and she started to get
crazy,
I guess you could say there's been a
regime change and suddenly,
at least from the perspective of some
fans,
Lord Lucas was replaced by a money
hungry animated mouse.
Now do we have a problem?
It's like the governmental equivalent of
Queen Elizabeth relinquishing the throne
and after a nice surprise,
ending the British monarchy to Mary
Berry.
After Disney gained rights to all star
wars intellectual property and started
making controversial decisions,
they found themselves in a big old
legitimation crisis.
What the fan base is going through can
perhaps be best understood by looking at
one of the biggest legitimation crises
of the last millennia,
one that changed the landscape of the
entire world.
You see,
Disney is facing the same kind of
legitimation crisis the Catholic Church
did in the 15 hundreds when their
congregations began to rebel.
Up until the 16th century,
the leadership of the Catholic Church
had total control over the meaning of
the Bible.
Since only priests,
bishops,
the pope and maybe the occasional rich
guy had access to hard copies.
Books,
including the Bible,
were so expensive that very few ever
learned to read.
This famously allowed the church to get
away with some seriously shady shit like
making people pay the church and the
form of indulgences to get their loved
ones out of purgatory.
But all that changed when good old
Johnny Gutenberg invented the printing
press in 1440 and enabled the rapid
reproduction of texts.
Suddenly regular people could read the
Bible and what do you know?
They had slightly different
interpretations of some of those crucial
techs.
In this case,
a crisis of legitimation happened
because the masses,
we're no longer merely consuming
religious meaning,
but also helping produce canonical
interpretations.
The legitimacy and authority of the
Catholic Church was seriously thrown
into question by people like Martin
Luther who posted 95 reasons why the
Catholic church sucked right on their
door.
This crisis of legitimation and the
proliferation of different kinds of
Christianity really sucked for Europe as
competing factions really,
really liked murdering each other.
So in this metaphor,
the Bible is the original star wars
universe.
And why did George Lucas get to
interpret it however he wanted because
he wrote it,
maybe he's not Jesus in this analogy,
but he's at least an apostle or a
prophet.
But now the authority has moved from a
single divinely inspired leader to a
larger and fallible organization.
And people question why they wield
authority and developing clause.
I holy texts or it's Canon and the
recent films,
but especially with the last Jedi,
they changed many of the agreed upon
values,
meanings and truths of the star wars
system.
If there was just a change of hands from
Lucas to Disney with the administration
of star wars remaining mostly the same,
people may not have asked questions,
but without the legitimacy of Lucas,
people started asking more questions and
Disney didn't stop there.
They also put the very identity of the
community when they took a super laser
to the Canon,
the canonizing radio dramas,
video games,
comics,
and hundreds of spinoff novels that
Lucasfilm previously considered part of
the Gospel.
Remember that a life world is important
because it defines a community by
clarifying who's in and out and who you
can trust.
You can't just go around hacking and
slashing what counts as star wars
because people's identities are wrapped
up in this star wars enthusiasts aren't
just consumers of this cannon.
They've helped make the meaning of the
Star Wars universe like the Catholic
church.
Disney now faces the wrath of the
educated masses,
except now the problem isn't just that
people can read a blog,
tweet,
make video essays,
produced their own cartoons and stream
content to millions of viewers and for
every Martin Luther,
there are a million angry youtubers and
bloggers each posting their own 95
problems with Disney star wars.
We live in an age where people aren't
just consuming media but are also
producing it where pro sumo and if
protestantism emerged with a printing
press and literacy took the interpretive
power away from the dude's with the
funny hats.
It seems like the age of the prosumer
empowers people to criticize the few
anointed successors of Lucas.
Now pro-sumer I know it sounds like we
made that word up,
but it's actually a technical term
coined in the 1980s by Futurists,
Alvin and Heidi Toffler to describe how
the role of the producer and consumer
merge in the age of modern technology.
Star wars hands are basically prosumers.
Extraordinary.
Everyday fans have played a huge role in
creating meaning of star wars by sharing
youtube videos,
posting video essays or fan theories.
Subscribing to our slash empire did
nothing wrong or re tweeting.
Lord palpatine in the age of pro-sumer
ism every theory about where Luke was
all this time,
who snuck his,
which Jeddah uses which light saber
fighting styles is one way of
contributing to the Star Wars universe.
It's a way for the community to practice
star wars.
Now imagine if you engage in your
religious tradition in your community
and all of the sudden the recently
appointed Church authority tells you
you're doing it all wrong.
The wafers are alive and while star wars
maybe the latest,
it isn't the only franchise open to
legitimation crises within their
communities.
Pro symbolism is beginning to affect the
relations between fans and producers
even scaring away.
James Mangold,
director of Logan,
who recently tweeted at the point when
work writing and directing big
franchises has become the emotionally
loaded equivalent of writing a new
chapter of the Bible with the probable
danger of being stoned and called a
blast femur.
Then a lot of bolter minds are going to
leave these films to hacks and corporate
boards.
So is the star wars system about to
collapse under the weight of its crisis?
Not necessarily.
The Catholic Church obviously didn't
crumble under there legitimation hiccup
and maybe star wars won't either because
the thing is systems learn.
After a few Vatican council's and papel
death,
the Catholic Church managed to revise
some of the violent theology and really
solidified the community under common
goals and shared beliefs.
Sure there were Protestants who totally
pieced out and started their own thing.
But in general the system learned,
adjusted and stayed intact.
So the question is,
which direction will the star wars
system take?
We'll Disney find a way to evolve in the
time of prosumer ism,
respecting their fans and the universe
they've helped create.
Will fans choose to grow with the system
and find new ways of interacting with
their beloved material?
Or will there be a reckoning where
Disney in the fans part,
ways like the Catholics and Protestants
each starting their own version of the
religion and competing for the souls of
viewers.
Let us know what you guys think.
And if you enjoyed our take on the star
wars crisis and I highly recommend
checking out our friends over at Cheddar
the recently launched their own youtube
channel and are cranking out awesome
videos that cover business,
tech media and news without the boring
parts from the inside scoop on the
latest news stories,
too detailed answers or even the most
ambiguous questions Cheddar has got you
covered.
Gender also produces videos that examine
the triumphs and failures of the media
we enjoy.
So I just watched their video on how
bankrupt marvel risked its main
characters to save itself as suggest.
You guys check it out too.
So they give you an inside look at how
marvel went from filing bankruptcy in
1996 to making James Cameron quiver on
his throne of shattered box office
records.
So watch the video and perhaps you'll a
new hope that Disney can redeem the
beloved star wars franchise.
And if you like it,
consider subscribing to their channel.
Just click here or the link below for
more videos from Cheddar.
And as always,
guys,
thanks for watching peace.