Crack Jerod here today.
We've got a favorite among the wise
crack staff,
the tale of humans picked for
experimental augmentations to find out
what happens when people stop being
polite,
start getting real at first.
Look,
the DSX franchise franchises,
they kind of wet dream for info wars
enthusiasts.
Murderous clocks by the Illuminati are
carried out by world governments while
the player traverses fema camps and
discovers the truth behind fake news,
but unlike certain performance artists,
dance sexist forays into conspiracy
serve as more than just a means to sell
dietary.
So the game reveals how paranoia informs
more of societies decisions than we'd
like to admit and serves as a cautionary
tale for the dangers of technology comp.
But there are no gay frogs.
Sorry,
Internet,
I don't like him putting chemicals in
the water that turned the frigging frogs
gay.
Welcome to this wise crack condition on
Dsx.
This video was made in collaboration
with our buddy Joseph over at real life.
Lord,
you can learn more about his channel and
check out his related video at the end
of this one.
And if you're here visiting from real
life,
Laura,
welcome and be sure to subscribe,
spoilers ahead for all the games.
The day sx series asks two basic
questions.
One,
what would it mean for society if we
could all become cyborgs with Jack's
arms and to what does the premise that
every conspiracy theory is true mean for
the real world?
And before we get into the ethics of
skull guns and neural enhancement,
we have to put on our tinfoil hats.
There is no shortage of conspiracy
theories in the day,
a sex series in the original game,
a splinter organization of the
Illuminati called majestic 12,
produces a nan night virus called the
gray debt as a means to consolidate
their power.
Why contain it?
Let it spill over into the schools and
churches let the bodies pile up in the
streets.
In the end,
they'll beg us to save them as producers
of the only cure for the disease as
well.
They can easily manipulate others while
capitalizing off the disorder.
Wrought by it.
The great death is a manmade virus.
Everyone up to the president is at
UNESCO's mercy,
as long as you Naccho controls the
supply.
If Ambrosia in the cul invisible war,
the illuminati controls two of the most
influential groups in the world,
the World Trade Organization and the
order a religious organization opposed
to the WTO.
By managing the conflict between these
two factions,
the Illuminati is better able to control
the world.
Finally,
in the new prequels,
we see the illuminati attempt to limit
human augmentation.
Since having a bunch of engineered super
humans running around isn't really great
for the whole compliant population thing
that they're going for.
If there's one thread that has run
through the sometimes vastly different
games in the series,
it's paranoia.
Not only is there the conspiracy,
paranoia,
but also paranoia directed at so called
outsiders and others.
Why don't you much greater going?
Ultimately,
the Games are fueled,
the profound power of paranoia and that
it doesn't matter whether the paranoia
points to the truth or not.
Paranoia,
independent of truth shapes our actions
and ultimately society.
Early on in the game.
Gunter,
your sidebar,
coworker,
who yearns for a skull gun is convinced
that the facility staff is replacing
orange soda in the vending machines with
lemon lime in an inane and unlikely
conspiracy against him.
The machine will not make a mistake.
It's still maintenance,
man.
He knows I like.
Oh,
so you think the staff has some kind of
plot?
Yes,
to do that on purpose,
except 20 years later in the game
sequel,
it's revealed in the ruins of gunters
office that he was right all along,
denying people their natural born rights
to choose their own artificially
flavored destiny's.
Like I said,
there's just something wrong with that
machine.
Probably some sort of office politics as
if to foreshadow the entire rest of the
game.
This idea of just because you're
paranoid doesn't mean they're not.
After you becomes the main ethos of Dsx
in mankind.
Divided colleague Spin Wild Tales of
getting hacked,
which turn out to be true.
We have a lot of enemies.
The people who bombed the train station,
you don't think they'd love to know
where we are.
You need to help me figure out who's
looking into us and make them stop other
suspect,
a police coverup of a bombing there
probably destroying all the evidence
there is right now.
Also true and I was right.
Even you,
the player must navigate who to trust
your old time boss David Saraf,
pilot Alex Vega,
your new boss that Interpol who may or
may not be working for the Illuminati at
every point.
The game undermined your trust in others
as you hack into the emails of your
coworkers installed listening devices
and get ambushed by enemies who were
tipped off about your arrival hell.
Even the suicide cult that wants to
merge with computers and mankind
divided,
turn out to only be a few years off from
being right.
JC Denton manages to do this with Helios
at the end of the original day of sex.
So why does sex make a point to validate
even the most far fetched ideas?
It could be in part a greater message
about how paranoia works in the real
world.
People who are paranoid often don't
invent things out of nothing,
but instead take interpretive leaps when
over analyzing the data presented to
them or if you thought he was high
strung before the attack only made him
more manic.
He's making connections.
No one else sees some that may not be
there,
but rather than dismissing this kind of
paranoia as mere delusion dsx runs with
it is a man rambling in the sewers about
mind control,
right?
Part of it,
the hive mind inside the gate,
I questioned what holds us together were
unequivocally yes.
You mean your attempt to control people,
amplifying your hypnotic techniques with
some kind of social enhancer.
This brings me to one of mankind.
Divided is most important commentaries.
Tracing the relationship between general
paranoia and racial paranoia.
Augmented humans as a metaphor for
racial discrimination isn't exactly
subtle as a mechanically augmented
Interpol agent.
You face harassments from the citizens
of Prague and literally live on the
wrong side of the tracks.
As you witnessed routine police
brutality inflicted on your augmented
peers.
Do you understand what fuels this
discrimination?
We're turning to cigar enthusiast and
psychoanalyst Jacques Lacan,
or at least with these liberty and
Dumbledore,
writes about him and forced flyboys.
Jack are paranoid.
Theories often reflect our own
identities,
ideologies and shortcomings rather than
the actual state of things.
For instance,
he cites a story from Lacan regarding a
jealous husband who even ever right that
his wife is sleeping around,
is still pathologically jealous.
If she stays late at work,
he'll pathologically assume she's being
unfaithful.
If she starts having male friends.
Same thing as a development of this
logic.
Gisha excites Nazi antisemitism.
If a Jewish person committed a crime,
it could very well be true,
but the fixation on Jewish crime spoke
more to German paranoia about foreigners
in pure blood then to any kind of real
issue.
In other words,
crime is just crime until a Jewish
person commits it,
then it becomes part of the Grand Jewish
conspiracy to ruin the German race and
so on.
You can look at conspiracy theories in
the same light are most laws made in
closed door meetings with lobbyists and
interest groups probably.
Are they all part of a secret cult to
serve their reptilian overlords?
Probably not.
Likewise,
in Dsx and he augmentation advocates
filter all information through the Lens
that augmented people are dangerous and
possibly an affront to nature,
talking heads use terrorism,
or the catastrophic August incident
where augmented people were hacked into
going into a homicidal rage to justify
apartheid style oppression of augmented
people.
This discrimination then fuels even more
violence,
thus making augmented paranoia,
a self fulfilling prophecy.
Everyone looking over their shoulder
terrified.
We're going to attack them again.
Somebody probably will treat people like
animals long enough.
They'll start acting like animals.
The power of paranoia to shape public
discourse can be seen in Dsx.
Eliza [inaudible],
defense of news coverage meant to
spread.
Fear toward the augmented is just
reporting the news.
Let Ms Dot Kim.
News outlets are simply reporting on the
current situation
and even if the reporting is true for
guest points out,
you can choose to only show my shoe,
which is very ugly,
but that is only a small part of me.
News outlets only care about a small
part.
I'm sorry Ms Dot Dossen,
but you can't trust the news outlets if
you want to understand the world.
The Org debate in the news functions on
two levels,
one as aquin points out to only report
on the negative aspects of augmented
existence and to to use augmented
violence as a validation for your larger
ideological project in this case be
human restoration act,
a bill that would either remove or
severely limit to the augmentations that
people have of course on like real world
news Pikus is news coverage is dictated
by the Illuminati.
I was engineered
to monitor communications and data
streets to find out what people are
talking about and make sure it's being
discussed to correctly
as they cover up evidence of water
contamination in Prague and falsely
report that a flight was taken down by
an augmented terrorist
in yet another terror attack.
Two hundred and 51 passenger airlines
flight
rather than the truth that the plane was
shot down by a military installation
plane went down because of whatever the
military was doing there.
Not because of some augmented passenger
like bike is.
Clamps
are these paranoia is don't tell us much
about reality itself,
but instead shine light on the reality
behind the paranoia for Dsx,
that reality is a carefully constructed
story meant to combat augmentation so
that the Illuminati can better control
the population for their pro business
purposes,
but is there an even deeper truth to the
way paranoia operates in the game?
While the real world is not governed by
the Illuminati?
Depending on who you ask,
one could argue that it is governed by
the basic principle,
which the Illuminati in Dsx understands
this state of exception.
According to philosophers,
Giorgio Agamben,
there is a hidden law that why's behind
both modern liberal democracies and the
totalitarian regimes of the 20th
century.
The exception.
We've talked about this before in our
walking dead and attack on titan videos,
but they,
uh,
sex is exploration is wholly unique.
Accumbent builds off the theory of
sometimes,
right,
but always an asshole.
Carl Schmitt who argued that would
define sovereignty is not that the law
per se,
but the ability to suspend the law to
make the exception for Gambon.
This suspension of law marks all
totalitarian regimes.
The concentration camps were a physical
space where normal law was suspended for
more than a decade,
a state of exception,
whereas our modern liberal democracies
aren't building death camps.
The state of exception isn't always
imminent component of modern governance,
usually in the name of a national
emergency or an existential threat.
Governments today regularly create zones
of exception where the law no longer
applies or creates classes of people who
are outside the normal functioning of
the law and thus exist in this kind of
exceptional state.
Prisoners of war protected by
international law get replaced by enemy
combatants who gets sent to get mo were
regular us.
Law doesn't apply in DSX.
This logic seems implicit to the
conspiracy theory favorite fema in the
name of managing emergencies.
They build detention camps for political
prisoners and implement martial law,
be segregated.
Udall at complex of mankind divided
presents a similar zone of exception in
resembles a mix of apartheid era,
South Africa,
Jewish ghettos,
Becau,
luned,
wall city and Modern Day refugee camps.
The player witnesses horrifying examples
of police brutality and augmented people
who live in constant fear all in the
name of security,
and when tensions boiled over,
such as when an augmented rights
activist is assassinated,
the civil unrest justifies even more if
the illuminati wants to spread chaos
like staging a train station bombing,
it's because they understand that chaos
breeds people desiring security,
and when people desire security,
it's all the easier to suspend basic
rights and exert more authority.
While we may think of chaos and order as
opposites,
the game understands how they can become
entangled in the modern world.
Chaos is manufactured in discreet ways
in order for oppressive powers to
maintain control,
but besides illuminating,
no pun intended,
how security operates even in our own
non illuminati world.
They esx also uses the state of
exception as just one of its many
criticisms of transhumanism.
Transhumanism is the idea that
technology will help us overcome human
limitations like disease and scarcity,
prosthetics,
contact lenses,
and in vitro fertilization or just
stepping stones in the greater
transhumans project.
Transhumanism is baked into the very
idea of human augmentation asx.
However,
rather than blindly celebrating,
transhumanism,
it portends everything that could
possibly go wrong as the human race
unlock human potential and mastery over
nature that technology becomes available
to individuals and groups and can
potentially fall into the wrong hands.
Even augmentation technology developed
by the Illuminati soon escaped their
control as private corporations entered
the fray,
this forced the Illuminati to change
their stance and oppose augmentation.
No,
by going public with this discovery,
Saraf is forcing our hand.
Invisible war starts with a terrorist
attack that turns everything into a grey
goose and in mankind divided,
there exists an underground market for
augmentations which is likely assisting
both the good guys and bad guys.
As such,
the destructive potential of technology
often necessitates permanent states of
emergencies and martial law.
That accumbens work was critical of
basically,
as technology gets to epic,
the government will have little problem
convincing you that your rights have to
be suspended for the good of everyone,
but it's not just the state of exception
that's a problem for the transhumanist
future.
JBS Haldane,
one of the earliest thinkers of
transhumanism warrant in 1924 that
society would have a hard time keeping
pace with the progress of technology in
data lists or science in the future.
He wrote that the tendency of applied
science is to magnify injustices until
they become to intolerable to be born
and the average man who all of the
profits and poets could not move turns
at last and extinguishes the evil at its
source.
In other words,
technology will make social injustice is
worse until societal anger will boil
over into a full on rage in Dsx.
More often than not,
the dangers of technology are thrust
upon the poor.
Those who are augmented need to
constantly take neuropazine to stop
their body from rejecting their
augmentations,
but those with means can much more
easily obtained the drug.
And in the case of manual laborers or
soldiers who are augmented by their
employers,
let me guess.
Most of the laborers will mentored with
heavy duty industrial rings or the
government sends you what they want,
do what they want,
replace parts of you whenever and
however they want.
They exist in a precarious state where
the maintenance of their augmentations
is contingent on them maintaining the
same or similar job rather than
suggesting that human evolution through
technology will level the playing field
they isx suggests societal forces will
make inequality worse and just as
Haldane warns that this tension will
cause people to rise up and root out
evil at its source.
We see two competing movements in the
game focused on the same thing in human
revolution.
The humanity front uses violence to stop
the spread of augmentation and and
mankind divided.
A legal solution exists in the human
restoration act.
Meanwhile,
augmented people slowly entertained
violence as a political strategy and
tell the assassination of Taylor's
rucker results in full on riot,
you know,
would have rutgers death is going to
spread,
don't you?
When that happens,
the head of state police assures me
Golem city will become a war zone.
Another idea trumpeted by some
transhumanists is the idea of the
singularity.
A point at which artificial intelligence
will explode the rate of technological
development in the original dsx.
Bob Page hopes to create his own twisted
version of this by merging with the
Helios Ai,
but instead the player is given the
option to merge with Helio's to rule the
posts singularity world as a benevolent
dictator,
trenches.
The game doesn't necessarily put any
kind of judgment on this,
but the solution still feels a bit icky
and afterwards when the merger between
JC tensen and Helio's doesn't go as
planned,
the technological infrastructure of the
world collapses and chaos envelops the
world gc that's going black.
The message is not so subtly found in
the name of the two ais that usher in
the singularity Daedalus and ICARUS
and barriers between her falling.
According to legend Daedalus was an
ancient Greek inventor who invented
manmade flight.
His son ICARUS plummets to his death
after using the invention to fly too
close to the sun.
The collapse can be viewed in this light
as a too fast and too reckless
technological development that comes
metaphorically crashing down.
Just don't know what you're doing.
Everything when they lost everything,
the world would fall to pieces.
Haldane believed.
The only hope is for morality to keep
pace with science dsx explores the moral
questions inherent in our technology
driven future isn't right for companies
to augment their workers.
Instead of asking this beforehand,
the prevailing logic and the game is
augment.
First ask questions later.
What about installing chips to limit a
person's augmentation?
If they say go on a homicidal rage.
A brief debate may happen on TV while
legislators are trying to pass the bill,
but companies have already developed the
technology before anyone decides whether
this technology should even exist.
Technology first,
morality later,
and that's a recipe for disaster in a
way to Nsx is forcing us to ask these
questions.
We can find tailless rucker offering a
robust criticism of government's
limiting the abilities of the augmented
and even though we're a bit far from
Jack's arms,
the Games can make us question the
technological progress in our own world.
Usually I would get a lot of press in
for a knee,
but given that these social media has
radically redefined how we engage with
the world and we've only begun to ask
questions about its influenced after we
suspect it's done something egregiously
wrong.
So what do you think wise crack will
arch like dsx convinced us to take a
critical look at technology before we
decided to universally adopted?
Or are we diving headfirst into a
nightmare?
And one more question.
In a world where people trying to
succeed in places like Texas,
Catalonia,
and even California seems to be getting
more popular.
The original dsx seems weirdly
prophetic.
There's the national secessionist forces
and Texas is troubled attempt to leave
the union,
but how would that actually work?
Our friend Joseph at real life floor has
a great video exploring the hypothetical
secession of Texas where he and I are
from.
So go check out his video by clicking
here and be sure to tell them that wise
crack sent you.
And as always,
guys,
thanks for watching.
Peace.