This video is brought to you by
skillshare.
The first 500 people to sign up with the
link in the description.
We'll get a two month free trial.
What's up everyone?
Disembodied,
jared again,
man,
the DCEU has had a pretty rough go of
it.
We've already broken down what went
wrong in Batman v Superman and suicide
squad,
but today we're going back to the source
of all these issues.
The movie that began Zack Snyder's
vision of the DC universe that gave
birth to mustache gape,
tramp stamp,
joker,
Momoa,
dead eyes.
Wonder woman.
Okay,
that one was pretty great.
They never ending,
will they or won't they all ultimately
leading to the tragically bland
corporate mandated void that is the
justice league.
But none of this would exist if it
weren't for the film that set the tone
man of steel by trying to graph darkness
and grit onto a character devoid of such
qualities,
man of steel stumbles into a mess that
would ultimately doom the DCEU.
So let's rotate the earth back half a
decade and see how the Dcu went so
wrong.
So early.
Welcome to this wisecrack addition on
man of steel.
What went wrong,
and as always spoilers ahead.
Back in 2013 DC films was riding high
after the critical and financial success
of Christopher Nolan's dark knight
trilogy.
Those films successfully merge the pop
aesthetic of a superhero film with a
previously unmatched sense of weight.
No one explored.
The darker aspects of being the Batman
questioning whether the vigilante
himself was a destructive force,
did Batman beak in the very cycle of
violence he fights against with the
joker,
Bain,
and all the rest of these villains ever
have come to fruition if he didn't
exist.
If true,
what good is Batman are suppose it hero?
Is he a necessary evil?
These are weighty questions to ask.
And yet the dark knight trilogy never
tipped over into pump hostility.
The rare superhero films to be both
smart and entertaining.
It's no surprise then that DC wanted to
recreate this same success with their
other tentpole comic character,
Superman.
I mean those Christopher Nolan Batman
films.
Sure we're successful.
So why not do the exact same thing for
superman?
Seems like a sure fire hit.
What could go wrong?
So the powers that be hired,
another dark and gritty filmmaker,
watchman in 300 Zack Snyder brought in
the co writer of the Dark Knight Trilogy
and even gave our boy Nolan a story
credit and producer role.
There's just one little problem.
Superman isn't that feed darkness and
weight intrinsic to Batman and
emotionally scarred vigilante avenging
the death of his parents just isn't true
for Superman.
On the contrary,
Superman is supposed to be the ideal,
all powerful,
yet completely pure.
There's not a malevolent bone in his
body.
He's the ultimate good guy.
So how the hell do you impose darkness,
grit,
and weight onto the symbol of hope on my
world?
It means hope for Snyder.
The answer didn't lie with Superman,
but in the world around him,
America has changed a whole lot since
Superman's comic book introduction in
1938 where once upon a time the good
guys and bad guys were easy to deduce
and label.
At the time,
man of steel was written.
The endless war on terror had muddied
the waters,
one ton of obey Sinophobia and
insufficient veteran services.
Painting America as a far cry from the
supposed shining city on a hill man of
steel.
Questions.
If Superman,
the embodiment of the American ideal can
survive in the current disillusioned
America,
will he be accepted or rejected?
Ostensibly,
it's a coming out story where this
central question becomes,
should superman revealed himself to
society and lest anyone ever accused man
of steel of being subtle.
When Clark first discovers his powers
during class,
he runs away and hides out in,
you guessed it,
a closet.
So what answer does the film provide?
Should Superman remain in the closet or
reveal his powers and save the world
like the hero he's always been?
Well,
the answer becomes far darker and
murkier than you'd expect after young
Clark saves a bus full of students from
drowning.
Jonathan Kent tells him that maybe he
shouldn't have.
What was I supposed to do?
Just let him die.
Maybe
let that sink in.
The All American dad tells the
burgeoning hero he should probably just
let a bunch of children drown.
The crazier part man of steel treats us
advice as sound.
Jonathan in the same scene tells Clark
that there's more at stake than the
lives of a bunch of children in the
world finds out what you can do.
It's going to change everything or
our beliefs or our notions of what it
means to be human.
Everything.
Jonathan fears that when confronted with
WHO and what Clark is,
people will fear and reject him.
Humanities,
very reality will shatter and the
results won't be pretty,
and guess what?
Throughout man of steel,
we see this to be exactly the case.
When Clark hides in the closet after
discovering his powers,
he hears the children afraid of him.
When Perry Mason,
here's about the possibility of
Superman's existence.
He remarks.
Can you imagine how people on this
planet would react?
They knew there was someone like this
out there,
even lowest lane.
Superman's true.
Paramour is afraid when she first sees
the Almighty alien.
The questions raised by my rescuer.
Subsistence are frightening to
contemplate.
If Clark does decide to come out,
well,
it could end in his death.
Case in point as a teenager,
Clark is framed reading a book on the
philosopher Plato.
Plato actually detailed.
What would happen if a perfectly just
and righteous man were to ever come into
the world.
A man just like Superman in the
republic,
one of Socrates's pals suggest that this
perfect van,
we'll be scourged.
Rack bound,
evil of his eyes burned out and it lasts
after suffering every kind of evil he
will be impale so not good.
If Superman were to reveal his identity
and notably people would turn against
him and seek to kill him.
A fake.
We see play out in v Superman.
Snyder drives this point home by
comparing the hero to the other.
All good being in human history.
Jesus was an act of God.
Jonathan,
this was providence when Clark debates
with,
they preached about whether he should
reveal his identity.
He's framed in the foreground,
would they stained glass depiction of
Jesus in the background and later when
Superman rescues lowest from an escape
pod,
we see him in the classic crucifixion
pose.
Again,
not very subtle by comparing superman
with Christ snider as a real sense of
foreboding to man of steel because well,
we all know how Jesus's story ends and
here in lies the problem.
Clark has to become superman because the
movie's called man of steel,
not hipster,
sad beard man,
but man of steel puts itself into a
corner where it's constantly arguing.
Clark shouldn't reveal his powers,
that if he does become superman,
you will be feared,
hated,
and inevitably murdered.
There's no logical reason for Clark to
reveal himself to the world.
So this leads to two issues.
One,
Clark becomes a reluctant hero and to
the entire film becomes a refusal of the
call.
Now,
the reluctant hero is a well worn
narrative archetype in which a person is
thrust into circumstance where he must
save the day despite never really
wanting to do so.
Think Han Solo in star wars or John
mcclane in die hard.
This hero doesn't ever look to save
anybody.
He's just drawn into situations where he
must.
Similarly,
Clark doesn't look to save anybody in
man of steel.
He just sort of ends up at the right
place at the right time.
The school bus crash,
well,
Clark's already on the bus,
so why not the oil rig disaster Clarkson
in nearby fishing boat.
So why not?
Again,
lowest gets attacked by a tentacle that
just sketch Clark's only a couple feet
away.
You get the point.
But this reluctant hero archetype is the
antithesis of the superman myths.
If Superman is the ideal,
we strive to be the hero among heroes.
Then his reluctance to save anybody runs
contrary to his ethos.
Further by making superman a reluctant
hero,
it turns him into a passive character.
Things happen to Clark.
The bus crashed the oil rig disaster or
a stage five tornado as opposed to Clark
leading the narrative through action.
The entire film in turn becomes a
refusal of the call for Joseph
Campbell's Hero's journey.
When our hero is first called into
action,
he chooses to refuse often because
staying at home is easier and far less
dangerous.
For example,
in Star Wars,
a new hope luke initially refuses to
help Obiwan safe Princess Leia.
It's only when Luke returns home to see
his house destroyed and his aunt and
uncle dead that he decides to take up
action.
The refusal of the call is typically
only a brief stop on the hero's journey
and Campbell's monomyth.
It takes up less than a 17th of the
hero's journey.
Get in man of steel.
Clark refuses the call to become
superman for over half the film more
than an hour of runtime.
Imagine if luke had spent over an hour
contemplating the pros and cons of using
the force you'd grow to hate the guy.
This becomes the problem.
Man of steel.
Clark spends so much time debating the
merits of becoming a hero that in the
end he seems like a bit of a Dick.
I mean,
he's an almighty,
all powerful being who can save the
earth on one leg with only his pinkie,
and yet we the audience are as to
sympathize with why he shouldn't save
anybody.
When Jonathan Ken gets sucked up into a
tornado,
man of steel's intent is to depict the
moment as a tragic lesson,
but in execution,
well,
it's far less.
Clark could save his Paul from imminent
death but can't because doing so would
reveal his powers to too many.
I let my father die
because I trusted him because he was
convinced that I had to wait at the
world is not ready
yet.
Again,
man of steel treats this as a completely
reasonable action,
like of course that's what anyone would
do.
Superman's just let us father die
because there's at least 25 people under
the bridge watching even more.
The blame is placed on the world.
It's our fault.
Jonathan Kent died.
We're to ennoble,
not the superhero that could've saved
him in.
Oh,
I don't know,
two seconds.
Man of steel carries the cynicism to its
conclusion where superman in Zod duke it
out in metropolis,
nonchalantly killing hundreds of
thousands if not more,
but it's not superman who is cavalier to
this loss of life,
but the film itself,
man of steel doesn't realize the
implication this conclusion has on
superman and his heroic ethos.
The ending has treated it as a triumph
superman,
defeat sod and saves the world.
Who cares about a couple hundred
thousand extras?
Lois is fine.
Get over it.
Humanity never even accept superman.
After Clark reveals his powers and sorta
saves metropolis.
The government tracks in with a drone
questioning his motives.
How do we know you're woke one day?
Act against America's interests.
Superman two doesn't trust humanity.
Destroying the Afa mentioned drone and
telling the government to take a hike
that they'll never find out where he
hangs his cake.
So in the end,
the uneasy relationship between humanity
and superman is still well exactly that
the world's still isn't ready.
Early in man of Steel Clarksburg,
Father Jarell echoes the idealistic
sentiments of Superman's past.
You will give the people of,
uh,
an ideal to strive tool.
All right behind you that will stumble
fall,
but in time they will join you in the
Sun Gow and time it will help them
accomplish one.
This is the Superman of the 1930s of
Richard Donner and Christopher Reed.
But the words ring hollow in Snyder's
morally obfuscated worldview.
By the end of man of steel.
Snyder has crafted a superman who
shouldn't have saved a bus full of
children who let his father die and
destroyed the city.
He sought to protect all the idealism of
yesteryear has been sucked out.
Leaving a hollow shell were one stood
beacon of hope.
Man of steel's intent is to pave the way
for Superman and the Dcu to showcase the
uplifting origins of the greatest of
heroes and begin a multi crossover film
franchise.
But in reality,
the film has the exact opposite
reaction,
the wanton destruction of the third act,
the wishy washy hero,
the morally obfuscated world,
all paint a picture far from idealistic.
This isn't an uplifting story of a hero
coming into his own and being accepted
by the world.
This is a story of a hero being forced
into hiding,
ultimately rejected in fear by the
government and the people he seeks to
protect that darkness and grit the very
thing man of steel ads,
ironically enough becomes its own
undoing,
swallowing up the inherent goodness of
its central character,
turning the beginnings of the Dcu
franchise into the origins of its end.
Thanks for watching guys and as always
he's like lots of other youtubers.
You guys often ask us how we make our
videos,
which programs we use and how we learn
to use them.
At wisecrack,
many of us taught ourselves how to
master the applications we use today.
Luckily you can learn just about
anything online.
If you ever wanted to start a project or
learn a new skill but weren't sure where
to begin,
skill share can help get you started.
Skillshare is an online learning
community with over 17,000
professional and easy to use classes and
design,
photography business and more.
Whether you're already a creator or
you're looking to become one,
you'll find likeminded people with steps
and advice on how to take your ideas to
the next level.
You can take classes on everything from
drawing with ink to how to design a
mobile app to how to properly chop
vegetables.
A premium membership is super affordable
and starts at just $10 a month.
You'll get unlimited access to the full
range of courses,
but the first 500 people to click the
link in the description will receive a
free two month trial to skillshare and
all its amazing resources.
So head over to skl dot s h slash wise
crack for to be in your two month free
trial and get learning.
We can't wait to see what you create and
don't forget to subscribe and ring that
bell so you never miss what we create.
Thanks for watching and catch.
Hell next time guys.
Peace.