This episode is brought to you by
skillshare.
Get two months free at the end of the
video.
What's up guys?
Jared here.
This isn't the first time we've talked
about this season of south park,
but for lack of a better phrase,
just to briefly recap,
the season so far,
south park has been exploring the
feeling of hopelessness in the modern
world,
whether it's school shootings,
Predator,
priests,
outrage mobs or east suitors.
Nobody asks for South Park has been
showing us and exhausted population
resigned to the fact that nothing can be
fixed.
It seems like South Park is once again
evaluating their legacy in the world.
Last season's southmark reflected on
their impact on the culture.
Most obviously scene in the episode
super hard.
Penis in which kyle be standing for the
show itself condemns the harmful effects
of terrorists and fill up another
standard.
The show,
although the previous season never made
a definitive statement whether or not
south park is harmful.
Something interesting has happened in
the last few episodes with the recent
reintroduction of man bear pig,
Matt stone and Trey Parker seem to be
taking their efforts at self evaluation.
A step further,
in fact,
their new message seems to be more akin
to a full fledged.
We're sorry.
So welcome to this wisecrack quick take
on South Park season 22 episodes six and
seven,
and of course spoilers ahead.
Now,
for those of you who haven't seen season
tends episode man bear pig or just don't
remember stuff from over a decade ago.
It features our Gore warning south
hearts,
children of the half man,
half bear,
half pigments,
dressing.
I'm spreading man.
Bear pig awareness.
Hear each of your kids take a pamphlet
and a bumper sticker.
Mr Gordon takes them on a farcical
hunting to a cave where the children
almost died even as he believed that
children have died.
Al Gore gets super stoked about his
alleged defeat of man bear pig and how
people will in turn be super stoked on
him.
I killed.
I've saved the earth from certain
destruction.
Everyone is
for stoked on me.
Man.
Bear pig at that time and now was a
super cereal.
Not so subtle.
Stand in for climate change.
Gore had released his film an
inconvenient truth that same year,
and while one might view the joke of man
bear pig,
to be mostly about Al Gore's attention
seeking behavior,
you just use pig as a way to get
attention for yourself because you're a
loser.
There are plenty of hints in the South
Park Cannon that Matt and Trey didn't
take climate change too seriously.
In the season five episode,
terrence and fill up behind the blow.
We get this.
Uh,
excuse me.
My daddy is a geologist and he says,
there actually isn't any concrete
evidence of global warming.
That's not true.
Global warming is going to kill us.
All the Republicans are responsible and
in the season nine episode,
two days before the day after tomorrow,
people wrongly accused a flood on global
warming.
Oh Jesus.
When in reality stand just crashed the
boat into a beaver dam.
Shout out to our Fan Malcolm for
pointing this out,
man.
Bear pig also escapes from imagination
land.
The implication being,
you know,
climate change is imaginary.
Now man,
bear pig is back and it seems like Matt
and Trey have changed their tune on the
issue.
Do what you remember,
dude warned about this,
that Weirdo guy who came and told us
what happened,
he was right in man,
bear pig is real and the show is now
going out of its way to not only
associate man bear pig with Gore's past
warnings.
Oh,
is it inconvenient?
Now,
I tried to warn you all,
but no one took me theorial,
but to admit that they were wrong to
trivialized his claims.
In fact,
when it comes to making fun of climate
change blowhards,
it seems like they have a different
target now.
There's no scientific proof,
no real evidence of a man bear pig.
Why are you trying to figure out what's
going on with scientists?
Matt and Trey also take aim at people
who waffle around about whether or not
they should worry about man bear pig to
begin with.
It looks like Satan is here.
Should I start to worry,
which is a stark departure from this.
Even if global warming war real,
which all proven scientific data shows
it is,
and it would take millions of years for
our climate shift to happen and as smoke
fills the landscape of south park,
it seems like they may even be referring
to the recent wildfires in California.
Their apology decor is made most
explicit in episode seven.
What more do you want from me?
I've atoned for my mistake.
I'm sorry that we were getting a lot of
gifting information at the time.
You know even you were wrong about a lot
of the things you said would happen.
That's not to say they're letting up on
the almost 43rd president of the US.
He's still painted as a narcissistic
Douche who cares more about the image of
himself as a heroic climate advocate
than actually dealing with climate
change.
So now that the show recognizes the real
threat of climate change,
what is to be done?
Well,
if you're an adult in the town of South
Park,
the answer is Jack Enter the game that I
wish I was at home playing right now.
Red Dead Redemption.
Two,
all the adults from sergeant gates to
randy to the cops to even Satan analysis
score.
You're playing red dead redemption.
Two so good,
right are playing and for the most part,
they're too busy escaping to their new
hyper detailed,
wild west second life to deal with
something as depressingly hopeless as
man bear pig,
not unlike the reaction to Sharon and
episode one.
Sheldon were shocked they were killed at
a school where they were supposed to be
safe.
What else is going on?
The adults of South Park are more keen
on dismissing problems than addressing
them.
Maybe he's going to kill everyone and
he's gonna.
Stop.
Well then I guess I don't have to do
anything about it,
but more importantly,
this man bear pig business makes some
pretty clever parallels to the idea of a
faustian bargain.
Bargain comes from the German tale of
faust who through a contract inked and
blood sold his soul to the devil,
exchange for knowledge or worldly
pleasures and isn't a convenient that I
will miss.
Character comes back for this episode.
Belsky and bargains are everywhere in
literature and film,
sometimes with the devil and sometimes
not,
but the basic premise is that one
achieved some goal in exchange for some
kind of horrifying fate,
like an eternity in hell.
We soon find out that man bear pig is a
fate sifting demon who made a faustian
bargain with grandpa marsh.
He's sacrificed the future for some
sweet cars and even sweeter ice cream
here on the show is making a clever not
to the argument that the economic
prosperity of one generation has left
the current one.
As Stan says,
we're stupid.
Band applied.
A bunch of other old people made the
deal with Mandera.
Peggy.
It's here because of their greediness
screening and the most tragic thing
about it and why we think this fits with
our previous thesis of this being the
season of resignation is that Grandpa is
right in the end.
Man Bear pig offers to leave south park.
If they agreed to give up red dead
redemption and soy sauce,
he said they'll never come back again,
but we have to give up soy sauce and red
dead redemption.
Two.
Okay,
why soy sauce?
Well,
it's probably an illusion to the fact
that soy farming to supply both humans
and livestock has cut down a whole lot
of rain forest in the Amazon and the
south.
Partake.
Take Mandera pick up on this offer.
Just the ride.
Nope.
And for everyone who wants to blame baby
boomers on destroying the planet,
the kids are just as greed.
Could we possibly talk about
restructuring a new deal?
Uh Huh.
Nah.
The
episode ends with another foul skin
bargain.
This time,
literally a contract that shifts the
chaos of man bear pig on to the future.
There's actually an economic takeaway
here.
The idea of an extra banality,
as you probably know,
the basic building blocks of an economy
are a lot of smaller exchanges.
I give you some wood for your sheep and
we've completed a transaction that has
made both parties happy.
People agree to exchange different goods
and services.
And as a result,
the world exists well as it does,
but an externality complicates our
understanding of two private citizens
making a private deal.
That's because some exchanges have a
spillover effect or some kind of
external consequences to the trade.
So if I pay Alec $5 to let woody on his
neighbors smelling my dog's gnarly poops
is an externality of that transaction.
One they never asked for enter South
Park.
This faustian bargain with man.
Bear pig is a literalization of how
externalities work.
The town gets to keep soy sauce and red
dead,
but someone down the line has to deal
with the external consequences of that
transaction.
Namely man bear pig slaughtering
everybody when he comes back,
but more literally,
it's about how private consumption of
cars,
gas,
ice cream,
red dead and soy sauce impact people who
were never involved in that exchange to
begin with.
Now,
in real life,
cars produced carbon dioxide that enters
the entire world's atmosphere.
Ice Cream uses milk from dairy cows who
are fighting their way towards
humanities demise and red dead.
Well,
there's probably an argument to be made
about heavy metals and your playstation
or something.
South Park locates these externalities
geographically and sign here that man
bear pig has rights to the lives of all
children in third world countries,
which points to how poor people,
especially in developing countries are
way less able to cope with rampant
forest fires,
food shortages,
and rising sea levels and temporarily as
much of the externalities related to
climate change will go on to be some
other generation's problem
and you didn't get to what it would mean
for your grandchildren.
I didn't think I'd have grandkids.
I didn't even want children.
That's why I always came on.
Graham.
Graham's
so has southpark matured this season by
apologizing for their dismissal of what
now seems to be a very real issue.
Sure,
they may have recognized that they were
wrong,
but they still leave us with a classics
health part.
Conclusion.
Mankind sucks and there's nothing we can
do about it.
Hooray.
And since you might soon have to be
defending yourself in the post
apocalypse,
might as well get ahead of accumulating
as many skills as possible with
skillshare offering over 20,000
classes.
Skillshare is an online learning
community.
Perfect for jump starting your career
with classes on design,
web development,
and business strategy.
It's also a great way to refine the
skill you already have.
Love,
doodling.
With simple character animation class.
You can literally bring your
illustrations to life.
Love painting,
drive,
photoshop demystified to bring those
pieces to the next level.
Love posting videos on Youtube.
Well,
me too.
No matter what you're interested in,
each class is taught by a real person.
No robot serco store ghost robots here.
You don't even have to get off your
food,
although you might want to consider it
joy.
Get two months of premium membership for
free by smashing the Lincoln,
the description or heading to skl dot
ssh slash wise,
crack 15 to start taking their 20,000
classes.
Thanks for watching guys and see you
next time.
Peace.