This video is sponsored by skillshare.
Stick around to find out how you can get
three months of skillshare for just
ninety nine cents.
Yep.
Greetings and welcome to earthlink
cinema.
I am your host Garrick's,
where amyloid.
This week's artifact is American psycho.
Based on the book by Bret Easton,
Ellis island storing weight loss guru
Christian Bale.
The film takes place in 1989.
Give or take a millennium.
Our protagonist is human investment
banker,
Patrick Batman,
and he's got it all.
I'll legally blonde girlfriend,
two layers of skin and a brain disease
that makes them old murdery.
One day his work friend,
jared Letterman,
gets his driver's license,
making Patrick's Learner's permit.
Look,
admittedly pretty condemned to bury the
hatchet.
He invites him over for some rhythm of
the night and buries the hatchets.
Patrick leaves a facetime audio cover up
and a grossly inaccurate terminator.
Impression,
baby.
Pretty soon,
Norman Osborn starts asking questions
about Letterman's disappearance from
late night,
if only to inject some plot.
Luckily,
he's not really into facts will just
disappear and they leave it at that.
Later that night,
Patrick asks,
too lovable prostitutes to star in his
porno Chitty Chitty Bang Bang and wraps
production.
After the big coat hanger scene,
we're not through yet.
When the Hooli CEO gets his license,
Patrick hops back on the murder train,
but learns that he's gay and stops since
that would be a hate crime to clear his
head.
He books the prostitute for a sequel,
but totally forgets to tidy up his pad.
She's such a neat freak.
She leaves without taking her chainsaw,
forcing patrick to throw on some
clothes,
turn it
the next night.
Patrick remembers his pin and forgets
his cat.
When a woman tries to cut in line,
Batman tells her to wait and hell.
The fas asked what happened,
so patrick shows them he gives a janitor
and security guards some time off
because he's such a nice guy,
and then booty calls his lawyer.
Whoops.
The following morning,
patrick shocked to find his place spic
and span decks,
even though is Roomba broke forever ago.
The film ends with Patrick running into
his lawyer and an astonishing Pepsi
twist is revealed.
The lawyer doesn't charge for the our
American psycho,
satirizes consumer as values through its
portrayal of Wall Street yuppies.
Long before bitcoin became sentient and
blew up Guam for Patrick and Co,
meaning comes through what you own
reflecting the philosophy of Herbie
fully loaded.
Mark,
who's up in his book,
one dimensional man,
he writes,
people recognize themselves in their
commodities,
in their automobile.
Hi Fi set,
split level home and kitchen equipment.
Personally,
I recognize myself in my space,
Jacuzzi,
the film lampoons the trivial pursuit of
status.
When Batman and his colleagues compare
business cards to the casual observer,
they're all Comic Sans,
but in Patrick's world,
this becomes a tense power,
struggle over the slightest
distinctions.
That's subtle enough.
Way Coloring tasteful thing.
Patrick,
you're sweating.
Similarly,
the traders have become
indistinguishable from each other.
I mean,
they're all mammals to me and beneath
the flashy exterior,
there's no substance.
I simply am not the film comments on
humans' preoccupation with looking
mighty fine.
Often on instagram.
People are so obsessed with Batman,
superficial qualities that they failed
to notice.
He's gotten a haircut.
I'd like to dissect girls.
Did you know I'm utterly insane.
Great Tan Marcus.
I mean really impressive.
When Louis Sees Batman struggling with a
suspicious bag,
all he cares about is who designed it.
Where did you get that overnight bag?
The cost of his sheets is more important
than the fact that they are clearly
covered in cranberry juice.
I can only get these sheets in Santa Fe.
These are using visual imagery.
The film draws a connection between
Patrick's violent tendencies and his
material girl ism what appears to be
droplets of blood turns out to be a
supreme really decadent sauce called
Saracha.
Batman's call for dinner reservations is
juxtaposed with some pretty hardcore
pornography.
Although I've seen worse when we see
Batman's victims hanging in the closet
like Valentino suits,
we realized that to him,
human beings have been reduced to a mere
commodities and a bold fashion
statements.
As Patrick's behavior grows more
erratic,
we begin to wonder how much of this
documentary is real when he visits
letterman's apartment,
rather than encountering bodies and
blood soaked walls,
he meets only a realtor and a crazy low
asking price,
and as lawyer appears to contradict his
confession,
I killed.
That's simply not possible.
Why isn't it possible?
Because I had dinner with Paul Island
twice in London just 10 days ago.
These disparities could suggest Batman's
world is so jaded towards money.
A realtor would whitewash a murder house
to get a good zillow.
It could also suggest Batman.
Story is a fantasy,
a warning that in such a culture,
the potential for maniacal violence
could lurk inside any of them,
any of us.
For earthling cinema,
I'm Gareth Lloyd.
It's hip to be square.
Hey,
wisecrack.
Garrett guarantees intern jared here,
much like Patrick Bateman,
we hear a wisecrack believe in taking
care of ourselves,
although that's where the similarities
and what better way to take care of
yourself that my learning some new
skills help advance your hobby or career
checkout skillshare to find out how
skillshare is an online learning
community offering more than 18,000
courses in dozens of subjects.
Want to learn how to design a business
card that will put Paul Allen's to shame
or how to mix your music to give it that
sheen of consummate professionalism than
skillshare is the place for you members.
Get access to expert lead classes in
business,
entrepreneurship,
finance,
data science,
gaming,
and more.
All for less than $10 a month and to
save even more money,
you can get your first three months of
skill share for just ninety nine cents.
Now through the end of January.
Click on the in the description as k,
l dot s,
h slash earthlink 99 to get this special
discounted rate and pickup some sweet
new skills.
And if you haven't already,
be sure to subscribe and ring that bell
to keep up with all our latest releases.
We've got tons more coming,
including videos on near Automata,
rick and morty,
bojack horseman,
Captain America Civil War,
and more.
And as always,
thanks for watching guys.
We'll see you at Dorsia.