What
homie?
I got something special for my well
wrapped dollars today.
I'm about to lay on your.
The first episode.
I'm my new audio series.
Thug nodes get lit.
What are your boys?
You're going to keep doing this thing
bringing bad as literature to the
streets.
There's Tom Food Airways,
odd waves,
whatever the hell it's called.
This show is live now,
so check it out on apple podcasts or
your favorite podcast app,
but to give you guys a little taste of
what's to come.
I'm going to draw some hits from the
first episode right here,
right now.
Three examples of more money,
more problems in lit.
Have you thought Biggie had it hard?
You won't believe this.
These characters went through when they
started rolling in the benjamins.
Number three,
Lou Ella Moss from no country for old
men by Kar.
Mack McCarthy is 1980 and Lou Ella Moss
hunting in a Texas desert when he
stumbles upon a Satchel full of seed
notes at a drug deal that went south
dude's and instant seven figure ball up.
Unfortunately,
that money puts him in the cross hairs
of anti sugar,
a savage coin flipping hitman hide to
retrieve the stolen loot,
and this dude don't play.
It'd be saying you did.
You did.
After sneaking back into the badlands to
help out a dying man,
things go from bad to worse.
Lou Allen,
he's chased across the desert,
nearly eyes and sent to the hospital
after I shoot out what the seemingly
unkillable Shugart man I'm telling you
that dog and time is after Harris,
the guy threatened to put one in his
wife's,
don't bust his ass to meet her in El
Paso.
Unfortunately some Mexican hitman smoke
Llewellyn and leave his wife completely
on her own against the gun and that boy
heads on straight up waste this earth
just for being a third wheel and all
this damn that's cold blooded.
Lou Ella's life with stripe this moment
he brought home that chatter,
but then didn't really some say his
decision to help that die man back in
the desert is what ultimately can man.
Maybe this is a sign of Hulu.
Well and truly is a good person who's
just not cut out for that third life,
or maybe it's a warning that there ain't
no stopping depth.
Anyone,
not even for decent folks like Lulu
Island and Mrs Moss.
If the cartels didn't,
capital Shugar shows,
seeing the terminus,
the double to dust them both.
Hulu,
I would have skipped town with all the
monies I was there.
No escaping this showdown with death.
Either way,
Lou,
I would try to get out of dodge with all
the muscle is bankroll.
Combine them and have that Kinda cash dr
the book.
Then we're all know,
but Jay Gatsby from the great gatsby by
f Scott Fitzgerald,
a Nick carraway lands a job in New York
City during the twenties.
He rents a shack next to the swag bag of
Jay Gatsby,
a mysterious playboy who throws dope as
parties but never joins them.
It turns out gas be hosts.
These rages in the hopes of attracting
is back when honey dip.
Daisy Faye,
who lives across the bay from Gatsby's
crib with their douchey old money
husband Tom Buchanan.
After being blue ball for years,
Jay and daisy finally started hooking
up.
Unfortunately they do a good job at
keeping it away from daisy's hobby who
gets his revenge by telling her how
gatsby made all his bucks.
Bootlegging.
Yeah,
that boy gatsby a hospital man and
another twist face.
He decides to stick it out with her dead
beat.
Husband girl just can't handle the thug
life at Gatsby side.
I thought she was a ride or die chick.
Daisy.
I'm disappointed.
It looks like they couldn't be worse
with team gatsby until holy time side
bitch gets run over by daisy and the
girl husband fades.
Gatsby was behind the wheel.
That dead chick's crazy as hubby.
Hands down to gatsby's mansion and
glasses him in his swimming pool.
It's game over for the great gatsby.
Why did things go south for great
gatsby?
Maybe it was because his whole approach
to life will straight up whack.
Rather thought he can buy his way back
to happiness.
Well,
the gangster wide,
but daisy ain't one of his pants and
shirts that a human and the human heart
and the kind of thing you can buy on
Amazon.
You got to go on the black market,
but that kind of crazy becoming rich
didn't make me any happier than being
rich did for daisy.
I mean,
just look at her.
She's a top shelf social light on a
surface,
but her heart is busted.
Her marriage sucks,
and she's shallow as even nick thought
Gatsby's Corny as view of daisy being
all perfect wasn't jiving with reality.
The character was capable of achieving
their happiness they really wanted,
which might be why so many people
compare the great gatsby to the failure
of the American dream.
What is the American dream?
Well,
it depends on who you ask,
but it boils down to busting your ass
too.
You get enough bread to buy whatever
makes you happy.
Does the American dream holed up in
practice?
Well,
in the Great Gatsby,
the verdict is Hell No.
All the American dream got Jay Gatsby
was a death sentence for vehicular
homicide.
Gee,
thanks for driving,
Miss Daisy.
Number one,
Bilbo Baggins,
the Hobbit by j Dot r dot tolkien.
Bilbo baggins is a fat ass hobbit who
likes to eat,
glaze up and do Jack to one day some
nappy wizard crashed his crib with a
team of dwarves and invited him to
retake the lonely mountain and all this
prejudice from the dragon smile.
Damn.
That must've been some Danville.
Va was cheap and after major grubbing
billable,
joins the gang on a fantastic journey.
Pack with stranger things.
Then we seen on stranger things,
we're talking problems.
Trolls,
a magic ring that Bilbo pockets and an
enormous dragon tiller.
Top amount of blame.
Smile gets it correct and the doors
reclaimed their mouth.
The fastest thing you can say,
my precious five armies hustle over and
start scrapping over the recovered loop.
This results in the climactic battle of
the five arms.
Luckily though bill on ducks,
the dramas of Bob's the little shoddy
pieces out,
what only a small percentage is prize
money,
but it's all good.
He hurries home as fast as it's bad.
Last can carry them because you know
what?
That money's going up in smoke.
Y'All.
If you wonder why Bilbo didn't help
himself to more of the recovery swag,
it might be because so much of the crazy
in the hobbit goes down because of good
old fashioned greed.
Consider the dwarves and session to
reclaim the mountain.
Something Thorn.
Oh,
concealed leader of the dwarves
regretted as he lay dying.
If more of US valued food,
cheer and song above,
hoarded cold,
he says the bill Bilbo.
It wouldn't be a merrier world.
Just about everyone in the hobbit got
their minds on the treasure,
which might explain why talking chose
Bilbo is his main character.
As a Hobbit,
there's a childlike innocence to him
living a simple life.
I like the dragons doors and who all
about the money and the power was turned
off by greed.
That's probably tokens killed that we
should as well.
That's it.
Google does things up the middle earth
by swiping out.
One ring from the Creta Gollum.
What's this?
Greed.
I wasn't talking.
Setting up his future books.
What's the difference?
Because you know someone was seeing
dollar signs with that move.
Shout out to Pete Jackson,
three hobbit movies for,
and that's all the goods I got today.
Be sure to be on the lookout for more
nodes.
Get lit on apple podcast,
stitcher,
or wherever you get your new episodes
will be coming at you every week,
including ones on the most infamous
banned books.
My dropping moments in Shakespeare,
greatest bromances in lit.
You can subscribe to the podcast right
now,
so give it a listen and show you some
love and give me a nice review phase
with Tony in my well read Paula's aches.