This video is brought to you by
skillshare.
Yeah,
a wise crack.
Jared,
again,
as you probably know,
the Internet is obsessed with fantasy
life analysts was wrong.
Wife analysts was right.
The philosophy of Santos,
Hey,
wait a second.
Even showed up in fortnight,
but aside from infinity war grossing
more money than the entire GDP of Belize
and Josh Brolin being a bad ass.
Why is this fill in the most ubiquitous
since this dude,
after all,
not all diabolic plans get this much
internet debate.
Oh hell,
let's just do it.
We always do hijacks Jackson nuclear
weapons and hold the world hostage.
Well,
after a classic wisecrack brainstorm
session,
I eat unsafe amounts of caffeine.
We've come up with a possible answer.
It all has to do with the transition
from this to this nanos.
Welcome Liz.
Wise crack edition on this very
distinguished Chin and spoilers for
infinity war and the comics ahead.
It's important to note that the 2018
pianos isn't to fan,
knows has always been a comic book fan.
I was was created by Jim Starlin in 1973
and issue number 55 of the invincible
Ironman,
and he immediately became a hit with
readers in part due to.
Well,
the outright weirdness of his cars.
You see everything comic book Fan Ost
did he did to impress the object of his
affection,
marvel's personification of death,
who appears as a robed female skeleton
who doesn't really talk a lot and
wouldn't you know it.
She's just not into him,
but maybe if he defeats one more
adventure or conquers one more planet.
So you're telling me there's a chance.
Yeah,
like his later counterpart Comic Book
Vanos is definitely a product of his
era.
America in the late sixties and early
seventies seemed to be infused with
debt.
Robert Kennedy and Martin Luther King Jr
were slain in 68,
between 1968 and 1972 over a hundred and
30 American commercial airplanes were
hijacked with many of these hijackings
ending in fatalities.
By 1973 over 58,000
American soldiers had died in Vietnam
that had infested our culture.
Why not have a super villain lust after
her?
It's not the first time art has lusted
after death in many ways.
Comic Book Vanos with his obsessive form
of Necrophilia hearkens back to an
earlier time when obsessions like his
were all the rage he fits right in with
the capital are romantics of the 19th
century.
The poets like Lord Byron,
John Keats and Percy shelley depth was
nature at its most glorious and
triumphant,
keats himself and used on being half in
love with death and it's no surprise
that the greatest American poet from
this era is Edgar Allen Poe,
the man who invented the spirit of hot
topic hundreds of years before it
manifested itself in every mall across
America.
And in this vein,
Comic Book Fan.
Osu is a romantic 100 percent angsty
banjos once the whole universe to feel
his pain.
But if comic book Fan Ost Living His
passion driven emo life dovetailed
nicely with be so full sleep heart at
seventies,
how would he fair?
Now,
while today's America certainly has its
own boogeyman,
death isn't really one of them.
Sure there's terrorism,
but the fears of the information age are
more analytical,
more driven by endless streams of data,
whether it be 24 hour news cycles or 24,
our social media feeds,
oh God.
Just thinking about it gives me a panic
attack.
So marvel had to augment Thanos.
Specifically,
they had to tinker with primary
motivation,
keep him in obsessive lunatic,
but changes obsession from death,
which is so retro to data retain his
distinctive costume and appearance.
Sure.
Even keep the tire tracks on that sexy
Chinet,
his Butler bottom eyes,
all the fields cinematic banjos in
contrast to his four color antecedent is
not impulsive at all.
He rarely even raises his voice as
befitting to our era.
Cinematic Banjos is a rationalist
historically rationalism first rose to
prominence during the 17th and 18th
centuries.
This is Galileo pushing back at the
church about the movement of the earth
around the sun.
This is Newton deducing,
the three laws of classical mechanics,
pascal,
furthering our understanding of
geometry,
the salient furthering our understanding
of human anatomy.
It's descartes proclaiming,
I think therefore I am not.
I feel,
but I think these are the men and women
who pushed against all emotional
distraction in order to achieve a higher
truth.
So Berlin goes about his business with
the detachment of a rationalist.
It explains how he's able to murder his
own daughter for the sake of achieving
his utilitarian solution to
overpopulation,
erases every other man,
woman,
and child from existence,
and justifies it to cold logic.
So why this change?
Is it just a sign of the times?
Well,
maybe,
but there's also a second reason to
highlight the flaws of Tony Stark in his
seminal work on literary criticism
poetics.
Aristotle claims that effective
antagonists act not only in opposition
to the hero,
but also reflect a vital flawed aspect
of the hero.
This is the literary theory of foils,
Hamlet's self righteousness is so
complete that it compels him to deceive
and kill,
but the same could be said of his enemy,
Claudius,
hey,
you killed my father.
Absent Fathers Syndrome leads both Luke
skywalker and Darth vader to make some
very bad decisions and Sour Mon is
little more than Gandalf,
fallen from grace.
And so when we apply poetics to
avengers,
infinity,
war,
we discover why big,
bad thing I was had to be a rationalist
because our protagonist Tony Stark is
one to granted.
Tony Stark has his moments of being
overtaken with emotion.
He begins his first movie as a carefree
rich boy arms dealer.
Later events shake him out of his
comfort zone.
So much so that by iron man three,
he's so overcome with the emotional
aftermath of a near death experience
that he's more or less crippled.
From there,
he ping pongs back to the security of
stubborn rational thinking,
and it's in this headspace that he
creates ultron and advocates for the
Sokovia accords documents like that.
Documents which exists solely to enforce
order or rationalist best friend,
which brings us to infinity war.
Remember Tony Solution to defeating
Thanos?
He's going to secure Dr.
strange if he can keep the analysts from
acquiring the time stone,
the infinity gauntlet can't be
completed.
It's so mathematical that even Sheldon
Cooper would have no.
No.
Jerry,
no more big bang theory jokes.
It's an elegant,
logical strategy.
It is rational and it fails utterly.
Of course it does.
A need for rational solutions is the
vital flawed characteristic that Tony
has in common with Vanos.
Aristotelian storytelling demands that
Tony Fail,
but hold on.
It's not as if Tony Stark is the only
character in the movie.
In fact,
one could argue that the true beating
heart of the mcu belongs instead to
captain America himself.
Steve Rogers,
it Steve's emotional fortitude which
finally brings the avengers together.
Rescues the winter soldier from darkness
and denies the confines of the Sokovia
Corps.
Steve Rogers is marvel's capital.
Our romantic hero is driven by loyalty,
honor,
and his own principles,
romanticism versus rationalism.
It's this age old duality which forms
the core of the Tony Stark,
Steve Rogers,
antagonism from the moment they meet,
it forms the foundation of their
separate attempts to stop vanos stark.
The rationalist tries to out strategize
him while Roger's the romantic tries to
beat him up with an army and they both.
It's not just that they both fail,
that's important,
but that the only way they can come up
with to solve a complicated problem is
two diametrically opposed worldviews,
rationality,
or romanticism.
Having to choose between two extremes is
a defining characteristic of infinity
war.
The avengers can either a,
let vision live and risk vanos getting
the milestone or be killed her best
friend and stop Nanos or look at Dr.
strangest dilemma.
He can either let Tony Stark die and
perhaps defeat pianos or give it up and
save Tony and let half the world die.
He tries to use the time stone as a way
to defeat nanosecond.
After exploring 14 million options,
only find success once one in 14
million.
Dr.
Strange then gives up the time stone and
save stark.
Now we can assume that this rational
choice that strange makes is necessary
toward that one in 14 million success,
but right now it sure looks awful
because it allows our villain to win
being stuck between option a and option
B is stenosis.
Whole Shtick,
a man who literally control space and
time can somehow only think of two
outcomes in response to dwindling
resources.
Let overpopulation run its course
through war,
famine,
and misery,
or kill half the world.
He couldn't just snap his fingers to
make more food,
resources or even planets to live on,
but as a reflection of modern society,
this is exactly the point and perhaps
why fantas resonates so much in 2018,
as Maggie asked her recently observed in
the New York Times,
our life expectancy is declined.
Suicide rates have risen.
The opioid crisis has worsened.
Inequality has grown in confidence in
government has fallen when confronted
with the enormous problems of our modern
world.
It seems like every choice is damned if
you do damned if you don't work a job
that pays,
be miserable or work a job you love.
Be Poor and miserable.
Vote for a Douche or vote for a Turd
Sandwich.
It seems like in many facets of life,
we're given the options of Pepsi and
coke,
but no RC cola Bago boil on Fox and park
or Moxie,
and that's the problem with Dan knows
when you're a political imagination is
so limited and you only have a choice
between two things.
All the rationality and the world isn't
going to help you make progress.
In order to do that,
we need more imagination.
Whoa,
and what our political imagination is,
so she will never experience the joy of
Phaco.
Is there any escape Hegel road that
oftentimes in history the way forward
come,
so when we take two diametrically
opposed things and synthesize them into
a fresh approach.
This is probably what lays before us in
avengers four.
This is probably how our heroes will
ultimately defeat banjos and saved the
universe as they say.
When the old tricks fail,
you got to come up with new tricks.
As always,
guys,
thanks for watching.
Peace
intern interns clean this up.
This is ridiculous.
As your boss clean this up.
Let's see if skillshare can help build
your business using company values to
drive success.
Crucial conversations,
tools for talking with stakes are high.
What great managers do different.
Alright guys,
I get it.
I haven't been a leader that you guys
need me to be,
but I am going to create a high
performance company culture here wise
and I will
learn your names
and Nachos.
Clean the barricade.
We'll talk you.
Where did you learn to do all of this?
Well,
I went to sk l dot s h slash wise.
Crack nine and I got myself a premium
membership at skillshare.
There's over 20,000
classes and you can get the first two
months for free if you go to ski l dot
ssh slash wise,
crack night,
and you will do your best work in both
tech and business.
Mark.
It's Matt,
but did you say skl that sh slash
wisecrack nine.
That's right Mike.
It's Matt.
It's still mad.
It's always been mad,
but I'll check it out.
The first 500 wise correct fans or sign
up will get two months of skillshare
free.
So click here or at the link in the
description.
Thanks for watching guys.
See you.