This video is sponsored by movement,
watches and sunglasses.
More on movement at the end of this
video.
Hey,
wise crack jared here.
Today we're talking about the story of a
guy who takes down the finance industry
as he's hawks to imaginary friends.
That's right,
Mr.
Robot.
Robot follows hoody clad hacker Elliot
Alderson as he and his buddies
instigated a revolution and take down
equal a fictional mega corporation.
That's the gold standard of corporate
malevolence,
a conglomeration of Bank of America,
Walmart and Enron also Elliot's crazy on
the surface.
Mr.
Robot is a show criticizing capitalism.
Tell him about the type of money makes
you question right and wrong,
but to really understand Mr.
Robot,
we have to dig deeper into an idea that
is woven into the very fabric of the
show.
Alienation.
Alienation means to be estranged and
isolated.
In the parlance of Mr.
Robot disconnected philosophy deals with
different kinds of alienation.
There's alienation from humanity,
from the world,
and even personal alienation where
you've become a stranger to yourself.
Mr.
Robot explores them all.
Welcome with his wives cry condition on
the philosophy of Mr.
Robot.
Oh and spoiler alert.
Mr.
Robot is about lonely people trying to
connect.
Sometimes that means quite literally
connecting illegally to other people's
computers.
Agent Dipiro has no life,
no life and struggles to connect with
both strange men on the internet and her
Amazon Alexa.
Elliot struggles to connect with his
family,
his past,
his friends,
and even reality and the masses
according to Elliot can only connect to
each other through facebook,
instagram,
and linkedin.
The show,
even employees visual tricks to
emphasize the distance between
characters such as wide angle lenses and
framing characters near the edge of the
screen.
Elliot's and ability to connect is
caused by more than just his social
anxiety or that he talks to his dead
father.
Instead,
Elliot's alienation has everything to do
with God.
Let me explain.
Elliot is unable to understand his
actions,
his motives,
or even his relationship to other
people.
Mr Robot takes charge of Elliot's
physical body interacting with people on
his behalf all while Elliot is
completely unaware that anything is
transpired.
As a result,
Elliot isn't able to understand his
relationship with his sister,
Darlene,
or anyone else he might've interacted
with.
As Mr.
Robot and while Elliot Psychosis makes
his alienation from himself and others
unique,
the logic that dictates that psychosis
is nearly universal for German
philosopher,
Ludvig Feuerbach,
whose name means fire stream.
But I digress.
God was the primary engine of alienation
during the 19th century.
Humans created the figure of God
according to the lawyer Bach and
instilled in with their highest ideals,
justice,
love,
wisdom,
and so on,
but being a forgetful species,
they forgot.
Look at this virtuous God and said,
hey,
we're so much like this guy.
He made us just like him in this way.
The fact that man made God in man's
image is inverted to God created man in
God's image.
As a result,
Christianity is alienating.
We become estranged from our ideals,
ourselves and each other because we can
only relate to them through the medium
of God of figure that we've since lost
control of,
if this seems strangely familiar,
it should.
Elliot creates the figure of Mr.
Robot forgets he created him and then
goes about letting Mr robot run his life
in good feuerbach,
Ian and fashion.
Elliot says,
Mr.
Robot has become my God and even creates
Mr robot in his own crazy image.
Mr Robot is even liken to an omniscient
God always watching Mr.
Robot,
you have a presence.
Elliot's first response to the problem,
Mr.
Robot is to get rid of him.
He pumps himself full of adderall and
starts journaling in the hopes that he
can kill him off.
This in a way parallels the atheist
response to God,
but I don't listen to my imaginary
friend.
Why should I listen to yours?
We invented God.
Now we realize it,
so let's dump Joe,
but Elliot's therapist convinces him
that the answer isn't to dump Mr.
Robot,
it's to accept his delusion as part of
it.
At this point,
I think we have to accept the fact that
he is the legitimate and existence and
your life for 40 bucks.
The biggest problem isn't that we
invented God.
It's that we inverted our relationship
to God and said,
he created us.
I'm only supposed to be a prophet.
You're supposed to be my God or voc
thinks that God is the ultimate object
of thinking man,
a creation that speaks to the unlimited
potential of our reason.
Similarly,
Mr Robot represents Elliot's highest
ideals,
creating a better future without Evil
Corp.
One of the big issues with alienation is
the loss of responsibility.
You know the old,
I don't hate you,
God does.
It wasn't.
Elliot either suppresses the memory of
the unpleasant acts.
He has to commit in the name of a better
future like allegedly killing a guy or
imagines.
Mr.
Robot is responsible in the process.
Elliot isn't able to directly relate to
the world.
He helps shape or his peers and instead
has to relate to the medium of Mr.
Robot,
right?
It's only when Elliot admits that Mr.
Robot is his own creation.
Betty can finally carve a path out of
his own alienation.
When we've mixed up the relationship
between God and the world around us,
the world becomes confusing cause and
effects seem to invert themselves.
Galilee slips away and we lose touch
with our fellow man.
No longer are we the drivers of our
faith,
but events are laid out by the divine or
your imaginary friend.
We're no longer the judge of our actions
or the actions of others.
God is the rest of the world doesn't see
Mr.
Robot,
but that doesn't stop the show from
drawing an explicit connection between
Elliott's delusions and there.
So don't tell me about not being real.
While Mr.
Robot may be Elliot Scott,
the masses have a different God
consumerism,
which brings us to eight different kinds
of alienation.
Show Creator Sam.
Ismael holds nothing back in paying
homage to other films,
critical of consumer culture,
aside from the obvious fight club and V
for vendetta references.
One scene evokes John Carpenter's,
they live of film exploring the truth
behind modern capitalism and Tyrrell.
Welock is one big O,
two American psycho of film where people
become as disposable as commodity
sorbet.
Likewise,
one of the central tenants of Mr Robot
is that consumer culture is a collective
delusion.
One that is strange is us from the world
and each other.
When Mr.
Robot reminds Elliot that nothing is
real.
He says,
oh whoa.
Builds on fence.
Synthetic emotions in the form of pills,
psychological warfare in the form of
advertising.
Season one elliot decides to be normal
by hearting things on instagram,
watching marvel movies and drinking
starbucks,
drinking starbucks throughout the show.
Material Items and wealth is strange
people from their true selves.
Whenever Angela Moss has confronted
about her working for Evil Corp,
for instance,
she defends her character with displays
of wealth.
When she goes to buy a new pair of shoes
to replace a pair covered in her
coworkers brains,
the salesman confronts her saying,
tell me witness this thing.
You're here to buy new shoes.
I don't know who you think you're
talking to,
but I'll try the products next.
When again,
confronted at a bar by her father's
friend.
She responds
in 2007 and I've got a six figure salary
at the biggest thing on right in history
and I'm just getting started.
If Angeles motive seem unclear to the
viewer,
they're probably also unclear to her,
and a strange world is a disorienting
word.
Angela,
who stresses she needs the job.
Evil Corp officer is in the same light
as the guy who has to euthanize dogs for
a living.
It's just sick that in on me.
I got to pay the bills or the homeless
guy who allows Tarell to beat him
senseless while wearing sterilized
surgical gloves in prison.
Leon can only relate to elliot with the
prisons.
DVD Collection,
namely Seinfeld,
a show about nothing.
The human condition is a straight of
tragedy because in all of these cases,
mass culture and commodities inhibit our
very being.
Advertising and media encourage us to
destroy a part of ourselves to fit in.
You destroy parts of ourselves.
Every day.
We Photoshop our wards,
Hawaii annihilation is all we are.
It sells us pre packaged narratives
about love and life for Elliot.
Only when we destroy the alienating
forces of consumerism,
can we finally be free?
We will find our true selves again maybe
after wiping away the thick,
grimy film,
a facebook friend requests and vine
stars.
Thus,
Mr.
Robot shows a another kind of
alienation.
Commodity fetishes,
commodity fetishism works a lot like for
your box alienation and it should,
it's greater.
Karl Marx appropriated for your box work
for his own ends,
for marks of God mediating human
relations commodities.
Do we imbue commodities with abstract
value in such a way that everything
becomes commodified for Tyrell Welock?
Every interaction is an exchange.
Even going so far is he uses own body in
pursuit of greater wealth.
In the case of the Washington township
trial,
the people who died as a result of evil
corpse actions or treated as mere
commodities,
profits are more important than people's
lives.
It's for the same reason that evil
corporate executives can so easily
forgive colby after he testified against
them.
Every action isn't some indicator of
your character,
but an exchange of goods and services.
In the same vein,
Philip Price Hires Angela despite the
fact that she blackmailed them,
but what exactly are the stakes of
alienation in the world of Mr?
Robot.
It's control for both Feuerbach and
Marx,
the world of the object of collective
human labor,
the Labor that affirms our species being
or our membership to the human race
alienation destroys that species being
because the world that we collectively
build together as now been hijacked by
someone or something else,
it's no surprise then that every
character from Angela to elliot to
Tyrrell to price and ministers,
Zhong are vying for control.
You've brought up this issue
before,
this issue of not feeling like you're in
control.
The series even opens with a monologue
about the people who have the real
control in society.
Secret board meetings,
control who lives and dies over shrimp
cocktails.
So you were drunk eating shrimp cocktail
and it was raining when you decided my
mother would die and young people are
racked with debt,
forcing them into jobs they hate and
Elliot can't stop the voice in his head
from taking over his life.
Ministers Zhang is obsessed with time
surrounding himself with clocks,
if only to remind them of the one thing
he can't control.
Nice.
Just put a walking shadow.
No poor player that struts and Brett's,
he's on his stage and Ben is hurting.
You surrounded yourself with the
constant reminder of mortality.
Led,
seen,
constantly scribbling in his notebook
about control or fighting for control
with Mr.
Robot,
he attributes Shayla is abused by
Fernando Vera to the invisible hand,
the economic forces that control her
life.
There it is again the invisible hand at
work controlling us even if it pushes us
past our threshold.
In his therapist's office,
he likens the freedom afforded by
contemporary society to the choice
between Pepsi and coke.
The real question is,
where's the RC Cola?
Both tyrrell and Elliot blame their
fathers for their lack of control.
Early on,
Elliot blames his father for giving up
when Evil Corp poisoned him.
It's about how those bastard slowly
killed your father and how he wished
he'd done something about it,
but he didn't because he was his hero.
Just like you're being right now.
Hi,
Raul never wants to become his father
who's inability to speak English was a
reminder of his helplessness.
Father used to say that to me all the
time as a child,
what was the only English she knew?
The journals that Elliot frantically
whites about controlling is aptly named
red wheelbarrow tyrrells own reminder of
his father's impotence.
I'm silly.
Po Tyrell also likens murdering.
Sharon knows to absolute power.
He and others are really into playing.
God tend to leave a legacy.
The standard of which was set by God.
Elliot at times is unsure if he's Mr.
Robot Scott or Mr.
Robot is his God.
In the end,
Mr robot shows that nobody is really in
control in an alienated world.
The people at the top have become
victims of their own machinations.
While they may try to create an illusion
of control with armies of lawyers,
convoluted conspiracies and bunker data
centers,
they all experienced the same alienating
forces as the rest of society,
whether it be in the form of God or
commodity fetishism.
Conclusion.
Mr.
Robot is not only a show about lonely
people trying to connect,
it's about the engines that drive that
loneliness,
whether it's God or imaginary friends or
the things we own.
That engine distorts our perceptions and
turns a reality on its head.
We can never really be sure what's
reality or delusion and Mr.
Robot and that's sort of the in an
alienated world.
Can we be sure that any kind of reality
exists?
Thanks for watching guys.
But whether you're in reality or
hyperreality,
you'll want it to look good.
So if you decided it's time to step up
your game with a new watch or a new pair
of sunglasses,
you should check out movement.
And if you're one of the first 200 wise
crack fans to make a purchase at
mvmt.com/wise
crack using the offer code wisecrack
you'll get $15 off your purchase.
Founded on the idea that good style
shouldn't break the bank movement cuts
out the middleman giving you designer
great apparel at low prices with their
classic minimalist designs and quality
construction movements.
Watches keep you on time and in style
all starting at $95 and their sunglasses
are just cool.
They're lightweight,
handmade and start at 70 bucks with the
option to polarize most pairs.
So head over to mvmt.com/wise
crack or click the link in the
description.
Be sure to use the offer code wise crack
to get $15 off your purchase.
Free Shipping and returns are included.
So join the movement.
Thanks to Movement for sponsoring this
video,
and we've got more great stuff on the
wafer.
Y'all,
including videos on the exorcist,
saw stranger things and lots more.
So if you haven't already,
don't forget to click that subscribe
button.
It would mean a lot to me in my dog.
Catch all next time.
Peace.