This video is brought to you by audible.
Hey,
was helen here?
So jared is on vacation,
which gives me the chance to tell you
all about the philosophy of a show about
philosophy.
This could get meta.
The good place is a fascinating piece of
television because while it includes
philosophy lessons as a major plot
point,
it also incorporates its own ideas on
human nature,
fate and ethics for a show us sensibly
about teaching people to be good in the
afterlife.
The good place asks a more profound
question,
can those lessons actually make us
better people and if they can,
does that matter?
Welcome to today's much requested
episode on the philosophy of the good
place.
Spoilers ahead.
Okay,
so a recap for any uninitiated into the
world of the good place.
The premise of the first season is that
coworker betraying senior scamming
tequila slugging human garbage.
Eleanor Shell Strop dies and
accidentally ends up in the good place.
There's been a big mistake.
I'm not supposed to be here,
which is basically heaven,
except without all the religion he stuff
which we're laying makes it way,
way more elitist.
Only the very best to get into the good
place based on an intense point system
to determine exactly how good you are.
You need me to lie to old people and
scare them into buying fake allergy
medicine.
I get it,
man.
Which one's my desk?
Even though eleanor probably doesn't
belong in any religions,
good place.
The point system gets absurd.
Every single thing you did had an effect
that rippled out over time and
ultimately created some amount of good
or bad.
She's joined in her paradise
neighborhood by to honey,
a beautiful,
wealthy philanthropist.
John,
you a Buddhist monk and her supposedly
soulmate Cheaty,
a philosophy professor specializing in,
you guessed it,
ethics also.
There's a lot of frozen yogurt.
What is it with you and frozen yogurt?
Have you not heard of ice?
Oh sure.
That I've come to really like frozen
yogurt.
There's something so human about taking
something great and ruining it a little
so you can have more of it.
Oh,
those are good place is supposed to be
heaven for eleanor.
Being surrounded by people who are
better than her is actual hell.
After eleanor tells Cidi her secret that
she's there by mistake.
He decides to teach her to be a good
person by conjuring up a chalkboard and
giving her daily philosophy lessons.
This leads to some of the best
philosophy jokes on television who died
and left aristotle in charge of ethics
play doll.
Oh,
and John,
you is actually Jason,
a trashy Florida,
want to be dj who is also there by
mistake.
So he joins in on the ethics classes
too.
This is your first step towards not
sucking.
Cool.
I just have two questions.
One or football tryouts,
and does the school have a prom?
Oh No.
For most of the show,
eleanor's moral progress runs parallel
to her ethics lessons.
The more she internalizes philosophy,
the more see her making decisions that
are halfway decent,
if not downright suite.
The show at face value sets up the
premise that learning ethics makes you
act more ethically.
At least that's the premise the cheeky
and eleanor are working from as he goes
through the grueling task of teaching
contractual ism to someone who abandoned
dog sitting duties to go to a rihanna
concert.
You broke your promise as soon as it
wasn't convenient for you,
and now I have a very full office dog.
That idea that learning moral philosophy
can make you a better person is an
ethical theory in itself.
The question of whether or not ethics
can make you a better person and if so,
what ethical system best accomplishes
that is called Meta ethics.
Fundamentally,
the good place is a show about Metta
ethics even as it presents relatively
straight forward ethical theories
through cheeky and when cheeky teaches
you ethics,
he goes hard.
Well,
now that you've become acquainted with
existential crises,
I thought we could read death by
philosopher Todd May.
Sounds like the perfect beach read.
Eleanor gets the rundown on rawls lock
clout to Plato,
Sidgwick Mill,
hume,
Scanlan,
and quite a few other moral
philosophers,
including todd may,
who just happens to be one of the
philosophy consultants for the show.
Nice one time.
All of these competing philosophical
concepts are meant to teach eleanor and
Jason how to be moral enough to remain
in the good place,
but as any ethics,
one o one student could tell you,
learning a bunch of contradictory
theories on what makes someone act good
does not actually help answer the
question,
how the fork should I act?
Eleanor frequently expresses her
frustration with this,
but she keeps on selfish.
Here's the perfect test.
There's something fun that you want to
do and then there's something less fun
that people are doing for the common
good from the beginning of the ethics
lessons.
These frustrations hint that the real
question isn't which of these
philosophers should I base my moral
system on,
but rather is this the right way to
learn how to be ethical in the first
place?
After all,
gds inability to decide anything driven
by his thorough knowledge of philosophy
is his main flaw.
I miss my mom's back surgery because I
had already promised my landlords nephew
that I would help him figure out his new
phone.
I don't need the Cidi who once had a
panic attack during rock paper,
scissors because there were just too
many variables.
The show progresses.
Eleanor becomes a decent person,
CIDI gets slightly better at making
decisions and Jason Gets married to a
robot.
Oh,
that's enough out of you.
Robot lover.
That's risk not a robot.
We're still not sure if that last one
has any secret moral significance.
While you might say,
hey,
gds classes are helping.
It could be argued that eleanor and
friends are progressing in spite of his
philosophy class.
That's because there's a big difference
between learning ethics and doing ethics
and here's where we get back to Meta
ethics.
Those questions about what morality
actually is and how we ought to approach
it.
There's actual data to support the idea
that studying moral philosophy doesn't
necessarily make you more contemporary.
Philosopher Eric Schwitzer level
conducted a study between 2007 and 2009
there resulted in a maybe not so
surprising conclusion.
Ethics professors do non generally
perform more ethically then they're not
at the cyst and non philosopher peers.
In fact,
many of those peers belief that ethics
professors actually performed less
ethically than their counterparts.
This is consistent with the story of
cheating who despite knowing a buttload
about ethical theory ended up in the bad
place because of the people he
unwittingly hurt through his struggle to
apply those theories.
This is why everyone hates moral
philosophy professors.
Oh,
did we mention the good places?
Really the bad place.
We'll get to that.
I can't believe you figured it out.
[inaudible] also studied the effects of
university level ethics classes on
student behavior and concluded that
there is little to no correlation
between taking ethics classes and moral
behavior.
Again,
not a shocker.
We often see eleanor struggling to weigh
competing theories when deciding how to
act.
Irl comp says that lying is always wrong
and I follow that Max,
so you can't even lie to demons.
They're trying to torture us,
man.
We're behind enemy lines that suppose
out principles when you pick and choose
when you're going to follow them,
and she's actually trying,
which can't exactly be set.
A freshman and a fixed glass.
The Schwitzer Bible study even showed
that ethics books go missing from the
library more often than other kinds of
philosophy books.
Draw your own conclusions on that one.
I might not have been a saint,
but it's not like a killed anybody
wasn't an arsonist and never found a
wallet outside of an,
I haven't thought about returning it,
but saw the owner lived out of state,
so just took the cash and drop the
wallet back on the ground.
Okay.
That's really specific and that makes me
think that you definitely did do that.
Much of the shows,
comedy comes from the absurdity of what
moral theory looks like.
One played out in reality,
whether that's the panic of indecision
or the hilarity and Gore of the infamous
trolley problem happening with a real
trolley.
Here are the lovers,
the switch,
the tracks that the choice.
The thing is,
I mean ethically speaking,
I mean on the one hand you're telling,
telling you
see some of the clearest moral
improvement when the characters stop
weighing choices based on theory and
simply follow their gut,
which one of these confusing French
books,
we'll make it normal again.
It's that easy.
I mean emotionally,
he's all over the map right now and I
can't believe I'm saying this,
but I don't think this can be solved
with a book.
This suggests that while the fact that
eleanor is trying to be a better person
is certainly helping her make better
choices.
It's not the theories themselves,
the do the work.
It's a little more subconscious than
that.
Eleanor's progress might be explained by
a Meta ethical concept called moral
intuition,
ism moral intuition.
Ism aren't used that it's our intuitive
awareness of what's right and wrong,
not book learning.
Then Sam's are ethical knowledge that
might seem to be a problem for our main
characters since none of them appear to
have any moral intuitions whatsoever.
Plus here,
do you have a ton of preorders?
Here is your first cut of the profits.
Ho Lima,
Mum,
I can't believe you sold the tee shirt.
Does it help if they basically sold
themselves?
However,
there are branches of moral intuition
ism that suggest intuitions can change
while memorizing q may nod,
zap eleanor into a perfect trim free
angel.
It does open up a space for self
reflection that was previously pretty
close to off on kind of like a self
improvement kick.
Do you think you could help me out?
Teach me to get all horny for the
environment or whatever.
We could also read the show through the
rules of Aristotle's virtue ethics.
The idea that the best path to morality
is by following the example of virtuous
people.
The good place does seem to make the
case for the power of friendship,
but the problem with this theory is that
at least in the beginning,
there are no truly good people for any
of them to copy.
So Cheeky Teaching Aristotle is actually
pretty ironic.
Things get really intriguing when
eleanor goes back to Earth,
the end of season two from the get go,
she acts way more morally than she did
in her old life.
Despite having zero memory of the lesson
she learned in the bad,
good place.
This suggests that those experiences,
whether with books or with her friends
have ultra term moral intuitions,
even though she can't remember them.
Sure.
If she falls off the ethical wagon once
or twice,
I quit eat my farts benedict
cumberbatch,
but it doesn't take a lot of prompting
from Michael.
The barkeep for her to seek out some
help.
Something about eleanor is undeniably
different.
Also,
I met Michael makes a mean screwdriver
because of you know,
all the torture and stuff.
Although we aren't really going to talk
about predestination in this video.
The ending of season two pretty much wax
you over the head with their answer to
can people change?
Yes they can.
However,
this comes after an entire season of
eleanor in the gang making similar
decisions over and over and over times
802 every time Michael resets their
neighborhood.
So although we can make our own
destinies changing habits,
sure is a bitch or bitch,
son of a bench.
Although we over here at wise crack
think that the good place ultimately
rejects the idea that teaching ethics
directly leads to more ethical action.
It's not totally clear.
Gds lessons are no joke and the most
profound evidence of that is in Michael,
who after just a few weeks of lessons
becomes a decent person Ga's or at least
an honorary person.
If anyone send to fight off
predestination.
It's that guy.
There's just one more thing,
one philosophical inspiration in the
good place that no matter how tangential
it is,
your main argument we just have to talk
about to show gets a lot of inspiration
from a wise crack favorite John Paul
Sarte.
So in season one the finale reveals that
they are all trash humans and the good
place is really an experimental
neighborhood in the bad place where
Tahani Eleanor,
Jason,
and cheaty are meant to torment each
other for all of eternity.
Michael,
the demon architect who designed the
neighborhood has a theory that four
carefully selected people will torture
each other far more effectively.
Then butthole spiders were trying out
the new butthole spiders.
They're enormous.
Eleanor unknowingly tortures cheaty by
forcing him to make difficult choices.
His real life nightmare.
We are trapped in a warped version of
niches,
eternal recurrence.
Oh cool.
More philosophy that'll help us cheaty
tortures to honey by refusing to make a
decision to pick her over eleanor,
a reminder of the second best status she
had with her sister before her death.
I get tired of objective representation.
I trust my audience,
my bed.
He has a hat.
Yes,
well done to honey.
The honey maybe knowingly tortures
eleanor by providing a constant reminder
of how much better she is.
It's just so sweet,
teensy,
just like you,
your book.
To me,
that's fine.
And everything tortures Jason because
all he wants to do is be himself and he
can't even tell people his real name was
also,
he never got to see the Jacksonville
Jaguars when their division title last
year.
I'm not convinced that a life with no
floor to dance crew will ever be scarier
than ask Arachnids.
But Hey,
I'm not a literal hell monster.
So what do I know?
Another way to read the first season is
a modern retelling of philosophers,
John Paul Sartre.
No exit in it,
sorry.
Riffs on his famous idiom.
Hell is other people with three bags
locked in a room in the underworld who
make each other miserable through lies,
love triangles and everything you could
imagine from people who ended up in well
hell and in season one,
the neighbors of the good place managed
to make each other very,
very miserable.
It's important to clear up a common
misconception.
Hell is not other people because someone
brought their crying toddler to see
deadpool,
but because in no exit and in the good
place,
you're a turtle,
neighbors will bring out what you hate
most about yourself.
The torture is predicated not by say,
attending an eternal dinner party with
people who use the word mouthfeel,
but by letting those people decide how
you see yourself leading to the ultimate
existential as sin,
bad faith,
the similarities to no exit don't end
with the dope existentialists themes.
Some of the characters themselves have a
lot in common with their good place
counterparts.
I nez who describes herself as a damned
bitch is pretty much the 1940s eleanor
except a lot worse.
She turns people against each other for
fun,
causes misery wherever she goes and
thrives on her own.
Selfishness.
A stele is a high society socialite
who's obsessed with her own beauty and
wishes desperately for a mirror.
She insists that she does not belong in
hell and for much of the play refuses to
believe that she was a bad person on
earth.
I belong in the good place,
the real one with the good people.
Who do I speak to about correcting this?
Your role very well.
I would like to speak to your manager is
still snobbishness about the working
class is more than a little familiar.
She's not used to dressing like a
plumber.
Rats that when you call a female plumber
or is it a a toilet suite for or clunk
winch.
In any case,
that's how I'm dressed.
She also murdered a baby,
which to honey has probably never done
probably
we don't make any sense together and yet
when I'm with you,
I can really let my hair down,
my depart can speaking of course,
because I'd never had it up in the first
place.
G doesn't have quite the same amount of
overlap with his counterpart Garsa,
but there are certainly some character
traits that ring a bell.
Garcia is a coward which gets him
killed.
And Gidi is terrified of making
decisions,
which is just its own brand of
cowardice.
Oh,
I'm sorry everyone.
I just have some worries as well as some
concerns that could potentially turn
into outright fears.
Oh,
there they go.
Ah,
there,
there a few years now.
Well,
so remember how CIDI refuses to Pick
Tahani over.
Eleanor totally happens and no exit.
Sadly there is no Jason God.
That play would be so much better with
Jason.
Whoa.
What is happening?
She having an orgasm?
Did I do somehow?
So the good place is initially a show
about hell being other people and also a
show about the philosophy of
philosophies of which were discerning
the philosophy of also probably
something about Cacti.
But the real question to end on is this,
did watching this video on the ethics of
the good place make you a better person?
And if you didn't learn anything from
this video,
well don't say we didn't try to save
your ass.
Literally all of these lessons paid off.
Whoever said philosophy was stupid many
times.
And if you want to make like your
favorite anxiety driven professor and
get your ethics on,
consider checking out audibles expensive
collection of audio books with a 30 day
trial.
Your first book is free so you can check
out storing kierkegaard's fear and
trembling.
Not only does kierkegaard get Meta
ethical,
but he explores how to go from being an
everyday dirt bag to living an ethical
life.
And unlike other streaming services with
audible,
you own your books.
Audio books are an amazing sidekick in
your downtime as you lounge around or
hike or even to make your daily commute
a little more tolerable.
So go to audible.com/rice
cracker or text wise,
crack to 500 500 to get your 30 day
trial and your first audio book free.
One more time.
That's audible.com/wise
crack or you can text wise crack to 500
500 thanks to audible for sponsoring
this video.