This video is sponsored by Intel and the
upcoming vr film Pale Blue Dot.
Stay tuned after this video to learn
more about Pale blue dot.
Hey guys,
three dimensional jared here.
The first three seasons of bojack showed
us a protagonist that despite his
Hollywood success,
struggled to find meaning.
Buck season three ended with hope bojack
runs away from La and stairs that or
heard of galloping horses,
potentially embracing the idea that he's
free to choose who he wants to be,
which brings us to the core of the new
season.
Our ability to define and redefine our
own narratives,
woken lists very late wisecrack quick
take on bojack horseman season four,
and as always,
spoilers ahead.
Wrapped up in this season is what I'm
going to call the narrative self,
that how we experience things and
remember things are intricately wrapped
up in the stories we tell about
ourselves.
As philosopher Michael Geza,
Niga says,
we're natural storytellers.
After the brain computes and event the
illusory we,
that is the mind,
becomes aware of it.
In other words,
the way we think and understand the
world and ourselves is literally through
stories,
series creator.
Raphael Bob Waxford has spoken about
this idea of self narrative and bojack
because of the narrative we've
experienced,
we've kind of internalize this idea that
we're working towards some great ending
and that if we put all our ducks in a
row will be rewarded and everything will
finally make sense.
It's a struggle and we're all trying to
figure it out,
and these characters are trying to
figure it out for themselves.
This struggle to redefine one's own
narrative is integrally bound up with
each character's happiness.
Everyone moves closer towards happiness
as they move further away from the past.
Escaping the death of Sarah Lynn bojack
drives to his family summer home and
tries to redefine his own narrative that
he's a person who tries to be a handyman
but can't fix anything before later
recasting himself as a tragic hero who's
bojack horseman,
who's bojack Horseman.
He's a very famous TV and film star,
or he was,
yeah,
before he gave it all up for a life of
quiet anonymity.
Instead of making any real inroads into
redefining his own character,
bojack ends up reliving the past that
justifies his own self-loathing.
All the wildest show overlap the
narrative of his mother's abusive
childhood.
A cycle continued as she raised bojack.
Well,
Jack's life turns around when he
befriends a dragon fly named Eddie who
refuses to fly following his wife's
debt,
but after Eddie tries to kill them both
bojack season Eddie's fixation on the
past as a cautionary tale about what
grounding your narrative and a longing
for the past can do.
So the next day in typical bojack style,
he hires a wrecking crew to level the
sugarman house.
Uh,
yeah.
You think I just want to mope around in
a shrine to the past,
getting off of my own guilt while the
rest of my life passes me by authentic
much Princess Carolyn struggles to
redefine the family narrative that she
can do it all on her own as she tries to
get pregnant.
I don't need other options.
My mother had 12 kids.
My body was made for this.
We just got to keep tip.
There's even a whole episode framed as a
presentation by Princess Carolyn's
future descendant.
That is actually just a story.
Princess Carolyn tells herself to cope
with the president.
She used her current hardships as what
philosopher war freeman called Frodo
narrative,
or a story yet to happen.
It's the ending.
What happens next that gives these
moments meaning,
for example,
say,
did you ever hear the story of the
couple have moved to California?
I can't say,
oh,
it's a marvelous adventure.
You see,
they hardly knew each other,
but they shared a certain sensitivity at
a tastes for the unknown.
They were living in a one horse town,
so they headed west towards a town that
could accommodate three horses.
Oh yes.
I think I have heard this story.
I got a small house in San Francisco
near the bookstore,
except she doesn't know what happens
next,
so in order to cling to the old
narrative that she'll be fine and
fertile,
she invents her own ending,
and when I think about that,
I think about how everything's going to
work out because how else could you tell
people what the show tells us that this
narrative is misguided as symbolized by
her cherished family necklace that turns
out to be nothing more than worthless
costume jewelry.
Season four offers a solution to these
ailments.
In what Michael White and David Epston
called narrative therapy.
The point is to help patients re author
their identity by focusing on what they
value and then creating a narrative that
will help them pursue those values.
Nowhere is this more apparent than in
bojack must learn to overcome the
narrative that he's a terrible person,
especially in regards to Holly Hawk.
I don't want to,
but every time she looks at me with
those big innocent eyes,
all I can think about is every thing
I've ever done and I think I don't
deserve that kind of love.
We actually get to hear bojack self
narrative through his inner monologue,
your real stupid pieces,
but I know I'm a piece of that at least
makes me better than all the pieces of
who don't know are pieces of it.
Making things worse.
Bojack's forced to live with his abusive
mother,
Beatrice,
even though bojack's no longer living in
a shrine to the past,
still logging for the love of a mother
who doesn't recognize him.
When bojack inevitably does something
bad,
it just viciously perpetuates this
negative narrative starting the cycle
all over again.
However,
bojack may have finally broken the cycle
when he owns up to his actions with
hollyhock.
You are an amazing woman and after
Beatrice Laces hollyhocks coffee with
embedded means bojack lets it go rather
than perpetuating this multigenerational
tale of abuse and revenge.
When Beatrice finally recognizes Bojack,
he stops looking for validation that
will fix the past.
He just sees her as she is a sickly old
lady and in the least bojack moment of
his life,
he's kind to her.
He don't understand.
You're in Michigan,
Michigan.
Yeah.
At the lake house it.
It's a.
it's a warm summer night in.
The fireflies are dancing in the sky and
your whole family is here and they're
telling you that everything is going to
be all right.
In a final act of selflessness,
he lets hollyhocks eight dad's tell her
that bojack is actually her brother
instead of claiming the good deed for
himself,
but as a reward,
bojack gains something else.
I told you from the beginning,
I have eight dad's.
Yeah,
good,
but I've never had a brother.
Meanwhile,
Princess Carolyn tells us the stories we
tell ourselves aren't always real.
I got into this business because I love
stories.
They comfort us,
they inspire us,
they create a context for how we
experience the world,
but also you have to be careful because
if you spend a lot of time with stories,
you start to believe that life is just
stories and it's not.
Life is life,
so what do you think wise crack.
Can people really change themselves by
changing their own narratives?
Let us know what you think in the
comments section,
just as bojack is reshaping what an
animated Sitcom can be.
Intel is doing the same for storytelling
in virtual reality,
dedicated to content and technology
innovation,
Intel behind the vr film Pale blue dot,
allowing audiences to explore their way
through deep space where earth is just a
speck in the cosmos,
inspired by the iconic Pale blue dot
photograph.
The film brings other worlds to life
with visual effects,
sound design,
and an original score under the
direction of indie filmmaker Eliza
mcnitt.
The film is part of Intel's commitment
to empower vr filmmakers,
which is pretty cool.
While the film premieres in early 2018,
the first episode of the making of Pale
blue dot,
the behind the scenes mini series is
live now.
The series offers key snapshots of
McKnight's journey with her fellow
filmmakers.
In this new media,
we get to follow the team as they tackle
new challenges like what it means to
tell a story when audiences have
meaningful control of the experience and
why is crack.
We've consistently seen great filmmaking
come through,
learning to think on your feet and
adapt.
It's cool to see those same principles
applied to Vr and on this scale.
Watch the first episode on the making of
Pale blue.by
clicking here or on the link in the
description.
Thanks to Intel for sponsoring this
video.
Click subscribe if you haven't already
for more quick takes to come and as
always,
catch you all next time.
Peace.