This video is brought to you by wix.
What's up guys?
Jared here.
We're always getting requests from fans
saying,
you guys have got the cover.
Insert movie TV show,
video game,
mean book,
sarcastic joke here.
We'll then enthusiastically watch it,
brainstorm for a really long time and
often come up empty handed.
It's not that we can't think of
anything.
The show might hint at ideas,
but not fully developed them or evidence
keeps coming up refuting our argument or
sometimes a show was just plain
inconsistent or hey,
maybe we're just too dumb to figure it
out.
So when it came time to look at Netflix
is surreal.
Retro,
Futuristic Love Story.
We didn't quite get where we hoped.
We dug and dug and found some really
cool stuff,
but a cohesive philosophy of not quite
so we're going to do something a bit
different.
We're going to go through the ideas we
considered show how and when they work
within the context of the show and why
we ultimately decided not to go with it
and hey,
maybe this will serve as a foundation
for you to think about the show in new
ways.
This is another experiment for us,
so be sure to let us know what you think
in the comments and without further ado,
welcome to the inaugural episode of Wise
Crack Half Baked addition on superbad to
maniac and yup spoilers ahead,
but before we get into that,
want to give a quick shout out to our
sponsor.
Wix.
Wix allows you to build a great looking
website,
whether you're a freelancer looking to
showcase your skills or you're just
looking to share unused footage of
yourself tied up in a dank basement.
Either way,
it's legit,
free to get started.
Just head to [inaudible] dot com slash
wise.
Crack to sign up now,
back to the show.
Alright guys,
so first a quick recap is an order wish
me luck.
Maniac primarily focuses on Owen milgrom
and Annie Landsberg.
Oh,
in the schizophrenia.
Black sheep of a very wealthy family,
struggles with delusions of saving the
world and a made up brother and a broker
with a dysfunctional family,
struggles with drug addiction to cope
with the death of her sister and the
estrangement of her mother.
They enter a highly experimental
pharmaceutical study run by three
doctors and a supercomputer called dirty
that hopes to eradicate psychological
pain by having patients identify map and
ultimately confront their issues through
drug induced fantasies nd and Owen's
wires get crossed,
causing them to inhabit each other's
fantasies where they experienced whole
lifetimes together,
Gerd.
He gets depressed up to the death of Dr.
Morimoto threatening the experiment and
the subjects inside the final fantasy,
any comforts.
The computer finds the resolve to move
past her sister's death while Owen
confronts the fact that his fantasy
brother is just an idealized version of
his crappy real brother.
He saves the other patients and back in
the real world,
finds the confidence to stand up to his
family and the end.
Any friendship inspires Owen to escape
from a psych ward and have faith in his
ability to function or was that a
fantasy?
All right.
Now onto the pitches organized from best
to worst for your entertainment pitch.
One Don Quixote.
This one is an eight out of 10.
Almost good enough for video.
Miguel de Savantas is modern.
Classic is everywhere in Maniac.
One of the fantasy scenarios even
revolves around one nanny infiltrating a
seance to find the fictional last,
final chapter of the novel.
So why this focus on an old book?
Well,
let's break it down.
Don Quixote tells the story of Alonzo
Cayetano,
who become so obsessed with books about
chivalry that his mind dries out.
Essentially,
he goes mad,
which makes this line extra ironic at
this time is I am healthy andy now and
healthy people read books inspired by
his books.
Alonzo decides to become a knight errant
himself.
The bulk of the book follows him as he
goes on wild adventures,
including the one where he famously
attacks windmills.
He mistakes as giant windmills happens
to be the name of maniacs.
Second episode,
which briefly features and looking at
some during the road trip that ends in
her sister's death,
but trust me,
it gets deeper than that already.
We can draw a parallel between the
madness that makes don quixote one to
perform heroic acts and Owen
schizophrenia that makes him believe
that he will save the world like Don
Quixote.
Oh,
and can't distinguish reality from
fiction.
The more than that,
Don Quixote inhabits a dreamlike
mindspace that makes castles of ens and
giants of windmills turning the regular
world into a fantastic one.
Similarly,
the ULP treatment turns its patients sad
realities into fully fledged fantasy
adventures,
and he's Lemur.
Painting becomes a bizarre recovered.
The lemur story.
The copy of Don Quixote,
she picks up,
becomes the steel.
The final chapter plot Andy and Lee
watching a lord of the rings esque show
becomes this,
and Owen's hawk that kills Ernie verbal
inspires the save the world from alien's
tail.
This is madness.
I love Danny.
If I wasn't secret agent,
I would know I was a secret agent,
but perhaps the most powerful connection
between the two works is the shared
theme of transformation through the
power of dreams.
Congratulations.
You're a hero.
In the case of the dons delusions,
he adventures so that he may
reinvigorate a golden age when people
were more authentic,
as he says bless at the time and blessed
at the centuries called by the ancients,
the Golden Age,
and that time women spoke their thoughts
of love from the soul simply and
pretentiously exactly as they thought
them not searching for elaborate verbal
circumlocutions to beautify them,
truth and simplicity.
We're unmixed with fraud,
deceit and malice.
Justice remained firm and sure either
troubled nor offended against by
patronage and self interest as today.
She is so grievously tainted in troubled
and persecuted.
Judges did not feel themselves as they
do today entitled to be tyrants.
If Don Quixote's fantasies represents
his yearning for the days when people
weren't full of,
then one could say the ulp uses fantasy
to heal a society that has been defined
by isolation.
As James suggest at the beginning,
all levels of physics require collision
and bonding in order to progress and so
does the human heart,
comradery,
communion,
family,
friendship,
love what have you.
We're lost without connection.
It's quite terrible alone.
However,
the world were presented is one that is
tragically absent,
meaningful connection.
Hello,
Mrs Finklestein Donovan,
the first two episodes introduce a
vision of New York in which people are
more alienated from each other than
ever.
Most of the human interactions we
witness are purely transactional.
This is made quite literal with friend
proxy,
a service that provides you with someone
pretending to be your friend for a fee.
You're using a service that gives you
pretend.
Friends,
I have real friends.
This is just more convenient.
Then there's ad buddy where a human
being pitches you a product in exchange
for goods and services.
It's kind of like getting free content
on the Internet,
but having to watch annoying.
There even appears to be a market for
people to escape the world entirely.
Enter a void,
a box that basically allows you to
hibernate your life away instead of
engaging with the outside world.
There's also lines like this.
Thank you for braving the outside world
for me and the fact that a zoomy and
James Sleep in isolating drawers be
encroachment of consumerism into every
facet of our lives is further emphasized
by the omnipresence of advertisements
from the ads that purchased Annie's face
to the neon signs blaring through Owen's
window to ad copy on bridges and maniacs
New York.
You can't even take a shower without
being bludgeoned by ads.
So Don Quixote uses fantasy to bring
back an ideal era of authentic
expression and maniac portrays to lonely
souls,
finding connection through fantasy in an
era of isolation.
You don't do this.
I will do this.
It's important to note that in many of
the ulp fantasies taking place in the
real world,
all the creepy retro futurist stuff
seems to disappear when trying to save
her Lemur.
For instance,
the world goes from what the eighties
thought.
The two thousands would look like to
just the eighties,
but there's an important qualification
to mention here.
This golden age that Don Quixote waxes
poetic about never really happened.
There are many characters in the book
who've been mown the negative effects of
chivalry books.
Deeming them trash and assuring people
that there was never such an idyllic
time.
I can swear to you that in fact this
world has never seen a single one of
those nights,
nor any of their grandkids or their
stupidities,
and then don quixote is tricked into
hanging up,
is lance and becoming Alonzo k Hondo
again,
eventually renounces his madness and
dies a quiet death.
Similarly,
Annie ends up rejecting dirties,
offered to stay in the fantasy world
with her sister.
She accepts reality and together with
Owen moves forward confidently.
The problem with this is that although
it's clear that Annie's break from
fantasy is considered a positive
development for her character,
there's more ambiguity surrounding the
conclusion of Glencoe take.
Are we supposed to agree with the bulk
of the characters in the book who
claimed that fantasy has done nothing
but make him a fool?
Is it good that he's no longer out
adventuring or should we look at it like
don't Antonio Moreno who says,
may God forgive you for the damage
you've done to the whole rest of the
world and trying to cure the wittiest
lunatic ever seen.
Don't you see my dear sir,
that whatever utility there might be in
curing him,
it could never match the pleasure he
gives with his madness.
So why wasn't this made into a full
video?
Well,
despite these really great connections,
what else is there to say that reality
is better than being a mcmurphy?
That fantasy is a liberating force for
humanity,
such an exhilarating experience.
It seems like the connection between the
two works is that they both vaguely deal
with the nature of fantasy versus
reality,
but not in a way that could really
provide a definitive philosophical
thesis pitch to Mommy,
Daddy and me,
Ha.
I give this one a five out of 10 uptop
we should mention owens name is Sergei
milgrom is a reference to the milgram
experiment in which subjects were given
the ability to electrocute people and
continue to harm them under the
suggestion of an authority figure.
Pretty cool.
Shout out,
but didn't really see how it connected
to any of the events in the series.
There's also some serious freud and
undertones.
James is a pair of fillic,
meaning he's attracted to inanimate
objects.
You also has a strange relationship with
his mother.
In fact,
if we want to get all oedipal and we
always do,
the oedipal triangle of mother,
father and child seemed to be important
for many of the main characters and he's
mother walked out on her father.
Owen's dad is an overbearing,
fascist and mantle ray also without a
father in his life near drove my father
away and you slept in my bed,
way too much,
literally goes blind after confronting
his mother.
Can't see,
not so different than say a tragic
figure who stabs his eyes out after
romancing is madre.
He also built a computer model on its
mother's mind,
and while that's not in the Greek
tragedy,
it seems pertinent.
The computer is you play.
The ulp test also functions on the idea
that our mental ailments can mostly be
attributed to some unresolved trauma.
For Freud,
many of our neuroses and mental health
problems were brought on by unresolved
trauma that we must work through the
three stages of the ULP treatment.
Take a similar approach,
but with the mapping and confrontations
ages being more fantasy lives and less
laying on the couch talking about your
mom,
but the connection we really wanted to
make was to a pair of thinkers who were
strongly opposed to Freud's method,
philosopher gl to lose and his
psychoanalyst sidekick Felix squats are
the three things that got our spidey
sense is tingling were one,
the use of the term arborization to
describe the method they use to map the
brain too.
There are bonds I trees everywhere and
three,
the opening monologue suggests that the
universe and life are a chaotic series
of collisions for Dilas and watery.
The dominant way of thinking about the
world is arborescent that is resembling
a tree.
We often think about history and society
like a tree starting at a trunk and
growing in a mostly linear fashion while
occasionally branching,
but the laws in Guata re preferred.
Another natural metaphor.
The rhizomes rhizomes are the roots of
plants like ginger or weeds like
dandelions.
The important thing about rhizomes is
that they look like a series of
connections with no visible starting
point,
like say the roots of a tree.
Basically the world is too complex to be
understood linearly and instead of
simple cause and effect,
there's inputs,
outputs,
feedback loops,
and a lot of chaos that we barely
understand.
So why does this matter for maniac?
Well,
in some cases we could view the opening
monologue under this framework.
Life isn't so much a straight line as it
is a chaotic assortment of random
connections like the structure of a
rhizome.
The crossing of wires for Owen and Andy
kind of follow this logic,
the straight line of their computers.
Connections are interrupted by a random
connection.
Bonsai trees in theory would be an
interesting addition to the symbolism.
Not only is it defined by linearity and
branching,
but that branching is intentionally
guided by a human hand.
Maybe we could say that the show ends up
somewhere in the middle between being
totally chaotic,
rhizome and the guided branching of the
bonsai tree after all,
and he starts the show saying there is
no plan or pattern to the universe.
It's just gas and ends the show saying
this,
if this is assigned friend parks,
maybe the universe,
and we ultimately abandoned this idea
because we couldn't find any evidence
that linked the bonsai trees to the
couple times that chaos versus order is
referenced.
We had a few other clues to,
but they went nowhere.
For instance,
Dullas and quaternary are well known for
their Book Antietam,
which challenges people who sought to
analyze the world in Freudian terms
specifically they wanted to break free
of the oedipal triangle.
Mommy,
Daddy,
and me and mantle ray after interpreting
his blindness as a symptom of his
mother's behaviors,
rejects this Freud and framing and
accepts that it was instead brought on
by a kiss from a zoomy.
There's also this probably random
coincidence,
felix squat to rewrote a screenplay
called a love of you Iq,
which actually sounds kind of like ulp
about a subatomic consciousness than
inhabits a computer and falls in love
with a human plus and watery use.
Schizophrenia as a model to think about
the world where our desires.
We're not limited by the confines of
society or say capitalism and yeah,
maniacs shows a kind of dystopian
capitalism and there's a guy with
schizophrenia,
but it doesn't quite work.
Pitch three.
Owens schizophrenia.
Yeah.
This one's the worst now opposed to the
[inaudible] notion of schizophrenia,
which we need to say is not exactly
literal to the medical condition.
There's Frederick Jameson's rebuttal to
them.
Jamieson suggests that when people are
so bombarded with commercial images and
messages about who they can be or how a
product will make them into this or that
person,
they're actually imposing competing
ideas of identity onto them.
Therefore,
this causes a perpetually shifting
identity or a schizophrenia subject and
the more ones identity vacillates,
the more one consumes.
Therefore,
these schizophrenia subject is ideal for
such an economic system.
Mentees,
there's little doubt that the show hints
at a causal connection between advanced
consumer capitalism and isolation,
but his maniac using Oh,
in schizophrenia as a metaphor for the
ils heaped upon the denizens of the
dystopia.
No,
definitely a stretch.
It's interesting,
but there's no evidence we could point
to to make a confident case just because
we couldn't come up with a cogent
argument about the shows.
Grander messages doesn't mean it isn't a
good show,
nor does it mean it isn't a smart show.
There are some extremely clever things
going on.
The constant Easter egg references that
connect the dreams not only to other
dreams,
but to real life,
to focus on how narrative builds meaning
in our lives.
This makes sense and the small details
at the end that make us question the
validity of the real world above others.
Get it like when the the Lemur.
What makes maniacs so impressive is it's
daring visual aesthetic.
It's formless structure and it's regular
dips into absurdity and for that we
can't help but admire it.
It sticks to a relatively simple
thematic base and runs with it that
people need connection and it's our
ability to bond that can give us hope to
beat our demons.
That's all for now.
Let us know what you think about our
half baked format and as always,
thanks for watching,
but before you go,
we want to give a shout out to Wix,
the website building platform that
allows you to create a website for any
occasion from the student trying to
showcase their research to the advanced
designer.
Creating a portfolio masterpiece wakes
enables you to make a professional and
unique web page.
Also.
It's completely free to get started.
Wicks will enable you to create a
professional and unique webpage.
We also found that they were the perfect
place to host our main page,
but while that's still under
construction,
we've used their community features to
create a temporary site so you can vote
on what you think we should do next.
Right now,
if you head to the link in the
description,
you can decide on which bingeable
Netflix show we should cover on our
movie podcast.
Show me the meaning.
Yeah,
I know it's her movies.
Hey,
we're trying something new.
We've had a lot of fun creating these
pages and love hearing your feedback.
Get started by creating your own website
for free by clicking here or visiting
[inaudible] dot com slash.
Yes,
right.