What's up wise crack you've been asking
for it and it's finally time.
This week we're diving into the insanely
smart neon Genesis Evangelian.
Ava is a phenomenally complex story on
the surface it's about the end of the
world and teenagers and enormous
biomechanical monsters who fight giants,
alien Angel Robot Things,
but beneath that there's an
investigation of psychosexual
development,
intimacy,
unconscious human motivation and how
hard it is to be a person,
but the real meat of everything is about
hedgehogs.
Welcome to this wise crack addition on
the philosophy of neon Genesis
Evangelian but before we get to it,
we want to thank our sponsor blue apron
for enabling us to tackle Evangelian
with the rigor.
It deserves the verse hundred wise crack
fans to sign up with blue apron by of a
lincoln.
In the description below we have $40 off
your first two weeks,
blue apron ships.
You farm fresh ingredients right to your
door in a refrigerated box.
Shipping is free.
All you pay for or the delicious
ingredients that take 40 minutes or less
to make into an awesome meal.
Just look at the stuff the wise crack
team cooked up.
This here is a spicy smoked trout
sandwich,
although I wasn't there to try it.
The interns tell me it was exquisite.
They also hooked us up with the
ingredients to make chicken Tetrazzini
and Jalapeno cheeseburgers so you'll
have something tasty no matter what you
feel like cooking.
Blue Apron is always expanding their
offerings with fresh new recipes and
they're super chilled.
If you need to skip or cancer your meal
service anytime,
no problem.
Check out blue apron at the Lincoln and
description below.
Remember the first hundred wisecrack
fans to sign up through this video,
get $40 off their first two weeks of
meals,
so don't wait.
Thanks again the blue apron and onto
evangelian and if you haven't seen it,
spoilers ahead.
Just a quick note,
even though the Ava reboot is beautiful,
we decided to keep our analysis to the
original 26 episode series and the films
and have Evangelian and death and
rebirth and if you like this,
maybe we'll come back for more.
So first a quick recap.
In the distant future of 2015 the earth
is under attack by an earthly beings
called angels.
In order to combat them.
Humanity has created ass kicking robots
that sync with their pilots called
Ava's.
Of course,
the evas aren't all day scenes.
They're actually former angels infused
with the souls of humans inside the
empty shell.
Bj Ba is a human.
Some specifically be mothers of the
various pilots.
Shinji,
Ahsoka and ray who is a clone,
worked together to pilot the evas,
save the world and come to terms with
their inner demons.
Oh,
also,
ray bonds,
the DNA of original angels,
Adam and Lilith becomes a being
containing the consciousness of all
humanity and pretends the end of
existence.
But don't worry,
we'll cover that.
Do understand the ending of evangelic
and we'd have to dive into some
complicated ideas,
but I promise it'll be fun.
Part One,
as [inaudible] and mysticism,
neon genesis evangelian literally means
a new beginning.
Neon is derived from the Greek neos,
which means new genesis is a beginning
and a reference to the opening book of
the Bible.
And Evangelican is the gospel or the
good news from the same root as
evangelize.
So neon genesis Evangelian is a new
telling of the Gospel Genesis or the
easy way.
It's a reimagining of the book of
Genesis with lots of technology,
brooding and sex.
Ava is overflowing with religious
iconography.
Some of the references are easy to spot.
The show references the Dead Sea scrolls
explicitly incidents not depicted in the
dead sea scrolls may occur.
This should teach the old metal lesson
and Ritz go installs a six six six type
firewall to protect the madge I from a
cyber attack.
It cottey has installed a type six six
six firewall on the Mount Joe's external
feeds surface.
That's very difficult to breach.
Not to mention the presence of creatures
called angels,
two of which are named Adam and Lilith.
You might've expected eve,
but Lilith is Adam's female counterpart.
According to Jewish folklore,
she was created around the same time as
Adam and is usually described as being a
mother of Daemons.
You know,
evil in ava humans are the descendants
of Louis.
Some of the religious work is Christian
in nature.
The [inaudible] system.
The super computer network that runs
nerve has three parts,
each named after the three wiseman.
Casper Alphas are Mlq or you know,
the guys that visited baby Jesus to give
him the gifts of gold and I Frankenstein
and Helen Mirren put the majority of the
religious imagery is based on Jewish
mysticism and the Kabbalah.
Kabbalah is an investigative practice of
faith and mystical teachings at seeks
religious revelation and sacred
knowledge.
Some of its biggest fans are ancient
rabbis and also Madonna.
Most of the angels and Ava are taken
directly from techs and Judaism's
extended universe like Zahar.
Essentially the Kabbalah is Bible,
the Talmud and the book of Enoch.
Others are written in El Theosophy,
a form of mystical riding that uses the
El Suffix,
which is one of the many Hebrew words
for God to tie names to the divine and
it's all over Evangelian,
ramial Saatchi,
old material and Caladrius.
No,
sorry.
Scratch that one.
In cobblistic tradition,
the first being is Adam cadman.
Not to be confused with the other famous
Adam,
a being of light,
which is eerily similar to the giant of
light.
That is Ava's first angel named Adam who
explodes in the second impact.
That's second impact,
kills half the population of the planet
and turns the oceans read revelation
style.
This destruction is a nother call back
to the cabalistic tradition.
An event called the Chevron Tok Helene
or the breaking of vessels.
See in the beginning,
everything was connected.
Part of a universal unity that broke
apart,
leaving everything separate and creating
the many splintered world we live in.
It's sort of like a theological big bay.
The purpose of Kabbalah is to coon,
how long or the restoration of the world
it's traditionally practice through acts
of good deeds and prayer.
But in ava it's taken kind of literally
the ethical call of the Kabbalah is the
reunification of the world,
of the different fragmented parts of
Adam call up the syfy road,
which is depicted as the tree of life as
10 circles in a particular pattern.
It creates a sort of visual tree that
has meant to depict the tree of life.
It's why the random circles a pure
around ava one when it's attacked by the
nine manufacturer angels,
they're all fulfilling the sacred duty
or purpose of the Kabbalah.
The sephora roads re unifies everything.
Recreating the universe as a complete
whole and in doing so destroys the
individuality and separation that
defines life as we know it.
Many characters pursue the goal of
literally reunifying the world,
putting all the different
consciousnesses into one place.
The industry who are bitching,
oh stage and our souls will be at peace.
This finally happens after the Adam
Luleth DNA combined inside of Ray.
The reunification with the masculine and
feminine aspect of the angels is the
reunification of the world as well.
This raises the question of why exactly
the world needs to be reunited.
What does it mean for the world to be
broken?
To answer that,
we need only to turn to our adorable
friend the hedgehog and no,
not that one.
Part two,
the hedgehogs dilemma.
So much of Evangelian is eye candy,
sex,
big ass robots,
explosions,
more sex,
the apocalypse.
But it's at its most profound when the
narrative dives into the crimson red
lakes of sadness,
isolation,
and the human condition.
I'm seeing this for the first time,
and again,
this was the first time it pauses on
empty streets on telephone poles where
nothing scares the birds away and on
classrooms with no students.
The world without half its population is
a sad place.
The end of himes isn't partying like
it's 1999 it just sucks the characters,
miserable lives and intimacy problems
can be explained by a hedgehog and the
pre eminent philosophical pessimists,
Arthur schopenhauer in his book,
[inaudible] and perilite Hamina short
philosophical essays,
volume to schopenhauer details,
a short parable that has become known as
the hedgehog or the porcupines dilemma
in it's,
he explains the human condition by
comparing humans.
Two hedgehogs huddled together for
warmth,
though they crave warm,
hedgehogs can't get too close because of
their quills,
so they keep their distance and remain
cold or learn to live without the warmth
of others.
So what does this have to do with ava?
Well,
everything.
The hedgehog is dilemma is Eva's guiding
theme in episode three Writ Sukkot
explains the parable to mid Sato.
Do you know the fable,
the hedgehogs dilemma hedgehog?
You mean those animals with the spiny
hair,
even though a hedgehog may want to
become close with another hedgehog,
the closer they get,
the more they injure each other with
their spines.
It's the same with some humans
and episode four it's even called the
hedgehogs dilemma.
That desire to be unhurt drives a wedge
between people.
It creates a world of despair.
We see that world and its implications.
In episode 16 titled Sickness Unto
Death,
which is a reference to Danish
philosopher,
Soren Kierkegaard.
A sickness unto death is despair.
Eight terrible existential loneliness
which goes along with Schopenhauer is
hedgehogs pretty neatly as does episode
23 after Kaji is killed and he leaves a
sad message on mid satos machine.
She remarks another phone that will
never ring.
It's the epitome of lonesomeness waiting
for someone to reach out and call.
It's a depressing show filled with
depressed people.
Ahsoka piles her ava to find meaning in
life.
Without it.
She's just a sad girl crying in a dingy
apartment.
We see in flashbacks that though she may
seem gruff,
she fears being alone and pilots or ava
to draw people toward her and expand her
world.
There's Kendo who struggles with his
ability to show Shinji love and doesn't
know how to be a father when she,
she is near me.
All I ever do is causing pain.
When he's reunited with Youi,
he explains that I never deserved to be
loved,
so he rejected the world so he wouldn't
feel pain in his book.
The world as will and representation.
Schopenhauer argues that life is
suffering because the world is made up
of will and representation for
Schopenhauer.
The nature of reality is unity.
We'd all be at peace without this
struggle to communicate between
individuals.
Suffering is the result of
individuality.
To be human is to suffer because
communication,
perception and understanding we'll never
be perfect and that struggled to connect
is the source of our suffering.
The Universe is really one thing in
itself,
one entity,
but each individual will or ego can only
perceive the world from its own vantage
point or perception.
That's what schopenhauer means.
When he says representation,
anguish,
fragmentation,
alienation and isolation are all because
each person is in charge of their will
and there is a disconnect between what
we desire and what the world gives us,
which is echoed by cohorts.
This is mankind's fake.
If human hope,
this fun with the flex or Solano,
that's separation of wills is what the
show calls a tea fields,
which are something like the unique
human soul that's separate each person's
ego.
It's sort of their life force.
The barrier that keeps us from truly
connecting to each other.
Several times characters have
conversations about what it means to be
an ego and to have a body usually as
their body or consciousness is slipping
away.
Ray does this in episodes 14 and 23 both
exchanges are reflections on what it
means to be a human being that has a
body and is recognized by others.
You're right at the core,
we are all the same.
Our minds lack something basic and we
fear that lack and that is why we are
attempting to become one.
We will meld with and fill each other.
This is the instrumentalities.
Mankind cannot live without being
surrounded by others.
Mankind cannot live alone,
although you yourself are always unique.
That is why life is hard.
That is why life is sad and empty cause
want to close physical and mental
preference of others.
That is why we wish to me come on.
This struggle with isolation and the
pain of rejection defines ava.
Unfortunately as schopenhauer tells us,
being alive means living with will and
ego and that means pain that drive to
get away from this pain and ego is
something that we can explain what the
help of our cocaine addled friend,
Doctor Freud,
part three psycho analysis.
I know people are mad because Freud is
considered a hack and didn't science
hard enough.
I get it but hey,
eva explicitly uses 40 in terms ideas
and analysis.
Episode 19 is called Trajection,
a 40 in term that explains how people
take on characteristics of the people
around them.
You know copycats.
Episode 20 is called weaving a story to
oral stage.
The oral stage corresponds to the
weaning of a child from breastfeeding.
According to Freud,
when a child too soon and they're out of
touch with people's emotions and are
generally sociopathic,
wean them too late and they're dependent
too long on the mother for security and
end up neurotic Mama's boys.
Kind of like that.
Robin Aaron Kid from game of thrones.
All the kids in Ava's pilot classes are
motherless children or so they think in
fact Shinji.
His mom is unit one soul and part of
Asa.
His mother's soul is in unit two.
Both Ava's use the soul's inside them to
further bond with their pilots.
How the pilot reacts to their mother is
indicative of their general disposition.
It's as 40 and is it can get there all
morning.
The last love object that is their
mother except ray,
is less mournful and more melancholic
because she has no soul as an artificial
being.
She has no real loss to speak of no mama
soul to snatch and put in a robot.
For Freud.
Mourning happens when we know what we
have lost.
Melancholy on the other hand is much
more serious.
It occurs when people have no idea
what's missing.
Only that it causes them deep,
deep sadness,
hence the need for psychotherapy.
That's why the last two episodes of the
show are literally a psychotherapy
session inside Shinji his mind,
but if you depend only on the ava,
Ava will become your only identifier.
April will become your own lead value.
Without that value you the wheel,
you will be erased from this existence.
We mentioned the manager I super
computers before,
but we didn't tell you that they have
the mind of Dr Naoko Akagi imprinted in
them.
They are reflective of the tripartite
model of the human unconscious,
the controlling scientist as the ego,
the mother as the punishing and guilt
inducing superego and the woman as the
sexual in episode 18 is titled
Ambivalence.
A Freudian idea that eva really leans
into and bill mullins is the way that
people can passionately hate and love.
At the same time,
like when I eat chipolte lake for
example,
Shinji is constantly talking about how
much he hates his father.
However,
I really hated my father,
yet he gets in the ava over and over to
make daddy proud.
In episode 12 he explains,
he pilots the ava to hear words of
praise from his dad.
I think I finally understood the part
about being praised by someone when I
heard my father's words today,
and I also realized that the reason I
pilot my ava is to hear those words from
him.
He runs away from his dad nerve and his
responsibilities as an ava pilot,
but he keeps coming back.
I must've grown away.
I must've run away.
The real smart stuff he's done with
arrows and thanatos or the drive to life
and the death drive for Freud beings are
instilled with the pleasure principal,
the general inclination to avoid pain
and maximize pleasure.
So in episode 16 when Shinji falls into
the direct C or a pocket universe
elements,
yeah,
this world is filled with too much pain
and suffering to keep going on.
He's expressing his desire to minimize
suffering.
As it pertains to the pleasure
principle,
this struggle to avoid pain is aligned
with schopenhauer.
His ideas about will and struggle.
How can we ever avoid suffering when we
have to share a world with other people,
all of whom have their own desires that
sometimes get in the way of ours?
How do we find peace for sale a nerve
and even individuals like Gando in
Shinji?
It all comes back to
instrumentalization.
The process by which all human
consciousness is combined into a
primordial soup called lcl.
That desire to join a unified whole and
no longer be concerned with issues of
the self comes up in Freud to it's
called the death drive.
The death drive is a desire to return to
tranquility,
to the peace and harmony of the womb,
and what can be more peaceful than the
end of every once it's gone.
There's nothing to worry about.
Episode 25 has a direct call to this
with the text.
The case of Shinji Akari,
the boy who wished for death of his own
will then Kendo in the mind of Shinji
states that instrumentality.
Yeah.
It's not a return to nothingness.
It is merely a return to a state of
beginning.
It is no less than a return to the
primal wound that we'd lost so long ago.
Souls and minds will become one
attaining internal balance.
Oh,
return to Lilith and to coon hall along
the restoration of the world or the
reunification with the primordial being.
And so salian nerve are working for the
death drive and they count on Shinji to
become the arc for humanity,
that which will allow them to return to
a world without loneliness and
isolation.
Conclusion.
So the human reaction to the hedgehogs
dilemma is to seek tranquility and a
return to the womb.
But as we've seen,
that's simply a desire for death,
a running away.
So what has to be done?
Well,
it's Kaworu a character who is not
entirely human,
that shows us the way accepting
vulnerability Kaworu gives up his
individual desires and we'll so that
Shinji can live.
He is unguarded and open with his
absolute love for Shinji.
He represents a way out of the cycle of
constant suffering and isolation.
And he just gives damn good advice.
I know that by keeping others at a
distance,
you avoid a betrayal of your trust.
For a while you may not be hurt that
way.
You mustn't that you must endure the
loneliness.
Men cannot erase this sentence because
the owner fundamentally pain is
something that man must endure in his
hard and since the heart feels pain so
easily,
some believe life is pain.
In the final episodes and the movie
chinchy initially accepts
instrumentalization,
but when he understands just what he'd
lose himself,
he has a change of heart.
Your self image is restrained by having
to observe the barriers between yourself
and others.
You cannot see yourself without the
presence of awesome because there were
others.
I can perceive myself as an individual.
If I'm alone,
then I will be the same without others.
For this world is only of me,
then there will be no difference between
me and nothing.
At the end of the series,
Shinji rejects instrumentality.
Hi me,
I want to be myself.
I want to continue existing in this
world
mount as a world where everyone is
primordial soup and shares one mind.
What is this empty space?
An empty world,
a world where nothing exists with
myself,
but with only my Silva.
I have nothing to interact with.
It's as if I'm here but not here at all.
It's just if I'm slowly fading out of
existence,
he ops for one where people can be hurt.
Where we are in close,
where there is a separation and
individual selves where there are
individuals,
wheels,
desires and pain.
He confronts the drive to inorganic
existence and accepts the inevitability
of suffering in life.
That's correct.
If the pain is too harsh,
you can escape it.
If you really hated changing style.
No,
I won't.
I'm tired of escaping a little money,
but he also opens the door for hope and
joy.
So the first thing he does when he
rejects instrumentality,
he turns over and chokes Ahsoka.
She responds by stroking his face,
reminding us that the world they chose
is one of violence and pain,
but also love all three elements of the
story.
The theological,
psychological and philosophical deal
with something called lack in
psychology,
lack as explored by the Freud inspired
psycho analysis and philosophers.
Jacques Lacan is the missing center at
the heart of our existence,
the missing piece between representation
and the world in itself,
whether it be a scarcity of friends,
failing,
marriages and relationships or distance
between father and son.
Eva is able to consistently weave,
applaud that delves deep into the
visceral reality of humanities,
disappointing existence.
Three pilots,
Ray,
the Japanese word for soul,
ghost not or zero in unit zero Shinji
the pilot of unit number one.
The first real person introduced the
other,
the pilot of unit number two,
a girl a call back to the expulsion from
Eden,
the world of infinite knowledge and life
in the end it's just asa and Shinji,
a new Adam and eve,
a new beginning.
Hope you guys enjoyed this episode and
as always,
thanks for watching wisecrack.
We're really excited to share this
episode with you guys.
You've been requesting it forever and it
was actually a really rewarding show to
research.
We've got a lot more in the works,
so make sure you're subscribed and have
notifications turned on.
Hovering anime has been a really awesome
experience for us since the stuff that
is popular is actually really profound.
So my favorite videos aren't anime,
like our episodes on death note attack
on Titan and full metal alchemist
brotherhood,
which that last one might actually be my
favorite video.
So check out our animate playlist by
clicking here and hey,
if this video touched you,
consider checking out wisecrack plus,
it's a great way to help support us and
we do our best to make it worth it with
exclusive content and other goodies.
We love hearing from you guys too.
So let us know what you want to see
next.
As always,
thanks a lot.
Peace.