Hey,
wise,
crack jared here.
Okay,
so we're going to do something a little
risky,
a little crazy,
and maybe even a little sack religious
weren't criticizing Pixel because even
though it's brought us the tear jerking
joys of inside out wally and the toy
story saga,
it's genius is not entirely above some
sloppy storytelling.
Turns out no studio can resist the
allure of a cash grab,
grabby sequel,
and that's kind of what 2016 finding
dory felt like to us,
it just didn't seem as emotionally
resident as pixars best work and being
the obsessive nerds that we are here at
wise crack.
We had to ask ourselves why it's worth
mentioning here that according to the
Guardian,
finding dory underwent massive rewrites
where those rewrites to blame for our
dissatisfaction with the movie is
finding glory,
a lesser film than finding Nemo.
Is this simply a case of sql lightest or
we just overfish stories?
Well,
let's lay this thing and find out.
Welcome to wise crack addiction on
finding dory.
What went wrong?
And as always,
spoilers ahead,
but before we dive in,
thanks to the team at lastpass who
helped make this video possible like
everyone,
you're probably tempted to use the same
cube passwords over and over again.
I mean seriously coming up with hard to
crack passwords and remembering where
you've used them.
It's just a pain using the same
passwords again and again is a pretty
bad idea.
Sites like Tumblr,
Linkedin,
even Domino's had been hacked before and
with a constant flow of new data
breaches,
it's nearly impossible to keep track of
which hacked site could be jeopardizing
your online security.
That's where lastpass comes in.
It's an online password manager that can
help you protect yourself and preserve
your sanity.
Not only does last past help you to
create secure passwords,
but it also manage them for you know
more hassles.
No more remembering which password is
for which site.
No more forgetting where you wrote them
down.
No more getting locked out of your own
accounts.
You can safely and easily surf the net
and avoid having to enter the first
concert you ever went to or your
grandmothers cousins made.
Name the free version is great,
and if you want the premium features
like family sharing and priority
support,
it's just a couple bucks a month.
Thanks to lastpass for sponsoring this
video and check them out in the link in
the description to get started and now
on with the show finding dory comes up
short and at least four key areas we're
finding nemo excels for the sake of
clarity,
let's categorize these problems as one
clouded emotional investment too.
Shaky narrative structure,
three,
passive heroism and for purposeless
entourage.
To be fair,
these issues are almost impossible to
separate from one another,
so there will inevitably be some
overlap,
but here we go anyway.
First,
the question of emotional investment,
a key objective of any screenplay is to
get the audience to care deeply about
the protagonist,
a goal that's often achieved by first
getting us to care about whatever our
protagonist most values and slash or
needs.
Maybe the protagonist is focused on
scoring and internship or going the
distance in the boxing ring or on
breaking free of a suffocating life.
Whatever the case in most strong
screenplays that desire is established
early,
it's singular,
it's powerful,
and it generates our empathy in finding
nemo and finding dory.
The protagonist's goals are blatantly
similar in the first film,
Marlin searches for his kidnap son in
the second door.
He searches for the parents.
She hazely remembers,
although there's nothing wrong with
leaning on the trope of the missing
family member.
I mean it works for Liam Neeson.
Finding Nemo and finding dory
unfortunately have different attitudes
toward the magnitude of loss.
That's because only one of these films
offers us a baseline before it rips a
loved one away and it's that baseline
that creates emotional connection
between us,
the protagonist and the protagonists
need.
In other words,
even though the bulk of finding Nemo
keeps Marlin and Nemo apart,
it first offers a sense of what these
family members mean to one another as
early as the first minute of finding
Nemo Porch.
Hold what?
Marlin values more than anything else in
the world.
These are our kids.
We're talking about thinking they're the
best,
and Marlin proves that value system
through his actions in the films
baseline moments.
We see Marlin pledged to protect his
son,
then tease his son,
then prepare his son for school,
then bring his son to school and then
lecture his son.
You're about to swim in open water.
We have a sense of history,
so when Mimo gets kidnapped 15 minutes
into the film,
we like Marlin,
have loved and we have lost.
We are infested.
Finding Dory offers no such baseline so
it never offers the Gut Punch delivered
by its predecessor.
In fact,
dory loses her parents within the first
five minutes of finding dory in the
opening scene of the film,
Dory,
even to her own parents is positioned as
something of a liability.
A cute little goof.
Okay,
sweetheart.
What about that rhyme?
We learn,
we see the undertow and we say no,
no,
surely thereafter,
like bubbles in the bath tub.
Her parents vanish.
How much can we really be expected to
pour our emotions into losing characters
we never knew?
Where are your parents?
If finding dory can't get much mileage
out of the parent child bond,
that energized,
finding Nemo.
Then what is the central relationship
here?
Where do we invest our empathy?
You might guess that we feed into the
bond between Marlin and Dory.
After all,
they did spend a whole movie together.
They're probably totally buds now,
right?
Or what you can do.
You can go wait over there,
go right over there and forgot to do
best.
Not really.
Seems the arc of personal growth that
Marlin and Dory experienced in finding
nemo has reverted here with Dory now
being viewed as a nuisance by pretty
much everyone.
Sadly,
it isn't until dory is separated from
the relationships she formed in the
first film that were introduced to what
is supposed to be her source of support
in this movie,
the bond between Dory and Hank,
a curmudgeonly octopus who wants only to
exploit dory for the transport tag
attached to her fit.
No,
no,
no.
If I just take your bag,
I can take your place on the transport
truck and yeah,
I mean that's pretty much it.
That's the nature of their friendship.
Heartwarming,
right?
The emotionally deficient relationship
between hank and dory is almost entirely
transactional and deceitful,
which doubles down on the films empathy
gap.
But later finding dory hastily tries to
switch gears and that brings us to our
second point,
shaky narrative structure.
Take a look at most memorable films and
you'll find the protagonist making a key
decision right at the center of the
story.
It's a moment that reframes the
protagonists,
objectives and tests his or her resolve
some.
Refer to this as the film's midpoint
shift.
It's no coincidence that the halfway
mark is often a major moment of self
reflection for the protagonists,
a turning point in his or her journey.
So what happens halfway through finding
dory?
Well,
hank reveals he's got a soft spot for
that loopy bluefish.
He'll forgive me in a heartbeat.
Kid 300 new.
But where did this sentiment come from?
It's surely not earned by any particular
actions or moments in the film itself
because hanging dory are never really a
team.
And unlike Dorian Marlin,
they're never really shown enjoying
their adventure.
And Hey,
come to think of it,
hank isn't even the protagonist here.
In any case,
since Dorian,
hank have almost no moments of genuine
connection within the first half of
finding dory hanks.
Change of heart towards Dory,
midway through the film.
Can't help but feel unearned.
I don't care.
Contrast this with the realization
Marlin experiences in the middle of
finding nema and maybe wouldn't have
done it if I hadn't been so tough on him
here.
Marlin begins to recognize the error of
his overprotective parenting style,
and this realization is a direct result
of his control freak behavior,
nearly getting dory killed throughout
finding Nemo.
This midpoint shifts and other character
revealing moments are directly motivated
by cause and effect.
Mimo is motivated to put his life in
jeopardy because he learns his dad is
heroic.
Ua Dad's been fighting the entire ocean.
Looking for you.
Marlin is motivated to team with Dory
because he realizes dory can read.
You can read,
I can read later.
Marlin is motivated to separate himself
from Dory because he thinks his son is
dead in finding dory.
However,
key moments in the story like hanks
change of heart towards dory are largely
motivated by convenience and necessity.
There are simply what needs to happen to
move characters from point a to point b
later.
Dory refers the hank as sweet,
even though evidence of any such
sweetness is scarce at best,
but hey,
in this movie being an acid pretty
easily forgiven as long as you pay lip
service to some sort of growth deep into
finding dory.
Marlin tells story for,
since I've met you,
you show me how to do stuff I never
dreamed of doing crazy thing,
but even this sentiment to seems
unearned because it leverages moments
from the first fill in which Dorian
Marlin adventured and grew closer
together rather than from this sequel in
which they are either separated from
each other or annoyed.
Nevertheless,
this moment is meant to play as a moment
of self awareness and maturity from
Marlin,
which raises the question,
what is doerries key moment of self
awareness in finding dory?
You are remembered in your own amazing
dory way.
Wow.
You've got to wait until the movie is
nearly over to find out,
and this illustrates,
finding doerries.
Third Setback,
passive heroism for much of the film's
running time.
Dori operates as a passive protagonists,
one who responds to events rather than
create opportunities.
Some have this tendency is due to we're
all too convenient memory flashes which
handily take the story wherever the
screenwriters needed to go.
These flashes and even the occasional
undertow are driven more by chance and
proximity then as a result of personal
effort or growth.
Although sometimes it's almost as if the
film is suggesting doerries disability
can be willed away.
I remembered something.
This perspective seems fishy at best and
it doesn't leave Dory with many
opportunities to demonstrate her
ingenuity and develop it.
Events often happened to dory rather
than because of her,
and that's never a recipe for great
storytelling.
Of course,
a another cause of Doris passivity is
the nature of the films actual
environment.
After the films,
first 20 minutes,
dory quite literally becomes a fish out
of water,
a status which restricts her movements
to the whims of other characters.
How much can we expect our protagonists
to be the master of her own fate,
which is being carried around in coffee
pots,
baby buggies,
or a bucket that's labeled destiny.
By trading the thrilling blue ocean of
the first film to the claustrophobic
human centric clinical spaces of finding
dory.
Pixar ultimately hamstrings the scope of
the story it's able to tell and the
degree to which as protagonists can help
tell it.
Dory then isn't a driver of her own
story.
She's a passenger,
a passive responder to triggered
memories and odd partnership and very
often blind luck,
but at least her personal motivation
remains relatively clear.
Do you know anyone who lost a kid a long
time ago?
That wouldn't be me.
She wants to find her parents,
and so if we're willing to buy into the
premise of the film,
we must simply want to find them too.
Even though doerries desire to see her
family is very conveniently triggered by
the school of fish saying the word
right.
That's
It's true that doerries ultimate
objective is never in doubt,
but the same can't always be said for
Marlin in this film and it's even less
clear for Nimo who at this point seems
in desperate need of child protective
services and this leads us to the
purposeless entourage.
Oh,
pause here to ask a simple but important
question.
Why does finding dory involve all three
of these fish and does nemos involvement
actually negatively impact our feelings
about Dorian Marlin?
That's Marlin having just a year earlier
across the perilous ocean to save his
only surviving child now agrees to drag
that same child with him to guide dory
all the way across the ocean.
Again,
simply because how can you be talking
about the view?
And I remembered my.
No,
I'm okay,
but this springs from the studios need
for a sequel,
not from clear character behavior.
Ultimately,
finding dory commits the sin of asking
Marlin and Emo to undermine so much of
what made finding nemo powerful.
After all the emotional investment we as
an audience made in Nemos recovery and
finding Nemo.
Finding Dory asks us to believe that
Marlin responsible father extraordinary
is willing to risk his own son's life.
On the basis of Doris Hunch about her
parents she hasn't seen in years and no,
I'm not being hyperbolic.
Mimo really seriously almost dies.
I mean,
couldn't Marlin just find a babysitter?
Why is Nimo part of this new adventure?
Why does Dory,
who presumably cares about Nimo safety,
agreed to pull them along on a dangerous
mission to serve her own personal
agenda?
The film mostly bypasses these questions
and if we are to enjoy it,
so most wheat,
but we should all take a moment here to
at least recognize the weirdness of
ending a fish movie with a car chase on
the freeway and hey,
look at that door is a passenger again
in her own movie.
Thanks for watching guys piece and if
you want to see some more of our brain
tickling videos,
click here to check them out and make
sure to subscribe and ring that bell if
you haven't already,
catch you next time.
Guys.