Hey wisecracks and share it again.
You might've noticed that we have a soft
spot for cynical,
irreverent,
and even nihilist comedy,
but we've recently been wondering is
there anything on the other side of our
current cynicism is comedy based and
earnestness and genuine human emotion
still possible?
To answer this question,
we're turning to our friend Bo Burnham,
a comedian who might have cracked the
code for how to embrace all the
intellectual goodness of postmodern
irony
while
offering something with a real human
core.
Could we get the house lights up for a
second and could you put the lights on
stage?
Let the artifice fade away.
Now we're all the same like a candy bar
that has a hard shell of cultural
cynicism on the outside,
but a warm hug from your favorite aunt
on the inside.
Even though Burnham is still baby faced,
his work has actually gone through a few
distinct stages.
While his earliest work incorporates
postmodern cynicism and ironic
detachment,
I adopted a child from overseas to
rescue him from child labor factories
and on his very first birthday we went
to build a bear workshop is more recent
work.
Not only exposes the meaningless core of
contemporary life,
but also attempts to offer a corrective
with introspection and a search for
happiness.
On a scale from one to zero are you
happy?
Burnham might be the rare comedic figure
able to offer salvation from the empty
cultural wasteland.
That is our modern world.
So welcome to this wisecrack condition
on the philosophy of Bo Burnham and I
guess spoilers part one.
How did we get here to understand why
Burnham represents such an important
shift in comedy?
We first need to see how comedy arrived
at its postmodern era,
and more importantly,
what the hell is even meant by
postmodernism.
This phrase become so amorphous that it
can be used to describe everything from
cars to Scottish beer,
but a more helpful understanding can be
found in the work of Fredrick Jamison
who's work describes postmodernism as
the cultural logic of late capitalism,
which means that each new form of
economic life creates a related form of
cultural life.
For example,
when you're a poor college student,
your economic situation dictates a
cultural life of cheap beers.
Movies in a dorm room and paying for
dollar cheesy rollups with your laundry
quarters.
When you graduate and get a job,
you're drinking a locally made IPA
paying $20 for a movie ticket and using
your debit card for a cheesy Gordita
crunch.
A few years later,
you sell your app flush finder that
gives you a map of the cleanest public
toilets near you and you'll be drinking
aged whiskey sitting court side and
sending your scared assistant,
Adrian,
to grab you a crunchwrap Supreme Combo.
Each economic stage in your life leads
to a new cultural stage and
postmodernism is the cultural logic of
the current stage of economic
development,
which jamison calls late capitalism.
Now let's see how Jamison's ideas can
help us understand me shifting trends in
American comedy over the past 70 years.
We can do this with a three step
process.
Economic Culture leads to popular
culture,
which leads to comedy.
Let's start in the fifties America is in
a post war boom.
The Gi bill has led to record numbers of
college grads and homeowners.
It's easy to get a middle class job and
Cuba is just a quaint island of resorts
and cocktails.
This era's popular culture is all about
optimism and enjoyment.
What are you doing up here?
I thought you were downstairs.
Backs and chocolate all.
They kicked me out of there fast.
I kept pinching them to see what kind
they were
and their comedy sensibility can be seen
in someone like Jack Benny.
Congratulation bars,
why you would just shine when appeal of
a day data
by the mid sixties the boom time is
over.
The Cold War has people on edge and the
Vietnam war is on the horizon.
There were protests,
naked hippies and someone gave the
Beatles.
LSD.
The counterculture had snuck into the
popular culture and Lenny Bruce is on
trial for obscenities while George
Carlin is listing
and
by the 80s Reagan had promised endless
economic growth and we've got cable TV
to keep us company.
24 seven new media creates the
opportunity for a new read of superstar
and wild.
Michael Jackson sold out arenas with his
music.
Eddie Murphy did the same with comedy,
but let's be honest,
the most important thing is how fly they
look and red leather jacket.
It's in the nineties Comedians like
Jerry Seinfeld and Ray Romano had gone
from successful standups to television
stars.
How many was more mainstream than ever?
MTV giant cell phones and economic
growth,
a bounded and all the while.
How many rode this wave with a new
optimism and increasingly goofy spirit.
We're not worthy,
but just like Taco bell's Nacho fries,
good things can't last forever.
And by the dawn of the 21st century,
the.com
bubble had burst.
Limp Biscuit was popular and nine 11
left the country.
Wondering if anything could be funny
anymore.
Can we be funny?
Why start now?
As the aughts rolled on,
things didn't get much better.
The 2008 financial crisis was the worst
since the great depression and the weird
scrubs reboot left us all wondering if
nothing was sacred anymore.
Part too
comedy as cultural cynicism,
the political and economic cynicism of
the oughts led to a new form of cultural
cynicism in the media
design.
And I never was alone.
If you don't go squeeze on her day.
Wow.
Mostly known for its groundbreaking
character prison.
Mike.
The worst thing about prison was the was
the dementors.
They were flying all over the place and
it was scary and then they'd come down
and they suck the soul out of your body
and it height.
The office showed us the mundane and
often meaningless existence of the
American worker and the rest of his
division was slowly taken over by
reality shows that we're all completely
fake,
but nobody seemed to care.
One of the most recent shifts that helps
us.
The effect of late capitalism on comedy
is what we're calling the adult swim
phenomenon.
What started as a way for cartoon
network to get stoners to watch their
channel while eating double decker tacos
has since become the home of some of the
weirdest,
most absurd and most intentionally
cringeworthy comedy to hit the American
Airways.
Tim and Eric,
awesome show,
great job,
showed us a surreal and absurdist
version of the upside down.
[inaudible].
It's nice to put a good Eric Andre
ironically occupied the space of the
late night host,
the show how meaningless the late night
model had become while using interviews
with c list celebrities.
The highlight,
the vapid nature of it,
contemporary fame.
Mr Neighbors House has recently shown us
what happens when Mr.
Rogers has put through the postmodern
cynicism filter.
Uh,
no matter what the color and when you
lie,
you hurt your brother.
And of course our friends rick and morty
give us an animated response to the
classic philosophical question.
What if back to the future was an r
rated movie involving the multiverse
nihilism.
Nobody gets it.
Nothing you think matters,
matters and lots of brown liquor.
Many of these shows weren't even funny,
at least in the traditional sense,
whereas the 90s and early aughts used
canned laughter to tell our lizard
brains when to laugh.
Ah,
Eric Andre used canned laughter to
create an uncomfortable moment for all
involved
to hear about this.
Maybe Andre just wants to push the
limits of what we'll watch or maybe he's
asking you if there's even such a thing
as authentic comedy anymore.
We only know one thing's for sure about.
You've got to eat.
The lettuce is just straight up eat the
lettuce
at the same time that adult swim is
blossoming.
Occupy Wall Street is taking over the
streets of Manhattan and young people
around the world are questioning
economic and political institutions in a
way that would make the mug covered.
Hippies proud,
but I'm like their forefathers Linnaean
and George who used political cynicism
to infuse their comedy with an urgency
for truth.
Got No steel industry left,
can educate our young people,
can't get healthcare to our old people,
but we can bomb the shit out of your
country.
Three.
All right.
Don't swim generation.
Let this cynicism go from a rallying
cry.
This cynicism for cynicism safe rather
than a response to a troubled world.
This cynicism denied the existence of
real meaning or truth in the first
place.
Just say summit again,
it don't matter,
but not of this.
Madison
do return to the fourth meal of cultural
theory.
Fredrick Jamison.
This cynical comedy is a perfect
exemplification of postmodernism,
the same cultural form repeats,
but this time with iron ore to
paraphrase marks first as Johnny Carson,
ben is Eric Andre eating his own vomit.
Cynicism and irony led to a brand of
comedy in which truth meaning and human
earnestness are just useless relics from
the era of canned laughter and Pesky New
York mothers.
So are we now in this postmodern
feedback loop of meaninglessness?
Maybe not.
But to find out we have to return to our
friend Beau.
Nope.
The other one,
she's pretty,
but no,
no.
Not The obamas.
Portuguese water dog.
The comedian,
lanky white guy in his twenties yes.
Finally Jesus.
Three from irony to sincerity in Bo
Burnham,
our guys.
Before we keep going,
real charity here for a minute.
As you guys know,
we sometimes talk about pretty heavy
subjects.
Cynicism.
Nihilism avoids a meaning.
You know the drill.
But these topics can be,
to put it bluntly,
a bumper.
So that's why I want to talk about this
video sponsored for better help,
a counseling service that allows you to
connect with licensed therapists on your
computer,
tablet,
or mobile phone.
I actually tried the service myself,
so wait till the end of the video to
hear more about my experience until
then,
go to better help.com/wise
crack to get started.
And now back to Bo.
Bo Burnham is an interesting case.
As much of his early work was shaped by
the influence of Dutch absurdist haunts,
tailwind,
where have you been in jail?
For what?
Right?
I had no idea
and embodied eighth attach irony which
exemplified the tenants of postmodern
comedy.
Jesus can walk on water.
Can you swim on land
because there is no fixed standard of
truth or meaning.
Burnham used comedy to point the
audience to the slack.
Jesus
wasn't the Messiah.
Get back on the herons again.
I'm on fire with the head of past those
holy nights stuff.
Holy mother,
right
in his recent work,
Burnham pushes back against the
emptiness of postmodernism in an attempt
to find genuine meaning in things like
love and happiness.
We could say that rather than returning
back to ava.
Modern perspective,
Burnham pushes through postmodernism to
arrive at a post postmodern perspective
where the death of traditional meaning
is an opportunity for the creation of
new meanings.
We can see his progression by
considering his three specials as three
distinct stages in his comedic
development is first special words,
words,
words explores the death of art and
comedy.
The followup,
what goes a step further and operates
under the principle that meaning itself
is dead and his most recent special make
happy works through the death of meaning
in an attempt to see if real meaning and
happiness are still possible from the
opening minutes of words,
words,
Burnham aims to show the audience the
facade of entertainment.
It's all an illusion and I'm wearing may
God I'm wearing may got bay Guy Burnham
art is dead because it's really just a
means for something else.
So people think you're funny how they
get those people's mind and true to the
logic of late capitalism.
The real purpose of art is simply
creating opportunities for making more
money and presumably eating Nacho
cheese,
Doritos,
locos,
supreme's whenever you want and when he
speculates on what the forefathers of
counter cultural comedy would think.
His conclusion isn't pretty.
We're rolling in dough out car.
Lana rose eight is gray.
His array by pointing
to the death of art,
Burnham shows how comedy has just become
a way for charming narcissist,
make as much money as they can with no
imperative for authenticity or truth.
If words,
words,
words is Burnham's eulogy for the death
of art.
He goes a step further in what and
mourns the death of truth and meaning as
such,
artist alive,
not like Israel.
And he's aware that in the context of
people's actual problems,
laughter isn't the medicine we've been
sold.
That's it last towards the key to
everything is the way to solve all the
sadness in the world.
I mean,
not for the people that are actually
stabbed,
but the people like us that got to deal
with them all the time.
Unlike the adult swim comedians burden
doesn't just embrace the chaos that
comes from the depth of meaning.
He's asking what it means for us when
meaning dies.
None of you are go,
hey,
and asking whether or not the creation
of meaning is possible.
Maybe the life on earth could be have.
He has no conclusive answer in what,
and he lets us sit in that space of not
knowing.
Oh cool.
What is the point where he starts to
consider that comedy devoid of the
aspirations of any higher meeting is
just an equine atm.
By the way,
I'll stop beating this dead horse when
it stops spinning.
Now
make happy represents Burnham's attempt
to use comedy not just for criticism,
but as a vehicle to search for meaning
and he makes clear early on at his
comedy is not a mode of escapism.
You are here because you want to laugh
and you want to forget about your
problems,
but I cannot allow it.
You should not mind.
You should not forget about your
problems.
Instead of escape,
Burnham tries to use comedy as an
occasion for the audience.
Jukes truly encountered their problems
and maybe themselves in the process and
less you underestimate Burnham's desire
to make you think about some real shit.
Okay.
The world is not funny.
12% of the world's population does not
have access to clean drinking water.
The world is not funny guy fee area owns
two functioning restaurants
and while he has some facts wrong,
verdomme doesn't want to use culture as
a way to escape reality,
which is one of Jamison's worries about
postmodernism that it removes the
imperative for us to be critical about
the world around us.
Like a server who lets you know that
he's upselling you on donkey sauce,
not because it's good but because it
will make him money.
Burnham lets us peek behind the
comedians curtain entertainers,
they are lying and they are manipulating
you.
It's not all harsh reality for Burnham
though as he thinks the move past
cynicism has some upside.
We all deserve even on the days when we
are in our past cause we all suck.
Love can make a suck less.
Paul deserve love.
It's the very best part of being an I
would know.
I just turned 20
yeah.
And by adding that last line,
he undercuts his own point,
showing us a position that straddles the
line between naive optimism and ironic
cynicism.
The show ends with Bo Burnham's take on
a Kanye West concert circuit.
2016 cannot say much
New York cannot see much.
While it might start off with jokes,
listen to the people,
I'm sure 90% of the complaint letters
you get are about the width of your
cans.
Just make them wider.
He peppers this confession with some
more vulnerable moment.
Don't go to the gym because I'm self
conscious about my body,
but I'm self conscious about my body
cause that don't go to the gym
and he closes out with what seems like a
genuine wish for his audience.
Thank you.
Good night.
I hope you're happy
with make happy.
Burnham hearkens back to the socratic
tendencies from comedians in a previous
era,
much like the gadfly of Athens himself,
Burnham is urging his audience to truly
acknowledge their problems,
that unhappiness as the unexamined life
is not worth living.
And like aristotle,
his final words imply that happiness
might be possible,
but we have to work at it.
What's most interesting is that Burnham
doesn't simply reject postmodern comedy
for the sake of something new.
Instead,
he pushes postmodern comedy to its limit
to see what's on the other side.
And over the course of these three
specials,
we see him transition from irony to
cynicism to earnestness or from the
death of art to the depth of meaning to
the possibility of meaningful art after
the death of me.
Art For comedy as a cure for despair,
or is Rick Sanchez right now,
you might be wondering,
so what even burden thinks we should try
to be happy?
We live in a world where goodness and
truth seem increasingly illusory and in
a world where Nacho fries aren't even on
most Taco bell man use anymore.
Is it even worth moving past postmodern
cynicism?
One telling factor is that Burnham isn't
the only one trying to inject a post
postmodern sincerity back into comedy.
A great example is the most critically
successful comedy film of 2017 the big
sick,
which coincidentally stars Burnham as a
comedian obsessed with success and while
it's a genuinely funny movie,
it explores family success and love with
a sincerity,
not common in comedy films and it's safe
to guests that the inclusion of Ray
Romano isn't a coincidence as receive.
The cranky set calmed out of the
nineties portraying a complicated and
compassionate human being.
We've also seen this shift from irony to
sincerity in shows like Nathan for you.
I mean the ones I do get
you guys in a part of me is envious that
you know I don't have someone in my life
that is unless close with
and infusing absurdity with a story
about genuine adult friendship in
Detroit and even one of the darkest
shows out there.
Bojack horseman explores the possibility
of finding real meaning.
It takes a long time to realize how
truly miserable you are and even longer
to see that it doesn't have to be that
way.
Only after you give up everything can
you begin to find a way to be happy.
While Fredrick Jamison has yet to offer
an analysis of the way in which comedy
can cure the cultural illness of
postmodernism.
It might just be the case that Burnham's
work is telling us something about what
will happen on the other side of late
capitalism.
Either way,
the crunchwrap supreme is here to stay.
So maybe there are eternal truths that
we can all still believe in.
But Hey,
crunchwrap supreme is can't solve all
your problems.
Trust me,
I've tried seriously though,
there are real ways to help with life
struggles.
So this video is sponsored by better
help.
I actually tried out the service myself.
I spoke with a certified therapist named
Jennifer and it was really pleasant.
It was as good or better than any
therapist I've seen in real life.
So with better helping them communicate
with the counselor via message,
live chat,
phone,
or video conferencing,
you can do therapy,
whether you're in the pool,
when you're walking your dog,
whatever is most productive for you.
So what I liked the most about better
health is that it's accessible.
People who normally wouldn't seek out
therapy or don't even know how to go
about getting it,
can get access quickly.
It's also convenient.
Oftentimes when people do decide to seek
therapy,
it's only because they're at a really
low point in their life.
They're already desperate.
And when you're in that state of mind,
the last thing you want to do is jump
through insurance hoops,
knowing who's in and out of your network
or who don't go through all that,
paying exorbitant amounts or having to
deal with stacks of paperwork.
That's not the case.
With better help,
people are matched within 24 hours and
it's completely confidential.
So better help gets rid of the stigma.
It gets rid of the hassle,
and it makes therapy accessible and
easy.
So look,
if you're like me and you think you
could benefit from speaking to someone
on a regular basis,
consider checking out better
help.com/wise
crack or clicking here to get started.
And as always,
guys,
thanks for watching
peace.