This video is sponsored by Blue Apron,
the 100 wisecrack fans to sign up for
blue apron at the link in the
description will get $50 off the first
two weeks.
Stick around for some Tacos.
Greetings and welcome to earthlings
cinema.
I am your host Garrick's wormy Lloyd.
This week's artifact is team America
world police from South Park creators,
Oliver Stone and Matt Parker,
who were famously exiled from Earth
after literally pissing off everyone,
the film opens in France where some
kindly terrorists chaperone a beeping
briefcase that is until the US Olympic
team choppers in.
They win the interpretive dance round,
but take home the silver in not dying
over on broad street and actor named
Gary Sings about one of Earth's best
diseases.
Everyone has a attracting the attention
of agent Colson.
I mean Morpheus,
I mean a balding horny puppet.
He takes him to Rushmore Academy where
he asks him to do the plot of 21 jump
street,
but with terrorists.
Although considering how teens were in
those days,
there wasn't much of a difference in
Korea town,
a near site,
a dictator has the terrorists over for
Kimchi.
Giving them some bombs as party favors,
gary gets his eyebrows done at the spa
so he can infiltrate the Cantina Bar,
but soon team America shows up and
sweeps the gold medal and destroying a
native culture.
America's oldest past time,
the team gets drunk.
All friendship and Lisa and Gary do the
bippity Boppity Boo.
Gary's not the only one getting blown.
Jack donaghy fears the Olympics or
stealing Liz lemon's ratings and
partners with k town for a piece
ceremony where Kim will secretly
detonated bombs.
Oh No,
no air quotes on that one.
Remembering that it's the end of act
two.
Gary quits and gets mild.
The
Fat Guy,
suicide squad's HQ just as Kim blows the
team's cover and captures them,
but their covers not the only thing
getting blown.
That's a call back just for you.
Gary trains with Spotswood,
trainspotting,
if you will,
and they go to k town to get the band
back together.
They kill most of the film actors guild
and no intelligent life is lost with the
stage.
Empty Gary attention.
Whores it up and engages in the time.
Honored tradition of oratory.
The only thing that can be an asshole is
it Dick donaghy gets ousted from NBC and
Kim falls on an outright baseball cap
revealing his true form a horse team
America world police can be viewed as a
response to the surge of nationalism.
The USA experienced after nine slash 11,
considered by many to be just never
forgettable.
The film is a satire stylized after
massive Hollywood blockbusters and
Netflix's which commonly celebrated
American power and perseverance.
The film beats down cliche after cliche
like they owe it money.
It mocks the emotional levers these
films try to pull just as it makes fun
of the overly sentimental country
ballots that make war seemed great.
The big bangs and puppet bans lies a
more subtle exploration of America's
role in the world.
Some scholars support the hegemonic
stability theory,
which supposes that the world will be
better off with a superpower calling the
shots.
Team America believes in American
exceptionalism.
The idea that the United States was
better than all other seven countries
and therefore duty bound to shape the
world too.
It's obese standards.
Don't you understand?
Every country in the world is in danger.
How is it my responsibility to do
something because like it or not,
you're the one with the power to do
something.
The film pokes fun at this attitude by
showing various ways that Americans are
poorly suited to boss baby.
Every one around.
When the film identifies a foreign
location,
it notes the distance from the USA,
exemplifying the tendency Americans had
to look down on other countries as well
as the metric system.
Cities such as Paris and tattooing are
reduced to their most famous landmarks
which are portrayed incorrectly as being
right next to each other instead of on
top of each other.
Foreign languages are portrayed as
Jibberish,
although it's all human.
To me,
this ignorance and lack of respect for
other countries manifests as team
America demolishes world landmarks to
make room for a whole food.
Ironically,
the self centered attitude is similar to
the terrorist psychology according to
smoking hot,
Lisa,
usually a case of malignant narcissism
you brought on during childhood.
Damn,
you're tearing me apart,
Lisa.
The film asks whether this careless
destructiveness and the name of American
ideals is any better than the terrorists
intentional attacks because it's the
thought that counts,
but the film is far from a one sided hit
piece on American jingoism unchained.
It criticizes ignorance on the other
side of the aisle to the actors standing
in for Alcoholic Grad students,
or liberals think they're better than
team America.
The film actors guild believes that what
the world needs is compassion,
not violence.
All the team America does is create new
enemies,
but their position is based on the same
blinding Elitism as team Americas.
What the world needs is an international
advisory committee who truly understands
global politics,
namely us and their ignorance,
causes them to bumble their way into the
wrong side of a global crisis.
Ultimately,
the film concludes that despite the
occasional terrorist attack,
someone's got to deal with purely
destructive entities,
especially if those entities can sing.
So really in the end,
the film endorses a more cautious
America,
but in America,
yeah.
Nonetheless,
it was the state motto of Florida after
all,
before it flooded,
and the sharks ate everybody until they
were dead.
For earthling cinema,
I'm Garrick's God bless America for
rent.
Hey guys,
Garrett intern,
jared here while showing mastication is
strictly prohibited under intergalactic
last subsection six,
making food is not,
and with blue apron,
you can rake five star meals without
having to leave your house.
I mean,
why would you want to?
By signing up,
you'll get farm fresh ingredients and
easy to follow recipes that are under
800 calories per life form.
We made spicy black bean,
caramelized onion tacos,
but if you're feeling crazy and want
spicier,
check out their Mediterranean menu
featuring such hits as Oregano,
chicken and calibrate and Chili shrimp.
In fact,
the first hundred wise crack fans to
sign up with blue apron via the link
below.
We'll get 50 bucks off your first two
weeks.
While the dish we made was vegetarian.
They're large selection of menus,
updated weekly also features meet from
all sorts of animals.
Click below again to get a sweet deal.
I'm off to censor more mastication piece
guys.