This video is sponsored by legal zoom
more on legal zoom at the end of the
video.
Hey,
wise crack jared again.
Now I don't know about you,
but every time a new Christopher Nolan
movie comes out,
I happily shell out my harder and 25
bucks for a sweet imax 70 millimeter
experience.
There are few directors today that can
meld thought provoking philosophy with
big budgets,
spectacle,
but Nolan well,
he makes it look as easy as spinning a
top.
Now,
instead of focusing on one particular
Nolan film,
we're going to take a step back and look
at his entire filmography because
throughout all 10 of Nolan's movies,
certain themes keep coming back.
In fact,
there's so much to discuss.
We've pulled the ultimate Hollywood
move.
Today's Christopher Nolan video will be
the first of three on the director.
Now,
don't worry,
we're not pulling a hobbit and extending
a children's book into a seven hour
trilogy.
Think of this instead,
if you will,
as our Lord of the rings.
There's just so much great stuff to say
about Nolan that we have to make three
videos in order to do his work justice.
So sit back in your recliner chair and
welcome to this epic wisecrack Imax 70
millimeter presentation of the
philosophy of Christopher Nolan,
part one,
and of course spoilers ahead,
Christopher.
Nolan's films can be broken down into
three distinct phases,
the self,
society,
and the universe.
The first phase we'll discuss the self
includes Nolan's early work following
Momento,
insomnia,
and the prestige as well as inception.
These films questioned the nature of
personhood.
Can we ever truly know someone else?
Can we know ourselves in our own
thoughts,
be trusted.
Hell,
what even is a person to better
understand how these questions develop
and Nolan's work.
We're first going to have to learn a
little something about what French
philosopher Paul record calls the
hermeneutics of suspicion,
or as the cool kids say,
Hos hermeneutics studies how people
interpret text.
Think of how a biblical verse can be
interpreted any number of ways Christ's
crucifixion could be thought of as an
allegorical,
moral,
or even literal story.
Hermeneutics looks at all these
different interpretations.
Focusing on the methodologies people use
to justify their interpretations and
it's not just biblical texts,
legal,
literary,
philosophical.
Pretty much any text you can think of
falls within hermeneutics.
Heck,
I mean wisecrack is basically just one
giant site dedicated to hermeneutics.
All we do is interpret text,
film,
television,
literature,
video games,
you name it,
but record questions.
These so called interpretations,
identifying a group of outside the box.
Philosophers committed to drawing out
less visible and flattering Truett's
record called this group the school of
suspicion which sort of sounds like an
erotic French thriller starring
Charlotte rampling and Ludovic saying
Yay,
but unfortunately it's just three dudes
with facial hair,
Friedrich Nietzsche,
Karl Marx,
and Sigmund Freud.
According to record these figures and
the lineage day inspired,
we're committed to unmasking the lies
and illusions of consciousness.
They circumvented self evident meanings
in text,
focusing on what wasn't said and the
contradictions within all to decode a
true disguised meaning.
So while religious stories like Christ's
resurrection may seem to be about how
man achieve salvation for the school of
suspicion,
these stories disguised a hidden
meaning.
Mark stated that the true purpose of
religious narratives were to make the
misery of life more endurable,
Micha unmasked religion as the refuge
for the week,
giving purpose to the mentally fragile,
and Freud thought that religion was an
illusion that substituted ones wished
for a father with God.
Now yes,
hermeneutics of suspicion typically only
applies to text,
but it can be used more broadly to refer
to any so called interpretation.
We hold a self evident and what's more
self evident and well ourselves.
Yes,
you youtube viewers watching this video
with your eight tabs open and fidget,
spinner in hand,
what we drink,
watch where fink believe all inform how
we interpret ourselves and others,
much like the Hos Nolan questions,
the conclusions that come from standard
interpretations.
He confounds our assumed knowledge,
challenging our presuppositions to
reveal deeper disguised truths about who
the hell we really are.
Nolan's films are always about that
suspicious relation between our
subjective reality and the idea of an
objective reality.
Now,
this might sound like idealism to the
philosophically inclined among you,
but we're not arguing that Nolan
dismisses any external reality,
but rather he embraces a critical
disposition toward the accepted notions
of the self.
Take Christopher Nolan's debut following
the black and white indy follows billy,
a struggling writer who obsessively
watched people from afar to get
inspiration for his novel.
One day he follows a well dressed thief
named cobb.
No,
not that one.
After he robbed a house,
cobb quickly notices billy watching,
but instead of running away or attacking
the stocker,
he invites billy to join in on his
robberies.
Interested now see,
cobb is far less interested in stealing
precious items than in figuring out the
lives of people through their
possessions,
freaking in entering someone's life,
finding out who they really are.
Both cobb and billy interpret and
construct their own images of people,
Bill,
he by following strangers around and
Cobb by breaking into people's homes and
rifling through their belongings.
But Nolan immediately questions.
If these conclusions hold any merit
suggesting you can't rely on appearances
in possessions to define a person,
as cop himself says,
when burglarizing a house,
take it away for cub,
violating a person's property forces his
victims to reevaluate themselves.
When the possessions people hold dear
are taken away or altered it in effect
causes them to question their identity.
Nolan also questions peoples reliance on
appearances,
carb urges billy to cut his hair and don
his same suits which bill he immediately
does because he wants to be just like
his mentor,
but this is all a setup.
The blonde woman is working with Cobb to
frame building the earlier break in and
make over just a long con on the poor
writer.
Billy's own presuppositions of cop are
revealed to be false,
a far more dastardly intent lurking
beneath his friendly smile and
mentorship.
Compliment Nolan's
suspicion towards using possessions and
appearance to define others carries over
to his next feature momento the film's
protagonists.
Leonard suffers from anterograde Amnesia
and relies on a series of possessions,
photographs,
notes,
and tattoos to remind himself of who the
people around him are and whether they
can be trusted.
Leonard puts complete faith in these
items depending on them exclusively to
guide his actions.
He trusts natalie because his notes tell
him to be kills teddy because again,
his notes tell him to.
He's the one he believes the car parked
outside his,
his because he has a photograph that
tells himself
my car is your car.
Oh,
you're in a playful mood,
but of course these momentos aren't
nearly as reliable as Leonard belief.
He don't even know my name.
Teddy [inaudible].
You read it off of the picture.
Nolan,
in true hos fashion creates drama by
throwing suspicion toward the validity
of texts.
In this case,
photographs,
notes,
and tattoos.
How can we trust something we read if
the source itself is questionable?
Truth is Natalie.
Can't be trusted.
That car parked out front actually
doesn't belong to Leonard and Teddy.
Well,
he's not the guy.
Leonard could kill it all.
Leonard may say,
well,
I go on facts,
not recommendations,
but thank you,
but if the truths these facts are based
on are incorrect,
then what use are they?
Nolan constantly draws a distinction
between Leonard subjective reality and
the idea of objective truth.
Well,
what we were trying to do is essentially
present a,
an idea of the tension between a
subjective view of the world,
the subjective way in which we have to
experience life,
and then our faith in an objective
reality.
Beyond that,
in Leonard's subjective view,
he's a husband avenging the rape and
murder of his wife after a break in,
but as the film reveals,
his wife actually survived this initial
attack.
It was Leonard who accidentally killed
his wife,
forgetting he had already given her her
insulin shot.
Moreover,
Leonard actually already caught and
murdered his wife's rapist over a year
ago.
He uses text to trick himself into
believing that this idealized revenge
mission still exists.
You don't want the truth.
You make up your own truth like he
police.
It was complete when I gave it to you
who took out the 12 pages?
You know,
it wasn't me saying was you don't do
that to create a puzzle.
You could never solve
Leonard conditions themselves to believe
in the lives he's created to the point
where even his own longterm memories are
fabricated.
He substitutes the story of Sammy Jankis
for his own so he doesn't have to live
with the guilt of accidentally murdering
his wife.
Nolan here extends the Hermeneutics of
suspicion from simple texts.
Leonard's unreliable notes to Leonard
himself,
his own false memories.
I lie to myself to be happy in your
case,
Teddy.
Yes,
I will.
This suspicion continues into Nolan's
third feature insomnia,
wherein Momento Leonard is an unreliable
narrator who's unable to discern reality
from his own fiction.
Insomnia's chief protagonists,
detective will.
Dormer seems to be the opposite.
He's reliable,
intelligent,
and perceptive,
but if momento focused on a broken man,
attempting to rebuild his sense of self
insomnia takes the counter approach
showing how even the most rock solid guy
like say an Alpha Chino can crumble in
the self doubt with just a little push.
See,
madness,
as you know,
is like gravity.
All it takes is a little push
hold up ledger.
We'll get to you in part two anyway,
after will mistakenly shoots his partner
in the fog.
The guilt of the event triggers intense
psychological confusion and well
insomnia.
He hallucinates his dead partner room,
seemed to distort around will and
everyday noises become blisteringly.
Irritating.
Later,
we'll hallucinates that he actually did
see his partner in the fog and that he
deliberately shot him.
Unlike momento insomnia,
provides no clear explanation about what
is true,
did will deliberately shoot his partner,
or was it just an accident?
The answer who knows Nolan yet again
extends the Hermeneutics of suspicion.
Now questioning reality itself,
he implies it's much more complicated
than just accepting either pure
objectivity or subjective idealism.
Perhaps we can't ever be sure of the
world around us by the end of insomnia.
Will doesn't even know if he
deliberately shot his partner or not.
Did you mean to shoot hat anymore?
The Prestige is pretty much Nolan's
greatest hits as he tackles all the
hermeneutics of suspicion from his
earlier work.
They'll film is told through a series of
journals,
many of which are fake.
Once again,
casting suspicion on good old texts,
all of the films magicians use disguises
to mask their tricks.
The Great Chung Lynn Sue pretends to be
a cripple Alford borden where's
disguises to mask that he has a twin and
both Alfred and his Frenemy,
Robert and repeatedly pretend to be
audience members like in following and
Momento.
Appearances can't be trusted and the
self is constantly put into doubt.
Even Alfred's own wife doesn't know his
secret,
confused that her husband could be so
loving one day and so cold,
the next unaware of the existence of her
husband's twin.
I love you today.
Some days it's not true today.
You don't mean it.
I love you today.
It's true.
No one uses magic yet again to question
subjective reality versus the idea of
objective truth.
From the audience's subjective point of
view,
the bird really does disappear and then
reappear,
but in reality,
there were actually two twin birds,
one dead beneath the table,
the other reappearing and the magician's
hands.
No,
just asthma.
Mentos Leonard prefers to live in the
illusion of is manipulated subjective
reality.
The audience to prefers illusion over
truth.
They don't want to know how Robert
Literally duplicating himself each
night,
murdering his double in a water tank
beneath the stage.
They'd much rather live under the lie
that Robert Disappears and then suddenly
reappears on the opposite end of the
theater.
People actually believes the things I
did on stage.
They wouldn't clap that screaming
as a filmmaker.
Nolan views himself like these
magicians.
He plays with illusion and Mr.
Direction to keep the audience guessing.
We know that we're watching a movie,
a projection on a screen and illusion,
but we don't really want to know this
truth,
so we revel in the imaginary world that
Nolan has crafted.
This is what Nolan ultimately wants to
affect the audience through trickery.
For him,
the truth deep down is that we prefer
the imaginary over reality.
What is knows the truth,
solid
Nolan suspicion towards reality.
Climaxes in inception of film work,
every single thing is put into doubt.
That guy who looks like Tom Berenger,
well,
that's actually Tom Hardy,
can trust your eyes that thought you
just had.
It's actually been implanted by Leonardo
Dicaprio.
Can't trust yourself,
your children waiting to play outside.
Actually,
it's all a dream.
Maybe can't trust anything.
Inceptions protagonists,
dream thief,
carb.
No,
not that one can barely discern his
reality from a dream to the point where
it doesn't even matter in Cobb's
supposed reality,
he's on the run,
chased by goons with guns through
Byzantine pathways in Cobb,
supposed to dream.
He's well still on the run,
chased by goons with guns through
Byzantine pathways,
chase around the globe by anonymous
corporations and these courses and where
the protections persecute the dream to
me.
You don't believe in one reality
anymore.
Nolan deliberately draws this parallel
to showcase how muddled the two are put
simply,
there is no difference between dream and
reality because subjectively cop can't
tell the difference,
such as the fate for COBB's wife mall.
She believes that her reality is still a
dream and to wake up she must kill
herself.
Possessed by an idea.
This one very simple idea and changed
everything that our world wasn't real.
She needed to wake up to come back to
reality,
but what is malts actually right?
What if cobb has been dreaming the whole
time?
What if you're wrong?
What if I'm.
What's real,
no definitive answer is ever given,
which is exactly Nolan's point in the
end,
only the question remains that last
indelible image of that Damn spinnings
hopped,
spinning,
but just slightly wavering,
provides no definitive answer as to have
carb is dreaming or awake only further
proving that in the end there is no
truth,
no reality,
only the suspicion thereof,
well at least until we get to part
three,
through each of Nolan's early films,
he casts doubt on appearances,
on possessions,
on others,
on ourselves,
on our thoughts,
and finally on reality,
but if you can't trust anybody else and
you can't trust yourself and holy,
you can't even trust the reality
surrounding you,
then how the hell does society function?
How can people come together and form a
stable working unit?
Given the foundational bedrock is so
wonky?
This is the question,
Nolan explorers through his dark knight
trilogy,
which we'll explore in the next part of
our own wise crack Nolan trilogy.
Thanks for watching guys piece.
Nolan is a master at making you question
your sanity,
but there's no reason your legal needs
should make you feel that way.
Legal Zoom is the smart way to handle
all your legal essentials and they're
giving wise crack fans 15 percent off
their purchase.
Whether you're setting up a new business
or planning family matters.
They'll help you breeze through the
process like it's nothing.
Legal Zoom eliminates the guesswork of
trying to track down an attorney you
trust,
calculating how much your legal work
will cost in having to drag yourself to
a lawyer's office.
Legal Zoom works with a network of
independent attorneys to help you with
all sorts of projects,
the formation of your company,
wills and trusts,
trademarks and patents contracts and
more.
When we decided to do wisecrack full
time,
the most important step was making sure
our business was set up right.
Separating personal stuff from the
company and navigating all the
intricacies of state and local laws can
be a huge pain,
but legal zoom offers the services and
resources to make sure you get it done
right.
Head over to legalzoom.com/wise,
crack at the link in the description
below and bring all your questions about
starting a business.
Planning a family or copyright and
trademark stuff.
You'll get 15 percent off your purchase
just for being a fan of what we do.
Thanks to legal zoom for sponsoring this
video.
That's all for now.
Wisecrack.
Don't forget to subscribe to help us
reach 2 million subscribers and ring
that bell so you don't miss a thing.
He skies.