This video is brought to you by skill
share.
What's up wise?
Crack Jared again.
Now you would think that after almost 20
years of some of the most intense fan
hatred ever,
thumbs way down,
you didn't like,
no,
I think I deserve a public apology from
George Lucas.
There'd be nothing new to say about the
worst star war,
the phantom menace.
And yet here we are.
After the release of return of the Jedi.
In 1983 millions of fans begged George
Lucas to create a new star wars film.
Studio executives begged him,
toy makers,
begged him and after constantly saying
no.
Finally in 1999 everyone got their wish.
George Lucas released the phantom
menace.
Problem solved except not really upon
release.
Star Wars fans rose up in fury and
demanded the head of George Lucas on a
tuscan spike.
They rallied together and aol chat rooms
and Yahoo message boards.
And for the first time in these short
history of the Internet,
fans from across the world banded
together in the righteous cause of
tearing George Lucas a new one for the
unforgivable sin that was making this
movie.
And hey look,
they had a point.
The phantom menace,
for lack of better word,
sucks.
Hundreds of articles,
essays and videos have been written
about how it sucks shadow Mr Plink it.
So you don't mind.
I like the characters.
Know what you're stupid and why it
sucks.
So much so that it has become a given
that there's absolutely nothing
redeemable about this movie.
But what if that's not entirely true?
Relax.
I'm not going to argue that many
chlorines were a great idea.
It is possible he was conceived.
Instead of want to talk about what the
phantom menace gets almost right.
Because conceptually there are some very
promising themes at play here.
Namely Nazis.
It's no secret that the original trilogy
largely wanted you to conflate the
empire with the third,
right from the costumes to the use of
color.
And of course naming the soldiers storm
troopers.
But how did the galaxy get to be this
way?
Like Nazi Germany,
which descended into totalitarianism
through democratic means,
George Lucas aspired to portray
something immensely important with the
prequels.
How a peaceful republic can
democratically descend into full blown
nazi-ism.
So what went wrong?
Well,
let's find out.
Welcome to this wisecrack condition on
star wars.
Episode one,
the Phantom Menace.
What went wrong?
And uh,
can you spoil the movie with no plot?
Oh,
and if you want to hear us nerd out
about the Disney star wars backlash,
check out our special episode on our
movie podcast.
Show me the meaning.
You will smash that link in the
description for everyone who hasn't seen
this in over a decade.
Here's a brief recap and organization
called the Trade Federation is
protesting trade taxes by blockading
trade with the planet and the Boob.
But I guess it doesn't have to make
sense because really they're doing it
all for their boy.
Darth Sidious,
Aka Senator Palpatine.
There are public,
a certain quiet gone gin and his
apprentice.
Oh,
we Kenobi to negotiate,
but the trade federation tries to kill
them.
They flee to the surface of Nibu,
which is now being invaded by the trade
federation and counter the worst
character ever conceived in cinematic
history.
Save the Queen and try to zoom off to
the Galactic Senate where they can
explain what a bunch of jerks the trade
federation is.
But they get shot up and at the find
supplies on tattooing where they meet a
nice slave boy with incredible force
blood.
There are some like gambling.
They liberate the boy,
leave his mother to rot and head to the
Senate to plead their case.
There's a battle quite gone dies or we
won murders.
Darth Maul and Palpatine is now the head
Honcho of the Galactic Senate.
Also,
jar jar is a general,
the original trilogy,
while wonderfully enjoyable are not
complex works of emotional art and
they're not intended to be.
There are updates of the flash gordon
buck Rogers cereals from Lucas's
childhood.
The heroes were good men who often were
white and the villains were evil men who
often wore black just like luke
skywalker and darth vader.
There's no ambiguity here and that's
okay.
The phantom menace on the other hand is
quite ambiguous,
quite gone,
lies in cheats his way through most of
the story.
He as per the light side of the forest,
quietly meditates before his final
confrontation against Darth Maul and
gets wrecked.
Obiwan fills with rage and emotion
associated with the dark side.
And only then can he effectively avenge
his master,
not quite the black and white morality
of the first three films,
but most notable is our benevolent
heroin Queen Ahmed Dolla.
She spends the phantom menace trying to
save her people,
but for all her noble intentions,
she mostly gets manipulated by senator
palpatine and even proves integral in
getting him elected supreme chancellor.
When good leads to victory for evil,
we've entered the realm of the morally
ambiguous in his essay art and moral
education philosopher Christopher
Hamilton expounds on the richness of
such moral ambiguity in so much as they
force us to confront our own moral
beliefs.
It's a sign of great art.
So did the phantom menace give us that
gut punch that comes with us
reevaluating our own moral beliefs?
Of course it did.
Right,
right.
Okay.
Just kidding.
I felt nothing all 20 times I've seen
this movie.
Ambiguity is a great idea when dealing
with complex issues like political
systems,
trade federation,
planetary autonomy,
solving humanitarian crises.
So why didn't it work?
Because the characters have no agency.
Author.
Chuck Wendig,
who has written extensively on the
subject defines agency and fiction as a
demonstration of the characters ability
to make decisions and affect the story.
They have motivations all their own.
They are active more than they are
reactive.
They push the plot more than the plot
pushes on them and contrast.
He writes that characters without agency
tend to be like little paper boats
bobbing down a river of your own making.
They cannot steer.
They cannot change the course of the
river.
The river is an external force that
carries them along,
meaning the plastics,
his hand up the characters cavernous
bottom hole and makes the character do
things and say things in service to the
plot in the phantom menace.
It's almost like Lucas took this rule of
bad writing and ran with it quite gone
and Anagen and Pat May and Obi wan and
God helped me judge.
Our banks aren't nothing but little
paper boats.
They have no internal conflict,
no external life,
no personal obsession outside of what
the film dictates and that river pushing
them along.
And I'll,
as we later learn,
it's the dark side.
It does everything possible to see the
future and the biggest casualty besides
the time you and I just wasted being
bored is the political message itself.
The best example of this is the story of
Queen Amidala Pad May,
along with many of the other characters
are mere ponds of palpatine.
That's not necessarily a bad thing,
but as we'll see,
palpatine's manipulations quickly turned
into how to cover up bad writing one on
one.
Here's what we know about pat mate.
She's a queen who doesn't want to submit
to some invader because,
well,
that's what Queens do.
Just a likes democracy because hey,
she's not evil.
So in Star Wars,
how does a queen who likes democracy
lead to the eventual downfall of said
democracy?
She gets manipulated.
Palpatine creates a crisis on the Bu,
which mirrors the prototypical false
flag attack of the Reichstag fire.
And she has to plead to the Senate to
intervene.
But palpatine's since he's smart,
knows their feckless bureaucrats and
will do nothing.
He plants a seed in dollars.
Mind,
I must be frank.
I mean,
I just hate that isn't it'll chance to
send it to will act on the Indonesian.
She sees his warning come true.
This is Brad Thompson.
Pint is conceited when you defer your
motion to allow a commission to explore
the validity of your accusations
calls for the supreme chancellor to be
ousted
and is the village of no confidence and
child suffer Lauren's leadership
so that a real statesman can take charge
and cut through the bureaucratic red
tape that real estate's been just
happens to be our ambitious senator and
future Emperor Xiv.
Palpatine Aka darth sidious.
Here's where our paper boats become a
problem.
Characters without agency are well
boring.
But in this case of trying to get into
the complexity of not only how
democracy's fail,
but how well meaning people are
implicated,
paper wrote characters rob us of our
ability to reflect on what's actually
happening.
Beat for beat.
It makes sense.
Palpatine warrants or of something.
She sees his warning come true,
so she falls for the deception and even
sounds good,
but maybe because Lucas was too busy
cramming in 8,000
dumb lines for this guy,
it falls flat.
Each beat could have confronted our
character with a choice they might
deliberate over with or at least talk
about this choice.
She might argue with Palpatine,
she might confide in a friend,
she might reach out to an outside
government for help.
She might deny palpatine's bargain at
all costs and Toba toll on her citizenry
gets too high,
but in the phantom menace,
things just kind of happen because
everyone is a pawn,
not a person with agency,
and that destroys our ability as the
audience to reflect on these issues.
When we identify with the characters we
identify would their dilemma asking
ourselves,
what would I do when in the dark knight,
the joker rigs to boats with explosives
to give each one the power to obliterate
the other before they get obliterated
themselves.
Midnight,
I blow you all alone,
however,
presses the button.
I'll let that though.
We bite our nails as we debate the
merits of killing someone else to save
our own skin.
There's no such tension in the phantom
menace because pat may is just
palpatine's puppet.
And what's the deal with the other
senators?
What are their motivations?
Who knows?
We're just hold when and how they side
with palpatine.
And to make matters worse,
at no point does pad may regret the
decision that would eventually destroyed
democracy in the phantom menace or in
the later movies.
If her initial decision to remove the
supreme chancellor from power gives us
no room to empathize and think.
At least we can empathize and think
about her regret.
But no for a woman who later says this,
so this is how it appears.
He dies and their supplies,
you might at least expect her to sob
quietly in some corner because she
literally made this happen.
By contrast,
consider Jamie lannister from game of
thrones.
He was a loyal guard to the mad king.
Zapped when the mad king tried to
incinerate all of his citizens.
Jamie broke his sacred oath and murdered
the person he swore to protect.
Then the king drove my soldiers back.
Jamie is haunted by this decision as
he's derisively called Kinsler for the
rest of his life and while he probably
made the right choice,
he's also acutely aware that he is more
or less responsible for the current show
in Westeros.
He takes responsibility for the choices
he made and that allows us to identify
with him or we can even look at rogue
one where a good characters involvement
in the creation of the death star is put
front and center.
Not only does this lack of agency rob
meaning from the how democracy dies
theme in the phantom menace,
but it also makes all of Lucas's topical
and timely takes on news of the decade,
more or less meaningless.
The phantom menace came out in the late
nineties just years after governments in
Bosnia and Rwanda had committed
genocide.
So when the queen of Nobu is pleading to
an international,
I mean interplanetary government body to
intervene in the slaughter for people.
George Lucas inspiration was pretty
obvious on a narrative level.
Do we care?
Not really vague shout outs to current
events.
Don't a good political allegory make you
need choices.
Instead,
we understand it as just another step in
Palpatine's greater machinations.
When the Senate fails to do anything,
we don't understand their motivations
for doing so or their personal failings
aside from a line or two from palpatine
describing them as an effectual.
And then there's the trade federation
talk of taxes and trade in the opening
crawl was likely meant to invoke
contemporary debates about globalization
and free trade,
right on the heels of Nafta,
which was passed in 1994 and anti
globalization protests.
So what does the Trade Federation want?
Why did the Senate passed taxes on
trade?
Who The f knows?
It's also worth noting that aside from
the political themes,
characters getting pushed along the
narrative stream with no choice is
everywhere.
In the case of George,
our heat literally succeeds via
incompetence in the battle of Nobu,
his fumbling and carelessness
accidentally release whatever these are,
which destroy a bunch of enemy droids.
I think this must be what business
people mean by failing up.
And then there's Anagen who pushes a
bunch of wrong buttons,
which very him to the droid ship where
he can press a few more buttons to save
the day.
Yeah.
What if this is the real curse of the
phantom menace because it could have
been a powerful movie.
More importantly,
it could have been a powerful children's
movie and join the likes of Harry Potter
as kid fictions covering horrific
political history,
but it's not,
not even close.
Just mark it down as another example of
grandiose ambitions ending and a face
plant.
Indeed,
there are few things more painful than
missing the mark on projects you pour
your life and soul into.
I would know.
So before you dive head first into your
next endeavor,
you're going to want to make sure you're
equipped with all the skills you need to
make it a success with skill share.
The online learning community,
you can take over 20,000
classes and design business technology
and more how to be a Jedi master,
not included.
Premium memberships give you unlimited
access to high quality classes on must
know topics so you can improve your
skills,
unlock new opportunities.
And do the work that you love.
If you're looking to start your own
business like we did with wise crack,
I highly recommend skill shares,
classes on entrepreneurship,
including art of the starch,
turning ideas into high growth
businesses,
brand strategy,
building a business that lasts,
and entrepreneurship online business
planning.
One O one join the millions of students
already learning on skillshare today
with a special offer just for wisecrack
viewers.
Get two months of skillshare premium for
free by heading over to skl dot s h
slash wise crack 11 or clicking the link
in the description below.
May the force be with you and as always,
pee.