This video is brought to you by
skillshare,
the first 500 people to sign up with the
link in the description.
We'll get a two month free trial.
Yep.
Greetings and welcome to earthlink
cinema.
I'm your host Garrick's wormy Lloyd.
This week's artifact is spirited away,
the award winning masterpiece from
legendary animator and confirmed Silver
Fox.
How yells a media Xochi.
The story opens on a 10 year old human
female named Shahir row and her parental
units as they get lost in the woods,
and if a human is lost in the woods and
no one is around to hear it,
does it register as a sentient life?
Form point is these schmoes accidentally
stumbled their way into a magical land
filled with delicious food.
That's by none.
Get a million free.
The parents start stuffing it down
there,
gullets and lose their kosher status
faster than you can say,
Oh,
oh God.
To hero does what any child would do in
this situation and abandons her porky
parents to go beef up her resume.
Could you give me a job please,
please.
I just want to,
after much haranguing a wrinkly,
old cronut named you Baba hires to hero
to work in her bath house,
but changes her name to send as a show
of bad faith and so made this dreamboat
Haku warned said not to forget her real
name like he did,
or else it can cause a real headache at
the DMV.
You name a stink spirit arrives at the
bath house around mid same time.
It usually arrives for me.
Send cleans them successfully and to
thank her,
the Spirit bestows upon her the greatest
gift of all,
a little Turd and fused with IPECAC
elsewhere.
A guy named no face pays for a bunch of
food with gold,
which is the very foundation of a
transactional ecosystem,
so it doesn't really seem like much of a
problem.
Why is everyone screaming soon?
Who gets poisoned and Oh,
by the way,
he's also a dragon now sometimes saying
gives them part of that Turd to crunch
on,
which makes him bark off a shiny little
egg mcmuffin while she's at it.
She gives the rest of the term to know
face just to see how much barfing is
allowed in a pg movie.
Turns out it's a metric ass load.
Next,
send visit Zinni.
You,
Barbara,
his twin sister,
to give back the mcguffin.
Haikus stole during the breakfast rush,
an informed sen that it was her love for
her coup that broke some cursor,
another which is gross because sin is 10
and Huck,
who's gotta be at least 18 backoff
creep.
There are plenty of other fish in the
sea monster.
Later,
completely unprompted.
Send remembers a time she fell into the
[inaudible] River,
which they arbitrarily decide means that
huck who is short for Co Haku and he's a
river spirit,
so he's like a thousand and their
relationship is even more inappropriate.
Shame on you.
Japan.
You Baba gives sen last pop quiz where
she has to identify your parents,
but sen wasn't born yesterday.
I mean technically,
yes,
sin was born yesterday,
but Shahir wasn't none of these gigs or
my mom or dad and now that she's a hero,
again,
it's time to grab her rehumanized
parents and blow this popsicle store.
Spirited away is a coming of age story
and the tradition of classics like Tim
Burton's Alice in Wonderland and James
Franco's the wizard of Oz,
which similarly portray a young girl
transported to a strange place where she
asked to do a bunch of stuff at the
start of the film to hero is naive and
inexperienced with a dash of timid and
whiny,
sprinkled in for good measure.
Look to euro.
There's your new school.
It is only by solving problems and
helping those in need that you hero
gains the self reliance and empathy
needed to terrorize a giant baby.
Underneath this story of renewal and
vomiting lurks a cautionary tale of
greed and overconsumption,
particularly as it relates to post war
Japan after the shall we say messy end
of World War Two,
Japan experienced an economic boom,
no offense,
non taken that correlated with a
cultural shift toward capitalism and
away from traditional values.
The spirit realm takes the form of an
old amusement park styled after the
Meiji period of the late 19th and early
20th century,
which are two of my all time favorite
centuries discarded trines.
Adorn the hillside symbolizing the
relegation of cultural history in favor
of more modern pursuits like leisure and
interdimensional slipstreams.
In this economically driven environment,
overconsumption has dire consequences,
much like the type you might find in a
prenup to heroes,
parents snarfed down food from the
spirit realm,
despite its obviously suspicious lack of
vegetables.
Don't worry,
you've got Daddy,
he's got credit cards and cash.
In return.
They are transformed into pigs which are
commonly used on earth as a critical
symbol of capitalists,
cultures that would bring about the
eradication of humankind.
That's all folks.
The bathhouse furnace has also shaped
like a pig constantly gobbling resources
just to give guests a slightly more
temperate bubble bath.
When no face shows up overflowing with
gold,
you Baba and our workers milk that
proverbial horse for every last fluid
ounce,
but as the staff showers,
no face and access,
he can't help but shower them in stomach
acid.
The film expresses hope that modern
Japan can find a balance between
economic prosperity and spiritual
heritage.
There as much emphasis on remembering
one's name.
If you completely forget it,
you'll never find your way home and the
identity of one's parents look hard.
It's up to you to remember which ones
they are,
and even though I forget both of those
things on a daily basis,
mom,
they are important in forging a
connection to one's ancestry.
The message deepens when we consider the
context of the film prior to making
spirited away.
Director Hio Miyazaki was considering
passing the torch to the next wave of
artists at studio Ghibli,
though he reconsidered when he
remembered he was the man.
Furthermore,
at the time when many animated films
were visualized using computers,
spirited away was drawn using an
elaborate system of levers and pulleys
and it story conveys the hope that
future generations will flourish and
progress while at the same time
respecting the history of the art form,
whatever that was.
For earthlink.
Cinema,
I'm Garrick's Deloitte Arigato.
Hey,
wisecrack.
GEHRIG's is intern.
Jared,
again,
like many youtubers,
we often get asked what sort of
applications we use to make our videos
and how we learn to use them and why is
crack.
A lot of us are self taught and these
days you can learn just about anything
online.
If you've ever wanted to start a project
or learn a new skill but weren't sure
where to begin,
skillshare can help you get started and
sign up now and be one of the first 500
people to click the link in the
description and you'll receive a free
two month trial to skillshare and all of
its resources.
Skill shares an online learning
community with over 16,000
professional and easy to understand
classes in design,
photography,
business,
and more.
Whether you're already a creator or
you're hoping to become one,
you'll find a community of likeminded
people with steps and advice on how to
take your ideas to the next level.
You can take classes on everything from
html to knitting to how to shoot a short
documentary,
and if you've got a skill you'd like to
share with the community,
you can always teach a class yourself.
A premium membership starts at $10 a
month and gets you unlimited access to
the full range of courses and the first
500 people to click the link in the
description will receive a free two
month trial to skillshare and all of its
resources.
So head over to ski,
l dot s h slash earthling to begin your
two month free trial and get learning.
You can download their mobile app and
take classes wherever you are.
We can't wait to see what you create,
so don't forget to subscribe and ring
that bell so you won't miss what we
create.
Thanks for watching guys.
Catch y'all next time.
Peace.