This video is brought to you by
skillshare.
Hey,
wise,
crack,
jared here.
One of the most Cathartic things about
art for me is that it can give voice to
our frustrations with the world,
but while mocking,
this system is as old as art itself in
the 20th century of version of this
story became popular in which characters
not only criticize the system but
actively escape it.
I can cut it down,
but recently something a bit different
has become popular,
like hero rises up to defeat,
a degrading and exploitative system who
we know is fake bikes,
but in no time at all,
something happens.
The system manages to win in Black
Mirror,
at least our heroes rebellion against a
system of compulsory exercise that is
only redeemable for worthless forms of
entertainment and digital swag gets sold
as a worthless form of entertainment and
digital swag.
Is this the perfect metaphor for the
world we live in?
Where anticapitalists insurrection one
day get sold in mass by a large
corporation.
The next or how are we all just become
nihilists?
Join me live from the system itself as
we dive into classics like network or
Matrix,
fight club,
sorry to Bob,
you and a few others to ask the
question,
is resistance even possible?
Oh,
also rick and Morty,
because who can resist and yeah,
heavy spoilers ahead,
but first,
how did we get here in the US during the
19 thirties factories dominated economic
life and while those were the days where
many people could raise a family by
tightening rivets or something,
artists like Charlie Chaplin,
we're showing the bleaker side of this
in his film,
modern times chaplain expressed
anxieties about losing oneself to
factory life.
Chaplains spends the film struggling to
stand out,
express himself,
or make anything meaningful of his life.
The film really captures one central
complaint about fordist capitalism.
Work was repetitive,
meaningless,
and empty.
You spend time on some assembly line or
doing paperwork for your boss,
and there was no individuality,
creativity,
or authenticity involved at all.
At the end of the film,
he resists the monotony of his life by
walking off into the sunset to find his
brighter,
more authentic future.
This fixation on the dehumanization of
factory work and the escape,
the something authentic evolved as our
economy did.
If it wasn't repetitive factory work,
it was repetitive,
pointless office work like in fight
club,
the narrator rails against the
emasculating,
alienating nature of consumerism.
This is your life and it's ending one
minimum of time before Rowdy Tyler
durden sets up a gladiator pit for men
to express their authentic masculinity
and occasionally engage in domestic
terrorism or office space which bemoans
the drudgery of office work,
tps reports and that God be printer or
whatever the hell is going on in Brazil.
In the book,
the new spirit of capitalism,
Lucasville tanned skin.
Each sapelo call this modern time slash
fight clubs slash office space style,
criticism of capitalism.
The artistic critique.
It focuses on the loss of autonomy and
creativity as opposed to critiques that
focus on things like poverty or wages.
But what if all this complaining is just
making the system they rail against all
the more resilient,
like our protagonists from black mirror
or our second favorite,
rick,
and what if this isn't just something
limited to fiction,
but the very real workplace?
Well,
we can answer that question with
something that's more interesting than
it sounds.
I promise.
Management theory.
Boltanski Sapelo observed a specific
shift in management literature of the
sixties and Seventies.
They were all complaining about workers,
bad attitudes and lack of motivation.
What they found is that your modern time
style artistic critique was actually
affecting economic output workers
completely unstimulated by the lack of
autonomy or creativity or slacking off
or worse,
not even bothering to show up.
Furthermore,
in France,
at least all the talented college grads,
we're no longer interested in goal
middle management positions.
Boltanski Sapelo named their book after
one by sociologist Max Faber.
Faber asks,
how do you get people to buy into a new
economic system?
Well,
if your religion thinks that you need to
work hard until you die,
otherwise you'll go to hell.
Then it's a pretty great partner for
emerging capitalism,
especially if you got to do this all
day.
The spirit of capitalism is what engages
people with capitalism in the sixties
and seventies.
That old spirit was failing.
People wanted less fire and brimstone or
even good union jobs and more free love
and drugs,
so Boltanski and Sapelo ask what's the
new spirit?
The new spirit of our modern era engages
people on the grounds of things like
autonomy,
creativity,
and freedom,
but it's still the same system.
The people are still biking all day,
living meaningless lives,
but at least they have been show to
express their frustration for them.
Likewise,
you still have to work 12 hour shifts at
subway,
but at least you're now considered a
sandwich artist,
but going beyond this,
what can we make of resistance in the
new spirit of capitalism?
Do we culturally need a critique of the
artistic critique?
Let's go to one of my favorites network.
It's like 15 million merits.
The movie after learning,
he's about to be fired.
News anchor,
Howard beale announces his on air
suicide.
I'm going to blow my brains out right on
this program a week from today,
which he cynically remarked will make
his dwindling ratings go through the
roof,
going to get a hell of a writing out of
that.
Then in a pseudo apology,
he says,
he just ran out of bolts and rants about
the horrid state of the world.
Hi,
I'm mad as hell.
I'm not going to take this anymore.
His public meltdowns become so popular.
He's reinstated bringing unprecedented
ratings and therefore money to an
otherwise small network.
The network also creates the mouse a
tongue.
Our were a bonafide member of the
Communist Party preaches revolution.
I'm lorraine,
so bad ass Cami
culminating in one of my favorite lines
in cinema.
I mean,
that's why it's not going to see a Nigga
goddamn show until we go and its
indication.
The producers of network rightly
perceive that the capitalist model is no
longer about conformity.
Allow modern times,
but about rebellion and disillusionment.
Those are the things that sell.
They turned off,
shot up,
and they themselves limp and nothing
helps.
The American people want somebody to
articulate their rage for them.
Verbal Tansky and Chappelle existential
rebellion,
Marxist critique and revolutionary ideas
have basically become the official style
of contemporary capitalism,
and you thought I meant that
figuratively.
Perhaps nothing encapsulates this better
than the rick and morty episode,
the Rick Way to mix up for a bunch of
bricks,
toil away in a dehumanizing factory only
for an act of rebellion to be repackaged
into wafers.
They give you the taste of the unique
flavor of shattering the grand illusion.
We might consider media like network 15
million merits and simple.
Rick's as the critique of the artistic
critique.
Why bother railing against the
alienating nature of the system and it's
just gonna help someone else's bottom
line.
Sometimes it's not just cooptation.
Some media imagines a world where the
alternative to the system is just as bad
as the system itself.
In Fight Club,
for instance,
men who complained about the degradation
they face in their daily lives.
My two grown kids wouldn't even return.
My phone calls eventually go on to join
an organization where they have no names
in project may have.
We have no names are called maggots,
maggots and routinely run the risk of
getting their balls cut off.
These guys are going to take your boss.
Why did the men in fight club go from
being in masculine and under capitalism
to being literally emasculated by their
new dictator?
If anyone ever interferes with project,
may even you got to get us balls because
sometimes even our ideas for resistance
come from the system itself.
Other times,
the resistance is literally created by
the system to ensure its survival.
Consider everyone's favorite trench
coat.
Jesus neo the first matrix makes it seem
like neo is a classical savior.
Come to liberate the humans from their
enslavement to the machines and awakened
them from their illusions,
but we eventually learn in one of the
most pedantic monologues of all time.
That neo is just a product of the very
system he wants to undo morpheus desire
on even the prophecy are just part of
the way the system tries to tame the
human capacity for free will and use it
against them
and we have become exceedingly
efficient.
So
freewill doesn't help folks find ways
out of the system.
The system accounts for freewill and
channels that to the machines benefit,
so pretty bleak,
right?
We can't escape the system.
Some resistance actually comes right
from the system and the Matrix sequels
still shutting.
We be crying in a corner and not
consuming more media about
disillusionment.
If we fetishize durden's face on t
shirts,
haven't we missed the point entirely?
Things you'll end up owning.
Well,
there are some movies that move to
address this problem in snowpiercer.
Survivors of Earth's new ice age,
live on a train organized along class
lines,
the richest in the front,
the poorest in the back,
the poor stager,
rebellion,
and reach the front only to discover
that the revolt was orchestrated by the
trains leader to thin the population and
ensure sustainability.
At first,
it seems not unlike our previous
examples,
but the rebels decide that they would
rather crash the train and start all
over.
Ben Settle for these simple taste of
shattering the grand illusion.
Does this mean that the only way to
escape the system is to burn the world
down?
Well,
not necessarily in the recent comedy.
Sorry to bother you.
We see a third option in this film star
Telemarketer,
Cassius Green inhabits a darkly familiar
world where not even leaked footage of
human slash horse hybrid slaves can
prompt revolution,
but instead earns a fist bump from the
stock market and praise from scientists
and investors get it.
Capitalism is literally dehumanizing
folks by turning them into equine
people,
and that's still not enough for a wakeup
call.
In some ways,
maybe this holds a mirror to us.
We respond any better when we hear about
Amazon workers pissing and bottles.
Not always.
The film ends with a successful union
strike that makes our protagonist life
markedly better.
Even though the film is a very skeptical
about escaping the system entirely,
it seems to place a lot of hope in these
slow struggle to incrementally improve
it.
So what do you guys think wise crack.
Should we crash the train?
Is there room for slow change or do
simple rig wafers tastes too good to
risk it worth it,
and for prime examples of not being able
to escape the system,
consider this whether you want to break
out of the routine of a nine to five job
or whether you just want to expand the
boundaries of your abilities.
Skillshare can help you get to the next
level.
Skillshare is an online learning
community with over 20,000
classes and design business technology
and more.
Skillshare has tons of classes that can
help you up your professional game.
You can take classes like going
freelance building and branding your own
success to make quitting the day job
worth it,
or from blog to business to take that
side Gig and turn it into your main one.
Nothing beats being your own boss.
Skillshare premium membership gives you
unlimited access to over 20,000
classics.
Join the millions of students already
learning on skillshare with a special
offer just for wisecrack fans.
The first 500 wise crack fans to sign up
will get two months of skillshare free
to sign up.
Visit the link in the description or
head to sk l dot ssh slash wise,
crack 14 and get unlimited access to
over 20,000
classes today.
And as always,
thank you for watching guys.
Piece.