This video is sponsored by the team
behind marvel puzzle quest.
Stick around at the end of the video to
learn more about the game.
Hey wisecrack,
jared here would be imminent release of
the avengers infinity war.
We thought we'd go back and take a look
at the civil war.
Nope,
not that one.
This one
now
on its face,
civil war is a two hour spectacle of
biceps chases,
mandatory character introductions to
feed the mcu and man,
you know,
he lifts,
but in addition to some good old
fashioned fisticuffs civil war also
explores the idea of global fisticuffs
or international relations as you may
know it.
Which brings us to the question,
what do superpowers like the United
States have to learn from Tony Stark or
Steve Rogers?
Welcome to this wisecrack condition on
the philosophy of Captain America civil
war.
Don't forget to subscribe if you haven't
already and has always spoilers ahead.
While the civil war comics Uris deals
with issues like privacy and domestic
policing in the wake of the Patriot Act,
the film makes an ambitious break with
its source material.
Instead,
it focuses on a conflict between two
approaches to international relations,
civil war frames.
The conflict between Captain America and
iron man is a battle between two
opposing views on the avengers role in
the world.
Specifically,
the film asks,
should a US based high powered and
potentially destructive team like the
avengers be allowed to operate
internationally independent of
government oversight?
It's a poignant question to ask,
especially in the wake of America's own
questioning of its interventionism
abroad in civil war.
This question comes to a head in the
debate over the Sokovia accords.
The accords claim the avengers have no
right to cross national borders and
fight.
They're highly destructive battles
without the approval of all governments
concerned.
Their argument is grounded in the notion
of Westphalian sovereignty.
The idea that a nation state is an ought
to be in charge of all affairs within
its borders.
This modern notion of sovereignty only
came to exist in 1648 after the major
European powers were tired of fighting
either the 30 years' war or eight years
war,
which unlike the liar,
seven years' war actually lasted for as
long as advertise the resulting peace of
Westphalia created the idea of
sovereignty that we understand today,
but in our highly globalized modern
world,
things are a little more complicated
than when people were still charging
into battle on horseback.
Many contemporary political commentators
are all about the idea of a post
Westphalian world order.
They argued that globalization has
broken down traditional ideas of who
holds power were under this system.
Independent actors such as private
corporations and terrorist cells are
able to wield as much or sometimes more
power than the nation states whose
borders they cross at will.
In the film,
the avengers are portrayed as a product
of this post Westphalian world.
There are a group of US based
superhumans who go wherever they want,
whenever they want,
without the permission of local
governments.
The film even emphasizes this modern
notion of the avengers in its opening
where our heroes tried to catch a former
hydra agent while using the language of
a police operation complete with drones
and calls for backup
Sam.
We need fire and rescue and the south
side of the building.
However,
they function less like a traditional
police force and more like a private
security company.
If like main villain,
Zemo your family happens to be the one
that gets blown up in their latest
attempt at saving the world,
you might even consider them terrorists.
What would you call a group of us based
enhanced individuals who routinely
ignore sovereign borders and inflict
their will wherever they choose and who
frankly seemed unconcerned about what
they leave behind.
The sokovia accords then are the
Westphalian world dealing with post
Westphalian realities.
The debate over the accords is grounded
in two competing views of how the
international arena works.
Realism and liberalism realism argue
that states are self interested.
Power seeking rational actors who seek
to maximize their security and chances
of survival.
Liberalism,
stresses,
interdependence among states,
multinational corporations and
international institutions arguing that
these various actors can and should work
together for the benefit of all the
Sokovia accords fit this liberalist
paradigm to a tea under the new rule set
out in the accords.
Government actors I.
E.
The UN will work together with
nongovernmental forces.
In this case,
the avengers for the presumed common
good.
This means more rules and greater
oversight for the avengers who will no
longer be able to gallivant around the
globe fighting whenever and wherever
they please compromise
reassurance.
That's how the world works.
Tony Stark buys into the accords
liberalist framework but still manages
to do plenty of Gallo vantage.
He seriously thinking,
listen to you after this fiasco and
Leipzig,
you are used that cooperation with
sovereign governments even to the point
of accepting the imposed limitations is
crucial for stark respect for the
interdependent world order is part of
what separates the avengers from the
terrorist groups.
They fight.
We need to be put in check whatever form
that takes.
I'm game.
If we can't accept limitations were
boundaryless.
We're no better than the bad guys.
Steve Rogers,
on the other hand,
is a realist.
He's focused on security and his own
agenda first and foremost,
and argues against the Sokovia cords on
the grounds that they will make the
avengers less able to respond to
critical situations,
thereby putting the world in danger.
If we call Tony,
hi,
you won't believe even if he did,
who knows if the accords or let them
know we're on our own.
While the real,
his position allows for cooperation that
will increase the likelihood of the
world survival.
Captain America is simply unconvinced
that this cooperation will improve
security for anyone.
Steve argues that the shifting agendas
of those who uphold the accords could
lead to compromise security down the
line.
This is the United Nations we're talking
about.
It's not the World Security Council.
It's not shield.
It's not hydro,
but it's run by people with agendas and
agendas
change.
The film asked some pretty heavy
questions that may as well be directed
at a modern superpower.
Is unfettered power inherently
dangerous?
Do rules only tie up crucial fighting
forces in dangerous amounts of red tape?
Instead of providing some black and
white answer for an insanely complex
question,
the film offers us some ambiguity.
While one may criticize captain America
for his unilateral approach to solving
things,
stop telling you anything else that
you'll wrong.
You think you're right,
it makes you dangerous.
You could equally say the same of Tony
Stark as he tries to enforce the Sokovia
accords leading to plenty of collateral
damage along the way while exploring
these international frameworks.
The film also explores how personal
ethics can complicate these concepts.
When a terrorist blows up the UN killing
black panthers father,
he goes on the hunt for presumed culprit
bucky barnes.
The attack on the UN creates a riff
between those vendors who want the
government to take in bucky and those
who believed.
Captain America's right to attempt his
own rescue.
Where this conflict,
the film asks us to consider whether
it's better to act based on a
preconceived set of moral obligations
like the captain's obligation to Bucky
or with consideration for the greater
good like stark and his compatriots,
Tony Stark in his gang and body branch
of philosophy known as Utilitarianism,
which holds that actions should be
judged based on their overall
consequences rather than on their
adherence to abstract ideals.
Tony Stark believes that oversight will
reduce the amount of collateral damage
caused by their activities and that this
is reason enough to support the Sokovia
courts above and beyond his belief in
the usefulness of a liberalist world
order.
Tony Stark's supports the accords
because they align with his own
utilitarian conception of morality.
These two ideas are different though not
necessarily contradictory.
While he knows that the new rules will
inconvenience him and his team,
he's convinced that they will improve
the lot of humanity as a whole.
It's not about his personal convictions,
it's about the greater good.
Captain Rogers,
I know you believe what you're doing is
right,
but for the collective good,
you must surrender.
Now,
Captain America,
on the other hand,
flirts with an ethical position known as
deontology.
Deontology judges the morality of an
action itself without consideration for
the affects that said action might have,
again,
not contradictory to his real as
beliefs,
but different nonetheless from a
deontological perspective,
certain actions can never be justified.
No matter how much they might promote
some greater good like killing an
innocent person,
even if it could save millions more.
While Steve Rogers isn't they perfect
deontologist in the sense of Oh gee
deontologist Emmanuelle con,
he acts according to personal laws
rather than universal ones.
He bases his actions around a set of
moral duties.
CAPP believes that his moral duty to
save his friend Bucky Barnes trumps
whatever greater good might be served by
his death or imprisonment.
No matter how many cops bucky happens to
beat the piss out of it in the films
closing minutes,
we learned that all the carnage,
betrayal and heartbreak we've followed
for the last two hours is the secret
plan of former Sokovia in special
operatives,
Zemo whose loved ones were more
collateral damage of the avengers,
Zemo or feels that it was his plan all
along to tear the vendor's apart.
Showing Tony Stark footage of bucky
barnes murdering his parents.
[inaudible] bites enemies can rise
again.
The line was crumbles from within.
That's that
forever and here I think the film
suggests a failing all these
philosophical systems,
no matter how right participants in
these systems believe they are,
there will always be somebody who gets
the shaft.
Tony Stark is confronted by the mother
of one of the many eggs he had to crack
in order to make a superhero omelet.
Who's going to avenge my son's stark?
He's dead and I blame you.
She is essentially in the same camp as
Zemo.
Whether you're operating for the greater
good,
your personal ethics at the behest of
your own country or an international
agreement.
There's always a Zemo that loses out.
And that's the problem with the force.
As powerful as the avengers,
as division says,
I'll very strength invites challenged.
Challenge,
insights,
conflict.
Yeah.
Conflict
breeds catastrophe.
Someone is always going to get shafted
by these philosophical systems,
but when the team doing the shafting has
the collective force of a nuclear
superpower,
the forces that challenged them,
we'll invite equally destructive force
and that can turn out pretty poorly for
the world.
So what do you think are the avengers
right to agree to the accords?
Should captain America give up his own
code for the greater good or are there
just no right answers?
Let us know what you think in the
comments.
And thanks for watching peace.
Want to make like Steven Tony and lead
your own team of marvel characters into
battle.
Download Marvel puzzle quest today for
free to live out your comic book
fantasies.
Marvel puzzle quest is a match three
puzzle RPG featuring characters from
across the marvel universe.
Create your own Dream Team of heroes and
villains to take pardon,
awesome single player action as well as
weekly tournaments and events all
written by bonafide marvel writers.
You can even form alliances with your
friends to rank up in the leader boards
and earn cool rewards.
The Games available now on your mobile
device and steam Oh and marvel puzzle
quest is getting updated constantly with
new characters.
This month they're adding craven,
the hunter and Ghostwriter,
specifically Robbie Reyes,
his ghostwriter,
who you might remember from agents of
shield and word on the street is that
they're putting together some exciting
stuff for the upcoming release,
the Black Panther movie,
so stay tuned for that.
To top it all off,
the team behind marvel puzzle quest is
offering wisecrack fans a free character
to add to your team,
just go to [inaudible] dot com slash
wise crack or click the link in the
description to add Sam Wilson,
you know,
Falcon to your team for free.
Thanks to marvel puzzle quest for
sponsoring this video.
Be sure to subscribe and ring that bell
so you won't miss all the great stuff
we've got coming.
That's all for now.
Thanks for watching y'all.
Peace.