I think we're in a kind of period of,
uh,
late modernism,
renewed modernism in which,
uh,
the modern style,
which was mistakenly given up for dead
in the 80s with postmodernism,
uh,
has kind of come back reinventing itself
much more urbane correcting some of the
mistakes of modernism first time around
when it was so anti urban,
uh,
and with much more either restraint in
some cases and clarity and almost
sometimes minimalism and,
and,
or a kind of more expressionistic strain
so that we see different strains.
And I do not think that this is a time
that can be summarized in any single ism
anyway.
Uh,
there's too many different things going
on,
but,
uh,
probably the one that is kind of the
most,
uh,
unifying or compelling of the time to
the extent that anything can pull a
diverse time together would be this sort
of late,
modernist moment that we're in where
really good architects are reinventing
the modernist vocabulary
where we're at right now.
It's,
it's hard to ever encapsulate that with
a single building.
I mean,
there was a time,
you know,
it doesn't years ago when frank,
Gary's Guggenheim museum in Bilbao seem
to sort of sum up everything.
And it did and it,
it,
it was really the,
the symbolic beginning of a whole age of
architecture and they age of intense
engagement with architecture and with
doing buildings in some cases were
really quite wonderful and brilliant
and,
uh,
profound even,
other cases,
buildings that would just sort of
excessive.
Right now we've kind of pulled back from
that a lot,
but we're not entirely sure where we're
going.
Uh,
there's a tremendous interest in
sustainability today and in
environmentalism and buildings being
responsible from a green standpoint,
uh,
which is all to the good,
there's a greater sense,
I think,
of the building as part of a larger,
whole and less as an individual
standalone monument.
So we're more concerned with urbanism,
how buildings relate to each other on
the street and as part of a community,
we're more concerned,
I think with planning,
I'd like to hope.
And so,
uh,
we're not believing that you can keep
growing and spreading out forever and
ever across the landscape that,
that,
uh,
we've got to make our cities denser and
tighter in part to preserve the land.
Uh,
I sense a lot of that right now.
Much more willingness to begin to
consider alternate forms of housing as
reflections of alternate forms of living
and alternative family structures and
things like that.
You know,
uh,
for a long time we've just assumed that
everybody would fit into the same little
pigeonholed box,
either a little suburban house or an
apartment in the city or whatever that
was designed for a very traditional
nuclear family.
In fact,
family structures are different now and
they're changing and they're more
options.
And so why aren't there more housing
options at the same time to reflect
that?
You hear more people at least talking
about that now.
And I think if we were not in this
difficult recession where it's tough to
build anything,
we'd actually see more real stuff
happening right now.
But with luck,
we can use this time to plan,
to sort of develop ideas and be ready to
do more interesting stuff when the time
comes.
Hopefully pretty soon.