Hi there,
I'm Jason Guts and you're listening to
think again,
a big thing podcast.
Since 2008 big thing has been bringing
you big ideas in small concentrated
doses from some of the most creative
thinkers and doers around on.
Think again,
we take ourselves out of our comfort
zone,
surprising my guests and me,
your host with unexpected conversation
starters from our interview archives,
ideas that we didn't necessarily come
here prepared to discuss.
I'm very,
very happy to be here today with William
Shatner,
the William Shatner.
He created the role of Captain James,
t dot kirk on the original star Trek and
won two Emmy's and the Golden Globe for
his portrayal of denny crane on the
practice in Boston legal.
He's also written nearly 30 bestselling
books of fiction and nonfiction and
released to awesome albums of music with
the artists,
ben folds and others,
including Henry Rollins,
who's been on this show and his newest
book,
zero g coauthored with Jeff Rovin is a
science fiction terrorism thriller set
in the Year Twenty 50.
It begins with an unnaturally powerful
tsunami that destroys most of the coast
of Japan and follows FBI field agent
Samuel Lord,
as he attempts to unravel the mystery.
Welcome to think again,
William.
That was a long introduction,
but very,
very well done.
Thank you very much.
I want to talk about your book,
but before we do that,
as I am a longtime Shakespeare Fan,
and I know you started out in
Shakespeare,
I wanted to come out of left field and
ask you whether you have a favorite
character,
play,
speech,
etc. Of shakespeare,
any,
any favorite thing of shakespeare.
I wOndered if we could Start there.
Favorite shakespeare character,
character play speech moment.
Anything?
Yes.
I have to point at a henry,
the fifth in which I understudied.
Christopher plummer,
who was playing henry fifth at stratford
many,
many years ago,
and in repertory is especially this
repertory.
At stratford you open a play and then
the next morning after you've opened,
you start rehearsals on new play and
then you do that for four weeks and then
open that and maybe a third and a fourth
so that the understudy rehearsals would
be delayed until you finished opening
new plays.
And about the third or fourth day I waS
asked to go on stage as they understood
it because chris was ill for a moment
and they asked me to go on and I had
never,
not only had,
I never rehearsed it,
I'd never said the words out loud,
but I had been drilling myself for some
reason and I speculate about this and my
one man show.
Why did I drill those words so,
so emphatically?
Because nobody ever goes on for an under
say no.
I've never been in an understudy.
A relationship where somebody went on
for me or I went on for somebody else
except in this one instance in which I
had never spoken the words out loud.
And then I went on stage in front of
2,500 people in and critics and all
that.
And uh,
so how did it feel?
Was it terrifying?
How did it
no know I was on a wave.
I,
I don't recall being terrified.
I recall I've looked at pictures of
laird hamilton coming down to a way that
a 70 foot wave and I've got to think
that he had the same feeling.
And so I did this,
this thing pursuing you and your writing
and you can't lose your confidence
because the moment you doubt your,
it's over.
So it.
So that's how,
that's how it is For you.
You feel that you must,
you must keep self doubt completely at
bay because I've often thought that,
uh,
you know,
for me anyway,
you can feel the self doubt and then
say,
oh,
well,
you know,
there that is and still do your thing,
and just having a
that's good.
If you can say,
oh well there'S no doubt there's fear
and there is a dread and there,
oh look at that.
There's hysteria coming monday.
And then,
you know,
somehow deal with it and press on.
For me in life,
denial is perfect.
Denied.
Denied the experience.
Denial.
Oh,
that hasn't happened.
Is not going to happen,
I don't even want to think about it and
I'll die before.
Uh,
I experienced that and eventually it all
goes away anyway,
so I'm half jewish and so for all the
semi or fully.
But go ahead,
jason,
you should be in denial about that.
Well,
I was going say that woody allen gave us
all permission to sort of recognize the
terror and the anxiety and simply to
move forward and turn it into something
I don't know if not sexy,
at least acceptable in his case.
Turn it into a career.
Yeah.
So you've had an amazingly varied
career.
You're your best known to the general
public probably for the star trek films,
but you've been doing a million things
and,
and you've been writing for years and
years now.
How did writing enter the picture for
you were,
you know,
at what point did you decide to start
taking writing seriously,
if that's the right way to put it?
Well,
uh,
I,
the written word is where everything
begins and ends.
I've always known that.
So I've always written in one manner or
another.
I love poetry.
I love the usage of words,
uh,
in fact,
when I was just starting out,
I wrote some television,
half our players,
which the canadian broadcasting
corporation,
the cbc in Canada,
which was the equivalent of say nbc here
bought and I cast one of those shows a
girl and eventually married her.
She becAme the mother of my children,
so I've been writing a long time,
but the breath more measured and works
started when there was a strike by some
unions while I was making a film.
And there was nothing I could do.
I had to sit around and wait for the
strike to be over.
So I started writing.
I gave myself the premise of a policeman
in space.
I had done a police series.
So,
uh,
I began at 10 books and uh,
it became 10 books a year,
a year series and a movie.
So I noticed,
I saw,
you know,
looking through your work.
And by the way,
I really love those,
those albums that you did with ben folds
there.
They're really cool.
That album was called,
has been.
It was.
I really look at that.
Wonderful.
And um,
I,
I'm just noticing that in both the
writing and in the music,
you're collaborating and you seem to
enjoy collaborating.
I mean acting is the collaborative art
as well.
Do you find that you prefer to create
with other people as opposed to a in
solitude?
So science fiction is,
it's a strange form Your imagining a
plot and people,
but it's also littered with scientific
possibilities.
EIther imaginative possibilities are
possibilities that exist in the
laboratory that may come into existence
years from now and you have to be
acquainted with all that.
And it's a very esoteric
acquaintanceship to know science
intimately to be able to write about it.
No science individually.
Jeff rovin is tHis wonderful writer who
has that knowledge.
So doing the two of us,
me working on the more emotional aspects
and the plot and him working on the
scientific aspects.
We've created a lovely novel filled with
scientific possibilities.
Both that takes the plot along or that
are added like little diamonds that that
you'll read and may even smile at the
new political unions that couldn't
possibly be right in our year,
but 50 years might very well come to be.
That sort of thing is great fun.
What are so in the new buck in zero g?
I mean I think I gave enough of an
overview of the plot.
I don't want to give too much away.
It's definitely a fun and interesting
thriller set.
In 2025,
what are some of your favorite moments
or ideas in the book?
Anything you'd want to kind of highlight
for people who haven't read it?
Well,
we have a character there.
We took from the present day publiCity
about people who feel they've been born
in the wrong body,
so we named that character ed zilla and
adzilla instead of going for an
operation,
a changing his or her sex is able to do
it by.
We'll that's totally an imaginative
concept taken from the ongoing
controversies that are in our day and
age,
but someday in the future there'll be a
medical implant whereby by an act of
will you can change your sex.
Yeah,
I found that really fascinating.
First of all,
adzilla his parents,
uh,
I guess genetically altered her either
at birth or pre-birth.
Um,
and so that raises some interesting
ethical issues.
You know,
like about w w we are going to come to a
point no doubt in the near future when
parents actually may have some stuff
control,
I think with enough instrumentation that
could look into that aspect of,
uh,
of an unborn baby.
So since we're on the verge and in fact
did not on the verge,
we're genetically altering,
but we're on the verge of genetically
altering almost anything easily.
Why wouldn't it be possible to go inside
even just a concept and alter the
genetic structure of the unborn child?
It is happening when they see diseases
that are abnormal or why couldn't you do
almost anything?
Well,
let me ask you this,
were,
you know,
if you were in a position to sort of
start all over and have kids and you had
sort of unlimited genetic alteration
power,
what would you take advantage of it?
Or what would the limitS be for you
personally?
Well,
you see what you're addressing.
there is a real moral problem.
How much do you altered genetically?
That goes for food as well.
By the way,
gmos are apparently healthy.
They're allowing us to feed 7 billion
people that shouldn't be on earth in the
first place by being able to feed seven
and maybe 10 to 11 billion people in the
very near future.
We like lemmings have destroyed our
environment and we're only going to
destroy it further.
So we've genetically altered crops to
avoid disease.
So the limitation is not only on what
food is,
but how many people we can procreate and
chinese tried to do it by limiting it to
one person,
but that didn't work because now their
culture,
uh,
didn't want girls.
They wanted boys and saw a whole human
aspect to something that was going to be
really good.
A scientific breakthrough that offered
to humanity the hope of feeding
everybody and having no,
no starvation morphs into more people
and more pollution and a the end of the
world,
the end of the world is nigh because of
the number of people on earth.
And how do you reduce the number of
people on earth without getting into
mass murder,
are altering the baby in vitro did not
being able to have any children.
I mean the morality that that this
brings up is the springboard for so many
science fiction novels and that's what
we're.
That's what I'm.
I'm
indeed.
Well,
and you're in zero g there is that we
used to science station on the moon.
There are,
you know,
fairly complex space station.
So I mean that,
you know,
at least elon musk with his,
space x,
mars,
mission,
mission seems to think that that may be
one viable solution as well.
There was no way that human beings can
colonize anyplace else other than than
earth because the time it takes to reach
an earth like planet that has the
proximity to its star and many of the
values here,
which includes this thin skin of
atmosphere and the temperature range on
the oxygen,
the oxygen proportion came about by
evolution.
When chlorophyl stArted,
I mean you go back,
one thing bringS on another so that by
evolving here on earth,
we human beings have arrived at our
reptilian brain and our complex forehead
that evolved over millions of years.
How the heck you can't live underground
on mars,
even if you could,
you can't.
That's we,
we belong in sunlight.
And that sunlight is thousands of years
in the future.
Even if you could go at a rocketship
near the speed of light,
which you can,
it's going to take thousands of years.
We have forgotten.
We've got things on the books,
laws on the books,
uh,
understandings with other nations on the
books 50 years ago that we've forgotten
what they were and why you mill.
Oh,
that's right.
We made a,
an agreement 50 years ago.
We forgotten in 50 years what that
agreement was or what we were supposed
to do,
or imagine going a thousand years on a,
on a voyage and somebody's saying 500
years from now,
why are we here?
What are we,
where are we going on cheese?
I forgotten what the,
let's look back in the library and
dusting off 500 years old.
That's right.
We're on our way to send us a what,
why,
why are we going there?
Maybe let's turn around.
Maybe if they can figure out where I'm
hold travel and get us to some
exoplanets in,
you know,
10 minutes,
then we'll be in that situation.
But.
Exactly.
And,
and that's theoretically possible as
well.
Maybe.
Yeah.
I mean stephen hawking seems to think
so.
But uh,
Okay.
I think that brings us to the second
part of the show where we watch these
short surprise interview clips.
I don't know what they are.
I've not seen them.
So I want to,
you know,
we're going to have a genuinely
spontaneous conversation.
The first one,
which is by ryan holiday,
who's an entrepreneur and author
so but with magician were thought
provoking.
Is that what the idea is?
Ideally it is thought provoking and if
it's not then it's my job to provoke.
We'll make it fun.
Yeah,
exactly.
okay,
so we'll both watch and then afterward
we'll talk.
There's
a wonderful bill walsh quote about ego.
He says,
no ego is when self confidence becomes
arrogance.
Self assertiveness becomes reckless
abandon and so forth.
You say,
he's saying it's,
it's sort of past the point of any
reasonable utility,
right?
Confidence is great.
Arrogance is not great,
or cyril connolly's and ego like cancer
is sort of an over assertion of cells
and that sort of.
what I see ego is it's,
it's great to believe in yourself.
The problem is when your belief in
yourself is not based on anything real,
and so that's the enemy of,
of trying to do basically anything that
requires interacting with other people.
Right?
If you're a creative and you're not able
to take feedback because your ego is
either so strong or you're not able to
take feedback because you don't care
what anyone thinks,
your work's not going to get any better.
If you don't care about your audience,
you don't understand who they are and
what's going on in their life because
you lack empathy,
which is another symptom of ego.
Your work is going to suffer.
You can't work with other people because
you're.
You have to be.
You're selfish.
You have to be the center of attention
of all times.
You're not going to have a team around
you,
so it basically makes anything that
we're trying to do harder than it
already is.
Mm.
I guess I wanted to.
I wanted to get at,
you know,
the old phrase,
fake it till you make it right,
and I don't know whether that advice
rings true to you,
but the idea that at a certain point in
your career,
like when you're starting out and you're
doing a bunch of new things and you're
stretching yourself outside of your
comfort zone,
as you kind of said earlier,
you have to be sort of in denial,
push down any doubt and just kind of in
a way bluster forward perhaps.
But he's,
he's saying that that's kind of a
dangerous state of affairs.
I mean the,
uh,
if I'm,
if I'm reading that right.
Well,
let me first of all,
correct.
What's not correct but to what I said
about denial.
I was half joking about denial,
but indeed as a performer and I was
talking specifically about being on
stage and stage fright and all those,
the unknowns or a,
uh,
I'm a pilot for example.
And I remember when I soloed in a cessna
and I was making a turn by myself for
the first time,
the shadow of the windshield crossed my
face.
And I looked up with a great start
thinking something was coming at me with
just the shadow of the windshield.
I was so afraid of what I was doing.
I was up at the year 1500 feet.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Now if you panic,
god knows what'll happen.
So you need like a test pilot to control
that panic and like an athlete and a big
game,
use it so that you.
You extend your,
your faculties to,
to their limit,
right?
Some people can do it by combining the
use of those nerves.
Some people say,
I'm not going to even face those nerves.
I'm going to focus on what it is I have
to do and suppress anything else.
Both work I think.
But if you talk about ego,
then what this gentleman is describing,
ego and and trying to do something
somebody else has never done or that
you've never done.
He starts off with ego and the need for
the self confidence and the feeling that
I can do it.
But then he paints a picture of somebody
who was so egotistical that he doesn't
listen to anybody else like at a you.
Hey,
watch your ego because you're about to
step off the precedent.
So you might say,
oh,
well,
that's where the precipice is.
You can still be filled with ego.
I've got the,
I've got the kite in my hands and I'm
going to step off the precipice there.
Just point me to where the precipice is
if you don't mind,
and I've got the ego that I will sell
this kite in space,
uh,
but just to help me with the help they
get to the precipice.
You can have the ego and overwhelming
over weaning ego.
what,
what kind of a mind would get in a
spaceship and go to mars for the first
time?
Who would do that?
Except somebody who thought,
I don't care if I live or die,
I'm going to make this adventure.
The reAlity of the columbus sailing a
ship over the edge of the earth.
The reality is that he knew the earth
was curved or he heard the earth was
covered,
but there were many of us crew who
thought the earth was flat.
You sell long enough,
you fall over the edge.
They were on the edge of a precipice.
They thought,
or certainly columbus thought,
screw it.
I'm going forward and I'm taking the
risk of all these other people's lives
because I think we're gonna.
find the spices
and that.
I think that's what I wanted to get at.
You know what?
What he said was that you know you
shouldn't.
You shouldn't overestimate your ability,
but when you are going into the unknown,
you don't know what's going to happen.
yeah,
you don't even need a grand adventure.
What about a relatIonship?
what do you think didn't go well?
I'm going to go.
I'm going to ask that girl for a date,
right?
If you're shy,
if you're basic nature is shy and you
feel unworthy and she's so pretty and
she's so.
You think that that's above and you
suppress all that and you venture out
onto this flat earth of the edge of a
precipice.
You're going to ask for a date.
Yeah,
you have to suppress all those feelings
of inferiority and and think,
I'm,
I'm okay,
I'm going to do this to,
and not only that,
but the fact that people,
that anybody gets married,
knowing as little as anybody else knows
about anybody else,
when at the point at which they get
married,
no matter how well they know each other,
they don't.
They don't know anything.
That's exactly right.
They and I'm,
I'm one of your funeral authorities who
can attest to that very fact.
You don't know anybody that you marry
until you've been married a length of
time.
Yeah.
Even then strange aspects revealed.
Right?
And so I mean,
to go into that kind of adventure which
people do over and over again certainly
requires,
if not ego,
at least some kind of suspension of
disbelief.
You know?
Well,
see,
now you're,
you're in the area of suspension of
disbelief that you're okay.
You can do this,
this is worthwhile.
And your mother and father say a son,
jason,
don't marry that girl.
Right?
And you say,
dad,
I'm doing it right.
And your dad says,
all right,
it's your life.
Okay,
don't Come to me.
And uh,
sometime later you ring your dad and
say,
dad,
you were right.
May,
maybe,
maybe he'll be right.
Maybe he won't,
but you know,
maybe he'll be watching because he's got
his own prejudices and he doesn't know
this girl anymore than you do.
So you can see how complex the picture
is without painting a psychopath who
says,
don't talk to me,
don't drive the I know everything.
And I'm a.
And we,
we've heard some of those psychopaths.
I don't talk to me.
I'll fix it.
Uh,
I alone,
I believe I was listening to just such a
psychopath two nights.
Well,
there you are.
And that,
that I,
I don't admire.
But there are people whose core
knowledge of something is so profound
that they say,
look,
you don't know what I'm talking about.
Whether it's higher maths or
astrophysics or,
or this relationship,
you don't know what I know and I
therefore I'm going ahead with my ego.
I think I'm right and you're wrong.
Those people who have been right and you
were wrong.
We're the people who,
people who explored all those new
ventures,
they're the creative,
productive human beings who've lived
individually,
isolated,
individually over the generations.
One or two or 10 people in a generation
of made these steps into the unknown
that advised against it by everybody.
Well,
you hear these kinds of things like
about,
for example,
stanley kubrick,
right?
Who is undeniably one of the great
directors.
Right?
But allegedly he was just completely.
He map out his entire production.
Didn't want to hear from anybody.
Actors were essentIally tools in his
hands.
Yeah.
And,
and,
and you know,
you can stand aside and you can look at
that and say,
okay,
that's bad.
Uh,
or he might have learned much.
It's,
but it's not that.
It's a perfect example.
A director of a film has the vision,
right?
And his vision may be,
I thought a law those shoes and you need
a tie.
You need to tie the laces on the shoes.
That's my vision.
The wardrobe person as well,
you know,
they're,
they're made so that shoe laces are
untIed.
I don't care.
My vision is tie the shoe laces as
incidental.
Is that,
that's the vision.
Why that be eager?
Sure.
Why should the wardrobe mistress have a
vision that supersede the director?
Yeah,
and I think it's probably true also,
and you've worked with many directors
that people have just different styles,
some are more authoritarian and,
and,
and always in charge of everything and
some are probably like,
I know that
Jason Martin collaborative to do it has
to do with the vision.
Yeah.
A director may have a vision and every
aspect like why would a painter say to
you?
Um,
okay,
yeah,
go ahead and dabs of some color on my
painting.
It's okay.
Sure.
He's got the vision.
He's painting the whole picture.
That's what that kind of director would
do.
Other directors say,
well,
it doesn't matter.
Tie the shoe.
Listen,
don't tell the show.
I'm cutting up
above it.
And that's their vision anyway,
right?
That's right.
Yeah.
So you,
it's hard to argue what Is ego and what
does a psychopathic.
Right,
right.
Yeah.
What is ego in the healthy sense of sort
of knowing what you're doing and knowing
why.
Is there anything healthy about ego?
Right?
Well,
yeah.
I mean it seems so.
I mean.
Well yeah,
because most people,
you know,
what did the first person to say,
look,
we've just come out of the tree,
let's head north.
Right.
And the evolution of mankind began.
Some individuals had.
That's I,
you know,
I'm tired of sleeping on the tree here.
That's lie on the ground.
It seems much more comfortable.
yeah.
But you'll get eaten.
I think I'll be alert enough to hear the
tiger.
Yeah,
it's called leadership basically.
It's called
leadership.
That's exactly right.
And how can you lead with a group of
people?
It's complex by fred and this guy
telling us that the ego then leads you
into a psychiatry is as I think,
interesting.
Incorrect.
Okay.
Let's leave it at that assessment and
let's move on since our time is,
is a little limited to the next surprise
video and that's nickeel go.
Oh,
he's an educatIon expert.
Alright.
The statistics show that bullying is a
major,
major problem in most american schools
and what they find is that in school
schools have a number of different
qualities and one of them is the
antidemocratic governing structure.
Uh,
if you look in most american high
schools,
for example,
they are a gargantuan mammoth
institutions.
They have thousands upon thousands of
kids,
uh,
walking through the hallways every day,
and what,
what happens as a result of this,
and this is not necessarily the fault of
teachers or even just the people in that
school building.
When you have such a large student body
and you don't have a,
you have large class sizes.
There's not enough time for students and
teachers to have really strong,
authentic and genuine relationships and
students.
Basically what happens is they don't
have any relationships with fellow peers
and students that are really rich and
authentic level.
And so when students feel that they have
no power or no agency in their school
experiences,
what often happens is something called
clicks arise.
If students feel that they have to wield
power and get control within themselves
and within their ranks,
and so clicks are one of the major
phenomenons in american schools where
they create basically power structures
within the student body of themselves.
I actually Want to start in a sort of
oblique way and then come to the bigger
ideas here.
I wanted to start with like,
you know,
let us take a trip in the wayback
machine to Canada.
When you were a kid where they're
bullIes in your school,
were you a bully?
Were you bullied?
Was there,
was that a thing in your that you dealt
with?
Uh,
well,
you want,
you want to bring this specifically?
Yeah,
why not?
And bullying.
I want to start.
Well,
I mean I just find that it's sometimes
helpful to go from the particular to the
general and it,
and a little more colorful.
I'm happy to.
Yeah.
well,
when I went to a grade school and maybe
even as far as high school,
I was brought up in montreal,
Canada.
Okay.
And I'm jewish and uh,
being jewish in the miller that I was in
a,
it was an unusual and so I was attacked
a lot as a kid for being jewish and I
had flights every day.
It was more than one guy at a time and
crowds of kids gathered around yelling,
fight,
and I'd be the one in the fight trying
to handle one if not two and sometimes
three kids my size,
my age and I had fights all the time.
And one bully I remember in particular
who was,
there were places where coal was dumped
into the furnaces,
so they were raised like two feet above
the ground and so they provided a place,
maybe four foot square that was like a
crowning place.
So somebody would stand on this and be
the bully and then they try and get you
off.
That was part of the game to see you
could stand on the highest place,
the longest part of a bullying campaign.
But that's my experience about being
bullied.
I was bullied all the time.
Now,
I mean,
just looking back,
do you feel,
I mean,
not that anyone would wish that on their
child,
but did you become like tough as a
result of that or was that.
Well,
that's,
that's an interesting aspect.
You know,
wish on your child is an interesting
phrase.
You wish only the best for your child
kindness agonists,
ambition,
a softness,
delightful pink,
uh,
lots of food,
leonardo soft bed,
good.
You wish they would have that,
but what does that make?
Right?
What kind of a child does that make?
When you talk aBout bullying,
it seems to me you need to look at life
around you.
You look at other animals living in
concert with each other.
Look at a wolf pack.
Every social animal that I can think of.
Chimpanzees as close to human beings.
Apes,
all the great apes in concert.
When they live in concert,
there's one or two alpha males or uh,
in elephants.
Maybe it's a matriarchal and the alpha
female and they alone,
at least in the wolves,
they alone breed and their children are
alpha children.
Then they're handled.
Even the insects bees.
Think of it most maybe all aspects of
life living together.
There's a dominant individual,
but at the same time,
don't we have to say that like humans,
while we are like other pieces were
differentiated by the fact that we have
a prefrontal cortex,
we organized into societies,
we have the option to make decisions.
We organized into societies in which
there's a lead elect them or their
appointed or they assuming there's,
there are leaders and there are
followers.
Do the leaders achieve leadership by
bullying that?
What I'm saying is that we.
We don't,
it doesn't necessarily.
We don't have to organize things as
killer be killed,
that we are different from other animals
in that.
For example,
we,
you and I are not going out every day
and like ms dot shetty and people.
Now there are humans that are doing
that,
but no,
but how did you get this podcast?
Well,
not by machete,
well,
not literally,
but did you push somebody aside who
might've had a podcast?
I mean,
not,
not literally,
but I've just literally.
But somebody could have had a job,
but you got It.
Right,
right,
right.
Good point.
Um,
I love making a good point.
No,
it's,
it's good.
So you know,
going back to what he was saying in
terms of power structures and how they
create
bullying,
I mean regardless of whether we think
that this is a natural.
No,
not regardless.
That's the point.
Okay.
The point is it seems to be a natural
evolvement evolution in,
in a,
in a group that if the group has to do
something other than just sit around and
go into the ocean and,
and toast marshmallows by the campfire
then,
but then somebody brought the
marshmallows and somebody made the
sticks.
So in every group that needs to go to do
something,
go someplace,
there's always a leader.
Let's go there now let's go.
Okay,
let's go seven steps in that direction.
See what happens.
Yeah.
I guess where I guess where I want to
and you know,
and we're not debating.
I mean I guess where I,
where I,
where we are different.
Well where I differ is maybe we are.
Where I differ is just using the word
defer differ william.
We are not,
it's not a zero sum game.
Like we're not,
nobody's keeping score,
right?
I,
that's not,
I don't,
I'm not trying to win the podcast.
You Are.
Okay.
So know what I'm saying is like
leadership and bullying aren't
necessarily the same thing.
Are they?
oh,
I mean,
leadership and bullying are not the same
thing.
So where do you go?
Where do you,
where do you work?
How do you mitigate all those things?
So let me tell you what,
what I think about that.
I think we need to teach from birth on
empathy.
we need to teach the ability from one
human being to the other to place
yourself in that person's running shoes.
Baby shoes,
spikes writing shoes.
We need to everybody to say,
listen to what this person is saying and
crying out for help to be listened to.
Look at my experience here.
Look at what you've trIed on my toes and
that hurt.
Let me explain to you this hurt.
You've crushed my toes and that hurts
and I don't want to hurt you.
And norman,
maybe I'm not incapable of hurting you,
but listen to how I'm hurting.
And maybe you don't do it again and you
teach empathy to children because
empathy may not be natural sympathy
maybe,
but empathy to live in somebody else's
mind for a moment and understand
completely what that other person is
feeling,
I think is taught and you need to teach
that.
And as a result of that may be aspects
of bullying would dissipate.
yeah.
Maybe there could be more empathetic
leadership,
for example,
more empathetic leadership which will
hopefully get after this upcoming
election.
Fingers crossed.
We'll see.
I'm william shatner.
It has been great talking to you and I
think we'll leave it there because we
are almost out of time.
And a zero g zero g is the new book.
It is really,
really interesting and exciting.
And it's set in the 20 slash 25 slash 50
really?
But
no,
it's all right.
Just a few years difference.
I'm being empathetic.
Being an empathetic leader.
I do it.
Don't worry about it.
Did I understand you made a mistake in
2025 but it's really 20 slash 50 but not
to worry about it.
I'm with you.
Alright.
And let's go test marshmallows and go to
those.
Thanks so much for your pleasure talking
to you,
jason.
Pleasure talking to you.
Yeah,
and
that wraps up another episode of think
again.
I know you are busy.
I know you have lots of good things to
do with your time still.
If you like our show or love our show,
and especially if you're listening
regularly and you haven't had the chance
to do so yet,
I would really appreciate it.
If you could rate or review us on itunes
or your favorite podcast,
getting location.
Thank you.
We are back next week with novelists,
jodie pekoe,
whose new book is a big departure for
her.
It deals with racism in contemporary
America.
See that.