The Arctic,
a wash for centuries,
uh,
largely unknown,
very remote part of the Western world.
And it was only 100 years ago that to
discover is starting to go to the North
Pole and to these remote areas and then
the cold war or close to the Arctic in
terms of military confrontation and the
conflict between the Soviet Union on one
hand,
the western powers on the other.
Joe,
one of the most important things to
remember when we look at the Arctic and
the beginning of the 21st century is
that it is show recently that we as
mankind have been able to come together
to discuss on the site what do we do
with respect to the Arctic future.
There is no part of planet us,
which are so recently arrived on our
desk as a challenge and as an
opportunity.
So therefore the corporation in the
Arctic is one of the most crucial issues
of the 21st century.
For many reasons.
One age that uh,
this is the front line,
no climate change.
The aggression melting of the ice in the
Arctic will have consequences all over
the world.
They've only our quarter of the
greenland ice sheet melts.
This will lead to two meters rising sea
levels everywhere in the world.
And already we are seeing that the
present melting of the Arctic Sea ice is
causing extreme weather events in the
United States,
in Asia,
I than other parts of the world.
In audition,
the Arctic is one of the richest parts
of the world in terms of untapped
natural resources.
And with the continuous melting of the
Arctic Sea ice,
uh,
there will be a new shipping lines
linking Asia to America and Europe in a
revolutionary way,
like the Suez Canal on the Panama Canal.
That in his time a lot of this,
why the Arctic has now become the new
economic and political playing field.
In 2015 the United States takes on the
chairmanship of the Arctic Council.
It is the first time we change the
Arctic Council became a treaty making
organization,
but the US takes on that responsibility
and the chairmanship is not the US,
uh,
a formal role.
Uh,
it's just supposed to provide a vision,
uh,
a policy agenda and a direction towards
the future joints.
And very important that all the people
in the United States or introduced it in
climate change or interested in the
environment,
realize that in the next two or three
years,
the US will be in the leadership role
with respect to the future of the
Arctic,
of course,
in partnership with other Arctic
countries as well as the option of the
states from Asia and Europe.
Although the Arctic council liaison
intergovernmental body,
there is a role for activists and
environmentalist,
a expert scientist,
ordinary people in this process.
And in order to facilitate that together
with many other partners from the
Arctic,
I established last year what's called
the Arctic Circle,
which is a kind of a on the
international assembly where everybody,
whether it's a,
an individual or citizen or,
or government or corporation or a
scientific institute or university or
activist group can come together where
everybody has the same role,
the same rights to speak on and discuss.
So I would encourage,
especially the next two or three years,
everybody who is concerned about these
issues in the United States.
First of all,
to look at the Arctic circle on the
website,
Arctic circle.org and see if you want to
come to the assembly or if you want to
attend the forum meetings that will take
place in the United States in Greenland
and Singapore as well as Iceland in the
next 12 to 18 months.
But I'll,
we'll all be aware that your own
country,
the United States of America,
well from 2015 2017 be the leader in
making policy and agreement and map out
the future for that part of planet does,
where climate change is most
aggressively taking place.
There was a big great march in New York
about the climate at hundreds and
thousands of people participated.
I'm not sure if many of them realized
that in the early months of next year it
will be the u s who will chair the
international cooperation on that part
of mother Earth where climate change is
most aggressively taking place.