A lot of it was just,
you know,
the transcendental experience I had
reading,
you know,
I remember reading the Lord of the rings
in about eighth grade and just finding
that
inexperience,
just that,
just the level of engagement and
intensity in that experience that,
um,
you know,
the rest of my life didn't really match,
match up to that.
Um,
but I was also had that impulse to,
if I liked something or was excited by
something,
I wanted to do it.
Um,
you know,
I never was that comfortable in the role
of fan and I knew a lot of people who
were,
you know,
like,
um,
there are people I knew who just were
fanatical baseball fans and really
enrich their lives to kind of go to a
lot of games,
no more about statistics and everybody
else.
Whereas if I,
you know,
if I like baseball,
I wanted to play baseball and certainly
that happened to me with a rock and roll
when I was about 12,
13.
Um,
you know,
I started listening to a led Zeppelin,
aerosmith,
and,
uh,
David Bowie.
And you know,
really to me that was a central center
of my high school experience was,
was just music and trying to make music,
which was something that I had very
little talent for.
So I knew a lot of talented musicians.
I could play a little bit,
but,
but not well.
Um,
at the same time I was reading really
intensely and starting to think about
writing.
And when I picked up a pen and tried to
write a story,
I had the feeling that was completely
different from the feeling I had holding
a guitar and feeling like,
you know,
this is not my native language.
You know,
I don't know how to do this.
If somebody showed me,
I could kind of,
yeah,
I can make my fingers do what they told
me to do,
but I couldn't intuitively feel the
music.
Uh,
but when I started to write stories,
I immediately felt like,
oh,
I know how to do this.
I know where you'd go now.
Um,
I knew when it started doing to stop,
um,
you know,
it,
it came relatively easily.
Um,
and I would say that that feeling of,
I know how to do this,
that,
that kind of was the first thing that I
really loved in life.
That I felt like I could do at the level
I wanted to do.
Um,
and I,
I did discover that in,
in high school.
So by the time I got to college,
I was very clear with everyone.
I knew they,
well,
what do you want to do?
I want,
I want to be a writer.
Um,
so I guess that is,
um,
relatively early,
but I'd be surprised if a lot of other
writers didn't say the same thing
I read as a kid.
And My mother certainly encouraged it,
but they weren't educated people,
they were working class people.
Um,
so,
you know,
and I,
and I often meet a writers who have
similar stories.
You know,
I,
I remember in high school going to the
library and asking for the Magic
Mountain.
I had discovered Thomas Mann and,
and the librarian kept telling me that,
I must be mistaken,
but I didn't want to read the magic
mountain because you know,
nobody in this high school probably ever
had taken the magic out of the library.
But I said,
no,
I've been reading Thomas Mann,
I read death in Venice.
I read,
you know,
Mario and the magician,
this,
the seven short novels.
I thought they were great and I want to
read the Magic Mountain and I,
um,
so it seems funny now,
but,
but I'd certainly didn't have a
particularly literary childhood.
Um,
what I had,
I had some very good English teachers in
is sort of,
you know,
perfectly average public high school in
New Jersey.
But once they knew that I liked to read,
they certainly had suggestions.
You know,
I had a,
um,
teacher probably in 11th grade who,
uh,
said all,
you got to read a Raymond Chandler and
you know,
I went on a binge of,
of a reading,
hard boiled detective fiction back then.
I still feel the
influence that that had on my writing.
You know,
I think I found Chandler,
so a stunningly good,
and I found that writing so,
so bold and funny and colorful.
Um,
I still think of that as a kind of ideal
for,
for a pro style and like,
you know,
so there's just a recommendation from a
high school teacher.
But,
um,
I was just the kind of kid who took it.
If my English teacher said,
read Moby Dick,
you know,
I'd go and read Moby Dick and if they
said,
read Raymond Chandler,
I Read Raymond Chandler because I was
just hungry.
It was the same,
same thing.
I think a lot,
there are a lot of kids do this with
music.
You know,
if your friend says,
Hey,
you got to listen to King Crimson,
or you know,
you've got to listen to radio head or
whatever,
they'll go out and listen to it.
But I was like that with,
with books and that to me is a,
that's the one sign I think when I meet
a young writer,
I feel like if they read really
passionately,
um,
that to me is the one mark of,
you know,
you'll be all right.
I'm,
I'm always mystified when I meet writers
who,
you know,
they want to write,
they have this urge to express
themselves,
but they don't want to read.
It just doesn't make sense.