Welcome. Thank you for coming. Um,
I guess we can take a seat or something
like that. We can also stand up.
I don't really have a preference.
I'm
welcome here today. You're a Texan and
see if I'm allowed to call you that.
Eh, I mean I've been in talks
with you for a little while.
I am super,
super excited about you coming today and
talking to us and telling us about what
you do. Um, but before we begin, since
I've been at Google for a very long time,
but I also know people
that are working the Mba,
MBA embassies and in diplomacy and adds
a lot of a different approach to things.
Can you please just tell me about
your first meeting with Google in this
capacity as an ambassador?
Yeah, no. Well first of all, thanks for,
for hosting me today and thanks also
for listening again. Um, yeah, I'm,
I'm a career diplomat. So
you know, normally this is
the kind of gear that the,
that you wear and we're here
because of the UN General Assembly.
So a suits and actually ties. This is sort
of part of the uniform today. But, uh,
when I arrived in Silicon
Valley a 12 months ago,
I had one of the first meetings we had
was actually in mountain view with,
with the Google headquarters. And, uh,
it was a clash of two different
cultures and to some extent the class of
civilizations because, uh,
together with my tech bitsy,
we went there and more or less dressed
like this and our counterpart came out
and flip flops and a shorter shorts and a,
and I think in the old
Metallica tee shirt.
And we actually have a fantastic picture
where we standing next to each other.
And for me,
this was sort of the wake up call that
we actually need a dialogue but two
different worlds. And the after that we
also went out to buy a lot of the gene,
some of those white sneaker.
So now the uniform is different and
we are also in that area a little bit
different than what diplomats
and I'll be like, yeah,
I did hear about you saying that you'd
made really poor financial decisions.
I have too many suits. Spacing. Okay.
So, uh, you're the world's first, uh,
Eh tech ambassador appointed by a country.
Um,
can you explain to the audience a little
bit more about what a tech ambassador
does and the whole idea behind it?
Yeah, sure. Well, if we,
if we go back to or euro,
so on perhaps one and a half years ago,
um,
there was a in innovation processes inside
the Danish government and inside the
foreign ministry where we looked a
little bit on trends and how to bring
basically the foreign ministry.
And so the 21st century and a and some
very talented younger colleagues came up
with a number of different ideas
and one of them was so point,
I'll take ambassador. Um, and,
and the reason for this are two trends.
If we look at it, one, one being the,
we think technology and probably I don't
have to convince anybody in this room
or anybody watching him,
that technology is going to be one of
the main drivers for global development.
And it's going to have a
lot of positive effects,
but it might also have a couple challenges
along the way. In other words, uh,
technology will be defining the
winners and losers of tomorrow,
but it will also define some
of the foreign policy or
international relations of
this world. Uh, also balance
of power where I think
things like machine learning,
artificial intelligence,
perhaps even iot is going to be as
important as a conventional weapons or,
or even nuclear weapons.
So,
so the mindset of looking at technology
from a foreign policy point of view, uh,
goes to the core of this initiative.
And the other trend or the other main
reason why we did this was of course,
um, and this one I know I don't
have to convince anybody about, uh,
sitting here today, is that some of
the big technology companies now,
at least in the u s are becoming
very, very big, very influential,
not least with the platforms
that you guys said,
development and build an utilize.
But we also see in increasingly that,
that companies are perhaps using that
platform power also to begin influencing
policies and, and the, the
direction of this world.
So we basically are,
the Danish come visit is decided that
instead of just watching the future past
by outside the windows,
we wanted to actually begin treating
the industry and technology and
digitalization as a
foreign policy priority.
And by creating this a first ever et seq
representation and begin dealing with
these issues to see,
to influence the direction despite
being a very small country. And,
and what if like with a company like
Google have to gain by engaging immediate
with the tech ambassador?
I think you have a few more users than the
size of the Danish population. Um, but,
but, but I think, I think the basic
idea behind this is actually that we,
we can't do it alone.
I think government is always
trailing behind our new technologies.
We don't necessarily get it right
on regulations, on legislation.
Our policies are being challenged
because of the fast pace of these new
technologies.
And whether you call it the digital
age or the fourth industrial revolution
doesn't really matter because
I think the gap is widening on,
on our ability as governments,
always international organizations
to actually sort of cope with the,
with the future.
Um,
but I don't think that companies
are able to do it alone either.
And of course we might
discuss a couple of,
of examples over the last couple
of months or the last year or so.
But I think the point here is that we
need each other and we need to work closer
together than we have perhaps in the
past. And we need to find a, you know,
joint solutions on some of the big issues,
both global issues but
also national issues.
So this is basically a very big,
warm,
fuzzy huck on the Danish
government to the tech industry,
but also a sort of subtle way of saying
we need to come closer together and we
need to define together,
uh,
solutions to some of the big
issues that we are faced with.
Also on a global level. And then as
we talked about, you know, that's,
there's one part where
you're always saying, oh,
governments are trailing
behind and digitalization
for governments and all that,
but tech companies as well needs to
also be really add a level of how
governments are thinking about protecting
their inhabitants and own protective,
but also offering them opportunities
and that they can get get caught behind.
And this like global tech
revolution that we'll see.
Let's just call it the
fourth industrial revolution.
I think that's a nice term for it
because there's so many things that are
happening out there.
Um,
just to dial it back a little
bit because we start out,
we always talk about it like
it's Denmark and full disclosure,
I am from Denmark.
I've been living here for eight years,
but I still have a very
big stake in thinking how
interesting this is. You know,
so maybe you could explain
to the world why Denmark,
such a small little country on the
northern tip of Europe with the population
size of Colorado for Americans.
You know,
why is it Denmark of all
countries that start,
that becomes the first to a point,
a tech ambassador and gives them the
mandate you to go out there and try and
engage with us.
What do think are the three reasons
why we came up with this? I mean,
first of all, we have some extremely
talented younger colleagues who,
who saw this and who came up with the
idea and who were able to convince the
senior management back home that we
needed to go in this direction. Um, the,
the other reason is, uh,
is of course that um,
we have a little bit of street cred
on digitalization because we are very
digital country. We are, uh,
where they look at a UN, uh,
assessments or European Union assessments.
We normally come out at the top of the,
of these assessments in terms
of public digitalization.
You probably know that 90%, uh, of, uh,
of all communications
between the government and
citizens in Denmark are today
electronic. I think that's a, an all time
world record, which means that you move,
my grandmother needs a
new driver's license.
She has to log onto a computer and
go online to actually get that. Um,
so we have, we have a tradition
for being quite digital and,
and also using this as an actual thing.
Um, if you look at something which,
which every single day in the has,
that's a civil registry system,
something called the CPR
system is basically, um,
a number of a personal identification
number that is given to you within minutes
after your birth and it follows
you throughout your life.
And that contains a lot of the data
that the other countries are today
discussing.
Whether you need a sort of a,
a whole of government
approach or universal, uh,
identification system where you can store
medical records or educational records
and so on and so forth. And that's an
integral part of, of the Danish society.
And I think it's also one of the reasons
why we have a high degree of trust in,
in public government.
And that's perhaps actually one
of the differences between, uh,
between Denmark and the US. We tend to
trust the government quite a lot. Uh,
I think at least in the part of the world
or part of the US where I'm living in,
in silicon valley, the, there seems
to be a little larger trust in,
in the private sector and in,
but,
but the way we use the trust in
government is that we have the system, uh,
it hasn't been breached or hacked,
um,
yet and hopefully it will never do that.
But it actually offers a lot
of opportunities for using
the states at which is a
available.
So I think those two,
three things are one of the reasons
why we came up with the idea.
But the last one being that we have
always been a small country in Oakland
country, very dependent on
others also because of our size.
So looking into how we prepare
ourselves for the future.
What will it mean for our labor market?
What will it mean for, for global affairs?
How can we continue to take a,
a responsible approach to helping other
parts of the world that are perhaps
doing less well than we are cells. That's
the last, the reason why I think we, we,
we took this initiative
and then that vein and our history of
using big data as a way of the population
and trusting the governments with our
data. And you know, we, it is quite wild.
So thinking about that,
the government XSL access to all your
health information and all your income and
tax information on all these things.
And do you feel that that's a,
a driving force that the,
the, the government, the,
the population of 10 Max has all right,
we trust the government to forge these
relationships with tech companies.
And this is why it's not the u s a China,
France that's gone out
and done this initiative.
By the way, we, we
might come back to that.
Other countries are looking at what
we're doing with quite a lot of interest.
And I think a lot of other countries
are considering whether to a point tick
ambassadors,
whether it'll be in silicon valley or in
Beijing or in one Joe or somewhere else.
I think that's not the important bit.
But the fact that other concerts that
are getting inspiration for what we're
doing and acknowledging that we need
to treat technology and teach it so
platforms in a more
systematic way is positive.
So some extent it's part of my KPI that
we deliver other countries also because
it's super lonely to sit out
in Palo Alto all by yourself.
I really missed the
National Day receptions,
which is such an important
part of diplomacy these days.
I don't actually put that nobody is
watching. Right. So it can be completed.
They will eventually. Yeah, I'm a
blog but, but, but, but, but I think,
I think the trust thing is important but,
but I also be very honest
sitting here in front of, of,
of techies who understand this
much better than I do. You know,
we have a high degree
of, of confidence, uh,
between the citizens of Denmark and the
public sector. When you look at the,
at sort of perception data
on globalization or where
the world is heading,
the Danes, I'm generally also quite
optimistic. They look at the future in a,
in a positive light,
even despite of global affairs and issues
that you might point to a currently.
But I think it's also fair to say it
doesn't take too much or too many.
Facebook came [inaudible] a case
cases to perhaps tilt that confidence.
Um, and we spoke a little bit about
the civil registry system before. Um,
and of course one of the reasons people
trust us is because it hasn't been
preached, it hasn't been hacked,
eh, but one could imagine of course,
that the public trust
in the systems and uh,
could go sour if we see
more of these big scandals.
So that's another reason why we need a
conversation with technology companies.
And that's one of the reasons why we
have a lot of focus right now on data
ethics,
on also on cyber security issues.
So we make sure we protect these systems
against the mullein excess basically.
And I would also say as a comment,
you know,
working at Google and I've been here
for these last nine almost 10 years,
it's what's happened over the last year,
you know,
has sort of for the first time,
from a personal perspective,
I work on these platforms is,
is that we are all of a sudden on the
wrong side of the trust conversation.
Right. That's kind of new for us. You
know, it's always the government's,
that's that the, that, the public's
mistrusts it's usually the, the,
the tech companies have been good beacons
and stewards of all this data and all
these things, which we still
are, but it's just the,
the fact is that many of the things
that we offer and have has far reaching
implications that we might not
have been able to, um, to predict.
But I can say that the
discourse internally in the
company is very much what you
were saying that like we need to make
sure that we get around as good to hear.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I guess
that's also why you're here
today. You know, it's not a, Oh,
take the promise here.
We're just going to shut the door.
It is a thing that's on everybody's mind.
And we can also see that a lot of audience
here is, that's a good point, right?
Uh, but let's, um, I started
out saying, you know,
ask questions cause technology
can really cover everything. It's,
there's not a lot of things that's
not influenced by technology.
Your water's Datadriven, you know,
it's everything that is put into it.
That's tech driven water,
whatever. But I would say that,
um,
a fair question could be what have been
at the core of your work the last 12
months that you've been a
tech ambassador? Yeah. Well
one of the differences between the job I
have now and some of the jobs I've been
doing previously is I get one
question all the time. You know,
what on earth are you doing and what are
the success criteria for actually doing
that? And I can tell you nobody who
came directly from Jakarta in Indonesia,
nobody ever asked me the question,
what do you actually do?
And what's the added value of,
of having an embassy in Indonesia?
We're having an invest in Indonesia.
I get that question question the all
the time and my answer is not very sexy,
but,
uh,
I'll give it to you unless what we are
trying to do is basically elevate our
dialogue with the tech industry where
the companies but also with other
countries and international organizations.
I mean,
it's not a coincidence we're
meeting today, uh, during the,
the UN General Assembly week because
technology and digitalization is going to
be an important topic you're on
development on, on the future of a,
of multilateral systems.
Um,
but the core of what we are trying to do
and what my team is trying to do is to
offer to dangerous authorities a formulas
platform for having a dialogue with
companies like Google or some
of the others [inaudible] eh,
on a wide range of topics.
And what does that mean?
It means that we're doing
exactly the same as a,
as other embassies all over the world.
Not only dangerous emphasis, but you know,
US embassies or a Belgian embassies and
that is representing his authorities on
whatever topic might be
relevant. So, in other words,
one day it might be coming to to mountain
view and say we'd like a conversation
about data privacy.
Uh,
the next day it might be a question of
digital taxation because that's a topic
that is very much on the agenda in Europe
these days. A third day it might be,
you know,
how could,
how could we get access or convince Google
to do investments in data centers in,
in Denmark.
And the third day it might be on some
difficult questions on how do we avoid
platforms being misused for, for
radicalization, extremism or terrorism.
So that wide range of topics is there.
It goes to the core.
What we're trying to to do, I think
it's important to say that this is,
this is not a pessimistic tick agenda.
Um,
and I'm not saying this to be
friendly to techies in this room, uh,
but this is really about the use using
and reaping all the opportunities that
technology brings about.
And when we fundamentally think that
technology will do good for this world,
but we also have a realistic view on it
where we think we have to work together
with Google,
with others to make sure that we mitigate
those areas where they're the real
dangers and we'll difficulties,
for example,
on creating sort of global inequality
or a digital poor part of this world,
which I personally think is going
to be one of the major challenges.
Getting the remaining three and a half
billion people online so they can also
reap the benefits of these issues.
But at the core of what we're trying to
do is really this government to industry
conversation. And in that sense, what
I do is very old school. In fact,
I would argue that it's sort of
bringing in diplomacy back to its roots.
A diplomacy has always been about putting
people into hotspots where changes
were under way.
In the old days it was typically into
a wall prone areas or where conflict
existed. Today, it's about
putting a diplomat's into,
into the heart of Silicon Valley so that
we can have conversations with you guys
on how we fix the world or we make sure
that we don't undermine some of the key
values and institutions that we've
been working on for very long time.
Yeah. And I think it was a small,
easy issues and small, easy as yours.
But like we got to also have to got
with fact that there's something called
legislation that you guys represent.
You know,
and we must looking at legislation,
which is a tool you guys have is a tool
that the governments have view the US.
Everybody has,
you know,
you can say legislation and technology's
definitely does not always move at the
same speed.
Uh,
and obviously we can talk
about Gdpr as an example.
Many people in here has been involved
with that. And, uh, it's, it's, it's,
well, it's, it's, it, it has been
in the works for several years.
When we look at how long
it takes from the disease,
an example to actually be put
into practice, you know, we,
we can also see that in California.
They can push the consumer privacy act
through and I guess two months that was
real fast that they do these things.
That's a part of it that's very,
very interesting to how legislation
and the political agendas and all that.
It's not always fine tune to come with
our emergency entirely and they will look
at what is coming up with
blockchain and AI. You know,
when we look at decision
making and governance, um,
what do you feel that we,
you and I and everybody else I can do
to close the gap between technology and
regulation and we can start
saying what can governments do?
Well,
a couple of different angles
on the questions of course,
the million dollar question, how do we
fix these issues? Well, I think from a,
from a government point of view,
we have to recognize that we are going
to be challenged over the next couple of
years or the next decade because of
the piece of new technologies. Uh,
you mentioned blockchain.
I think Iot is another good example.
And of course machine learning
and artificial intelligence
is probably going to
transcend everything we do. I mean,
no sector will be left untouched.
No industry will be left on touch and
therefore no government will be left
untouched. Um, I think from
the industry side, um, and,
and I don't want to be sort
of a too rough on big tick,
but what I would say is that I think we
have a shared responsibility here. Um,
one of the things that I continue to
argue quite a lot is that we might not see
eye to eye between Europe and
the u s and some of these issues.
There has been a bit of tech ash in Europe
and I think on the US side there has
been perhaps some,
uh,
some concerns about the direction that
Europe is taking GDPR being one of them.
I think antitrust legislation,
uh, is another one,
but it doesn't change the fact that we
have to stick together because we're
still products of the same values that
we paid a very high price to, to get to.
Um, at the conclusion of that is that we
have to work also to find the right way
forward. And, and just to take one
example, if you allow me, restaurants,
digital taxation, I know it's a tricky
issue. It's a tricky issue in Europe.
And I know it's a tricky issue also with,
with headquarters or taking the
industries. But if you look at Europe,
technology companies pay around half of
what traditional companies are paying in
Texas. And you could say, well,
that's a smarter way of operating.
But for the most European countries,
this is an existential issue because
this is what basically undermines our
ability to pay for education or healthcare
basically to uphold the welfare state.
Um, there are a couple of proposals
from the European Commission, um,
currently being discussed. Um, I don't
think they're particularly popular in,
in mountain view, but you can
correct me if I'm wrong on that one,
but it doesn't really change
what I think is the way forward.
And that is that we have to work together
on finding solutions also, for example,
in digital cessation.
So what I mean by that,
I think we need to answer sort of into
a contract where we come to the industry
also looking for advice,
looking for some suggestions on
what is the right way forward,
not to stifle innovation to make sure
that we have a protech pro platform
environment in Europe.
But we also expect from the,
from the tech industry and from the senior
management teams that they help us to
find the right way forward.
It's not good enough to say we don't
like the European Commission's proposal.
And when you then ask the question,
so what should we do instead in with the
answers? Well, let's not offer us to, uh,
to define. I think it
is. And I think that's,
that's where we are today at a
crossroad where we have to expect from,
from the senior management of the tech
industry that they help us define the
right way forward.
Whether it is on digital taxation or
whether it's on regulation or whether it's
on legislation because of the absence of
that is not going to help the industry
and it's certainly not going to,
to help the governments or,
or in our case Europe
either. So. So that's the way
forward, uh, in, in my view.
And that's what we're trying to do
with this initiative by the way.
No, I, I see it and I've could
at some point say there's,
the communication is pretty much
like one way as you're saying,
like we do get engaged and
say we don't like that,
but maybe we could build a feedback loop
in that sense. But yeah, that takes time.
And that's why you're the
first tech ambassador.
She start getting these
feeds going. You know, it's,
it's a legislation again, right?
That's the tool that sets in one way.
And maybe there's a gap in legislation
in Europe that needs to be fixed and
agreed upon by member states
and the European Union.
Can I just add one thing?
Restaurants. I mean I think, um,
I I don't think are revealing any state
secrets by saying that of course Europe
is not always a United on how we deal
with technology and digitalization,
how we deal with a big
technology companies.
There are different views among
the 28, uh, or you 27 soon.
Um, but, but what we often,
and I think that goes a little bit
back to one of your first questions.
What's the,
what's the value proposition that we
bring also to a company like a Google?
Well that is to have a dialogue also the
issues we might not see eye to eye on.
It's also an opportunity to begin
discussing, you know, how to,
how do we create the regulation or
tomorrow so it doesn't undermine the
commercial activities of the taking the,
which is perfectly fine for us.
We don't have any problems
with monopolies. We don't
have any problems with,
with companies growing and making money.
As long as that is not misused,
that dominant position is not being
misused. So I think, you know,
companies like a Google or
Facebook or Alibaba and others,
they will find no better friends than a,
than Denmark in the sense that we've
always been light on regulation,
but we always been right on regulators.
We have to make sure that we go in
where it matters also to protect our
institutions and democracy
and human rights or the big
stuff, which, which is, uh,
important and which we fought quite a
long time for over several centuries.
We have to make sure we don't
undermine those institutions.
And having that discussion and
bringing the two parties together,
I think is going to be
essential in the next decade.
And I think from a personal
perspective and all that,
and I think it's been for many that it
is actually a point where we should get
to, you know, it's technology moves
at such an increasingly fast paced,
even if you are in it,
you're not necessarily always able to
predict the influences it has all around.
And this is the, the
exponential change, right?
It is faster and faster and faster than
Moore's law and all these things and the
human brain thinks linearly.
And so there's organizations you
don't necessarily get into that,
but we'll try and get ahead of that.
And it would be the,
the aspiration and that sense
and why you are here. But, um,
let's try and,
um,
look a little bit of a wider perspective
because your mandate is actually global,
right?
Like we've been talking about the u s
the European Union and all these like
complicated dense matters that are there.
But let's talk a little bit about like,
we have some exciting opportunities
is out in the tech diplomacy.
So, uh, your team is Kinda like you,
you work from mountain where you work
from Silicon Valley. Sorry about that.
But you know,
we also have a part of your
team is situated in Copenhagen
and in Beijing. Yeah.
For you, what does it actually mean to
be an ambassador to a global industry?
No, it's not just, it means
having meetings at horrible times.
So almost everyday because
finding a common time to,
to have the whole team present,
there's basically impossible because
of the time differences. Um, this,
this is also a foreign policy experiment.
I think it's important to mention
that we haven't done it before.
We don't think anybody
else has done it before,
but we think it's the right way to
look at diplomas in the 21st century.
That it's not only about having
a one embassy to one country,
but it's in fact looking at, at a,
at an industry or a sector in a,
in a holistic way. Um, again,
I represent the foreign ministry.
So it goes without saying that we are
focusing on the global aspects of,
of new technology. Um, so,
so I think if you look at
the u s or the America is,
if you look at Europe and if look
at Asia, uh, changes on the way, um,
it goes without saying that there is
a shift or a change also in balance of
power. Uh, I think when you look into the
crystal ball, it's evident that, you know,
in Europe received, we'll move
east, I guess where we're sitting.
It could also move a west. But, but
the point being that, um, you know,
China and other Asian countries,
Eh,
look as though they're going
to be using technology as a,
as a game changer also for their position
on the global scene. It's interesting,
you've look at investments in
artificial intelligence. The last year,
venture capital investments,
I think a 30% or so went to the u s uh,
48% went to, to China and the rest
went to the rest of the world.
Which by the way includes
two European Union.
I think it doesn't require too much
creativity to see that that's perhaps the
contours of the new global order and a
and that we might see technology being a,
being a, you know, a driver for
significant change. I in the global scene,
I think what we're struggling in
Europe is of course to have, you know,
a better focus on innovation.
We need to also build some of the Unicorns
that the US and China and the Asia is
extremely good at doing.
Um,
and I think that requires us to take a
look on, on regulations, on legislation,
but it also requires us to take a look
on mindsets and perhaps a little bit on
access to capital for some
of these big companies. Um,
I think Europe has a role to play. I
know we're sitting in New York, but, but,
but I think Europe could play a role in
the sense of help define the boundaries
for newer technology.
I know that Gdpr,
the data protection regulation is
not necessarily popular everywhere.
It's not popular everywhere in Europe,
either with small and
medium size enterprises.
But it's a first attempt to try and define
the boundaries and to make it crystal
clear that data is something
which is also personal,
something that you can own yourself and
that you have the right to be forgotten,
uh, further down the road.
Is it perfect? Perhaps not,
but it's an attempt to try and set some
boundaries for new technologies between
sort of the wild west of silicon valley
where everything goes and where it's all
about building and creating, uh, but
also the the wild east where you see the,
the utilization of new technologies
happening in perhaps not an unregulated
space but certainly a speech which is
very different than what we see in Europe
by now. So, so again, from
from our point of view,
from a foreign ministry point of view,
this is is also about looking at where
the world is going to be not only in five
years but also in 15 years or 25 years
because that matters even though you are
a very small country at the top of your,
no. Yeah. Now you're talking about,
I guess looking at when we talk
about the China and all that,
you're looking into
like the private sphere,
what sort of invasion we can find there.
But we are talking also a little
bit about like influences,
voiding policy and all that. Yeah.
Which we were talking about before.
What kind of like similarities
or differences do you
see between trying to do
that in the u s and Europe and in Asia?
Trying to get in there and see if you
can influence that and the foreign policy
side.
Yeah,
it goes without saying that we've been
spending quite a lot of time with US
technology companies to begin
with. Um, also again for,
for Trans Atlantic reasons, we think
it's important to stay together and,
and where we've been trying
to do is, is to use, um,
all diplomatic tools,
which is going to have going into the
headquarters to have conversations trying
to convince in a gentle and nice way the
headquarters to begin focusing more on
some of these issues.
Also to take action in in particular
areas where we might have issues or
challenges. Uh, that has worked
well with some companies,
perhaps a little less well with,
with other companies.
Some of it is also because of
curiosity. You know, what is this about?
Is this sick Plumas initiative?
Is this all about bringing the big
stick of regulation and trying to, to,
to do damage to the opportunities
that the companies, well, it's not,
and once we've had the opportunity
to explain what we're trying to do,
most companies have said,
well,
we actually see that this makes sense
and we would like to work with you on,
on this agenda, but we need more people
around the table. We need more countries,
we need all the international
organizations around the table. Um, it,
which is by the way, one of the
reasons we're sitting in New York.
I can join the UN week, uh, you know,
we welcome the UN secretary general's
decision to set up a high level panel on
teach Sukkot a corporation.
So I think that's,
and the European Union has done
something similar, uh, under the, uh,
the high representative Mogherini.
So, so I think this is a trend.
We are seeing more countries.
We are seeing international organizations
beginning to step up to the plate and
focusing on, on digital, uh,
issues and on technology proceed.
So there are some differences.
And of course there are differences.
Also when you look towards her China,
um, and some of the big companies,
they have their,
uh,
my prime minister is going to
meet Jack Ma later this week.
So perhaps I can come back on Friday
and give you feedback on how that
discussion was compared to some of the
other discuss with. That'd be great. Yeah.
Um, no, I actually had it's, it is,
it is fascinating. And I'm, you,
you're talking about
the investments into Ai.
That's the u s is making the
China's making, which, you know,
we move into a decision making
faster decision making world,
um, which is really, yeah, no,
but I want, and this is my own like
little thing. I always feel that,
that's so interesting to look into for
you in 10 years giving everything that
we're doing with Ai.
I never think that in 10 years.
How do you think the Security
Council will look like?
I think it'll look more or less
as a dose today. Um, uh, it, it's,
they don't think Google have a seat.
Huh? We can do a sweep stake up,
see where the, where it hits. Um, I think,
I think it's important to
say that although we are
arguing for a closer public
private partnership on
some of the big issues,
there are still a domain
which should remain for fo,
for estates and foundations states.
And I think the UN will remain at the
Security Council will remain if fora where
states are discussing some
of the big issues. However,
I think what we will see is,
is a,
a small revolution where all these
discussions will also take place in the
margins of the UN Oh, in the margins of
the European Union where we begin, uh,
having, uh, you know, discussion
groups or discussion for us,
uh, to bring about the opportunity to sit
together with the industry and actually
talk about issues including
foreign policy issues,
including how do we make sure that you
guys will also take responsibility for
bringing the next 3 billion people online.
Uh,
you will also take responsibility to
make sure that we don't have, again,
parts of this world that will,
we'll fall behind because we shouldn't
forget that this is not only about,
you know,
bringing health care or
education to people that are
less fortunate than others.
This is also about making sure that the
root causes of extremism or migration,
that they will not be nurtured simply
because of global inequality. So,
so these are real issues.
There might be commercial opportunities
for a company like Google,
but also from a, from a, from
a government point of view,
it is incredibly important that we work
together to try and fix some of the, uh,
um, some of the inequalities that
might exist on a global level.
And then you answered one of my
next question. I'm sorry about that.
That's completed. That's where we should
go. Right? We should, uh, we should, uh,
meat instead of the problems. Probably
not. You should be verbalizing them,
but diverse, we're talking about like
privacy and fake news and all that and,
and where we are there and
how we can work together.
But I do feel that that's the future of
collaboration and the UN and that if we
can talk about like what the last 60
years to find the Security Council and the
end of World War Two and where
are we moving with the Cold War,
whether that's relevant in
the next 10 years perhaps.
But then as we move beyond that,
it is bigger challenges that we
will need to partner ourselves.
We cannot have the hammer
of communism or the,
the power of capitalism to solve
some of those trains. Yeah.
On my personal opinion. Anyways. Uh,
I have two more questions left and then
I think I'm going to start opening it up
to the floor for questions.
Um,
and um,
uh,
I've been listening to your podcasts
and we also met last year, uh,
right when you became newly
minted, Eh, and uh, you know,
the one thing you did say was
that after the first year,
your success criteria would really be
that you weren't the first and only tech
ambassador. Hello.
How's it going out there
relatively well,
but not exactly as good as I hoped.
And we are seeing a, you know, a lot
of other countries coming up with,
with similar appointments.
I don't think anybody else had been
given exactly the same title, but Eh,
you know,
I have a group of colleagues around the
world that are dealing with some of the
same topics.
Some of them are called cyber ambassador,
some of them are called ambassadors
for digitalization or those are called
ambassadors for entrepreneurship
and startups. Um,
but I think we will see a wave coming,
uh, in, in not too distant future.
And again,
I think that would be absolutely fantastic
on where she think that this is in
the interest of everybody.
Not only the government spent,
in fact also the of the industry.
Um,
it would also enabled us
to take collective meeting
so you don't have to open
the doors every time an individual
take ambassador comes by,
but that we can actually begin looking
at how to cooperate together and perhaps
I can deliver. So those small t,
so we're not ready with it yet.
But one of the things that
my team is working on is,
is in fact to perhaps create sort of a
coalition of a of like minded countries
and,
and a couple of companies
where we actually create a
forum where we can discuss
the broad range of topics in relation
to technology and where technology is
heading.
So perhaps we,
when we went to have a conversation next
year that will be established and we
can talk a little bit about the vision
and where we see that to hitting. Um,
I think that's about what I can say today.
So stay tuned for more
information on that,
but it actually talks to the core
what we're trying to achieve.
But that's a Chromos initiative.
No, but that's actually
true. You know, it's,
it makes it bigger companies easier
too because we are organizations,
right? We have, we're at fault
that everything that happens,
it's very top down to try and say,
hey,
there's something really interesting
we need to engage on here.
Sometimes it's hard to
get that bubbled up.
So the bigger you have to be with the
brand and umbrella organizations and we
are engaging with that,
you know,
the UN even for us as can be hard to
engage with or even state departments,
which I've tried previously in my job.
Yeah.
We tip work very close to the Dana state
of various things. So it's a, it's,
it's, it, that would be a
very good thing. Um, again, I,
I need to refer it back to me listening
to the podcast and all that. I,
I, and it's, by the way,
it's called tech promise.
You talk and it's an amazing podcast
and you should realia Casper has some
fantastic people. He interviews and
they paid him to say that. Yeah,
get a little bit,
it's on podcast addict.
You can easily find it on soundcloud
and everything. No, it's, it's great.
And on Itunes, right? Yes.
Sorry. Yes. That's okay.
It's an open plan. Diversify. So it's
an open platform does, it's all good,
but really a, if you are having any
interest in, in this sort of thing,
please get into that. Uh, and
if anybody has any questions,
please like get to the
microphones. Um, but you know,
you always finish with the question
of these talks saying like, Hey,
what question should I have
asked you but I didn't?
And what's the answer to that question?
Yeah. You know, it's, it's the
poor man's response where you,
you're know that you're not clever
enough to come up with a good question.
So it's a nice way to get people
to, uh, to come up with a,
with some interesting answers,
I think.
I think the question you restaurants
and I sort of indicated a little bit of
reply all it is, what can you do
for us? What can Google do to,
to support an initiative
like that? Um, and I'm,
and I think what is important
is that we, we, we, uh,
experience and we see also publicly a
renewed societal responsibility from the
second story. I'm not doing this all my
Google here, but the industry per se,
we need to see a societal responsibility,
which is proportional to the kind of
influence you guys have when you look at
the platforms and all the new
technologies that you're rolling out.
We haven't spoken too much
about healthcare, but no,
it's a massive investment all also
for, for coming like, like Google.
I think there was a commercial
dimension to this and that is, I,
I think we all are,
is desperate to see a lot more
responsibility, a lot more engagement,
a also a lot more creativity in finding,
you know,
answers to some of these
difficult questions. Um,
so I think what you can do for us,
which should serve cool own interest or
the industry's own interest is actually
to open the doors and begin becoming
more comfortable with having discussions
with governments. We're not
out there to get you. In fact,
we out there to work with you and
a and help each other solve the,
what I think are really timely.
I'm incredibly important questions,
not least in this day and time and age,
we're talking about democracies.
We're talking about human rights issues,
about gender equality,
what's all about the, you know,
inequality at the global scale.
These are not small issues.
These are incredibly important issues
regardless of whether you work for
government on the dark side
or whether you work for a,
an upcoming year to your industry.
A company like a Google
duly noted. Thank you very
much to sign here. If you
have somebody else do that. But
no, I, I it's, it's a, it's,
I think everybody is, is, it's always
looking for making collaboration.
Um,
the like know Google has a mission,
right? And that is making the
world's information. Yeah.
How has it helped me here?
Free and universally accessible.
Exactly. Right. Which
really ties in I yes.
You have a test when you're moving to
Google it have to be able to answer this.
Yeah. Yeah. That's amazing. Yeah. Now I'm
getting a little flustered in that sense.
Can't even recite the
mission. But anyways, uh,
let's start with the questions all the
time we have and let's start with the
right side and microphone. Hi, you
could state your name and then, hi,
I'm Gabriela.
I'm a designer here at Google.
Thank you so much for talking to
us today. Um, so my question is,
I'm from Mexico, um, where the,
where the idea of the government
knowing everything about Usaa is bad,
just you don't want that.
So I'm curious,
how did you achieve this like 90% of
your interactions with citizens being
digital.
Is there a lot of infrastructure?
Like do people have computers at home,
do they all have in or did they
have that kind of Internet literacy?
And the second one is,
did you have to persuade them at
all or do they just trust you?
Yeah, a really good question. Um,
and, and thanks for posting it.
We, we're not letting me put
it this way. You of course,
like noticed that it's much easier to
implement systems like that when you have
a small homogenous country like Denmark
where the distances are relatively small
and where we already have a high
degree of, of digitalization. But,
but if I'm going to save a
little bit black and white,
one of the reasons I think we have such
a high degree of penetration of digital
solutions is in fact,
because we didn't ask the population,
this was something which
was implemented gradually,
initially primarily out of efficiency
reasons. We wanted it to, you know,
save resources, be more, get
more bang for the buck in,
in our communications and all service
delivery to, to people and going pitch it.
So it was certainly part of the,
of that iteration.
I think that discussion has changed
today where it's much more about quality,
not so not only about the efficiency,
but the honest answer is it was crafted,
introduced.
And the interesting thing was that the
public sector took the lead this one time,
just not something that came from
the private sector. Um, you know,
the public sites or took the lead.
It was not incredibly popular,
Nita and the private sector to begin with,
but people got used to it.
And today it's actually a competitive
advantage because these companies are used
to this. Uh, they've been
doing it for, for forever. Um,
but also the people are used to it.
And actually one thing which might be
shocking if you live in the u s is on
average,
it takes a day in 15 minutes to do the
text report or the annual tax report,
15 minutes, because everything
is provided. The digitally,
you just go in and your chick, uh,
you know, the numbers are they,
do they look okay?
Most people go to the end and see are we
getting money back or do we need to pay
some money? Eh, but that's some of the
advantages and people enjoy that. Um, so,
so I think the popularity is a,
is certainly there.
And so the second question was,
oh, did you have to, I guess you
kind of already asked me, like,
did you have to actually
persuade them to get on board?
But I think you said that you
kind of implemented it gradually.
Yeah, we, we did. Um, but, but of course,
as I said, what, what I think we had,
we had to pay attention to was to
make sure everybody was on board.
So there is an analog way of,
of replying to a,
to government questions or to interact
with the government because of course not
everybody is online.
And I think that's the important big
that you have sort of a safety net around
those that are not online. But the,
the direction is, is crystal clear.
We want to have everybody on
board and I think with the,
with the next generation coming on board,
that will be even more natural than
it than it is today. Um, but again,
it is easier than a country like Denmark
and they might be in a big country like
Mexico.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
Hi. Thank You Excellency. My name is
[inaudible] and welcome to Google. Um,
I'm an Lsu.
Uh,
I'm also a fellow Dane and I'm going to
preface my first question was saying I
used to work at your organization.
I have since switched your nice dress
shoes with this very comfortable sneakers,
condolences about your experience before.
Oh, thank you. So my first question
is on a foreign relations in general.
So Google is pretty good at making
decisions based on data and informing our
product development. How do you see that
informing foreign relations, for example,
in your own organization?
Are we sinking in more data to,
to make informed decisions?
And the second question is more on the
monopolistic nature of a lot of these
companies in the [inaudible] economy
and regulation of the same. Um,
so a lot of the innovation that Google
is doing is often when we go into the
marketplace and say, actually
we can do better. So take
for example, Google chrome.
It might be several, uh,
recently flat, but and,
or Google fiber where Google decided
to go out and challenge some of the
comments of the market.
Uh,
how do you avoid regulating some of
that innovation that also come from big
companies? And when you do that, once
you start to meddle in the market,
how do you avoid that?
For example saying, well,
we're going to regulate maybe some of
the American companies and European
companies, but maybe, uh, the Alibabas and
10 cents of the world, we then go in and,
and, and uh, get a bigger share
of that market. Yeah. Yeah.
So super good questions.
Um, one, the first one,
how do we use daytime informed policy?
Well,
I think we don't use it enough and part
of my mandate together with my team is
also too to help sort of
change the mindset inside the,
the government or inside the foreign
ministry in a more digital direction.
What does that mean in
practice? It means, for example,
that when we look at our development
corporation with Africa, with Aisha, we,
we also taking our a firm view on whether
we're doing the right stuff. You know,
is it,
is it good to focus on,
on a delivery of water in Tanzania and
Kenya or should be in fact look at the
infrastructure and building the right
competencies for people so they can again
reap the benefits of a, of the digital
age. That's one area to look at it.
The other,
the other areas of course,
to see whether we as a delivery
mechanism can use data in a,
in a better way inside the
foreign ministry. And, and
last year we have, sorry,
I have to to um, Nima a rival
company, but as a u s rival company,
we,
we supported a collaboration between
the Danish Refugee Council and IBM.
And that partnership was about
using data on migration flows. The,
first of all, it's a better predict, you
know, in Europe where people coming from,
what are the reasons why people are
migrating. But there's also too,
to help deliver better humanitarian
efforts. So in other words,
people in your extremely difficult
conditions in dire needs,
how do we get the right kind of assistance
to them so we don't send out the
wrong stuff they do or don't need.
And I think data is going to be creating
a small revolution in how we deliver
those kinds of services. So we get more
bang for the buck. So efficiency again,
but actually also make
a bigger difference for,
for the people on the receiving end.
So I think data will play an
incredibly important role.
But as with any other organization,
it takes a little while to get the
mindset going in that direction. But,
but that's part of what we're trying to,
to help with on the other,
on the other issue, um, you know,
I think your 0.2 to one thing which
we're still struggling with in Europe and
that is how do we support innovation? How
do we make sure that we don't regulate,
uh,
technologies in a way that actually will,
we'll be shooting ourselves
in the foot in the long term.
There is a lot of focus on
antitrust and competition. Man,
I'll be honest with you to share that.
You know, when I, when I moved to,
to the u s last year, um, and when I went
to the headquarters in Silicon Valley,
one of the first question was
always, you're Danish? I said, yeah,
isn't the EEU Commissioner
for competition? Isn't she
dangerous as well? And said,
yeah. And they said, you know,
how, how does that work together?
Because you just said this is a,
a tech positive environment. Um,
but I think permission and I told
commissioner of SDR myself, so again,
I can tell there's honesty.
The interesting thing is just under
12 months we've been underground. Um,
I think there has been a convergence
of view across the Atlantic on some of
these issues where there is a recognition
that regulation is not only a bad
thing as long as we do it in the right
areas and then leave the other areas
alone. Um, so I think if you
look at commission investor, she,
she's gone from suddenly being persona
on Carta and certain parts of silicon
valley or the bay area to become a
little bit of a rockstar. And you know,
things are changing when the venture
capitalists are saying, well,
perhaps we need to take a
look on recommendation and
we need to invest more in
companies that have a bigger
social corporate responsibility,
then things are changing.
I think that's a positive thing.
And I think that will actually also built,
you know,
a better companies and Mocha
commercially sustainable companies. But,
but I think the jury is still out on
how we get it right in, in Europe.
And we can't fix that as a small country.
But I would argue not to be too focused
on my own country that we punch above
our weight on these issues simply
because we have, you know, the,
the degree of digitalization and we have,
you know,
a positive approach to technology.
So we can hopefully also help make
sure that you're a moose in the right
direction on some visits,
difficult questions. But again,
we need the industry to help us to
find what the right direction is.
So that's why we are, we're inviting
everybody to, for, uh, for longterm dance.
Thank you. Um, and we
have a question over here.
Sure. Appreciate it. Thank you for
coming and speaking to us today. Um,
as a veteran myself of
a similar organization,
I was a worked at the US government or us,
um,
you govern an it office while
I was getting started up. Um,
I have a great appreciation for the
opportunity and the challenges you have in
front of you. And you sort of
answered this a little bit,
but as you speak about the breadth of
what you're doing in the per view of it,
I'd imagine there are probably some legacy
pieces of the Danish government that
may not want you meddling
in their business.
And how have you been able to get the
opportunity with them to create the
influence you need to sort of enact
these things back on home ground?
Yeah,
that's evident be an insight.
Has a question and you know
how difficult it is to yeah.
Bureaucracies to tumor when the right
duration. Well, the interesting thing is,
you know,
I come from the foreign ministry,
but I would actually argue that we work
as much on the domestic agenda as we do
on the foreign policy agenda. Um, there
are numerous activities back home,
which is about preparing Denmark for four,
the fourth industrial revolution.
And one of the things that we're doing
is actually linking up with a lot of the
ministries back home or at
the authorities where the,
whether it's the ministry for Philipa or
the Ministry for transportation or the
Ministry for health care.
And the thing we're doing with them is
it's both to be sort of a Ford operating
posts in the epicenter of new technology.
So basically being out there collecting
information during small analysis,
you know, telling a colleagues back
home, you better be aware that, you know,
Google is looking at the retina scanning
for diabetes patients. You know,
that that will have an impact also on
the way we treat, uh, patients back home.
How do we propel our health care systems
for that kind of new technologies
coming? Yeah. A theater, the
attorney. So very soon. So,
so being that sort of beacon out there,
bringing information back home,
I think face an incredibly important part
in both changing the mindset back home,
but in fact also in a very practical
way help look at, you know,
is all legislation prepared for those
opportunities or the areas where we want
to work with,
with Google or other companies to make
sure that when you do healthcare or when
you do education that we,
that we get it right.
So it also fits together
with, with our approach. Um,
I don't know whether you know this,
but Uber was introduced in Denmark and
then it was a band, uh, I think, uh,
more or less a year after
its introduction, uh, for,
for a number of different reasons and
eloquent to say that, that my office had,
had been in existence a five years ago,
that it would have fixed everything.
What I would argue though is that I think
Uber is a pretty good example of a new
technology or new platform coming into
Europe coming into Denmark where have,
had we had a tech ambassador
or my office a few years ago,
we could have identified that and said,
well,
let's work with the Ministry
of Transportation back
home or the appropriate
authorities and see what we can do. Uh,
what are the, what are the fine lines,
what are the red lines for Denmark?
And then have a dialogue
with a headquarters over
here to make sure there's not
introduced in the wrong way.
And I think that should be
an interest of the companies,
but it's certainly also in the
interest of the, of a country our size.
Did you notice how I avoided
answering exactly how I know,
good positive answer to I'm sure
other existing challenge to thank you.
No, but to be honest with
you, it's not always easy,
but I think in any organization or
any, any big industry, you know,
there's always resistance when
you're trying to things in,
in a new way that we've experienced
that. But I think, I think the,
the goal is so important that we get
this right. Um, that, uh, you know,
eventually it will,
it will cause a lot of changes both in
mindsets and also how we do business. And,
and we've seen this just under
12 months within the underway.
I want to make sure we get
through all our questions. Sure.
People aren't lining up.
So over here,
hi, my name's Jimmy. Uh, I'm a former
Googler and my question is, um, you know,
anyone who's been paying attention to
the news has seen there's like increasing
evidence that Russia, for example,
is using technology platforms,
whether it's Twitter or Facebook
advertising platforms to try to influence
democracies.
Um,
do you see that these sorts of
geopolitical conflicts have a risk of
increasingly spilling over
into tech? And, uh, what would,
uh, you know, what's
your expectation or, um,
the Danish foreign ministries expectation
for Google and other tech companies
role?
You know,
is it as a neutral arbiter or would you
expect them to take proactive measures
and these sorts of conflicts?
Yeah, got that question. Super
quick question. And, and it,
it enables me to say that I think
we realized that cyber
issues, uh, is, is, uh,
is not something that will go away.
In fact,
it might increase over the
next couple of years. Also,
as we digitalize more and more parts of
our societies. And, and of course we are,
you know,
Mike government has set this repeating,
we're extremely concerned about
the way Russia is operating in,
in the cyber security
arena. And we need, uh,
to have better defensive mechanisms,
but we also need international
collaboration to try and
sort of mitigate these
issues. These are not small, um,
you know, destructive incident.
This is about potentially metalink with,
uh,
with elections or undermining
public confidence in institutions,
et cetera. So these are relationships
that we'd take extremely seriously.
We need an international collaboration.
Um, also to make sure that,
that those maligned actors that are
actually performing these things,
that they are brought out in the open and,
and in in the right circumstances
that we have attribution in that case.
But we also, and that's to answer
the last part of your question.
We certainly expect the industry to take
a responsibility in this area and we
know it's incredibly complex
and if there is a, you know,
a very fine line between a meddling with
the freedom of speech and freedom of
expression and then of course removing
content that you identify positively as
being a,
you're not truthful or,
or basically a based on
so it doesn't exist. Um,
and I think that that dilemma is
going to be be important to try and,
and find the silver bullet for,
it's not good to be said,
but we're going to put a lot of the
efforts into it and we expect and we are
going to work very hard to make sure
that the industry also plays a part.
It's part. Thank you. So
we are at time, however,
I would like to if possible, and I get
an okay from the control room back there,
um, to, um, to get the last few
questions for. So over here.
Hi, I'm Kira and I actually just
joined a Google New York from Google,
Denmark. So I have Lyft and works in
Denmark for about year and a half.
And in the last 10 years that was the
10th country in which I lived and work.
Uh,
so what I see is that there's actually
this growing population of people who,
you know, they might not be just digital
nomads, but obviously that's, you know,
part of the group as well,
uh, who are kind of, you know,
in different countries and obviously
they're experiencing the digitalization
level in different countries differently.
Uh,
and what I noticed this is that actually
no country that I've lived and work in,
they really think in any way about
people like that who actually have their
presence beyond the country. So I know
that officer Denmark has done a lot,
and with like Estonia with, they're
like east citizenships, you know,
they're looking at that as well. Uh, but
I have kind of a two fold question. Like,
could you share and you know,
is this part of a discussion where
people are becoming more globalized and
they're not really looking at
any single one country, uh,
as like the source of truth of their
identity or of their digital identity?
And number two, you know, do you
feel that you, in your position,
can you actually do something about that
or are you having these discussions in
your circles as well?
Oh, enormously difficult. A question. Um,
what I would say is that
I think you represent, uh,
a group which is growing in
numbers. So these years, um,
I think if you look at it from a,
from a country point of view, uh,
what there is renewed focus on is that
we need people like you with skills and
competencies to help,
you know,
drive the economy and built
the new technology companies.
And I can tell you very honestly that
I haven't met a single Dane is tech
company wares and said, well, we're
in desperate need for, you know,
skills and competencies that are very
difficult to find even in Europe or in
Copenhagen or wherever it might
be. Stockholm is throwing.
Yeah. Um, so on so forth.
So I think a lot of focus we'll,
we'll go into,
into that direction both to make sure
we educate a new generation that has the
right skill sets to,
to work in a digital world,
but also to make sure that we can attract
the kind of competencies that we need
for, for the companies. The problem is
of course it's a global competition.
You know, when you sit
in, in Silicon Valley,
I don't think I met any
company where they said, well,
it's damn difficult to find,
you know,
the right engineers or the software
engineers that, that we need.
The competition is fierce.
And I think that competition will
become increasingly a global.
So we also need global solutions to,
to those aspects.
Whether I can do anything
in that dimension. Well,
I think what we can do is to bring back
information and knowledge that these are
discussions that are taking
place or some on the, you know,
the next generation of tech savvy
people that we would like to,
to attract to Denmark. Um, we,
we can't offer any good weather
and Denmark, but you know,
the city is not too bad and you can
bike around to everywhere. So there are,
there are pros and cons.
So perhaps we need to be better at
branding their mark or so because of the
weather, but because of the
quality of life as well.
And that's where he can pay me back
money if which page, then capital.
All right. I know we're way over time,
but last question from over here.
Uh, hi, my name is Tim. I'm
a software engineer here. Um,
my question is, uh, you know,
traditionally when new
technologies came into space,
we generally didn't have an investor,
right? We didn't have an investor,
JC standard oil. Um, and, uh, you know,
traditionally when you want to do get
access to technology or to skillset,
you would usually work with the State
Department or whatnot of whatever country.
And through that you'd create
economic, you know, deals or whatnot.
And so, and that's been the case
I guess until now to some extent.
So another way of asking
the same question as um, uh,
like what's, uh, I understand the
initiative of trying to, you know,
outreach to the tech industry, but
can you give me an idea of, of like a,
what's the urgency coming
from to some extent?
Yeah,
really a relevant question and
perhaps I can begin by giving a,
give you a example of the kind of
critique that we've been faced with a the
first year. Um, it's, it's quite
often that we are being asked,
so are you now putting companies before
countries? So in other words, is this,
you know, elevating Google tour a defect
or a state without having, you know,
democracies below it and all of
that. And, and my reply to that,
or I'll reply to that is always,
well this is in fact about trying to
protect the role of states in the future
governance because I think governance
is going to come under a lot of threat
there or a face,
a lot of challenges because of the kind
of platforms that you guys are building
and rolling out. It doesn't
respect the national border assess.
Perhaps some of the older
industries would. But I think
the real, you know, the,
the pertinent part of your question is
why is it different now than it was,
you know, 50 years ago when the
oil industry began to roll out.
And that I think is because of the
piece. So, so I do think that, you know,
I don't want to call it an exponential,
but I think what we're
seeing is incredibly fast
pace of the new platforms we
rolled out. The way that, uh,
the technology basically penetrates
everything we do, all sectors. Uh,
it doesn't matter whether you're in
construction or whether you're in health
care technology is going to be a game
changer potentially within a very short
time span.
So I think that's the reason why we
think time is ripe and it is something
different than, than oil. Uh, I
think data is not a finite resource,
so you'll continue to sort of expand
and build on that and it gives enormous
opportunities.
Um,
edit might also challenge our country
like Denmark or the European Union or the
United Nations in a more profound way
than what we've seen with some previous
technologies. So, so that's at least our
argumentation that this is different.
It feels different,
and therefore we need a different,
a reply or response to that. And that
reply or response in our case, uh, is,
is part of [inaudible] is here to do.
Okay. Well, thank you. Thank you.
Thank you everybody. Uh, if
you could give her a hand,
Casper.