Okay. All right guys. Thank
you so much for coming.
Really appreciate you guys coming. We
have an awesome, awesome speaker lined up.
I'm personally very excited. I'm a big fan
of this guy, James all at the chair. Uh,
he's a a multiple best selling author.
He's written books like choose yourself,
reinvent yourself, a trade like buffet.
He's a serial entrepreneur. Investor.
Vcs invested in over 20 companies.
Uh, he's a prolific podcaster.
He's interviewed people like Steven
Pressfield, Tony Robbins, uh, to, to,
to Rick Ross who, uh, you know, uh,
ran a big drug empire in the 80.
So people from all walks of
life. Uh, he's a crypto expert,
but he likes to remind people
that that's not all. He's about a,
that is all the rage right now. Um, and
he does an awesome class on masterclass.
You guys should check out. Um, and uh, if
you guys want to learn more about them,
go to James altucher.com.
Um, so without further ado,
let's start this interview. I really
appreciate you coming here, James.
Jessie, I can't tell you how much I'm
appreciative of being invited here.
So my favorite company
in the world.
Absolutely.
And you apparently have a pretty good
story when it comes to Google, right?
Well,
well,
so one time I started this company
and I'm always in the mode.
As soon as I start a
company I want to sell it,
which is really kind of not
a good philosophy to have.
But unfortunately that's my philosophy.
And uh,
so the incident the company started,
I basically went around to every company,
um, AOL, Yahoo, Google,
Forbes Interactive Corp,
and it was kind of like a social media
site for people interested in investing.
And I basically say we're for sale.
Google finance was just
starting at the time.
I don't even know what's
happening now with Google finance,
but Google finance was, uh, uh,
starting at the time and I met with
them in New York and it was great.
Like it was in this conference
room where then it goes,
it went right into a video screen
where the people in San Francisco,
we're on the other side.
So it felt like one big conference table.
And I just remember walking into
Google in New York and people were
skateboarding around.
There was like chefs making lunch.
There are people getting haircuts.
There was like everybody,
everybody had like three monitors
are crazy monitors and I just,
I'm like, oh my gosh, I really want to be
here. Like I want to come to work here.
I hadn't had a job in 12 years at that
point and I just really like wanted to
just hang out there.
And I remember waking up at two in the
morning and I had that feeling like you
get when you're on your, your first
high school date with a big crush.
And I had this feeling like, oh my
gosh, I love Google. And so I wrote,
I think it was a Katie Jacob Stanton was
running, um, Google finance at the time.
She ended up, she ended up working
for Obama then working at Twitter.
I don't know where she is now.
Um, I wrote her and I said,
I really love the meeting.
I love Google.
I can't wait to our next conversation.
It's like everything you would write
as like after your high school crush,
first date. I wrote in
this email like, you know,
like hours after I met them
and she never wrote back.
I never heard from them again and,
but,
which is typical loss of that
high swell first date. By the way,
I never had a first date in high school.
I had a first day when I
was in college finally.
But I'm imagining that's what I be like
if he had a first dating in high school.
So that's my goal.
We'll set bay.
Yeah. Well anytime you want to come hang
out and just, just let us know. Great.
Um, so, uh,
I want to just get into your background
a little bit just for some context, uh,
for, for the people that
don't know out there and, uh,
you're very kind of vulnerable and open
about the adversity you've faced in your
adult life. But take us back to the
beginning. Give us, give us like a, a bio,
give us everything.
Sure. So, uh, I'll, I'll
speed it, speed through it,
but I was a technologist at heart.
I majored in computer science. I went
to graduate school, Computer Science.
Um, in fact, the last time I was
on this campus, I visited, uh, uh,
next Grad school classmate of mine,
which was astro teller who runs, uh,
I don't know what it's called.
That was Google x. Then.
I don't know what he's going to ask. The
moonshot moonshot. A. Yeah. So, uh, uh,
uh, and then I, and then I
got really interested in,
in writing. I wrote a
four failed novels, uh,
which is, I don't know where they are
now. They're thrown out somewhere.
And I decided I wanted to be
an entertainment industry.
So I went to work for Hbo in New York.
And uh,
from that I was able to combine
several interests at once.
I knew technology, I knew how to
build websites in the mid nineties.
No one else knew how to build them.
So I,
but I was also in the
entertainment industry.
So I started a company that focused on
building a very particular niche sort of
websites. So you could probably
even tell what kind of websites,
just by the way I look, but every,
almost all of our websites where uh,
uh, the websites of
gangster rap record labels.
So that's supposed to be
a little bit funny. Um,
well we did bad boy records, loud
records, the source magazine,
that's where records jive records and um,
American express.com which most people
don't know is actually a gangsta rap
record label and a timewarner.com
we did miramax.com,
uh, with where I'm on. Harvey
Weinstein was running it and we did um,
kind of edit.
It was funny.
We did kind of edison.com [inaudible]
website and then we made an internal
website for them to keep
track of their y two k stuff.
And I remember asking them
and one of the meetings,
where are you guys going to be
during, you know, on December 31st,
1999 and they were 100% of them was
like where we are going to be long,
far away from New York City then because
they had no faith in their abilities to
keep the electricity going on y
two k but everything was fine.
So they didn't know anything.
But so I, so I, I started that,
that company we grew pretty fast and
then during the boom of, uh, you know,
everybody was acquiring an IPO and so on.
So we sold the company as I remember my,
my sister who was in like junior high
school at the time was learning how to
build websites at that point. And I
was thinking to myself, oh my gosh,
I charge HBO $75,000 to do a three
page website about Dennis Miller.
And now my lip,
my junior high school sister is learning
how to build websites so that this
business is going down,
this industry is going downhill and within
probably within three or four years,
every single business and that
industry was bankrupt and a,
so I sold that company
and started a VC fund,
started a Hedge Fund II.
Along the way.
I went totally broke. So I
sold this company, cashed out.
It wasn't like I had paper cashed out
for enough money for the next three
generations of my kids, grandkids,
great grandkids could live,
and then I managed to spend every
single dime like there was one summer.
It was really, it was really
unbelievable. Then again,
it wasn't like on paper there was one
summer I probably lost $1 million a week
and then at the end of it I go to my ATM
machine and I had $143 left in my bank
account. So then I, I, I,
I lost all this money and so I wrote some
software to figure out why did I lose
this money? I modeled, I did all
sorts of statistical pattern modeling,
pattern recognition on the stock market
over the past 60 years and started
trading based on,
on this software that I wrote,
built up a hedge fund than
a fund of hedge funds.
Then I built this kind of
social media site for investing,
uh, sold that. I started another
hedge fund after that. Um,
and then gradually I started doing
more and more angel investing because I
realized I really couldn't handle day
trading and hedge fund investing was so
stressful for me in every way.
I remember I would put on a trade and,
and there were,
the trade would instantly go against me
sometimes even if like every software
was shouting it and I thought I could
outsource my emotions. So the software,
but I was still get so stressed like
I would, I would go across the street,
there was a church across from my
house and I go across the street,
no one would be in the church and I would
literally go right up to the statue of
Jesus and I pray,
please make s and p futures go up.
I'll do anything. And I'm
Jewish, so I'm in the car.
It just wouldn't work out.
And um,
and so eventually I did
a fund of hedge funds,
but I decided to get out of the hedge
fund space and I focus more on angel
investing, which was, which
was much easier, not easier,
but much more relaxing
for me. And then I, I,
I had previously written a bunch
of books in the finance space,
but then suddenly I
started writing about my,
as around 2010 I started writing about
the things I was feeling vulnerable about
and the things I was scared
about it. And I realized, look,
this is much more important to people.
Not everybody cares whether apple is
a better investment than Microsoft.
Uh, but everybody goes through periods
in their life where they don't know what
they're doing. They don't know
what path they should be taking.
They feel like maybe they've made some
mistakes in their journey and they want
to reinvent themselves. And so I became
very interested on, because I had read it,
mentored myself so many times,
I became very interested in this process
of reinventing myself and getting rid
of all the obstacles along the way. Like
if you, if anybody were to decide, oh,
I don't want to be a
software engineer anymore.
I don't want to be an accountant anymore.
I want to be a an actor, I want
to be a writer, I want to be,
um, I want to be a doctor or
work in the healthcare business.
Somehow people will always,
the first thing everyone will
tell you is you can't do that.
And because I saw it time after time,
I've probably reinvented my career
15 times. And that's conservative.
And every single time someone has said,
usually the first person I spoke to,
my mother has said,
you can't do this. And, and, and,
and, and you have to figure out, well,
how am I going to do this both
psychologically and mentally?
How am I going to learn to do this? How
am I going to be around the right people?
So that they influenced me?
And, and I'm inspired by them.
How do I stay healthy enough so I
have the energy to do the sticks,
a lot of energy to reinvent a career.
How do I kind of spiritually
and void the anxiety of failure?
If you try to, if you say to
yourself, okay, I'm going to,
I'm not going to work in a cubicle.
I'm going to be a professional
skateboarder. Well, if
you do that initially,
you're going to fail every day.
You're going to fail at it. Um,
because you're going to
realize you're going to,
you're going to love something enough
that you're going to realize, oh,
the best people in the
world do it this way,
but I'm not that good yet because you're
going to understand the difference
between the best and yourself.
So you have to get through the psychology
of how do I keep improving even though
it's so hard and so painful
to fail every single day. Uh,
and just all these things of the process
of reinvention, the pain of reinvention,
the pain of success is,
uh,
is very psychological and requires a lot
of energy and it requires a lot of, uh,
uh, spirituality is the wrong word, but
a way of dealing with the anxiety of,
of trying to improve yourself no
matter what age you are. You know,
we always think, oh, when I'm 18,
that's when I'll put myself on the right
path because I'll study it in college
and then I'll be an expert and then all
succeed at what I say to in college.
But what if at the age of 40,
you decided you want to change?
What if the age of 60, you decide you
want to change and people change at every,
you know,
I don't know anybody who's done the
same thing from the age of 20 to 60.
And you have to be able to deal
with all the ups and downs. Now,
some people don't and they decided they,
they stay the same and they get gradually
that chronic level of anxiety that
just builds into their system.
And then every disease
basically is related to that.
Like that slow stress that you don't
really notice but exists as opposed to
handling the volatility of,
of trying to succeed at something that
volatility eventually subsides and you
succeed. But it's very,
very difficult on that path.
And so I became very interested in,
that's why I started the podcast.
That's why I wrote these books. Choose
yourself, reinvent yourself and,
and with choose yourself was a
great example where I didn't want,
I wanted to write a book that was a story
that was for me and I didn't want to
deal with and I,
and of course because I was,
the book was called choose yourself or
wanting to figure out how do I choose
myself with publishing this book here.
If any of you have written a book
or tried to write a book before, uh,
it's very hard to get published. And,
and, and the rewards of it are very small.
So you have to get through,
when you submit your book to somebody,
you have to get through an agent,
you have to get to through an editor's
assistant. An editor has to say,
this is a great book of Marketing Team
for a publisher has to say this great
book, this is a great book. The publisher
has to say, this is a great book.
It public tries a committee,
they have to say it's a great book
bookstores that I have to say,
it's a great book.
So all these steps along the way,
you have to have all these people who
are not qualified really to tell you your
book is good or bad when you're the
only one who is qualified to decide.
So I decided to skip that with the book.
Choose yourself.
And I've done that ever
since. And that, by the way,
what's my most successful book has
sold over a million copies. And, uh,
uh, you know, again,
the benefits of not only
doing what you love doing,
but figuring out along the way how to
avoid the obstacles that nobody else has
even thought to avoid, uh, choose
yourself. I ended up self publishing,
I self published it through another
smaller company down the street called
Amazon are actually up the
street very far I should say.
Uh, you know, and again,
with everything you do,
there's ways to usually choose yourself
to kind of avoid a lot of the obstacles
and pitfalls that the gatekeepers,
we'll always try to put in your way that
you can't do this people. Yeah. So, and a,
in a nutshell, that's,
that's my background.
I could talk about specific hedge
fund strategies was that's not as as
interesting or how to make a website or
whatever that that's not as interesting
how, and you will writing, uh, manuals
for computer chips at one point, right?
Yeah.
Long time ago in a I,
there was a company called
four systems that, uh,
had the fastest chips out there and I
was writing there their manuals and I
remember, uh, and I wanted to be a writer
and so I thought they hired me figuring,
hey, I knew computers, I knew hardware,
I'll play around with their chips,
I'd write.
So I wrote the initial software for
their chips and then I wrote the customer
manuals and they were,
they were so bad cause I was,
you can't do something
you're not interested in.
And the CEO calls me in his office
and he literally said to me,
don't even take any pride in your work.
And like what kind of response
is that going to get? Like,
am I going to suddenly realize, oh, you're
right, I can take more pride in my work.
I just immediately, I think
thought to myself, I'm like,
I'm like nodding to him on his
suggestions, but I'm thinking to myself,
I have to quit this job as quickly as
possible. And that's what I did was,
was quit. I quit and left for
HBO. Uh, I know I left eye.
There was an intermediate job in between,
but yeah.
How so how do you go from, from that,
from like working a dead end job,
not being inspired?
Uh,
maybe having some kind of like learned
helplessness around like trying things on
the outside, uh, to what you are now,
which is an idea machine where you,
you're trying things constantly. If
you think of something you'd do it, uh,
you're involved, you have your hand and
you know, millions of different things.
You're incredibly productive.
How do you go from that to
where you are now and, and,
and maybe focus on the incremental kind
of small steps you took in that dead end
job?
It's to get where you are now.
I mean there's, there's a lot of
different answers. I'll, I'll,
I'll kind of skip ahead 20 years
to answer it. At one point,
uh, not quite 20 years,
maybe 18, 17 years later,
but at one point I was broke again
probably for the third time I,
I kept making a lot of money and then
somehow faring out the fastest way
possible.
It was like,
it was like my life's goal to figure
out the fastest way possible to lose
millions of dollars each time. And so
one time again, I was broke and I was,
I remember I was on a Hammock,
I had two houses and there's nice piece
of property and there was a hammock in
between them and it was just pouring
rain. And I was, and I realized, you know,
I'm broke again.
It's pouring rain.
I there was the IRS that literally
like stamped on the wall of the house,
like, you know, going to
be seized any day now.
And I'm on this hand and I'm thinking,
how could this happen to me again?
Why is it happening to me again
and again and again? And uh,
I,
I realize well,
the way up things were happening
differently than on the way down.
And it was what I talked about earlier.
I had focused on,
on the way up every time I had focused
really hard on physical health.
It's basically, it doesn't mean go to
the gym every day, but it means eat well,
move well, sleep well, emotional health,
which means be around good
people who will support you.
One toxic person will.
You need to 20.
You need 20 or 30 positive people in your
life to counteract one toxic person in
your life. And it's such an important
rule. That ratio never changes.
Creative health,
which is do one creative thing a day.
And spiritual health as I referred to
it before, but the creative health,
now I'm going to go back in
time a few years. Um, so it,
prior time I had been broke,
uh, I decided, okay, I want to,
I had never been in the hedge
fund or finance space before I,
I had been in the Internet space.
I was a technologist.
I had been in the creative space,
I had shot TV shows,
I had done a bunch of things,
I had written books. Um,
but I want it to be in the finance space.
So that's when I wrote this
software modeling the stock markets.
And I wrote to everybody in the business
that was a hero of mine and I said,
can you meet me for a cup of coffee?
I'll just take five minutes of your time.
Can you meet for a cup of
coffee? Uh, I got zero response,
zero to 50 people.
I got zero responses because it's not
as if Warren buffet is going to suddenly
get my email and say,
Gladys,
hold all meetings.
James Out of the chair is going to buy
me a 60 cent cup of coffee downstairs and
I really need to meet this guy and let
him pick my brain for five minutes.
There's probably be more like an hour
or two. Um, nobody ever says that.
I don't know why I say Gladys was his
secretary. It seemed like the sort of,
if you thought were
above it and a secretary,
it's like Gladys or Bertha or something
like that. Like, I dunno why I think that.
I don't know why. I think she's a woman.
I happen to know she's a woman now,
but could have been a man.
He has a secretary, but um,
nobody responded. And so
I figured, you know what,
I need to get figured out every
time something goes wrong.
It's not the common
denominator in all these years.
It's not like Warren Buffet or,
or all these people were bad guys.
I'm the common denominator in
50 people not responding to me.
So what did I do wrong? And you
have to think about it. And so,
well I was being totally selfish.
His warrant,
all these Bill Gates time is
more valuable than my time. He's,
he's a better human being than me.
So why should he give me
five minutes of his time?
And so I needed to,
to start exercising what
I call the idea muscle.
Now if you have a bicycle accident and
you're in the hospital bed for two weeks,
you need physical therapy to walk again,
your leg muscles will atrophy that. So
it's the same thing with the idea muscle.
If you don't come up with ideas
every single day and even bad ideas,
you'll lose the ability to
come up with good ideas.
And so I started writing down
10 ideas a day just for myself.
They can be ideas about businesses that
can be ideas of books I want to write.
It could be just stupid ideas like,
oh,
here's 10 pieces of clothing
I'm going to design. Like just,
I don't know how to design clothes. Here's
10 pieces of clothing. So every day I,
to this day,
I still come up with 10 ideas a day.
And today for instance,
I'm,
I'm an advisor on a a TV show.
I came up with 10 ideas for them.
And uh, uh, uh,
yesterday I had an idea 10 things.
And this is not even ideas for business.
10 things I value more than money.
And I remember on the very first list
of ideas I wrote, this was in 2002,
I wrote,
um,
10 games I could teach people,
uh,
to be great at, in, in, in, in
just three or four easy tips.
So the idea is I wanted to write a book,
how to beat your friends and family
at every game in the universe.
Because when you go to thanksgiving,
you play your friend right after dinner,
you break out the monopoly board,
a or scrabble and you want to beat all
your friends and family and humiliate
them completely and why not?
If you're going to beat them,
you might as well humiliate them.
And uh,
and so I wrote down 10 ideas of games
and then for each game that three or four
ideas of how to win in that game.
And then now suddenly I had an idea
for a book that I could easily write,
which I never did. Most ideas are bad,
but like take a game like monopoly.
What's the one thing you need to do to,
to beat all your friends
and family and monopoly.
It's just one tip and you'll beat
everyone at monopoly. Anybody know,
build hotels is not correct.
Persuade them. Okay. If
you're a good negotiator,
but there's one set of properties,
I'll give you a head.
There's one set of properties that are
far more valuable than any other set of
properties by a factor of like five.
So parking and Broadway,
you're saying park place and Broadway.
That is the most valuable pieces,
but a squares.
But it's not the most important to own.
In fact, those are the worst. All of them.
Sorry to say. Um, no. I'll
tell you now. Nobody got it.
The orange properties say in New York,
I have Saint James Place in
Tennessee and I'll tell you why.
The most popular square to
land on in monopoly is jail.
Cause there's three ways land on
jail either let him to go to jail,
square the dice, take you to jail
or the community chest is a car,
go to jail immediately.
So there's three ways to let on jealous.
The most popular square on the board,
the most popular roll
with the dice is a seven.
Seven takes you to the utility right
in the middle of the RN squares.
So you're most likely to land
on the R and the squares.
So someone else should own.
You should own the orange squares and
then build hotels on just the RN squares.
And then you'll win. Bam. That's monopoly.
After the talk I can answer
about any other game monopolies.
The easiest to understand.
So,
so then I started writing 10
ideas for these other people.
So I wrote 20 emails or I really
researched each person. I said,
here's 10 ideas for your business.
10 I didn't ask for a cup of coffee.
I didn't ask for anything with
one guy wrote, here's 10 ideas.
He was a well known writers, still is
a 10 ideas articles about investing.
You should write with another person.
Big Hedge fund manager. I said,
here's 10 pieces of software
that you could use. I,
we have very similar
stylistic way of investing.
Here's 10 pieces of
software for you for all.
Even teach your employees how
to use the software they work.
Here's the my personal track record
with them. You could have them.
And another person, I
wrote 10 ideas for him. Uh,
and out of those 23 people responded,
you still get a very low response rate,
but you're,
but you're giving now instead of trying
to take ideas are all about giving.
He always want to help people with
each idea. So the, the writer said,
these are great ideas.
Why don't you write them for us?
So I started writing for his website.
It was Jim Cramer.
We started writing for the, for his
website, the street.com and I beat,
and then I got a book deal based on
what I was writing because it was very
different type of stuff and
that, and I wrote, you know,
seven or eight books about investing
after that and I've been on CNBC a billion
times. Jim Cramer was about
to call him my podcast again,
so you build a relationship
over over decades.
Another person who responded
was this big hedge fund manager.
He invited me over for lunch,
we got to know each other and he ended
up personally investing money with me and
then I started my hedge fund and then
the third person who responded and said,
yeah, sure I'll have, let's have
lunch and talk about these ideas.
I never responded to him.
12 years later I hit reply on
that exact same email and I said,
hey, can you come on my
podcast instead of lunch?
This is 2014 I hit reply on that
email instead of 20 instead of 2002 he
responded and said,
sure.
It's the only pockets he's ever been
on the seem to lab who wrote fooled by
randomness,
Black Swan antifragile uh,
and now he's coming Wednesday called
on my podcasts again in February. So,
so he's never been ever been
on any other podcasts. So it's,
that's another thing I typically do is
I'll go through my emails from 10 years
ago and I have 280,000 unread emails.
So I'll hit reply on on an email from
2007 and just answer as if I got the email
yesterday and no one has ever not
responded to that way of getting back in
touch. You know how sometimes you
don't get back in touch with someone,
you feel really bad about it.
Wait 10 and then reply
life hack number eight, 67.
So, uh, so this, this idea,
so I haven't stopped doing it since
2002 every single day I'll write down 10
ideas up, but then sometimes people say,
sorry if I'm answering very long. No,
it's great, but, but you asked
about the micro steps you take.
Sometimes people say, Oh, I
did. Ideas are a dime a dozen.
Execution is everything. People
don't realize execution is a subset.
Execution ideas are a
subset of actual ideas.
So I'll give an example that involves
Google and and particularly android.
I was that uh,
uh,
a birthday dinner and our friend of mine
was there with his brand new girlfriend
and I said, oh, you guys look
really cute together. And they said,
oh, we just had the conversation,
we're going steady now. And I'm like,
do people still say that going steady?
Like if that upgrade and,
and he said, yeah, we even
deleted are dating apps.
So I had an idea of the next day on my,
I did an a a 10 app ideas and one of the
ideas was let's make a going steady app
and are going steady app. Would you agree
that you download the going steady app?
You Bro,
you linked to each other.
You both say we're going steady and it
deletes all the dating apps on both bones
and it keeps track of all
the dating apps out there.
Just in case there are new ones.
And if the other side ever let downloads
a dating app or does anything tricky,
we figured it all out. The other person
gets informed. And so I wrote down,
what's the 10 execute?
So then the next day I wrote here
is the 10 mini execution steps.
It's not like, oh, uh,
how will I raise VC funding for this APP?
That's the stupidest thing of all.
You don't,
you don't think of a ways to help
people and then immediately say,
give me money to help people.
You need to show that you're a qualified,
a good person to, to help
people. So I thought,
what are the 10 next steps in execution
that I can do to create this app?
So I went on freelance.com and
I specked out the whole app.
So first I specked out the
whole app actually. I said,
this is what the front screen looks like.
This is what the sub screens look like.
Here's how you log on, here's how
to people connect to each other.
Here's how to people message each other.
Here's the list of Apps I want to watch
out for. And then I expect it out.
And on freelance.com I
got 10 companies from us,
India and Malaysia, the big
three as we call them. And uh,
that was a joke. But, uh, uh,
uh, add, everybody said, oh,
we'll do it for $1,000 or $2,000 or $500.
And then I called up each one and I said,
the one question I have that I don't
know and I can't figure it out with my
research,
the one question I have wa is can android
and Ios from within an APP find the
other ad? Ooh. See what
other apps are on the phone?
It turns out android,
yes. Ios. No. And since,
uh, many, you know, I didn't want to
just do it for one operating system.
I didn't do that idea even though I'm
absolutely sure it would have been a huge
hit.
But uh,
but here's a case where I had the idea
I had the execution ideas I executed on.
They were all,
it took me three hours,
two hours from beginning to end to
figure out t to Spec out the site, the,
the APP. Talk to at advertise it to
actually find developers, call them,
figure out what my main question was,
ask them and determine it was not
a good idea, a good enough idea.
So execution is not as
hard as people think,
but you still have to be good at idea
generation to be good at execution idea
generation. So you know what those
micro execution steps are. Now,
if anyone could help me figure out how
to do from within IOS APP to see the
other Ios apps we're in business.
But that's kind of an example of, you
know, ideas can lead to execution.
They're not separate. It's not that
execution is everything, ideas or nothing.
They're there, they're
interwoven and connected. Yes.
That was my huge response
to that question.
Great answer. Thank you. Um,
so you've had these kind of wild financial
swings that you just describing your
life, um, and it, it's, uh, been
kind of a volatile path for you.
How is that changed your philosophy
and how have things like minimalism and
stoicism and kind of non attachment
to material things and money kind of
informed the way you think now?
Yeah. So, so, uh, I
mean it's really, I see,
I see what I call failure porn
all over the Internet now.
Like, oh, I failed. So my next thing
will be a success. Oh, I failed.
Here's 10 things I learned.
X Sorta as tells me that they didn't
quite fail because failure is really
insanely painful and difficult. You know,
some failures more than others, but,
um, and it's really unpleasant. It's
an unpleasant feeling in your stomach.
You feel like, you know, just
because you hit rock bottom,
it doesn't mean you're not going to go
even lower. Most people I know who say,
well, I hit bottom here and
then if I drill, like on my
podcast, people will say,
I hit rock bottom here. And I'm
like, really? Well, what happened?
Where were you six months
later? And they were like, well,
then I was in the street with a
needle out of my elbow. Oh, okay.
That sounds like more like rock
bottom to me. Um, and uh, uh,
so it's really,
it's really painful,
but I think that's what really
focused me on at the end of the day.
I really, I really, and I say
this to my daughters to a,
I ask them to ask themselves,
who have I helped today?
Because if you've helped,
that means you have some energy that,
and that means you have ideas and so on.
But really I,
I make sure I check the list every
day. Physical health, emotional health,
creative or idea health and spiritual
health and the spiritual health. Again,
can I deal with the inevitable things
that I can't control? Like, oh,
this business failed. You know, it's
over. I mean, there was one day,
can I tell a story again? We
have time. Yeah, go for it.
So there's one day I was
on the set of a TV show,
some friends of mine who
created this TV show and uh,
they invited me to watch
the pilot being filmed.
And like one of my favorite
directors was filming the pilot.
Some of my favorite
actors were in the show,
having the best day I was on the board
of a company and my shares in this
company,
we were worth millions of dollars.
And I get this message
in the middle of the day,
emergency board meeting and I'm thinking,
great,
the company got sold,
I'm going to finally cash in
on the shares and I'm going to,
it's going to be great.
And um,
I get on the board and I mean, I got on
the call and it was announced right away.
Well,
our largest shareholder,
he just told us he owes
$90 million to the IRS.
He never disclosed that before.
Uh, we had to tell our bank,
our bank has fired us as the management
team except for this one board meeting.
They're going to pick apart the company
and just sell it in pieces to their
other customers. Uh, it was a billion
revenue company and we're going to sell,
they're going to sell off each region,
um,
and dissolve the company just so
that they can make their money back.
We owed them like 15 million,
which was nothing really for a billion
revenue company, but it was, you know, we,
this was the rule and a,
within days my shares went from being
worth millions to be worth zero.
And I try it on the board,
like on the call,
how about I buy the pieces or have I
find buyers for each piece of the company
or have it, I've raised money and we just
pay back the bank. And they were like,
everything I said,
it was just too late.
They've already locked us out
of the offices. It's over. And,
and now I get off the phone and now my
favorite actor is filming this amazing
scene.
If I even told you the scene and you've
seen the show and you've seen the scene,
and, and, and my, my favorite director,
he's directed like
limitless. He directed, um,
all these great movies and uh,
and I just figured, you know what,
I'm in the middle of nowhere. Uh,
I just lost millions of dollars,
but I'm on this as the person. I'm gonna
ever on the set of a TV show like this.
I'm just going to enjoy
the rest of the day.
And so I spent the next eight hours
asking questions to the directors,
the writers, the actors. Uh, and a
few months later I explained to the,
one of the writers what had happened
that day and they were like, oh my gosh,
you were the last one
to leave. You were, uh,
asking questions all day long and
enjoying it. And, uh, you know,
I think it's really important and like I
couldn't control anymore that situation
and I knew I wasn't going to sleep at
night cause I was going to be depressed
and anxious, but I figured, okay,
right now I'm here and I'm never
going to get this chance again.
We only live one life and I'm gonna
learn a lot and I'm going to take what I
learned into,
into new things and new opportunities.
And I decided to focus on that and not
think about this negative thing until I,
I made an appointment to think about it
later with myself when I got home. And,
and that's how I acted in the
day. And I think, you know,
not wallowing and things you can't
control is a very important part of um,
you know, moving forward
and making progress in life.
Otherwise it will just be
always held back by these,
these negative events you can't control.
Yeah.
And how do you use failure
to hack the 10,000 hour rule?
So for those of you that don't know,
Malcolm Gladwell wrote a book called
outliers about 10,000 hours required to,
or this is just part of the book,
10,000 hours required to be
really great at any skill. Um,
and it does make you a
little kind of defeatist.
It makes you think you don't have to
be Mozart or Andre Agassi to get really
good at a certain scale. So how do you
use failure to kind of short circuit that?
Yeah, so that's, that's a great question.
So anytime you want to get good at
something, I don't know how old, uh,
many of you are.
Bomb 49 I'm going to be 50 in a month.
And just as an example,
over the past year I've gotten somewhat
obsessed with doing standup comedy.
So I, I do stand up comedy
at different clubs, uh,
all around New York.
I'm doing Chicago next week.
I go up three to six times a week.
And um,
and it's a scary thing.
It's the scariest thing and it's the
hardest skill I've ever had to learn.
And I've learned many different
skills in my life, uh,
that are considered hard skills.
And,
and I talked to a lot of comedians
and they're all like, yeah, 20 years,
15 to 20 years is if you
watched a special on Netflix,
chances are that comedian you're watching
has been doing it for at least 15,
probably more like 20 or 25 years.
And I'm thinking to myself, uh,
oh my gosh, I want to do this in a
year. I don't want to do it in WWE.
I don't want to be doing
this when I'm 70 years old.
And it's so painful because you're,
yeah,
you're making people laugh,
but before you go on,
you're really nervous and sometimes you
bomb and sometimes you get heckled and
sometimes you feel really awful afterwards
and there's so many sub skills you
need to learn.
It's not just about telling a good joke,
there's maybe 50 different sub skills.
And by way of comparison,
I'd say becoming a chess master,
maybe there's 20 different mutually
exclusive sub skills you have to learn and
master to become an overall
chess master with comedy.
I would say there's about
50 subscales. And so, um,
part of this is related to
here. I said to myself, well,
I've been doing all these pie.
I've done 300 podcasts with
amazing peak peak performers,
the best performers in the world
at what they do. Again, I'll again,
I'll mention Tony Hawk at skateboarding
or Garry Kasparov at chess or,
uh, astro teller from Google
has been on my podcast. Um,
Sara Blakely is probably the only self,
made a female billionaire on the
Forbes list who mentored spanx.
She's been on my podcast area and a
Huffington, uh, so many great writers,
actors, Comedians,
athletes, entrepreneurs,
Richard Branson was just on and so,
but on the 10,000 hour rule specifically,
I also had on Anders Ericsson who
Malcolm Gladwell in his book outliers,
he's quoting Anders Ericsson and the
10,000 hour rule. So I wanted to know.
So I invited Anders Ericsson on
Anders Eriksson broke it down.
It's not quite 10,000 hours.
That was just a catchy phrase that
was used in the book for some people,
10,000 hours. For others it
wasn't. Um, he said the Beatles,
which was the example in
the book, the Beatles, uh,
performed 24 hours a day.
I had these German porn clubs before.
They were famous just, and that was
how they got their 10,000 hours.
Was the example.
Glad will use a now Anders
Ericsson thought it was more
like 4,000 hours when he
calculated it out. So I figured, okay,
it might not be 10,000 hours for everybody
if you have some talent and so on,
although Erikson doesn't
believe in, in talent. And uh,
uh,
then I started asking everybody
what were common denominators in,
um,
your 10,000 hours in your,
in your move towards world excellence.
And there's a couple of ways that you
can kind of hack the 10,000 hours and an
important one,
I'll get to failure in a second,
but an important one is building up
a strong community of friends who are
already successful in that subculture.
So anything you want to get good at,
let's do you want to get good at tennis.
There's already a subculture.
Like if you just show up at the
professional tennis courts or whatever,
nobody's going to talk to you
because they don't know who you are.
And they're already friends
with all the other pros.
They don't want to talk
with the weaker players.
But if you can somehow figure out how
to be friends with all the strong people
in the space that you want
to get good at, um, that's,
you can literally skip five to eight
years of work because they know everything
you're doing wrong.
And they could just look at what you're
doing and they say this, this, this, this,
you're doing wrong. So as an example, I
had a pink, like many people probably,
I had a ping pong table in
my basement when I was a kid.
I played ping pong every day when I,
the whole time I was growing up and
I've played ping pong for 40 years.
Then I took ping pong lessons a few
months ago from a Worldclass Ping Pong
player.
Like he's world champion level.
100% of the things I was doing were wrong.
So the way I held a racket,
the way I swung, the
way I did, the backend,
the racket itself, uh, the way I stood,
even the way I kept score was wrong.
I didn't even know,
I didn't even know, I didn't even
know the rules of pink. So, so,
so just by taking a few lessons,
I immediately was like much,
much better than I was
for 40 entire years.
And so that's the importance of
being around. You're the, you,
there's, let's say you're the average
of the five people around you. Well,
if everybody around you
is a chess grandmaster,
you're going to much more easily be a
chess grandmaster as opposed to just
playing bad people all day. And you
know that's true for everything in life.
So that's,
that's one fast way to hack a good,
let's say it really is 10,000 hours,
although I think it's less.
That's a way to hack like at least four
or 5,000 hours out of that 10,000 hours.
Now failure is extremely important.
So let's say comedy,
I go up on stage and one time I go
up and I used the same exact joke and
everybody laughs the second time I
bought up on stage and nobody laughs.
In fact,
I might even get heckled and I have videos
of both I video tape all the times I
go up on stage where most of the
times I go up on stage. So I'll,
I'll take the videos and I'll show
it to several comedians and I'll say,
what is the difference between these
two videos? I don't understand.
I'm not seeing something.
But they've been doing it 20 years.
So they instantly see many,
many things that I don't see.
I'm completely blind.
For me,
I'm only asking is the joke funny
or not for them, they're asking,
how are you holding the microphone?
How are you moving around the stage?
What does your voice sound like? Are
there more men than women in the audience?
Are there more older people than
younger people in the audience?
Are there more tourists or
non tourists in the audience?
Do you have a friend in the audience who
happens to be the first one laughing?
Um,
there's so many things they're
looking at that uh, they might say,
you may seem,
you may think you said the same joke,
but it's actually a different
joke in these various ways.
You switch these two words or you took
two sips of water instead of one sip of
water in the middle of that joke.
That was one response that was completely
a hundred percent the difference.
The reason why the same joke was funny
one time and not funding the other is
that in the middle of the joke I took
two sips of water instead of one sip of
water.
And there was a reason why the timing
created too much tension on the two sips
of water versus the ones who are,
but it took a professional
comedian to tell me that now. So,
so again,
failure allows you to ask,
you know, you can say, oh, I
failed the best, I'm going to quit.
And that's what most people do.
Anything that's hard,
anything that's worth doing is hard else.
Everybody would be a success
in everything. So everything
worth doing is very,
very difficult.
So you're going to fail in big ways
and you're going to fail in little ways
every single day. Every single time I go
onstage, I fail at something. And, um,
and I'm just speaking specifically about
comedy. I can be talking about chess.
I could be talking about business and
business. There are so many sub skills,
again are probably say there's about 30
different sub skills that you have to
master with each one to be, to make
money for yourself. Um, but I'll,
I'll just stick to the common
example for a second. Um, uh,
you know, I had one case where, oh,
but this is why it's important to be
the question is how do you get to get
professional comedians? Uh,
look at my little stupid videos.
They don't want me to be better.
They don't want an extra person
saying he's a he or she is a comedian.
But I,
because of my business expertise,
I bought part of the comedy club
and that I performed at the most.
So now I get to talk to,
and I have a podcast
so I could talk to any,
almost any comedian I want to talk to.
And right in the middle of my podcast, oh,
this is part of the bog guys. Look at
these two videos of me doing comedy.
Tell me where I went wrong.
And it's a great way to get feedback.
And so I've figured out how
to hack getting professionals
to look at these mini
failures I do along the
way and give me help.
So most people wouldn't even to guess
what the most important skill is.
In comedy, you would think the obvious,
which is humor. Now, by the way,
humor itself is divided into a
bunch of different sub skills.
Like how you write a,
a punchline is different than how
you tell a funny story. Public,
a funny story in public speaking,
it doesn't work.
Telling the same story in stand up comedy,
no one will laugh and kind of money.
Everyone will laugh and
public speaking. So, uh,
but the most important skill that many
comedians have told me is not humor but
likability. And so that's why you
see many comics who are unknown.
They get on stage and they started
talking to the audience where you're from,
where they say, I grew up and I was
bullied and here's the worst bullying.
And then they tried to
make a joke at the end,
but they're self deprecating
in the beginning. So you,
the audience can relate a little bit. Um,
that's only one way to build likability.
There's other ways to build likability
and you're learning all those sub skills.
But like on business, I'll give you a
very important set of sub skills. So,
obviously product development is
an important sub skill in business.
But most people think that's the only
skill. Oh, if we build a good product,
people buy the product. Vcs will invest
in money. Most. But I, I've done, uh,
hundreds of angel
investments at this point.
I'll tell you an incredibly important
skill that is different from any other
skill in business.
But I won't invest unless I see the CEO
and maybe the other investors have this
skill. It's really hard to
sell your company. So selling,
nobody wants to write you a
check that will make you rich.
Nobody wakes up in the morning and says,
you know what?
Today I'm going to make Jesse Rich.
Nobody has ever woken up and said
that in their lives. It's unfortunate.
No one has said it about
anybody. I'm so, so,
so having the ability to
convince somebody else.
Of course there is southern company
is not about making somebody rich.
But the reality is it is.
And so you ha so there's all sorts of
ways you have to have this skill to
convince people to buy your company.
And that's 100% different skill than
raising money, than selling the products.
Then managing employees, then sales, the
negotiations, then building a product.
All of these skills are important.
Dealing with a landlord is almost as an
important skill as developing a product,
uh, for various reasons that most
people would suspect. For instance,
if Google bought a company
and I had a landlord,
my landlord has to approve that Goebbels,
the new tenant instead of me.
And if the landlord says, no,
you can't sell your company.
So there's all these little things that
most people don't think about when they
start a company.
And I've seen so many,
it's been the cause of so many failures
of mine investing in the wrong set of
skills. Uh, and now I ha
I have one trick for it,
which is I only invest in
alongside people smarter than me.
So I outsource my thinking to people
who have big research teams doing due
diligence. And ideally the CEO has
built and sold the company before.
So I know he's got the whole
skillset and so on. So,
but these are some ways in
which failure has taught me.
And I'll just give you one quote from,
so ray Dalio was on my podcast last week.
We haven't released the
podcast yet, but, um,
he is the founder and still runs
the largest hedge fund in the world,
is worth about, you know, he's
worth tens of billions. Uh, he,
he said in the podcast,
pain plus reflection equals progress.
And that's a very valuable quote
relating to all, all how, you know,
how you hack these,
these 10,000 hours.
Yeah. I want to get to Q and
a and an a second real quick.
I want to couple two questions. Sure.
Oh, I promise I'll answer more. No,
you're all good. Um, so
the two questions are, uh,
what's your favorite podcasts
you've ever done and why?
And then the second question is,
what's your favorite life hack a,
or to put it a different way,
what's the one thing these people can
do that will have the greatest kind of
multiplicative effect, positive
effect on their, on their life,
whether it's sleep or
whatever. So, sure. All right.
So, uh, the, the, the greatest,
the best podcasts I've ever done.
It's really hard to answer cause I,
I learned so much from all
of these amazing people.
Like I dunno how many people grew up
on Judy Blume books. For instance.
Like I grew up reading,
Judy Blume was the best
children's writer in the 1970s.
You sold 150 million copies of her books.
And I would never have imagined when I
was in fifth grade or sixth grade that
one day I was going to talk to Judy bloom.
Like that was an amazing moment for me.
I know it doesn't like
the most amazing thing,
but usually the best pockets I've ever
had is my last podcast cause that's the
one that's still so fresh in my memory.
And I'm thinking about it and I'm thinking
about the things they say. So again,
Ray Dalia was the, the
last one I did, but I'll,
I'll talk about the worst podcast I
ever did and what I learned from it. So,
uh, this was in 2014 I did
this podcast with, um, the,
the rapper Biz Markie to know Biz
Markie. He did that song, just a friend.
It's a kind of like a popular
song. And I said to him, uh,
what's it like that everybody
knows you primarily,
you've done a lot of songs and
albums and things in your life,
but everybody primarily
knows you from just a friend.
And he was very upset. He said, I've
done much more than just a friend.
And I said, that's true, but two
things I want to point out. One,
if I go to your website,
the e this song immediately
starts playing just,
and if I, if, if I were to go to
China right now and ask anybody,
do you know who Biz Markie is?
If they know you at all,
they're going to sing just
to Fred. So he's like, yeah,
but I did Gaba, Gaba, Gaba,
and Nickelodeon. And I did this song,
that song, and he hung up on me. And um,
so it's the only time I ever hung
up on me on a podcast. And so,
so I figured, okay, well it's not
so fun to just put this podcast up.
So what I did was I put,
I,
I had the audio engineer play the
podcast and then with another person,
we analyze what I did wrong
throughout this podcast.
So we kept having the engineer rewind,
fast forward, rewind, fast forward.
And we kept commenting how I could've
done a better job when this podcast,
so that, so I made it like a metal
podcast about doing this bad podcast.
So every,
everything is content,
every everything, you
know, process is art.
Just as much as the outcome.
The process of,
of the final outcome is artistic
in and of itself. You know, I,
we had scheduled at one point for
the podcast, Jordan Belfort, who's,
uh, you know, he's famous for being the
wolf of Wall Street. He's a criminal.
He wouldn't spend time in jail and
he's not, he's, he did his time,
so I shouldn't say he was a criminally,
he spent time in jail,
Leonardo Dicaprio place him in the movie.
But before the podcast,
he asked, slowly time I was ever asked
this, he asks his publicity team,
I shouldn't say he,
his publicity team said,
you need to submit all the questions
in advance. And I said, no,
that's like Soviet Russia did that.
Like,
I'm not doing that and I'm going to
ask him whatever I want to ask him and
listen to my podcast.
I'm never mean to anybody on my pocket.
It's not like I'm trying to trap somebody.
So chose me.
They didn't do their work on my podcast
and, and I didn't want to in any way.
It wasn't like he was a peak performer.
The guy was a criminal.
So he didn't want to, I didn't want
to have him on my podcast again.
He did his time. Not a criminal. I
have to say that legally. But, um,
but so was that a failure or a success?
Well,
I wrote an article mentioning that
I turned process into content.
It was an article that appeared
on 20 different platforms,
got tens of thousands of views.
And I don't think he's a bad guy.
He could have just been as
publicity team. I have no idea. But,
but everything I do that doesn't work out.
I always figure out how do I take this
process and turn it into art in some
other way or turn it into a business or
a turn it into an opportunity or turn it
into an idea for somebody else.
So I always repeat that to myself every
day processes art because whatever we
do, however we falter, even if
I completely fail, for instance,
at comedy,
the process of failing,
like I've written about bombing and just
the process of how you deal with that
becomes art becomes, and for me, art,
I write for for so many different things
and for so many different reasons,
you know, becomes connected to all my
other businesses and my all, you know.
So now, not only, not only am I
writing about bombing and comedy,
but for one group of my readers,
I'm writing about failure and another
group of readers I'm writing about,
here's the metalanguage
of how to learn anything.
And part of the process of me learning
something that's a hard skill.
It doesn't matter what the skill is.
So there's so many different levels.
When you treat processes, art, there's
so many different ways you can,
you can use that to create new works of
art that have nothing to do with how you
started.
So that's incredibly valuable.
So I think that was the answer
to what's my theory of podcasts.
So I took that Biz Markie experience and
I made art out of it in a different way
than was than I had initially expected.
And then your second question was
lifehack favorite one. Okay. I,
and this happened to me
even yesterday. Uh, uh,
somebody comes up to me and says,
I read that 10 night year at your
suggestion of doing 10 ideas a day.
I thought it was nothing. You know,
the best life hacks are not like, oh,
inject this super soldier serum into your
arm and you're going to become captain
America. Like the best life hacks are
simple ones that people don't realize.
The compound effect of it
over time becomes a miracle.
And so writing 10 ideas a day improves
your idea muscle and strengthens your
idea muscle 1% a day.
1% a day compounded is 3800% a year,
billions of percent over 10 years.
So you're going to be like,
your ability to compete against everyone
else becomes so powerful over time,
even over the course of a year,
even look over the course of three months.
If you just write 10 ideas a day,
and someone came up to me and
told me this yesterday, he said,
I didn't think this would be anything.
I figure I'll try it for a couple of
weeks. And he said it was like magic.
What happened? It'll create so many
opportunities. It will create so many,
whether it's businesses or
skills or relationships,
or if you want to meet your
future wife or husband,
it's this one thing, and I'm not, I'm
not even advising people to do it.
This is what it's done for me and it's,
it's in.
It's the result of that have been
incredible. Then number two, of course,
is um,
uh,
making sure no toxic people
are in your life. You cannot,
you cannot cure a toxic person.
You could only remove yourself from their
presence and so be around people you
love and who love you. I know it
sounds corny or Cliche, but the,
you know, I, he even described it
in a simple way as a hack, you know,
to take between four and 8,000
hours out of the 10,000 hour rule.
It's so incredibly
important. Uh, uh, you know,
those two things alone are,
are, if you just do that,
your life's going to change
almost overnight. And, you know,
we keep toxic people in our
lives all the time. We think, oh,
I have to deal with this person because
they're my cousin or my neighbor,
or they're my friend since,
since high school. Well,
let me tell you something
that's important about that.
The guy who lives in another
town who you never see,
that's never the toxic
person in your life.
It's always the people close to you that
you think you can't get away from the
toxic people in your life. And that's the
hard thing for people to realize. Oh No,
that's my, my grandma.
I can't avoid her. Well,
I'm sorry. That's, you can't have
taught you only live one life.
Are you going to spend a big percentage
of it with somebody who is going to ruin
your life? Anyway, that's, I don't
want to end on a negative note though.
Uh,
so I won't say the 10 ideas a day and
being around people you love and who love
you,
that hacks really the 10,000 hour rule
because that allows you to take failure
and just fling yourself onto your idea
machine and onto these people who love
you and they are the safety net
that will bounce you back up.
Awesome. Do you guys
have any questions? Yeah.
You alluded to family and I was just
wondering in these tumultuous ups and
downs,
how it affected your children or how did
you protect them or was that part of,
did you want them to be part
of that and then, um, yeah,
that's great question.
So the question is, um,
when I was having these ups and downs
and they happen maybe four or five times,
let's say three,
where I went completely broke to
the point where I lost a home.
We'll had tax issues.
You know,
was really depressed and suicidal.
Um,
and then there were other times
kind of in between. And, uh,
how did this affect my family,
particularly my children's,
I had two daughters and now they're older.
Um,
I suppose ultimately, um, they would
know better than me how it affected them,
but I very hard to um,
be positive around them and not let them
see how things were affecting me and
tried to put things in the best possible
light. I suppose that to some extent,
having two daughters for me personally,
uh,
inspired me on a couple of ways to keep
going for their sake and to show them
that this is as an,
you can't,
you can't teach by telling somebody do
this. You could only teach by example.
And I hope,
I don't know what the final result
will be there 18 and 15 now,
but I hope that by examples for all
these years they turn out to be,
and so far so good,
they turned out to be good adults,
but I always tried to
buffer them from everything.
I'm sure it worked to some extent.
It didn't work for others.
Maybe in some ways they're more anxious
about things than I, than I realized.
But again, time will tell you. I,
I did think of it though
and being aware of it is,
is the first solution and just doing the
best you can is after that is important.
But I wouldn't like, I wouldn't like
shake them and say, you're two years old,
we're going broke.
I would never do anything like that.
I did get for better or for worse.
I,
we are mother and I did
get divorced though.
I don't know if it was
related to all my failures,
but I certainly wouldn't want to
be married to me at that point. So
any other question? Yeah. Hold on one sec.
Uh, in 2018, what's your
thoughts on going to college?
2018. What's my thoughts are
going on, going to college,
the same as my thoughts in 2005.
So in 2005,
I was a columnist for the
Financial Times and um,
I wrote this article why nobody
should ever go to college again.
And at the time I was the
only person saying it. Um,
and there was lots of people
trashing me on different blogs.
I actually lost some good
friendships over this. And um,
now I think it's a more viable discussion,
right?
I think people can't have this discussion
without being slaughtered by everybody
else. But, um, the way I see it is
in college so many,
you know,
tuitions have gone up faster than
inflation every single year since 1977,
but every single year there hasn't been
one year where inflation went up higher
then tuitions. And in part that's
because the government backs, you know,
we'll lend you money against your tuition
and it's the one kind of loan you,
you can't get rid of in a bankruptcy.
So of course,
let's give it to every 18 year old
who's totally unqualified to borrow this
money. So you create
this skewed, you know,
there's already this problem
in, in society where, you know,
rich people get certain benefits.
I don't mean to sound,
this is not a political bias.
This is the truth.
Rich people have certain
benefits and poor people don't,
and a d and that divide
gets greater and greater.
And that's why we have all this political
strife right now more than ever before.
We have all these,
these political enemies like half of
Facebook hates the other half of Facebook
and vice versa because of
these political problems.
And uh,
I think in part it's created by
some kids go to Harvard and they,
and they see their parents can pay for
it and other kids borrow $200,000 to go
to a worse school.
And meanwhile,
there's plenty of places online
to learn faster and better.
There's so many online
educational resources to learn
more than you would have
learned in college that
I don't understand why,
why 100% of kids don't just learn for
free better and start making money and
don't go into debt? It seems to me like
a no brainer. Just thinking about it now,
I have an 18 year old and so
she was a senior last year,
which foreshadowing and
I had, I kept saying to her
throughout her whole high school,
we need to have this conversation.
You're not going to college.
And she would just, which wasn't really a
conversation, right? It's like a command.
And she would literally just turn around
and start walking away. And I would say,
don't walk away from me.
It's like the only time I've ever got
angry about her was like on the topic of
college. So I'm like, don't walk away
from me. We're in the middle of a mall.
I want to argue with you in front
of all these people. And uh, Eh,
cause that's the only time we spend
time together was when she was,
I would take her shopping and uh,
you know,
but I realized, I realized
several things. One is,
you know,
a,
I wasn't being a very good father if she
didn't feel comfortable having a very
basic conversation with me.
So again,
I had to parent by example and show
openmindedness and listen to her,
what she wanted to do with her life
and offer her a real alternatives.
I even wrote a book,
bought 40 alternatives to college and I
self published it and she did not read
the book.
Um,
but so one time I said to her,
look, what do you want to be?
And she,
I know she's going to see this on a video,
but she lied to me, I suspect. And she
said, oh, I want to be a neurobiologist.
And I'm like,
you have never once spoken to me about
anything relating to neuro or biology or
any igg or any nerve.
You're just not interested in this. You
want to, you're interested in chemistry,
are you interested in statistics?
So you understand understanding all of
these sub things are going to have to
learn. And she's like,
yeah, yeah, I'm interested.
And so I would buy her neuro biology
books. Did you read it? Never read it.
So, um, but I knew she, since
she was in kindergarten,
she's been in every single performance
in her school ever. Like, so I'm like,
you want to be an actor?
Why don't you,
why don't you act?
And I'm like,
well you have to go to college to go
major in agony. I'm like, no, you don't.
The first skill had acting
as learning how to audition.
So here's what we're going to do.
This is what I offered her.
I am going to give you in cash.
It's like a brick of cash,
the tuition I would have paid to
that school. You're going to, um,
the president of that school.
Just a great to go out on the podcast
so I shouldn't make fun of it.
And uh,
and all you have to do is watch
a movie with me every morning.
We'll pick a different movie every day.
Just have to watch one movie with me
every morning and then spend the rest of
the day going on auditions because
you'll learn how to, you'll learn a,
if you like the lifestyle,
be,
you'll learn how to get better at
auditions when you're 18 instead of when
you're 23. Um, see you won't have
any kind of debt or you know,
you were saying I would have saved
an enormous amount of money. Uh,
and you'll just be that much
ahead of all your peers.
You'll learn so much more about acting.
Actually being in New York, I have no,
I've had like Broadway producers and
other producers on my podcast is one call
for me to get you. Oh, this is,
that's the real advantage you have.
And might as well take advantage
of it. And she said, no.
Uh, instead she decided to go to
college, which she's enjoying very much.
And so I'm against it and
she's an adult and I figured,
okay, I still want to, I don't know.
I don't know if I did the
right thing or the wrong thing,
but I wanted to be supportive of her.
Now she's deciding what to major in,
at least major in acting.
So you learn a real skill that you're
interested in and not learn some something
like neurobiology, which I know
you're not interested, it's not,
it's not like being a neuroscientist
is a fall back profession. You know,
just learn an actual skill.
It's very hard to learn acting.
And then you could see if you want to
be an actor and come to New York now
people will say, well what
if, uh, you know, what if,
what's she going to do later on
if it doesn't work out as acting?
Does anyone here, actually this
is a different sort of place,
but most people I know don't actually
do what they learned in college.
I was a computer science major.
I went to Grad School of computer science.
And then my first real job
doing computer programming,
I was so bad at programming.
I had to go to remedial programming
classes for two months just to be at the
lowest level of my job at programming.
I went to an ivy league undergraduate
school for computer science and I went to
a top two or three graduate school
for computer science. Again,
many employees that are here
went to the same graduate school.
I know they were in my class and uh,
it didn't help me.
Only the real world helps you.
So that's my 2 cents on 2018 pay.
Ya Anybody? No, don't go to, uh,
let's pass the mic over there possible.
Um,
what's your biggest insight
on a relationship and dating
that most people don't
realize?
Biggest insight on relationship and dating
that most people don't realize and to
qualify,
I'm really not an expert,
but I will tell you a couple of
things I've learned through failure.
And then a couple of things I'm trying
to guess. Uh, as I go along, first off,
I don't know if you remember this book
of roles. It was written in the 90s,
sold 3 million copies. Um, great book. Uh,
these two women wrote about dating.
They were all my podcast recently and I'm
not going to discuss their Bob, but um,
they gave me advice and bear
advice to me was do online dating.
And I said, no, I'm never going to
do online dating. And they said,
why not? And I said, you know,
everything is related to supply
and demand. The value of how you,
of how you look at something is
always related to supply and demand.
I sort of feel for me personally,
that online dating creates this
illusion of infinite supply.
So it reduces the value
for me of a relationship,
a long term relationship. Now, short
term, who knows? That's not what I go for.
I go for our longterm and for me,
I feel like having just the feeling of
infant and supply will, oh, I don't,
this person doesn't like Chinese food.
Swipe out onto the next one. So this,
this, this value I place on
really getting to know somebody.
So I prefer, uh, uh, I,
I prefer meaning somebody through friends
or through some sort of interactions.
But, um, uh,
the other thing that's really
important is it's okay for PE.
You have to have anger compatibility
with who you go out with.
If you ever have that relationship where
you're arguing over here and they're
arguing over here and
somehow you're like trending,
I don't understand what you're saying.
You just said this,
but now you're saying like, you
don't, you're not compatible.
And the way you're arguing,
there's something completely,
some line of communication completely
off. Now, many people will say, well,
that happens in every relationship,
but I've seen plenty of relationships
where that never happens. And they,
they argue, and maybe they
argued for a serious argument,
but somehow they resolve it. So I think
anger compatibility is, is important.
The other thing, um, the
other thing I will say is,
uh, it's one thing when two people are
able to support each other through hard
times. If, if you're in a relationship
with somebody and they get sick, you're,
you help them through hard
times or they fail in business,
which happens to me regularly, you'd
help me through hard times. And um,
but that is not the
important thing to note.
The important thing to really ask is
does this other person helped me through
successful times?
So let's say you were dating somebody who,
I'll just use the actress
example. Oh, they say to you, uh,
I just got to acting gig.
I'm going to Costar and oceans 18 with
Brad Pitt and I've got a kit kiss Brad
Pitt in the middle of the movie.
Now,
if I think a really good thing is to
be supportive of them achieving their
dreams, you know, and they will
in turn will be supportive of you.
And that's a sign of an extremely healthy
relationship that will last forever.
And there's even studies that show that
that's the type of relationship that
will last forever,
even more so than the people who help
each other during hard times is the people
who support each other during
successful times. So I think,
I think that's really important.
And then finally I will quote
a good friend of mine. Um,
I've had both him and his
wife and my podcast. Uh,
basically he said to me,
the most important decision you'll ever
make for your career is who you decide
to spend the rest of your life with.
And I really do agree with that.
Who was that person? Uh,
so it's Brian Koppelman who
created it. He wrote rounders,
ocean's 13. Speaking of oceans, he wrote
one of my favorite movies, a solitary man.
He writes the TV show billions
and his wife Amy Koppelman,
she's written three excellent
novels. Uh, plus the movie.
I smile back starring Sarah
Silverman and they have a really,
they've been together forever.
They've really, they've it.
And he was the one that we
were giving a talk at a,
I was interviewing him at
another company and uh, uh,
he said this to me either in the talk
or maybe when we were on the plane.
I forget, but I remember it though. Do
you want to take the final question?
So I'm super curious about this
and I just felt like I had to ask.
So I was going to, first of all,
I was going to ask you like,
what are you most proud of? And then I
was like, no, I'm more curious about this.
And I'm lucky,
I'm most proud of speaking here at Google.
Awesome.
Google. Oh my God, I'm
speaking in. Thank you so much.
I'm speaking in front of the best
company in the world and, and,
and just to add to that, Google is
such a great, I'm going to interrupt.
You're asking your questions.
Is that okay on time or so Google,
there's one aspect of global that
is such an important lesson in life.
When you go to Google, what was
this one page website, right?
When you're the search engine,
I'm talking about google.com you go to
Google and Google has nothing on it.
There is nothing, there's nothing
there. It's if you want to,
but what you do is you type in,
Oh,
I want to learn about motorcycles
and Google will as fast as possible.
It'll literally say to you,
I don't know anything about motorcycles,
but we've determined for you.
Here's our 10 favorite sites
and 400 more if you want,
but here's the 10 favorite
sites about motorcycles.
Why don't you go to one of them?
And so they get you off of,
they measure success by how
you guys measure success,
by how fast the customer
leaves the website.
So now if you want to find out about,
I dunno,
tennis, uh, where do you go? Well,
I remember that other site,
google.com was so good at helping
me find out on motorcycles.
I'm going to go back to Google to find
out about tennis. So once the life lesson,
if you're the source and
you're willing to just, hey,
you don't have to give me any money.
You don't owe me anything.
You never even have to come back here.
Maybe this is the last
time you and I meet,
but I'm going to still give you my all
and send you to the best resources.
Who are you going to go back to?
You're going to go back to the source,
which is global. That's such a gift,
credit, wherever you can give ideas,
wherever you can always be the source,
be the be the Bank of knowledge and
information and giving and then everybody
comes back to you again and again.
And that's, and that's the goal.
That's why I'm so proud to speak here.
What's your question?
Ooh,
that was really nice.
My question and when I'm most
curious about is what is,
what is the story behind your hair?
Like honestly, no lie. The first,
the first article I ever read by you,
I was just like, wow, this person,
he looks very interesting and a little
funny looking like maybe I'll read this
article and see how it is. So,
uh, I'm just always been curious.
So I've always been curious
cause it makes you stand up.
I worked in a cubicle, I kept it,
had worn a suit or ball, went on TV.
I used to go on CNBC a lot.
I kept it short.
Now I work from home most of the time
and they don't really pay that much.
I just go a little wild.
So I had to do, you know,
most of the activities I do don't
really require me to, I don't know,
I'm not dressed up or anything. I have
only a few outfits to my name, you know,
for a long time I only had,
I would never have more than 15
possessions to my name. And, uh, I can,
I didn't really consider
myself a minimalist. I just
didn't want to own anything.
I didn't want to think about anything.
So I didn't want to think of
anything except the things I loved.
And it's just part of
that. I just, um, you know,
I just live the life I want to. I
want to live and nothing, I don't,
I don't need extra
frills, so, I dunno. No.
Anything you want to plug before
we go? No, I'm just happy.
I'm really super excited. You invited
me to be here. I'll, I'll promote your,
your dad's toolbox. Can I do that?
She shit tools is a great book. Uh,
I honestly, to be honest, I read the
second book, but I forget the title.
I have a really bad coming alive,
coming alive and great book. Uh,
I think we were planning on having
him on the podcast at some point.
Scrapebox I really enjoyed that.
I really enjoyed both, but I will,
can I say one more thing about memory and
is it related to gold? Gold too? Yeah.
So,
um,
I'm always constantly worried because I'm
preparing so much for podcasts and for
other things.
I really forget a lot of things.
I'll even be like out on a day and
I'll forget the name of the woman,
even if I've been dating her
for months. So, uh, which, so,
so one time I signed up for 23
in me, um, which is, you know,
indirectly I think Google was an investor
or Google ventures is, or I don't know,
there's some connection there. And, um, I,
I had the gene, I did the test, uh,
the DNA tests and I had the gene,
oh,
there's a little bit extra chance you
could have early onset Alzheimer's,
which is a BS statistic.
If you have a 0.001%,
20% more chance doesn't really mean
anything. It's not, it's how they always,
doctors always scare people. But, uh,
so I wrote to the CEO at the time
and I said, oh, there's all these,
I did some research.
There's all these foods you can eat
to delay the onset of Alzheimer's.
How about I write the,
um, the [inaudible],
which is like the gene, how about I
write the [inaudible] cookbook and,
uh, you know, recommending all
these, you know, Alzheimer's foods.
And she wrote back instantly that book
would be a bestseller. You know, why?
And I wrote back why, and she said, uh,
because no one would remember
if they had already, yeah.
Bought it. I gave, I gave credit to her.
Thank you so much for coming.
I appreciate it.
Yeah.