Thanks for joining us at this talks at
Google event to everyone here and on the
live stream and watching
the video recording.
We're lucky to be joined
today by Jordan Harbinger.
I missed the cue
means a lot means a lot.
So Jordan and he's the host of the
successful podcast, the art of charm,
which focuses on psychology,
performance, life and success.
And he's brought up a wide range of
people onto the show from celebrities to
subject matter experts in
the sciences and the arts.
He recently had Neil degrasse Tyson on,
which was pretty awesome episode,
I might say.
Definitely check that one out.
And he's going to be talking to us today
about building relationships and social
capital.
So some very interesting stuff.
And if we have time we might hear a
little bit about a story of how he was
kidnapped in Serbia. So we'll just leave
that, leave that to be expanded further.
So without further ado,
here's Jordan.
Thank you very much.
Got The second round.
Everybody was like on point with the
applause. I appreciate that a lot.
It's great to be speaking here at Google.
It's great to be speaking in front of
a room of people at all because a few
short years ago I was extremely
shy and shy isn't actually,
she's not even the word
for it actually at all.
It was more like crippling anxiety,
especially as a kid.
I hated being in school. I hated being
around other people. I don't know,
something like they're all looking at me.
I'm sure one or two of you in the audience
have seen or felt like that at some
point in your life,
especially when you're younger.
And so I started skipping school a lot
and it went a little something like this,
get up, get dressed, get on the bus,
go to school and then immediately show
up for maybe one class or try to show up
for a few classes or just
turn around and walk home.
And it wasn't the cool kind of skipping
school where you're going to fancy
restaurants and dancing on parade
floats like Ferris Bueller,
but the kind of skipping school where
your parents come home at 4:00 PM or 5:00
PM and finding playing video games
in your underwear. So that system,
the education thing,
the formal education thing really
wasn't working for me at all.
And I started to get my act together
a little bit when I was older in high
school slash college and I graduated
from the University of Michigan Undergrad
and my friends all had
bright futures ahead of them.
They were going to work at AOL,
which was a big deal at that point in
time and they were right heard of that and
other people were working in finance and
things like that and buying their newly
back in fashion, acid wash jeans
and heading off to New York.
And I wasn't really sure
what I wanted to do.
I needed a little bit more
time to figure it out.
I'm sure we've all heard that phrase
or use that phrase before as well.
And so one day I got a bright and
early because I needed a new disc man.
The one with anti-skid because when your
roller blading, that's what you need.
Otherwise it bumps around
all over the place.
And I think I just ripped space
time with that 98 reference there.
But you need to have the mega base,
you need to have the anti skip.
And frankly I eat at 2:00 PM was about
the time I rolled in because it was
college.
So Brighton early is a relative term,
but I started talking with the guy
that worked at best buy and he said,
you know a lot about this stuff. You
know, what are you doing after college?
And I thought,
well you're looking at it man,
this is what I'm doing right now and
maybe I should work here for the summer.
I know how to fix computers and how to
build computers. I can install software,
remove software.
This is the late nineties or early
two thousands at this point I think.
And this is a perfect job for me,
right?
I can easily fall into into this
field. And he said, soy, your role man,
you know you have to work selling music,
cds and things like that.
The remnants of the cassette section
at best buy before you can move up to
computer repair and customer service.
So all my friends with
their bright futures,
I saw my bright future go down the
toilet in front of a life size cutouts of
Brittany Spears,
so that system wasn't working for me,
still not working for me and
I did what a lot of guys do.
A lot of people do when they run out
of career options entirely and they're
backed against the wall and they feel
like they have no future and I became a
lawyer and so of course I'm
stuck in law school thinking,
okay this just bought me three more years.
Good plan.
Everybody says you can get a great
job once you get out of law school.
This is for sure going to be a winning
strategy for me and I really felt out of
place most of the time if not the
entire time I felt out of place the vast
majority of the time and that's called
imposter syndrome and pretty much
everybody has this.
I don't know how you felt when you got
hired here at Google and everywhere that
I go speak,
there's always some measure of people
and we won't even do a show of hands
because it's so predictable
every single time.
There's always some measure of people,
the majority in fact,
who think that they're the group or the
person that slipped through the cracks
and that at some point they're going
to get found out that they don't really
know what they're doing or they're not
really as talented as is everybody else
in the room and it's only a matter of
time until they get found out and possibly
or likely fired.
And that is what I had in my head
when I started working on Wall Street.
Now the guy who hired me,
his name was Dave and Dave was cool
and no lawyers were cruel really.
And that's kind of a general rule,
but especially at this particular firm,
there weren't a whole lot of guys that
were doing finance that were really well
respected by everybody.
And everybody thought Dave was just
the man and he was a guy from Brooklyn.
Andy had a 10 so obviously he knew
something that other people did not know.
When you're from Brooklyn, you
have a 10 take notes, right?
Everybody tends to take notes on that and
this guy was never in the office ever.
And if there's something that
you might know about lawyers,
it's that they bill in six
minute increments generally,
and this is what they're doing when
they're in every phase of their,
their workday, they're billing in
these little increments of time.
So they stay in the office all day,
oftentimes all night,
and everybody was working all the time,
especially on Wall Street in 2007 2008
one time I went up to my office on a
Saturday night, probably maybe even a
Friday night to show it off to my friends.
This is probably my first
month on the job and I thought,
I'm going to go up in this big Manhattan
skyscraper, open up a bottle of whiskey.
We're going to hang out in my office and
talk about how we all finally made it
to New York and we're doing really well.
And when I opened the elevator door on
the 42nd floor of world financial number
two, the place looked like Monday
morning. Everybody was in there.
I'm talking everybody except for our
summer class, which is what I was in.
All the partners were there. All of the
associates, junior and senior were there.
There were closing some deal and
it was kind of a normal situation.
I didn't know that at the time.
I actually went back in the elevator,
push the ground floor button
and get the hell out of there.
Obviously as fast as I could before
they gave me some paperwork or some
documents to review because I wanted to
continue my life and my evening and my
weekend.
But what ended up being really frightening
was when I went back to work on
Monday morning, I asked the
senior associate, what's the deal?
Why are there so many people in
the office on a weekend? You know,
are we closing a big deal or is there,
are we short staffed? What's the problem?
And he said, no man, we're
always here at this time.
There's not a weekend that
goes by that we're not here.
10:00 PM 11:00 PM one two in the
morning if there's any work to be had,
we're doing it.
I mean we bill in six minute increments.
There's one guy that wasn't there
besides me. Of course Dave was not there.
Dave was nowhere to be found.
Dave wasn't there at 2:00 AM on a Saturday
and he certainly wasn't there at 2:00
PM on a Tuesday.
And this was so confusing to me and
luckily Dave was assigned by HR to be my
mentor and not right. Not the
kind of mentor. It's like, oh,
we're on the top floor, do an oyster
shooters with Matthew mcconaughey,
like on Wolf of Wall Street.
Not that kind of mentor.
This is the kind of
mentor where HR is like,
you have to hang out with this guy twice.
Check the boxes when you do so that we
know you mentor this person during the
summer. And uh, he was thrilled
about it. As you might imagine.
Everybody else that was on this mentorship
program that was in the law firm was
going to see blue man group to put a
little bit of a timestamp on it too,
to go out for drinks and
have $190 seafood lunches.
And my mentor was being forced at this
point now that I ratted him out. Pro Tip,
never do that to HR.
He was being forced to take me out for
coffee in essentially the basement of our
building and mentor me by force.
And what that entailed was him banging
away on his blackberry with a full
keyboard and black and white screen
and probably playing Brickbreaker,
which is still one of the best games
of all time on any mobile platform.
He asked me or told me
rather to ask him anything.
And at this point I didn't have a
whole lot of questions lined up. Right.
I just figured mentorship
was kind of unidirectional.
I didn't know that I had to play a
part in this other than showing up,
which you know, shows my, my
understanding of Wall Street at that time.
But he didn't have a clue either.
So the first question that I asked them
was something that I was pretty sure it
was going to get me fired, but I didn't
care at this point because again,
I thought it's only a matter of
time until they find me out anyway.
I might as well get this one off my chest.
And I said,
how come everyone is always in the office?
Always billing hours,
always billing in six minute increments,
but you're never here.
What are you doing all day?
What do you do at our law firm?
And he put down his blackberry
and he leaned in and he said,
who's talking about what I do all day?
And at this point I'm just like,
this is how you get fired at Starbucks
for sure in front of all these people.
I'm going to get reamed out by a
partner and walk home and just,
I'm gonna leave my phone there. I'm not
even to go back and get it. This is it.
This is the end. It's going to be the
most embarrassing time in my life.
And of course I backtracked like
crazy and I said, well, you know,
some people here, maybe I've mentioned
that you're just not around a lot.
I don't know. You know, I'm busy
working so I didn't even notice.
But he goes, well look, let
me be honest with you man.
I bring in all of the deals
for our real estate department.
I go out and I meet potential clients,
which at that point were investment
bankers and I do things with them that
create relationships and
then they give us business.
That's why we have a new million dollar
deals every couple months or every
quarter here at the firm.
And I was super confused by this because
it didn't occur to me that going out
and getting relationships with
people would somehow bring benefit.
I thought people found law firms in the
yellow pages and hired them and that was
it. Or maybe they were
really good at something.
And so people noticed and they
hired them because of that reason.
And that turns out to be
only part of the equation.
So what Dave was actually doing was lead
Gen, business development, networking,
relationship development, whatever you
want to call it, but it was very informal.
The reason he had a tan was because he
was always outside golfing or running or
cycling with these bankers. He did
Jujitsu, which made him walk with a limp.
By the way,
I don't know why people still do that.
Everybody I know who does
Jujitsu is injured, but he
would go on charity cruises.
He would go out to lunch
with people all the time.
He would go on charity dinners.
He was always gone for the weekend at
someone's house in the Hamptons and at
that time being 26 27 years old,
that sounded amazing.
Not just because it sounded relatively
easier than checking for Commas and 800
page documents, which is what
I was doing most of the time,
but because I actually had some inkling
that I would never get better at the
lawyer side of things.
I couldn't make myself smarter and my
competitive advantages have evaporated
because when I was a kid,
I got by a little bit on general smarts.
I'm sure y'all are familiar with that.
You go to school and you just kind of
show up and it's not that hard, right.
All the way through high school.
But then you get to college and
even if everyone's as smart as you,
90% of the people there are drinking
their face off every single day and you
just kind of have to focus in even a minor
way to outdo those folks and now work
them.
And that worked in law school as well.
But by the time you get to Wall Street,
everybody's willing to work
and everybody is smart.
And I was sure as heck convinced
that they were smarter than me.
And that became a huge problem because
any competitive advantage that I had been
leaning on for my entire life
had essentially evaporated.
The moment I walked in the door of that
term and I started at the bottom of the
totem pole with no plan
on how to work my way up.
And so the way that the things that
Dave was talking about, this networking,
this relationship development,
this changed the way that
I look at work forever.
Because if he can learn this skillset
or if he can have this and I can maybe
figure out how to do part of that stuff,
if I can figure out some ways in which
I can increase my skills in that area,
by the time all these really smart people
that I'm working with me on the same
level, figure out they even need to do
this. I'll already have a four or five,
six year advantage.
I'll have a long leg up in this race.
This is kind of a tortoise and the hare
type thing, right? So if I start now,
maybe if I stick around long enough
and don't get fired before then I'll
actually have a fighting
chance at making partner.
That's my plan to get to the top of the
long game. You know how that turned out,
so I want to, I don't need to explain
that one, but this is just such a massive,
massive realization for me and it really,
really changed the way that I started
to think about relationships and then I
started to think about my work there.
It was sort of a secret third path to
get to the top that nobody else was aware
of. Now, Dave was not
the most skilled lawyer.
He was not the smartest lawyer.
He was just the best connected lawyer.
And that sounds a little bit troubling
because obviously you want people who are
competent to be on the top.
It wasn't that he was incompetent and
I just want to make that really clear.
He was,
it wasn't just that he got by on charm,
it wasn't just that he
got by in relationships.
He worked his way towards the top,
but his relationships are what pulled
him and propelled him, I should say,
over the top,
early in the game and kept him up there
because as somebody with very rare
people, skills and sales
skills essentially for client
development, networking,
whatever you want to call it,
those skills are so rare in technical
professions like being a lawyer, doctor,
dentist, Google perhaps that they're
actually so rare that they demand higher
compensation and they,
they get you into doors that
would otherwise maybe be
close to you at least for
a few more years.
And since they were so rare,
they made him so valuable to the firm.
And this was a guy bear in
mind who when he hired me,
I saw him when they forced
him to mentor me, I saw him.
And the third time that I saw him,
he was in the elevator for an all hands
meeting with the managing partner,
essentially the CEO of
the firm and he jokes,
is there some kind of emergency meeting
going on? What are you doing here?
So it became almost a meme,
a joke inside the firm that
Dave was showing up at any
given time because it was
so rare.
It was an event that everybody started
talking about an actually made jokes
about. So this is how we
calculated his hourly value, right?
We looked at his time spent in the firm.
Every six minute increment was worth a
certain amount of with him billing out at
about 800 bucks an hour.
If he brings in a million dollar law
deal and he spends 40 102 hundred hours
working on that particular deal,
every single deal that he gets his worth,
I won't do the math for
you because I that's not,
that's why I became a lawyer first of all.
So they don't have a lot of math.
It's a hell of a lot more than 800 bucks
an hour and those deals stack onto each
other because you get
deals from the same people.
So his time was worth more than
any other partner in the firm,
probably worth more than most of the
other partner's time combined in the firm.
So he was able to write his own ticket
and that's why when I realize that you
needed to work outside the system in
order to succeed inside the system,
I started to get my notepad out and take
notes because I figured if I can master
this skill set, then the sky's the
limit in the professional spheres,
in any technical profession,
in any professional whatsoever
that I've ever encountered.
The strength of your relationships
translates directly to opportunity,
prosperity and flexibility. And
this is, these are all separate,
but they're all equally important in many,
many ways.
And that has to do with what you end
up doing now, five years from now,
10 years from now,
how you're compensated for doing
that and where you're doing that.
And it's a safe bet that a handful of
people in this room like networking.
I definitely don't even
like the word networking.
I think it's kind of got a dirty kind
of crusty feel to it these days because
it's smarmy,
right?
You think throwing business cards
in someone's face and being like,
call me when you need a financial manager
and that nobody likes those people.
So it makes you feel dirty thinking,
I don't want to do this. I don't if,
if I don't have to be that guy and I just
keep my head down and work, you know,
I'll get to the top of this.
And to a certain extent that may be true,
but the rest of us,
we hate networking for that reason and
that actually harms us because that's not
the only way to get relationships built.
It's not the only way to
build relationships with
other people and keep them and
maintain them and grow them over time.
And that's why there's that fundamental
difference that we have in our heads of
what networking is,
how it works and how we might learn it
or not learn it depending on how angsty
we get around that particular term.
At the art of charm,
we teach people how to leverage
opportunity, leverage relationships,
get deals that competitors can only dream
about due to those relationships and
turn something that most
of us dread secretly or not
so secretly into one of our
strongest competitive advantages.
And no surprise, the old trope,
it's all about who you know,
not what you know that that
gets thrown around a lot.
But when people say that there's usually
a little bit of stank on the end, right?
It's not like, oh, it's all about
who you know. It's usually like, oh,
it's all about who you know.
And we throw that out there when somebody
gets promoted over us or when we lose
a deal or when we don't get on the
project that we want to get on or when we
lose a job or worse,
lose a relationship or a partner because
of somebody else's relationship or
their skills inside those relationships
and even inside companies like Google,
the most brilliant idea that you have
can fail if you don't have the right
people around you. If you don't
have the right team around you,
and I hope none of you have
experienced that firsthand,
something tells me that most all of
you have at this point in your career
experience,
something like that.
That might even be why you're
here and when I was young,
when I was in college and to a
certain extent in law school,
I thought that networking relationships,
networks in general were things that you
were born into. Your family had them.
You went to a fancy private school where
you wear a blue blazer with a little
insignia on it and you hung out and played
croquet or polo or something all day,
and everyone on everybody went
on to do something amazing.
And then you could call those,
those
guys
and
gals
together@theendofthedayandfigureoutworlddominationdot.dot,
profit, right? That's how
I imagine this would work.
And sometimes people marry into it,
which by the way, if you can do that,
highly recommended,
uh, for the rest of us,
we kind of have to figure out how to
generate these relationships on our own.
And if your parents didn't do
this for you, you have to do this.
If you want to reap the benefits yourself
and if you want your kids to reap the
benefits of relationships and networks
that you've grown over the course of your
life because these things don't
happen necessarily by themselves.
The good news is that with intentional
application of these topics,
you can actually surpass people that were
born into a good network because they
are coasting,
they're coasting on their
previous momentum and we
have our foot on the gas if
we're intentional about it.
Again, the tortoise and the hare
networking and relationship development
is a way of being. It is a set of habits.
This isn't something that
turns on and off over time.
It's something that's always on but not
in that always on used car salesman kind
of way.
Something that you do that you systemize
and I think I'm in the right place to
talk about systems. I hope something that
you systemize and have it work for you.
I moved to San Francisco from la about
three or four years ago now and after a
year or two in San Francisco,
a lot of my friends who had grown up
there or he'd been there for a decade and
change would remark things like,
how do you know so many people?
How are you getting
invited to so many things?
How can we have all these
different relationships? I
don't really understand it.
I work from home. Actually. I don't know
if y'all know that I work from my house.
I see no one except for
my wife all day long.
I hang out with my cats
more than most people.
How are these relationships
being developed?
It doesn't make any
sense from the outside,
but once you see the matrix
and see how these things work,
there's really no going back
because you can start to systemize.
Everyone has the capacity to do this. It's
another important key. A lot of people,
how many people think they're introverts
are kind of self proclaimed introverts
at some level. All right, cool. I was
like, oh no one's raising their hand,
but couldn't.
Classic introvert fashion.
Everyone waited for someone else to do
at first. Good. I'm in good company.
I am also technically speaking
an introvert and that's fine,
but what it's important for us to realize
is that we don't have a medical excuse
to not build relationships anymore.
Introversion is one of those things.
It's like, well, I would go and develop
relationships. I would go to this event,
but I'm an introvert so I'm off the hook
and then you go back to whatever you
like to do, which is me time. If you're
anything like me and I understand that,
but we can't lean on that anymore.
All of all that introversion means is
we prefer to not socialize with other
people or we prefer to recharge
by focusing on ourselves.
It has nothing to do with our
ability to learn these skills.
And in fact new research now shows
that introverts in large part are more
introspective and are better at
reading other people's behavior,
which coincidentally is great for
building and maintaining relationships.
So your homegrown network keeps
opportunity flowing into your life at an
unstoppable pace. And that's true
whether you're inside a company,
whether you're an entrepreneur, whether
you've got a good side hustle going.
And by the way, it's pure job
security inside an organization. Dave,
by the way,
left are sinking law firm cause we were
heavily leveraged in 2008 with the real
estate thing. I was in the real estate
department by the way. Not a good bet.
He walked out of that sinking ship and
walked right into a partner level job at
another firm.
And I know this because I saw him in the
elevator while I was working at Sirius
XM satellite radio doing the art of charm.
And he said,
don't I know you from somewhere? And
the answer was no, I don't think so. Uh,
he walked right in. Everybody else was
punished by the reception, a recession.
My other partners, my other
bosses there, they're retired now.
Some of them were in their forties I
don't think they had planned to do that
after slaving for a decade, decade and
a half to make partner on Wall Street.
And some of them are still unraveling
that mess from a decade ago.
The recession was a decade ago. There's
still retired. This is not good.
And it's not that they didn't do the
right thing. They build so many hours.
They worked so hard for their job,
their from their clients,
but they just didn't have the book of
business to save their bacon at the end of
the day. And the hitch here
really is that even if we were,
you collectively decide to willfully
ignore this particular skillset,
you're just being willfully ignorant of
the secret game being played around you
and you're not immune to the consequences.
I'm sure plenty of the other partners
in that firm thought, you know,
look at Dave's the guy who
goes out and get the business.
There's always going to be room for
me here. We always need workhorses.
And that's just not necessarily true.
You have to diversify your skillset and
if you're going to skill stack and have
multiple skills that you are good at,
one of them better be
relationship development.
So I like to give homework and I know
how much everyone here loves homework,
but in the next month, and if you're
taking notes is a good time to do that.
And the next month, pick one person
in your network who is a weaker tie,
but with whom you'd like a stronger
alliance. So somebody who thought, well,
you know,
I should reach out to that person or I
haven't spoken to this person in a long
time and just commit to
trying to proactively reignite
that relationship through
small favors.
And I'm talking about
finding out something they're
interested in sending them
an article or two that you read
this recent on the subjects or uh,
helping them prepare for a presentation
is something that I always like to do.
If you're, if you've got skills
and the presentation department,
that's always a good one because most
people feel a lot of nerves and anxiety
around it if you're in their corner or
you can help them with their slides.
Anything really simple, especially on
a topic that you enjoy is a really,
really good gift or favor so to speak.
So invest in real time and energy into
that relationship over the next several
months and you will definitely see
dividends that much a promise you and also
create what I call an interesting people
fund and funnel a certain percentage of
your paycheck, certain very
small certainly, but use
this to pay for lunches,
drinks,
things like that.
Even a plane ticket to visit someone
or visit an area and have lunch with
somebody or dinner with somebody with
whom you want a stronger connection.
And you guys have the super super hookup
here at Google because you can invite
people into the campus to have lunch,
do a tour that is built in for you.
So if you haven't done that or if you
haven't made good use of that over the
past six, eight, 18 months
or ever start doing that,
maybe just once a month, time flies.
But these things stack up these,
this is compound interest.
The other reason is that opportunities
are often over the horizon.
And what I mean by that is we often
don't see the benefit that can come from
helping other people or from reigniting
relationships with other people.
So right now a lot of you
are thinking, well, okay,
I know a bunch of people but I don't
really know what I want from them or what
they would want from me,
so forget it.
It's there's nothing I really
need so I'm not going to do that.
And that is a huge mistake because since
opportunities are over the horizon,
what that means is that you have no
idea whether or not you can help them or
they can help you.
Neither of you know this case in point.
When I first moved to La, I had a too
thick and if you've ever had a toothache,
you probably know the pain is,
it's like it's in your brain.
This is some of the most intimate
destructive pain that you can feel.
It's so distracting.
It's all consuming.
It seems like it's inside your head and
there's nothing you can do about it.
There's not enough Tylenol in the house,
there's not,
there's not of painkillers commercially
available without a prescription that
are going to help you without killing
you if you have a strong enough to think.
And the problem was this was pre Uber.
Okay, I didn't have a car at the point.
I moved straight from New York to La.
I had no dentist and my
insurance was garbage.
So of course I'm calling every dentist
I can find in the yellow pages and
they're saying like, oh, just
go to the Er. Just go to the ER,
they'll take care of you.
When you go to the Er with a tooth ache,
I have a feeling they tie a string to it
and slam the door and send you on your
way home because as we all know,
healthcare with no insurance or
crappy insurance, especially dental,
things like that, not the business,
so I posted in on Facebook,
does anybody have a
dentist that I can use?
I need to get this too thick handled so
I can continue with my life and a total
stranger because I have my
privacy settings completely
screwed up at this point,
replies to the thread and says, actually,
my aunt's a dentist in your area.
I don't really know you,
but it sounds like you're in pain.
Do you want me to give her a call?
Absolutely, I do. Absolutely.
I walked down there bright and early
before she even opens up shop. They open,
they take care of me. I don't
get overcharged. I go home.
A much happier camper than I was before.
Now,
of course I go home and I'm infinitely
thankful to this particular stranger who
I still to this day, I've never met,
and I write back, thank you so much.
You're saved my bacon here. And he says,
great, I've really, I'm glad to do that.
By the way, I'm looking for
a job in graphic design. Of
course there's a rub. Look,
I'm not hiring a graphic designer.
It would be really convenient for purposes
of this story if I needed a graphic
designer, but alas, I'm not
gonna lie to you like that.
So I said I would keep my
ear to the ground for him,
which translates roughly to,
yeah, whatever, man. Thanks.
Anyway, however, four days later,
five days later, another
entrepreneur hit me up and said, hey,
your website looks really great.
I've had a lot of flaky designers.
What do you think? Do you know anyone?
Well, we do all of our design in house,
and I said, look, I don't know anyone,
but this random dude from Facebook
gave me his portfolio. Here it is.
It's attached.
All I know is that he helped me find a
dentist and he seems like a nice person.
Not exactly qualifications you would
want in somebody who you're going to hire
fulltime for a position. Right.
But it turns out that later on,
after doing a series of discreet
jobs for this entrepreneur,
this particular individual ended up
getting a full time job at this particular
company.
So he went from essentially working at a
local cafe and posting about his job on
Facebook every five minutes to getting a
full time job in his industry of choice.
The reason that this story is important
and relevant is because I had no idea
that I could get a dentist from a person.
I never knew I.
That was obviously not
something I forced saw,
which was the reason I posted
there in the first place. However,
if he had literally asked every single
person that he knew and then he'd ever
met in his whole life for a job,
he still would not have found the job
that he got by helping me selflessly.
That is what I mean by opportunities
lying over the horizon.
You don't know who you can help and
you don't know who can help you.
You have no idea,
neither of you do and you won't find out
until you start being generous with it.
And that's why we have ABG,
which is always be giving.
Has anyone seen Glengarry Glen Ross?
ABC always be closing.
So I'll let you youtube that one later.
But essentially it's about going after
what you want and mercilessly getting it
and forget everyone else at art of charm
where rock and ABG always be generous
or always be giving.
And what this means is that since
you're helping other people with no
expectation of anything in return,
you can find those opportunities that
are lying over the horizon in many ways
you can,
it's not always going to be like this.
Obviously this is a numbers game and a
you want to be the guy or gal that looks
like they're always just getting lucky
and hitting the lottery because of the
numbers.
The way you increase your odds and a
numbers game is you keep playing the game.
You keep increasing the numbers.
So in the next week,
introduce two or more people that you
know already do not know each other and
the way that you do this is
not by surprise attacking
them with an email where
they're both cc to everyone hates
that. You hate that. I hate that.
Of course they hate that.
Some people don't know this but I,
that's why I always throw it out there.
This is called the double opt in intro.
Okay. You email one and you
say, Hey, I know this Guy Bob.
He works in graphic design like you and
he's got a lot of capacity for work and
he's really talented and then you reach
out to the other person and you say, Hey,
this guy James is really cool, super
interesting guy, got a lot of work,
always seems like he's got
deal flow coming through.
Are you open to meeting him?
Do you guys know each other already? If
they both say yes, you make the intro.
If one says no, you don't, and I know
what you're thinking, Ooh, that's awkward.
What do I tell the other person
who said yes when one says no,
the answer is you say the timing
isn't right right now. True. No lying,
and you leave it at that and if they ask
you again in a few months, no problem.
The only time that you would ever say
anything else is if there's a serious
issue with that, and that's sort
of beyond the scope of this,
but I would say that every
time you double optin,
you're most likely going to get a yes,
especially from people that don't have
a ton of incoming people that they call
the introductions coming from people that
they actually trust. Which by the way,
is you people who are doing the ABG thing.
We're networking well,
who are building a lot of relationships
will always say yes to an intro.
It doesn't mean they
have to hire that person.
It doesn't mean they have to have lunch.
It just means they have
to say yes to the email,
which usually leads to some sort of
call or even just a mutual connection so
that they're on each other's radar.
That alone is enough.
If you're thinking about the the utility
that each of these people have to the
other person in the interaction,
that alone is enough and if
you do this in the next week,
and if you do this once a week,
you'll have made 52 give or take some
nos introductions every single year,
which is a ton,
and once you start ramping this up,
you realize this is actually really easy
because if I need help with something
or if you need help with something, the
way that this becomes scalable. Again,
going back to graphic design,
let's say that I'm a graphic designer
and you need help with your website.
I don't have time to
do your graphic design.
I don't have time to do graphic
design for everyone in this room.
What I might have time to do is introduce
everyone in this room to different
capable designers.
So what I've done is provided value,
followed the ABG rule of
giving and helping and being
generous without actually
doing really more than connecting one
corner of my web to another part of my web
that makes it scalable.
That's important because otherwise you
will drive yourself freaking crazy and
you'll lose your job and
be homeless. Dot. A dot.
The end on the other side of the equation,
you've got to think about a challenge
that you yourself are dealing with and you
have to ask for help from
their network as well.
Where people get stuck with the
ABG stuff is they go, oh great,
I'm going to help everyone,
and they start sending 58,000 email
introductions every single week and they
never ask for what they need and
that becomes almost a pathology.
If you're there, great. It's a good
sign that you're doing some stuff right.
Start asking for what you need.
People want to help you in return.
It's reciprocity, which is a human law,
psychology, and it closes the loop.
I like to say because I always feel
a little bit of, wow, I really want,
I want to do something for that person.
You know,
they've been so generous with me.
If you allow them to do that,
they feel good about helping you as well.
There's not really a better win than
there can be from those two particular
things hitting simultaneously or at
some point in the same three, six month,
even year time span.
So
yeah,
we've already talked about
why networking is valuable.
We've already talked about how to
introduce people to one another.
We've already talked about how to make
it scalable and we've talked about
helping people and finding those
opportunities over the horizon.
The other reason to do this selfishly
or not so selfishly is that your network
is unique to you. You can have a
bank account with no money in it.
We've all been there and you have value
to offer somebody with $10 million,
whatever, a bajillion dollars in their
bank account because you and your network,
your network really is one of the only
things about you that is truly unique.
I know we're going to probably,
there's going to be some discussion about
how we're all special snowflakes and
usually that comes at the end of this,
but I will tell you that your network
is one of the only things that is unique
to you.
It's one of the only things you have
that nobody else or very few other people
have, especially if you've been building
it up over time. So business of course,
fundamentally is people selling
things to people that they already,
ideally no doing business with people
you know and like is one of the most
common ways to do this.
See the Dave example in the beginning
of this particular discussion,
and everyone's already heard,
well you only go as high as
your five closest friends.
And I'm not saying ditch your friends.
That would be like the opposite of a
of a Tony Robbins seminar probably,
but we're not gonna.
We're not gonna do that here.
Networking and relationship development
is one of the single best ways to make
sure that you're surrounding yourself
with as many high quality people as
possible. You're doing a great job.
You're in this room here at Google,
not bad so far,
keep it up.
But many people in this company and
outside this company are running into the
problem where maybe professionally
they're surrounded with all stars,
maybe personally not so much or sometimes
the inverse depends on what department
you're in here. I guess that's what
I've heard. So in the next day,
take a look at your appointment book,
your calendar,
your Google calendar hopefully and
over the past three to six months,
who have you surrounded yourself with?
Who have you been hanging out with
professionally and personally,
with whom have you spent the most time
and are you happy with the influence
those people have had on you?
Because a lot of people think
that they can resist that,
but you all know you do fall into the
same habits in the same traps is the
people that you're surrounding yourself
with voluntarily or not and that's why
it's so toxic to be around people who
don't have the same values as you who
don't have the same ways of
thinking and mindsets of success,
happiness and things like that.
Then you do now caveat,
this is not a game you play just
because you want the spoils.
It is important to me personally
to help people buy a whole company.
The Art of charm is founded on that
basis and I like helping people.
I like coming and speaking to people.
I love seeing people succeed and I love
interacting and if somebody does not
have integrity,
do not build your network around them.
It is so tempting to do this.
It is so tempting to go, well,
this person's high up on this totem pole.
They're really good at
this particular thing.
They have high visibility in this area,
but they're a total scumbag.
That will always, always, always
come back to bite you in the butt.
You just have to zoom out far enough on
the timeline to see how that's happened
with those people in other areas and you
will see yourself becoming a victim of
that same thing.
If you don't believe me,
look at what those people have been
around before and zoom out on the timeline
and you will find an example of your
future if you associate with those people.
I mean it's also important,
this whole,
this entire process is important because
unless you've been intentional about
the process of surrounding yourself with
better people and leveling up in that
area, your immediate
surroundings in social circle,
there's a pretty darn good chance that
it's loaded with people who are satisfied
being essentially mediocre in whatever
area that you're trying to level up in or
one or two areas that you're trying
to level up in health, fitness,
professional life.
We've all got those people that are have
kind of been around us for a long time
that maybe are no longer adding value
but subtracting it a little bit of an
energy vampire.
One might say,
and if you surround yourself with
high achievers at work and at home,
you will absolutely crush.
You will crush it.
They will bring you up and you can bring
them up with you as well and people
like I said,
want to help you.
If you're excited about helping
them get their goals accomplished,
they will get excited about
doing the same for you.
Always be giving and you will
get that as simple reciprocity.
And this is something that high
performers rely on all the time,
every single time. If you want
to look at charities for example,
they're loaded with the well to
do and there's a reason for that.
It's not just about being social,
it's a way for people in distinct silos
to be around other people that they
would normally never get to interact
with while working on a common goal.
That is a very sort of tricky thing
to wrap your mind around sometimes,
especially when you just
see it from the outside.
But when you get in the middle of that,
you realize that most of those people
are thinking like that. It's a strategy.
It's not coincidence.
Okay?
The number one rule of
relationship building is to
build it before you need it.
Dig the well before you're thirsty.
Networking.
Once you need something like a
job or a relationship for example,
that is not effective. And a lot
of people think they can do that.
How many people have
been like, oh, you know,
I'm totally gonna start this
relationship development thing,
but I've got to get this project done.
I've got to move up one rung
on the ladder at work. Um,
I've got to get this website going.
I really need to, uh, you know,
get my move handled first and
get settled in my new place.
Some sort of excuse to false deadline is
often what keeps us from moving forward.
We have to ditch those because think
about this, who would you rather help?
Somebody who's helped you out with a few
things over the last few months in the
last few years or someone that calls you
out of the blue and is like, hey man,
yeah, what's up man? I want
to take you out for a beer.
It's been such a long time and then you
get there and they're like Herbalife or
whatever, right? You're
just like, ah, God,
I knew it or I knew
this is going to happen.
Waiting to form relationships
only once you need them.
It's like carrying a spare tire in the
trunk of your car after you're stranded
on the side of the highway. It's not good.
So here's a thought exercise for you.
Yeah.
Imagine that you got laid off from your
job today. Not going to happen. Hopefully.
Now you have my personal guarantee.
How's that?
You got laid off from your job today.
Who are the 10 people that you would
contact for help if that happened?
You get laid off today.
Who are you contacting 10 people for help
and figure out what you're going to do
next.
Make that list of 10 people.
Then reach out to them now
when you don't need anything,
if you've been laid off,
you know that's a good idea.
So networking, creating those
relationships only when you need it,
it's not effective. It is too late. 80%
of new jobs are found through networks,
not through monster.com you don't
want to see the stats on that.
Nobody looks at their inbox even they're
using the new Gmail spam filters and
stuff like that.
It doesn't matter.
It's all via the network and
everyone who works at my company,
everyone who works at the art of charm
has gotten their job by networking and
relationships. That obviously makes
sense because that's what we teach.
You will find that works in 80% of cases
and when you get to higher performing
jobs,
better jobs that are
higher paid compensation or
involve different or better
projects, that number, that percentage
goes much, much higher because the job,
the stakes are too high to
rely on a simple recruiting
process that doesn't have
a little finger on the
scale from relationships and
previous vetting from people
who've been there or know that person.
So this is about action.
It's not about collecting business cards,
it's not about your Rolodex
if those things still exist,
which I doubt the best way to do this
is to create a platform to do this.
A lot of people of industry blogs, my
platform is my podcast, the art of charm.
It puts me in visible place.
It puts me in a position to interact
with interesting people that have other
connections and connect
with connect doors.
So if you don't have a podcast so you
don't have the big old blog or you can't
talk about what you're working on,
which was a lot of you,
I know that the greatest way I found to
do this is to organize little low key
low pressure dinner parties with people
in similar or different industries that
are relevant enough. We're one person
each time can teach the group something,
so you might have a dinner party at your
place and you might teach a little bit
of Seo. I don't know if you
guys are allowed to do that.
That's my go to example,
but whatever,
put something else in there instead.
Somebody might teach outsourcing
that might be a better one for you.
Social media is a good one. Uh, these
are things that are pretty default.
These work really well with entrepreneurs.
They work really great for people in
general who are interested in business.
Y'All are pretty technical.
Some of you I would imagine,
and you can teach certain discreet skills
to the group in a way that doesn't set
you up for any sort of trouble at work,
but also sets you up on a platform and
if you're hosting these dinner parties,
you can invite different people.
You can insist they bring one other
person that you don't yet know and someone
who's been there the previous week
comes prepared that next week to teach a
subject doesn't have to be an hour long
lecture can be something really simple.
It doesn't have to be white boarded,
just has to be interesting and valuable
enough to keep people showing up and
keep the event fun enough that people
continue to come and continue to bring
others into that.
This sets you up as the network hub.
It sets you up as the connector and if
you can connect with other connectors,
now you're cooking with gas. Of
course, my platform, like I said,
is a podcast and look,
networking is a muscle.
It grows with use. It is not a pie
that gets eaten up piece by piece.
If you call in help from somebody that
is not going to use up that contact.
A lot of people operate like that.
They're afraid to call on somebody.
Well I don't want to email them
about this because you know,
then I've used my one time that I can get
in touch. No, it's quite the opposite.
It's a muscle that grows with use.
The more you network,
the more you introduce people to
others and where you create that value,
the more you ABG,
the more that muscle will grow.
And if you hoard your network, it will
atrophy the same as a muscle as well.
So it all comes back to ABG and
doing so in a systemized way.
And uh,
one final sort of example here of asking
for help because I know a lot of people
are shy with that. I didn't get into
law school the first time I applied.
I didn't get in at all.
In fact,
I got rejected and I remember sitting
in a house up north and just thinking,
wow,
that was my hail Mary at figuring out
what I was going to do for the next three
years. I can't even get a job at freaking
best buy with a college degree from the
University of Michigan.
I'm so screwed.
I don't even know what
I'm going to do right now.
I should just walk into the Great Lakes
that I'm looking at right now and just
keep walking and figure out,
figure it out from there.
I mean there was nothing happening.
So in desperation,
I reached out to a lot of my friends
who had already been admitted.
They were a year ahead of me,
a couple months ahead of a semester ahead
of me or just getting in at that same
level and I said, what would you
do? And they said, all right,
write a letter that explains why you
should be let in and send me a copy and I
will look at it.
Almost everybody said something similar
along those lines because I had them all
on one thread and so I wrote this letter.
I figured this is just such
a waste of time. I don't,
I don't even know why I'm doing this,
but they kind of forced me to do it.
I was just going to say, great, thanks
for the suggestion and not do it.
My friend Greg, thank God he made
me do this. So I sent it back.
I got a bunch of corrections based on
the way that they've learned their legal
pros and argumentation.
Put it in a really interesting
format that I'd never seen before.
It looked like a legal brief of some kind
and I sent it to the admissions office
and a couple of those guys and gals
sent letters to the admissions office
telling them why you think
it was a mistake that I
wasn't let in into the school
at some point. And I was
definitely Michigan material. Um,
cause I went for Undergrad and law
school just to avoid confusion.
And so after a few weeks I got a call
from the admissions office and they said,
look, never seen anybody do this.
This is a really interesting idea.
And the fact that you put this into
such a coherent argument in a letter,
you sent it back, you weren't expecting
anything. And my trade off was,
you don't have to let me in for this year.
Let me in for next year and
I will kill the rest of it.
I'll figure out what to do with my time.
And we all know how you can kill
a year in college pretty easily.
And so they said, fine, we'll, we'll
convene the admissions committee,
we have another meeting
and I'll run it by them.
And they called a few days later and
they let me in, not for that year,
but for the next year just as I
had suggested. So think about this.
I got into one of the best
law schools in America where,
where an I'd previously been
rejected because I asked for help.
Those people were glad to do it.
We're still friends to this day and I'm
still getting a reminder every single
month about how valuable that
law degree was. So all right,
now I think we've got a little bit of
time left. Uh, you keeping time. You get,
we're good. Great. So let's
go to Serbia. So here's a,
here's a more fun example of the
law school in my humble opinion.
So in 2005 is 25 years old and I worked
for was actually coincidentally killing
year before law school and
I had a fellowship from the
Department of Defense to
go and work in Serbia, which is in the
former Yugoslavia, not Siberia, Serbia,
different place, former Yugoslavia,
southern Balkans, Europe area.
And when you go to Serbia,
you have to register with the government
and tell them where you're living.
And the police have to stamp this
little piece of paper that says you're a
foreigner living in the country. And
now that's really foreign to Americans.
But if you've ever been to the eastern
block, this is super commonplace.
They love to keep tabs on everybody and
everything and you have to live with a
Serbian person.
You can't live on your own.
You can't just stay in some
house that you rent on Airbnb,
which didn't exist at the time. You're
not allowed to do anything like that.
You have to have somebody
who is vouching for you.
And this got really annoying because
every time I left the country or left even
the county city area where I was,
I had to reregister so I had to,
every single time I would take a drive
to a restaurant outside of Belgrade.
I had to reregister with the police
and that was never a smooth process,
often involved in an annoying fee and
also was salted in me having a couple of
incidences that really got old fast.
For example,
I was coming back from a visit to Germany.
I came back at about 11 o'clock at night
or 10 ended up in the police station
where the registration has done around
10 11 at night and the police officer who
was on duty there decided that since I
was in the police station at that hour,
I must've done something wrong even though
I walked in alone and he put me in a
prison cell with three chain smoking
prostitutes who spoken aloud as foreign
language for the entire night,
smoking unfiltered cigarettes and it
was one of the worst nights of my entire
life and I decided this
is not happening again.
I am not doing this registration thing.
This is an offense to freedom everywhere.
I'm not doing this. And so I decided,
I'm just going to say to hell with this.
They're not, they're so disorganized,
they're never even gonna find me. Well,
I'll let you know how that goes.
So I could see the brilliant plants have
my friends say that I was staying with
them even though I wasn't.
And then you know,
what are the police gonna do come
in and specs and see where I live.
So the police came and inspected to
see where I live and I wasn't there.
And they said, Yo, yeah, he's
traveling. Did they said, okay, fine.
And so they came back about
two weeks later and they
said, where's his stuff? Oh,
he's not here.
And so the police gave my friend
yelling at an ultimatum and they said,
if he's not here the next time that
we come, we're going to look for him.
But you're going to help us and you're
going to stay with us until we find them.
And that was pretty loud and
clear for guess what Jordan,
you're moving tonight at 1:30
AM luckily moving was easy,
didn't have anything at our house.
But what it did mean is that I had to
go to the police station and register
again and I decided fine,
I'm going to do that.
So I decided to pull the same thing
cause it worked for a few months with
another friend and that guy went
and moved to his weekend house,
like a cottage for months.
So he wasn't home.
So what the police found when they went
to inspect again was not only was I not
there,
nobody was there at all for a long,
long time and that raised a red flag
and when you live in the eastern block,
red flags mean trouble.
So this started to get
really scary for them, right?
That my friend was getting calls
because I was registered there and I was
hanging out and thinking, look, this is
fine. You know, I'll just go and fix this.
But Serbia is not exactly the kind of
place where you walk into the police
station. As I've learned
before. And say, Hey,
I heard you guys have been looking for me.
What can I do for you?
So I decided I'm going to handle this.
Just not right now.
So I had an appointment at the American
embassy to take care of everything.
But before that I had tickets to a
music festival and this was going to be
awesome.
So I went into the music festival.
It's three days long and it was
on this Turkish fortress island.
It looks like game of Thrones.
In fact,
I think they may have filmed some
game of Thrones stuff there. It's a,
it's an island that is an Ottoman Empire
fortress and there's 20 stages set up
here when they have this festival,
no cars allowed. Huge. I mean it is,
it is just mindblowingly enormous and
cool and everything was going so well.
I'd been up for probably like
a day and a half partying,
hanging out with my friends, drinking. Um,
we did some weird cameo on MTV Europe
where I didn't understand what they were
saying to me,
but it didn't matter and I just,
I couldn't have been having more fun.
But there was a black jeep that started
rolling around the island towards when
everybody was getting done and they were
kind of inspecting people and looking
through the crowd and shining the light
on people as dawn broke and everyone has
to leave on this bridge and walk on this
bridge. And so as we started to do that,
they stopped a friend of
mine and me and they said,
where are your passports?
Because in Serbia you have to carry your
passport with you everywhere you go.
If you're a foreigner,
you have to have your international
id with you no matter what.
I carried a copy because who's
going to carry their passport?
You're going to lose it hold big thing.
So I carried a copy of my passport.
That was not satisfactory.
So what did they do?
They called to make sure
that I was who I said I was.
But guess what happened when they called?
He's not registered.
We've been looking for him.
Whoops.
Also to add a little bit of something
else, something special to the pot.
My friend had a bit of a checkered past
where he was related to an organized
crime figure from his family and they
had moved and then he came back to hang
out in Serbia. So these guys figure
we've hit the frigging jackpot. You know,
we've got an American spy who's basically
a fugitive and some mafiosos kid.
So at this point I think, great,
you know, we're going to jail,
hopefully not worse and make
things a little bit worse.
These guys were not sober.
These guys were on drugs.
And to put this into a
little bit of perspective,
Serbian state security
officers at this point in time,
they're not like the American FBI.
These are guys who fly in
militias and Bosnia or whatever.
Their village got eradicated by
Cro ads or Bosniaks or whatever.
Now they live in Serbia.
And in order to not be prosecuted for
war crimes or things that they did back
there that were illegal,
they became agents of the state that
are above regular prosecution laws.
So they basically just run around, do
whatever they want, except for any,
obviously not getting any therapy for
their PTSD and all of the things that are
causing them to be hammered
at 7:38 AM in the morning.
So they're slurring, they're not rational,
they're aggressive. And I'm thinking,
great, I'm going to get pistol whipped in
front of like 20,000 people and there's
nothing I can do about it. And my friend
is all doing the, the the classic,
let me talk my way out of this type thing.
And that's not going too well.
And I'm replying. Look man, I don't,
I'm not a fugitive, I'm not a criminal.
I just teach refugees English and
I'm not, look, here's my passport.
We can go get the real one.
We'll go to the embassy and it'll make a
not a big deal out of it. And they were,
they thought that was an okay idea.
But first they had other ideas,
so they said get in the jeep.
And the problem is when you
speak a foreign language,
often those little connector words
like get in or get over are kind of
confusing. So when they said get
in the jeep, I thought, great,
I'm going to get in the jeep.
And it turned out that they meant get
on the jeep and what they meant I get on
the jeep was that they didn't want me to
be inside because the back had a bunch
of rifles in it and a bag of Doritos,
which is kind of weird.
They didn't want me to sit there.
So me and my friend had to hang onto the
running boards and we're hanging onto
the side of the running boards and our
hand through the open sunroof of the jeep
and they're going pretty slowly at this
point to drive off this island where
there's no roads, no cars.
After we get over the bridge,
we start cruising a little bit and they
start throwing popcorn out through the
sunroof because I forgot to tell you this,
they robbed a popcorn vendor
before we left the venue.
So these guys are throwing the popcorn
up through the roof and they're trying to
get us to catch it in our mouths
while we're driving on the highway.
We're going 40 miles an hour and
I'm thinking, oh, this is great.
I should just like a tuck
and roll or something. Right?
Except when you're going 40 miles an hour,
you're just kind of thinking,
what part of me is going to fly off if
I do that? So no talking, no rolling.
Then I saw the flashing lights, flashing
lights. Thank God the police are here.
They're going to pull us over. They're
going to find out how ridiculous this is.
They're going to cut us loose or they're
going to send it straight back to the
embassy. Worst case, I get deported.
I can live with that. Okay.
The problem is these guys unrolled their
window and did one of these and the
cops turned their lights off and pulled
over to the side of the road because
again,
black jeep government plates,
it doesn't matter if we're on the side
trying to catch popcorn like a couple of
clowns so that this point, I'm
starting to get really scared, right?
Because 15 minutes later we
pull up into this neighborhood,
small boarded up houses and little
things with like those, those shutters,
those metal grates are down over the
front. And I'm thinking, oh my God,
this is serious.
This is not harmless fun.
This isn't just people having fun with
some tourists. This is the real deal.
And I'm cut off from the world and I
haven't been this scared since prom,
98 different story. And I'm like,
freaking out here. You know,
don't want to get out of
the jeep or off the jeep.
I don't want to get into the house.
I don't want to go down to the basement
of the house. And the guy says, look,
get in there and everything's gonna be
okay. Pardon me if I don't believe you.
Okay.
But that was the message.
And at this point I'm scared. I don't
know what to do. Can't run anywhere.
I've got nowhere to go.
So we go in, we sit down,
they're bashing my friend. And because
now he decided to play the Dune.
Do you know who my father is?
Game works every time. And, uh,
so I'm explaining, look,
I'm an English teacher man.
I teach 11 year old kids in refugees,
how to speak English. That is it.
They're calling bs on that. You're
a spy. You're a unregistered.
You're an unregistered foreign agent.
Nobody had heard of that until
Michael Flynn. Thanks Flynn.
Not Don't have to explain that one
every time. So it's a no, you know,
we're on our way to Lipa.
It's got the best food in town.
I heard they got the best food anywhere
in the city and he gets heated.
This agent, it's heated and
incredulous and a little tense.
A little too close to my face and says,
obviously you don't know anything about
Serbian food if you think Lipa has the
best food in the city.
And I thought, all right,
now we're on to something better here.
What about his knocked Pete's
on Yon Belgrade, man, look,
if you haven't tried stepping via to
you don't know anything about this and
you're not qualified to
talk about Serbian foods.
So I ask him what he
orders when he goes there.
This is something that changes the energy
of the conversation. At Art of charm,
we call this changing the
frame of the conversation.
It goes from me being
interrogated by a crazy,
deranged drunk state state security
agent to a somewhat equal footing
discussion, if you will, on
Serbian food and culture,
and the key is that I kept behaving like
I wasn't in trouble and that everything,
even though he was enraged at certain
points, even totally irrationally,
I'm remaining as completely
calm on the outside anyways,
I can obviously inside and freaking
out without any regard whatsoever,
and I ask him, look man, what
are you order when you go there?
I'm going to go there tonight. Wink, wink,
right when I got out of here
and I'm setting that anchor,
man, let me Outta here.
I even invited him to go with us.
Seriously.
Now this type of thing is called
the Benjamin Franklin effect.
When you ask somebody for advice,
when you ask somebody for recommendations,
they feel an affinity for you.
They feel an affinity for
what you are representing.
They feel an affinity for helping you
and it's a backwards rationalization that
they create in the brain. Benjamin
Franklin used this really, really well.
He would borrow books from people that
hated him and they would become friends.
That's why this is called
the Benjamin Franklin effect.
So we started talking about a homebrew
liqueur called Rakia. And of course,
the only thing that's Serbian people,
like more than talking about drinking,
is drinking. So I said, I think
I could use a drink right now.
It's about eight o'clock in the morning.
Don't judge me. Desperate times,
desperate measures.
So he gets up and you suddenly walks
out of the room and I'm thinking, okay,
great. This is my time. Activate
eighth grade taekwondo skills, uh,
wrestling, middle school wrestling.
Sure. Leg catch something, right?
And then Dee come out and run.
That's the plan. Sounds good, right?
What could go wrong? And sometimes
the unknown is scarier than the known.
You know, you don't know what's
going to happen. This guy's gone.
I can hear my friend
and his butt kicked in.
The next room is getting punched in
the ever. I mean, it's just awful.
I'm sitting there like to things saw,
hadn't come out at this point or it
would have been losing it, right.
There's like sharp objects in there and
pipes coming out of the wall and these
little rusty things and I'm like,
that could get attached to a part
of my body if I'm not careful.
So I could see him coming back and he's
got a club in his hand and I'm like,
oh my God, this is how it ends,
you know? And I thought, all right,
I've got about a whatever percent chance
of just getting away from this guy and
figuring out how to dodge it or
tackle him or something like that.
And about 10 feet away from me,
I realize it's not a club but a bottle
and it's a bottle of rocky up and he
slams it down the table. He pours a couple
of glasses of his stuff and he says,
well,
you know,
we're just going to wait for your friend
and my friend to get done talking.
And I thought, okay, well
look, I mean this is not nice,
but this is an airplane mask.
Situations like help yourself before
you help the other people next to you.
So I'm wondering how I can get myself out
of this and get my friend out of this.
But so far I'm pretty much out of ideas.
The first idea I have is drink that shot
and then regroup and then come up with
a new plan. So I realize this
could still go sideways, right?
This is still happening. We're, this
is a heated conversation, right?
We're going back and forth. And finally
I hear from the next room, hey, you know,
your friend has a big mouth. I'm shutting
it for him. How's it going over there?
Right? And these guys don't really
know that I can understand Serbian.
So I figured this could really,
really be bad for my friend and it
could just as easily be bad for me.
This just right now I feel okay with it.
Right? And your brain wants to do that.
It wants to think everything's gonna be
fine. Everything's gonna be all right.
It doesn't necessarily mean it has any
basis in reality. So I said, look man,
I feel really sick. You know,
I've been awake for a long time.
You're feeding me this stuff. I'm stressed
out, I'm dehydrated. I just need water.
And I know there's no water in there.
I know those rusty pipes have no water.
I know they don't have any water.
I know the jeep doesn't probably have
any water because they finished the beers
they were drinking as they drove
us to this place. So he goes,
all right, stay here. And I said,
of course, where? Where would I go?
So he gets up and he goes in the
other room and after a long time,
it feels like an eternity.
I hear the jeep doors close
and I've realized they're gone.
They left and I don't know
if they're coming back.
So I grow and grabbed my friend, dude,
get up, we got to go. He's half limping,
half being carried out of this place.
And we go to a restaurant a few
hundred meters away, a few blocks away.
And I know what we must have looked like
because we're covered in dirt and blood
and popcorn and the waitress is coming
up and she goes, hi, how can I interest?
Immediately doesn't even
finish. The sentence starts
walking away and I thought,
wow,
we look like zombies.
We look like zombies that were junkies
when they were alive and now are zombies.
And so the police come, the regular
police, thank God who take us,
get arrest us again,
take us to a police station instead
of an underground torture chamber.
So I'm still on, I'm still
ahead here. This is good. Right?
And then at this point I
am getting interrogated by
the police captain and he's
just like, what is going,
where did you even come from?
And this town looking like
this at this hour, what are,
what is going on here? And my Serbians,
not that my smoking, Serbians,
not that great.
Especially with a couple of booze,
a bits of booze in me that
hour, no sleep. And I'm new.
I can understand more than I can speak.
That's how it goes with foreign languages.
So I asked him if he spoke German.
He spoke German and he said,
no, I don't speak German,
but my girlfriend is a German teacher.
Thank God. So I get on the phone with her,
I'm on the phone in the police station
in Serbia telling a police captains
girlfriend in German.
What happened to me when I got arrested
by their secret service telling her this
ridiculous story left out the part
about robbing a popcorn vendor.
And at first she's like,
okay, I'm not sure I believe
anything that you're saying,
but she's a language teacher
and I'm a language teacher.
I'm there to teach English. So I start
asking her, look, do you know my boss?
Do you know the person
who ran this convention?
Do you know the person who
wrote the textbook where I
did the English voiceover?
Do you know the other teachers that I
met at these various mixers for teachers
when I was teaching language in Belgrade?
And that is one,
her attitude changed since we had
these mutual connections. See,
actually believe what was going on
here because she didn't know me,
but she knew people that knew me.
Okay.
Again, it's all about relationship.
She's not buying who I was.
He's not buying the story until she
buys who I was. So she's embarrassed.
She's embarrassed on behalf
of the country. She tells
the police captain, look,
let us go. They cut us
loose, and they did,
and were obviously look like we're up to
something covered. Drunk, covered a dirt,
blood and popcorn.
And so as you can see,
the advanced social skills that are taught
this rapport, this networking concept,
the ABG big concepts that
we talked about today,
and the concepts that we teach at the
art of charm can not only help you keep
your job, get a new job, start your
business, keep your side also going,
or just help you advance
in your personal life.
But they're actually the reason I'm still
kicking and talking to you here today,
and that is my time.
Thank you so much.
This has been a real honor and
I appreciate your attention.