Uh, want to talk about
grief a bit? So I've
lost a number of,
like I mentioned close friends and
a mentor in the last 12 months.
And uh, you mentioned your
husband who passed away earlier.
Uh, and if I get any facts wrong,
obviously please correct me.
But colorectal cancer 42,
I'm 40,
which really caught my attention and my,
the first time I had an opportunity to
go abroad outside of the United States
was to Japan as an exchange student.
And I lived with a family,
went to Japanese high school and I'm
still close to that family 25 years later.
And the father and that host family
is my second father effectively.
And I planned on bringing my American
family to Japan later this year to meet
them for the first time,
my two families.
And I just found out that my host
father's in the hospital, uh,
late stage,
very aggressive cancer diagnosed,
uh, as metastasized, probably will
pass away in the next two months.
And what kind of cancer? Uh, it's,
I would have to go back to
the email because it was,
it was very emotional and then cognitively
difficult for me to translate because
there's a lot, it's in Japanese and it
was all specialized medical terminology,
but it's, it's in the lung, it's in
the liver. Uh, a lifelong smoker,
very typical for Japanese at that age.
I think it might be also a sofa.
Jeal uh, so this is, Ha has had
me thinking about grief and, uh,
is there anything I should do
in advance to prepare for that?
And they'd just be very curious if
you're willing to talk about it,
to describe your experience of grieving.
And you could start at any point in time,
but as it relates to your experience with,
with your husband,
and certainly after that we
can get into it. But I mean,
you've done a tremendous job
of highlighting the types
of diagnostic tools and
preventative tools that people can
use, which, which we'll talk about. But
I don't even know how to
think about grief. I mean,
I don't know if I've allowed myself
to ever experience it before,
but I know I'm going to be hit with a
hammer. A couple of friends that I did.
No, I did. They have passed away.
And it's been very recent that it hasn't
been this close. These are friends,
but they're not a second father to
me. Uh, and I think in a sense the,
um, the mentor passed away.
It did hit me pretty hard,
but I've only in the last six to 12 months
actually been allowing myself to feel
more things. That's a much
longer story. But, uh,
I've had a lot of it kind of conflicted
relationship with this person.
I know I've had a lot of armor for
decades that I've built up over time for a
lot of different reasons and it's
been very useful for some things,
for protecting me,
but I've realized that it also keeps a
lot in that is very ultimately corrosive.
So I'm trying to develop
more of an ability to feel
and instead of looking at it
as a liability,
um,
slash I don't know. How do you,
how do you describe grief? Um,
I mean, I can, I can talk a little bit
about my personal experience. You know,
I had a, I was on top of the
world, had this great job,
had two beautiful children and
of course a wonderful husband.
I have to say we were having challenges,
some challenges in our marriage because
I think I had this just sort of out of
the blue success and some suddenly
became a household name and had all this
attention,
which I think can put a lot of pressure
on a relationship or suddenly it doesn't
feel the power dynamic doesn't
feel as equal. Right. Um,
but, uh, you know, we were,
we were really, you know,
and love and enjoying our lives.
And,
uh, you know, just out of the
blue, Jay hadn't been feeling well.
He had been tired. He'd been traveling
and we kept thinking, oh, east,
we have two little kids. He's
covering the Oj Simpson trial. He was,
uh, you know, his schedule was crazy.
And then out of the blue he
just was doubled over in pain.
And our nanny who was Irish
at the time called and said,
chase doubled over in pain and uh,
I don't know what to do.
So he didn't have a doctor like
so many young men, which is,
you know, if anybody
takes, there are many,
I think takeaways from our conversation,
I hope.
But one is that men especially,
I think because women go
see gynecologists honestly,
that a lot of men don't go
and get physicals or they
don't even have a GP or an
internist. And Shave was one of those
guys who played lacrosse and football and,
and college and was never smoked ever.
I don't think he ever even
tried a cigarette. I never,
I don't think he even tried pot ever. It's
sort of crazy when you think about it.
Drank moderately, uh, took pretty
good care of himself. I mean,
and uh, and it just, boom,
he had stage four metastatic colon cancer.
So we went from one day,
just everything was great.
We were buying a house in the country and,
or had a house in the country
and we're really enjoying that.
And Jay was riding horses in central
park and doing his thing professionally.
And I was at the today show and our
girls were great. And, uh, we had,
I mean,
Carrie was less than a year at the time
or just had turned a year old when he
was diagnosed on April 3rd,
1998, 1997. Sorry,
he died nine months later in January.
But,
um, you know, it's just, it's so,
it's so debilitating and chattering
and destabilizing and, you know,
it's such a process.
And I was in such denial and he
was one of these very smart people,
but he didn't want to
know about his health.
He didn't want to know the gory details.
I don't know why,
because he was so smart,
intellectually curious and
interested and I don't know,
maybe he knew. So I kept all this
stuff from him, which I really regret.
I would say, oh, there's only
shadows on your liver. Don't worry.
It's going to be okay. Uh,
we're going to figure it out.
I remember sending his scans to Nih,
you know,
cause I had a lot of
connections because of my job.
And I remember very prominent cancer
scientists calling me and saying,
Oh God, this is, this is really bad. He,
I arranged for him to
get hepatic artery pump,
which pushed the chemo directly to
his liver that was covered. I mean,
the tumor burden on his liver was
awful. And, uh, anyway,
so I was, I went into,
I think my,
my husband John says I'm very
good in an emergency. You know,
I get very focused and very
proactive and driven and I went into,
I am going to try to fix this mode.
And uh,
so I was sort of doing that,
I think to avoid the grief because I had
to do something and it was just, I mean,
what can I say? It's the worst
thing in the world to see someone,
first of all,
your life just changed in an instant
then to see someone suffering then to try
to figure out how can you help
somebody. I mean, it's just,
it's really overwhelming.
And, uh, you know,
I think my grieving process began the
day he was diagnosed because my doctor,
who was the internist, Jay went to see
when he was in this pain. You know,
he pulled me aside into one of those
little patient rooms in the hospital and
said, [inaudible] the, this is really bad.
That the prognosis is very bleak.
So what do you do with that?
Except for do everything you
possibly can to change the outcome,
which you realize you probably
can't change anyway. It's a very,
uh, challenging thing to
deal with, but you know, I,
maybe my regrets will help you
with your situation and that
I never really said to Jay,
what are your hopes and
dreams for your kids?
Can you write the girls a letter?
Can we videotape you talking to them,
uh,
to say everything I wanted to say to
him because that was an acknowledgement
that he was gonna die and
I just couldn't do that.
So maybe if things are so bleak for
this person is so special to you.
First of all, you need to tell
him no and you need to write him.
Maybe go see him and feel that
that you don't have any regrets.
Thank you.