Soundcheck,
uh,
could you mouth the blue ball for a
second and tell me what you had for
breakfast today? For breakfast
I had egg whites, onions,
chicken and one slice of Bacon.
How much weight have you gained in the
last 12 months? 40 pounds. Optimal.
The hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism
living this year.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs.
Your one stop shop for all
things graphic design related.
I've used 99 designs for everything
from banner ads to book covers,
including sketches and mock ups
that led to the four hour body,
which later became number one
New York Times Number One,
Wall Street Journal and the brainstorming
and a lot of it took place with
designers from around the world.
And here's how it works.
Whether you need a t shirt,
a business card, a website,
an APP thumbnail,
whatever it might be,
you submit that project and
designers from around the world,
we'll send you sketches
and mock ups and designs.
You choose your favorite and you have an
original that you love or you get your
money back.
It's that straightforward.
And many of you who are listening have
already used it and created some amazing
things that I'll be sharing in the future,
but in the meantime,
if you want to see some of my
competitions, some of the book covers,
as well as get a free $99 upgrade,
goto 99 designs.com forward slash Tim,
that's 99 designs.com forward slash.
Tim this episode is brought
to you by Athletic Greens.
I get asked all the time, if you could
only use one supplement, what would it be?
And my answer is
inevitably Athletic Greens,
it is your all in one
nutritional insurance.
I recommended it in the four hour body,
did not get paid for that and I
travel with it to avoid getting sick.
I take it in the mornings to
ensure optimal performance.
It just covers all my basis.
If I can't get what I need through whole
food meals throughout the rest of the
day, and you can get 50 oh my
gosh, 50% off. Yes, 50% off.
If you go to athleticgreens.com forward
slash Tim that's athleticgreens.com
forward slash. Tim, check it out.
It's tasty, but more important.
It will help you not screw up when
you're doing your nutritional planning.
For me, it just covers the
basis, takes a load off my mind,
puts a lot in my buddy and uh, check it
out. athleticgreens.com forward slash Tim.
Hello squirrels, chipmunks and
muskrats. Why muskrats still be racist?
We welcome everybody here because this
is the Tim Ferriss show where my job is
to attempt to deconstruct world
class performers and teachers,
whether they are investors,
chess prodigies, actors,
musicians or entrepreneurs.
In this particular case,
this episode features Noah Kagan.
Noah Kagan is a friend of mine
I've known for many years.
He was number thirty@numberfouratmint.com
which was sold for God knows how much
money, I think a hundred plus billion
dollars and is the chief Sumo I,
he cofounder of sumo me.com which offers
free tools to help grow web traffic
among other things.
Also a top rated Taco connoisseur.
I'm not sure we're going to get into that,
but he has most important created for
products that have made more than seven
figures and that is what we're going to
delve into in this particular episode.
Lots of tactics, tools, routines,
and so on that Noah has used himself and
has helped other people to use and Noah
was also my co teacher in the
Tim Ferriss experiment episode,
build a business where we led Cindy,
a novice entrepreneur into scaling and
launching her business in one week and
there are a lot of the behind the scenes
goodies where if you go to itunes.com
forward slash timferriss that is two hours
and two ss a itunes.com forward slash
Tim Ferriss.
I think there's an hour of bonus footage
with some really nitty gritty call
script sales and marketing stuff
that I think you will enjoy.
But this episode by itself
Superstrong Standalone,
lots of takeaways, lots of resources, and
if you don't want to write it all down,
you can get the show
notes@fourhourworkweek.com
forward slash podcast,
that's four hour Fou,
r h o u r four hour workweek.com
forward slash podcast.
Without further ado, here
is miss you, Noah Kagan.
Enjoy Noah,
my man.
Welcome to the show. Thank
you for having me, Tim.
I have been looking forward to this for
quite a while because every time we talk
and we've known each other for years,
I come away with notes upon notes of
things that I want to test or try.
So I'm hoping and expecting sternly,
like an angry,
yeah, that's a lot of pressure.
This as we will have this,
but for people who don't have uh,
too much context,
you were number 30 at Facebook.
Uh, you are number four employee.
It meant which sold to intuit for
a hundred plus million dollars.
And you've created multiple products
now that have earned seven figures. Uh,
what else should people know perhaps
as background or what would you like to
tell them about as context? I thought
that was pretty good man. I was like, wow,
whoever that guy is, he
sounds pretty good. Hire that
man. Speech writers. I mean,
you know,
the,
the only other thing is,
is like I came out like a lot of
people who are listening, you know,
I came out of Berkeley or whatever
college you come out to and I worked at a
corporate job at Intel sitting in
a cubicle. Um, and then, you know,
I didn't really use it,
networking or any of that kind of stuff
to kind of eventually go to these kind
of cool companies and be able to create
my own businesses that give me the
freedom to do a lot of
things I want to do.
And you are in Austin, Texas, is that
right? Yes sir. Where did you grow up?
I grew up in bay area, about a mile
and a half from the apple headquarters.
So near Cupertino
somewhere. Yeah. You know,
the question of why there
has been a mass exodus,
it would seem from cities like New York
City and San Francisco to Austin is one
I've never really heard. Uh, you
answer. So maybe I can just ask you,
why is Austin becomes such a hotbed and
why did you choose to move to Austin?
Yeah, I mean, I actually interned
like in 2000, about 10 years
ago and I came out here and, uh,
I never heard of the place. I didn't even
know. I mean, in Texas now it's, you know,
because the Internet,
people know that there's a,
there's places inside of Texas
they have like photos. Uh,
but I never knew what Austin was about.
And I came here and I had sex with this
person and then I got drunk and it was
like, like, what's that book,
Lord of the flies where it's like the
young kids take over in high wind.
Yes. It's basically like
that. But we have a city.
So I came here and I was like, how
come no one else is here? You know,
you're paying half as much as the bay
area for housing. We actually see grass,
a lot of grass around us.
Um, you got a lot of Tacos,
which is what I'm known for and it's like
one of the capitals that Tacos in the
nation and it's kind
of like, um, you know,
it's like what the barrier was
probably like 10 years before now.
It's just like you're packed and
you're paying the same prices. Uh,
and I think also fundamentally
there's a few key things for you.
But fundamentally I just,
I didn't want to also just be around
startups talking about their funding a all
day long.
And so Austin provided a lifestyle
from me where it was more affordable,
really attractive women, a
really good outside life.
Like when I leave the office,
I have a good lifestyle. It just
really fit that fit, that balance.
And that's why I think it's,
you know,
it's one of the fastest growing
cities in the nation right now.
Yeah. It's one of my favorite cities. I
almost moved there after college actually.
It was between,
uh,
Austin NSF and I didn't make it to the
final round of interviews for trilogy
software. So that made the decision
for me. So I was came very close.
I could have forked another
way and ended up in Austin.
Did you get like flown out and like
first class in the limo experience with
trilogy?
I don't think I made it that far.
I think,
I think they recognized a
terrible potential employee
very quickly and decided
that, uh, I would be more trouble than I
was worth, which is probably accurate. Uh,
you know,
you know what's funny about that? Like
I got a job offer, well, I applied,
I've applied for Google twice and
I've been rejected twice and I'm like,
is Google really good or am I that bad?
Or is it just like,
I meant to kind of run my own thing.
And I remember what I did
my interview with Google,
I couldn't remember how to do division
that makes it hard to get a job at
Google. I imagined, I was like, dude,
I gotta use my calc. I gotta use my phone.
Do you mind? He's like, okay, it's not,
you're not gonna get the job done.
So like if you don't,
if you can't do 12 times 12 no,
I'm sorry I have some bad news
and lets you run it. You know,
for our cafeteria jobs.
Occasional good. It was the
division man anyways, so awesome.
I mean coming back to it,
it was just more of a,
after being the barrier around
engineers and all that stuff. My life,
I wanted something a little
more affordable women and
outside and just kind of
like a slower lifestyle.
I would say for younger people I would
actually recommend going to these busier
cities. Cause you're
surrounding yourself with like
hungry, hungry people better or
what age would you say that is?
I'm saying up until 30 I would say like
a really populated city personally. And
that's what I did because you're around,
people are hustling and it's
really inspiring and it's
motivating and there's a
meetup every day and we, you
know, we have that in Austin,
but it's nowhere near the level
of the bay area or New York.
And so I'd say if you're going to you,
I would want to be around that and get
connections to that and experience that.
Cause you're, I mean,
if you look at Austin,
like how many big companies have come
out of Austin? Tim, like name too,
Dell and blank. I'm sure there
are others. You could, okay.
So [inaudible] was actually
really good fuels. What'd she say?
I said Willie Nelson biofuels.
The Willie Nelson Dude. I mean, I was
going to say it like a, we'd joke,
but like name, name to that came
out of the bay area. I mean,
you could go on for days,
right? Yeah. So, and that's
a different special. Yeah.
And You have a density in SF that
you don't have an Austin, namely,
I guess what I mean by that is you
have the peninsula and the bay area,
but just within San Francisco you have,
let's just call it 700,000 people,
very densely packed in. So getting
to events, meeting New People,
uh,
bumping into the icons are billionaires
you want to meet is as easy as going to
a handful of different coffee shops.
Whereas in Austin,
in my experience having
gone to south by southwest,
so many times it's more spread out
much like Los Angeles or those types of
serendipitous moments are a
little harder to engineer. I mean
the funniest one from me,
I was walking in San Francisco a few years
ago and I'm talking about paypal with
my friend Boris and then I'm like,
oh my God.
Literally the Guy Walking in front of
us was Peter Teal and I was like, Peter,
we had a question about paypal.
Could you mind if I ask you,
is the cofounder of paypal for people
wondering who's in the first money into
Facebook? And another actually another
guest on the podcast as well. Uh,
the,
the place I'd like to go next and I think
maybe working backwards make sense to
you.
I'd love to experiment
with just frontloading this
episode with a lot of tools
and tactics that people can play with, uh,
as soon as they listen to this episode.
What are some of the tools,
whether they're apps or otherwise,
that you are really into at the moment
or that you find extremely useful?
Yeah.
So I'll give you my top
things that I use in,
I think everyone should literally
use right now and go do these things.
Number one, and this is, it's
not even an APP or anything,
it's speeding up your mouse pad.
It's the number one productivity hack
cause you're on your computer almost all
the day. Go to your settings, speed up
your mouse, but double what you're at.
It takes a few minutes to get used to,
but you realize like holy crap,
everything starts at the top.
So speed up your mousepad,
everything will get faster. I really love
that one. I, because anytime I'm on a,
someone's slower, I'm like,
wow, it's so slow. What's
wrong? Is Your computer broken?
So you're just going to
system preferences and then
keyboard. And then when the mouse track
pad, actually it's one of those three.
Yeah.
Trackpad yeah.
You Click on track pad and then you go to
your tracking speed and move it to the,
basically almost the fastest.
And then your keyboard is,
or the way that you get around computer
to significantly faster. Got It. Uh,
let me just go through a
list of things that I love.
Other things on the computer. Alfred
APP, if you're not using Alfred App,
it's free. And basically instead
of having to even move your mouse,
you can just hit a launch bar and then
type in whatever app you want and it'll
automatically loaded.
So if I wanted to open Firefox,
I can just hit command space for our
type of hit enter and it's loaded instead
of me having to move my mouse anywhere
on the screen. Is that uh, I've,
I've heard of Alfred before I use,
uh, I guess it's spotlight, uh,
just built into the [inaudible] waste
lower man. It's just a lot slower.
It's way slower.
And with Alfred App you can do contacts.
I can do math with it sometimes
when I need help a lot of
the times. Okay. Got It.
When I have to do this division.
So Alfred APP is an awesome one,
especially for getting around your Mac.
Don't know if they have a PC version yet,
but who uses PC? Um, I don't know.
Do you feel bad when they have like
when people are using hotmail or PC?
I'm like Rosa everything. Okay.
Is there, okay, let me go.
I'm going to go more because I didn't
know what I want to give the meaty stuff
we um,
I use,
so let's get into apps like web and
other things for this is one is a kill or
one, it's a chrome extension called
Facebook newsfeed eradicator. Hmm.
And this one is amazing and I used to work
at Facebook and I know all of us, you,
you have this like weird thing where
you're so used to going phase where you
just type in Ffa and your, your
hand, you can't even control it.
And so we install the
Facebook newsfeed eradicator.
You'd go to Facebook and it blocks
your news feed and then you get there.
And I do it.
I'd probably do 10 times a day.
I go to Facebook and I get there and
there's nothing there. And I'm like, well,
I guess there's nothing for me
to do today. Everyone's asleep.
And I go back to my work.
Um,
because I think people are looking for
so many different productivity hacks.
I just try to focus on the big ones that
are really helpful in that one is huge
cause I go Facebook,
nothing's happening.
Go back to my day and get the
things done I want to get done. Um,
I use schedule once. Yeah, great program
me to love [inaudible] you use that too?
I do.
Yeah.
It was introduced to me by Andrew Warner
of Mixergy who's done thousands of
interviews and I as soon
as he booked me using that.
So I was the one who is speaking. You
do that. You make Tim Ferris on that.
I don't blame him though.
If you said Oh it's so nice and it's,
it prevents so much confusion. Do you
want to just explain how sure. So good.
The reason I like it, they have a $99 a
year plan. Make sure you find that one,
cause they have all
these different options,
but you can get in there and get
the $99 a year. When I believe,
and the nicest thing about it
is it's such an annoying thing.
So like if me and him wanted
to meet, I'd be like, Tim,
are you free next Tuesday at four? You
would have to come back and say, no,
how about Wednesday? And
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
With schedule once it connects
automatically to your calendar,
when you send it to someone,
you could set your preferences.
So like I am very specific preferences.
Like I don't do meetings on Thursday,
I don't do meetings before 10:00 AM. Uh,
I don't do meetings during lunchtime.
I don't have anything after five.
And I only do meetings for
15 minutes because I really,
if it's longer than that,
like we need to figure out
why it's going so long.
And then basically I send
that to you and say, hey Tim,
let's talk for that kind of period.
And then it makes it really easy for you
to just compare that to your scheduled,
choose the time and it auto goes into
my calendar and we're done. Yeah. And,
and one of the other benefits,
uh, that I noticed, number one,
the first thing someone will see when
they click the link to grab a time is
it'll say, set your time zone
total in. That avoids all
of the confusion. Like, oh,
sorry,
I thought it was 4:00 PM CST
and not PSD.
And then you have to book it again.
It avoids all of that and it
sends reminders to people. Um,
I've been using it for instance, if
I'm doing, let's just say recording,
and I don't typically do this,
but if I'm,
if I were recording five podcasts in a
day or I had some type of batching like
that, I would block out an entire day
in say one hour increments or two hour
increments and then have everybody just
pick the time that is remaining and
available because it also happens if
you're emailing separate people competing
for a certain day,
let's just say you'll,
you'll book one person than the other
person will walk at the same time and it's
just a huge headache. So this thing
saves just dozens of hours of headache.
Totally, totally worth it. Um,
other ones? Yeah, no, go for
it. Uh, other ones, followup.cc.
Uh, this is my, one of my secret weapons.
Uh, I basically can never forget anything.
It's like I call it my Jewish mother and
my inbox because my mom never forgets
anything. She writes everything down. Um,
and so it followups you see does is like
if I'm emailing Tim, which you know,
we do from time to time,
I'll email him and in my bcc I'll put
when I want to remind, remember it.
So what it does is that I'll put like
oneDay@followupcc.cc and in a day it will
email me back and say,
hey,
here's the email that you sent in the
reminder about it. So you can do this for,
people would be like,
hey,
I'll check in with you in two months
or I'll follow up with, you know,
even for things you want to do as a to
do, like, let me do this in two months.
So let me check this email in a week.
You can either afford it or BCC it
and it'll automatically remind you.
And I've just found that it basically
helps me never forget anything because
sometimes you just keep it in your inbox.
And I personally don't want anything
in my inbox if I can and the subs would
move out anything or remember anything
that I want. So I highly recommend that.
Yeah. Automating followups.
Super. I was just so nice. I mean,
and there's two email tracking
tools for open to stuff like that.
I just wouldn't follow up. Kind of the
lightest weight, easiest for me to use.
Other tools that I've been using, a lot
of using perch.ceo is totally free. Uh,
for everyone who is doing,
I know a lot of your people are starting
either starting or running their own
businesses. Perch provides free, um,
people to people like a Webcam.
So we have four people that work remote
and it's kind of weird cause they were
like, what the hell are these
guys doing in the office?
And we're wondering what
they're doing sometimes.
And so [inaudible] gives you the chance
if you have two iPads or two phones, uh,
to see each other.
And so it helps for communication.
And also just like being a part of a
team versus like a random remote person.
Very cool. Yeah, I hadn't heard of
that one. I really liked that one. Um,
I like my fitness, so I'll go to a
few on the phone and web. They're,
they're kind of mixed. I use my fitness
pal.com almost. Well, I use it every day.
Um, and I use it because if you really
want to lose weight or gain weight,
which were, I mean, you know,
we can talk about a bit.
I've gained 40 pounds in the past four
months and now I'm losing 40 pounds in
the next five months or six months.
The hub,
just, just so people understand
what's going on here. Oh, how much,
how much of this 40 would you
say is muscle versus fat? Well,
I don't know the exact, I didn't,
I probably should have been more.
If you had to estimate how
much of that is muscle?
Probably like half and half maybe.
I don't know the exact number.
I think it's a bit more, honestly, so
just, we'll come back to this guys.
But Noah sent me a of himself.
I hadn't seen him in about six months
and could not recognize the eye.
Um, now granted you're hitting a bicep
pose in the gym. No, you are. I'm kidding.
But it was a shot from the gym and
I was just like, what the hell?
It was a naked selfie dude. Come on
since Tuesday. Naked Selfie Tuesdays.
That's kind of our routine.
Uh, so we'll come back to that.
But what you can talk about, what
do you ever use? Myfitnesspal?
So I use my fitness pal and I track
every single thing I eat and it,
and it's not so much that I want to
be OCD and obsessive about like, Oh,
I have to check everything and I want
to count everything. But it gives me,
if you really want to
accomplish something,
and this is a tool that if you want
to lose five pounds, it'll say like,
eat this amount of calories
and this much macros,
and in four weeks you'll hit five
pounds. And so it's like, well,
why wouldn't I do that?
And it just makes me more accountable
to help me hit the objectives of what I
want to hit.
And so it's like,
am I under my macros and the amounts
I wanna be hitting today or not?
And it just makes my life so much
simpler to be able to figure that out.
And over time you kind of even know,
you start knowing what your,
you know much more about the food that
you're actually putting your mouth about.
Like how much protein a chicken has
versus a steak versus like, um, you know,
like a quest bar,
which is one of my favorite protein bars.
Doug, definitely. And uh, for those
people wondering what macros are a,
that's just referring to
the macro nutrients. So the,
the what percentage of the food you're
eating calories you're eating are coming
from fat,
protein or carbohydrates generally.
And then when people refer to
micronutrients, those would be,
say the trace minerals and so on
and so forth. Vitamins. There we go.
And I'm actually experimenting with some,
some somewhat unusual macros right now,
which are about 80% fat calories,
15% protein and 5% or less carbohydrates,
typically less than 30 grams a day
just to optimize for brain function as
opposed to body function, which
is working pretty well. Uh,
what have you noticed about that?
Uh, I've noticed that when I hit,
and I'm using a device called
the precision xtra with x
Tra for tracking ketones,
uh,
at at a very precise level that you would
hope since it's called the precision
Xtra. Uh, it gives you
a readout in millimolar.
So instead of peeing on a Keto sticks,
these things you can buy at Walgreens
or wherever to indicate if you're in
Ketosis or not,
you can get a concentration.
So I'll prick my finger and
check in and they'll say, oh,
you're at 0.7 millimeters
or 1.5 millimeters and four,
my optimal mental performance.
I've just noticed that I perform
best at between say 1.1 and uh,
let's just call it 1.7 millimoles.
And My, my belief up to this point,
because I hadn't had a good tool
that was a nice quest Burp, uh,
up to this point has been
the deeper the Ketosis,
the better my brain will perform
because the brain likes ketones.
But for me that doesn't
appear to be the case.
So I've been able to get super
specific and sort of use my,
the food I put in my mouth,
like a sniper shot for mental performance,
which is awesome. Um, so that's been the
primary benefit. And along with that,
I've noticed for instance,
all of my morning fatigue for say the
first half hour of the day is completely
gone. I mean 100% gone. I
wake up and I'm ready to go,
which is has never been the
case when I'm carved dependent.
So That's interesting.
It's funny, I was thinking,
I think a lot about, I mean,
I think we don't think about how much we,
how much sleep affects us and we all
know sleep more and it's better. Um,
I actually used to work in
bed sheets at Macy's. Um, so
wait,
now you worked in bed sheets,
like you were selling bed sheets or
you'd wrap yourself up like Casper,
Casper the ghost?
No, I sold bedsheets. The old woman,
uh, on commission. How old were you?
How old were you when he did that? That
was in high school. All right. And uh,
so I learned a lot about like bedding
and we also worked in a towels.
But one of the things I was gonna suggest
is like we're were talking about apps
and tools. I think a lot people don't
think about their physical tools. So, uh,
I've tried to optimize my bed. Um, I
think I've done a pretty good job. So the,
the company that I use
a coming on Amazon now,
the one that I just tried actually a week
ago that I'm going to be upgraded into
is called Tuft and needle.
It's a lot like these kind of hipster
guys out in Arizona. Really Nice.
And they have like the
super comfortable mattress.
And then I found there's a guy literally
like in the Middle Midwest isn't,
he looks like your, your uncle. And
He created a thing called my pillow.
We heard of this.
No I haven't. I've heard of Tuft
and needle though. That one,
that name has come up a couple
of times a month friends.
So I have to take a look at those guys.
Yeah,
I can put you in touch with them.
I went and slept on it and laid on it like
a few days ago. It was great. And then,
and I'm going to upgrade to that.
They have a,
and then I use a pillow called my pillow,
which is like try phoned.
I don't even know what he does,
but it's really good because what I
realized is like the more that I'm
comfortable in bed, I just feel better.
Absolutely. And I wake up feeling pretty,
I'm good every morning and I use a
company called parachute for the bedding.
And so those are the kind
of the combination that I've
been using. And I'm like,
damn, I'm feeling really good when I wake
up in the morning from all that stuff.
And what, uh, what does the, just to,
to come back to two
things or a few things.
The nightly rituals, what does,
what does, what does the last say,
two hours of your days typically
look like? And when do you go to bed?
When do you wake up,
et Cetera?
The, my night varies a bit more. Um,
but what I do at night is I try
to put myself to sleep by reading.
I noticed I'd try to watch shows or
anything like that and then I just get
stimulated. So I'll go
to bed and I, you know,
I won't always have to
read a business book,
which my brother had always
kind of gave me crap about.
Like there's other things
besides nonfiction.
And so I've been reading like
Jack reacher books. Like,
I don't know if anyone has common,
you know,
suggestions for books that
are fiction that are good.
Like the Martian was probably
one of the best ones.
Is that,
that's a graphic novels.
Uh, it's, it's movie Tom Cruise is in,
which is all surprisingly good last year.
Got It.
But I'll read,
I'll basically just try to read and that
helps me go to sleep versus stimulating
me. Uh, like I would watch shows like
big love, which wasn't that good. Um,
or now I'm watching daredevil,
but basically I realized like if I wash
this off in bed, I don't go to sleep.
So now I just do books and said, and I've
been doing that for a little while. Um,
so like the Martian was
an amazing fiction book.
It's probably one of the
best in the past year or two
that the, the whole story of the
Martian, I think, what's his name?
Andrew wire or weird or something
like the whole story of how that was,
uh,
I guess self published or very,
very small to start with and just
developed a massive cult following.
Then the audio book was a huge,
huge blockbuster hit and it's taken off
and I think it's now being developed
into a movie or maybe the movies or
going out and I love that type of story.
It's just like 50 shades of grey.
Everyone turned it down. Um,
and it just became a viral
sensation on its own,
which then led to it becoming
a blockbuster, like the
book, go the fuck to sleep.
The children's book that was leaked as
a pdf among people in the publishing
world became this huge buzz item
and then became a bestseller.
Uh, that's awesome.
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
What time do you typically go to bed and
when have you found you performed best
or how, how do you perform best in
terms of going to bed and waking up?
What are the two? One thing I do
is I don't keep a phone in my room.
I think that's a common thing.
We wake up and we have a phone right in
our room and we just get all stimulated
by that. So I keep my phone in a separate
room, hallways, um, going to see various,
I think when I'm excited,
like I remember that Guy Steve Have
Lena from like five to 10 years ago.
We had really good content.
He was very like strict about wake up at
this time and don't wake up this time.
So I've changed my routines in the
past year and it's helped me where one,
I sleep in darkness now,
so I don't sleep with natural light
and I don't really use an alarm.
And I noticed I wake up a little
later now, but when I wake up,
I don't need coffee and
I feel more refreshed and
that's just what's worked for
me.
So I wake,
I think now I used to waking up at seven
30 and I'd have to go to like do my old
man p. I don't know if you
know, do you do that at all?
Oh,
well I am a bit of a water hug,
so I usually wake up also in the middle
of the night to go to the bathroom,
which I, yeah, I've had
my prostate checked. Um,
love the experience just getting
up. But no, I, I, you know,
I've checked out all that stuff. I
just drink too much water. So yeah,
I get up and I do the old
man p once or twice probably.
Yeah.
So I just found I slept better,
so I moved my bed to
darken it and Tucker Max,
our mutual friend does that as
well. Um, and then when I wake up,
I try not to just go get overly stimulated
with like my phone and everything
already happening.
And so my morning routine and then I
actually find that the days I'm not having
coffee the morning I'm like,
oh,
I slept better when I've been sitting
in darkness that's been happening. Um,
and then I tried to stay away from my
phone for the first hour of my morning.
So it's from the first hour making,
ideally the same breakfast every morning.
And I generally will rotate
that every three months.
And so like now my breakfast is, is
one cup of egg whites, two eggs, uh,
with 2% cheese.
And so I'll have that in the morning
for breakfast and then I'll read for the
next 30 minutes.
And you just scramble
all that up together?
Yeah, I actually did what you recommended
one of your early youtube days where
microwave it. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
The three minutes low carb breakfast.
Yeah it was out. I was like,
damn, you can microwave eggs now?
Like micro everything. Um, no but
I've actually found like, you know,
it's relaxing and I liked that I'm
eating the same thing so I don't have to
think about it.
Cause sometimes actually when you
have to think about dinner or lunch or
breakfast, it's kind of tiring. Yeah.
It's like I was telling me to do and you
have to process all this extra energy
that I don't really want to.
And so then I tried to create a routine
where it's like breakfast first thing
and then it's a reading a book.
Whatever I'm interested in at that time.
The, I'd love to dig a bit on the books
because I know you've read a lot. Uh,
and you've mentioned books to me before,
like uh, well there, there are many,
but uh,
I think one of them I found very helpful
and I've recommended to my startups,
which is a who,
and maybe maybe you could explain a or
introduced that book and some of the
others that you found
very helpful, uh, for,
for business and just for designing
your own style of business.
Sure. The one thing I wrote before, I
forget, Tim, one thing I've noticed,
there's two kinds.
There's many attributes,
but I always think it's interesting
to try to understand like what are the
fundamentals of successful people like
you and other people that it's like, oh,
what are they doing that
regular people aren't?
And the two things I've noticed is one,
I haven't really met any super
successful people that don't read.
I don't know if you've noticed that.
It's very, it's very unusual. Yes.
I've never met like, oh yeah,
I don't really read anything.
I don't really do anything.
And the second thing is this is
one that everyone can do today.
And I do it every day. I
even do it in hotels, which,
and it's not something perverted.
Um, I know that's what you got.
It's not exclusively something for
perverted. Yeah. Let's be clear. They, uh,
I make my bed everyday.
I don't know if everyone else does that,
but I've always noticed is just like a
great way to get my wind in the morning.
Um, and some other people, I think
I've mentioned that, but that's like,
I do those things like,
you know,
I make sure I'm reading every day
and I make sure I make my bed.
Those are kind of like two wins in the
morning that always, I'm like, Nah,
it's pretty good day.
So do the book.
Not to interrupt,
but I wanted to actually re enforce that
for people because I never made my bed.
And then two things happened.
Uh,
I saw a commencement speech by a war hero,
uh,
who, you know, just a highly,
highly decorated veteran who'd also
come back to civilian life and just done
incredibly well in the private sector.
And he said,
you can't always change everything
in the world you want to change,
but start with making your bed in the
morning. And I was like, what? Huh?
But it stuck with me. And then I met a
monk, I think his name is Dundee punny.
I might be messing up the
pronunciation. In any case, he said,
if you want to have a feeling of
sort of calm control over things,
and I'm paraphrasing here,
start with making your bed in the
morning so that when you come back to it,
it's not complete chaos and you feel like
things are in disarray. And I was like,
wow, that sounds kind of silly, but
whatever. I'll try it for a week.
And it's been just a,
it's had a huge psychic impact.
That's an incredible psychological Roi.
So I do that every morning as well.
Yeah,
I mean it's funny,
I was talking with my team about similar
kind of like what are the things that
you can do today and you don't need
anybody else and you could, you know,
make yourself feel better and get
better. I would say success. Um, and,
and two things that I've noticed is,
one, this is kind of a tangential,
but it's organized your dollar bills.
I don't know if you do that.
Uh, I'm not sure. You
mean like by denomination?
Bye. I do. By nomination,
I do it in the same order.
So they're all front facing and my wallet.
And so I think it's a Susie Orman
things she said 10 years ago or so,
but I've done it and I just think it's
like a respectful thing for your money
and it kind of makes you
like, okay, money's good. Uh,
and the other thing is that with the bed
thing and things in my life in general,
I don't know who told me this, but it's
hard for me to let it go, which is like,
just do it now.
And so if you see something that's
broken or if it's on the floor,
if you have a dish, just like, just
get it over with. And I try to, I like,
for some reason I can't let that go.
We're not, there's things like that.
It just helps me get that kind of
stuff done and it's relieving. Yeah.
So I do that. That's done on, do you have
mantras like that or anything? Mentally
I do. Well, I do, uh,
or reminders that are just soundbites
that I've picked up over time.
One of them that I thought was really
profound in a lot of ways was advice I got
from this, uh, this mother. I mean, I was,
I stayed with a,
a,
an older couple and their family
in Panama at one point and the,
they were real power
couple, I mean the, the,
the wife had done a ton when
she was focused on career.
Husband was a huge player and had bought
and sold some of the biggest companies
in central and South America. And
they were both really, really, uh,
content and accomplished.
And those two don't always go together.
They're actually pretty rare.
And, uh, what she said to me was,
you should make sure you always have,
uh,
an incredible bed and,
and at least one incredible pair of
shoes because if you're not in one,
you're going to be on the other. And
I was like, Huh. And so I started,
I had always bought kind of the cheapest
shoes to get around. And I was like, Eh,
it doesn't matter. I kind of, I
viewed my shoes like a car almost as,
which is how I view cars. I'm like, I
don't need a Ferrari or some fancy cars.
Just getting me from point a to point B.
Like give me the crappiest thing,
the cheapest thing that'll,
that'll do the job.
And I viewed my shoes in the same way
and I didn't realize how many physical
problems I'd created until
I actually invested in,
started investing in better shoes.
You don't need a lot. I mean,
you've got kicked off one pair of,
it's like one pair of very good
walking shoes and, um, and you know,
I tend to prefer these days,
uh,
not necessarily the five fingers or
anything like that because I don't think
those are great walking shoes. Uh, it,
because the human foot is not designed
to walk on concrete or asphalt. Uh,
but rather what you would call it,
zero drop shoes.
So shoes that don't have an elevated heal,
but do have some protection for
the bottom of the foot. And, uh,
you can spend say 20 to 40 bucks on
a good pair of Chuck Taylor's or,
uh, vans that, and I have a
black pair of vans, for instance,
that can double as dress shoes.
Nobody notices.
I had people compliment me on the shoes
when I'm at like a business dinner and
like, oh, this a great shoes. What? I
heard that and I say vans and they just,
they're astonished. So
that a tip, you know,
having I high quality bed and uh,
and high quality bedding and then at
least one pair of high quality shoes is,
it's something that's
stuck with me.
I think that's so wanted. You
know, one thing you were saying,
I thought it was cool.
It's like when you tell stories,
it's so much easier to remember. So
when like two weeks I'd be like, yeah,
Tim was like in the jungle in Panama with
like some guru and they told him about
she was in a bed.
And it's so much easier for me to remember
that versus you just be like, yeah,
I have a bed and better shoes.
Oh yeah, it won't, it won't
stick. Right. And the only reason,
the only reason I've remembered that is
because the context is unique. Right?
But what we remember, it's, it's
funny, there's this music artist,
and I'll talk about the book, who, but
this is music arctic named stitches.
I don't know if you've ever heard of him.
He's kind of like off the grid.
He's Florida based, but the guy is
insane. Like he talks about doing drugs.
He does it, doesn't talk about
it. He does drugs on stage.
Like he's got stitches tattooed all over
his face. And uh, it's very extreme.
And you know, maybe it's
a fad. Maybe it's for now,
but it makes me think about marketing
and business and being remembered.
And you kind of made me realize like
you don't get remembered in the middle.
No, you don't. You don't get remembered
in the middle and you need to,
that's why I recommend a look.
It's not a perfect book,
but it is a very helpful book.
At least for me,
the 22 immutable laws of marketing,
the old version, not, don't get the,
like for Internet one,
that's like AOL era. Uh,
get the old one,
which is like airlines and imported
beer and all of these case studies. Uh,
but it really points out
that if you want positioning,
whether that's for a product for a stay
a point you're trying to persuade people
to accept or negotiation, you have to, uh,
it's not enough just to be better.
You have to be different because no one
will have a chance to realize you're
better if you don't have their
attention first. Uh, and uh, since it,
just thinking if positioning in that
way is basically better as necessary but
not sufficient I think is super critical.
It's funny though, cause we're
were like trained as, as like a,
I think humans to follow orders and
raise her hands and stay in line.
And I always try to encourage people
and myself included to break a rule.
And so I'm like, you're not every day,
but I'm like, okay, can I run this light?
Which not obviously I'm trying to run
lights and help people, but it's like,
all right,
well it says do not enter this way,
but maybe I should just
enter it or you know,
one thing I've recommended people
is like the coffee challenge. Yeah.
I was going to say you're
the coffee challenge
because when we, uh, when we were filming
the Tim Ferriss experiment together,
you actually forced our student to go do
this, which I thought was fantastic. Uh,
and uh, so maybe you could explain that
to people because certainly, uh, the,
the Jason Bourne style going the
wrong way down a one way, uh,
is probably not what I would
suggest people to do. But, uh,
the coffee challenge is something
I would suggest everyone do.
So maybe you can explain that.
Yeah. Um, well, it's funny. I, so
I'll tell the story of my brother. Uh,
so I told my brother to do the coffee
challenge and he's like, I'm a doctor,
I'm the man, I could do anything. And uh,
so we went to like some random
place in Arizona where he lives.
And so the coffee challenge is you have
to go up to the counter and you order
coffee and if you don't drink
coffee, water, tea, if you
don't drink tea or water,
I don't care. And then you just ask
for 10% off. And everyone listening,
I know you're listening right now. In your
ears, you're like, oh, that's stupid. No,
it's stupid, Tim. I'm going to
pause this podcast, whatever, uh,
because it's so easy. I've been
doing sales 20 years. And uh,
I told my brother to do it and he's
like, are you kidding me? I could do it.
I'll do it in a minute.
So it was on his birthday last year
and he goes up to the guy and he pauses
cause he's scared
and I filmed in the whole thing and
I was like, he's like, uh, could,
could get up to percent off. And they're
like, uh, why? He's like, because,
and they, I do believe they
ended up giving it to him.
And the coffee challenge sounds kind of
silly, but the whole point is, you know,
to of business and in life and
to even, you know, being on,
not necessarily the extremes,
but you have to ask for things and
you have to put yourself out there.
And that's the hard part. And for anyone
who hasn't done the coffee challenge,
once you go do it,
you'll learn a ton about yourself.
Nothing that you could read in a book
or that you can even do just hearing.
So next time today you're at a place
where you're buying something Astrid,
10% off. Tell him Tim
sentia don't do that.
No essential, I'll take it. It's fine.
Tell him to come to me and see what you
learn about yourself because you realize
it's harder than it is. But once you
get over it, and that we did this for,
there are monthly one k
product where it's like, hey,
go figure out that asking for money and
asking for things isn't as hard as it
seems. And the now you can start
asking for things that you're like,
well now I want you to buy something, a
minor service or a product that you know,
I really believe in versus just,
you know, asking for a discount,
which is more of a practice.
Yeah.
And I think there,
there are a couple of things that
are important to underscore there.
The first is a lot of the limitations
we feel we have are completely self
imposed and a,
and if you look at say the coffee
challenge or comfort exercise,
like one from the four hour work week,
which was going into a coffee shop.
And I would suggest probably doing these
two and two different coffee shops, uh,
just go in and lay down on the floor
for like five seconds and don't say
anything and then just get back
up like nothing happened. And, uh,
the worst case scenario is so
trivial.
You know what I mean? It's so true.
It's just a little bit of discomfort,
but it goes to show you how many rules
we follow that may not be serving our
best interest. Right? And, and those that,
the coffee shop roles
are just easy to break.
So it's a safe experimental lab. But,
uh, you know, when people are like, well,
I can do this or I can do that.
And I remember asking Matt Mullenweg
the lead developer of wordpress,
who's now the CEO of Automattic,
which is $1 billion plus company. Uh,
I asked him a question at one point and
I was like, well, is it this or is this,
and his, uh, his answer was,
that's a false dichotomy.
Meaning you're asking
me to choose between,
between two things that are not mutually
exclusive or there are other options,
right? Like what is, see, what does
the c option, what does the D option?
And it's, it's a, there's an expression,
and I'm paraphrasing here to quote
actually from Thomas Edison who said, you
know, when you've examined all the
options, just remember Colin you haven't.
And it's like, Huh, interesting.
And I mean, for, for example,
with the Tim Ferriss experiment
with the TV show, uh,
when the division at Turner went out of
business and everything got shut down,
everything got shelved. Uh,
almost everybody basically
said like, that's game over.
All right, let's all move on with our
lives. We had a good time and that's it.
You can't get the TV show out,
you can't get the TV show
back or anything like that.
And it took a year of looking at,
you know,
what if I did this absurd thing,
what if I took this absurd approach?
Like how do I craft a deal when it's,
even if I were to get the
show back for Turner, it's a,
it's a rounding error on pocket change
for them. They're, they're just,
there's not really incentive.
So like how do you figure out the deal
structuring and so on and eventually
found a way to do it.
But it took a lot of poking and prodding
and kind of rolling out hypothetical.
It's like taking a piece of paper.
Okay.
So I'm just going to freehand write and
flow for like 10 minutes and just like,
what are the most absurd things I could
do to possibly get these things back and
not judge, right? You're going to
throw out really stupid things.
Probably some illegal things,
probably some dangerous things. Uh,
probably some completely
self destructive things.
And then you look through it and you're
like, okay, now this is interesting.
And I heard a quote from,
or a story from a comedian,
one standup guy and he said,
uh, how did he put it? He said,
writing well or generating good ideas
is like orchestrating a room full of
people in a firearm. Urgency.
He's like, when if there's a fire,
you can't have everyone rush
for the exit at once. Um,
and then because they'll
get blocked in the door,
but you have to let each one out at
a time and then you can organize it
afterwards.
You can like group them into whatever
you stupid mediocre and good ideas after
the fact. And so just doing that
type of freehand idea generation, um,
for solutions I find to be, to
be super helpful. But I know I'm,
I know we've bass around a little bit but,
but it was just talking about the whole
book. But you know what's funny to him?
Cause like, uh, I mean obviously,
I mean you are a little more known
on the Internet and you know,
we've done some things that people will
be like, well, you're Tim Ferris. Right?
And that's actually what I hear a lot.
And so it, it's like, well, you're Tim,
so it's easier for you. And I don't,
I don't think they have, I don't know.
I think a lot of people don't have the
realization that like everyone has an
opportunity.
Yeah, I know. It definitely,
and I had, I mean, for instance,
I had something I was doing
online recently and, uh,
this guy responded on Twitter and
he said, well, it's easy for you.
You're Tim Ferriss and you have a
blog with a million plus people.
And this other guy, um, um,
well known blogger Darren,
Darren rose or remedy roused
r or w s e pro blogger,
uh, who's very, very, um, savvy
content guy with a huge audience.
He said, we all start at the same
place, zero readers, you know,
and it's a psych rather than,
rather than dismissing a,
dismissing other people as achieved
things that are unattainable, recognize,
like they,
they started kind of like naked and
alone in the world without any skills.
Those are, they had to develop
that. And, uh, you know,
you and I have a lot of the same
challenges even still today, I assume.
I know we've had some pretty
deep conversations about
challenges we've had that
everybody else has. And it's like,
you don't get rid of those problems.
You just kind of trade up,
uh,
that's do preach. I'm like, Ooh,
this sermon was good right there.
I'm like nodding. I'm like,
yeah, tip. I mean one thing,
you know, especially cause I,
you know, started a few
businesses and uh, what I,
what I think most people don't realize
is that every major company, Facebook,
Dell, Microsoft, Google,
all of it started with like one dude
or two dudes are two women with no
customers. Yup. They all started the
same size as everyone else. So you know,
it start there,
get that one customer and build up.
And that's how you get to become the
size of those companies are, you know,
have a large side or whatever it is
that each person wants to accomplish.
Yeah, absolutely. I mean,
Amazon in the early days, I
mean, their, their desks were,
I think they were just doors from cheap
wooden doors from home depot across two
file cabinets. Like those were
their desks. You know when it was,
you know what to think about.
Tim especially like with you.
So I met you before you're
even a first booking on.
I always think it's the funniest thing.
I email you,
I got an email intro to you and I've
got an auto responder that's like, Hey,
I'm surfing in Costa Rica and I'm like,
who the fuck is Tim Ferris?
I know an autoresponder surfing in Costa
Rica. They will be back in two weeks.
I'm like, all right, I don't
really want to meet this guy. Um,
but I think what separates out a lot of
the winners versus losers is that it's
not only that you got the book out there,
but you've been doing it
consistently for 10 years.
Same with Zuckerberg at Facebook
is that it's easy to be,
to get a hit for a week or a month
or two months, but do it for you.
Zach has made decisions for 10 years.
You've done your stuff for 10 years,
like as soon what I've
been doing for five years,
like you know those things like,
I mean you don't have soon as
now a seven figure business,
but I mean $12,000 in myself the first
year. Yeah, right. And that it's like,
well no, you're making good
money now. But it's like, yeah,
it starts small and then you've got to
keep going. You've got to persist with it.
No, definitely. And you have to
choose the good teachers. And for me,
because I was on my own so much and
probably for you books were a lot of those
teachers
for me. I love how you brought it back.
And everyone here, that right there,
that's an interviewer. All right,
so we're going to do the WHO books.
So let me just look.
Do you mind if I just rattle them
off and then people just go by him,
rattle them off and then I
might ask you to dig into some.
All right, so here are the books.
So I went through, I have a,
I can give you the list for
everyone about every book I've read.
I can't like every book
and movie I've read. Um,
and I'm just gonna give you
like the seven inch one,
the business related and personal that I
think are just super, super helpful. Um,
my favorite one in the past year
has been a centralism. Yup. Um,
and it's basically just the whole
book literally is just like say no to
everything. That's not important.
So I learned that at Facebook.
That book was a great reminder of it.
And even like with our main product,
tsunami.com like we have one goal,
which is to hit a certain revenue target.
And every decision we do is either
does it help towards that or not?
And we no to everything else. Um, the WHO
book that in, feel free to interrupt me.
I'm sure you will. I don't
know. Do I? We've, uh,
we've known each other long enough.
I'll, I'll jump in if need be. Perfect.
The whole book is, there's a
longer book called topgrading, uh,
which I wouldn't read because it's
like, it's sick. It's really thick.
The Hook is like a
condensed version of it.
And I learned it at meant
where the founder was using it.
And so who basically helps you create
a framework for thinking about who you
want to hire, the questions you want
to ask and then how do you filter,
find them and then get down to make
sure you have the right person.
Matt interview was great cause he makes
people audition for the jobs and I liked
that. But I also use who, which you know,
helps you have some really basic questions
that you could standardize so that
you can compare people who,
who has some really solid chapters that
lay out exactly the series of questions
that you can ask at different points
in the process. It's really solid.
What I'll do, Tim, is I'll email you after
this. I'll email you my, I'm so weird.
I write book reports on every book I read.
Awesome.
And so I'll email you the book report on
who. So for the people that, you know,
it's funny cause I think if you read it
you'll get more out of it cause you'll,
you have to keep reading the same message.
Most books are one page,
but you repeat it enough times, you
remember it. Um, and so yeah, I'll,
I'll send you the book report
afterwards so that people can uh, cool.
Get the condensed version. I'll add,
I'll add all sorts of goodies in the,
in the show notes of my two other,
my favorite sales
business book of all time,
which is one of the underground ones.
And I think you might know Amanda Holmes,
but it's from her father and it's
called the ultimate sales machine.
And this book is just like,
it's like an underground,
I had it on my shelf for six months.
It was the one that you kind of skip over.
Like I have a books on my shelf now
and I skipped over him. I'm like that.
I get to that one later.
And I finally got it for an airplane and
I get on the airplane and I opened the
first page and I'm on the introduction
and I'm like, all right, rabbit ear,
that page, next page, rabbit
here, next page, rabbit here.
Like the whole book was folded over and
I finished it on that airplane ride and
it's one of these books that
not enough people talk about,
but everyone who reads it is always like,
oh, I'm really glad I read that one.
You must fold your pages like Origami
best you guys is because I usually hear
dot. I usually hear dog year, but
rabbit here I kinda like, yeah,
I've actually been trying to carry a
pen when I read certain business books
because I just find it easier to come
back to the specific sections I want to
write in my book reports.
Um, other things,
an old school book that if you're
looking to do service type business,
million dollar consulting is great for
how to raise your prices and how to
actually start your own service
or consulting based business.
I really liked that. Um, right now I'm
really thinking a lot more about sales,
especially with Zumiez, we're
growing that product. Uh,
so I read two books recently that
were really strong on sales ones,
the sales acceleration formula,
and that is more around SAS based selling,
but it could still be good for, you
know, how to find the right as a surface,
like a, the the sumo of meetings
or the dropboxes of the world. Wow.
You've lumped me with Dropbox.
Thanks Bro. No problem. Hey man,
the tsunami, the googles. Um,
so it's basically like how to find
like filter through people on Linkedin,
how to ask the specific texts or
how to ask for a referral. Um,
you don't ask for, you don't email
someone asking to hire them. You asked,
emailed them,
asked to refer someone else and that's
generally a good way to get to know them
and possibly get a referral.
Well, it's like raising money. People
say if you want, if you want money,
ask for advice. If you want advice,
ask for money. Oh Man. Actually No.
One thing that I think Shane, you
know Shane Snow? I do. Yeah. Oh yeah,
he's been on your side.
If he wrote a,
he did a bunch of experimentation with
soylent when it first came out and then
wrote the first kind of review of
two weeks of being on it on my blog,
which caused all sorts of viral storms.
But uh, yeah, yeah, I do know Shane.
I love Shane and everyone should check
out his book smart cuts. It's actually,
it's a really good book too,
but that wasn't even the point.
Shane told me one of the great ways you
can get a mentor or meet anyone you want
to meet is just interview them.
So that's something actually for me,
there's companies I really respect,
like Taco Deli, it's a look,
it's my favorite Taco in the world. Um,
and then Austin. And so I basically,
you know, you reach out
to people like, Hey,
I just want to promote you to my audience.
And even if you have a small audience
and what Tim, me and you can actually,
I think we're going to possibly later
show people how to get their own audience
live right up in the show. Oh yeah. Well,
I don't, won't be live, it'll be recorded.
And you can do it instantly when
you listen to it on your phone.
And so shame was basically like,
yeah,
interview people and then there's a chance
for you to meet and connect and it's
the best way to get ahold of someone
versus normally you ask an email and be
like, hey, can we just hold something?
Um, a few other books that I'm really,
I really enjoyed spin selling really
shifted my mindset about how you are going
to be approaching customers and really
thinking about like the formula which is
like, you know, situation, problem,
implication and then like natural
solution or need solution.
And it basically helps you really
transition people to be like, Hey,
what problem do you have? And think about
if you're really helping them and say,
well, if you're going to need this help,
you should probably use our solution.
It's a great way. It's the iPhone.
So think of yourself as an advocate,
which is like, hey, you have,
what's your situation? All right,
what problem do you have? All right,
well how would the, if we can solve it,
how would that make your life
better? Oh, well, guess what?
We actually have that solution for that
problem that we just solved for you.
That you sound like you was
what really important for you.
Yeah, no, absolutely. And this applies
in more places than people might realize.
So for instance,
I had someone asked me recently,
why do you think people take
action when they read your stuff?
Like it seems like there's a high
conversion rate compared to most books.
Like people actually take
action. And I was like, well,
I'm not sure if that's true, but, uh,
I hope it's true. And if it is true,
I think it's because
in each of my chapters,
let's just say in the four hour body,
I basically take that spin selling
approach of establishing the problem first
and combine it with the sort of story arc
of like the writer's journey or Joseph
Campbell's stuff and tie it
into an aerator that people
can remember. So it's, uh,
the,
these types of mental frameworks apply
to more contexts and areas than I think
people might realize.
I mean, it applies to everything. I mean,
I don't think people realize that like
the two most important things I've,
I mean I don't have to most important
to very important things or copywriting
and selling.
And I think those are that in personal
finance or three of the probably most
undervalued or under recognized things
that people should spend more time
learning.
What have you read that has
helped you most with copywriting?
Number one thing. And it's completely
free as the Gary Halbert letters. Yeah.
So my good level and if you know my good
buddy, yeah, yeah, yeah, of course. Yeah.
We can get,
I never like copywriting course and
Neville got me into him in his car.
His writing is just so fluid.
Um, and obviously it's practice,
which I always hate because when you
hear a cliche things like they like, oh,
I know it's practice, but I want
tips. And so the Gary Halbert letters,
he wrote these things called the Boron
letters were to his son while he was in
jail.
And uh,
they're just phenomenal copywriting
pieces about how to sell and how to think
about things. And we can link to that.
Those are totally free and great. Um,
there's the other stuff, like Ogilvy
on advertising is a really good book.
It's so, uh, it's,
it's so often recommended but
so few people actually read it.
It's a really good book.
You know what?
I did it and I like literally saying this
is not a joke for you or your audience.
Like I w I in college, I in college,
obviously that's a great sentence.
In College I was in,
I was in English as a second language.
What Dude? I'm American. I was
born in San Jose, California.
My parents speak English,
so I'm just try to give you an idea of
how bad of a writer I was and maybe still
am. Yeah. Are you serious? Yeah. Dude,
I was an English as a second language.
It was me and a bunch of people who can
speak English. You took ESL courses? Yeah.
Well I didn't want to be like crash the
course or was it, was it recommended?
Was a requirement of cal because I wasn't,
my English was so low.
I wish it was like a joke. I'd be like,
oh, well, yeah, I can speaking. It's like,
dude, I, I'm from America.
You know,
that's,
it's funny you mentioned that
because I remember looking at Toefl,
the test of English as a foreign language
and people generally don't actually
understand the mechanics of
their native language very well.
But you forget that and you think
you're like, oh, I'm a native speaker.
Of course I know English. And then
you look at the test and they're like,
what is the difference between anything
in something? And you're like, uh,
I would totally fail TOEFL if I had to
take TOEFL to get into anything. Uh,
absolutely would probably flunk out.
Yeah. No, so that's serious.
So I'd take your Harvard helped and
actually no one thing that's not a book,
but really probably changed the game for
me writing wise, besides riding a lot,
uh,
was getting an editor and that's it.
Cause I would write something and
I'd be like, this sounds great.
I can't believe how good it.
And then I would show it to Neville or
Anton at the [inaudible] team and they'd
be like, this is garbage.
And I'm like, no, it's good.
And then once they would start reading
it, um, and give me the feedback,
it changed and I'm like,
okay, now I'm getting wide.
It's not as entertaining or how I can
improve things like photos and bold and
how it shifts around my sentence,
grammar and structure.
How would you suggest people
implement that for themselves?
If they're asking someone to, to
proofread something, uh, what do you,
what are the instructions that you give
on or what type of person are you
looking for? Wa working backwards.
I'm looking for someone who I like their
writing and also I'll tell you what I
did last year,
which was really helpful.
I created an inner
circle and it basically,
it was people that I really enjoyed
their writing and I said, hey,
I'm going to create a
small group of people.
I think there was about five of us and
anytime we're putting on an article,
let's send it to the group and you
can leave comments in the Google doc.
Everyone can just leave a comment.
So it doesn't change the writing,
but it can give you feedback about
that type of writing. And it also,
when you finally finished article,
those people would help promote it,
which is a whole nother marketing tactic.
So do those people,
then you would upload a new doc to Sam
shared folder and then just invite those
people via email or how do you guys
exactly, well, so if you created a
Google doc, so I would go to Google docs,
create a file, just any file.
I would share it with them.
So I'd share it with you and then on
that file and you can have it be just
comment only. And so they would go
in and leave a bunch of comments.
I would go fix it and be like, wow,
that was actually a lot better.
And then subsequently my writing even
get stronger and I would do it for them
when they had their articles.
Got It. Got It. Okay.
Cause like I dunno for you, like
I'm, I'm still, you know. Okay.
dork.com my personal blog, you
know, it's 100,000 subscribers.
It gets decent metric. I'm still scared
of my writing because it's just like,
cause you know, and that's why I like
having an editor because I'm like,
there's probably tons of grammar that's
going to get ripped on and know it
represents me and I want to look good.
Um,
so having the editor and like
peers be able to edit my things,
especially with like with Google docs,
I know a lot of people use like
Hemingway or, uh, what does it draft?
Yeah. Draft I've used, it's
pretty sweet. Um, draft I
like, I haven't used Hemingway,
like the name despite the guy's
a somewhat unfortunate end.
But those are two ones for like group
editing. I mean, so for writing. Yeah.
Those are the stuff.
And then the two ones I would say
coming back to like selling stuff, um,
spin selling. I just mentioned sales
acceleration formula we talked about.
And then I'd say lastly, there's a
book called small giants. Uh, okay.
Which are all giants is a great book.
Uh, it does, I'll let you describe it.
It had a huge impact on me though when
I read it. What was the impact of five,
seven, eight years ago? Well, I in I
assume we're talking about the same book,
it's a bull, Berlin, Berlin
Willingham. Uh, it just,
I think the sub,
what is the subtitle?
Something like companies
that choose to be the best,
not the biggest or something
like that, but the, uh,
the idea that size or growth does not
have to be the measure of success if
you're an entrepreneur and she's a very
conceptually uncommon thing to hear.
Uh,
and I just loved,
that's one of the books that kind of put
the finishing touches on convincing me
that, you know, selling, trying to find
price insensitive people to sell to,
uh,
is just a complete game changer or making
something that is so good and so over
delivers it. You can charge
a premium price. Um, those,
those are a few of the things that I
took away from that. What about you?
That's very long.
I mean,
I think a few people that are listening
that are not in silicon valley,
I don't think they understand like how,
I don't know. I don't know exactly.
Not as fair,
but it's just like everything is about
if you're a billion dollar company and if
you're going viral and if you're a lot
of funding and if you're not here and
nobody in you're nothing
and everything is pointless.
And it was really refreshing to hear
these, you know, pretty, you know,
substantial companies like a Clif bar
or I think there's a beer company in San
Francisco, uh, that we're doing
great things in big companies,
but just doing it in their own way and
it's, you know, it's very empowering.
Realize like,
yeah,
you can do your own thing and it can be
big and you don't have to compromise on
those things. Like my favorite
Taco shop here, it's been,
they've been around since
1999 and they have five shops.
But our common notion is that
you have to go viral, not viral,
but you have to scale.
So 10 shops in 20 shops and they're going
at a pace that's comfortable for them.
They don't have to be Starbucks,
you know,
and they're just doing their Taco Deli
thing. And that's why I respect him and,
and you know, I get, I
talk about them so much.
Yeah. Uh, it's, it's, it can
be a really profound, I think,
awakening for people when they start to,
when they sit down and
really try to assess what,
what would add value to
their lives and more joy and
excitement.
And that's,
that's very rarely money for the
sake of money because the money you,
you exchange for an experience or,
uh,
interacting with certain types of
people or any number of things.
And there are other ways to get those
things besides scaling a company,
making a, making a bunch of money that
you can trade for those things. I mean,
for instance, you mentioned
the Taco shop. Uh,
you could look at other examples like
Jiro from Jiro dreams of Sushi and his
like 12 seater,
a three star Sushi restaurant in Tokyo.
He has no desire to scale that.
You know what I mean? In fact,
it's kind of antithetical to his entire
personality and a mission for sort of
perfecting his craft. Right. And you know,
one of the examples of from small giants,
uh,
there was an Auntie to Franco example,
but then there was another example which
I thought was so awesomely niche and so
just fantastic, which
was a, and I thought,
I'm pretty sure I'm
getting the book right.
It was a leather pants and a specifically
the person who made leather pants for
like Sheryl crow and they became a huge,
the famous cause she
has nice legs and asked,
but also the pants were
really cool and you know, for,
I think Aerosmith and so on. But it one
of these examples where they're, uh,
they're like this guy I
bought a hunting rifle from,
he makes 20 rifles a year and they're
customized. They're just incredible.
And he'd done me a bunch of favors
and I wanted one of his guns.
But it was also just to say thank you.
And they have no desire
to scale and how that,
how dramatically that improves their
quality of life and ability to ability to
optimize other facets of their life when
you remove that as the sole objective.
Anyway, I just, uh,
I'm really glad you brought that book
up cause I actually have it on my
bookshelf literally in my living room
positioned in a way that anytime I sit
down on my couch I can see it face out
right next to a handful of other books
like a Zorba,
the Greek and the magic of thinking
big and a few others have you to read a
Richard Simon's book. Oh surely. You
must be joking. Mr Feinman there.
Have you talked about in the show?
I don't think I have, but it's,
that is actually another one of the like
half dozen books that's up on my shelf.
I mean why, why don't you talk
about that book for a second?
Because it's one of my
favorite books of all time.
It's one of these books and I have it.
So if you ever meet me in person,
I'll give you my, I have an extra
copy cause it's just that amazing. Um,
this is a guy who won the Nobel prize.
I believe he helped
create the atomic bomb.
Yup. Yeah. He worked at Los Alamos,
also helped identify the o ring
that caused the challenger disaster
and just the amount of stuff that
he's done, you're like, okay,
this guy has got to be weird
and he's just so greatly weird.
Any talks like a human and just
like all of all these extremes.
I think the biggest thing that I took
away from the book is just this curiosity
to life and experiences where he would
just start like, oh, well, you know,
one day I just thought
drinking wasn't fun,
so I stopped drinking and he walked
out of a bar and never drink again.
Or do you want it to pick up?
I think was a bongo drums.
Yeah, Bongo drums. Uh, he also
wanted to learn how to pick up linen,
so he would go into bars.
Uh,
just didn't give a shit what
other people thought too,
which was amazingly refreshing. Uh, he
decided he wanted to learn how to, uh,
safe crack to open safes.
And so he would prank people in Los
almost where they were building the atomic
bomb.
So he would,
you'd take out confidential papers and
like put them on the desk of somebody who
wanted to freak out.
Yeah.
So I,
the,
the final book and what I love most
about it just makes you curious about the
world.
I was mentioning briefly,
like my brother's kid is touching grass
for the first time and I just look at
grasping that grasp,
whatever.
And this kid is like touching grass and
feeling it and experiencing it and it
makes you kind of just appreciate all
the things that are going around in life,
in the world. I'm like, oh,
that's really great. And uh,
and I think that book just inspired
me with that and that's why, you know,
highly recommended.
It's a, it's a must read. And also
the fact that when he was on his last,
you know, on his last legs,
towards the end of his life,
he was still doing things that he,
that challenged his belief
systems or his skill.
So he learned how to paint very late in
his life as a scientist who is super die
hard engineer who really felt
like the Romance Romanticizing of,
uh, say people who would argue
that, you know, the scientist, uh,
takes the magic out of something like
a flower because they deconstruct it in
scientific terms. And his argument
was that's entirely the opposite.
We can appreciate so much more
that you can't see and uh,
but felt compelled to sort of trade best
practices with a friend of his who is a
well known painter and,
uh,
become a white belt again
and suck at painting.
And I don't know if this was in his book,
I think there's a, there's actually a,
an interview with Richard
Fineman. Uh, I'll,
I'll link to this in the show
notes@fourhourworkweek.com
forward slash podcast.
But,
um,
there's a youtube video then I'll link
to call it the pleasure of finding things
out. And I think in that might
be somewhere else. They talk,
he would go to strip clubs
to paint as like an old dude.
And, uh, just really was,
was not affected by public pressure.
And that's something I admire so much
as in times when I feel defensive,
like I have to protect something that
I've created or anything like that.
Uh,
the fact that he was willing to seemingly
throw it all away by doing things that
would negatively impact his reputation
when in the end they never did.
Nobody cared because they're too
busy thinking about themselves.
Exactly. And to add to that team, I
think you're, you're running the money.
One thing that I started doing as a giver,
I'm like,
well I know I try to notice like when
I'm feeling really good or like what
happened that made me feel really good.
And I was noticing that reading and
like studying and learning like reading
findings book made me feel really good.
But I noticed as we get older you just
like you scheduled day run all the work
stuff you're doing.
And so on Tuesdays from 10 to 12,
I scheduled nothing but learning.
So every Tuesday it's on repeat and that's
one of the main tactics I put things
on repeat on the calendar. So 10 to 12
every Tuesday. And my friend level, uh,
got me into learning from youtube
videos and I'm like youtube videos.
And so I go on youtube videos
and I bookmark specific people.
So finding the videos are amazing
and an Elon Musk's videos are just as
phenomenal. And I was like,
wow, you can learn from youtube.
I never really thought of intentionally
going to find things to listen to and
watch.
What, how did you choose
that time? On Tuesday?
Uh, Monday I do team meetings
and so I would, you know,
I kind of almost would be
tempted to do it all day,
but Monday is kind of like my
organization day. Um, I can give you,
if you can talk about afterwards,
I do a specific thing that really helps
me on my Mondays. Uh, so Tuesdays,
like the next day that I'm available to
start thinking about things because most
of your good stuff doesn't
come when you're doing it
comes when you're thinking.
Um, and then I'm starting to incorporate
on my Thursdays trying to do like a fun
activity like disc golf.
So on Thursday afternoons and Thursday
mornings tend to 12 I'll try to go out
and just be like play disc golf or go
for a bike ride or something where I just
have time.
That's my mind is like a little more free.
What uh,
do you have your activities
clustered by day?
Like what do you do? For instance,
you said team meetings on Mondays.
Is there a certain focus on Tuesdays
aside from the studying Wednesday,
Thursday, Friday. Like do you,
do you break things out and
categorize them that way?
I don't bash,
the way I look at my week is on
Monday mornings I basically have three
categories that matter to me, which
is like work, workout in personal,
and then I labeled three things
for each one and work out.
I put four because I work out four days
a week. So I have three things for work,
for things on workout in,
three things for personal.
And then I put those in my calendar
during the week about when I want to batch
those tasks. Like I want to do my work
things this time during these days.
And then I leave the rest of the
calendar open and I think market,
I learned that from Mark Andreessen where
he's like certain things are gonna be
more important to certain days.
I'm not going to try to lock
it out for something else.
And so then I just focused
on a three s a commit to
doing@theweekandtheneverymondayireviewmycalendarwithmyfriendadamfrommybodytutor.com
and so we share what we said
we're going to do [inaudible] body
tutor.
Yeah.
Have you heard of my body tutor.com no.
Dyi T. U. T. O. R.
I mean if we can talk about,
I'm having to stay long and talk health
and fitness but he basically has helped
me get abs and now he's helping me book
up to 200 and he's helping me to get big
back down too bulky,
ripped,
bulky and ripped at like one 75 and I've
been working with him for about little
over four years and he's one of my best
friends. What are some of the, I'm sorry,
go ahead. Well I was going to say, so
that's what I, how I organize my week.
We're on Mondays.
I email him a review of the previous
week using followup.cc because it reminds
me, and I think if you don't
review what you've done,
it's hard to know how you're progressing.
And then I come into what I
want to do this upcoming week.
And so everyone should get
an accountability buddy. Um,
cause it's so Adam emails
me, I'm like, Yo, what, why
didn't you do this last week?
Or how come every week you're doing
the same crappy thing that's not doing
anything you should think differently
about it. Um, so I think for a side,
products are fulltime businesses.
I still do it with him and I've been
doing this with him for a few years now.
Very cool. I want to, I want to,
to pick a little bit at some of the tips
you have for people who might want to
gain muscular size. Uh, I'll,
I'll, before I get to that,
I want to add a few other resources.
So you mentioned my body tutor,
which is great.
I hadn't heard of it.
So that's definitely going to go
in the back of my mind on the list.
A couple of others that people might
like for finding accountability partners
would be a coach. Dot
me, coach. Dot Emmy. Uh,
it used to be lift, uh, the Oh really?
Yeah. And I advise those guys so I've,
I've had fun running
experiments with them.
The other is there are two others actually
a stick.com as t I C K k.com where
you can put money on the line that
you can lose if you don't hit certain
milestones, which is very incentivizing
for people as a consequence.
And then a one that is very
strictly a money related,
which is dietbet.com so if you
want to lose weight, uh, you can,
you can put together a
betting pool basically and,
uh, and, and make that work,
uh, for gaining muscular size.
This is, I, I as you would imagine,
get a lot of questions about this,
but what were the biggest, uh,
if you had to give someone advice,
say guy,
who is your size before
you started bulking up for
gaining 40 pounds in 40 funds
in six to 12 months. And let's just say
most of that should be muscle. What,
what would be the advice if they're like,
I have never been able to gain weight men,
I think I'm doing everything that I could
possibly do. What, what are your tips?
Well I would start with the foundation
so I wouldn't actually even recommend
this to most people because it is
how'd you go once you hit that goal to
come back down cause you get comfortable
eating like Nachos and you
get comfortable with eating,
like drinking beer and you know,
obviously some people do clean books,
but I did a mix of it.
So what I would actually recommend is
get a foundation of being able to eat
healthy consistently and
maintaining or losing your weight.
Probably maintaining for at least,
I would say six months to a year.
I've been doing a consistent diet for two
years before I even tried to book. Hmm.
So I don't think if you,
unless you're ready to be able,
unless you have the mental
capacity to be able to control it,
I wouldn't recommend it because it's very
easy to let kind of get lost with it.
Uh,
and that's why my fitness pal and Adam
were so helpful because for two years I
was eating very consistently and losing
weight and getting the body I wanted.
The one thing, it was fascinating, Tim,
was until I started doing my fitness pal.
Um, I was going to the gym
like three or four days a week,
but I was thinking tiny and I'm like,
what's The f what the F is going on? Uh,
and it's because I wasn't eating
enough protein and say, fuck frick.
I don't know. Like I was on Pat Flynn's
podcast and he's just like, he's like,
I had to edit half of your
interview. And so, you know, the,
and I've been watching big
love the Mormon TV show.
So I'm just like all about it anyways.
So basically for a long time I wasn't
eating enough protein and that's why I
wasn't getting bigger. And so that's what
made me a little more curious about it.
So number one,
I would say try doing,
just maintaining or losing for a year
so that you're comfortable with it.
The big things with gaining weight.
So I went from one 60 to 200 and
a few months. Uh, so number one,
I would say plan your calorie intake,
how much you actually need to be
having each day. Because otherwise,
besides that you're blind.
You're just like, well,
I should have this many
and you really don't know.
So if you want to hit a certain way,
just work backwards from how many calories
you need to be eating every day to
get that amount. Um, I'd say
the big things for me were one,
I had a buddy who was doing it at the
same time and that was a game changer
because he's doing it and he's gaining
weight and I'm like, well fuck,
I have to do it too.
And it was just much more helpful to
have someone supporting me and my,
one of my best friends, John
Ross was locally and we're
both gaining. Uh, secondly,
I did use weight gainer,
which I don't know if there's debate,
I haven't looked at the tons of science,
but it does help you gain weight
and get the mass that you want.
It does go away a little bit
cause of creatine involve law,
which I'm not going to get into
because I don't know it super well. Uh,
but that really significantly
help me anyway. And,
and ultimately you kind of have
to look at like, all right,
you get tired of eating, you get it to
a point of like, I am sick of eating,
so what is the cheapest way to get as
many calories and as much protein in my
body to help you gain this weight?
Uh, so in the morning it was like,
how can I do protein shakes, a
quest, bar, egg, wall heights,
eggs,
whatever I could take and
basically doubling everything
I was already currently
doing. So whatever you think
you're eating, eat double.
But basically it at some point
where you have to figure out,
and what I started doing,
it was like,
what is the protein ratio is a food
and just eating the highest protein to
highest like calorie food, uh, to really
put on as much weight as possible. Yeah,
it's the, the working out isn't the
hard part. It's the eating by far.
And you plot and you plateau, man. I hit
like one 70, plateaued, won 80 plateaued,
one 90 plateaued. And you
know, it's funny as a,
the last night I wanted to hit it by
March 1st to 200 pounds. And this is,
you know, I hit, why was that like
one 97 and a and my girlfriend,
I was like, and I was, it was like 12.
It was not tall. It was like 10 30.
And I'm like, Oh, I'm not going
to hit it. And she's like,
you need to stop being a bitch and
start putting some food in your mouth.
And, uh, you know, and I've ate and
drank and ate and then at, you know,
before midnight I was uh, you know,
like Cinderella, I hit my 200.
There's one other thing that was really
helpful to him that aisle and I think,
I don't know what tool you use.
I use we things scale.
Yeah. With things. Yeah,
the automatic um, sort of a,
I guess it's Wifi or Bluetooth enabled
scale that automatically creates graphs
for you.
So I
use what I do is I have a wee
thing scale and I take my,
and you can embed your
weight chart online.
So I embedded it online and I shared it
with Adam and he would check in with me
every day to be like, you're skinny,
you're fat, you're fat, you're doing well,
why aren't you getting more
weight and so forth. Um,
and it's very counter cause
most people want to lose weight.
And so when you're trying to gain weight,
and especially me,
I'm like the guy you never want to before
I would say I'm the guy you never want
to eat with because
I'd be like egg whites.
Can you separate the cheese particles? Uh,
can you put no, but it's like, I'm like,
God, do you want any of the
food that they're serving you?
And so it was a shift in me but having
Adam and then I have a Facebook like
workout group where I was
posting my weight and you know,
I think the more people that you have to
care about you and that are checking in
on you, uh, on a regular basis,
the more it was easier for me
to help accomplish that. Yeah.
The more you get people invested in your
progress and that could be a Facebook
group that you create or just promising
to put Facebook status updates,
uh,
once a week for instance.
And making that commitment
publicly is extremely helpful.
A couple of points I'd like to underscore.
The first is the fact that leaning
out first we'll help you bulk faster.
There are a bunch of biochemical
reasons for this and um, and,
and sort of a biochemical but also a
neuroscience related reasons just in terms
of regulation of Leptin and Ghrelin,
Ghrelin and all of these
things where if you lean out,
even for two to four weeks,
doesn't have to be that long.
But certainly getting to the point
where let's just say hypothetically,
you choose the slow carb diet from,
for our body.
You're already at say 14% body fat.
You drop two to 4% in
a four to eight weeks,
then you will have developed a
probably a very good degree of insulin
sensitivity.
And insulin is an anabolic hormone.
That's why bodybuilders
sometimes inject insulin, uh,
competitive bodybuilders,
which I would never recommend
because you can kill yourself.
What does that do for them?
It allows them to store more calories,
ingested in muscle
tissue, uh, and elsewhere.
But it's a very, very, very
dangerous thing to do. Uh,
and, uh, you, you can mimic
that a little bit with say,
low doses of Alpha lipoic acid and there
are other things that act as insulinoma
medics as they would call them. Um,
but if you lean out, like if I really,
really want to get big for whatever
reason I haven't done in the ages because
it's just such a slog.
I mean,
you feel like a Kobe beef cow
just being fattened for slaughter.
I mean it's really, it's so,
it's still laborious. Oh my God.
Like I didn't want to eat. You can
get to it. Like at first you're like,
at first it's hard to do. You're
like, oh, I shouldn't have,
I shouldn't have egg yolk. Even, I
know fat is good and all that stuff.
But then you have egg yolks and then
it's like six egg yolks and then you're
like, fuck eggs. Yeah, well exactly.
But you do have your kind of supersize me
moment where you're like, amazing. Yeah,
baby. And then a week later you're
just like, can I stop? Please?
I want to tap out please.
I'm on the eating on the training.
Um,
I'd be curious to what your
biggest mistakes were that
you'd been making from a
training perspective.
Totally. I mean, the number one
thing, the number, number one,
number one thing was I wasn't
eating enough in the beginning.
So even like last year when I wanted to
start getting like bigger muscles, uh,
I just was eating so little
food. I'm like, well,
I'm supposed to eat live like egg
whites and these things and you know,
and I don't like don't try to get bigger.
You should,
you need to eat more food
and you stop being a bitch.
And so I started eating the egg yolks
and Tucker Max always giving me shit for
it too. It's like, dude, you
got to stop being a bitch.
And I guess that's maybe a common theme.
Uh,
and so you do that and you realize
like bigger dogs need more food.
So if you want to be bigger,
you need to put more in. Yeah.
So that was number one. And then I started
just doing heavier sets and less reps.
What would a, so what were you
doing and what did you change it to?
So I,
there's actually a few different programs.
There's a guy named the online coach
and he does a thing called the shoal
program.
It's like something hypertrophy.
I don't know what he stole
like s c h o l l s H, u l
as he has a program that
I was following and I can,
I can send that to you afterwards.
So I followed his program and a lot of
what his arguments like super heavier
weights, five sets and then I
would focus on core movements.
So I break my thing out into four days
a week. And so the biggest mistake,
cause I was doing super heavy,
super high reps with a lighter weights
for a long time and now I just wanted to
get bigger and bulkier. And it's funny
cause when you saw me you're like,
Holy Shit, you're huge. And it's like one,
I ate a ton more and I and I monitored it
and then I lifted a ton of heavier, uh,
versus the lighter weights,
which in my opinion just kind of
give me more of the definition.
Yeah. Or just make you more injury prone
depending on how you do it. Certainly.
I mean there are a lot of folks who
do sort of high rep high velocity,
which is just asking for
all sorts of issues. Um,
and now is the the shool program,
the online fitness coach,
was it a sort of five sets of five reps
type of situation with exactly what
limits. Okay. So it's very
similar. Then there's a,
there's a book that's become
very popular among engineers,
oddly enough in silicon valley called
starting strength by Mark Rippetoe.
Rippetoe knows his stuff. He's, he's,
he has some very pragmatic approaches to
this stuff and he actually has a second
book and probably more but one that
I have really enjoyed, which is,
is a lot denser and probably
not the right one to read first,
but called a pragmatic
programming I think it is.
And it's all about lots of medium term
and long term planning of training and
how to cycle it and so on.
But I think that's biting off more.
Which one should we start with a starting
strength? Starting strength. Yeah.
Starting starting strength
or for for simplicity sake.
I think a lot of the protocols
that Pavel Tsatsouline,
some people say his name Todd Celine,
but it's possible who really popularized
kettle bells in the United States.
Some of his programs are just amazing.
So there's, there's one called, uh,
if you search easy strength and
Pablos fame, a lot will pop up.
A very simple, and, um, my,
my podcast interview with him went really
deep into a bunch of his approaches
for strength and endurance and flexibility
with Pablo knows his stuff. Um,
also a great example of making,
finding the minimum effective dose that
produces the largest disproportionate
output or outcome. Uh, yeah, five
sets of five is hard to go wrong with.
Yeah. I mean, two of the
things that, you know,
the two of the things I would say would
really help me during that whole process,
especially for anyone trying to be in
fitness. Um, if you know, it's one,
as much as we want, like
less input, more output,
which I think you've done very
well because you figure out like,
how do I get maximum thing for, for
less. Part of it is consistency,
which I'm not gonna spend a ton of
timeline cause you don't, you have to go.
That's the point. Like in my calendar,
if you looked at my calendar today, Tim,
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday,
there's gym in there automatically.
I don't even get to choose.
It's just there at a certain
time and I do it every week. Um,
so consistency has been big.
And then secondly,
this is kind of more of a hack
one that it's not really a hack,
which is something that
really motivates me. Uh,
I follow fitness people
on Instagram. Uh, yeah,
a lot of people use Instagram for all
their friends that they, you know,
post stupid photos. And I don't really
follow any friends. Uh, all I follow,
I follow his wrappers and fitness people.
What is your Instagram?
Uh, Noah Kagan. Got It.
But I follow like this online coach Guy,
he posts great workout videos.
They post things like there's,
um,
I'll pull up some different people that
I recommend, but now he has this great.
Um,
and what's awesome about it is that they
just post all the different workouts,
what they eat,
motivation.
And so during the day when I'm on the
toilet or I'm kind of feeling lazy,
I go on my Instagram and I see
that their bodies are ripped.
And what was your recommendation?
We're going to come back to looking at
ripped bodies while sitting on the toilet.
Well the two things I was going to
recommend is number one, if you're in,
it's dropping out and I'm not
sure it's going to on today,
but I basically went and upgraded
our routers like an asis rt,
eight six dine net Dasher,
but basically like focus on the things
that are the highest levels of the funnel.
And I noticed my router is the first
thing that my internet comes in that
affects all of my work.
And so we went in and I don't know,
this is like a 200 $300 router.
So if you're at home and you're
working on your internet matters,
like go in and invest in that because
that's at the top of the funnel and
optimize the things where you get
the biggest results downwards.
Definitely. So you said two things, what
would, what's the other one? I don't know.
The router, the router and then
Instagram. We'll, we'll, let's,
let's come back to Instagram. So
looking at rip people, uh, I wanted to,
uh, have, I thought I was
maybe a Weirdo on my own, but,
so I actually do the exact same thing.
I'm trying to get better at gymnastics
and more bodyweight calisthenic type
movements. Ooh. So all,
almost all of people I follow
on Instagram and I'm just Tim.
Tim Ferriss with two r's and
two s's on Instagram are, uh,
like gymnastic bodies or
maybe gymnastics bodies, uh,
is incredible.
There are a couple of very impressive
par core athletes and acrobats,
including a friend of mine named Travis
brewer who competes on American Ninja
Warrior and was actually one of my
park or teachers for the Tim Ferriss
experiment when I like
destroyed my entire body. Uh,
but in a really fantastic coach
and just incredible, crazy athlete.
Um,
and I'll do the same thing
when I am feeling rushed or
inclined to skip training
for whatever reason. I will
go on Instagram and check
those folks out. Very cool.
And there's like, do you follow
calisthenic kings are, uh,
there are a number of them.
There's like callous then knows
I think is a Greek Greek guy.
There are a bunch of them.
I mean, there's so many,
of course they're are only
maybe six to 10. There's a guy,
I want to say his name
is Trevor Blackwell.
I'm also following some Olympic weight
lifters or guys who do a Olympic lifts,
uh,
who are beasts just because that's another
thing that I'm kind of focused on at
the moment. Uh, but, uh, that's a,
that's a much longer story. Uh, let's,
let's,
let's flip gears a little bit and talk
about some of your business rules or
guidelines. Uh, and I know
you've, you've mentioned before,
I think the four one,
one a and I was hoping you could elaborate
on that and maybe talk about some of
your other guidelines
or rules that you have.
Yemen,
uh,
so come back to some of the
business things that have
worked really well. I mean,
what I've learned, I'm
noticing my brothers, you know,
starting his own business.
Um, and you know, Neville
as I've mentioned earlier,
is trying to get certain
things organizing.
I've realized that like simple rules are
actually the easiest way for you to be
successful. Uh, and so the four one one
is specifically for Appsumo and you could,
you know, apply to yourself,
but we basically were like,
how many deals do we need to
do a month to be successful?
And then we can just follow that rule.
So for Appsumo, it's four one one,
which is just like four deals a month,
one free deal,
one promotion of an internal product
every month. And as long as we do that,
we're successful and that's for us.
But for yourselves listening,
how can you create simple rules?
Like once a week I have to do a blog
post once a week I have to make a sales
call and do the one, one, one thing,
which every week you do
with that one activity.
And I've just noticed the more
that we have simple rules,
it just makes it a lot easier for us
to be accomplishing those things and we
check in on them.
And so it just makes it life a lot easier
and a lot more effective and likely
that there'll be accomplished.
Do you use a Google spreadsheet or
project management stuff like a base camp?
We're in a sauna or Trello or whatever.
How do you actually keep on top of that
stuff with your team so that it doesn't
just get written down on a piece
of paper and lost along the way?
So I'll call it, I call it
the Susan Sue formula, uh,
or the angry Asian mother formula.
Anyone who you're talking to.
So Susan sue is this five foot,
nothing Asian checkers,
like one of the most bad
chicks you'll ever meet.
And so she came and ran sales for us
for about a year or two years ago.
And what she did, and you know, they
do it, we do it on the sales team,
is that they check in every
morning and every evening.
And so Susan's would be like,
what are three things you're going
to get done today? And if noonday,
what three things did you get done? And
that was, it's definitely a lot of work.
But I've been doing that with like Neville
is trying to grow his email list and
every morning, um, he's, you know,
he's going to be like a sure thing I'm
going to do at the end of the night.
He checks in with me.
He's like,
here's what I got done today and
here's my progress. And so what we do,
what I recommend for most people though
is I do a once a week check in with
everybody personally.
And I find that to be the most helpful.
If you want to be Susan Su level,
do a daily in the morning and evening.
And that's insanely effective because
it's like, here's what I'm going to do.
Here's what I got done. And you get
that stuff moving forward for sure.
Um, for me on Appsumo at a higher
level, I check in every week. Uh,
generally I just check in on person and
we have a dashboard that we check in
every day.
Is the dashboard in Google apps or
what does the text, and for that,
the dashboard, you're going to be pretty
smart. It's literally something we made.
It's just one number. So
I'll tell you, for tsunami,
our goal is to make a million
dollar revenue business this year.
So that's our goal for the business.
And so we have a target of how much
money you need to make a month,
which is $83,000. And then
we know how, so the, that,
that website is literally just
what is our revenue against that.
It's literally one number.
And if you ask anybody in our company,
like actually I'm kind of curious
to ask him, uh, I don't know,
walk into the interview, but if I have,
I'll ask him my chief chat right now. Uh,
what is our team goal for the year?
And this is something I learned from
Zuckerberg in terms of how to get things
organized.
I don't try to organize everything.
I try to focus on what's my number
one goal. And that's what Zuck did,
which is the number one goal
for him was growth. And I think,
I don't know if I mentioned
the story to you before,
but I went to Zuck trying to get him to
make money every telling the story. No,
no, I'd love to hear it. I
went to and I was like, dude,
Facebook needs to be real business
one day. Uh, let's make some money.
Don't you want to like stay
in the business and make a
lot of money for so that
we can, you know, be a company one day
and really profit. And he's like, no,
does that help us grow? I'm like,
no, no, I won't it this girl,
but it'll help us make money and make,
you know, make a business. He's like,
does it help us grow?
You know?
And so what he did that I've applied at
my businesses and that's all I ever do
now,
is that I pick one's very specific goal
and I check on it and a regular basis.
So as an example,
let me just break down the sumo me one.
Our goal is $1 million a year.
I have a spreadsheet that breaks out
how much money that is each month.
And then we have our dashboard that
shows it every day about how we're
progressing towards it. And on a
every month on the first of the month,
I just check how we did against what I
projected that we need to be doing to hit
our goal. And so everyone is focused
around that one goal and nothing else.
So I,
I love this and this is,
this is something that when
I'm say interviewing people
and trying to obviously
pick up lots of things
that I can use myself.
I mean this is not just for publication.
I like talking to people like you.
So I can pick up new book,
recommendations, tools, approaches,
and this is very consistent. Uh,
when you look at the very top, top,
top performers where for instance,
uh, we mentioned teal earlier
and, uh, who is not only a billionaire,
but he's done it several times over in
different ways. I mean, that's very,
very hard to do. And he was a famous, uh,
it, it, it turns out, and this could
be apocryphal, I don't know if it's,
if it's totally true,
but I think it is that at paypal he gave
every person one top objective and it
was a measurable objective.
And if they came to him for like an
office hours type of meeting or pull them
aside to ask him a question about
like, why don't we do this? Or Hey,
I need some help with such and such,
he would ask them,
how does this contribute to
your number one priority x?
And like how is it driving the numbers
forward? And if it was not related,
he wouldn't talk to them about it.
That's exactly right. I mean, that's
what we do at up soon. I just, uh, for,
for the Sumito comm product, I asked our
team, I just, clothes aren't team chat.
You know, what's our goal for the year?
And it will, the guy was joking me to put,
you know, 100,000 monthly recurring
potatoes. Uh, his nickname is potato.
So that's what he calls money.
Um,
but everyone on the team knows everyone
is aligned and for have similar.
In the past it was like last year was
a billion people seeing sumo me.com and
we've got to,
we hit a bit like a year before it was
$1 million a month in one k.com which we
did for those half a
million email subscribers.
And the point is not that well
no it gets everything done.
It's just I don't do anything else.
And that comes back to the essentialism,
a book that you were mentioning earlier,
which really kind of
drives that point home.
Yeah, I mean and obviously you have your
high level thing and you break it down.
So like I was telling you, I'm struggling
right now with, we have two customers,
we have small, medium business, self
serve and then we have enterprise.
And so I have to come
back and look at art,
which helps us accomplish our goal better.
And you know,
that's what I have to go and spend
time solving to then say, all right,
well what will help us go faster and
easier to hit that number one goal?
And then focus just on that and then
kind of keep going through that process.
Like right now I get interview
requests probably like every two days,
every three to hey, come talk to
my interview. And I'm like, well,
this helped me get to my goal faster
than doing another activity and it won't,
so I don't do it. And that's specifically
like this. And I'm like, yeah, okay, Tim,
you know,
Tim,
a few people have heard of Tim Ferriss
and a lot of people will check this out.
So it will be significant to worth my
time to help me really accomplish my goal.
Uh, and everyone on the
team is aligned with that.
So speaking of goals, I think a lot of
people have goals. They're like, you know,
yeah. That Noah Guy, he's been talking
about building an email list. Yeah,
I know he's helping devil,
I should really do that.
And they have the should do that.
And that's as far as it goes, right?
Maybe they take a note, maybe they put
it into their notes in their iPhone,
whatever. And that's where it lives
forever and it never gets implemented.
So you mentioned earlier that,
uh,
you would do a demo or basically give
people something they can do now to,
to pump the ball down if the then down
the field a little bit and make some,
some progress. And I think you
mentioned email subscribers, uh,
if I'm right, correct me if I'm
wrong, but w what is that exercise?
Oh Man. So as soon we.com is free
tools to get to grow your website.
So how to get a bigger email list,
how to get more shares and,
and just for people who are listening,
I use that on my blog.
And it's not because I do love you, but
it's not because I love you. Oh, Timothy.
Um, so here's what
we're going to do. Like,
I think one of the things that people
love about you and what I respect about
you is that you're about getting
shit done. Like, you know,
for our work is how do I get things done?
How do I do less work to get more,
even more things done? Uh, and you know,
you want to understand the elements of
those things and you're very curious and
very specific about that. Um, so, you
know, I'd love for you to listen to notes,
but anybody who does what I had to teach
them to do the highest result person,
we're going to do a giveaway.
I'm going to pay for it where I will fly
you to hang out with me and our office
and put you up in a room. I'm not around
it. Know that sounds a little creepy. Uh,
and I will, you know, you can work with
us on any project you have for a day.
We'll get you Taco Deli for the person
who actually takes action because I know
for you that's really important to him.
And I want,
I don't want you to just listen
to this interview and not do shit.
I want you to listen to the interview,
take action, and make your life better.
That's what makes this
worth it for me. And, uh,
just so people have a context here,
what is the deadline for doing this?
Well, I'm going to give you things
that you can do in real time.
So I will say a week from when this goes
public because you should be able to do
those things within that day and
right now as you're listening.
So I would say if you're weak,
that's already long enough. Okay,
got it. So I'll just say for guys and
obviously a void where prohibited, blah,
blah, blah, you can't be mandatory.
You need to be over 18 years of age.
You can't be a whatever. You could
take over the prices, right? Man, blah,
blah, blah, blah, Blah and uh, no,
no purchase necessary, all that shit.
And none at all. There's
actually, it's totally free.
And what I want to teach people is how
to start a business or how to share your
message with the world.
Instantly if even if you don't have
anything cool right now and the,
and so the person who does the most,
you're going to fly them to Austin
and show them a good time and uh,
perhaps free cuddles,
always cuddle this dude bro.
Hugs, Bro. Hugs. Well, so here's,
let me just start with like, you know,
we did this monthly one k product, uh,
when they, when Kate icon to show people
how to start a business and you know,
5,000 plus people and I've
been able to help a lot. Um,
and a lot of people are like,
why do I start?
And I think the two things I want to
say is either if you want to start a
business or if you just wanna get your
message out there started now so that
whenever you want to do in the future,
I know Tim,
I actually read when I was studying all
you your popular interviews to figure
out what stuff you're out into. We want
to hear. And you would actually said, hey,
I wish I had an email as sooner so that
as you have books or things you want to
promote or get out there, you can have
direct communication with your audience.
So I want to specifically show how anyone
listening right now can get a hundred
people on an email list for free
so that when they have a message,
they can get it out instantly.
Yeah, let's go. Let's rock and roll.
All right.
So whoever gets the most of their email
list within the week from when this goes
live, I will fly you out and
pay for food, pay for hotel,
and help you with whatever business
stuff you want to be helped with. So,
all right. So here's what we're
gonna do. You have a phone,
you listen to this podcast. Is that how
most people listen to the podcast in?
I think a lot of people are listening
on their phones. Maybe not exclusively,
but on whatever device. But let's, let's
just say you have a phone handy. Sure.
All right.
So if you're on your phone,
I'm speaking right into the microphone.
Come back to your phone or
if you're on your computer,
come back to the computer
and hang out the, all right.
So I want you to grab your phone
and here's what we're gonna do. The,
I want you to get a hundred subscribers
and I'll just say it again cause I think
it's important.
If you want a hundred subscribers,
it's so that if you ever want to start a
business or if you ever want to promote
something or share your message,
even start it now so you can
do it whenever you're ready.
Instead of waiting until later and
not doing anything which will pop,
it will piss me off. So if you
want to get a hundred subscribers,
here's what I want you to do. Choose any
topic you're interested in, like Tim,
let's actually, we'll do it. I'll do
it live right now as well. What's a,
what's a topic that you're interested in,
Tim?
Like something recently that you've been
thinking about or reading or curious
about?
Interested in the ketogenic diet,
which is like the,
Oh, the Kido thing. Yeah.
I'm interested in that. I'm,
I'm really digging deep in that right now.
Okay.
So would you want to
start a new newsletter?
Uh, I am trouble. I
probably have my hands full.
You're a little busy. All right. Yeah,
I will do the Kido topic newsletter.
I will get a hundred people right now
on it so that I can share that message
with other people. And then maybe I
can say that Tim likes the Quito died.
So choose a topic that you're
curious about, interested in.
You want to talk about the certain
people. Here's what I want you to do. Tim,
do you have your phone on you?
Uh,
I have my phone off because I didn't want
it to interfere with what we are doing
here.
Okay. Attention to me, so that's good.
All right, well for whoever's listening,
here's what we're going to do.
I'm going to take a photo of myself.
So take a photo of yourself now.
I want you to go to your social networks
and I'll, I'll post all this stuff
on a, in the blog post to also,
which I'll get people in Finland,
but continue to,
and here's what people are going to say.
Well no one Tim have followers or fuck,
who cares about followers? Even if you
have 100 people, don't worry about that.
It doesn't matter if you have 10 a
hundred or five, take a photo of yourself.
Now I want you to post it on your
social sites, Facebook and Google,
Facebook and Twitter.
So right and don't even,
you don't have to sign up for service.
No, we don't have an email list. I guess.
What's an email list? Provider? Gmail.
That's a great way to start
your newsletter so that
you know I just to give you
a context like absolutely as a high seven
figure business and 90% plus just come
from an email list.
So just to give you context about,
oh you actually can just be email
is kin create large businesses.
So posting your social, I'm starting a
newsletter and then attach your photo.
You're going to see my photo on Noah
Kagan and then say email me and then put
your email. So I'm going to do mine
about Kido cause I'm curious about Quito.
Email me Noah or I'll put Quito at,
okay.
dork.com and this will go to my inbox
and now I will get a list of people who
will be curious about Kido.
So it didn't cost me any money.
It took me about two seconds.
So if you're on your phone,
take a photo of yourself,
go to your Twitter,
and then I'm going to go to my Facebook
and just post it socially and starting a
newsletter about Kito Kito at,
okay.
dork.com and so I just tweeted that and
now people are going to start emailing
me about Kido.
And so that's one tick tactic.
So we're going to do with two more,
uh,
and then you will
actually probably have a,
if not more people interested
in what you want to talk about.
So if you want to sell them something or
if you just want to put out information.
One thing I've noticed him is that
one tactic that I do is in my, okay,
dork.com newsletter. I have an auto
reply. When people join that say,
what's one thing I can help you with?
And then they tell me their questions and
that's actually businesses. People say,
Hey, no, I want help with this.
And basically you just look for the
pattern of what the constant questions
people keep asking you and
you say, hey, email this.
I'm going to create a book about this.
It's 10 bucks.
You pay me via paypal and I go make it
and this is what I've taught 5,000 people
in. And they do it and they
get businesses. The Problem
Tim, is people are like,
it can't be that easy because they're
looking for some magic bullet or some
golden trick or something more
complicated, but it's not.
It starts with one customer
and helping one person.
And this is the way you can actually
start it while you're listening to the
podcasts instead of waiting to eventually
start your business. Definitely.
No, I stay, I and I've seen, uh, you know,
there are people out there like Neil
Patel has done some very similar stuff,
right? I mean he's, he,
he's, he's been like,
pay me this and then I will
add you to this email list.
It's so simple and makes a ton
of money. I mean, there are,
it doesn't have to be complicated.
In fact, if it is really complicated,
it probably not the right answer.
So you said there were a couple of
other things that people should yes.
So you posted it,
I posted them on Twitter and then
posted on your Facebook and have people
emailing you to subscribe. That's number
one. And they just email you don't need,
you don't need any software,
you don't need to sign up for MailChimp,
which is free, but that's complicated.
Just keep it really simple. Secondly,
go to your email signature. So
Tim, for you on your settings,
on your phone.
So if you have an iPhone goes,
I don't even know what android who uses
android. Um, but on iPhone go to settings,
male and scroll to the bottom to your
signature on your signature to say,
reply to me if you want
the latest tips on Kido.
And so if you already have a mailing list,
make sure you update your signature on
all your accounts on a regular basis.
So unlike my personal one,
it says,
come eat tacos with me and people click
it all the time and then it's like, oh,
you should join my newsletter.
Basically what I try to recommend people
as you're starting businesses is keep
it as simple as possible. Don't spend as
much money as possible and importantly,
leverage the assets you already
have available. When most people,
Tim don't realize is that they have
at least 50 to 200 people minimum on
linkedin. That could be potential
customers, but they think, oh,
I've got to do like a Facebook ad,
which is going to cost you money
and I want to discourage that.
And so I'm trying to say,
how do you already have assets?
Do you already have a church group?
Do you already have a Facebook group?
Do you already have,
uh,
your colleagues that you can use Azure
customers to join your newsletter and
eventually make a business out
of it? Cause you could say, Hey,
I'm creating something. You
should buy it. And guess what?
Now you have access to these people
via your newsletter. Is this,
is this connecting?
Yeah.
I can't sell it because I'm talking
to myself a little bit. Yeah,
no, no, no. This, this all makes
sense. And I want to give a,
just a quick text suggestion for
people who might be like, oh my God,
but I don't have, you know, let's
just say your name is, uh, whatever.
Bob Jones. So I don't have a
Bob jones.com domain. I don't,
I can't, I don't know how to
create a kito@bobjones.com
email address. Uh, a workaround for
that, which a lot of people don't.
It's so simple and I couldn't believe
how useful that says when you figure it
out. If your email
addresses, let's just say
bobJones@gmaildotcomifyoucreatebobjonesplusanythingyourightatgmail.com
your
email, we'll still get delivered.
So you could, you could put, Hey,
I'm on Twitter, you can say I'm
starting a Kito newsletter. Email me at,
uh,
Bob Jones plus symbol kido@gmail.com
if you want to join people email that.
And it allows, it then allows you
to search by that email and sort.
Uh,
and you don't have to set up anything new.
You're just using a plus sign and some
kind of identifier before the ad symbol.
Um, super, super useful.
And Expedia, Expedia,
you can also do for this is if you're
signing up for a new service or anything,
a newsletter you can put plus
and then some identifier.
So it's like if I sign up for, you
know, but whatever, super, super, uh,
you know, underoos
heroes.com and, uh, I'm like,
you know,
I wonder if these guys are going to spam
me and I want to know if they do or if
they sell my information
or anything like that.
I want to be able to automatically send
it to trash without giving them my real
email address. Right? So
bobJones@gmail.com that's
valuable information.
I don't want to be getting shit from
all sorts of people potentially if they
leak my information. So I'll, I'll,
I'll put Bob Jones plus you know under
is@gmail.com and that way I know if my
information has been leaked and I can,
I can just junk that email address and
have it all go to spam for instance.
So that exactly that plus approach,
it's super helpful.
I don't think enough people know that one.
The other thing I would add to that as
do the plus filter and do that and then
in your settings create uh,
filters. Do you create this?
So I would, I would do for
all these people in Gmail is,
I don't know these other services
and most people use Gmail,
but in labs of GML and your settings lab
turn on canned responses and enable it.
Then what you do is create a filter.
So whenever,
and you can do this in a search box
really easily. So I said Kido at, okay,
dork.com or I could do my email address,
which is Noah Kagan plus quito@gmail.com
which is what Tim was suggesting to you.
And so what you do is you searched
to at, you know Quito at, okay,
dork.com and I've already got Tim,
I already got a two people
emailing me for the newsletter.
That's fantastic.
And so what you do here is you click the
little down Arrow and you click filter
messages like these and you create a
filter like this or it now it says,
you know,
create a filter with this search.
And what I would do here is I
have a canned response that, look,
I know you're going to
create any software,
so send a canned response and
the camera's sponsor would be,
when I create that's like, Hey, what are
you interested into learning about Kido?
And they would just tell me what I should
be creating for them and possibly even
selling them in the future.
Definitely. And, and I want to point
out just a couple of things. Well,
actually before I do that,
are there any other steps
or recommendations and then
I have just a couple of
observations that I think might be
helpful for people who might find this
intimidating?
Yeah.
What I want you to do is if you have
a phone, you can do this right now.
If you're listening as podcasts,
you don't have to go anywhere else,
you don't have to pay for anything and
you could start your business instantly,
which I've never seen anyone do before,
but you can do with the technology
we have available for free.
So number one posted on your social
posted on Facebook and Twitter.
I put a photo cause it's
a little more a parent.
Maybe you want to put a little more text
and just give them the email address to
email you to join on your signature.
I wrote this Tim,
which I think you'll appreciate.
It says for all my signature on my phone
it says reply to me with a hell yes if
you want the latest Kido
News. I like it. I like,
and I've actually used it in some of
our sales collateral and it works really
well because we were like, Oh hell
yes. Sure. And so now I'm going to,
I do it for sales, but you can put in
your signature and now that's done.
So in every 50 emails I
send every day on average,
I now have probably about two to five of
them being like, oh yeah, cool. Hell yes.
I'm like, what do you
tell yessing about? Um,
but set up your filter and they get
the reply and then now you have the
questions to be answering. The last
thing I would say that is really cool.
It's go to your team. Do you have
favorites on your phone? Yeah. Yeah.
I'm actually really curious. That's
fascinating. Who's on your favorites? Man?
My phone is off, so I'm not sure. No. You
know who's on your phone? Act like that?
Who's are your favorites? No, no, I'm not
sure. Honestly, I'd have to look at it.
I know I'm not, I don't talk to you that
often, but uh, like all my favorites.
This is just like my brother and
my girlfriend. A few other people.
I like my coworkers.
Um,
go to your favorites cause it's the
easiest one not to have to think about and
just click on their names
and then text them. Hey Man,
can I send you information about
Kido? It's cool. Died information.
What I want to go back to that point that
was critical and I thought most people
are probably ignores it. Just go to
the people that already like you.
If they won't even buy from your industry,
from you, it's only gonna get harder.
It will not be easier. And what
I want to do is you, you know,
you took your assets,
you used it,
you had set up some passive things like
your signature and texting people that
are your favorites. And if they don't
know someone, then you ask for a referral.
And men,
do you know any person that's like a
fatty or anyone who's like crazy into
health that might be interested in
Quito News? And this is just basic,
obviously we can get more
fancy and complicated,
but this is the way that it starts.
This is how you get that first customer.
That's how you start the Facebook
or Google or Amazon or Microsoft.
No, I didn't. Then I started interject
this one to say to people, a few things.
Number one is keep in mind you
can always abandoned the project.
I think a lot of people were like, wow,
but I don't know how to run a newsletter.
I don't really want to commit to
another part time job. Oh my God.
Like what happens if blah, what happens if
this, what happens that it's like, look,
you can always just send an email
to these people would be like, hey,
had a huge fire pop up. The kido
newsletter's going to have to wait.
Sorry guys might have more newsletter
and then you're done. You don't have,
it's not a major life commitment that
you're not going to be that you're not
getting married to the newsletter.
A and like an Irish Catholic family.
I mean it's like you,
you have options here and it happened to
me,
him to happened to me six months ago.
I started an events business to show
people how to start an events business
where I sold tickets and then I
made events. And then I was like,
I kind of don't want to keep doing events
cause I'm trying to run appsumo and
sumo me. And so I just refunded the
difference to people and it, you know,
it's very straight forward all always
with integrity and just letting people
know their expectations.
And just, just to actually add another
example. So I've done this many,
many times and sometimes things don't work
out or you don't like it and you quit.
So I tried to make a membership site,
a very inexpensive membership site as an
experiment ages ago for $10 a month or
something like that. And it turned
out that I just, at least at the time,
didn't like managing it and
the technology wasn't great.
So the experience wasn't perfect.
And I was like, you know,
just don't want to do this anymore.
It's too much psychic drain.
It's not worth the trouble.
So I refunded everybody and there were,
there were several, several hundred
people probably refunded everybody,
everything that they'd spent. And just
shut the thing down. And uh, you all,
you almost always have that option. But
there are other things like the podcast,
I was like, you know what, I'm not sure
if I'm going to like this internally.
I'm going to commit to doing six
episodes as an experiment and then I'll
reassess it and I might ditch it and
they'll just be like my mini series of
podcasts and it worked out. So
I kept on doing it. Um, the, um,
so to bring it back to the competition
then for those people who are listening,
they're like, yes. Hell yes.
I want to compete. Uh, guys,
you can find the blog post for
this episode@fourhourworkweek.com,
forward slash podcast all spelled out.
And in the comments you have to leave
your results and you have to leave your
results.
Uh,
just to make it easier for
everyone on my side to manage,
you're going to have to put Hashtag
Noah at the top of your comment.
And if you can't follow
that set of instructions,
we're not going to look at your comments.
So do that.
Hashtag Noah at the top of the comment
and a what should they include in their
comment?
Noah?
Yes. So two things.
There's going to be there.
There's definitely people on your
audience. Your audience is awesome.
Like I've met a lot of people that,
and they're all over the world. I'm,
they're like, yeah, I love Tim and,
and how my life has changed it.
So I know that there's already people who
are kicking ass and running successful
businesses. You're like, well Noah,
I already have a successful business.
I'm in Australia. It was a great
Australian and is that pretty good?
That was going to Australian like
kangaroo, British accent. Um,
so I'm looking more for the
people who are taking actions.
So if you already have them
was take action on really
significantly growing that
on the seven days.
I'm looking for people who have the
biggest results either from zero to a
hundred or from a thousand to 100,000.
And so what I really want to see is
what have you done to really grow your
mailing list in the next seven days
from when you've listened to this?
And for the people, just
to remind you, if you,
if you don't have a mentalist or if you
don't have a business or if you have a
business,
this is the best way to communicate
with your customers whenever you want to
sell them something.
Or even if you just want to share
your message with the world,
you have direct access to something that,
how often do you check your email?
I know how often I check
mine. Uh, it's, it's a lot,
especially coming on the toilet, you
know, like oh email, it's toilet time. Uh,
that an Instagram. The second thing
that I wanted to mention to him.
So number one,
Hashtag Noah your comment and show me
what you've done in this week and we'll
full expenses flight anywhere in the world
hotel and you get to work with us for
a day. The second thing is if
you already have an email list,
I was talking with Tim about it. We've
put together on our side like a free,
no upsell, cross sell down.
So free course for you guys.
So go check it out.
If you have an email list already that
it's email [inaudible] dot com slash Tim
and that's fully free. There's
nothing to sell their, I'm sorry.
If you want to give you money, you're
welcome to, but not with this. Uh,
and that will be it's 10 experts that'll
show you how to grow your mailing list
on more advanced tactics
if you already have one.
Very cool, and I will put this in
the blog post as well, guys, but uh,
which we'll have show notes and links
and all sorts of other things that we
talked about in this episode.
But, uh, just to recap,
so in the comment,
if you're going to do this,
Hashtag Noah your
results and what you did,
quantify it whenever possible,
and then I want you to end with the most
important lesson that you learned in
doing this exercise.
Um,
so that the comments themselves
because become very useful resource for
everybody. Um, good stuff.
And I'm just want to see people take
action and they do and then get results
because you can do it from your
phone. There's no excuse. Yeah, no,
there's no excuse. Uh, so let's, let's
do this. No, I am a, I actually, you're,
you're making me think of all the things
I want to do now and I know you're
running a company, but we have to,
we're going to go do a flotation.
I'm taking my girlfriend first surprise
flotation evidence, a flotation tank.
I have done flotation tank.
Actually.
I was introduced or finally
pushed to try it by Joe Rogan. Uh,
and you're talking about like a
deprivation tank basically. Exactly, Yep.
Have you done it before? I have done it
before. Um, actually is our first date,
which I don't recommend, but I've done
it many times. First date is a very,
that's an intensive kind of creepy silence
of the lambs first getting in a box
naked in someone's house.
It's not the idea.
You have flotation tank at your house.
No, no. I went in Austin a few years ago.
There was not a, there wasn't,
there wasn't public ones.
So that a private one in some
ways, his house. So I was like,
I swear this is legit.
I'm not just trying to get you naked.
I just need to get into Xbox naked
and I'm gonna close the door on you
and I'll tell you on that experience,
I was actually really scared because
it was my first time so I had a panic
attack. Wow, that's, yes, no good.
But subsequently I've gone to like
larger ones that are like super clean and
legit. And I do it like
once a month. My, I,
I generally bounce between that and
Chinese massages like the reflexology,
cause they're only 35 bucks
and it's like the secret.
What's the secret white people don't know.
So I don't want all you
guys going to do this now,
but reflexology massages or
35 bucks or Chinese massage,
there's no happy endings and
it's the most affordable,
effective massage I've ever
found. Yeah. I need to,
I need to get all my reflexology action.
I use something called
a rad roller are Rad.
It's like two lacrosse balls
melted together to roll out
my feet each day. Uh Oh.
So these kind of like just nugget sized
recommendations I think are really fun.
So let,
if you wouldn't mind
just in a sort of wrap up, I'll ask
you a couple of rapid fire questions.
You don't have to answer
super, super, uh, concisely,
but just to the extent possible,
we'll,
we'll try to do short questions and short
answers and we'll do a couple of, hey,
could you speak shortly? Not Long, just do
it. I'm like, yes, I'll do it. Less words.
I use my ESL skills.
Uh,
when you think of the word successful,
who's the first person who comes
to mind and why? Evan Williams.
So for those people that he
is the co founder of Twitter,
blogger medium, uh, all,
all around baller, why,
why is that? So, you know,
I think it's easy to do a
business once and be successful.
I think when you can do it multiple times,
you're a bad ass. Um, and I don't know,
success is very relative
to how you define it,
but if it's money or if it's
whatever it is you want it to be. Um,
I think from like a business
creation and making society better,
Evan is very interesting
communication and he didn't, you know,
it's pretty big that you did blogger. I
think most people do blogger and tap out.
You're like, you know, I'm, I'm pretty,
it's like you on Musk. He did one thing,
you know,
he's already sold the company and then he
did paypal and then he did another one.
It's like him and everyone's just like,
holy Moly, you don't just do it once.
You do it many times. Um, because easy
to hit a home run once, but to do,
do it consistently. Just I think the
consistency of it and dedication is,
was really impressive to
me about that. No, I agree.
And what's also impressive and really
inspiring about that is generally
speaking,
the guys who have that type of
consistency or gals and do it repeatedly,
are doing it for reasons other than the
money because they already have more
money than God and some of these cases.
And it's really about the mission.
And I think that's partially why
some of them like Ev, you know,
I've spent time with as, and he's,
uh, he comes across as a happy guy.
You know what I mean? It's a, and
that's not what does surprise you.
It's incredibly surprising because the,
the,
the type a personalities that I usually
run into who have made hundreds of
millions or billions of dollars are
so driven that they have trouble
appreciating anything that they have.
And I don't feel like
that's the case with f. Um,
so all the more impressive to me that
he's able to maintain that type of
perspective. Uh, okay. Do you have
any favorite movies or documentaries?
Uh, yes. So my fair movie
immediately is commando.
It's a horrible Arnold
Schwarzenegger movie. So easing,
oh my God, it's, it's great.
I just, I don't know. I was a kid. I
watched it over and over on Beta tapes,
which you younguns probably don't
know about. Um, I love con, uh,
two other ones I think are just really
well done. It's count of Monte Cristo.
I haven't seen that. Oh,
it's just such good revenge.
If you just want to get revenge, like
you have an ex girlfriend or something,
you watch this guy and like
I need to be like him. Um,
and then there's a recent documentary
called the jinx. Oh, I haven't seen that.
Oh Dude, you're going to
blow your mind. What is,
which one I don't think everyone wants
you to do and no one wants you to do.
But this guy blows people's minds
with his gun and he gets away with it.
Huh? It's a, it's a documentary on
Robert Frost, which you probably,
you've heard his name or seen his
name somewhere, but they just like,
they get you and the ending is
just insane. Don't, all right.
If you ever watch the jinx, go watch
the jinx and thank me later. Awesome.
I'll throw out another one for
people who like documentaries,
King of King of Kong,
uh, or man on wire. You can
look at those two and then,
and then choose one to suit your tastes.
Uh,
what advice would you give
to how old are, you know, no,
33, dude, I'm like dead in
the Internet zone. I'm like,
I'm old. I'm dinosaur. Yeah,
you are a dinosaur. What advice would
you give to your 25 year old self?
Uh,
and I say my first five
I've been asking, I've been telling
people 20 but we're fucking,
everybody's a fucking
idiot. It's 20. Yeah,
I was going to say condoms morning
after pill condoms now. Um, you know,
I'd say that the number one thing that I,
and here's the thing,
I think a lot of these things people
can hear and then they just discard.
So let me just tell you how to do it.
So get a mentor, but you're like, oh,
I don't know how to get a mentor.
Here's what you should do.
Email the person that you respect the
most that's done the thing you want to do
that you know right now.
Like get up,
have your phone and text them
and email and be like, hey,
I think you're the really best
person I know in the space.
Like can I meet with
you on a regular basis?
And if they are like a person
who's too busy for you,
ask them who they'd recommend.
Like,
who do you learn from locally or Internet
lead or wherever that I could just
talk to on a regular basis.
And I really wish I would have
been more active in securing that.
And you don't have to go try to get Peter
Teal or Tim Ferriss or no king cause
we don't want to help you.
It's like we want to have like we don't,
we're busy doing things that we want to
help at scale. It's hard. Exactly. Okay.
Thank you. To see that's where we
have Tim, I'll use the ugly word,
ugly ass word in that capacity.
But,
and so it's not that I
don't want to help people,
it's just like I don't have the capacity
to help as many people as I'd like.
And so when I was 25,
I think I would have spent more time
finding someone that's done the things I
want and helping them and having active,
uh, meetings with them to be like, Hey,
you've already done where I want to go.
Why don't I just learn it from you instead
of wasting all the time that I had to
do. Um, number two, at 25 hours
a week I'd worked for free.
So I would go help that person.
So email your friend, be like, Yo,
can I meet with you? I'll help you with
whatever you want. And if they don't,
if they're not busy, ask who they'd
recommend. Uh, and then third,
I really just kind of look at your phone
or your Internet browsing or in your
home and look at the products or services
that I was using at today right now
and go work for those
companies. Hmm. So yeah,
when I was 25 and I did do this and I'm
really happy to this, but I was like,
I just like Facebook.
I'm going to go try to work there.
I just love personal finances.
I did a personal finance workshop this
morning with my team because I just love
talking about money. Um, and
so I went and worked at mint.
So go and try to surround yourself or put
yourself in places doing the work that
you really want to be doing. Yeah.
And he's just way to do that.
It's just look at what you're
already enjoying. And then go like,
think about if you could do that all day.
Absolutely. And some
other related, uh, bits,
I just actually heard this
yesterday from someone, uh,
older gent actually who's,
uh, he's not above asking for
mentorship.
And um,
I usually discourage people from using
the word mentor or mentorship because
it's just, it screams unpaid fulltime
job. So if you're going to pitch,
people don't use that wording, but I
think the work for free piece is huge.
And when he said he got one of the biggest
names in Silicon Valley to mentor him
effectively,
although he didn't call it that because
he said it pretty much the same thing,
he emailed this guy out
of the blue and said,
I really respect what you've done with a,
B and, c, I've read everything about it.
Um,
here are things I've done.
If you have something that might be
sort of credible, if not, that's fine.
And then he said, I know
you're working on a book. Uh,
I would love to ask you some very
specific questions for every hour that you
spend with me.
I will spend four hours proofreading your
book or helping you with the book pro
Bono.
And that's how he got the first meeting.
And then the guy agreed to meet with
him on an ongoing basis for, uh,
more than a year and never took him up
on the proofreading offer even though
that was sort of the sugar that that
made the pill go down. Um, so that,
that's a really important
point. And Charlie Hoehn has
some good writing on this.
H O h n on, on working for
free. Really? 100%, uh,
a book. Oh no, go for it.
No, no, no. He's a bookworm assessment.
Proof of proof graduate is just epic for
younger people starting out or anyone
or anyone who's starting over or
trying to reinvent themselves. Really.
Other thing too, I think you
said, which is super trade,
I just want to highlight it for everyone
listening is don't email people.
Be like, Hey, I'll help you with
anything. Because I'm like, well,
now I have to think about what to do and
you're going to be a shitty free labor
person. Yeah. Like that's the worst
because you're getting like 10,
how many animals do you like roughly
how many miles you get to do like, Hey,
I want to work with you.
Can I hang out with you can have coffee
with you from people you don't know?
Uh, at least a hundred a day.
Uh, the Holy Shit to my team.
Or B, if they manage to somehow, you know,
spam a hundred emails and get one. Right.
Exactly. And so, you know,
it's interesting to think
about like, how do you,
how does the person stand out
to actually get ahold of him?
And so here's how you do
it. You won, someone told me
this yesterday, I loved it.
It was called the swipe.
The one thumb rule,
which is your email should be able to
be one thumbed on the phone. Yeah. Yeah.
Which I thought was pretty good.
I thought that was a good way of
looking at the one thumb rule.
The second thing is don't tell Tim,
you can study Tim all day.
All of your stuff is public.
Most of it that you're working on
or thinking about ghosts, study Tim.
And do the work, then send
it to Tim. There's a guy,
brian@videofruit.com and Brian does this
for a lot of people. Are He emails you?
And he's like, Hey, I made this video for
you and to this marketing role for you.
Hey, I did this document for
you here. I just sent it to you.
I'm not expecting shit. And then you're
like, well damn, this is really good.
What else can you do?
Yup,
Yup.
Milling Timberlake who tune, we
should just like, can I help you?
I'll be a free intern just so
they can learn to pick your brain.
Yeah. And I don't, uh, I don't reply to
any of those and that it, number one,
because they don't have the capacity.
And I think for a lot of
tasks like that that are,
and don't make no mistake,
that's a task that I have to,
I have to do that instead
of something else. Um,
piece of advice that I got from someone.
Um,
but I'm blanking on who said this to me,
but they said, and it was so I was like,
wow, okay. That is great.
And it, it's, it, it's,
it sort of comes back to your point
about doing your homework and they said,
if someone hasn't done their homework
to determine if something is a fit,
I don't have the time to explain to
them why it isn't a fit. And I was like,
isn't that good? And I like
that. And I was like, Oh man,
that is a, that is a gem. And uh,
so that when I have ended up, uh, doing,
uh, for instance, ending up working
with Charlie or whatever his number one,
they did something of value that was
highly specific in indicated they'd done a
lot of homework.
Uh,
that was very helpful and they
didn't expect anything in return,
but they did such good work that I was
like, like you said, I was like, Huh, wow.
What else can this guy do a, or you know,
maybe maybe someone's like, hey, here's a,
you know, uh, uh, this is
not an example. Please.
I don't need a thousand of
these sent to me guys. But like,
here's a summary of podcast x.
And I thought this would be useful
for you to use as a pdf, uh,
as my logo all over it. Yeah.
Well, but if they're like, hey,
if you want me to do a few more of these,
like I have some dead time between
now and Blah, um, let me know. But if,
if I don't hear back from you, no
problem. Right. And I think another Pr,
another mistake a lot of
people make is they buy, and I,
and I've been guilty of this in the past,
you know,
and I look back at some of my behavior
when I was just getting started and I
cringe because it was in retrospect,
I'm like, no, fucking wonder.
I didn't get any responses. Uh, if,
if you send emails like any of what
we've described today and you don't get a
response, don't take it personally.
And that's easy advice to say.
But I would take it one step further.
And the way you don't take it personally
is assume that the people who don't
respond to have excellent reasons for
not responding. Right. And I'm like,
maybe someone in their family is sick.
Maybe they're trying to take care of
their kids. I'm in trouble at school,
maybe fill in the blank. Just assume they
have a good reason for not responding.
And um, there's another expression, God,
I wish I could remember who told me this,
but you know, don't attribute
to malice that would, that,
that which can be
explained by incompetence.
But I would modify that
and I would say don't,
don't attribute to malice what can be
explained by incompetence and competence
or just buisiness.
Right?
So just because someone doesn't get
back to you right away or just because
someone sends you a short
email and misses something, uh,
don't immediately assume that it's
because they're trying to fuck with you or
because they don't respect you.
I see so many people get wound up and
they're like, oh my God, so disrespectful.
I'm like, oh, so blah.
And they shoot themselves in the foot
and I've been guilty of that myself.
I think that I'm pretty quick
to anger and very impatient.
So it's taken a lot of effort to try
to sand down the rough edges. But, uh,
another lap, just one last tip,
uh, is, uh, for finding mentors.
A great way to do that is to volunteer
for local business organizations that host
events. That's what I did when
I moved to Silicon Valley.
So you can volunteer at events where
they have local icons or business leaders
coming to speak, and you get to
interact with those people. And if,
if you're volunteering somewhere,
by the way,
it does not give you
license to do a shitty job.
And most people think that's true.
So you can stand out just by doing twice
what you're asked to do as a volunteer.
And that's how you get to know people.
Like I did,
I got to know Jack Canfield to
cocreate a chicken soup for the soul.
And then many years later introduced me
to the guy who became my agent who sold
the four hour workweek. Uh, that was
pretty cool. Yeah. All right. So to know,
next question,
uh,
what is the purchase that you've made
in the last say six months for $100 or
less,
that has had the greatest impact on your
life purchase in the last six months?
The episode?
I would say one, I purchased it around
that time, but it's my nutribullet.
I don't know what that is. It's
the magic bullets, bigger brother.
The magic bullet, which is not
a sexual device. It's a blend.
I guess it could be in some weird ways,
but the nutri bullet is basically like,
I like smoothies, I like my protein
shakes, I like blending up things. Um,
but it's always a pain in
the ass to clean. Right? And
this you could just blend,
drink out and wash out
and there's no cleaning.
And every time I get this is like the
gift I give to most people. I'm like, do,
if you don't have any to triple that in
your kitchen, like you're missing out.
And it's just really effective for like
blending anything and getting it up.
Like I have a Vitamix,
which is like a $500 blender.
And I just don't even use it anymore. It's
a lot of cleanup for that thing. Yeah.
Well yeah,
it's like I have to get a cleaning lady
to assist me to clean up thing. Uh,
and the neutral that you can do,
you know, in 20 seconds or less.
And it's just been a really effective
and it's one of those things that like if
you don't have it, I just
buy it for people because
that's what I know they need.
Very cool.
Well action packed.
I love how many things we were
able to cover and uh, yeah,
I would love to hear what people think
and also the competition people can check
out. So go to four hour
work week.com forward slash
podcast to check that out. Uh,
one more thing I'm going to mention for
folks is that you and I both were on an
episode of the Tim Ferriss experiment
and coached someone through launching
their business and went through a lot of,
of information that we weren't able
to couple cover in this episode,
like creating call scripts and tons of
challenges like the coffee challenge and
so on. So that's, I think
people would enjoy checking out,
but where can people learn more about,
you know, uh, find you online, et cetera.
Yup. A number one thing for my
personal stuff is going to be an, okay,
dork.com okay. Dr K. Dot.
Com and business related.
If you know,
for the tools and every,
a lot of the main things I was talking
about, it's going to be@sumome.com.
That's a lot of the businesses that we've
been building in recommending for most
people.
Awesome. Uh, anything,
any parting advice or thoughts
that you'd like to give to folks?
I would, I would two other
things, cause I looked at I,
and this is kind of a thing,
like I think there's a,
there's a ratio of how much you invest
in something to how much you get out.
So if you're sending emails to people
like Tim or a customer or anybody you want
and you're sending a quick email,
you're probably not getting a response
because you're not investing that much.
So I invested in researching shows and
comments to see what is gonna make this
the most popular episode ever.
And that's what I wanted to
be with a number of comments.
So make sure you go comment. Uh, even
if you don't do the challenge. Well,
two other things that a lot of people
were asking about. Um, you know,
we didn't morning ritual,
but you guys asked me what do
I listen to while working out?
And I want to share some of my favorite
rap artists. Yeah, yeah, let's do it.
Your audience. So if they want to
get, they want to get pumped up.
I listened to a lot of like hardcore rap
and I get mixed tapes from datpiff.com.
How do you spell that? Dat
I f F. Dot Com. Hmm. Uh,
so I can't,
I'll shit send it off soon.
I'll send you my Spotify
playlist too for my workouts. Um,
but the guys I listened to a lot lately,
or like Travis Scott
and Wally's new album,
those two have been going really strong.
So if you're going to go work out and
go check out a Travis Scott and Wallay,
how do you spell Wallay?
A w. A. L. E. Y. La.
[inaudible].
Do you have any music you listened to
that you're embarrassed to admit you
listen to?
Mostly Emo, which is just
going to be like promise ring.
It's like kind of crying
and crying and stuff.
It's like, oh, I'm a little
bitch. I'm a little bitch.
Um, the, so that's number one.
I listened to a promise ring.
Um, a lot of their stuff is good.
The other thing Tim,
would,
you guys talked about alcohol and people
seem to like alcohol recommendations.
So, uh, if you're a Tequila Fan,
Casa Amigos is affordable and delicious.
Hmm.
And it's a George Clooney's Tequila and
it's phenomenal. I drink the Rep Rosado.
Uh, if you're a little more expensive,
which is the best for the price,
it's called Klossy has Zul and
that's $100 a bottle or 89,
and it's a porcelain white bottle. And
it's insane. If you'd like to, Kayla,
is that what you order when you
walk into a bar? You would just, uh,
it's normally $20 a shot,
so it depends on my mood.
I'm like $20 a shot. I have the
bottle at home. I could wait.
I'll just get a soda water.
Uh,
and or if a, if you're a whiskey
fan about coneys single malt,
anything by balconies,
it's a number one whiskey in the
world and it's a Texas whiskey.
Bocconi is B. A? L? C. O. N.
Yes. Yes sir. Awesome. All right,
well we will have some Tequila and Tacos
in Austin said, God, that sounds awesome.
Thank you so much for the time,
man.
I and everybody be sure to check out
all the notes and goodies and links and
recommendations, Spotify
playlist, et Cetera,
at four hour workweek.com forward slash.
Podcast
this episode is brought to you by
Athletic Greens. I get asked all the time,
if you could only use one supplement,
what would it be?
And my answer is
inevitably Athletic Greens,
it is your all in one
nutritional insurance.
I recommended it in the four hour
body did not get paid for that.
And I travel with it
to avoid getting sick.
I take it in the mornings to
ensure optimal performance.
It just covers all my bases.
If I can't get what I need through whole
food meals throughout the rest of the
day, and you can get 50 oh my
gosh, 50% off. Yes, 50% off.
If go to athleticgreens.com forward slash
Tim that's athleticgreens.com forward
slash Tim check it out.
It's tasty but more important it will
help you not screw up when you're doing
your nutritional plannings.
So for me it just covers the basis,
takes a load off my mind,
puts a lot in my body and check it out.
athleticgreens.com forward slash Tim
this episode is brought to you by 99
designs your one stop shop for
all things graphic design related.
I've used 99 designs for everything
from banner ads to book covers,
including sketches and mock ups
that led to the four hour body,
which later became number one New York
Times Number One Wall Street Journal and
the brainstorming.
A lot of it took place with designers
from around the world and here's how it
works. Whether you need a t
shirt, a business card, a website,
an APP thumbnail,
whatever it might be,
you submit that project and
designers from around the world.
We'll send you sketches
and mock ups and designs.
You choose your favorite and you have an
original that you love or you get your
money back.
It's that straightforward,
and many of you who are listening have
already used it and created some amazing
things that I'll be sharing it in
the future. But in the meantime,
if you want to see some of my
competitions, some of the book covers,
as well as get a free $99 upgrade,
go to 99 designs.com forward slash Tim,
that's 99 designs.com forward slash
Tim, Tim, Tim, Tim,
Tim, Tim, Tim,
Tim to Tim,
Tim to Tim.