Tim morgan with the show.
So you sent me a photograph on route or
I guess just after arriving here and uh,
you had a gian open and blood
running down your face. Yeah.
And where were you and what happened?
Oh,
I was not but four miles away from
here and we just had the IBJ GGF world
Jujitsu competition this weekend.
And so last week we are doing very sports,
Jujitsu training,
getting people ready for the tournament.
Um, I hate sports, Jujitsu. Um, I,
I think Sports Jujitsu is the abomination
to what martial arts is where like it
takes something that's really cool and
then they make it sporty, you know,
it's like, oh, let's give some
points to do some stupid things.
And then people that, you
know, the mutation, the evolve,
like how evolves it be it like it loses
its balls and I don't like things that
had balls and then no longer have balls.
Kind of like the emasculated man.
And that's what Jujitsu, it's almost
become like Jujitsu to me is like,
I'm going to get in mount or site control.
I'm a pick your face up,
I'm a smash it into this cement and then
I'm gonna push your eyes out and then
my bite your cheek off. That's Jujitsu
to me cause they, you know that,
that's the origin of it. The gentle
art. Yes. The gentle locked. Um,
and so today we did combat.
You did too.
So just to have a total paradigm shift
just to make people's heads explode
instead of like talking about, you know,
getting four points for back controller,
getting four points from mount or
getting a take down and get to,
it's like find a place that you can
hold somebody down and then hit them.
That's it.
I was watching a video in prep for this.
I think it was from sheepdog response.
She can, we can talk about in a second.
But you, you had control on someone.
You're right on top of them.
They're all turtled up on the ground and
you sort of wiped your fingers on their
eyes and you're like, okay.
Yeah, I just took your eyes up.
So something along the lines of like old
man Jiu Jitsu leads to all men time or
something like that. But there's just a
huge, such a huge Delta between the two.
I think you have to look at the
origin of what things are and then the
abomination of what they become. You know,
what you, you, you see as he's really,
the genesis of a martial art was they
had to learn how to protect themselves or
they didn't have weapons,
so they had to create something to fight
the dictators that we're killing them.
Or there were, um, the Samurai
that were really good with swords.
So then the ninjas came along to use
stealth because if you fight a Ninja head
on, you're going to die. So
let's create something new. Um,
and then over time that loses what it is,
you know,
like you have to be able to competitively
practice something to get good at it.
So then you can implement
sport and that would,
that's what kind of differentiates a lot
of these different Jujitsu. You're all,
a lot of these different martial arts, uh,
are just really tiny little rules. Like,
what's the difference between judo and
Jujitsu and Jujitsu and Greco Roman
wrestling and Greco Roman wrestling,
freestyle wrestling and
collegiate wrestling.
And so they're very small differences.
That's to make them a sport.
But if you take those rules away,
you get back to what the martial art was,
which was how to fight for your life
and not get murdered, you know? Yeah.
And I think,
I think it's also a misleading when
people think of the term martial art and
they turned it into some
type of performance art daily
body paint. And I'm like,
start putting my chest all over this
window. I'm like, I'm doing martial arts.
And it's actually when you go back to the
translation from say whether it's like
Woo Shu in Chinese or any of these
like boot Jujitsu in Japanese.
I used to live in Japan.
It's actually Marshall Technique
that then got translated to art.
So it's, it's lost. It's uh,
some of its impact through
a mistranslation in a sense.
And when I look at your career,
I saw you fight live and uh,
some early Strikeforce events
when I was living in San Jose.
And then became fascinated by your
military career, which we'll talk about.
It seems like you're very good at game
time decisions and acting under pressure.
So I want to talk about
training though for a second.
Could you talk about what you
say to yourself when you train?
And at least my understanding is it
begins with hurry up. Got Dot. Yeah.
Hurry up and fail.
Um,
funny enough as I send you that picture
of me dripping blood out of my face and
like I've blood already clotted in my
mouth, you know, and like, you know,
like he gets like stuck as it starts.
Congealing you know,
it turns into that gelatin up inside
of the kind of weird cavities inside of
your nose. Um, so if you like
cough, like chunk, start flying. Um,
as I was trying to explain
what it means to train,
so somebody came up to me at the end of
practice today and they're like, man,
I keep,
I'm getting tired or I keep quitting.
Or I had a couple of people that just
tapped from the position that I was in or
that they were in. And, uh,
so hurry up and fail is this mantra of
I want to get to the breaking point of
where I can't go on any longer and I
want to stay there because then the next
time I train that that wall has moved.
I mean ever so slightly, but it's,
it's moved.
So then the next time I can go in and I
can get to that point as far as hard and
as fast I can and I can stay there.
So the next time it's gonna
move and repeat until finally,
if you look back months later,
you've progressed so far today as,
as that Onnit academy and we did the
exact same workout we did two months ago,
same weight and what two months ago left
us on the ground like almost heaving
in,
in nauseous,
couldn't stand about to throw up today
we blew through effortlessly and Juan
Shane and I looked at each other like w w,
w what are,
what are we supposed to do right now
because we have an extra 16 minutes.
Cause we went through it so fast.
So in two months there was a such a clear
change of looking back and seeing like,
man, I got bigger, I got
faster, I got stronger,
and I ultimately got harder to kill.
So in Jujitsu it's the exact same.
You you rush to that breaking point.
And by no means do I want to say someone's
going to break me because if somebody
can break me, I welcome it. Like bring it.
I see I go all over the world to try
and find people that can do that.
So I can find that point where I'm going
to fail and then the next time I do it,
it's going to move.
You know?
So when you then fast
forward to an example of
an environment which the
stakes are a little higher.
So I'd love to talk about hydro.
Gracie started with an r for the
use of non Brazilians out there.
It's chatting with a mutual acquaintance.
Actually before we get
to mutual acquaintance,
I owe credit to the person
who made the introduction,
who is Donald [inaudible],
who I went to college with,
who used to be a super lightweight blue
belt that I could throw around because
of judo.
Now I can no longer throw
him around because he's a
black belt and co owner of a
school,
which is where you were training today.
What's the name of the school and
grace? Who am I to, I think it's, um,
it's where the Gracie is,
is it's in his lineage.
Show him coiler Gracie black belt.
But Donald Parks and Paula Brendao
are the ones that run the school.
And you know,
it is a shark tank of passionate people
that love family and martial arts.
And that's, uh, that's what that place is.
And for those of you don't
want staph infections.