Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
Now it does seem like I'm
a cybernetic organism,
living tissue over metal.
Hello Ladies and gentlemen and
welcome back to the Tim Ferriss show.
What you're about to hear is part two
of a multipart conversation with Rolf
Potts, author of vagabonding,
world traveler, extraordinary,
one of my favorite people.
If you didn't catch the first part,
you might want to do that before
venturing in, but if you don't mind,
your stories is more of a jigsaw puzzle.
Then by all means, keep on listening.
We bounced around a lot.
It's a very eclectic conversation,
so you could certainly listen
to these things out of order.
This episode is brought
to you by 99 designs,
so you can check out a bunch
of my competitions that I've
run@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash Tim and ex officio,
and if you want to see some of my favorite
pieces of travel gear as well as a
video on rapid ultra light packing,
then you can visit ex officio except for
shale ex-officio dot com forward slash
Tim and I almost forgot.
Of course there are a ton of resources
and links and websites and books
mentioned in this episode.
All of it can be found in
one place in the show notes,
so you just have to go to four hour
workweek.com all spelled out forward slash
podcast four hour workweek.com forward
slash podcast you can find the show notes
and resources and links for this episode
as well as every other episode like
those four Peter Teal,
Tony Robbins, Mike Shinoda,
you name it so you don't need to
scribble furiously unless you want to,
but four hour work week.com forward
slash podcast is where you want to go.
Without further ado and
further porky pig imitations,
please enjoy part two of the Tim
Ferriss show with Rolf Potts.
What are some of your favorite
books or commentaries on writing?
Uh, what is this funny? Because I, I
teach writing in various contexts. I,
but I teach at a summer writing
program in Paris and then I'd been, uh,
doing a class at Yale the last
couple of years. And, uh, so I,
I'd been reading a lot of craft books
recently and I realized that I had crossed
my carrying capacity that I needed to
stop freaking reading books about writing
craft. That like I had learned all
the metaphors there. There were,
um, and so, I mean there's some,
there's some journalistically minded
books like Roy Peters Clark has the
writer's tool kit, I think it's
called a, and Philip low paid,
uh,
has a book called a collection of essays
about the writer's craft called to show
and to tell, I think, uh, because
you know, the old adage goes, I show,
don't tell, but he's a believer in
the idea of strategic telling and in,
and he's a brilliant SAS team
stuff. Spell his last name, a.
L. O. P. A. T. E. Got it. Uh,
he sort of the modern father of,
of the Bella touristic essay,
the personal essay and he,
he actually came up from New York
to talk to my El students in, in,
in person earlier this
year. Um, and he's, he's,
he's kind of writing is very different
from what you and I do and he might sort
of frown on it to a
certain extent that he's,
he's really about that old going back
to Montana high art of the essay.
But he really has some
good advice on writing and,
and jumping back to screenplays.
The breakthrough for me in my writing
when I took my first vagabonding trip and
thought I was going to be the new Jack
Kerouac and tried to write about it and
realize that one chronological retelling
of what I did was not going to work
regardless of how beautiful
the sentences were.
A with stumbling into screenwriting,
uh,
20 years ago and learning
the importance of structure.
And so those classic screenwriting,
the tomes, like, you know,
the student field's screenplay
book or Robert McKee Story,
which is actually ridiculed in the
movie adaptation. Right, right, right.
I think Cox actually plays a
Robert McKee and that movie. Um,
I think that those are useful because
they go back to the very core of how we
communicate as humans,
how we tell stories.
And you can get tired of the three act,
a screenplay structure or
the needs of the audience,
but the audience is damn important. And
I'm a big believer, uh, and you know,
I'm not a believer in cultural hierarchy.
I think that the high literature
is important and good, but, um,
I mean I just wrote a Popey B
movie. Uh, I think that, uh,
that it's good to know how Raymond
Chandler stretchers his narratives in the
same sense that it's good to know how
Montaigne's structure is his narratives as
well. So I would say if people are
looking for writing craft books,
don't be afraid of any kind of book that
just talks about how to tell a story.
And I think that movies are great
metaphors for how to tell a story.
And there's crappy movies out there and
you know, adaptation. It's sort of a,
a lampoon of how we invariably
tell stories in movies.
But just because you learn a very basic
and formula, what formula way of say,
telling a cinematic story doesn't mean
that you have to use that every time.
It just means that you understand the
rules and then within the structure of
those rules, then you
can shine. As a writer.
I very much concur. I, uh,
I have an embarrassing confession,
which is,
has been agonizing over a
screenplay for several months now.
And, uh, I think partially
because I've loaded,
I've loaded the expectations,
uh,
and the burden so large on my shoulders,
it's,
it's roughly
an adaptation of the four hour
workweek and a lot of the backstory,
and it's intended to be comedic but
instill or at least convey a lot of a sort
of philosophical takeaways that hopefully
will, will spur viewers to do, uh,
interesting things in their lives and
make big changes, blah, blah, blah. Um,
but I've been agonizing over at the one
thing that did help me to at least get
started. And I have quite a lot
on paper. It was a save the cat.
I thought that was,
I don't know if you've seen this book,
but I found it so helpful
because I also read,
I took McKees story seminar
actually, uh, which was,
which was a quite an experience in
and of itself. Uh, I mean the, the uh,
the portrayal and adaptations
not far off the mark. Yeah.
Uh, but, uh, uh, uh, a fun
experience. Then the last,
uh,
I really found a save the cat to hold
your hand and walk you through at least
getting things down on paper by saying
are right by this page and this minute
you should have this type of element
and really allowing you at least get,
um, I wouldn't consider
what I have a first draft,
but a skeleton structure down that I can
use to fill in the blanks with all of
these random ideas that I have. Um,
totally agree. I think that, uh,
you know, become recently
interested in, in Joseph Campbell,
had a passing familiarity with Joseph
Campbell, watched a few documentaries. Um,
but the, the hero's
journey and, uh, the, the,
the Mono myth I find very interesting,
uh,
just as a way of getting started,
if you can sort of lay out these markers
for different stories that you're
considering telling. Um,
but, uh, you know, another,
another thought that I had,
which we don't have to go too deep
into unless you have thoughts on it,
but is that that beginner's
mind that you mentioned,
which is achievable through
travel or vagabonding, uh,
is also, I think one of the
primary benefits of, uh,
what you might consider therapeutic
use of psychedelics. Um, and that's,
uh,
it'd be part of the reason that people
often describe with the right set and
setting a psychedelic experiences. One of
the best experiences of their lives is,
I think the same reason that many people
would describe their first vagabonding
experience as one of the best
experiences of their lives.
And that's the present state
awareness and the beginner's mind. Uh,
and the appreciation that both of
those experiences tend to catalyze. Um,
but yeah,
well,
I touched on that a
little bit in vagabonding.
I sort of gently dissuade readers of the
necessity to say smoked marijuana when
they travel because reality is giving
you this present state awareness.
You know,
if you allow yourself to be bored or
if you allowed yourself to be lonely or
just, if you allow yourself to
have experiences by accident,
then suddenly you're having,
you're discovering in a vivid way that
don't need a artificial enhancement.
Definitely.
The,
one of the pieces of advice that
you gave, I'm pretty sure that, uh,
you gave this advice, I feel
free to, to, uh, to correct me,
but was getting lost the benefit of
getting lost and heading out of your,
your housing, whatever that might be.
And just walking off in one direction,
maybe with a map,
maybe without a map and just walking
and taking random turns for a few hours.
And I have found that so invaluable,
not only while traveling,
quite frankly, but even in San Francisco
and places where I've lived or live,
uh, exploring by foot. Um,
a terrain that you might otherwise for
the sake of convenience use taxis for,
for instance. And it's, it's been, uh,
I think a major priority
for me when I travel,
uh, not for business but
for this type of, uh,
experiential reflection
and exploration to,
to try to catalyze
discomfort whenever possible.
And uh, that doesn't mean a pebble
in the shoe, but, uh, to, uh,
for instance,
to purposefully go out of my way
to encounter language difficulties.
And one of my favorite ways to do this,
uh,
I'm typically a night owl like
I mentioned, but when I travel,
I try to switch it up. So I like to try
to wake up in some cases very early.
And I did this in Greece.
My first trip to Greece,
I was traveling with a close friend
and I started waking up really early.
I would just leave the blinds open
and I'll wake up as early as possible.
And my habit was to,
to go for a walk and just hand
wave and try to ask the locals.
These were on some very small islands
where I could find a cafe or a bakery.
And inevitably I would go
to these bakeries or coffee
shops and there would be a
small group of really old Greek
guys sitting outside debating what,
whatever old Greek men debate.
I would imagine it's probably complaining
about politicians and so on and so
forth. Much like every other
sort of gaggle of old men
early in the morning, uh,
everywhere else in the world. Um, and, uh,
and then I would just proceed to kind of
sit down and try to have a conversation
with these guys.
And it was always hilarious
and extremely fun.
And, uh, I ended up being basically
the court jester for these guys for,
for a period of time in the morning and
they always got a kick out of it. So, uh,
I think that, um, yeah, I
mean I said that, that, that,
that's seeking out of a mild discomfort
or uncomfortable situations I think is,
is really one of the main, um, values,
um, uh, and benefits that
I've taken away from,
from travel in the last,
certainly last 10 years or so.
Yeah.
This ties into a lot of ideas that are
really close to my heart and that I've
sort of embraced even since
I discovered vagabonding.
And it's fine that you're talking about
the old Greek guys because as a travel
writer,
one of my biggest strengths,
and it could be an accidental strength
as a person who wanders out with purpose
of getting lost,
is that whatever town I'm in,
inevitably the town Weirdo finds
me like the most eccentric by,
and if you read my second book,
Marco Polo didn't go there.
Like one third of the stories are about
me with a really strange dude in Lebanon
or Burma or someplace and it,
it's sort of connected to the idea of
the old Greek guy sitting there is that
they,
they see each other every morning.
But the chance for an American to stumble
in and sort of have a semi comical
exchange with them is the most exciting
thing that's happened to them all week.
You know, it's like their wives
have stopped listening to them,
their children have
stopped listening to them,
and so they can take you under their wing.
And just the things that you learned from
these guys is amazing. Um, and so that,
that's funny that, that's,
that's very relatable because I,
I feel like for whatever reason,
I don't know if I, if it's my,
my Midwestern tendency to,
to,
to talk a little bit less and maybe
listen a little bit more something that I
always meet these guys who just have
the weirdest, um, view of the world.
But you were talking about
walking out and getting lost in,
in vagabonding I talk
about how if in doubt,
just walk until your day
becomes interesting. And this,
and this is sort of tied into a concept
that I've discovered since then and as a
concept set that I teach in my Paris
classes because we're in the city where it
was invented and it's the idea of the
flinor. Are you familiar with the flinor?
Yep.
Only reason I'm in passing.
I want you to expand on it.
The only reason I know I recognize
that word is because, uh,
a friend of mine named Nassim Taleb
who's very famous for having written the
Black Swan sure. And a number of other
books describes himself that way.
Yeah. Uh, and um, so maybe you could, uh,
expand on that because I would
love to hear more. I quite frankly,
I didn't know much about the term.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a wonderful idea that they get in
a sense when I was walking until my day
became interesting, I was being a
full neuro before I knew what it was,
but it goes back to it's a bode layer
and in, in, in, in, uh, uh, you know,
over a hundred years ago in Paris,
uh,
and it's connected through
French ideas through the,
the situationist of the 1960s.
And the idea is that,
and flaring is something that
I use in travel, but it was,
it was really invented as a
concept in your own hometown.
And the idea is that you become so used
to and inured to your hometown that
you're not seeing it anymore.
That is to become a purely utilitarian
space in between point a and point B.
You've seen,
he's living that in your routine.
You're not really live in your routine.
You're just sort of,
and this is a paraphrase, but you're
sort of Zombie walking through your day.
And so being a full neuro,
if Linda is not someone who
walks through his own city in,
in a utilitarian or pragmatic way,
a full or someone who goes out
in search of experience, uh,
and there's someone,
um,
it's also tied into the
idea of psychogeography that
instead of walking through
a city,
uh,
with the idea that you're going to say
see tourist attractions or that you're
going to go to visit your friend
on the other side of town,
is that you're going to walk through the
town psycho geographically and you're
going to collect the color red and you're
just going to see how many forms the
color red con can take, are going to
look for every parking meter in town.
Where are you going to look for license
plates with the letter Q on them?
Or are you gonna look for
every immigrant restaurant?
And that is going to organize your day.
That psychogeography being a flaneur
is even less structured in that you're
just, you're just wandering. Um,
and it's a wonderful,
it was invented to be done
in your hometown to break
out of your own habits. Um,
it's a great thing.
It's a great way to break out of your
tourist habits where you go to a city and
there's 100,000 things you
can do at any given moment.
And you do the obvious thing which
is go to the tourist attractions and,
and I'm not going to knock that.
There's a reason why there
are tourist attractions, but
people talk about how, oh,
there's the beaten path.
Everything's been discovered.
Everything has already been done. And
it's like, actually that's not true.
You know, Paris is the most
tourist city in the world,
but you wonder for 10 minutes and
pretty soon you're going to be finding
something that's unique to itself.
Even along the Sean's,
all these [inaudible] even you know this
Shawn do mar with the Eiffel Tower is
if you just embrace the idea of the flinor
and walk until something catches your
eye and stay open to experience instead
of your plans, then you're going to,
um,
you're going to be living in a way where
you previously had only been consuming
those moments. And
Flinders. F, l A. N. E. U.
R that's right with a little hat
over the a got us caught my eye.
All the languages I've attempted,
although this one very halfheartedly,
I just cannot seem to get a grasp on the
French because I panic when it starts
to erase any of my Spanish or confused
anything and I'll sort of studied.
But Paris, what does it like
to teach in Paris and art?
What type of students are you teaching?
Oh, I teach it at the American Academy.
I'm actually the, the course director
and it's sort of become my baby.
I've been running this writing workshop
for the last 10 years on roofs on shock
in Paris and my students
are like age 18 to age 70.
And it's just, it's a large
number of people. I mean,
some people are there because of they
know vagabonding or my writing or they
know some of the other writers
who teach there. I have two,
one other nonfiction teacher and
two fiction teachers, so they can,
it's not just travel,
right.
And they can study poetry or a
screenwriting or short stories. Uh,
and so a lot of people have just,
it's,
it's sort of a bucket list thing for them
is that they want to come to Paris and
be a writer for a month.
And it's,
and it's one of the exciting parts
of the program is that it delivers,
you're there on the left bank,
you're in the University of district
of Paris and you're, you know, you're,
you're firing in all cylinders that
you're, you're writing all the time,
you're interacting with writers,
you're reading a lot and you're
being a flaneur is, and this,
it's funny that I discovered the
flinor in the context of Paris,
even though I'd already been doing it.
And I, even when I'm not teaching travel,
writing the flinor is such
a great creative exercise
for my students who might
be writing a poem rather
than a travel story. Um,
and evil and Wa talked about how a
city like Paris is sort of like a house
that's been wallpaper and over so much
that the only thing holding it up is the
wallpaper, is that there's no,
everybody's written about Paris.
And so you have to find a way
that is against expectations.
And the only way to find that is to
get out and wander and find your own
interests.
You know,
and I've had students who have
brought their skateboard and through
skateboarding and Paris had discovered
sides of it that nobody else is seeing.
And they've discovered, you know,
uh, the French skateboarding culture.
Um, and so yeah, my, my students are
just there for the romance of Paris.
And the great thing is that it's
a great, you know, July in Paris,
his romantic place to be, but it's
a great place to deliver. You know,
you can walk outside of a classroom and
in 90 seconds you're aware of victory.
Hugo lived when he was 11 years
old. Um, and, and so there's
this huge, I in, in, in,
in, in three minutes, you can go to a
place where Hemingway got shit faced,
you know, cause like, we're literally,
we're on the street, you know,
that he describes, you
know, in a movable feast.
And so I think that energy,
I mean,
it's like we could teach the same thing
in North Dakota and it would still be a
very professional, I'm very proud of
what our teachers are doing, but there's,
it's almost like a catalyst.
Paris puts people in a mental state
and almost like an athletic performance
thing is that people are in Paris and
they're not going to blow it, you know?
Right.
They don't live in Paris.
They're were going to come to Paris and
they're going to do something special.
Um,
and it creates this energy that,
that amazes me every year of people
just uncorking some really, um,
some really good stuff. And, and just
having some, going back to time, wealth,
just an experience that is, that is
very specific and very, very Parisian,
but very unique to
themselves. So, uh, I've,
I've really loved my
association with that city.
Sounds amazing.
How many students are in the course?
It varies from year to year. Um,
we've been averaging about 24. Uh,
it's capped at 32.
Uh,
and so probably anywhere
from 18 to 32 students.
God, I feel like I should take the
course. It sounds amazing. I, uh,
I fantasized a fairly frequently about,
uh,
going to graduate school or a attempting
something like an Mfa for creative
writing because I really haven't ever
explored to fiction outside of elementary
school doing some exercises in elementary
school. Um, what do you find of,
of the students who take this
course, uh, what are the care,
what are the shared characteristics of
the people who get the most out of it?
Then I'm going to leave
that open ended on purpose.
I think it's, it's an earnest desire, um,
to do their best combined with sort of a,
a humility,
almost a beginner's mind, tight
humility towards writing. Um,
and sometimes I can get it very young
and brilliant college students, um,
who will come in sort of a leg above
maybe sort of a mid career professional,
but because the college student is,
has not quite cultivated, it's, it's,
it's a strange thing to think,
but there's this sort of confidence and
self assuredness that college students
have that like a mid career professional
doesn't have and that can get in the
way of the beginner's mind.
And so that sort of know
it all is a wrong word,
but like the overconfidence of a,
of a brilliant college student
might impede his or her, uh,
advancement where like someone who's
35 or 45 and is just there to soak in
everything and work as
hard as they can. Um, I,
I think it's the person going
back to the beginner's mind,
it's the person who is willing to embrace
the beginner's mind and work hard and
synthesize the creative aspect with the
parts of Paris that you can't overlook.
You can't just come to Paris and sitting
in your room and write all the time,
any more than j j p Morgan should have
been reading TeleTech's is the whole time
he was in Egypt.
That that interactive going out and
having fun and having a bottle of wine by
the Sen and Flynn during,
through the city and discovering things
by accident is going to feed what's
happening when you're alone in your room.
And so I think it's the students
who can find that balance. Um, and,
and the students,
I think to a big extent,
it's the students who have been almost
like vagabonding who'd been saving their
money and this, this
means something, you know,
they're not just gathering from their
limitless pool of resources, uh,
to pay for their month in Paris, but
they have earned this with their sweat.
It's like a chapter in vagabonding and
talk about how the work you do makes your
travels meaningful.
I think it's the people who come in
and know the value of what they have in
Paris,
that this,
this one month is a special time that
can catalyze them into a new creative
state.
Those are the people who are gonna who
are going to get things delivered for
them. And, and you mentioned MFAs.
I, I got a mid career MFA. Um,
and I don't know, there's, there's
some advantages of that sort of thing,
but I think there's an extent
to which that creatively,
a one month program like this can
cover a lot of those MFA basis without
compromising two years of your life.
Right, right. Agreed. I mean, I'd
love to hear your thoughts. I mean,
my basic feeling is that,
uh, the benefits, uh,
would be, and I mean, it's, it's
maybe sounds ridiculous that, uh,
I feel very isolated writing a lot
of the time and, uh, it's, it's,
it's sort of odd that I'm,
you know,
the access to more people than
I've ever had access to in my life.
Yet I spend a lot of my time
feeling quite isolated and lonely.
And, uh, there's, and I don't know
many writers in San Francisco, I just,
that's not in my social sphere.
Uh, which maybe is a good thing.
Maybe it's a bad thing,
but the idea of being any group of
people going through the same experience,
um,
having that sort of
shared study experience,
I'm sure with some degree of
commiseration every once in a while with a
structure that actually facilitates
experimenting with new types of writing is
very appealing to me. So
maybe the month, maybe that's,
maybe that's a great solution as
opposed to two years, like you said,
which I don't,
I don't think I could,
I think that will remain
a fantasy in my hand.
I think they both, they're
both good for that social, um,
that community of writers situation.
I'm just like this,
the friend that I'm swapping houses
with w who lives in Brooklyn is a Grad
school friend and I just, you
know, in my late thirties,
I was able to make very,
very dear friends through my two years
of Grad school where there's an extent to
which at that that like
MFA programs aren't really
designed for 38 year olds who
are already successful as writers.
Um, yeah. And that, and then that, um,
that a month program,
I mean obviously I have a vested
interest in my own one month program,
but a one month program can deliver both
the community and a more concentrated
spark of uh, of inspiration, uh,
without having to go through a two
year cycle that isn't necessarily um,
tailored to someone in your situation.
One thing a two year program can give
you is his structure, like deadlines,
monthly deadlines.
But if you've already written a book,
I think there's an extension to witch
dyke that exposure to poetry or fiction or
screenwriting and just 30 other people
who are gung Ho and are locked in on that
similar creative openness that that one
month catalyst can be more youthful,
useful in both senses then then a more
extended no certificate program the last
two years.
You know, it's, I, I am happy
that you misspoke for a second,
said useful because in a way I think
it's almost appropriate because like you
said,
the charge of a group
in Paris recognizing,
uh, for most of them that it's a very
unique opportunity that required a lot of
sacrifices to make happen would charge
it with a certain useful energy,
which I'm trying to reinfuse
into a lot of what I do because,
uh, and I don't think this
is purely a function of age.
Maybe it's exposure to just the doom
and gloom of just general Internet
bullshit. Uh, but, uh,
I'm trying to beat back my own cynicism
with a club and really try to prevent
myself from becoming apathetic. That's
a very strong word. But there's just,
there's a lot of instability and,
and craziness in the world if you go
looking for it or if you were spending a
lot of time, uh, on
social media for instance,
and I want to combat that with,
uh,
a pipe positive and charge
you youthful energy. Uh,
so it's very interesting.
Well, I think that that goes
back to the idea of, uh,
of success versus lack
of six test and that, um,
as certain kinds of successes,
more meaningful when you're
30 than when you're 40,
because you have a different relationship
to that success after you've been
steeped in for awhile.
So finding the screenplay that you
can bang your head up against or,
or embracing poetry or any or,
you know,
Samba dancing or, or anything else
with that, didn't, that vulnerability,
that beginner's mind, uh, that
youthfulness. I think that, that,
that is so useful to use the
right word this time, uh, in,
in rejuvenating your
relationship with yourself.
Just like when I started out as a travel
writer and there were certain by lines
that were really important to
me that aren't now, you know,
and by by lines you mean
publications and credits?
Yeah, yeah. I'm going to write
for the San Francisco Chronicle.
I'm going to write for national
geographic traveler, good publications.
They do good work. But I realized that
once you took away the, the, the, um,
the thrill of that initial success of
having a major publication acknowledged
the quality of your work, then
the h shifted, you know, what,
what I was doing with the content, uh, I,
I guess transformed a
little bit. And so, um,
so now I'm writing a screenplay with,
with zombies in it.
Not that I'm going to become
a a B movie screenwriter now,
but it brings me joy,
you know,
sort of that childlike joy in the creative
process that doesn't exist anymore
with what I've already become
professionally successful at. Right.
And so I think you get into that pattern
and it sounds like you're experimenting
with this already,
um,
that you become successful in a certain
manner of, of creative expression.
And, and a, and a certain
matter of expertise. Um,
and then I think a way to keep yourself
fresh is to try activities that you
might fail at. And a, I think, right,
if you aren't failing at something
a fairly substantial once a year,
then you're not pushing yourself enough.
And of course travel is a great
venue for inviting failure and, um,
you know, mild humiliation. Uh,
but, but, but sure. I, you know,
I think,
I think it's great that you're,
that you're bashing your head against a
screen play that might not work out. Um,
10 years ago or maybe eight years ago,
I sort of had my vagabonding screenplay
where I was sort of expressing
philosophical ideas of,
of a,
a vagabonding through a coming of age
story and it didn't quite work. You know,
maybe I'll go back to it,
but it was a good thing to have
tried and not quite succeeded at.
And I'm not saying that that's where,
where your screenplay is going,
but that process I think is important
for keeping yourself sharp and keeping a
perspective,
a mid certain jadedness
to other kinds of success.
Definitely. Uh, the,
the, the, the adjective,
well, the adjective successful
has come up a couple of times.
When you think of the word successful,
who's the first person
who comes to mind and why?
Oh Man. I don't know if, I don't know
if a person comes to mind. I, you know,
I think when I was 28,
I may have a,
I may have been able to name like a travel
writer that I wanted to be like Pico
Iyer or Tim Cahill. Um, and I
think the reason that a person,
when you asked that question at first,
it didn't pop into my head because I have
that different relationship to success.
You know, that the hunger
to be like Pico or Tim, um,
played itself out in
a very integrated way.
It became a part of the energy
that made me a travel writer. Uh,
and so now I don't think,
you know, it's funny, I,
um, I feel like our backgrounds are
fairly similar. I'm from Wichita, Kansas.
You're from springs, right? That's
right. But Bullseye Middleclass families,
it feels like that's right.
And you had your Ivy League [inaudible]
league experience right out of high
school.
And I didn't it like I did my,
I taught at Penn and then Yale for a
couple of years really recently. Um,
and that became a part of me felt like
I needed to measure myself against that
standard and it was a great experience.
Um,
but now that has also been
folded into my idea of success.
And so I think this might
be a little bit tied into
talking about the creative process
and sometimes it can be difficult.
That what my notions of success,
how are,
are slightly different and
it has a different energy.
So I'm not thinking about
someone I want to be necessarily,
but it's back into that.
I think it's more about appreciation.
Like my role models and I,
I'm still blanking on who I might
point out are not achievement people,
but appreciation people,
you know,
people who have found the success and are
synthesizing it in sort of a good life
kind of way.
Definitely.
I think this is just somebody who can't,
who comes to mind? Uh, I've, I've asked
this question of a lot of folks and, uh,
more, uh, more than a few times,
Steve jobs comes up, but he's,
he's actually not a in many ways,
um,
exemplary, uh, based on
what you just described.
And I think Steve Wozniaks
cofounder very much is, uh, I've,
I've met was on a number of occasions
and I even gave him a little tango class
prior his dancing with the
stars experiment. And, uh,
he released savers and
loves life and has built a,
as built a life for himself where he is
able to enjoy or experience the joy of
discovery and, uh, is a
genuinely happy human being.
Um,
and this is going to sound funny,
but despite all of his material success,
uh, because I think that, uh, the,
the material success,
not to say that that's a bad thing,
I think that it enables more than it
disables, but, uh, it can become a,
it can make people very defensive,
uh,
where they spend the vast majority of
their time managing the protection and
growth of their assets as opposed to the
growth in other areas of their lives.
And I've, I've certainly, I've been,
I don't have hundreds of millions
dollars or anything like that,
but I've been very fortunate to have
enough success with publishing and
elsewhere that, uh, I don't
have to worry about where the,
the next month's rent is coming
from. Um, but I've, I've,
I've witnessed that in myself and
I think that there's a possibility,
and maybe this isn't true,
but I'd be curious based on
your observations, if you,
if you've noticed this
in your coming from, uh,
a very middle class background
where there were many,
many times when money was tight in
the family and we weren't able to take
certain trips or,
uh,
get certain birthday presents or
whatever it might be a go out to certain
restaurants that, uh, my,
my inclination is to be very,
um,
to focus on the, the, the defense
and protection of assets more per,
more than perhaps those people I met,
for instance at Princeton who grew up
as Bluebloods where money is a known
quantity. It's, it's a,
it's an element that for multiple
generations, the family is,
it has become comfortable with,
um, so, uh, unless you're,
if that's worth exploring, but, uh, that,
that's something that I try to be very
cautious or aware of because I think it's
a, it's a, it's a terrible
inclination that I have.
Wait, will, you touched on
a couple of things, a couple
of new concepts I've come,
I've sort of wrestled with very recently
and it actually made me realize who my,
who my role models are going to be
to your earlier question, but yeah,
get light teaching at Yale for example,
which is such a good institution.
You know,
I came into into Yale in my early forties
and my excitement at being at this
institution after all these years,
you know,
after being a person when I was 17 at the,
at the college fair in Wichita, Kansas,
I remember looking at the Yale table
and feeling sorry for the guy who had to
come to Kansas and not even going there,
you know,
just because I came from
a family that, that, um,
that you don't spend money on an
ivy league education. There's,
there's more practical ways to get your
IB education if it wasn't an expectation.
But me sitting as a
teacher in a class at Yale,
this is very recently who's excited
about being at this institution in a way
that the 18 year old student isn't,
you know,
the 18 year old student is just relieved
to be there because they've been
expected to be there for years and it's
a part of their socioeconomic status.
Um, and they, they didn't have to go to
their safety school sort of situation.
Right.
And so in a way that's sort of a,
a gift of middle class in
this is that you're not,
you don't have those expectations.
Nobody's going to be disappointed. Sure.
You don't end up at Yale and
then you can actually have this,
this beginner's mind,
that experience of being a 42 year old
who over the moon about being a Yale
professor all of a sudden.
Um,
and actually the other thing you
asked about when you think of success,
who do you think about?
Actually I've been really fascinated
just like in the last couple of months of
the stories of Dave
Chapelle and John Hughes,
Dave Chappelle being the comedian who had
turned away 15 $50 million and society
sort of said, oh, what's wrong
with him? And then John Hughes,
who in the 1980s made all of the best
team movies ever and then just sort of
disappeared to become a quiet person.
And did he make home alone or am I
making that up? He made home alone.
He made all of those
brat pack teen movies.
He made hump alone or did
he also make that one?
He may have been involved as a screen,
I might be making that up.
But he had involvement with movies through
the 90s and then just sort of stopped
doing that altogether. Um,
in the two thousands. And we,
and I'm still in the
process of researching this
personality type because I'm
really interested in the relationship
that these guys have to success.
And they were both judges sort of harshly.
And I think that these are guys who are
really trying to wrestle with the idea
of who they were versus who their success
dictated they were supposed to be.
Right.
And so Dave Chappelle,
we live in a society where you have
to be insane to turn down $50 million.
People were questioning Dave
Chappelle's mental health.
That was a very prominent feature
of the whole discussion. Yeah.
Whether or not he had gone literally
insane when in fact it could have been.
And again,
I'm still researching these guys.
That could have been a
radically sane thing to do. Um,
a friend of mine,
Rachel cods Egon side who's a,
who's a great up and coming journalists,
wrote a piece,
a profile of him for the believer where
she went to his hometown and yellow
springs and talk to his mom,
yellow springs, Ohio. Uh,
talked to his mom who is a professor and
actually ran into them in a coffee shop
but sort of wanted to respect
his privacy sort of thing. Right.
And Dave Chappelle is a fit happy
guy living on a farm in Ohio,
hanging out with his friends and it feels,
again, I need to do some more research,
but it feels like he's a guy who
decided what would make him happy and he
realized that $50 million and
getting locked into a show wouldn't.
And similarly,
John Hughes is a beloved guy.
And then these are two examples there.
There's other examples
that one could throw in,
but he was beloved for his team movies.
But I think there came a point at which,
especially by people of my generation,
there came a point at which that he didn't
want to be beholden to the breakfast
club and 16 candles anymore.
That he, he's a family man and a,
and a guy who was passionate about
his creativity and I think he chose,
um,
being happy in a city that he loved
Chicago with family members that he loved
over making, you know, the breakfast club
three and making another $10 million.
Uh,
and so while I wouldn't say while these
guys didn't pop into my head as examples
of success,
there are guys that have sort of captured
my attention because I think the,
the sort of public perception of,
Oh,
here are these guys who have disappeared
with these two examples there.
These guys aren't disappeared
there. They're not people
who disappeared, but they,
they return, they realized
that they had, they had the,
the structure in place to live the lives
they wanted to live and they quietly
have been doing that.
I love it. It makes me want to
immediately start researching.
But if you're on, if you're
on the job than a, and I,
given that I enjoy your writing so much,
I'll probably just wait. Well actually
it's funny but I'm not researching
it from a writing point of view.
So go ahead and take it. It's just like
from an intellectual point of view,
you know, there were at all
points that Heraclitus said,
you never step into the river,
the same river twice because it's a
different river and your different men,
and that's probably not a direct quote,
but you're always trying to make sense of,
of how you're living and
how other people are living.
And suddenly this is just
a random intellectual thing
that I probably wouldn't
have thought about in the context
of success until you brought it up.
And here's two guys that I think, you
know, we're crazy like foxes. You know,
that that said,
no thanks American idea of success.
We're going to take real success.
We're going to take time, wealth,
and live in ways that make us
happy instead of trying to, to, um,
live up to artificial ideas of success.
So I wouldn't actually, you can have it,
Tim, and I want to read this. I want
to read this book or article on the,
uh, on success management, you
know, management and I like it.
It feels like an important topic.
Yeah,
yeah, I agree. Especially
because it's such a,
it's such a nebulous term that
I think there's a, there's a
lot of insidious potential, uh,
for such a heralded,
pressured,
nebulous term in particular.
Uh, interesting. All right. I'm,
I'm going to assure that seed will,
we'll just sit in my head and not go away.
So I might have to scratch that itch.
Well, I mean, if, I mean, if
so many ways of looking at, at,
at prospective in success,
but in dental terms,
we're all more successful then the kings
of Europe 500 years ago, you know? Right.
So there's that. The keeping up
with the Joneses idea of success,
you know, that comparing yourself to
other people, idea of success, um,
is useful to an extent,
but it's also toxic.
And so it's a part of this
idea of success management,
which is a phrase I only just now said,
but it feels like it's the other half.
There's a million books about
how to become successful,
but perhaps there's not.
Perhaps the idea of how to
manage one success in a,
in an enrichening and in life enhancing
way is something that more thought needs
to be, uh, you know, addressed that topic.
Definitely. Uh, well this, this is a,
this has been a fantastic conversation.
I have just a few more
questions I'd love to ask.
I want to be respectful of your
time, but, um, I think, uh, I'm, I'm,
I am very hopeful
full that people will
enjoy this and they should
definitely, um, let us know if they,
if they want to round two at some point
if you're up for it because this has
been a blast. Uh, but the,
the, uh, the questions I have.
So there are a couple of rapid fire
questions. Uh, you walk into a bar,
what do you order from the
bartender? What's, what are your,
your drinks of choice or drink of choice?
I have turned into a,
into a whiskey guy and I'm,
I'm actually giving myself a
little vacation from whiskey
just because almost like with internet
connectivity and became too easy to like
have a nightcap that compromise my
morning productivity and you know,
being in the middle class
guy, I am, you know,
I love Woodford reserve and I'm talking
about the bourbon, any types of whiskey,
but Evan Williams black label,
it makes me happy.
Um, but I'm taking a little vacation from
it just because it became my, you know,
my booze version of the Internet where
it just became unnecessary for me to be
having, you know, another Evan
Williams and you know, I like,
I like this single malts
and stuff like that too.
But as far as something like I needed
a freedom app for my bottle of Evelyn
just duct tape over the mountains.
Right, exactly. Exactly.
Like an anti booze pacifier.
I should sell one of those.
And it's not,
it's not alcoholism because I've been on
my whiskey fast for about two weeks now
and I never think about it. I just
needed to get my monkey brain off of,
off of my,
my whiskey night cap because it was
delightful and unnecessary and completely
counter to my own creative life.
You know, there's a very lazy,
it was like checking my feast Facebook
feed for the third time in 20 minutes,
you know.
Anyway,
eventually I will return to whiskey
with pleasure, but I'm on a,
I'm on a little mini retirement
from whiskey.
I, uh, I understand. I just took a,
took a month off of booze
entirely for similar reasons. Uh,
do you have a favorite
documentary or documentaries?
What into my head is,
is Verner Hertzog grizzly man.
Oh boy. Have you seen this? I've,
I've, no, I've heard of this.
This is the one with the,
uh,
I think part of the reason I may have
avoided it with, with a horrific, uh,
epilogue if I'm not mistaken, is
this, is this the same movie that, uh,
um, uh, the epilogue,
well, let me, let me rephrase that.
Our, our people eaten by bears.
It's eccentric fellow named Timothy
Treadwell who spends 13 summers,
I believe it's 13 summers in Alaska
with grizzly bears. And the 13th summer,
he's actually eaten by a grizzly bear.
And it's something,
this is not a spoiler because you
know that from the end of the movie.
And one reason I like it is that it's
such an interesting experiment in story
telling.
And I,
and I use as an example with my students
about how you infuse narratives with
mystery,
with the idea that you're going to get
certain information later on in the
narrative.
And he hurts all,
gives us the answer to the mystery
almost immediately, which is the what,
what happens?
Timothy Treadwell gets eaten by a bear,
but then it's like the how it gets
answered, but then it's the WHO,
it turns into this,
who the hell is this guy who had hang
out for Grizzlies for 13 summers? And,
and I'm not saying it's not my
favorite or it's not one of my favorite
documentaries from the standpoint of like
sort of life changing model for how I
want to live or even how I want to make
a documentary. But it's such a brilliant
use of narrative. Verner
Herzog is just so good. Um,
literally yesterday I was looking at
like these spoofs of like Verner Herzog,
reading, curious George, which it's
just, it just killed me. It just,
it was so funny if you've seen,
if you've seen grizzly man with his
sort of Germanic voiceover here,
this spoof of him leading Kuli
as George was Achilleas monkey.
So it's so uncanny. Anyway, that
that's sort of an aside, is that he's,
he's another one of these role models
of someone who is so brilliant.
He is sort of an replicatable.
He brilliant in the way he uses narrative.
And it's such a subtle and simple and
brilliant way of telling the story of
Timothy Treadwell, you mostly through
Tim Treadwell's own video, um,
that it's just,
it's just a fantastic documentary and
it doesn't really tie into lifestyle
design,
but as far as using it as a model for
using found footage and existing resources
for telling a really, really, um,
profound story about human nature and
the people who sort of go against human
nature and nature itself and
the assumptions of nature,
it's just fantastic. And,
um, yeah, a guy gets
eaten by a bear, but, um,
it's less macabre than you might think.
Uh, this is a random one, but, uh, we,
we mentioned adaptation earlier. If, uh,
if nick cage came to your house
for dinner, what would you them?
Oh God.
Well I'd probably,
I'd probably go to all these and
find some cheese brought worsts um,
just because that's sort of how I roll,
you know,
it will be the same if you showed up at
my doorstep in any number of friends or
celebrities. Um, that,
that's an interesting guy.
And this is another complete aside,
but I'm a little bit obsessed
with the movie con air.
That requires some elaboration.
Okay.
Because I saw it on a bus
in Syria and that movie,
like if you took every,
if a computer took every action movie
cliche and turned it into an algorithm and
spit out a movie, it would
be con air, you know,
with a cast full of Indy
actors. I mean, Steve,
who sent me is in that movie and uh,
John Malcovich isn't that movie,
but I watched it on a bus full of Syrians.
And they didn't have any of the
snarky, self-aware, judgmental,
hipper than now attitude towards it.
And they cheered at the end and then
they cheered in the middle and as an,
and that became a part of my
emotional experience of Syria, which,
and this has been 14 years ago,
which is this amazing place.
And it's become this
heartbreaking place because, um,
I know that the people I met there
and who were so wonderful are,
are living hard lives now.
Um,
and so I want to write an essay about
this at some point about my emotional
relationship to con air that is somehow
tied into the experience of travel along
with like the helplessness of
seeing what's going on in, in Syria.
And sorry for this to take a serious turn,
but it's one of those limitations
of travel, you know, for all of the,
of the beauty of humanity
that I experienced in Syria,
which was such a wonderful place years
and years ago that I have this dumb nick
cage movie tie it in to my emotional
experience of the Syrian people. Oh, so
you should absolutely right
that I think that'd be a,
I think that'd be a fascinating piece,
Roger that,
uh, so to cheese bratwurst,
that's it. Come on over.
It's signed me up. Uh, what,
what is the,
uh,
the most gifted or the few
most gifted books in your life?
Meaning aside from the books that
you've written and of course, uh hmm.
People who followed me for a while know
that I've given away hundreds if not
thousands of copies of AGB OnDeck.
But, uh, and thank you for that.
Of course. Yeah, of course. I think
it's, I view it as, as a, as a must read.
Of course. You know that, uh,
aside from your own books,
what books have you gifted
to other people the most?
Well, you could probably guess. Um, Walt
Whitman's leaves of grass. Definitely.
And, and, and this is,
this was especially a young
adults to mid thirties gift,
and this is going to sound funny,
but I,
I probably gave it to every woman
I dated for like six to 10 years.
Not because I was some sort
of jaded pickup artists,
but because I felt it was
so true to my own, you know,
you know,
joyous attitude towards how I wanted
life to be and just sort of the openness
like this 19th century gay dude capturing
these ROVs straight guy emotions
towards, you know, the joy of life.
And so I apologize if I sound
data to my ex girlfriends,
but there's a point at which that
I felt so connected to that book,
you know, that I would give it to people
I was falling in love with, you know. Um,
and so that continues to be a book that,
especially for,
for young people who are just sort of
coming into wrestling with what's in store
with them for life,
leaves a rass this,
this great reminder that joy and,
and openness to experience and
inclusivity is something that is going to,
is going to be that catalyst that makes
every, every experience more exciting.
I love it.
Yeah. Any, any others? What do you, what
have you been gifting to your, uh, your,
your girlfriends for the last while?
Let me think. You know, I've, I have
so many writer friends now, um, that I,
I,
um,
like I have really good friends from my
Grad school program who are poets and
like you're,
you have a poetry bestseller if you
hell out to sell 150 books of poetry.
Right? Uh, and so I've been
buying a lot of poetry, uh,
by my friends or even just by poets I
respect simply because that one purchase
and handoff is meaningful to them in a
way that other people might not be. Right.
And this is something
we haven't touched on,
but poetry is useful for non poets
in the way that it uses language.
You know,
there's nothing more pure and distilled
in a way that every single word operates
in poetry. And so my friend Eli
Burrell just came out with a book I'd,
I've been buying that for friends. My
friend Heather, Heather Dobbins comes,
had a book that came out with a
poetry and I think poetry is a good,
and hopefully my friends who are
receiving these books or reading them,
it's just a good reminder about how
important language is and how much you can
do, um, on a single
page with language. Um,
and so that would be, I guess
leaves. We were asked as poetry too.
So somehow I'm this po prose writer who's
besotted with poetry for the last 20
years. Um, that, that's
a big thing too. Um,
definitely I need to,
I need to read more poetry.
I've never been much of a consumer of
poetry. Partially I think because I, uh,
I dealt with a lot of sort of holier
than now liberal arts majors and at
Princeton who seemed to
imply that if I understood,
if I, if I insisted on understanding
the poetry, that it was,
uh,
above me that I was lacking
the intellect or somehow if,
if I couldn't appreciate what I considered
to be nonsensical,
right.
Rose that I did just, I just
didn't get it. Uh, and, uh,
that I think gave me a bit of an
allergy to poetry that I should probably
revisit. Uh, besides, uh, Walt
Whitman. Any, any other poets that, uh,
that you would recommend to
the intrepid reader of poetry?
Well,
I'm actually a guy who speaks most every
summer in Paris is a guy named Stuart
does shell.
How do you spell his last name?
D.
I. S. S. I. S. C. H. E. L. L.
It's very dude like poetry. Um,
I mean it's like a country song about
the pickup and the dog or what are we
talking about it?
I mean, he, he's from Jersey.
He's from Atlantic city. Okay. Um,
and it's not dude like in
Bro, like poetry, but it's
just like if, if you're, uh,
you know, like a, a straight male who's
encountered bigger questions in life.
There's something very relatable about it.
Got It.
Penguin Po publishes him also a guy who
was born in Kansas and he was sort of
out there and his poetry is really
infused with a lot of pop culture is,
is Michael Robbins who wrote up a
poetry book called Alien vs. Predator.
That's just sort of a trip
to read. In fact. Yeah. Um,
it's a fun book to just read by and
read out loud to your friends because
there's so much.
He's like using this,
these strange meters and rhymes
with poems about axl rose,
you know, rhyming, axl rose with
something else. Really interesting guy.
He's also published by Penguin.
So those are a couple of dude poets that
I think would be accessible or at least
appealing to people who aren't
usually vested in poetry. Um,
Billy Collins being another example.
These are all men. Actually.
There's a woman named
aiming at Duke who Motl. Um,
in easy, h, u k. You,
m. A, t. I, T. I l, great woman.
I've spoken with her at a,
at a writing and environment
con conference and very
accessible and beautiful
poetry. Um, one recommend mandation.
I might have people for people
who are interested in poetry,
which I would imagine
for your and my audience,
both is maybe not a huge priority of
people who will read our books. Right? Um,
just get an, get an edition
of best American poetry any,
anytime in the last 20 years.
And read through the palms and
the ones that you don't like,
forget about them and the
ones that are appealing,
find other poems by those authors.
Um,
and that's how I've found some
of some of my favorite poets.
That's great advice.
And I,
I just wanted to raise also one other
poet and I've, I've, and this is,
this is one of the rare poets
you broke through my PR,
probably unfounded bias against poetry.
Uh,
Naomi Shihab Nye, uh, a s, h, I h a,
B and y e two words.
Um,
her father is a Palestinian
refugee and just a really enjoyed,
have enjoyed her poetry and kept it quiet.
This is so stupid,
but it just goes to show how early
bruising can affect how you behave as a
supposedly mature adult. Uh, right. Uh, I,
I enjoy her poetry
because I understand it.
It's beautifully written, but
I, I get it, there's sort of a,
a message being conveyed or a point or
a description of something concrete.
And, uh, I suppose I was based on the, uh,
sort of condescending,
uh,
lectures that I would get from people
at Princeton who were probably very
similar to the guy in the bar in
goodwill hunting, who's reciting, uh,
you know, right. Plagiarized classics. Uh,
just like imagine that
dickhead and multiply it by a
couple of hundred people up.
I guess I've never really talked
about it. But Naomi, she have NY, uh,
is a poet that I've, I've come to
really appreciate. Uh, so I need to,
I need to read more poetry.
I'm glad that you were sort of
lighting of lighting a fire for that
and those poets are out there. A major
Jackson is another guy edited, cursing me,
African American guy from Philly, um,
who actually taught at the MFA program.
I didn't study poetry, but he was
there. Great Guy. Um, and, and you know,
for every completely abstract poem that's
playing with language in a way that is
almost meant to be pretentious,
you have Porphyria,
it's very soulful and accessible
and great. Um, and uh,
people might bag, well people
deeply voice, vested in poetry.
My bag on the accessible stuff, but
there's a lot of it out there and again,
the best American series
or other anthologies might
be a good way to find it.
Or even just going to poetry daily and
ignoring the poems that seem completely
inaccessible and following up on
poems that seemed to really be, um,
delivering something relatable. Donald
Hall is another great one. He's, he's in,
he's pushing 90 now, but he's a wonderful,
wonderful poet based up in New England.
Well, Ralph, I want people to, uh,
to continue exploring your thoughts.
How can they,
what is the best way for them to, to
learn more about you, find you online,
et cetera.
Uh, my author website is
[inaudible] Dot Com uh,
that links to all aspects of my travel
writing career and also my career as a
journalist and an essayist if they want
to know more about vagabonding hey,
they can buy the book. They can also
go to vagabonding.net which I can,
we should probably remind them,
has resources that go in tandem with
the vagabonding audio book that you
published and are also more updated
than the print book that came out, uh,
11 years ago. So vagabonding.net/resources
will allow you to,
to follow up in a lot of the stuff
that we've talked about today,
a lot of these websites like
boots and all. And then finally,
anyone interested in my Paris a course
which takes place in the month of July
and every summer is Paris
writing workshop.com, um,
which is also linked from, uh, my author
websites with Paris writing workshop.com.
We'll give you all the basics about that.
And Twitter is at Rolf Potts.
So a many ways to find me.
And that is Ralph with an f,
uh,
for those people who might be wondering
what the spelling is with an o and an
app with an o and an f in an R and
a couple of tees as well. Yeah.
So Rolf Potts and a few folks who,
uh,
are interested in the,
the book club.
So I do have a book club and vagabonding
was the very first book I used to
launch that book club.
And a,
you can hear a sample of the audio
book and a and check it out@audible.com
forward slash Tim's books. So
you can, you can, you can get a,
get a scope on some of the books that have
had a huge impact on my life and I'll,
I'll thank you once again are off because
vagabonding certainly hit me at a very
important time in my life where I could
have gone many different directions and
I feel like it steered me in
a very positive direction.
And if I hadn't read
vagabonding quite frankly,
I don't know if the four hour workweek
ever would have been written. So, uh,
so thank you once again for,
uh,
for having that impact on me and many,
many thousands of other people as well.
Well, I appreciate it that and I
appreciate you championing the book too,
that I've really,
it's really gotten to people who
may not have found me otherwise.
So it's a great synergy happening there
for sure. And I will continue
to champion it. So Raul,
thank you so much for the time and uh, I
would love to continue this sometime, uh,
when you're, when you're
available, uh, and uh, and uh,
not taking a sabbatical from,
from electronics. Uh, and uh, until next
time. Thanks so much for taking the time.
All right, thanks for having me,
Tim. Talk soon. Thanks all. Bye Bye.
Thank you for supporting the
sponsors of this show. 99 designs,
which is your one stop shop for
all things graphic design related,
go to 99 designs.com forward slash Tim
to see the projects that I've put up,
including the mockups and drafts of
the book cover for the four hour body
Ex-officio Ex-officio and I go way
back ex-officio dot com forward slash.
Tim,
you can see the clothing that I've used
for traveling through 20 plus countries,
including underwear.
By the way,
that's about half of my
underwear drawer right now,
ex-officio dot com forward slash Tim you
can also see the viral video that I put
out, which shows you how to travel
the world with 10 pounds or less.
As always,
you can subscribe to this podcast on
iTunes and you can find all of the links
and resources from this episode as well
as every other episode by going to four
hour workweek.com forward
slash podcast spell it all out,
or you can go to four hour workweek.com
and just click on podcast feedback.
If you have feedback, I would love
your thoughts, anything at all,
who you'd like to see on this show,
ping me on Twitter at t Ferris.
That's twitter.com forward
slash t, F, e R, r, I s,
s or on facebook@facebook.com forward
slash Tim Ferriss with two r's and two
s's. And until next time,
thank you for listening.
Yeah.