[inaudible]
hey you people,
I'm Tim asked me to make a
quick video of our home gym.
Now there's a couple things about
the home gym that's crucial.
If you are a busy working person,
this is driving me crazy.
If you're a busy working person,
you absolutely have to have a home gym.
At the very least a
Kettlebell and a jump rope.
You got to be able to train on your own.
And if you own a Shim,
you definitely have to
have a gym on those.
You're never going to train ever again.
So this is our home gym J.
Stars on the camera up my number
one trading partner of all time.
You'll see that there's a lot of bikes
in here. Um, we have a walk bike,
which we love lots of kettlebells.
Um,
we believe in the aerobic base.
This is probably largely in part to
a Brian Mckinsey's influence, um,
from an urge to an assault bike to the,
uh, to the concept to stand up skier,
um,
our bikes up there.
Then we have a few kind of miscellaneous
mobilization pieces in here and then
skateboards and bikes. Anyway, but this
is where some of the other work happens.
Call the things that are on our house.
Um,
Juliette has all of her girlfriends
come over a couple times a week.
How many times we j three times a week,
four times a week, four times a week.
They train here. We have the
Cherryland to barbell club for men.
So I bring all the boys over.
We squat heavy.
Then we had this thing called kids squat
club and a once a week we're being all
the kids over. And this is
predicated on an idea that, uh,
that our friend Matt Vincent put
out, they said, hey, you know,
someone's in interviewing him, they
were like, how do you get strong?
And he's like, well, just squat
heavy once a week for 10 years.
Tell me what happened. So we started
out with them once. Your kids,
so we do a little squatting. Um,
so we have the rogue rig here,
which is nice tire flipping
my current favorite things.
Donny Thompson's fat
bells. This is my, uh,
it's really made a difference on my wrist.
It's a kettle bell with a handle on the
inside and you see over in the corner
the Onnit Mace, hey, tell
my feeling not athletic.
I swing this bad boy. I love it. I think
it's aesthetic and beautiful and uh, and,
and make goes sir forwards.
You can see all the other kit and then
come this way because the home gym up
slackline notice Lachlan got to have
it up all the time. And then um,
we decided that when we were finishing
out the house, come on back real quick.
We made some tweaks to our pool design so,
and this was directly influenced
from Laird Hamilton, uh,
all his work in the water,
which you know,
based on some interesting stuff
he was doing. And then Wim Hoff
course,
another Brian Mackenzie and performance.
But we went ahead and we
made our pool 11 feet deep.
So it's 11 feet, it's drop off,
celebrate kid friendly pool.
It drops straight down to box.
And then,
so we do a lot of interesting work around,
come on this way,
Jay would do a lot of interesting
work around carrying the heavy ball.
We have a hundred pound ball
there. We've got dumbbells. Um,
you can see all this stuff on XPT life.
That's a double layered. His finally,
you know, his, his vision, bringing
in with Brian and whim. But, uh,
this piece of it is a huge piece.
So it's just about downregulation
we're in the hot tub.
How many times a day you think,
Jay?
Probably two times a day at least
in the summer. Maybe more. But uh,
and then around the corner
here you can see where, uh,
we do normally have our boat
storage for outriggers, but, uh,
we have our little um, ice tank
there. That's our ice bucket.
Dumbbells for the pool, uh, a bin full of
a million, a million snorkels and masks.
And by the way,
this is our home setup and I think ideas,
you forget that we also have massive,
massive outdoors and we have never lost
track of the fact that you should be
training to get outside. Anyway, this
is the, uh, start at home health center,
Jay store on the film.
Thanks so much for watching guys and be
sure to consider signing up for my email
newsletter by clicking on email newsletter
because I share private Q and A's
exclusive content.
Awesome things like five bullet Fridays,
which is the five coolest things I've
discovered in a given week exclusively via
email.
And that's for the die hard.
That's for the people who really want the
main line of usefulness and how to and
uh,
to really ride along with me as I learn
and discover the most useful things that
I find. So check it out,
email newsletter, click on it,
and please let me know what you'd
like more of in terms of video,
in terms of audio.
I will try to make it for you.
So let me know in the comments
and thank you again for watching.