[inaudible].
Kevin, welcome to the Tim
Ferriss show. Thank you.
I am excited to be here and for
people who don't know, Kevin,
allow me to introduce Kevin Systrom at
Kevin on Instagram as an entrepreneur and
cofounder of Instagram.
While at Instagram,
Kevin served as the CEO where he oversaw
the company's vision and strategy and
daily operations.
That is a whole lot which we will
talk about under his leadership.
Instagram grew to over 1 billion users.
That's with a B and launched dozens
of products including video, live,
direct messaging and creative
tools, stories and IGT. V.
The company also grew to more than 800
employees with a campus in Menlo Park,
new offices in New York City and a
new headquarters in San Francisco.
Prior to founding Instagram,
Kevin graduated from Stanford
University with a BS in management,
science and engineering.
He currently lives in San Francisco with
his wife and daughter, where to begin.
So we've spent a little bit of time
together. We have a little bit of time,
fortunately not three minutes on morning
television to explore all sorts of
things.
And I thought we could start
with one since you seem to read,
not just why a widely but intelligently
and we'll hopefully get into that.
Are there any particular books that
you have gifted often to other people?
Yeah, totally. Um, of course now
all my friends are having kids.
I give kids books, but, uh,
the one I give people that are,
are trying to learn actively
as principles by Ray Daleo. Um,
it's interesting actually
someone gave me the pdf,
it was a pdf before his buck gave me
the pdf and I like skimmed over it.
I was like, Oh, this is pretty
good. And they were like, no,
I seriously think you're gonna love this.
And I,
for some reason I didn't get around
to it for maybe a year and a half.
And then I read the actual
book and I was blown away. Uh,
it's both a guide to life,
a guide to business.
And also I think an
insight into, uh, ray and,
and someone who's built an amazing
business. If you guys listening,
don't know what he does. He a runs a hedge
fund called Bridgewater and he's, um,
he's so much more than, you
know, just a finance thinker.
He's also just a brilliant philosopher.
So I give that a lot because I think
it's a, a great guide to life. Yeah.
He's a fascinating read it.
I have, I have actually,
and Ray's been on the show for
those people who were wondering, uh,
just just to, how many commas are
involved in Bridgewater capital,
the thing they have $160
billion under management,
something along those lines a little
bit. And, uh, he has a lot of very,
uh,
in some respects,
controversial and unusual
practices within Bridgewater,
like recording meetings and saw on and
allowing a all employees to have access
to, uh, the, the minutes and
so on. Have such meetings.
Are there any other books that
helped you in the early days from an
entrepreneurial standpoint
or that you found inspiring?
Totally early on. Um, we read, uh,
Mike and I both read the lean startup,
I think it's called lean startup method
or lean startup. Can't remember Eric.
Eric Reese. Um, and I
remember very early on, um,
I was,
I went to like one of his like book talks
and I was like one of like 13 people
sitting in this little room in Palo
Alto and I was like a super fan still am
actually. And uh, so I don't know
that I've read the entire thing,
but the principles from lean
startup I still apply today. Um,
one of which is like do the simple thing
first and that was our number one value
at a well actually community first was
our number one value at a Instagram.
Number two was do this simple thing first
and still to this day I come back to
that. So if I were reading two books,
I probably read those two books.
And if we,
if we,
if we look at do the simple thing
first from a practical standpoint,
could you give us an example?
And I love that you brought
up Eric because I remember
also we also have been on
the show. He has not, but I remember
going to start naming people.
He's a great guy. He's a great
guy. I would have them on. Uh,
I remember going also too,
I think some hotel conference
room probably in Paulo
Alto when he was initially
testing out the material that later
became the book in these workshops. Yeah.
Yeah. It was like that. Yeah.
Talking about avatars and all
sorts of different things, uh,
doing this simple thing first,
uh,
the scope of your
responsibilities at Instagram,
at least reading,
even just your bio kind of makes my head
spin to imagine what is involved and
how easily distracted you
could become. Uh, what,
what are some examples or any examples
of doing the simple thing first?
Putting that into practice? Yeah.
The first thing, the first thing I'll
say about doing the simple thing first is,
um,
people love to make their lives more
difficult than it needs to be. It's like,
you know, you talk to people who are
saving for retirement and you know,
you don't have to go figure
out a hedging strategy, right?
Like for currencies to
save for retirement.
It turns out just like generally putting
in a mutual fund is not a bad idea.
And the returns you get for ever more
complex strategies either in life or
finance, they're like, it's harder
to eke out the incremental value.
And I think what I found in a startup
is when you're small and you're two
people, it's me and Mike were
coding late into the night.
Like you don't have time
to make things complex.
You have time to make things work.
And what ends up happening
is you over optimize.
So you might think you know
how it's going to break.
So you end trying to build a bunch
of things before it breaks and,
and then it breaks in a
different way and you're like,
why did I spend all that time on,
you know,
that fix when actually I needed
to be doing something else.
I feel like that that's true in life.
I think it's true in business.
It's true in finance, but so
some examples, um, early on, uh,
maybe the best example at
Instagram was we were a,
here's the layman's term version.
We were on one computer,
basically one server and a,
we had enough space to store the data
on that one server and Instagram became
popular, right. And it turns out all the
data couldn't fit on one server anymore.
And we were like, this
is a novel problem. Uh,
let's figure out how to split it among
two servers or three servers or four.
And instead of just like writing a
single file that said like, Hey, listen,
if your user id is, you know, even
your on this server and if it's odd,
you're on that server,
which would have charted the data
across two servers very well in
deterministically.
Uh,
what ended up happening was we threw
everything out and we were like,
you know what, let's adopt this crazy
new technology that does auto sharding.
And it was fancy and had all
these bells and whistles.
I won't name it because I don't want
to throw them under the bus. Um,
but we spent,
I don't know,
four months trying to rewrite
our system to be on this new, uh,
database.
And eventually after a crushing a bunch
of times and US having issues with it,
we were about to run out of space
and Mike was like, screw it.
And he literally spent maybe two hours
in the afternoon writing that file that
we should have written to begin
with and it all just worked.
So I'm over simplifying things
a little bit for a fact.
But like that's basically what happened.
And I still think about that story to
this day in terms of an executive making a
decision with his cofounder about what
to do. Always do the simple thing first.
And it's amazing to me how many people
think the quality of their management
they think is judged based
on the complexity of their
decisions or the outcomes.
And it turns out actually the right
thing to do is sometimes the simplest and
it's the most effective.
So I live that as a value
both in life finance and uh,
and at work as well.
So I'm going to rewind the clock
a little bit because I think this,
you could do that in editing,
but yes,
we can slice and dice. But this'll be
like watching the movie memento. Okay.
Got It. Uh, it's basically usually what
it's like when I do an interview. Yeah,
exactly. So pretty, pretty
standard protocol. Uh,
I would love to talk about,
and we won't spend a ton of time on this
because as we chatted before recording,
I think you've talked about the
origins story of Instagram a lot,
but for people who don't have any context,
I think it's worth diving
into a little bit, uh,
doing this simple thing first makes me
think of a common problem that I see in
startups and in software
development of any type really,
which is feature creep and these products
that start off with a focus lose focus.
And it,
it seems to me that you effectively
did the opposite in some ways for the
creation of Instagram.
Could you,
can you give people a little bit of
background on how Instagram came to be and
you can tackle that short version,
medium sized, however you like? Well,
first of all, I'm having to talk about
where Instagram came from. I just, um,
it's such an interesting story in my life
and that I've talked about it a bunch
of times,
but I forget that it's actually super
interesting to hear for people who might
have signed up for Instagram
a couple of years ago.
I think it's been around
forever. Right? Um,
but also I think it has
some interesting lesson.
So I'll combine both talking
about the origin story,
but also how we kept it simple.
Um,
Instagram came out of one wanting to be
my own boss. I was like, you know what?
I want to work for myself.
I want to work on ideas.
I really hope I'm going to make
money. Um, and I remember, uh,
telling at the time, my mom, uh, I was
like, Hey, I'm going to go do this thing.
And she was like, what about
health insurance? I was like, oh,
what about health insurance? Like, I
totally forgot. Um, so my point is,
I was a little naive,
but I wanted to do my own thing.
And I had a bunch of different ideas.
One of which was a terrible
idea for a checking APP.
Actually. It wasn't terrible,
but like for at the time there were a
bunch of checking apps and we're sitting
in Austin right now, south by
southwest, you know, zoom back six,
she's seven, eight years ago. It was
all about Gowalla and foursquare. Right.
Everyone was all about sure. So I had to
have my version. Um, and it wasn't bad,
but you know, it wasn't good
either. And uh, catching him. Yeah,
it was called Bourbon.
Um, and be URBN I still,
I think I own the domain name
somewhere. Um, but anyway, we, uh, what,
what happened, I was working
on that. I left my job, um,
and I happened to be able to raise money
for it and I'm not sure how or why,
but um, checking apps were all the rage.
So we raised some money. It was, you know,
a couple of well known firms in the
valley and I had just enough money to work
on it.
And I met my cofounder Mike at the time
and I know I needed a bunch of help
cause I'm like, I'm technical
but not like, you know,
I'm not a true engineer in the sense
like I didn't study it formally.
So I met Mike and he was one of
the power users of Bourbon and uh,
he was like, yeah, this will be
super fun. So we decided to join up.
We worked on Bourbon for maybe,
I don't know,
three months and it was clear
it wasn't working. Okay.
It was like very clear the startup
was going nowhere. And, uh,
we decided to pivot and this is where
keeping it simple, um, comes in.
We actually got to the idea for Instagram
by taking away features from Bourbon,
not by changing at all.
So a bunch of the features of Bourbon.
One you could check in at a place,
but two, you could add a photo of
what you were doing at that place.
So you and I were out to drink somewhere.
I check in at the Bar,
I can post a photo of the beer I'm having
or the cocktail or whatever. Right. Um,
and it turns out people kind of liked
the checkins the thought it was pretty
lame because it was a me too thing.
But they love showing
people what they were doing.
They loved taking a picture of the bar,
the restaurant that whatever. And uh,
and we realized to keep it simple,
we were going to have to cut
every other feature of Bourbon,
which we did and we just kept the photo
part. How did you decide on that feature?
Uh, because we made a list and we asked
ourselves what exists in the world,
what sucks? Meaning you look
out in the world and you say,
what opportunity is there to fill if stuff
doesn't exist and it's a problem that
can be solved. Ak like the experience
sucks, then that's what you should go do.
There were a lot of check in apps.
There were a lot of planners and
meet up things in group chat things,
but there was no solution
for posting great photos too,
like lots of friends all at once.
So we made the list,
we crossed off the things we thought
were pretty boring or just there was no
opportunity in them.
Um,
and we circled the photos thing cause
we saw the confluence of both mobile
phones being pervasive. Like
again, go back in the day.
Not everyone had an iPhone,
like maybe the iPhone had been out for
a couple of years at that point in 2007,
eight. Right? So, um, we
knew that cameras are,
we're going to be pervasive
in people's pockets,
that people were going to be carrying
these camera phones, you know,
wherever they went.
But we didn't know if it would be
successful or not to capitalize on that.
But it was the only thing that
looked like a greenfield opportunity.
Everything else felt crowded.
That's a different way of saying it.
So we got to the idea by cutting
everything away from Bourbon circling,
the one thing that we felt like was the
biggest opportunity because it didn't
exist yet and it was a big need.
Um,
and we built the first version
of Instagram a note. By the way,
the first version of Instagram did not
have filters. Um, and people forget,
the only reason Instagram worked early
on was because of the filters and filters
came about because I was on
this walk with my wife. Uh,
we were taking a small vacation.
I had been working on Bourbon for a while,
I was exhausted. Um, and we're
taking this walk along the beach.
And I was like, oh, so you're excited
about this new APP we're building.
We haven't called it Instagram
yet. She was like, yeah,
but I don't think I'm gonna use it
cause my photos aren't that good.
I'm was like, okay, well why
don't you think your photos
are good? And she's like,
well all your friends,
you know,
you post these amazing photos and
they're all like filtered it and stuff.
And I was like, oh, that's because
they use filters. And she goes,
oh well you should probably add filters.
And uh, we came back from that walk.
I went straight to the room and I just
like got on my laptop and I made the
first filter, which was x pro two. Um,
this is the long way of
saying we cut features,
we focused on what we thought the world
needed and then we got to the heart of
the issue of why people wouldn't use it
because people didn't feel comfortable
sharing their photos by solving those
things right in a row and keeping it Uber
simple.
I mean even that first filter could have
been written in open GL and could have
been a lot faster.
You tap on that filter,
it took like three seconds to
show you the filter. No one cared.
It was fine. Yeah. Keep it
simple. Keep it super simple.
Now you mentioned,
you mentioned Eric Reese.
His book is as perhaps
one of the influences, uh,
Lake to look at or dig
for lessons learned,
best practices,
observed,
anything at all that you took
away or very difficult times.
Anything from a few previous experiences.
So we'll go back to the
Mayfield fellows program.
Uh,
was there anything in that program
that you found particularly useful?
Uh, and then the next,
then I'll hit. So, uh,
we can certainly do them in
order or not would be Odo. Yeah,
I mean, where, where do I start?
Okay. So, and what did he bless feel?
Fellows program? Yeah,
Mayfield fellows program. Uh,
it's a program at Stanford where they
take, I think they still take 12 a year,
12, uh, typically graduate students. Um,
although I snuck in and I'll
explain that in a second. Um,
who are interested in
entrepreneurship and they, um,
they focus on what is called
an entrepreneurship education.
So they do three months of case studies,
kind of like going to
Harvard Business School,
but case studies on just
entrepreneurship. Then three months, uh,
you spend,
um,
at a real startup getting real experience
and then you come back and the last
three months, so it's a
year long program, uh,
meaning three quarters of the school year,
um,
you come back and you debrief on your
own experience and you actually write
basically a case on your, um, experience
over the summer. So I did that.
Uh, I, my junior year I snuck in
by like, I dunno, I basically,
I was like, Hey, but like I founded
this startup, not really a startup.
It was a website at the time that
was like a competitor to craigslist,
but for Stanford students only.
And uh,
I prayed that they would take me cause
I was so excited about entrepreneurship
and they let me in, um,
years later, by the way, uh,
one of the people who ran the
program still runs the program,
actually pulled me aside and was like,
just so you know,
we were barely about to let you in.
And I was like, thank God you did.
And she was like,
but the thing that made the difference
was that you were out there actually
trying to start something.
And I guess less than number one is like
never expect you're going to get a no,
like always put your name in,
right.
Number two is actually do the thing,
like actually start the startup.
It don't just go to conferences about it,
don't just like write articles
about, started to something. Um,
and that carries a lot of weight. Um,
but that was Mayfield fellows program.
And maybe the last lesson on the Mayfield
fellows program that I got from it was
real. There's nothing in the world that
can substitute for real experience.
Doesn't matter what we're talking about.
If you want to be a chef,
working in a kitchen is the only way
you're going to learn going into culinary
school. Whatever I'm sure is great. But
working in a kitchen is the way to do it.
If you want to be, gosh, um, like a,
like a tech founder, right?
You got to start a startup.
You've got to know what it feels
like to put it all on the line,
lose everything and then come back.
Right.
You can't learn about
investing unless you invest.
I mean name whatever profession.
It's like real experience is so
much better than what's in a book.
That doesn't mean that books aren't
helpful, but you've got to do it.
But they're in the adjunct.
Yeah.
Very hard to become a professional soccer
player by reading books on the physics
of soccer. Although I gotta tell you,
I took this personality test, um,
and the results came back,
but one of the main takeaways was
like prefers learning by reading.
And I was reading my results to my
family cause I thought it would be
entertaining. And my mom was like, oh my
God. Like I remember when you were a kid,
you just read everything.
And my dad was like, yeah,
like you said you were
going to be interested in
playing baseball. So, uh, uh,
I was like, I bought a Mitt for you
and we were going to go play catch.
And you're like, Dad, I got to go to
the library. And my dad was like, what?
And he's like,
I got to read about it.
So I literally went to the library and
read about how to pitch and then played.
And I think that's my ammo. It's just
I'm wired that way. Did you remember the,
it was an okay pension,
the name of the personality test
or the assessment leading? Um,
yes, it was the, uh, golden personality
tests. Schooled and personality.
I think it was golden. Yeah. Why
did you take that test? It's a a,
it's a variant on the Myers Briggs test.
Uh,
but it actually gives you very
specific breakdowns of every dimension.
So for those of you listening that
don't know the Myers Briggs test, uh,
there are basically four main
dimensions, uh, of the personality test.
And it tells you,
for instance,
whether you're more casual or if you're
like very calculated and punctual,
that kind of stuff. Um, I wanted
to know more about what I was like.
I had talked about Ray Daleo before.
Um,
I spoke with him and he was saying,
yeah, everyone who joins Bridgewater,
we give this personality test. And
I was like, well, can I take it?
Like I want to know what I am like.
And my cofounder took it,
a bunch of our senior execs took it.
Um, and it was illuminating to learn,
see on paper,
which you know in the back of your mind.
And then of course it
helps you work with others.
But a big part of it was reading on
paper what you're actually alike and
realizing for instance,
I do learn by reading.
So I'm not someone who likes to sit in
a lecture hall. I want to have the book.
So if I'm going to learn something new,
like the way to learn is not for
me to go to like a, a conference.
It's to like sit down with the best book
possible and that might not apply to
you. Right? Like if you took it, maybe
you like learning some other way,
but I wanted to know what my API was.
So that was helpful here. Api.
Yeah, I like it. That's true. Yeah.
We all learned application programming
interface. He used to know some acronyms,
uh,
on reading.
There are different ways to
read books and I had, uh,
found in some of the research
for this conversation.
A mention of Mortimer Adler
is how to read a book. Yeah.
Could you talk about how you read?
How weird is it that I'm like,
so into reading that I have to
find a boat that's how to read.
Like where does it stop? How to
read, how to read a book. Um,
have you ever read the book? I
haven't. Okay. Um, it's fine. Um,
I can save you some time. Yeah.
Basically the idea behind this book is,
uh,
it's how to read a book most effectively.
Most people open the first page and they
start with the first word and then they
go until either that they get bored
or they push through or whatever. Um,
and the claim and the book is
basically that, that is not correct.
That instead what you should do is
familiarize yourself with the structure of
the book first. So the most important,
uh, I, I would say his thesis,
the F is that the most important part of
reading a book is to actually read the
table of contents and familiarize yourself
with like the major structure of the
book and then familiarize yourself by
skimming the book and figuring out what
the main arguments are.
In fact,
one of the secrets that I love and I can
still do to this day is most authors in
the last paragraph of every chapter,
especially the last paragraph of the book,
will not only summarize
their main arguments,
but make the points they actually have
been waiting to make the entire chapter.
And by reading just those paragraphs,
you get a pretty good idea
of what the book's about.
Then you go back and you
read like you normally read.
But with the context of knowing the
overall arc of the story rather than
guessing where it's going to go.
I don't recommend doing this with the
thriller because of the old ruin your but
with nonfiction I think it's
fantastic. Um, but that's, uh,
that's how to read a book.
And by the way,
for those of you Mortimer fans out there,
I probably didn't do it justice,
but go by the book,
kind of go by the book,
which will encourage you to buy yet
more books. I have this seriously,
if I could show you my room right now,
my bedside table,
it's just stacked with books.
I've got a book called uh,
mathematics politics cause I'm interested
in both politics and also the math
behind elections and that stuff. I think
how to read a books probably there.
Um, one of the books do I have, I've
got books on, uh, on flying cars.
I'm learning to be a pilot.
Um, it like, it ranges. Oh,
I've got a quantitative finance
books I've got, but like,
it's the most fun I've ever had. Just
like plowing through books. I guess.
It's good. I don't have a
job right now. I don't know.
It does create a little space is how
quickly it gets filled out. It does.
Well, I mean, you're not talking,
I don't think. Is it podcasts?
Especially the long ones.
Uh,
Odo what was Odo
and uh, what did you learn
there? What did you observe?
Yeah, audio was the
precursor to Twitter. So, um,
you were talking about Mayfield fellows
program. Uh, my internship was ODL.
So that three months over the
summer I spent at Odeo. Um,
I remember I showed up the first day I
brought my own computer because I thought
when you worked at a company, you bring
your own computer. Cause I was like,
I don't know. Computers are expensive.
Right? Like you bring your own. Um,
and they're like, oh good.
You brought your own computer.
I think there were thrilled. Um,
and it was a Evan Williams and,
and no glass where the cofounders
of Odo and uh, they were like, oh,
I forgot you started today.
And I was like, Yep, here I am.
And actually it was one of
the best experiences learning
from Av who's brilliant.
Um,
and Noah,
who's also brilliant and like just
seeing that startup tried to take off,
it was a podcast directory, believe
it or not, maybe a little early. Um,
it was the right way of they just paddle
a little early. Yeah. Which by the way,
another lesson and this whole thing,
timing is everything.
Like the number of amazing ideas and
teams that either came too early or too
late. It's like you've got to have that
essential element of timing and it's the
hardest to predict. But it was a
podcast directory and you know,
honestly a lot of the,
the famous podcast folks got started on
Odo and there are a bunch of that are
still around,
but it turns out back then there wasn't
exactly a business around podcasts and
it didn't go so well and
they ended up pivoting to a,
an idea started by an engineer.
There are Jack Dorsey,
who by the way also started I think
like maybe my first or second day.
And I remember him walking in and I'm
like on the Internet. He's like, Oh,
I'm jack. And uh, I learned,
actually he gave me a couple of coding
assignments over the summer. Um,
I remember learning some javascript
from him. So it's a small world.
It turns out super small, but that's
what Odio was and that was my experience.
It was awesome and I'm very
thankful to all those guys.
What do you view as some of say,
just as an example, as superpowers?
I mean, he's a very impressive guy,
very understated in a lot of ways. Uh,
what did you, what did you observe, uh,
in the secret sauce of, of f?
Because he's also a repeat player,
right? I mean, this is, he's not
a one hit wonder. So what, uh,
what have you observed in him?
It
turns out blogging and communication
is a thing and it doesn't go away. Um,
and there are lots of companies
that can be started around it. Um,
what did I observe? Uh, what was
really long time ago, but, um,
or what superpowers do you think he has?
He could talk present tense too. So I,
he's super determined. Um,
and super calm under fire.
There are a lot of,
uh,
there are a lot of CEO's
that, um, are very like,
uh, emotionally volatile and
AV, at least in my experience,
is not one of those people.
In fact,
he's determined and hardworking and I
can't remember his background story,
but he's like, yeah, you
know, I went to this college,
it wasn't that great and I just worked
my ass off to get here and to build this
thing and then eventually
sell it to Google that was
blogger and then to be able
to start this thing. And I remember
his work ethic because at one point,
I'm pretty sure he was convinced we all
were working hard enough. So he sent us,
he didn't send us,
he,
he offered for us to go to this seminar
by David Allen getting things done.
And then I remember sitting
in the audience and just
like the Odo crew that were
like,
I don't know,
six or seven of us at the time at the
David Allen getting things done, you know,
uh, not conference but seminar. I still
try to use that stuff today, by the way.
Um, but the signal was like, we work
hard here and we get stuff done.
And he was there. He was the
first one in, last one out. Um,
and as a CEO I understood
what that model meant,
one that I could learn from the CEO that
if they had ways of getting things done,
you could,
you could learn that as an employee.
And I tried very hard at Instagram
to learn stuff and then pass it on.
But also just the work ethic that is
required to get startups off the ground.
It's incredible.
Plus willing to call it,
like he was willing to call Odo and
pivot to this thing called Twitter.
And Trust me when we were calling it
on Bourbon and pivoting to Instagram,
I was thinking about that moment. I
wasn't there in the room when they did it,
but I can imagine, you know, the,
the bravery that it takes to switch
like that, it's hard. But uh,
but paying attention to people like ev,
an entrepreneurs like that
and entrepreneurs like Jack,
I think you begin to learn that there
are patterns and you have a little faith
in their ways and, and you, you end
up trying to mirror it in many ways.
I completely agree on the edge of having
a calmness as a competitive advantage.
He's very good at pausing
and not jumping to respond.
Uh,
so he's,
he's been able to choose his response
I suppose instead of being reactive.
I think you're very good at that as well.
Thanks. And um, I want to talk about,
since it's come up a few times,
uh, pivoting or ending projects.
Yeah. Because there's a, in some aspects,
a fetishizing of perseverance in a lot
of places including silicon valley,
the world of tech.
And yet if you,
if you look at a lot of the
largest public successes,
many of them had some type of pivot or
shutting down of something that wasn't
working.
Uh,
how do you know it's the
right time to stop in when,
how does one go about making
that difficult decision?
Like are there telltale
signs that this is just,
it's not that another 50% of effort is
required another x number of hours per
day,
but like this is fundamentally flawed
in some way that is going to prevent it
from working. I think, let's
take this question in two parts.
First is let's just talk about the
premise that most successful things,
our pivots,
which I believe is true.
One of the really fun things to do is
actually, do you know the wayback machine?
I do. Right. Uh, I think it still
exists. I haven't tried it a long time,
but you can go and type
in any way web address.
And then I think it allows you to like
select the date of that website so you
can basically see the history of the web.
It's super interesting.
Go to youtube and figure out
when Youtube was founded.
I can't remember, but like you can
look it up on Wikipedia, right?
And go to that date.
Like around the beginning you will see
youtube was a dating site before it
became youtube. What we
know as youtube. Right.
Do that for most major things that you
get excited about or like look up the
history of Facebook when it was, you
know, it was facemash beforehand.
It was something before that.
I'm the only one that I don't think
was a pivot was Google and they've done
pretty well. So that's the
one counter example. Um,
like that literally was their project
and they made it a company and it worked
really well. So I don't know.
Um, but most other projects,
our um,
our pivots from an original idea.
And I think that's because one,
it's really hard to tell what works a
priority like doing it before anything
before you actually, you know,
put it into, into people's hands.
It's really difficult.
Like you don't know if it's going to work.
The key to entrepreneurship
is failing really quickly.
So putting it out there, seeing
if it works, if it doesn't,
than diagnosing why and then like
focusing on how to improve it from there.
Um,
so one,
I agree with the premise that
most things are in fact, uh,
like second runs and then
to the importance of pivot
I think is that most of the
time you get it wrong. So the question
is knowing you're going to get it wrong,
how equipped are you to deal with that
failure really quickly before you run out
of money.
And the entrepreneurs that I've seen do
very well are the ones that are equipped
and engaged on the change from something
that's not working to something that is
far too many people because of ego or
whatever. Stick with ideas far too long.
And, uh, I think, you know,
it ends up really poor that yet or look
at something that isn't working that
might have a different application.
Right. If you look at post it notes,
we actually a failed adhesive, right? Yep.
And then you look at say
five Agra which was failed.
It was a,
a failure from the perspective of
whatever it was initially a
tested for or intended for,
which I think was lowering blood pressure
and normalizing for blood pressure.
And then the,
excuse me,
can you check off all the side
effects of this blood pressure pill?
There's a pattern here.
The,
the recipients were asked to send back
their samples and all the women's send
their samples back and almost none
of the men did. And they're like,
wait a second,
what's going on here?
I can't tell if this is a family friendly
show and we should dive into this or
how we can, we can, uh, you know,
it is family friendly but a modern
family still be the director. Scott,
this will be the, the director's
cut. This is like no way. Pivots,
pivots are important.
And how do you train,
if you do the ability to recognize say
confirmation bias or this is something
certainly ray thinks a lot about is
identifying from the perspective of an
investor where you might have piece
coming to sum cost fallacy or any of these
other things that could steer you to make
bad decisions or we're not stop things
has,
is that something that you've,
you've trained in yourself or is
that innate from birth or upbringing?
I think I was talking with my wife
the other day and I was like, Nicole,
I think one of my failures is that like
I always think things are not going to
work out or I'm wrong in some way. And,
and we were going back and forth. I was,
she was like,
oh,
well maybe that's actually a strength
because like you're so hard on an idea
that you're like trying to prove yourself
wrong to test the integrity of your
idea or a test, the integrity
of your thesis or, and like,
so you mentioned ray,
like I think a big part of knowing that
you're right is working as hard as you
can to prove that you're wrong.
And if you can't,
well there's only one option left,
which is you're probably right. Um,
but a lot of people I think
are afraid to gather feedback.
I think Mike and I at
Instagram very early on,
tried our best to be open to feedback.
I think as a young executive
I was like, no, I'm the boss.
Like all ideas are great, all
my ideas are great. Right?
And after a couple of failures, I think
you learn really quickly that like,
hey listen,
I know there's this myth that like the
best founders just have like the midas
touch and every idea they have is
perfect. You know, like Steve Jobs,
he touches everything and it just
becomes gold. And it's right.
But it turns out there a lot of
failures in these people's lives.
They just usually get written out of
history. And then what you see is a,
as a trail of amazing ideas.
I mean,
so much to write a book on all the bad
ideas amazing people have had right over
the years. And because she has
10 volumes set. Totally. But like
I think get the wrong idea. There
is no Mitus touch. Like the,
one of the things I hated most working
in tech was the idea that there's like a
product guy or a product girl,
right?
Like that you're like somehow someone
who just knows what's going to work.
Most of the successful people I know
have tons of bad ideas and it's about
editing them out. Um, and figuring
out which one is actually right.
Because honestly,
what does the Mendoza line?
It's like if you bet 200 like above 200
year, like a pretty good batter, right?
In a world where your
average is going to be 1%,
you've got to generate a
ton of ideas before you get
one roughly a hundred right?
Yeah. So, and 1% would be like
way higher than the average.
So how do you figure out which is the one?
It's,
I think it's by being super not mean to
yourself, a critical on the idea in a,
in a constructive way and pressure
testing it with other people. Um,
but I just,
I like always have an,
I'm just wired in a
way that assumes every,
whether it's idea or thesis or
whatever I have is wrong. And I'm,
I'm more worried about being
wrong than I am looking bad,
you know what I mean?
No, I get it. Do you have any, uh,
particular questions that you ask
yourself or other people when your stress
testing an idea or alternatively
how you solicit feedback and,
um,
I give an example since I write,
I have all these books. I want
people to act as proofreaders. Uh,
but I don't want them since they are
my friends to be an unnecessarily nice,
but guess what? They all light.
Yeah. And so I will, I, I,
one of the questions I'll ask them,
I is in a given chapter,
I'll say you had to cut
10 to 20% gun to the head,
which tend to 20 would go nice. Right.
And it forces their hand in a sense.
Are there other approaches that you like
to use or like others to use on your
ideas for stress testing?
Well,
first off,
I think it's important to realize
how people are just wired.
Not to be honest. Not that they lie. I
mean, I guess technically it's a lie,
but I don't think it like
comes from a bad place.
They're wired to avoid conflict.
So like you go in a restaurant
and the server comes by, you know,
maybe you didn't like it
as the server comes by.
When's the last time you
actually literally told them
like everything was great,
but that thing was too salty? That was,
you know, I like to eat. By the way.
That thing was too salty.
That was undercooked.
Like next time you go out to eat and
they're like, how was everything?
And you're like, you
instinctively just respond. Great.
Thanks if it is that
actually what you thought.
Like most people have one or two
things they wish could be better.
And what's crazy is I think of myself
in that situation every time I was down
there, I'm like, man, if I
were on the other side of this,
I'd really want to know the
truth because without the truth,
you can't improve. Right.
And you have to be careful.
Cause sometimes people have opinions
and they're not always right,
but only if you don't know,
you can't act on it.
And I've been surprised how
many people I've met, um,
at least in the food industry, right?
Where at least if you do it in a nice way,
you're like, listen, I just, if I
were on the receiving end of this,
I'd want to know so I'm giving this
to you, do whatever you want with it.
And it's always interesting to see that
people that are like grateful for that
feedback and you're like, that person's
going to go kick some ass. Totally.
And the people who are like, what's
supposed to be that way? You know?
And you're like, well, okay, like, but
like what if it isn't? You know, like,
um,
and I think it's really important
as you mature as an executive.
Like I definitely started in the place
where I just like didn't listen to
feedback. I was, you know, headstrong.
And then as you have more and more
failures that by the way, everyone has,
you begin to realize it's really
important to collect that data and that
information from people.
No one would tell me like
when I was presenting on
stage, everyone would be like,
great talk, great, awesome job.
Great. You killed it. And I was like,
that's not possible. Like, like a
few talks in a row that happened.
And then we hired someone and I'm not
going to pick on them and tell you who
they are,
but we hired someone who came up to me
after and Gabey three pieces of feedback.
They were like, you need to smile
more. You need to do that. Like,
I know you're a happy person,
but you're not smiling when you're
talking about this really happy subject,
like smile. And I was like, oh
my God, that person's right.
They literally watched every single
interview I had done for like the last two
years and just had a list of things and
I was so grateful for that because it
was feedback that no
one else would give me.
Do you remember any of the
other points? Uh, it was, um,
slow down pause, right?
Uh, it was smile more.
Not because you're trying
to give off a vibe that,
but just what's funny is you can't
overdo smiling. It turns out like it's,
it's hard. Um, and I'm just like,
I'm a serious person so I
don't think smile as much. Uh,
what were the other things?
I'd have to go back to my notes,
but those are the two things
that stood out. Yeah. It's a,
people don't give you feedback. It's
crazy. And by the way, the thing is,
the more important your company gets,
the higher up you go,
the less people are willing to do it.
Yeah.
So you actually have to like dig for it.
And that's one of the
weirdest feelings ever is.
Please tell me something negative,
but you asked a specific question,
which is like what are the tools to do it?
I don't know that there are any like
specific tools so much as like when's the
last time you,
the listener did that?
When's the last time you went out
of your way and you said, hey,
like I really want honest feedback on
this. And when someone gives you feedback,
you don't respond in a defensive way.
You say thank you and you
encourage the behavior.
If you could do that man, like the
self improvement that comes with that.
Yeah.
And the honesty that comes with it if,
depending on the format can
be a really remarkable, I,
you may have done this before,
but I had not done a a 360 interview.
Oh yeah. I avoided doing the first one
they wanted me to do ever. I was like, oh,
this is just like a, a management
thing. And then the second one I did,
I literally tried hard to do it. Like
I asked people to participate. I said,
please be as honest as
possible. Yeah. And, uh,
I remember I was chatting with
Joe Gibeah about his first three,
16 year reviewed for people who
do not know what that is. Uh,
there are different ways to approach
it, but in effect, your superiors,
peers, slash colleagues and
subordinates are all interviewed.
So the people that you interact with
most or all interviewed about your
strengths and weaknesses and so on.
And very frequently,
at least in my case with uh,
my employees and so on,
it was anonymized to ratchet
up the allowable honesty.
And,
uh,
it was a great example of how valuable
honesty can be and also how difficult it
can be to digest if it's
really full frontal.
And I think Joe said he like went
to his car and the parking lot.
I cried afterwards. I had a tough time.
I had a really tough time with it,
but it ended up being very helpful and
I was able to look at it with a cooler
head,
not because I was angry,
but I was really sort of like cut down
at the knees by some of the comments.
And it was really important. I mean,
if you've spinach stuck in your teeth,
you need somebody to tell you.
The hardest
part is how to tell when
you've got spinach stuck in
your teeth or someone just
doesn't like you and,
but you have to be willing to get both.
Yeah.
And then ask yourself which of these
have merit and not to write things off,
but you have to be able to go through
it and just ask yourself. Um, but yeah,
that was hard. Yeah. I remember
my first one and I just,
but now I think about it and like,
no matter what I do,
whether it's another company, whether
I'm doing a writing project or a podcast,
whatever, like, so I just walked off
the stage at south by southwest and um,
I could see the screen that was displayed
after we left and they asked people to
rate the rate, everything like rate
the speakers are at the hose. Like,
and I was like, oh, I really want that
data. I'm going to ask him for it. Uh,
because I want to know, like,
was it interesting to people?
What topics didn't they like? Like, did
we come off as authentic or inauthentic?
Like where were we?
Um,
but it's funny because no one ever tells
you anything and it's unless you dig
for it, you won't find it. Um,
but honestly I think letting people
know that it's safe to give feedback,
asking for a proactively, et Cetera,
et Cetera is important. I just,
the amount of people go out of their way
to avoid conflict is pretty wild. Yeah.
Which,
which
often works in the short term,
but can really be caustic and road
relationships in the longterm.
And if you're avoiding that,
and you,
your comment on the rating on
screen made me think of, uh,
Kyle Maynard, who is an
incredible, incredible guy who's a,
I was also been on the bad guys,
but he had learned at one point,
or it was given a piece of advice from
a very successful CEO of a large company
that if you ever asked somebody to write
something from one to 10 to disallow
seven,
because seven's,
it's like semi is all three and
a half stars. You're like, yeah,
exactly.
So you mentioned restaurants.
So it will very often ask people in
restaurants if they're giving me the,
everything is good response, which
is gives me no information to act on.
As I'll say. All right. On any,
I'll give them two options and I'll say
one to 10, but no, seven. How do you rank?
And it's, it's sort of bear. Then they,
they're forced if they're straddling
that to do a barely pass, which is a sec.
So I'm not going to order that or an
eight, which is a strong, that's a,
that's a confident endorsement and a
suit that can be applied to all manner of
things. Uh, that's a really cool, I'll
do that from now on. You know, sevens.
Yeah, let's, let's talk
about tough times. Uh,
so you mentioned are none. The life of
an entrepreneur is golden. True. It's,
you know, it's, it has been, uh,
it has been said that your life is
all highlights. No, I'm kidding.
That hasn't been said. A company
made that happen, but I want it to,
I want to talk about,
I want to talk about some of the
maybe tougher times that, uh,
that you're willing to share, if any.
Some of the maybe course darker periods,
tough decisions. We're, uh,
anytime you had kind of self
doubt or felt lost because, uh,
and where I'm going with this,
I'm very curious how you
then recontextualized it
found the silver lining or
just got through it. Um, because it's, uh,
some people get knocked down and they
have a really tough time getting back up.
So when people are able to do that,
I like to look,
look inside and see what actually
happened. Yeah. So, yeah. Any,
any at all that you're
willing to talk about?
First thing I'll say is a lot of people
assume that like business people,
entrepreneurs,
like whether they make money like a lot
of money or they saw a company or they
go public or whatever and their CEO's for
a long time, or world leaders, whatever.
A lot of people assume these
people don't struggle, right.
That somehow they're inhuman or whatever.
Like,
I feel like I wake up every day with
a lot of the same worries I did before
Instagram was a thing. Am I working on
the right thing? Did I do enough today?
Is that idea of the right idea?
And I still have just as many failures
as I did before Instagram and well inside
of Instagram as well.
Now don't get me wrong,
there are structures around me now
that allow me to come back from those
failures. Um, but
I guess my point is like getting knocked
down is like a really common thing.
No matter where you are in your career,
no matter where you are in your
progress of building something.
And in fact it usually happens more, the
more important thing you're doing. Right?
So early on it Instagram,
uh,
I think there were a bunch of times I
remember pitching the idea and having
really smart,
intelligent folks look at me like I was
a crazy person for working on anything
related to photos.
Um,
I remember trying to hire some of,
like the most amazing designers early on,
um,
who just like wouldn't join because
they didn't believe in the APP.
I remember press stories,
um,
or investors investing in competitors
even though they had invested in us.
So choosing the other, which is
fine, listen, like it's up to like,
investors should be able to choose
who they think the winner is.
That's their job. But it's tough, right?
To think you're not the winner. Um,
all of these things happened along the
way and we were knocked down multiple
times. Um, whether that was in
our heads are actually there, uh,
in reality.
Um,
but the thing that kept us going was
realizing it wasn't other people we were
trying to impress. I mean, of course
we wanted a community for the APP.
The reason we got back up each and every
time it was because we loved what we're
doing,
right?
Like if your goal is to
gain people's approval,
like the startup business is a
terrible business to get into. Heck,
like if you're a singer,
like the worst business to be in,
in the world because everyone's going to
tell you your stuff stinks until maybe
it doesn't. Right. But you have
to believe in what you're doing.
I love what you're doing.
That itself has to bring you
the most amount of excitement.
Otherwise getting knocked down is going
to knock you off the horse and you're
off forever.
And I,
I often think like was it determination
that got us to where we got or luck or
some combination of both of them because
I don't know if you have a bad idea and
you're determined on it and don't listen
to anyone, it's like not great. Right?
Yeah. But at the same time we wouldn't
be where we are if I had listened to most
people. It's crazy. Yeah. So, um,
I dunno if there's a secret to getting
back up otherwise other than maybe
creating no choice but to get back up.
Like I didn't have another job.
What was I going to do? Like sign up
for business school. I don't know.
Like I had quit my job and raised a bunch
of money and I really loved what I was
doing. So every time one of
these failures would occur.
What was the other option? Can you
think of one? A desk, job, desk, job.
Can you think of an example?
Uh, of a tough time,
a tough decision,
a tough rejection from an investor,
a designer,
anything.
And what you then said to yourself,
I'm very curious about self
talk. Right? So it's like,
whether it's like Shaun white on
the final run in the Olympics.
And I asked him what he said before he
left the gate to himself and it was who
cares? And he like explained
why it was like, who cares?
And I didn't expect that answer
and found it really interesting.
I mean in the sense that like he's done
all the preparation he could possibly do.
He's either ready or he isn't. And
there was an entire explanation for it.
Uh, and what fighters say
before they get in the ring.
If there is some type of self talk.
I got one. Yeah. Yeah. Let's go
straight to the interesting topics.
Selling our company.
Yeah.
So we sold our company
and it was April of 2012.
Um, and by all accounts,
if you start a company, uh,
for a lot of entrepreneurs winning
quote unquote, and by the way,
I don't agree with this
definition, but, um,
but winning is quote unquote either
selling or company or, or, uh, you know,
having a public offering, an IPO. Um,
for a lot of people that's like the
traditional outcome for a startup.
Um, and we had sold and we were
13 people and it was $1 billion.
It was really exciting. And, uh,
and I remember like right
afterwards everyone being like,
so it's over.
And I feel like that was the most
painful thing to hear because I had no
intention on not doing Instagram.
I like wanted to work on it for
the next, you know, whatever years.
But everyone I met was like, so
you're done now, so it's over.
It was like, no, no, no, no, no.
And like we would try to hire people
and they'd be like, no, it's over.
And I remember people working at
the company telling me it was over.
And a couple of people ended up
leaving pretty soon after that. Um,
and I remember one of them saying, yeah,
there's like nothing else to learn here.
I like, where can we go from here?
Mind you, at the time we had,
I don't know, 50 million users. We got to
a billion by the way. We had no revenue.
We got to a lot more than no revenue.
Um,
we grew to a thousand people on the team.
We opened up multiple offices all around
the world. I got to do everything.
We're meeting the pope to meetings
some idols like I got to, it was crazy.
So the idea that in 2012 we sold our
company and then everyone just kind of
counted us out. That was painful.
W W how did you contend with that?
Like what was your response to that?
I think with me,
it usually comes with the competitive
nature of proving people wrong.
If you look at that like histogram,
sorry to use that word,
but of how long founders stay
after they sell their company.
I'm pretty sure there's like a giant
like lump around one month to one year.
Right?
We were there for six years after we sold,
which I think goes to show how incredibly
determined we were to show people that
Instagram wasn't done, that we
were at the beginning, not the end,
and that it didn't matter
if we sold the company,
we were going to make something
out of this thing. And for me,
I think the motivation comes
with proving people wrong. Um,
because I hate when people discount us.
I hate when people tell us we're not
going to be something that you know,
that because we've sold it's all over.
Uh,
but looking from the outset,
I get their perspective.
I just wanted to prove them wrong.
Yeah. Yeah. It's a powerful motivator.
Yeah.
I think,
and part of taking that personality test
we talked about is understanding what
your motivators are because if
you know what your motivators are,
then you know how to get
yourself up in the morning.
How to work hard and had it right. And
you know what, things are not motivating,
but competition is one actually it's
interesting. There are two dimensions, uh,
of the personality test. There's
competition and then there's challenge.
And I didn't,
I always thought it was competitive.
It turns out I'm actually
not competitive at all.
I mean I'm a little competitive
but not that competitive.
I have very high scores on challenge,
which means setting goals for
yourself and trying to meet them.
But it's like self imposed
rather than comparative.
Writes it in sort of
an intrinsic motivator.
It's an internal motivator of like,
I want to go get this thing done.
So for me,
I think at that moment it was more about
self challenge to prove to myself that
I could do it. Um, and that
we could build this thing. Um,
it worked.
How did you learn to manage?
Uh, that's, that's a man and I had to,
yeah. So how does one learn to manage?
Because you, and it's not just time
within a larger company, right?
Because you can,
you can find plenty of people who make
the same mistakes for 20 years in a row.
Yeah.
And somehow managed to limp along
and sort of do decently despite their
weaknesses.
But when you sold the company,
how many employees do you have?
13.
13 and then I think I managed
like three of them. Right.
So you then went through, why do you
think of companies have hierarchy?
They're like,
I don't want to manage people.
You manage them and before you know
it you've got like a tree, you know,
90 layers deep on joking.
Well, I'd be, I don't,
I mean there is some truth to that I
think. But how did you learn to manage?
Where there any particular
lessons? Resources. Um,
so I have to say anything at all while
I was going to say my job was different
than most, which obviously is
an understatement, but like
I'm going to tell you the philosophy I
subscribe to and then I think you're,
the listeners can decide if it
makes sense for them. It might.
I decided that I had
nothing to lose because,
or at least I didn't think I had anything
to lose. Um, because I had my job,
I was excited about it.
I was running this thing and I knew what
I didn't know or at least knew that I
didn't know a bunch of stuff.
My philosophy was hiring the smartest
possible people were way better than me,
um, to work for me. And that feels weird
because you're like, I have no experience.
I've been doing this for two years.
How do I hire someone that has maybe 15
years of experience in the engineering
or 15 in, you know, operations
or the list goes on.
Um,
but the ironic thing is by hiring
people that were way better than me,
but like I would see myself working for
someday if they started a company that
actually you end up creating
the best possible team.
And I think that works because
I felt like I had job security.
So a lot of people are worried,
well if I hire great people beneath me,
then then maybe one of them will
take my job and I don't know where,
like the reality is on that spectrum in
the real world. Like I don't know. Um,
but I think that's actually one of the
issues I looked for most in the company,
which was, um, people
hiring down on purpose.
Like people do it reflexively,
they hire down, they're like, no,
I need someone with less experience
than me who they should be younger.
They should have less, fewer
years of experience. Right.
Cause I should coach them.
And actually if everyone hired up,
you'd have like the most bad ass company
in the world. So how do you manage that?
I guess my point is I found people that
were way better than me and the way I
managed was by managing the vision and
direction of the company and then asking
those people how to get there and making
sure those two things were connected at
all times. But I didn't have the
regular job of like, you know,
managing a bunch of new grads out of
college and like coaching them on their
careers, um, which exists in
mass in Silicon Valley. Um,
so I'm not sure my management
like experience mirrored that,
um, of most, but I think
there's a lot to learn,
which is hire really great people
that someday you want to have,
they should have your job.
So you hire these people if you
subscribe to this philosophy.
And then I imagine there are
different strategies and routines and
rules and so on that you put in place
to give structure and direction to this
team of all stars.
And so,
so one that I could ask about
would be meeting structure.
So in the course of prepping for this,
a nice bound this a few places,
but in the, in the New York Times,
feel free to fact check this, but,
uh, I'll just read this
briefly and then making,
I'd love to hear you elaborate on what
the meeting actually looks like and,
and how, how you handle it. So some of
the bottlenecks, this is from their time,
some of the bottlenecks the company is
addressing the law in the past year,
our internal,
for example,
Mister sister man is cofounder realized
that one of the primary holdups was
their own decision making.
So in the past three months they started
holding meetings in which they just
make a bunch of decisions and
then this is quoting Mr System.
We have a dock in which we list out the
inventory of decisions on products as if
it's stacked up in front of the
machine waiting to be processed.
Mr System said and then we have sessions
where we sit down and we'd decide you
just work through the decisions.
So this is something that you
might be able to do in an informal,
unmatched way when you have three
direct reports or 13 employees,
but as it grows it seems like this
type of systematizing could be really
important.
Can you describe
how a meeting like this functioned?
Totally and why names?
It's really funny for me to think of
myself as being a referenced as mister
sister. It's very, it's, it's very formal,
Mr System with inventory
of decisions. Um, okay.
So here's the context. Have you ever had
the book the goal, the goal, their goal?
I have not. Yeah. Um,
it is a book about basically
manufacturing and supply chain management.
It sounds really boring, but I
promise you it's really good. Um,
last name is gold rat. Uh, I
think it's cold, right? Yeah.
Who wrote the book and it's kind of an,
in fact, if you talk to business people,
a lot of people will say
it's their favorite book.
Like I wrote in one of my
weekly updates to the team.
I wrote that I was reading
this book and that I loved it.
And a bunch of people were
like, Oh, I love that book too.
So it's a business book that talks
about how to optimize a supply chains
basically. Um, but it's
written in narrative form,
which is kind of cheeky, right?
It's, it's not like a business,
it's a business book,
but it's written with a narrative.
Like there are characters
and it's actually pretty fun.
So I say, go have a read.
Um,
but what I realized in
reading this was that, uh,
any system is most constrained,
or at least the thesis of the book is
most constrained by the slowest process.
Um, I think they called it
a Herbie. Herbie, have you
ever heard that? I have, yes.
Because the beginning of the book kind
of like boy scouts. Yeah, exactly.
If you want to explain what it is,
I know we're getting there. Um,
how many times are boy scouts going to
come up in a podcast? Right. So, uh,
the narrative is that they're on some
trip and they like have these, uh,
boy scouts lined up. I
think it's like, you know,
the main character's son or something is,
was in the line of boy scouts and a,
and Herbie,
it might not be PC to talk about now,
but urby is a little overweight and he's
at, I see at the back, I don't know.
Basically they figure,
I think it,
the way it goes is no matter
where they put him in the line,
the line can only move as
fast as the slowest process.
That's kind of the takeaway. Okay.
Um, again, people who are super fans,
the goal can correct me on this,
but the essence of it is your slowest,
um, your slowest part in the chain
is always going to limit output.
In this case, the slowest boy scout
limits the progress the troop makes, um,
which isn't actually all that,
um,
isn't all that intuitive until you
read this book and you go through it.
So with decision making, what we realize
is a lot of things were coming to us,
but unless we would decide on an important
decision, it was basically like, uh,
inventory stacking up in front
of a machine that wasn't moving.
And of course,
the machine can output
products that people want to
go use until those decisions
get made. So it sounds,
again, really intuitive,
but if you think about a company as,
you know,
the raw materials go in and
raw materials or ideas, okay.
And they go through machines
that transform them into reality.
So they go from an idea to a mock
to, uh, you know, uh, a final, uh,
final draft to aversion,
to out testing with Beta testers
out to the real world. That,
actually what you need to do is make
sure all machines are running at highest
capacity,
including the one that moves ideas from
the idea pile to mocks from mocks to
actual.
Right.
So you worked on the chain and
we realized very early on, um,
in reading this book that a lot of
the lessons that usually applied to
manufacturing actually apply to
making decisions at a company as well.
I had actually forgotten about
that book until you mentioned it.
I'll have to pick it
up. Yeah. The goal, uh,
of a long list of books to tackle.
How do you choose books that
you're going to read it?
I know you've given a few examples of
things that you're interested in, uh,
but how do you filter the universe
of books to those who end up reading?
And I mean, you can maybe just pull up,
you could pull a few real examples from,
from uh, those you've read and it
can indicate how you got to those.
But is do you have a process for
selecting books? Well, first, uh,
or describe doing well
first I don't read fiction.
Not that there's anything
wrong with fiction.
And I know people that read a lot will
be like, what? You don't read fiction?
Come on, there's so many
grades. I don't know,
it just doesn't get me up in the morning.
So, uh, there we go. There it goes,
you know, a good portion of books, uh,
down to nonfiction, nonfiction books.
Then I asked myself what topics I care
deeply about or what things I really want
to learn. So for instance,
learning to fly like, okay,
what are the best books
to learn to fly? Or, uh,
if I want to learn about investing
or finance, what are the best books?
Or if I want to learn about productivity,
what are the best books?
And obviously Amazon is great for that
and you can read through reviews and, um,
but honestly a big part of
me reading is just like,
there's usually some outcome I want.
Like I want to be able to do x,
what do I have to read that will
teach me as fast as possible?
Because like with a book. Okay.
So with a class you got to like,
wait until the class happens,
go to the class and then wait
until the next class with a book,
you can literally like just get
through it in a week or a day or,
and then you can reread it and reread
it. And I just, I find that like,
if you want to learn a new skill,
there's nothing like sitting down with
a nonfiction book on that topic that's
uh, you know, well laid out
and, but sometimes, you know,
you got to call it,
I've,
I've been a quarter way through a bunch
of books on topics that I thought I was
going to like and just throwing them
out because I'm like to the trash. Uh,
so they don't, it doesn't always
work that way. Do you read, uh,
and if you don't, this isn't a
value judgment, uh, biographies.
Do you ever read biographies?
Okay. So, um, I have not read,
no, but I really want to. Okay.
So the one area that I want to
spend way more time on his history,
including biographies, which I
consider a form of history. Um,
although biographies can be fairly
selective in the history they tell that's
true of all history books.
Um, I feel like their
holiday, you a 41. Pretty sure I'm 41.
That's okay. We'll fact check that one.
I'll get back to, uh, I'm 35. Okay. Uh,
our lives are really short
compared to the history, uh,
recorded history and it turns
out if you look back in history,
things patterns emerge. I read this
great book called Lessons of history.
I was just have you read it? Will and
Ariel, fantastic short. It's excellent.
It's like a leaflet. Like you
could read it in today. Great.
There's some parts that I disagree with,
but for the most read that because Ray
Dalia recommended it. It's a great book.
Yeah. Yeah. I, the number of people I
meet that are like, they've read it.
And anyway,
the takeaway is that things happen
over and over again or at least certain
patterns emerge. And I guess what I'm
saying is if you look back at history,
you can learn a lot from
reading people's history,
whether it's a biography or a history
of a specific segment of companies.
So for instance,
I think if you want to study the
acquisitions of companies and where those
founders have gone and what they've done,
and more importantly,
what do most founders do
next after selling a company
and taking some months off?
How many take one month off? How many
take a year? How many take five years?
How many never emerge
again, right? Like, but how,
what are the differences between those
that decide to do something and those
that don't? So even in my own
exploration of what's next
in my life, I find myself not
reading necessarily biographies,
but I do read accounts of,
you know,
entrepreneurs that have launched
big things and none, you know,
new things in the future and those who
haven't. And I started asking myself like,
what are the patterns that emerge?
So, no, I don't read biographies yet,
but I want to. And, uh, and history,
I think more generally is a
super interesting topic. Uh,
there's some excellent
biographies out there. Uh, I,
I think you might enjoy a Gingiss Khan
and the making of the modern world. Okay.
Excellent.
Excellent book for a lot of reasons.
I'm trying to think of the ones that
had been recommended to me. Um, yeah,
I'll have to get back to you on that.
David McCullough has a lot of really
good biographies and the Wright brothers
and so on. Uh, it was actually given
to me by very, very successful, uh,
consumer packaged goods
entrepreneur here in Austin,
which turns out to be sort of ground zero
or the epicenter of a lot of CPG stuff.
So cool.
Yeah,
but isn't it interesting how many people
have so many similar patterns in their
lives?
And I think there's this great equalizer
when you realize what you are doing or
going through or whatever.
Well,
it might be super unique to
you and you're 35 or 41 years.
It actually turns out like it happens
over and over again to people on their
lives. Not everyone, but like,
it's occurred in the past and
you have a lot to learn from it.
That's basically my point and that,
that I think it's 120 page book.
Lessons of history is fantastic
place to start. I expected it,
I actually downloaded it as a kindle
book and let it sit there for months
because I expected it to be very dry
and it's a beautifully written book.
It's very impressed.
And then if you like that as a,
as a taste test and then you can go into
there, what is it like 10 or 20 volume,
uh, and said, look, he Demery of their
volumes, right? That's right. Yeah.
It's like the cliff notes the cliff.
Yeah. Okay. I'd like to ask you,
this is one of the questions that I had
been hoping to ask ever since we booked
the podcast.
And that is about advice that you give
to entrepreneurs that very few actually
take.
And I'll explain just by way of example.
Uh, I'm asked all the time how, how, uh,
various folks should launch books
where people come to me asking,
how should I launch a book?
How should I write a book?
How should I get a book published?
And I might tell them,
for instance,
don't try to write for the entire world.
If your goal is to hit the New
York Times bestseller list, right,
for like 10 to 20,000 people per week.
In other words,
you really only need to get the
flywheel spinning because people use the
bestseller list as a shopping list to,
to write a book that at least
20,000 people will love,
but they end up writing
something too general.
They end up writing something
to general. Uh, and uh,
I tell them to give a ton of buffer before
the book is published and to write it
in such a way that for instance,
it can be read modularly and then they
don't do that and they wonder why they
can't run excerpts. Uh,
and, uh, it's, it's,
it's been incredible to me how,
and I put together a blog post,
which just like how to write a best
selling book this year where I lay out the
exact playlist, uh, or not
playlist rather, but play book.
And nonetheless,
it's like one out of a hundred who
actually implement even a portion of the
steps.
Are there any particular bits of advice
or recommendations that you give to
entrepreneurs that you're surprised
aren't taken more seriously or actually
followed?
Yeah,
number one advice I always
give is to solve a problem.
So many people, uh, when
they found a company,
you found a company just to found a
company or they're like, I've got an idea,
ideas are not companies. Ideas are
not products. Like you're like,
well I'm going to combine this thing with
this trend and we're going to do this.
It's a cool idea.
And you know,
usually the warning signs
are that includes some
element of a current fad like
AI or something. Not that AI
is a fad, but like, you know,
it's a wave that's happening right now
that I think it's easy to make your
company somewhere interesting
if you're just like,
and it uses AI or like crypto or like
there always warning signs that I see with
the pitches that I,
that I hear from people when they include
those words and it's not backed up by
a clear problem that you're solving
for the person on the other side or the
company. On the other side,
the counterparty, right? Um,
so I always say, make sure you're
actually solving a problem.
Now there are different
ways that can be wrong.
It could be solved already really well,
in which case you're not solving a
problem. The idea might be great,
but you're not solving a problem.
It can be a really neat idea with not a
lot of people that need that problem to
be solved, in which case it's not
really a problem for the world. Right?
Maybe we could broaden this by saying,
solve a problem for the world, um,
or it just misunderstands
what people need.
Or it doesn't even take into account
what people need. You're just like, oh,
it sounds really cool. I'm going to
do this, this, and it's a hot market,
so I'm going to figure it out.
And the number of times I've seen
entrepreneurs go that direction because it
feels good to be part of the trend.
It feels good to see you have a
cool idea without asking yourself,
does this actually solve someone's
problem? Like, if I go talk to people,
it does this literally like relieve
people that this now exists.
The number of times I've seen people
ignore this advice, it's countless.
What's crazy to me is I feel like it's
our secret sauce at Instagram and I'm
like, this is great. Like we
can just keep doing this, right?
Like every product we work on
hopefully is solving someone's,
and I feel like I'm giving this advice
away for free, but no one's taking it.
That's, that's it's all also true
for nonfiction books, right? Yeah.
The number of books you
pick up and it's like,
I bought the book because
I have the problem.
You don't have to spend 80% of the book
describing the problem. You got it.
You got it.
Uh,
what are other common mistakes that you
observe among entrepreneurs or creators?
So we can make it, make it broader.
It doesn't have to be broader,
but people who are trying to do their
own thing, entrepreneurs or otherwise,
uh, what are some common mistakes
you see? And it could be,
it could be within the
venture back startup world,
but it could also be broader than that.
I think going at it alone is often I
mistake and that doesn't mean you have to
have a cofounder,
but not having a team is a mistake.
I see a bunch of people feeling like,
Oh, I'm just going to do this by myself.
I'm just going to it.
Um,
there's an incredible power
and having people around you,
even individuals who are like maybe the
face of their company have an incredible
team around them.
Uh,
and I think trying to do it all yourself
is like not only a recipe for getting
it wrong, but also a recipe for not
being able to get back up. I mean,
how do you get up when
you get punched down?
We'll sometimes having someone else
in the room with you to be like, yeah,
let's get up and get them.
You know, it helps. Um,
I think that's a mistake.
I see a lot. But, uh,
you know,
the crazy thing is that having gone
through it and making mistakes yourself,
it's not clear to me that like those are
all mistakes and every other situation.
So I'm trying to be careful
in overprescribing my
situation because there are
counter examples as well.
Sure.
That's the really important
point actually, uh,
that I think is worth underscoring
for folks. And that is for,
for nearly every rule that
someone might prescribe,
there's probably a counter example,
you know,
the se leader of which would prescribe
the exact opposite. Yeah. Right.
And so it's, it's, I
suppose in part finding
the rules that are compatible also with,
uh,
what you hold to be the core values
or philosophies that guide you.
Like being passionate about the product
or the service with the company.
Because that has some real practical
implications. If you're not passionate,
are you in fact going to be able to
summon the endurance, like you said,
to sort of walk through or around or
climb over the various walls are gonna pop
up? Probably not. Right. So
then you can find the examples.
It's sort of suit your personality in
the set of values that you've set out for
a given company. Uh, what, this is,
this is a metaphor question,
but if you could just a few more
questions and then we'll, we'll wrap up.
If you could put a,
a quote, a word, a question, anything
noncommercial on a billboard.
And really what I'm asking is to
get a message to billions of people,
which is crazy to think that you,
you can't actually do that now.
And so they supply forums
like, like Instagram. Uh,
but to get a message simultaneously to
billions of people could be an image.
What, what might you put on
that billboard? I don't know
if it sounds cheesy, but,
uh,
the advice that I got that has driven me
the entire way is follow your passion.
Like I cared so deeply about social
media and so deeply about photography and
there are so many people that were like,
social media is crowded,
photography is lame. You
know what I mean? That like,
the only way to get through those is
by loving the thing or the mission that
you're on. And, well, it again,
it sounds kind of cheesy.
Maybe we could wordsmith is
follow your passion and thing,
but like the number of people that don't
follow their passion because people
talk them out of it and I
think that's a crime right. At
of course you can't follow your passion
and not expect consequences. Like, listen,
if you're passionate is to go fly fishing
and you want to do that all the time,
that's great. But you often
know, okay, like can I pay
my bills? Right? Like can I,
there are,
there are constraints,
but if you've thought
through it and you love it,
there should be no one's
standing in your way. Yeah.
And like the number of people
that tried to stand in our way,
like they still like listen, even long
into Instagram, there were people,
you know, predicting our demise. And so,
I don't know, like at a certain point,
it's not like ignore the
haters. That could be the
other billboard by the way. Um,
it's, it's like you've got
to follow your passion.
As long as you've thought through it,
you've done the math, you think about it,
like go for it. And don't let people
stand in your way. You know, like,
it's just so sad when people don't
do that and life is short. Uh,
like you said,
I mean our lives are so short relative
to sort of the span of human history.
And I think that's another benefit
of reading history is it puts that in
perspective.
Like these lives are sort of the deep,
the flicker of I think in Novell brava
competence and like the flicker of a
firefly in the sort of scope of,
of history. It's really short,
really tiny. And I had this, uh,
this one coach who said to me,
he's like,
often people wake up when they have
someone close to them that dies or um,
or they come down with some really
serious illness and they realize all the
little things they were spending all
this time worried about don't matter
compared to these like
grave big things in life.
And it's important to
keep that perspective.
So I'm not trying to get
all like serious here,
but I think it's really important
to keep things in perspective.
And I think that, I dunno, like I guess
it's another word for maturity, right?
But, um, the faster you can get there,
the faster you realize a lot of what
you think matters doesn't matter.
And the things that you're not thinking
about matter a lot more than you're
giving them credit for.
Um,
which is why you should follow your
passion and love what you do every day.
Don't get me wrong, by the way, I want
to clarify. A lot of people are like,
you should love what you
do. And I agree, but I,
I think it's more you should love
what you're shooting for. Yeah.
Because work is hard. Yeah. It
can be miserable at times. I mean,
nothing great in this
world ever came easy.
Like if you want to be
an amazing guitarist,
you're not going to get there easily.
A Trane really hard get shot down a bunch,
right?
Like they're all like,
it's a universal law in the world that
great things come with a lot of work.
And what you have to do is I think love
the thing you're shooting for rather
than the everyday of the thing. But
I think a lot of people are like, oh,
I should love every day. It's
like, no, no. Everyday it can be,
there are a lot of hard days ahead.
The thing that gets you through those
days is loving the outcome you're shooting
for and it,
and being excited to get there Sunday.
Okay.
Well, Kevin, I'm excited
to see what you hatch next.
Thank you. Let's see if after you've
done your pattern recognition on this,
a Meta analysis of founders who do
various things at various points.
I'll be curious to see where
you end up. Uh, but uh,
do you have any closing remarks?
Anything you'd like to ask people to do?
Any thing at all that you'd like to
say before we wrap up? No pressure,
right. You don't get, you don't have to
ask all your friends about this podcast.
Perfect. I like that recommendation.
Awesome. Thanks for having me.
This was a lot of fun.
Yeah.
Good to see you again and to everybody
listening for links to everything that
came up,
the books and all sorts of other things,
the names of people and so on.
We will provide links to all of
that in the show notes. As always,
at tim.blog/podcast,
you can just search Kevin or system
and it will pop right up and until next
time,
thank you for listening.