Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
You posted a question.
I'm a cybernetic organism living tissue.
This episode is brought
to you by four sigmatic.
You might remember four sigmatic
for their mushroom coffee,
which was created by those
clever finish founders.
And when I first mentioned
that coffee on this podcast,
the product sold out in less than a week
at lights you up like a Christmas tree,
which can be really useful.
However,
recently I've been testing the opposite
side of the spectrum of new product and
that is their Reishi mushroom elixir
to help me end my day to get to sleep.
As you guys may know,
longtime listeners,
at least I struggled with insomnia for
decades. I have a largely fixed that,
but still shutting off my monkey
brain has never been easy,
still isn't easy very often.
And I found Reishi,
which had been fascinated by for
a few years now, has been very,
very effective and calming
their old formula. However,
forcing Maddix old formula included
Stevia. And I like to avoid sweeteners,
all sweeteners for a host of reasons.
And I then just ping them and asked,
hey guys,
I would love to experiment with
this and maybe actually suggested,
but I'd like a version without
sweeteners if you'd be open to it,
if too much of a headache,
don't worry.
And they are always game
for experimentation.
So they created a special custom version
without the Stevia, without sweeteners.
Now it is part of my nightly routine.
Their ratio looks or comes
in single serving packets,
which are perfect for travel.
And in fact I'm about to leave the
country right now and I have a packet in
front of me. This just going to
sit in the end of my carry on bag.
You only need hot water and it mixes very,
very easily.
Here's some recommended copy
that they put in the read.
So I'm going to read it and then
I'll give you my take quote,
a warning for those in
the experimental mindset,
Reishi is strong and bitter in
parentheses, like any great medicine.
So if the bitterness is too much,
I recommend trying it with honey and or
nut milk such as almond milk and quote.
So I'm going to say no,
you should suck it up and you should drink
the tea because it's not that bitter.
And maybe you should take the advice
of all Chinese people when they're
criticizing young. When they
say [inaudible] sure. Cool.
Which means you're not
able to eat bitterness.
Bitter is in many cases and indication
of things that help liver detoxification
and so on.
Not saying that's the case here,
but I've tested this ratio
lecture on family members,
on friends, everybody has liked it. It's
a little bit earthy. It's not that hard.
So I would just say suck it up and no,
don't put in honey or milk or any of
that shit. Just drink the goddamn tea.
It's delicious I think. Right? If
you like poo air, that kind of stuff,
that type of tea, you're going
to dig it. So just try it. Okay.
Back to then my read. If you'd like
to naturally improve your sleep,
both onset and quality,
I think naturally you might just enjoy
this reishi elixir without any sweet
nurse. It has organic, Reishi
extract, organic fueled, mint extract,
organic rose hips extract, organic
Tulsi extract. And that's it.
No fancy stuff, no artificial watching
McCall it anything. So check it out.
Go to foursigmatic.com forward slash
and Ferris and get 20% off this special
batch. I don't know if they're gonna
be making much more of this, uh,
it since it was made specifically for
you guys to do me a favor and try it out
so that they continue to be
open to experimenting with
me to create products for
you guys. Specifically. Check it
out. Four sigmatic, that's Fou, s, I,
g m, a t, I c.com forward
slash Ferris, F, e R, r,
I s.
S and get 20% off the special batch and a,
you must use the code Ferris to
receive your discount. F. E R, r,
I. S. S. So again,
go to foursigmatic.com
forward slash Ferris and then
use code Ferris for 20% off
of this rare exclusive,
limited run of Reishi mushroom elixir
for nighttime routines with out any
sweeteners. Enjoy. Hello.
Am I sexy?
Little mink says,
this is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job generally speaking,
to deconstruct world class performers of
different types to tease out the habits,
routines,
favorite books,
and so on that you can use this episode,
I'm going to showcase one
of my recent favorite books,
and by recent I say in the last few years,
there are not many books that I highlight,
something within nearly every page,
much less than printing
out those highlights,
putting them together with a binder clip
and carrying around at various points
to review and to journal
on and so forth and so on.
That book that I'm referring to is
essential ISM subtitled the disciplined
pursuit of less.
It is a fantastic book.
I was very impressed the
first time I read it.
I've been continually
impressed when I've rewrite it.
It's had an impact in how I approached
various types of problems and
opportunities, so I want to share
two chapters from that book with you.
Read by the author Greg Mckeown,
Gregory McEuen on Twitter.
Let me spell that for you.
It's a little tricky for most yanks,
Gregory McKeown, m a, C, k, e, O, w, n,
also Gregory mccuin.com. Uh, and uh,
I'm lying.
It is not Gregory [inaudible] dot com
it's Greg mckeown.com so you can figure it
out.
There aren't too many Greg or Gregory
McKeown's running around with essential
ism.
The two chapters that I'm going to share
are related to how to say no gracefully
and how to uncommit because I think it
is very easy to listen to podcasts with
success stories and tactics and habits
and to create an ever growing or never
ending to do list.
You might have 73 different things on
the draft version of your morning routine
and that is stressful.
So I would like to help you visa vi
Greg and his book essential ism to maybe
shorten your to do list and lengthen
your not to do list. So again,
these two chapters are from essential ism,
subtitle,
the disciplined pursuit of less.
Maybe sometime I will have Greg
on the podcast discuss further,
but this episode is experimental.
I am considering showcasing books,
not brand new books.
So publishers who are
listening do not hammer.
We with a thousand pitches they're not
going to get in, will not be on. Uh,
but books that were published at least a
few years ago showcasing books that, uh,
I have read at least two
times and this is one of them.
So let me know if you like it. And without
further ado, how to say no gracefully.
How to uncommit by Greg McKeown.
Chapter 11.
Dare the power of a graceful.
No.
Courage is grace under pressure.
Ernest Hemingway,
the right,
no spoken at the right time can
change the course of history
in just one example of many Rosa parks.
Quiet but resolute refusal to give up her
seat on a segregated Montgomery bus at
exactly the right moment coalesced into
forces that propelled the civil rights
movement as Ponch recalls.
When the bus driver saw me still sitting,
he asked if I was going to
stand up and I said, no, I'm not
contrary to popular belief.
Her courageous,
no did not grow out of a particularly
assertive tendency or personality in
general.
In fact when she was made a secretary to
the president of the Montgomery chapter
of the Naacp,
she explained I was the only woman there
and they needed a secretary and I was
too timid to say no.
Rather,
her decision on the bus grew out at a
deep conviction about what deliberate
choice she wanted to make.
In that moment when the bus driver
ordered her out of her seat, she said,
I felt a determination cover my
body like a quilt on a winter night.
She did not know how her decision would
spark a movement with reverberations
around the world,
but she did know her own mind.
She knew even as she was being arrested
that it was the very last time that I
would ever ride in humiliation of this
kind of avoiding that humiliation was
worth the risk of incarceration.
Indeed to her, it was essential.
It is true that we are hopefully unlike
the to find ourselves facing a situation
like the one faced by Rosa parks.
Yet we can be inspired by her.
We can think of her when we need
the courage to dare to say no.
We can remember her strength of conviction
when we need to stand our ground and
the face of social pressure to
capitulate to the nonessential.
Have you ever felt a tension between
what you felt was right and what someone
was pressuring you to do?
Have you ever felt the conflict between
your internal conviction and an external
action?
Have you ever said yes when you meant
no simply to avoid conflict or friction?
Have you ever felt too scared or timid
to turn down an invitation or a request
from a boss, colleague, friend, neighbor,
or family member for fear of disappointing
them? If you have, you're not alone.
Navigating these moments with courage
and grace is one of the most important
skills to master in becoming an
essentialist and one of the hardest.
I did not set out to write
a chapter about courage,
but the deprive looked at
the subject of essentialism.
The more clearly I have seen courage
as key to the process of elimination
without courage. The disciplined
pursuit of less is just lip service.
It is just the stuff of one more dinner
party conversation. It is skin deep.
Anyone can talk about the importance of
focusing on the things that matter most
and many people do, but to see
people who dare to live. It is rare.
I say this without judgment.
We have good reasons to fear saying no,
we worry. We'll miss out on
a great opportunity. We're
scared of rocking the boat,
stirring things up,
burning bridges.
We can't bear the thought of disappointing
someone we respect and like none of
this makes us a bad person.
It's a natural part of being human.
Yet as hard as it can be to say no to
someone failing to do so can cause us to
miss out on something far more important.
A woman named Cynthia once told me a
story about the time her father had made
plans to take her on a
night out in San Francisco,
12 year old Cynthia and her father
had been planning the date for months.
They had a whole itinerary planned down
to the minute she would attend the last
hour of his presentation and then meet
him at the back of the room at about four
30 and leave quickly.
Before everyone tried to talk to him,
they would catch a trolley car
to Chinatown, eat Chinese food,
their favorite shop for a souvenir,
see the sites for a while and then
catch a flick as a dad like to say.
Then they would grab a taxi back to the
hotel, jump in the pool for a quick swim.
Her Dad was famous for sneaking
in when the pool was closed,
order a hot fudge Sundae from room
service and watched the late late show.
They discussed details over
and over before they left.
The anticipation was part
of the whole experience.
This was all going according to plan
until as a father was leaving the
convention center. He ran into an old
college friend and business associate.
It had been years since they had seen
each other and Cynthia watched as they
embraced enthusiastically,
his friends said, in effect,
I am so glad you are doing some
work with our company. Now.
When Lois and I heard about it,
we thought it would be perfect.
We want to invite you and
of course Cynthia to get a
spectacular seafood dinner
down at the wharf. Cynthia's
father responded, Bob,
it's so great to see you dinner
at the wharf. Sounds great.
Synthio was crestfallen.
Daydreams of trolley rides and ice cream
Sundaes evaporated in an instant plus
she hated seafood and she
could just imagine how bored
she would be listening to
the adults talk all night,
but then her father continued,
but not tonight. Cynthia and I
have a special date plan, don't we?
He winked at Cynthia and grabbed her
hand and they ran out of the door and
continued with what was an
unforgettable night in San Francisco.
As it happens, Cynthia's father was the
management thinker, Stephen r Covey,
author of the seven habits of highly
effective people who had passed away only
weeks before. Cynthia told me this
story, so it was with deep emotion.
She recalled that
evening in San Francisco.
His simple decision bonded him to me
forever because I knew what mattered most
to him was me. She said, Stephen r Covey,
one of the most respected and widely
read business thinkers of his generation
was an essential list.
Not only did he routinely teach essential
list of principles like the main thing
is to keep the main thing,
the main thing to important leaders
and heads of state around the world.
He lived them and in this moment
of leaving them with his daughter,
he made a memory that literally
outlasted his lifetime.
Seeing with some perspective
his decisions seems obvious,
but many in his shoes would have accepted
the friends invitation for fear of
seeming rude or ungrateful or passing up
a rare opportunity to dine with an old
friend.
So why is it so hard in the moment to
dad to choose what is essential over what
is non essential?
One simple answer is we are unclear about
what is essential when this happens,
we become defenseless.
On the other hand,
when we have strong internal clarity,
it is almost as if we have a force field
protecting us from the non essentials
coming at us from all directions.
With Rosa.
It was a deep moral clarity that gave
her unusual courage of conviction with
Steven.
It was the clarity of his vision for
the evening with his loving daughter.
In virtually every instance,
clarity about what is essential fuels
us with the strength to say no to the
nonessentials.
Yeah.
Essentially
a second reason why it is hard to choose.
What is essential in the moment is
as simple as an innate fear of social
awkwardness. The fact is we as humans are
wired to want to get along with others.
After all,
thousands of years ago when we all
lived in tribes of hunter gatherers,
our survival depended on it and while
conforming to what people in a group
expect of us,
what psychologists call normative,
conformity is no longer a
matter of life and death.
The desire is still deeply
ingrained in us. This is why,
whether it's an old friend who invites
you to dinner or a boss who asks you to
take on an important high profile project
or a neighbor who begs you to help
with the PTA bake sale.
The very thought of saying no,
literally brings us physical discomfort.
We feel guilty.
We don't want to let someone down.
We are worried about
damaging the relationship,
but these emotions and muddle our clarity.
They distract us from the reality of
the fact that either we can say no and
regret it for a few minutes or we
can say yes and regret it for days,
weeks, months, or even years.
The only way out of this trap is to
learn to say no firmly, resolutely,
and yet gracefully because once we do,
we find not only that our fears of
disappointing or angering others were
exaggerated,
but the people actually respect us more.
Since becoming an essentialist,
I have found it almost universally true
that people respect and admire those
with the courage of conviction to say no.
Peter Drucker in my view,
the father of modern management thinking
was also a master of the art of the
graceful. No. When me, hi, sent me. Hi.
The Hungarian professor most well known
for his work on flow reached out to
interview a series of creative
individuals for a book he was writing on
creativity.
Truckers response was interesting enough
to me high that he quoted it verbatim.
I am greatly honored and flattered by
your kind letter of February 14th for I
have admired you and your work for many
years and I've learned much from it,
but my dear professor [inaudible] hi,
I am afraid I have to disappoint you.
I could not possibly answer your
questions. I am told I am creative.
I don't know what that means.
I just keep on plodding.
I hope you will not think me
presumptuous or rude if I say that.
One of the secrets of productivity in
which I believe whereas I do not believe
in creativity,
is to have a very big waste paper basket
to take care of all invitations such as
yours.
Productivity in my experience consists
of not doing anything that helps the work
of other people,
but to spend all one's time on the work.
The good Lord has fitted
one to do and to do well.
A true essential list.
Peter Drucker believed that people
are effective because they say no.
Okay.
Nonessentialist say yes because of
of social awkwardness and pressure.
They say yes automatically without
thinking often in pursuit of the Rusch one
gets from having please someone,
but essential is know that after
the rush comes the Pang of regret,
they know they will soon feel bullied and
resentful both at the other person and
that themselves. Eventually they will
wake up to the unpleasant reality.
That's something more important must now
be sacrificed to accommodate this new
commitment. Of course, the point
is not to say no to all requests.
The point is to say no
to the nonessential.
So we can say yes to the
things that really matter.
It is to say no frequently
and gracefully to everything,
but what is truly vital,
a nonessentialist avoid saying no to
avoid feeling social awkwardness and
pressure and essentially
just dares to say no firmly,
resolutely and gracefully and
nonessentialist says yes to everything and
essentially just says yes only
to the things that really matter.
So how do we learn to say no gracefully.
Below are general guidelines followed
by a number of specific scripts for
delivering the graceful no.
Yeah.
Separate the decision
from the relationship.
When people ask us to do something,
we can confuse the request with
our relationship with them.
Sometimes they seem so interconnected.
We forget that denying the request is
not the same as denying for person.
Only once we separate the
decision from the relationship,
can we make a clear decision and then
separately find the courage and compassion
to communicate it.
Okay.
Saying no gracefully doesn't
have to mean using the word no.
Essentially lists choose no
more often than they say no.
There may be a time when the most
graceful way to say no is to simply say a
blunt no, but whether it's, I am
flattered that you thought of me,
but I'm afraid I don't have the
bandwidth or I would very much like to,
but I'm over committed.
There are a variety of ways of refusing
someone clearly and politely without
actually using the word know.
Later in the chapter you'll find more
examples of ways to gracefully word,
y'all know,
focus on the trade off.
The more we think about what we are
giving up, when we say yes to someone,
the easier it is to say no.
If we have no clear sense of the
opportunity cost, in other words,
the value of what we are giving up,
then it is especially easy to fall
into the nonessential trap of telling
ourselves we can get it all done.
We can't a graceful no grows out of a
clear but unstated calculation of the
trade off. Remind yourself that
everyone is selling something.
This doesn't mean you
have to be cynical about,
I don't mean to imply
people shouldn't be trusted.
I'm simply saying everyone
is selling something.
An idea of viewpoint and opinion
in exchange for your time.
Simply being aware of what is being
sold allows us to be more deliberate in
deciding whether we want to buy it.
Make your peace with the fact that saying
no often requires trading popularity
for respect.
Okay.
When you say no, there is usually a
short term impact on the relationship.
After all, when someone asks for
something and doesn't get it,
his or her immediate reaction may be
annoyance or disappointment or even anger.
This downside is clear. The
potential upside, however,
is less obvious when the initial annoyance
or disappointment or anger wears off.
The respect kicks in.
When we pushed back effectively,
it shows people that our
time is highly valuable.
It distinguishes the
professional from the amateur.
A case in point is the time that graphic
designer Paul rand had the guts to say
no to Steve Jobs when jobs was looking
for a logo for the company. Next,
he asked rand,
who's work included the logos for IBM
ups and Ron Westinghouse and ABC to come
up with a few options, but ran, didn't
want to come up with a few options.
He wanted to design just
one option. Saran said, no,
I will solve your problem for you and
you will pay me and you don't have to use
the solution. If you want
options, go talk to other people,
but I will solve the problem the best way.
I know.
How do you use it or not?
That's up to you.
Not surprisingly,
[inaudible] solved the problem and
created the jewel logo jobs wanted,
but the real lesson here is the effect
Rans pushback had on jobs who later said
a rand.
He is one of the most professional
people I've ever worked with in the sense
that he had thought through all of the
formal relationship between a client and
a professional such as himself
ran took a risk when he said no.
He bet a short term popularity loss for
a long term gain in respect and it paid
off
essentially just accept they cannot be
popular with everyone all of the time.
Yes.
Saying no respectfully,
reasonably and gracefully can
come at a short term social cost,
but part of living the way of the
essential list is realizing respect is far
more valuable than
popularity in the long run.
Yeah.
Remember the tick clear. No can be more
graceful than a vague or noncommittal.
Yes.
As anyone who has ever been
on the receiving end of
this situation knows a clear
I am going to pass on.
This is far better than not getting back
to someone or stringing them along with
some noncommittal answer.
Like I will try to make this
work or I might be able to.
When you know you can't,
being vague,
not the same as being graceful
and delaying the eventual no,
we'll only make it that much harder and
the recipient that much more resentful.
The no repertoire,
remember essential list.
Don't say no,
just occasionally it is a part of their
regular repertoire to consistently say
no with grace.
Then it helps to have a variety of
responses to call upon following our eight
responses.
You can put in your no repertoire
one the awkward pause instead of being
controlled by the threat of an awkward
silence. Own it. Use it as a
tool. When a request comes to you.
Obviously this works only in person.
Just pause for a moment.
Count to three before delivering your
verdict or if you get a bit more bold,
simply wait for the other
person to fill the void
to the soft no or the no,
but I recently received an
email inviting me to coffee.
I replied, I am consumed with writing
my book right now, Smiley face,
but I would love to get together.
Once the book is finished,
let me know if we can get together
towards the end of the summer.
Email is also a good way to
start practicing saying no,
but because it gives you the chance
to draft and redraft, y'all know,
to make it as graceful as possible.
Plus many people find that the
distance of email reduces the fear of
awkwardness.
Three,
let me check my calendar
and get back to you.
One leader I know found her time being
hijacked by other people all day.
A classic nonessentialist.
She was capable and smart
and unable to say no,
and as a result,
she soon became a goto person.
People would run up to her and say,
could you help with x project meaning
to be a good citizen? And she said yes,
but soon she felt burdened with
all of these different agendas.
Things changed for her.
When she learned to use a new phrase,
let me check my calendar
and get back to you.
It gave her the time to pause and
reflect and ultimately reply that she was
regretfully unavailable.
It enabled her to take back control of
her own decisions rather than be rushed
into a yes when she was asked
for use email bounce backs.
It is totally natural and expected to
get an auto response when someone is
traveling or out of the office. Really
this is the most socially acceptable? No,
there is. People aren't saying they
don't want to reply to your email.
They're just saying they can't get
back to you for a period of time,
so why limit these to vacations and
holidays? When I was writing this book,
I sent an email bounce back with
the subject line in monk mode.
The email said,
dear friends,
I'm currently working on a new book which
has put enormous burdens on my time.
Unfortunately, I am unable to respond
in the manner I would like for this.
I Apologize, Greg, and guess what?
People seem to adapt to my temporary
absence and non-responsiveness just fine.
Five say yes.
What should I do?
Prioritize saying no to a senior
leader at work is almost unthinkable,
even laughable for many people.
However,
when saying yes is going to compromise
your ability to make the highest level of
contribution to your work, it is
also your obligation. In this case,
it is not only reasonable to say no,
it is essential.
One effective way to do that is to
remind your superiors what you would be
neglecting if you said yes and forced
them to grapple with the trade off.
For example, if your manager
comes to you and asks you to do x,
you can respond with, yes, I'm
happy to make this the priority.
Which of these other projects should I
de prioritize to pay attention to this
new project?
Or simply say I would want to do a great
job and given my other commitments,
I wouldn't be able to do a job I
was proud of. If I took this on,
I know a leader who received
this response from a subordinate.
There was no way he wanted
to be responsible for
disrupting this productive and
organized employee,
so he took the nonessential work project
back and gave it to someone else who
was less organized.
Six say it with humor.
I recently was asked by a friend to
join him in training for a marathon.
My response was simple. Nope. He laughed
a little and said, ah, you practice.
What you preach.
Just goes to show how useful it is to
have a reputation as an essentialist.
Seven use the words
you are welcome to ECS.
I am willing to why for example,
you are welcome to borrow my car.
I'm willing to make sure
the keys are here for you.
By this you are also saying
I won't be able to drive you.
You are saying what you will not do but
you are couching it in terms of what you
are willing to do.
This is a particularly good
way to navigate a request
you would like to support
somewhat but cannot throw
your full weight behind.
I particularly like this construct because
it also expresses a respect for the
other person's ability to
choose as well as your own.
It reminds both parties
of the choices they have
eight I can't do it,
but x might be interested.
It is tempting to think that
our help is uniquely invaluable,
but often people requesting something
don't really care if we are the ones who
help them as long as they get the help.
Kay Krill,
the CEO of an Inc Aka Ann Taylor and
loft women's clothing retailers used to
have a terrible time saying no to
social invitations. As a result,
she would end up at networking events.
She had no interest in attending.
She would find herself going to office
parties and regretting it the moment she
got there.
Then one day,
one of her mentors came to her and told
her that she had to learn to jettison
the people and things of her life that
just didn't matter and that doing so
would allow her to put 100% of her energy
into the things that had meaningful
her.
That advice liberated her.
Now she is able to pick and choose
with practice politely declining.
An invitation has become easy for her.
K explains,
I say no very easily because I
know what is important to me.
I only wish that I learned how
to do that earlier in my life.
Saying no is its own
leadership capability.
It is not just a peripheral skill.
As with any ability,
we start with limited experience.
We are novices at no.
Then we learn a couple of
basic techniques. We make
mistakes, we learn from them,
we develop more skills.
We keep practicing.
After a while we have a whole repertoire
available at our disposal and in time
we have gained mastery of
a type of social art form.
We can handle almost any request from
almost anybody with grace and dignity.
Tom [inaudible], the former CEO of
Heidrick and struggles once said to me,
we need to learn the slow
yes and the quick no.
Chapter 12 uncommit win
big by cutting your losses.
Half of the troubles of this life can
be traced to saying yes too quickly and
not saying no soon enough.
Josh billings
by any estimation.
The Concorde jet was a
striking achievement in
aeronautical engineering aboard
this passenger plane.
You could fly from London to New
York in as little as two hours,
52 minutes and 59 seconds.
That's less than half the time of a
traditional plain making the Concorde,
the fastest passenger plane in the world.
Unfortunately,
it was also an extraordinary
financial failure. Of course,
many great ideas,
innovations and products are,
but what made this one different was
that it consistently lost money for more
than four decades.
Yet each time it went over budget,
the French and British governments
poured more and more money in.
They did this even knowing that the
chance of recouping their continued
investments,
let alone the original expenditures
were minuscule with the planes,
limited seating, few orders coming
in, and the high cost of production.
It was clear that even
with exaggerated estimates,
the project would be profitable.
Indeed,
when the British cabinet papers were
released under the 30 year rule,
they revealed that government ministers
at the time knew the investment could
not stand on normal economic grounds.
Why would intelligent,
capable British and French government
officials continued to invest in what was
clearly a losing proposition for so long.
One reason is a very common psychological
phenomenon called sunk cost bias.
Sunk cost bias is the tendency
to continue to invest time,
money,
or energy into something we know is a
losing proposition simply because we have
already incurred or sunk a
cost that cannot be recouped.
But of course this can easily become
a vicious cycle. The more we invest,
the more determined we become to see it
through and see our investment pay off.
The more we invest in something,
the harder it is to let go.
The sunk costs for developing and building
the Concorde were around $1 billion.
Yeah,
yeah. The more money the British and
French governments poured into it,
the harder it was to walk away.
Individuals are equally
vulnerable to sunk cost bias.
It explains why we'll continue to sit
through a terrible movie because we've
already paid the price of a ticket.
It explains why we continue to pour
money into a home renovation that never
seems to near completion.
It explains why we will continue to wait
for a bus or a subway train that never
comes instead of hailing a cab and
it explains why we invest in toxic
relationships even when our
efforts only make things worse.
Examples like this abound.
Consider this somewhat bizarre story of
a man named Henry Gribbon who recently
spent his entire life savings $2,600 in
total at a carnival game trying to win
an oversize banana.
The more he spent,
the more determined he
became to when Henry said,
you just get caught up in the hole.
I've got to win my money back.
But it didn't turn out that way.
The more he invested in trying to
win this utterly non essential item,
the harder it was for him to walk away.
Have you ever continued to invest time
or effort in a nonessential project
instead of cutting your losses?
Have you ever continued to pour money
into an investment that wasn't panning out
instead of walking away?
Have you ever kept plodding down a
dead end because you could not admit,
I shouldn't have pursued this direction
in the first place ever been stuck in a
cycle of throwing good money after bad.
A nonessentialist can't break free of
traps like bees and essentially list has
the courage and confidence to admit his
or her mistakes and uncommit no matter
the sunk costs.
A nonessentialist asks,
why stop now when I've already invested
so much in this project and essential
list asks, if I weren't already
invested in this project,
how much would I invest in it?
Now in nonessentialist
thinks if I just keep trying,
I can make this work
okay
and essentially stinks.
What else could I do with this
time or money if I pulled the plug?
Now a nonessentialist hates admitting
to mistakes and essential list is
comfortable with cutting losses,
sunk cost bias,
while all too common isn't the only
nonessentialist trap to watch out for.
Below are several other common traps
and tips for how to extricate yourself
politely, gracefully,
and with minimal cost.
Avoiding commitment traps.
Beware of the endowment effect.
A sense of ownership is a powerful thing.
As the saying goes,
nobody in the history of the
world has washed their rental car.
This is because of something
called the endowment effect.
Our tendency to undervalue things that
aren't ours and to overvalue things
because we already own them.
In one study demonstrating the
power of the endowment effect,
the Nobel Prize winning researcher,
Daniel Conaman and colleagues randomly
gave coffee mugs to only half the
subjects in an experiment.
The first group was asked how much they
would be willing to sell them Mug for
while the second group was asked what
they would be willing to pay for it.
It turned out that the students who owned
the mugs refuse to sell for less than
$5 and 25 cents.
While those went out,
the cups were willing to pay only
$2 and 25 cents to $2 and 75 cents.
Okay.
The mere fact of ownership,
in other words,
caused the McGowan is to value the
objects more highly and made them less
willing to part with
them in your own life.
I'm sure you can think of items
that seem to be more valuable.
The moment you think
about giving them away.
Think of a book on your shelf you haven't
read in years or a kitchen appliance
still sitting in the box or the
sweater you got from aunt Mildred,
but never wore whether or not you
get any use or enjoyment out of them
subconsciously.
The very fact that they are yours makes
you value the more highly than you would
if they didn't belong to you.
Unfortunately,
we have this bias when it comes
to nonessential activities
as well as belongings.
The project that isn't getting anywhere
at work seems that much more critical
when we're the team leader on it.
The commitment to volunteer at the local
bake sale becomes harder to get out of
when we're the one who put
the fundraiser together.
When we feel we own an activity,
it becomes harder to uncommit.
Nonetheless, here is a useful
tip. Pretend you don't own it yet.
Tom Stafford describes a simple
antidote to the endowment effect.
Instead of asking how
much do I value this item,
we should ask if I did not own this item,
how much would I pay to obtain it?
We can do the same for opportunities
and commitment. Don't ask,
how will I feel if I miss
out on this opportunity,
but rather if I did not
have this opportunity,
how much would I be willing to sacrifice
in order to obtain it? Similarly,
we can ask if I wasn't already
involved in this project,
how hard would I work to get on it?
Yeah,
get over the fear of waste.
How Arcs,
a professor of psychology at Ohio State
University who studies judgment in
decision making was puzzled by an enigma.
Why are adults so much more vulnerable to
the sunk cost bias than young children?
The answer he believes a
lifetime to exposure to the
don't waste rule so that by
the time we are adults,
we are trained to avoid appearing
wasteful even to ourselves.
Abandoning a project that you've invested
a lot in fields like you've wasted
everything and waste is
something we're told to avoid.
Oc said to illustrate this,
he gave the following scenario
to a group of participants,
assumed that you have spent $100 on a
ticket for a weekend ski trip to Michigan.
Several weeks later you buy a $50 ticket
for a weekend ski trip to Wisconsin.
You think you will enjoy the Wisconsin
ski trip more than the Michigan ski trip.
As you are putting your newly purchased
Wisconsin ticket in your wallet,
you notice that the Michigan ski trip and
the Wisconsin Ski trip up for the same
weekend, it's too late to
sell or attorney the ticket.
You must choose which to use.
When asked which ski trip will you go on?
More than half said they would
opt for the more expensive trip,
even though they would enjoy it less.
They're faulty.
Reasoning was that using the cheaper
ticket would be wasting more money than
using the expensive ticket.
It's natural not to want to let go
of what we wasted on a bad choice,
but when we don't,
we do myselves to keep wasting even more.
Instead,
admit failure to begin success.
I remember a friend who would never stop
to ask for directions because he could
never admit he was lost,
so we would waste time and energy driving
around in circles, getting nowhere,
the epitome of a nonessential activity.
Only when we admit we have made a
mistake and committing to something,
can we make a mistake of part of
our past when we remain in denial?
On the other hand,
we continue to circle pointlessly.
There should be no shame in
admitting to a mistake after all,
we really are only admitting that
we are now wiser than we once were.
Yeah,
stop to force a fit
in the movie.
Tootsie.
Dustin Hoffman plays a struggling
actor who was trying to get work.
The movie begins comically with a series
of failed auditions at one he is told
we need someone a little older.
At the next year's told,
we're looking for someone younger.
Then at the next,
you're the wrong height to which
she responds, I can be taller.
The executive responds, no, we're
looking for somebody shorter,
desperate to make it work.
Hoffman's character explains, look,
I don't have to be this tall.
See I'm wearing lifts.
I can be shorter for the
executive also insists. I know,
but we're looking for somebody different,
still persistent.
The would be apt to pushes back again,
I can be different.
The point is that we often act like
Dustin Hoffman's character by trying too
hard to be something we're not, whether
in our personal or professional lives.
It is all too tempting to force
something that is simply a mismatch.
The solution
get a neutral second opinion.
When we get so emotionally hung up on
trying to force something that is not the
right fit, we can often
benefit from a sounding board,
someone who is not emotionally involved
in the situation and unaffected by the
choice we make can give us the permission
to stop forcing something that is
clearly not working out.
I once wasted months of effort trying
to force a project that just wasn't
working out. Looking back, the more I
put into it, the worst things became,
but my irrational response
was to invest still more.
I thought I can make this work.
I did not want to accept I
had been wasting my effort.
I finally shared my frustration with a
friend who had the advantage of being
emotionally removed from the project,
someone who wasn't burdened with the sunk
costs and could evaluate my decisions
with some perspective.
After listening to me he said,
you're not married to this and with those
simple words I was liberated to stop
investing in a nonessential,
okay
be aware of the status quo bias,
the tendency to continue doing something
simply because we have always done it
is sometimes called the status quo bias.
I once worked at a company that used an
employee evaluation system that seemed
to me so woefully outdated that I became
curious about how long it had been in
place as I searched for
its creator in the company.
I found that nobody up to and including
the longstanding head of HR knew of its
origin more shocking. Still in the
10 years she had been at the company,
nobody had once questioned the system.
It's all too easy to blindly accept
and not bother to question commitments
simply because they have already been
established. One cure for the status quo.
Bias is borrowed from world of accounting
applies zero based budgeting.
Typically when accountants
allocate a budget,
they use last year's budget as the
baseline for the next year's projection,
but with zero based budgeting
they use zero as the baseline.
In other words, every item in the proposed
budget must be justified from scratch.
While this takes more effort,
it has many advantages.
It efficiently allocates resources on
the basis of needs rather than history.
It detects exaggerated budget requests.
It draws attention to obsolete operations
and it encourages people to be clear
in their purpose and how their
expenses aligned to that project.
You can apply zero based budgeting to
your own endeavors instead of trying to
budget your time on the basis
of existing commitments.
Assume that all bets are off.
All previous commitments are gone.
Then begin from scratch asking
which you would add today.
You can do this with everything from
the financial obligations you have to
project. You are committed to
even relationships you are in.
Every use of time, energy or
resources has to justify itself a new.
If it no longer fits,
eliminated altogether.
Stop making casual commitments.
Some people's days are full to the brim
with soft commitments they have taken on
unintentionally through an offhand
comment or casual conversation they had
somewhere with someone you know the kind,
I mean you're chatting with your
neighbor about her work on the PTA,
your colleague about a new initiative
she is heading up or your friend about a
new restaurant he wants to try and
before you know it, boom, your committed
from now on. Pause before you
speak. It might sound obvious,
but pausing for just five seconds before
offering your services can greatly
reduce the possibility of making a
commitment you'll regret before the words.
That sounds great. I'd love to fly
out of your mouth. Ask Yourself,
is this essential? If you've
already made a casual commitment,
you're regretting find a nice
way to worm your way out.
Simply apologize and tell the person the
when you made the commitment you didn't
fully realize what it would entail.
Okay.
Get over the fear of missing out.
We've seen ample evidence in this chapter
suggesting that the majority of us are
naturally very loss averse.
As a result,
one of the obstacles to and committing
ourselves from a present course is the
fear of missing out on something great
to fight this fear,
run a reverse pilot.
One of the ideas that has grown popular
in business circles in recent years is
prototyping.
Building a prototype or large
scale model allows to test,
run an idea or product without making a
huge investment upfront exactly the same
idea.
It can be used in reverse to eliminate
nonessentials and a relatively low risk
way by running what Daniel Shapiro,
a director at linkedin calls a
reverse pilot in a reverse pilot.
You test whether removing
an initiative or activity.
We'll have any negative consequences.
For example,
when an executive I work with took
on a new senior role in the company,
he inherited a process.
His predecessor had gone to a
huge effort to implement a huge,
highly visual reports on a
myriad of subjects produced
for the other executives.
Each week.
It consumed enormous energy from his
team and he hypothesized that it was not
adding a great deal of value to the
company. So to test his hypothesis,
he ran a reverse pilot.
He simply stopped publishing the report
and waited to see what the response
would be.
What he found was that no one seemed
to miss it after several weeks.
Nobody had even mentioned the report.
As a result,
he concluded that the report was not
essential to the business and could be
eliminated.
A similar reverse pilot can be carried
out in our social lives are their
commitments you routinely make to
customers, colleagues, friends,
or even family members that you have
always assumed made a big difference to
them,
but that in fact they might barely
notice by quietly eliminating or at least
scaling back in activity
for a few days or weeks.
You might be able to assess whether it
is really making a difference or whether
no one really cares.
Even using these techniques.
It's true that [inaudible] can be harder
than simply not committing in the first
place.
We feel guilty saying no to something
or someone we have already committed to
and let's face it,
no one likes going back on their word yet.
Learning how to do so in ways that were
Ghana. You respect for your courage,
focus and discipline is crucial
to becoming an essentialist.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work week.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled
out and just drop in your email and you
will get the very next one and if you
sign up,
I hope you enjoyed,
this episode is brought
to you by four sigmatic.
You might remember four sigmatic
for their mushroom coffee,
which was created by those
clever finished founders.
And when I first mentioned
that coffee on this podcast,
the product sold out in less than a week.
It lights you up like a Christmas tree,
which can be really useful.
However,
recently I've been testing the opposite
side of the spectrum of new product and
that is their Reishi mushroom elixir
to help me end my day to get to sleep.
As you guys may know,
longtime listeners,
at least I struggled with insomnia for
decades. I've a largely fixed that,
but still shutting off my monkey
brain has never been easy.
It's still isn't easy very often.
And I found Reishi,
which I've been fascinated by for
a few years now, has been very,
very effective and calming
their old formula. However,
four sigmatic old formula included
Stevia and I like to avoid sweeteners,
all sweeteners for a host of reasons
and I then just ping them and asked,
hey guys, I would love to experiment
with this and maybe actually suggested,
but I'd like a version without
sweeteners if you'd be open to it,
if too much of a headache,
don't worry.
And they are always game
for experimentation.
So they created a special custom version
without the Stevia, without sweeteners.
Now it is part of my nightly routine.
Their ratio looks or comes
in single serving packets,
which are perfect for travel.
And in fact,
I'm about to leave the country right
now and I have a packet in front of me
that's just going to sit in
the end of my carry on bag.
You only need hot water and it mixes very,
very easily.
Here's some recommended copy
that they put in the read.
So I'm going to read it and
I'll give you my take quote,
a warning for those in
the experimental mindset,
Reishi is strong and bitter in
parentheses, like any great medicine.
So if the bitterness is too much,
I recommend trying it with honey end or
nut milk such as almond milk and quote.
So I'm going to say,
no,
you should suck it up and you should drink
the tea because it's not that bitter.
And maybe should take the advice of all
Chinese people when they're criticizing
younguns when they say
who and I'm sure cool.
Which means you're not able to eat
bitterness. Bitter is in many cases,
an indication of things that help
liver detoxification and so on.
Not saying that's the case here,
but I've tested this ratio
lecture on family members,
on friends. Everybody has liked
it. It's a little bit, or have the,
it's not that hard.
So I would just say suck it up and no,
don't put in honey or nut milk or any of
that shit. Just drink the goddamn tea.
It's delicious. I think if you
like who air that kind of stuff,
that type of teeth, you're going
to dig it. So just try it. Okay.
Back to then my read. If you'd like
to naturally improve your sleep,
both onset and quality,
I think naturally you might just enjoy
this ratio lecture without any sweet
nurse. It has organic Reishi extract,
organic fueled, mint extract,
organic rose hips extract, organic
Tulsi extract. And that's it.
No fancy stuff, no artificial watching
McCall it anything. So check it out.
Go to foursigmatic.com poured Sasha
Ferris and get 20% off this special batch.
I don't know if they're gonna
be making much more of this, uh,
it since it was made specifically for
you guys to do me a favor and try it out
so that they continue to be
open to experimenting with
me to create products for
you guys. Specifically.
Check it out. Four sigmatic,
that's [inaudible] dot com
forward slash a Ferris, F,
e R, r, I s. S and get
20% off the special batch.
And you must use the code
Ferris to receive a discount.
F. E. R. R. I. S. S. So again,
go to foursigmatic.com
forward slash Ferris and then
use code Ferris for 20% off
of this rare,
exclusive,
limited run of Reishi mushroom elixir
for nighttime routines with out any
sweeteners in general.