Do you think? I'm sorry. I'm
just thinking, uh, interview,
um, on the, uh, old Skype.
Any chance you could not move them?
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism
living this year.
Thank you.
For sure.
Boarding the sponsors of this show,
99 designs,
which is your one stop shop for
all things graphic design related,
go to 99 designs.com forward slash Tim
to see the projects that I've put up,
including the mockups and drafts of
the book cover for the four hour body.
As always,
you can subscribe to this podcast on
iTunes and you can find all of the links
and resources from this episode as well
as every other episode by going to four
hour workweek.com forward slash podcast.
Spell it all out or you can go to four
hour workweek.com and just click on
podcast feedback. If you have
feedback, I would love your thoughts.
Anything at all who you'd
like to see on this show,
ping me on Twitter as a t Ferris.
That's twitter.com forward slash t f e
R R I s s or on facebook@facebook.com
forward slash Tim Ferriss
with two r's and two s's.
This episode is a conversation between
yours truly Tim Ferris and Ed Cooke.
Ed Cook is a grand master
of memory based in Britain.
Great Britain,
a good friend.
He's made a number of appearances
in the four hour chef.
He helped improve my ability to memorize
anything and everything is also very
well known for coaching.
A writer named Joshua four from nothing
I he ground zero to becoming u s
national memory champion and I
believe a year or so of time,
a really astonishing feat and we'll get
into what grand master of memory means.
This is a two part episode,
so you have two separate parts.
They are very, very
dense. They're hilarious.
If you liked the Kevin Kelly episodes,
the Josh Waitzkin episodes or any
episodes that are similar to those very in
depth wide ranging, you are going to
love this episode. I hope you enjoy it.
So without further ado,
here's I'd cook.
Hello Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Tim Ferriss and welcome to a
special episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
I have my dear friend Ed Cook on the line.
I grabbed him last minute for reasons I
shall explain and he is a grand master
of memory among many,
many other things at the,
at the ripe old age of 23 is when
he turned that corner. But Ed,
where are you at the moment and,
and what are you up to summer?
I'm currently sitting in the,
uh, in the office where I work,
which is a converted method is chapel
in Bethnal Green London. Um, and it's
Friday night at 10:15 PM yes.
Well,
people with adequate social lives.
A, I kind of be a, you know,
running around town and
falling in love. Um, yeah, I'm,
I'm here and I'm trying to youtube
and I'm delighted to be here.
I wanted to actually share with people
what we just talked about doing an audio
check before we began recording where
you gave the best answer I've ever heard,
to a very mundane question,
which is what did you tell me
what you had for breakfast?
Or what did you have for breakfast?
And you can feel free to improvise,
but what was your answer roughly?
Well, it was a sound check.
So it, I myself of a sudden
embellishment. But yeah,
that was just what I think had a
couple of 'em partridges um, um,
a few sausages, some salmon, seven
campground kippers I think they were,
they were the campus and
the peat smoke kippers uh,
full boiled eggs and two poached eggs,
that kind of thing. Yeah, I caught her.
I actually don't know the English king,
but, um, I had a friend who, um, uh,
it was amazing. Fred
said a friend who, uh,
occasionally breakfasty to sorta chuck a
lot of counter be. I mean, I'd be like,
you know, what are you talking
about? And He'd be like, oh,
I'm just thinking about what,
you know,
Henry the sixth had for
breakfast every day.
I should,
I know I shouldn't give some background
for folks who may not realize that, uh,
you and I first connected several years
ago and you were tremendously helpful
with the four hour chef since that
was a book about accelerated learning
disguised as a cookbook, which
surprise surprise ended up being very,
very confusing to almost everybody
in the universe who came across it.
But there were aspects of it including,
uh,
chapters focused on pneumonic devices and
other types of memory techniques where
you were incredibly helpful. So first of
all, thank you very much for that. Um,
or my perfect and I was having trouble
piecing together how we first came in
contact.
How did we first meet?
And I should also just as context for
folks point out that Ed is in the UK,
I am drinking highly caffeinated tea.
He is drinking wine and this is
intended to be like a pub conversation.
So
please feel to the interpretation
did it already robots? So the context
of a, of a ripe old age just pub. Yeah.
Well we came into contact through,
um,
my dear friend Greg with whom
I co founded the company. Um,
and um,
Greg was then a phd student at Princeton
and I think you came to do a couple of
tools. He got shy with you and
it was through that, that we met.
That's right. And so, uh, for
those who are not familiar, uh,
ed is cofounder and the office
that he referred to is related to,
uh, his company memorize, memorize
Dotcom, which we'll come back to. And,
uh, the, the concept of being
a grand master of memories,
I were like concept that qualification,
what is entailed in becoming
a grandmaster of memory.
So, um, yeah, so, so I think I'll,
I'll explain that first and then
we can discuss it a little bit. Um,
just how stupid a term it is and
what a marvelous device for kind of,
you know, either ending a conversational
beginning one at a bus stop. But yeah.
So I'm at Grandma's to remind me, it's
a kind of title given out by the, uh,
the world memory sports,
but they should and,
and basically you have
to be able to remember,
I'm a 100 digit number in and out a pack
of cards in under a couple of minutes
and then 10 packs of shuffle
the cards in an hour. So it's,
um, so it's, it's three
parts of the world, maybe
championships, which determine,
uh, whether you can get this title
and um, yeah, I mean it's, um,
it's a great title.
I mean,
I can't really very compelling title
and I decide either the number of times,
you know, I've been in the kind of
losing situation and like club, you know,
outdanced um, you know, you know,
I'm not a symmetrical person, Tim.
Um, and, uh, you know, sometimes my
visual, you're kind of understates the,
the value of conversation with me. So
this is sort of like, and, but he's just,
you know, just, so I said,
what's your problem? It's
like, sorry, I'm [inaudible].
It's like, okay, you know,
device from champagne and then
we can talk further about this.
That's important qualification. But
yeah, it's, it's a very city concept.
But, um, the, you know, the, the,
the kind of the cultural context if you
want from which emerges namely people
doing competitive memory competitions I
think is awesome and fascinating because,
um, uh, because um,
in 1990,
the world record for memorizing a
shuffled deck of cards was 149 seconds,
which know if he could memorize a pack
of cards in under three minutes and show
that to somebody, they'd be fatty,
astounded. And we think you were teaching.
And you know,
it's not obvious to anybody that the
human mind would be capable of that. Um,
and I remember I was
very proud, um, you know,
10 years ago when I first broke a
minute, I asked like, oh my goodness,
this is extraordinary.
I mean,
the word record now is 21 seconds for
the memorization of a shuffled deck of 52
cards. You sort of think,
well, obviously, you know,
people presumably haven't got like
four times faster brains and they did.
Um, I'm only 24 years ago.
But the reason for it is,
is that there's been this
competitive culture in which, um,
there's an objective measure
of mnemonic speed if you like.
And over the last 10,
over the last 20 years,
people have on each year done their
best to outgun the rivals and the memory
scene and then very openly and freely
shared the techniques and hacks they've
used to be able to optimize these
30 arbitrary but nonetheless kind of
interesting processes of,
you know,
memorization and the results has been
an absolutely continuous linear increase
in the amount of stuff that people can
remember across of very wide range of
disciplines in a
particular amount of time.
So this is true or like names and faces,
random strings of words,
crazy like abstract, he
generated images, all this stuff.
People who have been able to think up to
test people's memories with as a result
of this community of
competition and sharing. Um,
you know,
people have got almost 10 times faster
now in the course of 24 years at
memorizing things when it was already
very impressive in the first place. So,
yeah,
I think that's why it's an
interesting thing. Yeah.
Is that a function of prize money,
Prestige,
social media? I'm very curious about the
dynamic that has produced that progress.
Because if you look at mixed
martial arts for instance,
UFC and you look at the first 10 of C's,
compare that to compare to the
competitors, to the competitors,
say a 30 UFC fcs later.
Compare those competitors with those of
today as the prize money has increased.
Among other things, I think it's
primarily the prize money. Uh,
you see a very quick evolution in terms
of whether it's selection bias or just a
larger pool of competitors
that has gone from say,
top 20% of athletes in the United
States to top 10 to top two.
And you're just looking at at mutants
in many cases now, uh, not to,
not to detract from their tech team,
not to diminish your amount is applicable.
Yeah. Right. Not to, not to diminish
their, their gentlemen laid demeanor, uh,
and technique and training.
But is what is, what is,
what are the contributing
factors to the, the, the,
the increases in,
in speed.
And came in, well, it over the
options. You have it up the um,
you can choose, you can
choose other ones. Yeah.
Well total Twitter followers
of a competitors of the
warm every term ships is,
uh, yeah, 20, 25 or
something. But, um, yeah, the,
um, and it's not money. There's no,
there's no real money on it. I think it's,
um, you know, I would just, I
would her suppose that, you know,
perhaps in a hundred years' time
if people, we did still care,
the current state of memory sports would
be considered still extraordinarily
immature. Um, and so I think we'll
probably, what of, what's the kind of,
it's like cricket in the 19th century
in England where people were kind of
working out the basics
of technique. Um, um,
in that case, historically, I believe
it was the invention of the steam train,
which allowed cricket.
They get good because, uh,
teams from further apart in the country
could visit each other. Um, the,
uh, information and press
was delivered quicker.
And so there was a sort of general,
um, increased in the talent pool.
We're competing with each other. And, uh,
and it was just possible to
even travel and sort of compete.
And it's something that said, like,
people from all over the world can do it,
you know, it's easy to hop on a plane so
that that's a contributing factor. Um,
but I think fundamentally
the motivation is there.
There's just so cool winning or doing
well in the world memory championships,
then it's purely a, it's
purely a kind of, um,
slightly comic form of status I think,
which drives it as well as
the fact that of course it's,
it's phenomenally interesting to,
um,
take something which every single person
there would never imagine they were
capable of doing and push it
and push it and push it to,
to see how well it can be done.
Um,
and it probably helps that it's quite
precisely quantifiable and he was like a
hundred meters or whatever else. And
I wanted to, I wanted to grab, uh,
something you mentioned and
come back to which is what, what
the average person is capable of doing
or what most people are capable of doing.
And,
uh,
perhaps you could recount for folks the
outcome of one of the experiments that,
that you and I did a
also involving your team,
which was related to the four hour chef.
So we wanted to incentivize people to
try to memorize a shuffled deck of cards.
And I was hoping you could talk a little
bit about that and the outcome because
a lot of people listening will
probably assume like a thousand digits.
I could never even remember a phone
number. I couldn't remember 20 numbers.
And they underestimate what
they're capable of doing.
So I would love if you could just perhaps
recount the results of the experiment
that we did related to the book launch.
Yes. That was, that was a fun, fun thing
we did. So, yeah. Or memorize we, um,
we don't just competition,
uh, with you, Tim. Uh, yeah.
At the same time as the launch
of the book. Um, and you know,
it was a $10,000 prize.
Um,
I believe munificent be supplied
by Youtube. Yup. That's right.
I spent it on a, yeah. Anyway,
so, um, so anyhow, so yeah.
So did I had this,
um,
this great engineer and the office called
tank who built this amazing system,
which was basically, um, a standard
memorize course where you would,
um, learned to associate with
each card in the deck. Um,
a person. And I'd actually
proposed like a group of 52 people,
but there are ways of changing
them to be people, uh, that you,
you wanted to have in your,
in your set of images.
And the basic technique underlying
this is the, um, you know,
cards are boring and a memorable
sequences are boring, are memorable.
How do you remember them?
Well,
you turn the cards into images
which are more memorable.
And so for instance,
Tim,
you are slightly more memorable
than the three of hearts say, um,
because you have characteristics,
you have a personality.
I can imagine you in detail,
like I made new interacting in situations,
so you're inherently more interesting
to my brain than mere card or figure or,
um, or, or anything like that. Um, and so
mean this is going to be and
couldn't be and here an expedition,
but I'll keep going. So, um, I think it's,
I think you do think you're doing great.
The assumption that I have
personality is a bit of a stretch,
but besides that you're doing fine.
I didn't say that it was an adequate to
I one. I just said there was one. Um,
anyway, so, um, so you know,
the basics of memory techniques is that
our minds love certain kinds of things.
So we're very,
very good at remembering spaces were very,
very good at remembering things, which,
which attracts our interest. And so,
you know,
a good of thumb I like to use is that,
and I think we should grab your attention
if you're wondering down the streets
is the kind of thing which will grab your
attention and your memory. So you know,
we'll something grey and um,
written in legal language.
Grab your attention if you
are walking on the street. No,
but we'll like kind of a small
elephant being attacked by Lemars.
I try to attention, yes, you will.
A spectacular lists of naked woman.
I tried to attention,
perhaps we'll um, a um, Balart do.
So probably not.
And so it's the same thing when we
kind of perceive within ourselves,
which is to say when we remember the,
the vivid,
interesting emotion grabbing
things. I again, Tim,
I'd like to clarify the evoke
vivid emotions particularly,
I mean I'd just take it as
yourself, but anyway, these things,
this is covering attention.
So the art of memory is basically
transforming information which is not
interesting into forms of
information which are interesting.
And four pack of cards. The
technique which I, um, I use myself,
um, and it's very popular
in the Miami community,
is to take each card and then
wrote, associate a person
with it. And, and you know,
if you go with personal association
could do this very quickly.
It takes like an afternoon for normal
person to associate with 52 cards,
52 people.
And then having got that code,
which is a bit like a language really
though you think of as language.
So if I say all our to
you, you'll say, oh, hi Ed.
And you've just learned that arbitrary
association between some letters or La
and a meaning. Know Hi there.
Something. Uh, and it's just
like that with the cards.
It's like a, it's like a very,
very small language, 52 words.
And so when you go through
the cards, you, I'm,
you imagine the people you've associated
with the cards instead of the cards.
And already it's massively
more interesting.
And the second thing you
do to tackle the sequence,
which is difficult to remember
because it's just a bland sequence,
is that you string these people who were
standing in the cards into an amusing
stories. So you, uh, you might be
getting your doorstep and you know,
there's Tim Ferriss and he's, he's
desperately trying to impress the queen.
She's not impressed.
And then slightly down the road we've
got like the pope and he's chatting with
Ed stone and, and, and you know, these,
these people are standing in for cards.
And because Tim is trying to impress
the queen, it's kind of funny, you know,
kind of a kind of colonial,
perverse humor vibe or whatever.
And it's just more interesting than three
of hearts, seven of spades, kinda think.
Anyhow, so that's the best city. So,
going back to your original question, we,
we put together a course on memos which
helped people make these associations is
that,
you know,
people will play on that for an hour and
they build up this vocabulary of waste
thinking about cards. So they're just
more interesting, more vivid, uh,
that sort of,
they attract more emotion and so they're
just generally more memorable. And then,
um,
we propose the technique very famous
and the memory kind of community,
which is just sort of imagine going
around a space and actually for your blog,
Tim,
I remember embarrassing myself when my
local street in a snow storm trying to
wonder around demonstrating how to
place images in space. I was like,
oh look up there. There's some of that.
I remember that very closely. They,
the search for it, good cook, Cook,
Cook with the knee on the
blog to find that video. Yeah.
Anyhow, so, um, so we
did the competition. Um,
so people learn the technique and they
could practice with this cool system on
the, on the website. And, um,
what was astonishing was that,
you know, a few thousand people
entered, you know, most people, um,
like basically couldn't be bothered
and give up quite quickly, but, but,
but basically anyone who did persevere
and actually just learn the images and
then start practicing. Um,
many of them got really good,
really fast. And, um, the girl
who ended up winning it, um,
who, whose name is Irina Ziad, she's
a fabulous young lady programmer who,
um, who lives in the Ukraine. I tried
to recruit her for memos, actually.
She was sort of only dimly
interested. Anyway. She, um, she,
um,
did it in about four days,
so it's just like sat on a computer,
a practice of thing,
and then within four days. So basically
now that I could do it under a second,
and then the memo is Christmas party.
That year we poked her in live on Skype
to prove that she could actually do it
and wasn't cheating as opposed to you,
about 200 people crowding into the church,
you know, scenes of unbelievable
at the butchery. Tim, uh, I, uh, I,
I think his eyes wide
shut. One of the, yeah,
it was that, but we better chat,
better lighting. Uh, Eddie,
how, um, yeah, it's just, you just
nailed it again, live on Skype. Um,
under the pressure.
We,
we told her I think that that was how
she could actually win the POWs and um,
and that's kind of it. Just a nice
example, you know, like it's, um,
it is very doable. And, um, I had,
I had a kind of another interesting
experience with, um, where I met a, I,
I went to the u s maybe championships
I think in 2005 with, um,
with my friend say this has
been a sort of diversion,
but I'll tell the other day.
So I got this friend called Lucas who's
from Austria, from Vienna who is, um,
a, an absolutely hilarious
and wonderful fellow who, um,
before we'd done this,
uh,
we've been contacted by channel
four and they were like,
we're just interested to hear how
her memory athletes train. And, um,
I always been a bit
suspicious to be honest. So the concept
of sort of self hacking, you know,
never be quite quite clear whether that's
something I really want to do my life
anyway, so I, so I said, well, you know,
like we like to get to high altitude
and I'm going to complete seclusion.
And I was kind of channeling an image
of Ricky Hatton, the boxer, you know,
going into the mountains
and sort of getting through
some there. They were like,
awesome. So anyway, Lucas and I, we
headed up into the mountains or we, um,
we put on as a source of comedy show
and this can be found on youtube, but a,
um, a kind of image of what a mental
athletes training program would look like.
Well, it's a sort of press ups
involving claps and I'm competitive.
I'm boxing style mutual recitation
and binary numbers and stuff. Anyhow,
so, um, it's, it's, it's a kind
of, it's a minor. So there,
for the sort of 12 or 13 people who,
um,
in your, in your listenership who, um,
who think that I'm actually
going to it, I get into an anecdote
within 90 days I would look at it. Okay,
so sorry.
We went to America and we went to the
u s memory chose ships and it was,
it was quite hilarious. So, so both of us
at that point, none American competitors,
we're not really allowed to
compete, but we were allowed
to, can be. And um, anyway,
we came first and second by a margin of
about times three because at that point
the sport was not very well
developed in the u s and M. Anyway,
there's a journalist then he was like, oh
my God, you're a geek. You're a a seven.
And the rest of it. And I was
like, uh, no, me, you know,
we were two young lads who've got
an enthusiasm for maybe attendance.
And so he was like, well,
there, but this is impossible.
So I was like, no, no, no, no,
I'll train you. So, uh,
so I trained him for a year and he
wound up the next year. And by the way,
I'm a pretty brutal coach.
It's a kind of a way of, um,
is a way for me to transcend my own
insufficiencies is to criticize others.
And so, so I trained him
up for a year and a, yeah,
he wound up winning the American
memory championships. Um, and um,
yeah, it, it was pretty cool.
And he wrote a book about it. Um,
that was Joe Garcia for
correct. Yeah. Let's just share
for his, um, yeah, he's super cool.
Moonwalking with Einstein. Yeah,
very, very, a book did very,
very well and had a great piece in wired
that introduced me to that, uh, as well.
Um, but, uh, sorry to
interrupt, not my, uh,
not mine.
Perfect. Perfect. Well,
I was, I was, I was, uh,
I was taken aback by your sudden
silence, which I mistook for, for,
uh, shy shyness, but I
think it's just drunkenness
taking another slug.
Nice. Nice. Nice to get you a camera
for our next podcast. The, the, uh,
so just to put in, just to put things
in perspective for folks with a,
it was arena, right? The
Ukrainian woman. Um, yeah. So she,
she learned to memorize a sh a shuffled
or randomized deck of cards and less
than a minute in four or five days.
Uh,
and the previous us record,
I guess a few years ago had been what,
147 seconds or something
along those lines. Um,
so she beat the US record with
four to five days of training.
I mean,
granted it was an older record,
but I think that that just highlights
what is possible for people.
And, uh, the, the,
the question I'd love to ask you is,
I mean, what, what are some, some, uh,
some perhaps if people
have an afternoon and, uh,
they are not going to necessarily
focus on the pack of cards.
Is there something else that they can
do to prove to themselves that they have
greater,
uh,
mental athleticism or
memorization potential than
they've ever thought possible?
Is there something else that they can do?
They can make love to a beautiful woman
in their imaginations without moving a
muscle.
Okay.
And why would you recommend that?
Um, well, it was a joke.
Okay, you got to, you're so dry.
It's just dry. British humor are,
we're still dragging her.
That was like, she just, that was a
straight straight out, oh that funny.
But I suppose the tinkle of a thought
which underlies every joke there,
but take it with a thought. We started
as a joke though. He's just, the
imagination is,
um,
an our capacity to form images just
while talking just what communicating is,
um, is already extraordinarily
potent. And it is,
wait, wait, wait. So what will
the thing which confuses people,
it's like how can you possibly
like form an image in a second,
which you then end up remembering
five minutes later. And,
um, the example I like to give is that
that's what happens in conversation the
entire time. So, you
know, if I say to you,
I might just describe my office to Tim
and then we'll actually test your memory.
I know, I know that you're sort
of getting out of bed and um,
getting, getting a little, a
little long in the tooth. Yeah.
Daughtery but uh, yeah,
so describe the office.
We've got a quite a colorful off it.
So I'm going to kind of,
I'm going to begin here where
I am and about 15 seconds,
I'm going to describe to you the
sequence of objects. I'm going to see.
I'm going to make it a bit more vivid
by imagining myself as an amusing
character. Kind of leaping around, say
like, let's say the I am, um, can you,
can you want it?
You name the amusing character Tim.
Uh,
musing Mortimer
motorbike is, I'm more trauma. Um,
and I'm gathering into a laptop.
I'm going to take a bottle of wine
right by me and I flung it into the wall
where there's a picture 25. I
didn't know what they are. I mean,
let's just say you're Cousy and sort of
jock straps and tattoos, Japanese men, um,
or a picture of them on the wall.
And then I jump around and others,
is this a hammock?
And in the hammock there are two labs.
This is not true by the way, but
anyway, two lambs, eating cheese. Um,
and then you jumped over
the hammock and then,
then something's a grand piano and
there's a young man playing shopper. Um,
and he's chopping away at the piano and
then move over. And then there's a swing.
So it goes from Canada to the swing,
does most of her,
and the swing is covered in pink roses.
And if you kind of trace up the
swing of the robe, you'll see the,
at the very top, there is a, uh,
a model of a rhesus monkey just
dangling from the top of the rope,
jumping back down.
You'll land on the kitchen table where
four people for a unfortunate memos,
employers are just trying to sort of
have a quiet evening in, um, you know,
reflecting on the, on the vicissitudes
of life. But there by the big Auger,
the big metal oven, and I'm the,
the metal oven is emitting heat.
And on the Auger there
was a pot full of spoons.
Okay. So that was, um, an incoherent
narrative. Last thing, about 45 seconds,
I'm guessing, uh, in
which I mentioned motors,
Mortimer's little adventure.
And, um, and you know,
the first thing I'd say
to your listenership is it
just merely by listening to
that you followed it, you formed the
images at the speed of talk, which is,
you know,
one or two images a second,
and you've strung that into a coherent
mental concept or Inca here and one,
you know, I'm drunk, come on, calm
down and goes. But anyway, you,
you start getting into intercare in of
concept in a spectacularly small number
of sectors.
I read something phenomenal.
If you think that it's even possible
to follow that, a battery out them,
we're going to,
we're going to not going to test you.
So I'm on my laptop more summers there
and he's looking at that to what happens
next.
Uh, it grabs a bottle of wine,
which is right next to him.
The throws it into a picture on the wall,
which has 25 Yakuza jock
straps with tattoos. Uh,
and then, uh, I'm having a bit of
recency primacy here. And then, um,
after that, um, I want
to say there, there,
there are two lambs in a hammock.
That's correct. Yep. And, uh,
I don't recall what the eating,
yeah,
that's what they are eating cheese if
I remember correctly. And then, uh,
then jumping out of the Hammock to a,
uh,
I believe it's piano after that there's
a gentleman playing Chopin and chopping
away at the keyboard, which was very
clever of you to use the ch twice.
That helped. Uh, and then, um, uh,
then from there we, we, we
get to a swing, which has,
is covered in pink roses and oddly enough
as a model of a rhesus monkey hanging
at the very top of it. Uh, and when
Mortimer jumps off of this swing,
he lands on a kitchen table
where therefore memorize
employees just trying to go
about their business. And it's
very disruptive, quite obviously a,
and there is a,
then next to them a,
this is where I got tripped
up a little bit. Um, the,
the Auger on the stove top,
I don't know what an Auger is a,
but there's a pot on top of whatever
an Auger is with spoons in it.
And then that's the,
uh,
the curtain falls and that's the end
of the Mortimer shows. I remember it
that Seg so well done too. So yeah, just,
just sort of a ticket it, we've done that.
So you go on laptop, bottle of wine,
you accuser 25 of them, jock straps.
So we're up to about six
items. How much lambs, cheese,
Pnh shop and shopping swing,
pink roses,
Reese's jumping off landing kitchen
table memos, employees. Oh, okay.
Even though you didn't know what
an Aga was, it is by the way,
his mother more of this
kind of European oven,
which is basically am a one ton
block of iron, permanently heated,
which acts as central heating and as a
cooking mechanism, which is what I mean.
And on top of that,
there was a pot with spoons and says it's
20 things you correctly remembered in
sequence. They're just really by
dint of understanding human language,
which you have successfully
recounted in order. Uh, and for that,
the, uh, the narrative helps,
but it just kind of give skips one an
insight into how these aren't in the same
way that say for instance,
firing an Arrow through a, um,
a blackbird,
you know,
we're just flying through the sky is
like a skill you almost have to learn,
you know, on the, on the top
of basic motor skills, but
you have to learn it very,
very specifically.
These sort of memory techniques draw from
quite fundamental cognitive capacities.
They're quite, yeah, it's quite,
um, it's quite basic. And you know,
I do this other thing where I kind of,
I do these things called memory works.
When you just get a bunch
of random pedestrians got
them together and say, okay,
we're going to learn whatever,
you know, the u s presidents,
the first pharaohs of Egypt,
what have you,
and you just wonder around the town
for about an hour and you're like, oh,
imagine you know George Washington, the,
I don't know who George Washington is.
I mean, just, okay, but imagine jewels is
shark washing himself tons. So they go,
okay, very good. They imagined
that in the window over there.
And you gotta wonder around and
with no prior training whatsoever,
you can sort of unlock is too
strong a word. You can just, um,
make use of the fairly
phenomenal underlying kind
of cognitive capacities that
you have at your disposal all
the time. So, so it's, it's,
it's not I kind of elusive
geek skill fundamentally. It's,
it's basically just to kind of cunning
use of what the human brain does best,
namely process wheel meaning imagine
interesting things happening in space and,
um,
and kind of integrate narratives.
I know I, it's, it's something
that I feel like, uh, and this,
this actually touches
on a sort of a deeper,
uh,
I wouldn't say insecurity,
but a conflict that I have an inner
conflict that I'm hoping you can help me
resolve. Um, very, uh, I'm very,
I'm very indecisive about my sexuality.
Not as, not at all. I wanted to,
uh, sexually ambiguous. It's caused
me a lot of strife. Uh, no, that's,
that's also not it.
The question is related to utility
of highly refining certain memory
capabilities. So I, when I
was in, when I was in college,
I read a number of books including,
I think it's just called your memory
and how to improve it as like the most
generic. I think that's it. Higbee uh,
most generic title imaginable for
something that talks about vivid imagery,
but I remember it becoming very
fascinated by memorizing numbers and,
uh, and then I might be getting the
terminology wrong, please correct me, uh,
if I am, but the, the sort of number
of consonant system where you're,
you're converting and the
numbers and the consonants,
you convert those into words and images
and that allows you to memorize long, uh,
long strings of digits.
And I would,
and I would place these images around
typically my surroundings and I think that
might've been a weakness in my method.
I would always use wherever I happen to
be as opposed to a predetermined route.
Uh, the, the only benefit to
that method is that I, when I,
when I would play this game with people
and I would typically have them pull out
a five,
a single and a $20 bill.
So I'd have them pull out bills
of different denominations
and I had memorized
the serial numbers on those different
bills and then you to the policy teams.
Oh yeah. It was, I wasn't fast enough to
make it really exciting. I was like, okay,
cool. Give me five minutes.
And they're like, what? Okay,
this is really boring. Um,
but what was really fun about it is I
would memorize these numbers. They would,
they'd be like, oh wow. It's amazing
that I do them backwards. Oh my God,
that's amazing. And then, uh, but it,
it only took a really a week or two of
practice to get to that point. And I'm,
and I'm so confident that
almost anyone can do that.
The what was fun about having the Loci,
I mean the,
the locations
dependent on where I was sitting at the
time is that very often I could bump
into that person a week later and say,
hey,
you still have that five or
that single or that 20 I can,
I can give you the serial number.
And I could remember it because
I had so many distinct locations,
which was kind of a
fun trick. Um, but the,
it took a decent amount of effort to get
good at that. And what I'm wondering is,
do you find that there are any particular
mental exercises that have a high
degree of carry over to other areas
or that have more utility than others
because there's,
there's so many different kind of
party tricks that you could develop or
competitive capabilities is if you had
to pick one that you think people would
get the most out of? Is,
is that even a possible?
Is that a good question?
But I think about this because it does
take time to sort of mean for me to
maintain a high degree
of proficiency with these things.
Right. I think the, I mean,
I wouldn't necessarily recommend to,
you know,
anybody with a rounded social
life to get too deep into the, uh,
the number of memorization
stuff. But I mean for, for me,
um, the, the interest in
memory techniques kind of, um,
is I guess, you know, emerges
out of a much more general,
um, interesting consciousness
and sort of, um, yeah, the, uh,
the curiosities of having a mind
of the character of that we have.
And, uh, to the question, um, you know,
what is the most generalizable,
useful,
um,
concept,
not maybe requiring practice
that one can draw out of. Um,
the theory into the history
of memory techniques. I think
I'd give two answers on the first is,
um,
you remember things which
ignite your imagination.
Um, and we all know this
in our hearts. You know,
if you're really into soccer or football
or as we call it here, you know,
you might be a,
a pathetic credit score,
but you might be able to remember
something like, you know,
if you actually added it up,
12,000 distinct football results,
the equivalent of a kind
of medical degree, uh,
in terms of scatter of information, it's
because you're interested in. So, um,
I think a lot of people,
um,
are kind of embarrassed
about the characteristics
of the mind that, you know,
the other things that they have a greater
tendency to remember the things which
they feel they need to do to really
wrap their mind around a topic.
And so the first thing would just be
like the most, the things which, um,
you find stimulating and interesting
other things you remember.
And don't censor yourself in finding what
those things are at allowing yourself
to kind of, uh, experience
information in that way. Um,
and so I'll try and make that concrete,
you know, um, I think the, um,
a lot of people will be reading some
nonfiction book about economics and it was
sort of ignite in the back of their mind
the idea that this is actually a bit
like their friend owl. Um, and
how he, uh, how he behaves with,
with their made Dan. Um, but it's
actually officially about, you know,
US China relations and you know,
that metaphor that,
that way of comprehending things that are
very kind of personal, perhaps trivial,
um,
manner of comprehending things through
the filter of one's own experience gets
suppressed leading to kind
of boredom and, um, uh,
a lack of emotional engagement with the
subject matter. And so, you know, uh,
just to say it succinctly,
like just,
just back wherever your mind needs to
go and endorse it and ignite interest
through kind of imagination would be one
thing because that's a very succinct,
a piece of advice. Uh,
second thing is succinct, uh,
which is just the, um, when two
things are in the same place,
either in your mind or on a diagram or,
um,
in a semantic space, if you, they
will get confused with each other. Um,
and, and I think the genius of the
special techniques is the genius of having
different contexts or different thoughts.
And you touched upon this actually
with, um, with your own, um,
adventures with five and $10 bills,
which is that where thoughts
were experiences and
thoughts are separated. Um,
they stand alone, they don't
interfere and they can, um,
they can persist through
time, but where they are, um,
sort of specialty connected and you know,
actual experience or um,
or especially connected to kind of
within the mind. So where, um, um,
where were two concepts just feel very,
very similar and you kind of,
when you're thinking about them, you kind
of thinking about them in the same way,
they will tend to fuse with each other
and then fail to be distinct entities in
their own rights.
So just literally separating stuff out
in space is incredible as a general
cognitive tip for brainstorming,
for resolving arguments,
for clarify emotions that in
relationship to you know, anything.
And you know, because
uh, because of this I,
I discovered some quite interesting thing
about how to design house parties. Um,
so you know, you still have these,
um, these moments where, you know,
we have an incredible Houseparty
talk to 25 really interesting people.
It will be, you know, super thing at the
time. You are just flush with happiness.
And then the next day the whole thing
would be in your mind would just be a kind
of a blur. You just be like, yeah,
I recall being in the kitchen and there
was some people there and we chat about
stuff. But, but because all those kind
of memories or on top of each other,
because of the spatial
constraints of a house party,
you don't really remember all
the things which happened.
And if you can sort of take a house party,
and this is true of any kind of
experience, it could be true of, um,
an evening out with friends.
It could be true whether it's
obviously true of road trips.
It could be true even of, um, uh,
of a friendship or a
romance or anything else.
If things are kind of
spread out through space,
if each kind of context or
experience has its own place,
then they can all live by themselves
and you just get a much richer level of
kind of autobiographic memory. Um, and
so we, with house parties specifically,
I kind of recommend always having
three or four phases to a house party,
a preferably with a different style,
a different kind of music.
I'm a different fundamental
focus specialty. Um,
and narrativize the transitions between
them. So rather than just being like,
there's a splurge of a house party and
everyone's just getting drunk and try to
chat each other up.
Instead you have a kind of a phase where
you're being quite portion drinking
champagne and listening to,
I'm listening to French music and then,
um,
a bunch of people arrive and you're
like, okay, we're not going to eat.
I know once more we're going
to eat on one leg and said,
you can have a bunch of time hopping
around chewing on reindeer or whatever it
is. And then up onto the roof.
It's a and you a differently.
And so by, by creating an artificial
structure you end up with, um,
you end up with much richer
experience. Um, um, and the, yeah.
So that there would be some ways from
Tim two pieces of advice or like, um,
make stuff vivid and personally
interesting and don't censor yourself.
And then if you are relating to anything,
it could be learning or even
just personally experience, um,
find individual spaces for each thing,
um,
because then they'll survive by themselves
and not just kind of merge into the,
um,
into the kind of fall off of similarity,
right. Blending together into
indistinguishability. So that has, uh,
it's funny when you,
when you start to think of just the,
the basic programming that we have,
uh,
that of course has a lot of applications
to dating as well. Uh, and you,
you did mention something in passing.
I want it to come back to which was
clarifying your feelings about a
relationship.
And I wanted to know how,
how you think about that because this
is a pain point for a lot of people at
different points in their lives,
or at least a source of anxiety.
How do you try to, uh, if
this is even the objective,
find objectivity when clarifying your
feelings about a relationship or maybe
it's just getting a better understanding
of, of your own subjectivity, but, uh,
I want it to kind of digest that
and buying a challenge. I wanted to,
wanted to just unpack that a little bit.
So how would,
how do you think about clarifying
feelings in a relationship?
It's actually quite funny
because, um, my girlfriend's cool,
Clara and your acid does sound clarifying.
Not sure there's much more I can
do, but, um, anyways, so, um,
I mean, I'm definitely not a
relationship guru, but I mean, I, I,
we're happy to freestyle on this subject
because I think it is fascinating and
is a lot of, it's a big source of pain
and, you know, and it's also, it's an,
and it's not just romantic
relationships. It's also, um, you know,
creative and personal
relationships, relationships
with friends and, um, and uh,
you know, I've, uh, I've
suddenly sort of, um,
thought about this a bunch because they,
one of the surprising features
of adult life alongside like, um,
not being competent as he was assuming
going to become competent, whatever.
Uh, and um, uh, and the
fact that sort of, um,
that you are actually going to be covered
adult and this is kind of, you know,
we'll see when you're 18, you know, it's
a pretty abstract thing. You kind of,
you know, aging is a kind of comic, um,
encounter with something you can
conceptually deny with certain futility.
But anyhow, so relationships to
the other thing where you of, um,
well when you're looking at a person,
your in some sense you experiencing
the entire, or at least, um,
that person is the focus of the
undifferentiated focus of a whole,
like incredibly complex,
um,
tissue of fundamentally distinct,
you know,
emotions and judgments and
attitudes. Um, and so, you know,
you find yourself in a relationship,
you know, in, in an argument saying,
and you're like, well, um,
and you basically, you're,
you, you come from an emotion,
you come from emotion,
which is like you probably don't perceive
yourself and you're thinking like,
I don't feel very happy about
what's going on sort of thing. Um,
and the tendency is to map that against
basically whatever springs into your
mind, um, or whatever the person is,
is telling you or what the
situation is. And so, you know,
this is why like someone's late to a
restaurant and someone can go absolutely
mental about it out. Of course, it's
got nothing to do with being late.
The restaurant. It's part of a whole load
of other stuff, which is dot, dot, dot,
right. At the same thing. Um,
and so, yeah, so for instance,
[inaudible] and an
argument that I have had,
which turned out to be,
um, amazingly stupid,
um,
I shall not shy,
but now I actually think about
what the talking room was about.
I'm not sure you're timorous
readers really what uh,
I want to hear about it.
So, um, so I had a, um,
going to have to cut this out of the
final recording cause I'm just going to
have to pause and just sort of
jumping to another topic.
One of the fascinating
things about language is that
when you begin a sentence,
even if you sort of have a,
a intimation of how the
sentence is going to end up,
you actually got no knowledge of where,
what the sentence particular
formulation is going to be.
So as you initiate your sentence,
you have kind of like, oh,
there's something interesting to be
said with a particular kind of internal
mental urge and the words begin to come
out and you kind of shepherd it and it's
slightly chaotic fashion to the
end of the piece of meaning.
You had implicitly wanted to admit
at the beginning of his had to,
but which is not like
consciously before your eyes.
At the beginning it just kind of,
it's like a seed which becomes a tree.
The seed contains the tree, but the seat
doesn't look like the tree or whatever.
Well, a similar thing with anecdotes.
Um, you know, you, I think, oh,
this is a really good idea, the best, best
sell Tim about this day. And then, um,
actually the anecdote is not
actually before your eyes.
And so I have to take a quick timeout
just to see where this having to is like
she get away.
No problem.
Um,
I can give you,
if you'd like a bite or a pause,
I can ask a few other, uh, and this
then I might forget to come back to it.
So we can also do that. Um,
but uh, I would like to come
back to it, but I'm cheap.
I could hit you with a couple of rapid
fire questions if that would take the
pressure off. Okay. When you
think of the word successful,
who's the first person who comes to mind
and why?
Um,
so I think of the German,
oh wait,
gutter, um, who, um,
actually this is, this is good. It's
a good topic. And I'm, by the way,
very happy to return to the previous one
because they're both interesting. But,
um, but I, I'm quite suspicious of,
um, um, the concept of marriage.
So like, it seems to be like one
of the guiding, if you'd like,
philosophical assumptions of, um,
you know, and I think actually,
especially like western
American California and, um,
culture that Marriott is the correct
thing to drive outcomes in humans lives.
So,
you know,
if you try hard and you know where it
goes off and your inherently really
talented and you're not
benefiting from saying, you know,
inherited wealth or whatever,
then the success and
happiness and whatever else,
there's my supposedly the immersion
of that is justified. Um, and,
um, and in fact, Tim, you
know, you, um, you know,
you write books in some sense and you
know, and you're, you're interested in,
you develop the concept of
improving as a person of, um,
of finding kind of powers
and talents and, um, um,
possibilities within yourself. And this
is kind of inherently attractive idea,
right? And it's very difficult on the face
of it to say, well actually, you know,
there's a problem with this,
but I don't know what I'm saying
those handovers but, but you know,
Mary is kind of a fundamental
assumption of, of um, of goodness.
Um,
in the mirror. It is associated with
effort. I guess I just want to define,
I think
the noble concept of math Marriott is
associated with efforts. So it's like, um,
if you do something really incredible
and you tried really hard that that
success is something you deserve. We
think of that as like morally justifiable.
Um,
which is kind of problematic
for sociological reasons,
but also programmatic for kind of a,
and the sociological reasons being,
some people have the opportunity and
situation to express their talents kind of
thing, but it's also
problematic because you know,
you just don't choose your marriage.
Um, and so you might say, okay,
I don't use my merits.
Um,
but actually I do choose them because I
trained really hard and I learned about
how to improve myself and I
express discipline. But again,
the underlying capacities which allowed
you to find the time to train hard and
control your, there's been, these aren't
things you choose and you know, and so,
so the, so almost all of our kind of, um,
culture of admiration for people who
do really well is based on this kind of
implicit moral idea that people
determine their own outcomes.
But once you kind of begin digging into
that, it's not really clear. They, they,
they do. Um, and the second
part of that is, um, you know,
what are the kind of categories and
concepts with which we use to kind of
determine Marriott. So like, um, you know,
I'm always really struck by
the fact that, um, that, um,
for instance, in our society,
there are people who are, um,
have a level of genius for
artistic expression and, um,
other things which aren't kind of
commercially valued and therefore aren't
really culturally valued except in
extreme cases. Um, who are, you know,
are only like seven pounds an
hour working in a cafe. Um,
they have a mental world
and range of learning and
sophistication of perspective,
which is enormously rich.
And like,
obviously compatible with that in most
cases, in many cases like, you know,
superior to according to
a different perspective,
someone who's like really good at coding
and commands $200,000 a year and has
high status and so on and
so forth. Um, and you know,
in that case there's a kind of a,
a, a kind of capitalistic I guess,
reason for ascribing merits to
one person over, over another. Um,
but you know, you changed the
perspective even slightly and um,
the Marriott flips completely. And so
the whole kind of concept of merit, um,
does depend on these kinds
of background thoughts about,
about what is valuable, which is
kind of often problematic. How would,
how would you flip the perspective with
the artistic Barista versus like, sir,
we'll say one, one example, one
different paradigm would be like, um,
towards richness of experience. So, um,
which, um, you know,
which people's mental Lowe's would
make for a better novel,
you know,
I don't show or whatever or
you could say like, you know,
effect on the environment. It is someone
who's Super Dynamic and successful.
The rest of it will tend to fly around
and create capital and spend the capital
in January.
He taught the world economy,
which generally heats up the world
and so on. And so, you know, we,
we have no way of tracking the kind of
externalities of human action either in
terms of comma,
I.
E the emotions of the people who surround
and come into contact with important
times to say environmental impact
because we can't track them.
And even if we could, we, uh,
we might not. Um, we don't.
So these aren't, these aren't metrics
which we could, couldn't tune into. Right.
Um, and because their metrics,
we're not, we can't get into,
we just kind of assume that
don't really exist. Um, and they,
they have no real influence on, you
know, um, a changes in behavior. But B,
you know, what, as a society or
culture, we find easy to admire. Um,
so how did, how did good to
make you think of marriage?
Just like Jesus bad and just
ask you a simple question.
Answer Big Leftwich. Dot. Okay. Just like,
I know, I know you hate iron rand. That's
fine. Um, what do you think? A good day
guys. It's really cool. Cool. So
he's like, um, at the age of 25, he,
um, you know, I, as a
teenager, he sort of,
I'm falling in love the entire time
and writing poetry to Australians.
And so then he's 25,
he writes a novel,
which kind of is an
extraordinary brilliance for
the troubles of young birder.
It's this wonderful story
of a young man who, um, who,
um, falls in love and I'm, it doesn't
really work out so well. And as an aside,
Gerta wrote this book by locking himself
in a hotel room for three months,
imagining his five best
friends on different chairs
and then discussing with his
imaginary friends, different
possibilities, applause
and so on and so forth.
Which is an example by the way of that
spatial separation I was talking about,
which is to say that in one's own mind
with his son when somehow it kind of
inherently boxed in and constricted and
by like imagining in different spatial
locations,
different perspectives,
and then kind of iterating and idea or,
or um,
or novel in this case.
Through those perspectives,
he was able to kind of give himself
five perspective separated out and uh,
and give himself the kind
of multidimensional play
ground for creating the work
of art, which by the way is an
awesome credit. [inaudible] hey have,
so it does that. And then
he starts writing, you know,
the best purpose already,
the best pro stylists in the history
of German language. And then, um,
there's this like jewelry. That's how I
was going to bring his thoughts to look.
He goes, he's appointed of the Weimar
republic as a kind of poet in residence,
but then just got really
interested in as other stuff.
So he started like redirecting the
construction of the canal system and do
various other stuff and um, and doing
lots of kind of inventive things.
And so then he gets into, um, um,
basically administered in administering
a human affairs and he becomes a fairly
good at that. And then
at the age of 39, um,
he basically falls in love
for the first time, Trudy. Uh,
or maybe that was starting to fall well
valley, how he just disappears one day.
He's like, he's like this very
prestigious, sultry, important position.
He's kind of like the mayor
of Weimar effectively. Uh,
and then he just pisses off to Italy,
just read,
leaving a small note and then
basically runs round, you know, falls.
And now with lots of beautiful people,
right?
Some of the best sort of sexually
what it poetry, every return.
Meanwhile he's becoming, Chris comes
back, becomes incredibly interested in,
um, in Newton's theory of physics,
which he thinks is appalling.
And like it doesn't capture the
mystery and beauty of color at all.
So he wrote so theory of
color, which is like, um,
uh,
an amazing fountain of incredible goodness
for philosophers and stuff about the
phenomenology of color perception
and how shade and context and meaning
influence the character of color. Um,
and then meanwhile his rating Faust,
famous play is the kind of greatest work.
And he kind of completes
that and it's 50 years,
but that hasn't lost energy at all and
goes through like three or four totally
different styles of poetry. Um,
you know, and by the time he dies,
the age of 82 ish, he, um,
has become really interested
in eastern culture. And,
and did I forget to mention that he,
he,
he's got this deep aesthetic vision of,
um,
of science and our relationship to nature.
And it comes up with basically what's the
theory of evolution. Um, and, and I'd,
I'd like studies plants and humans
and does this particular thing there,
which at the time a justification for
humans, differences for the animals,
which I think it was
called the Inter maximally.
We burn some random bone in your jaw.
And it's amazing how we try and
distinguish ourselves, you know, uh,
Percival thumbs language, humor, there's,
you know, consciousness or intelligence.
Uh, and that, that point, it
was the interface Minnery bird.
And he actually did some dissections of
animals and young humans show that this
burn was present in both it fuses later
in life and therefore is not the basis,
you know, and, and so therefore
it can be missed, but,
but humans are animals are fundamentally
the same. And he talks about plants and,
and the similarity of plants.
Um,
the efflorescence of a flower with the
way the human cranium kind of bends round
links up with itself.
And so he's kind of,
he's just cool.
He's like expressive.
He's incredibly independent.
When Napoleon invades,
um, I think he was living in Frankfurt
at the time when opponent invaders,
Frankfurt,
everyone else's like sheltering and the
houses and he was wandering the fields
looking for evidence about the
color pink for his theory of colors.
It's totally called transcending the
local context. Um, and uh, anyway,
so he's interested in
all this stuff. He's, um,
passionate and intuitive.
Um, he is a genius,
which helps.
Um,
but he produces a kind of a body
of work and a set of perspectives,
which,
um,
which is just fundamentally life affirming
and in a way which kind of carries
through the ages. And so, like I
actually got into girls, I, my God,
I was traveling round or the age of 80 in
the world is what people in England do.
And between school high school in
university, and I'm in my career,
I just had girders aphorisms,
his short little thoughts
in my pocket. And so I read and
reread and reread this book.
It's actually had quite a fundamental
perspective on my life because these are
his like little snippets of wisdom
on almost any imaginable topic.
Um, and all of them are
brilliant. You know, it's things
like the company of women,
his schooling in good manners
or boldness has genius,
power and magic or you know, uh, and,
and then the ones you don't
remember in, um, in, um,
their precise form,
but which nonetheless act as little
micro filters for interpreting reality.
Um, and, uh, anyway, so let's
say he's that kind of a big
influence on me. I mean,
one of his coats HD is like,
uh,
something along the lines of there
is nothing so depressing as um,
someone who is Derek,
um,
being praised by somebody who isn't.
Because when we praise people,
we put ourselves on a
level with them, uh, ads.
So I was actually just trying to think
of like a credit which related to this
situation. And so here I am praising
Gutter and actually as I'm describing it,
I'm kind of channeling a bit
of his general awesomeness
and feeling a bit better
about myself and uh,
yeah. Anyways, so, uh,
and by the way,
I just as a general concept that that
phenomenon of how a memory can have
influence perception is the fundamental
reason why I think it's still worth
knowing things even though we
can look them up. Because, um,
by looking everything up,
we give away and divest of the kind
of central flow of our consciousness
genuine, um, richness.
Cause it's by having,
it's by being able to recognize
the differences between
20 different birds that
you don't just perceive
a bird, you perceive, oh,
you do a particular variety of bird.
And what on earth is it doing round here
at this time of year, it must be lost.
Perhaps the migration patterns
being fucked up by global warming,
whatever it turns like pure data into
connection with a meaningful world.
And that's kind of what
memory does. And um, and so,
and that will be kind of my
general justification for,
for me things. Um, you know,
I liked that.
Ah, the, this is something that I,
I also grapple with just as
is I strive to sort of be
the master of this tool.
It is technology and not
the tool of the masses.
The,
you mentioned two things about good to
that I wanted to dig into a little bit.
You mentioned
passion and intuition and um,
you can revise that,
but those were two of the
characteristics of good to that you,
that you pulled out.
And one of the reasons that I,
I reached out to you very much at the
11th hour yesterday to see if you wanted
to,
to chat and catch up and just record it
because I thought it'd be fun for people
to listen to you.
Is that been having,
I've been having a bit of a tough time
with medical issues related to Lyme
disease and other things and uh,
have felt a little, a little down,
a bit in a bit of a slump.
And I find that you are always,
you always strike me as very,
and this could be an illusion,
so feel free to disabuse me of this
notion, but in a excited, very passionate,
very, uh, energized. And I'm,
I'm wondering if that is
something that you feel you've,
you've,
you've always had intrinsically,
or if it's something you've
developed and if, if the ladder,
and maybe it's a combination,
you know, how do you strive to,
to encourage that type of
state, um, you know, what,
what are the things that
contribute to your better moments?
Those are a lot of fucking questions
in one, but, um, and I don't have,
I don't know. I don't
have, alcohol is huge.
Yeah. There will, I do.
So if I might a slowing nonsense at
this end of the Skype call, but, um,
well first of all, sorry to hear about
the medical stuff from the depot of, um,
difficulties he has and that's,
um, undoubtedly tough and, um,
second thing. Um, no, I'm not
always really happy about it.
So I, it's funny, like day
a company has been, um,
an amazing journey full of just like the
highest highs and the most like exact
quibble, horrifying lows. You know,
because it's sort of a, it's, you know,
I guess it's just life really. But, um,
everything, you know, you start a company,
everything turns, it starts
out, you know, like, oh,
this is going to be absolutely incredible.
You know, do something amazing.
Everyone's going to love it and it's
all going to be beautiful. So thing.
And then,
um,
and then it turns out to be just like a
much more complex human process and that,
and you have, um, you know,
you have breakdowns in relationships
where people you love and you have,
um,
decisions you make where you subsequently
realized that they were the wrong
decision. And it caused a lot of
people's pain and you have, um,
successes, which are wonderful, but,
which are compromised by the fact that
they weren't what they should have been
because I think anyways,
so I of course,
like anybody else, like I'm,
um, I'm uh, a, uh, you know,
I have, uh, access to
the full range of, of,
of goodness or badness city. He
would experience obviously. Um,
I am quite keen on life though too.
Like I do,
I do. Um, and I, I do.
Yeah. So I'm curious.
I don't know where that, I mean,
cause I mean I've, I guess I've, I am,
I suppose it was also that I get my
energy from the world and other people
rather than internally. Like
I'm, I'm, I'm very kind of,
I'm on interested generally in,
um,
supposedly scientific assessments
of, you know, personality and,
and so on and so forth. I think the, um,
the reductive impulse
is demeaning to humans.
I'm also probably quite worried about what
I discovered if I really liked it too.
But, um, but, um,
but I am an extrovert and I did
read one thing, uh, in my studies,
according to science, which struck me
as fascinating piece of self knowledge,
which is the,
you know,
introverted people tend to have a
much higher internal level of energy,
so that a proactive,
interactive in every interaction with our
environment isn't so necessary to keep
them rewarded and interested.
And there were just an, I am, um,
undoubted the extroverted,
so I absolutely love and gain huge energy
for interacting with people and the,
and so on and so forth. Uh,
and so, so that's, that's
kind of a personality thing.
Um, regarding, um,
like passion, I guess it's, um,
this kind of might connect
with a few interesting issues,
but I think the, um, the,
I suppose I'm a,
I'm a dick and so I hate doing things,
which for me basic.
Yeah. I mean, as in like,
almost everyone in life has to like,
you know,
SLAAC it up and just get on with things
because things like it, but like,
I have a kind of quite visceral,
emotional reaction against being bored.
And that does, um, and that
does influence things. Uh,
the other thing you touched upon there,
which I think is such a good
subject is intuition because,
um,
the
process of rational need
justifying to yourself,
your action is it incredibly slow,
um,
full of like grayness and
complexity and generally,
um,
like
yeah,
it's like,
um,
it's sort of 5% efficient process of
moving forward in one's ideas and beliefs.
Uh, because you know, you're like, ah,
you know, we should really do this in the,
you know, on memorize or you
know, we share or um, I think I,
I think this girl is like the
personal I want to marry, but,
and then you, if you allow Russian,
I [inaudible] into this. Um,
you end up with like,
um,
a situation where all the energy is
going in the wrong place. It's like,
but on the other hand, he didn't
eat. She is, she know she,
when are you going to get along
with me and old age and like,
what kind of person am I really
looking to connect with them and say,
you know,
you could,
you can sort of double question yourself
to death though the on most things and
when you know, when life
is really, really good,
one isn't like pissing around like going,
oh, I really where I go in. I'm like,
ah, you know, it's, you know, it should I
turn left or right out of the door to day.
You know,
you end up,
it's going to existential burden's ass
stuck between a million possibilities and
never really doing anything right.
When things are going really well,
you're just like, this feels
right. You might be wrong.
Thank give a shit. Let's go.
And that is sad. Agentic and this is
actually something, I mean I've, I've,
I've really had a journey in this
within the, uh, within, uh, because, um,
because um, my intention where
they actually isn't at all with,
um, we're helping people
remember more effectively,
which is the kind of thing you might do
to a computer chip or know that is a,
an element in something
much more interesting,
which is like helping
people feel like a genius.
So helping people love the world they're
learning about or helping people just
get pleasure out of their minds and the
visions that their consciousness and
learning.
Um,
and one of the things about like as I
think it is probably true in almost any
profession because it starts out you've
got this thing where you're like,
you've got the,
the,
the push and shove between what happens
in one month's time and what happens in
12 months time and um, and so,
and all the time you're like,
wow. Um, yeah,
this idea we've had would be absolutely
incredible and would make people feel
like geniuses.
But on the other hand,
it's not going to move any
metrics for two months.
And it sounds a bit
irresponsible. And whatever.
I'd start in the early days, for
instance, I had this idea of the, um,
what we should cause we know
we're fundamentally like
a language learning side.
Um, and I had this idea that
we should all get on a bus,
like a converted double decker bus
and just go around Europe. You know,
a lot of coders, designers,
you know, the whole team.
I just got on a fucking road trip around
Europe and it would just be incredible.
It just be the best idea
ever. So, um, and you know,
we've learned so much about language and
it would have been an incredibly fun,
diverse, interesting experience. Um,
and it would have been a wonderful
way of getting PR and the rest of it.
But on the other hand, and this is
where rationality came in, you know,
what the hell are you doing?
You're supposed to be doing a startup,
you're in a bus going around Europe,
um, where he could asleep. Um,
exactly what function does this
have for the product, you know,
and so they're really, another thing
has come in and you're like, well,
and so that was,
that was an example of where intuition
was watered by kind of banal kind of self
recriminating rationality resulting in,
I'm,
I'm almost certain like a less
interesting product and less fun.
Now you bring up a really interesting,
uh,
you bring up a really interesting
set of questions and this is,
this is something that at
times I do better with at
times I do more poorly with,
but I've tried to at various
points in my life, um,
make increased the speed with
which I make decisions. So if a,
if a decision is
reversible and a nonfatal,
then I find my life is generally much
better when I just do exactly what you
mentioned, which is like left, right?
Who gives a fuck? I'm going right.
It'll be fine. And if it's
not, I'll figure it out later.
And making these types of reversible
decisions as quickly as possible so that
you don't have a lot of cognitive burden
and you're not sort of stuck up your
own ass all the time. Um, but
in the case of the bus, yeah,
the business, let's just say
or uh, how do you balance the,
in the intuition,
which at some at times can be an
irrational exuberance with yeah,
the sort of proof prefrontal
cortex calculation. Yeah.
Well that's, I, that's the question.
This episode of the Tim Ferriss show
is brought to you by 99 designs.
99 designs is the world's largest online
marketplace of graphic designers and I
have used 99 designs for years,
including to get cover concepts
for the four hour body,
which went on to become number
one New York Times number one,
Wall Street Journal.
It was a huge hit.
And here's how it works and
you can check everything out,
including some of my competitions.
You can see these book covers
and so on@ninetyninedesigns.com
forward slash. Tim,
whether you need a logo, a car wrap,
a webdesign and af, a thumbnail,
a tee shirt,
whatever.
You go to 99 designs.com
you describe your project,
and then within a week or less,
you have tons of designers around the
world who compete for your business and
submit different ideas
and designs and drafts.
You have an original design that you
love or you pay nothing. It is fantastic.
I have used it.
I have mentioned it before,
including in the four hour work
week as a resource. Check it out,
99 designs.com forward slash Tim,
and if you use that link,
you'll be able to see what
I've done on the platform.
You will also get $99
as an upgrade for free,
which will get you more designs,
more submissions. So check it out,
and until next time,
thank you for listening.
Okay? Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Yeah.