The common characteristic of the people
who had the most time and the highest
income is the ability to single task.
So single tasking being the
opposite of multitasking.
So to identify the
critical few objectives,
separate them from the trivial many
and focus exclusively on one of them to
completion without interruption.
Because the
default mode in especially a web 2.0 user
generated universe and I would include
email and user generated is it's very
easy to simulate forward motion without
accomplishing anything. And you cannot
possibly as much as we'd like to think so,
uh, organize and consume the
information that is presented to you.
So the only option left is to cultivate
this selective ignorance where you act
on the most important things. So I'll,
I'll, I want to hit a few concepts,
a few findings that you can
apply immediately and then
we'll jump into Q. And. A.
So the first is a concept you may be
familiar with called the 80 20 principle.
Hence,
you could look at a company like Ryan Air,
which has some ridiculous number,
like one point $4 million of
profit per employee. Okay.
There's a related principle
called Parkinson's law, uh, which I'd like
to explain briefly and then people can,
can play with it.
Parkinson's law indicates that a task
will swell and perceived importance and
complexity in direct correlation to
the time that you allotted. Okay.
So we generally think that if I have
more time I'll do a better job. Uh,
this is very,
very seldom the case.
So there are actually two ways that
you can identify the critical few and
separate them from the trivial many.
Number one is to do an 80,
20 analysis with the
metrics that you've chosen.
And the number two is to limit the time,
so to use very short deadlines.
So in essence,
you're limiting the tasks to very few
to limit the time invested or you're
limiting the time invested to force you
to focus on the critical few decreasing
inputs.
And increasing output I
think is the easiest way to
frame how we want to look at
time. And, uh, there are a few
ways to do that, but one of the,
one of the key variables
as information intake.
So you can either consume information
or you can focus on production and you
could really can't do
both at the same time.
It's a one way street before you
look at delegating, you can automate,
but related to both of those is
taking the most time consuming tasks.
So there will be some that remain and
really defining the process. Okay.
Now this sounds like Gobbledygook tech
business talk and I'll put it into
concrete terms.
Most people check email in very,
very specific ways and email being one
of the most time consuming activities.
They're afraid of outsourcing that or
delegating it to someone else because I'm
the only one who can check my email.
Well,
the fact of the matter is I get somewhere
between four and 5,000 email a week.
Okay.
So it's,
I'm pretty sure I'm at the top of the
room here or at least towards the top and
I have multiple email accounts
and multiple people helping me.
But one of my key assistants
has a document called Tim
Ferriss processing rules
and this is a working document
of explicitly how I check email.
So I had to take my internal process
and define it and put it on paper.
What am I looking for? How do I decide
which I reply to which I delete,
which I postpone.
How do I archive?
And she has essentially a step by
step guide to my cognitive process for
processing email.
She receives 90% of my
email goes through it.
And then each day we have
a call at 4:00 PM where it,
she'll have the name of the
person, company affiliation,
what they want me to do.
All the rest are details.
So those are the three top disqualifiers
I've taken a task that would take me
well over a hundred hours a week and it
drops it down to less than five minutes
a day. I listened to her voicemail.
As I'm typing out the email,
she numbers each of the to do items.
So I just do one, do this, two do this,
three do this. Okay. And
that's not limited to CEOs.