Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism living.
This episode is brought
to you by four sigmatic.
You might remember Fort Sigmadek
for their mushroom coffee,
which was created by those clever finished
founders and when I first mentioned
that coffee on this podcast,
the product sold out in less than a week.
It lights you up like a Christmas tree,
which can be really useful. However,
recently I've been testing the opposite
side of the spectrum of new product and
that is their Reishi mushroom elixir
to help me end my day to get to sleep.
As you guys may know,
longtime listeners,
at least I struggled with
insomnia for decades.
I have a largely fixed that but still
shutting off my monkey brain has never
been easy, still isn't easy
very often and I found Reishi,
which I've been fascinated by for
a few years now, has been very,
very effective and
calming their old formula,
however four Sigmadek old formula
included Stevia and I like to avoid
sweeteners,
all sweeteners for a host of reasons
and I then just ping them and asked,
hey guys, I would love to experiment
with this and maybe actually suggested,
but I'd like a version without
sweeteners if you'd be open to it,
if too much of a headache,
don't worry.
And they are always game
for experimentation.
So they created a special custom version
without the Stevia, without sweeteners.
Now it is part of my nightly routine.
Their ratio elixir comes
in single serving packets,
which are perfect for travel and in fact
I'm about to leave the country right
now and I have a packet in front of me.
This just going to sit in
the end of my carry on bag.
You only need hot water and it mixes very,
very easily.
Here's some recommended copy
that they put in the read,
so I'm going to read it and then
I'll give you my take quote,
a warning for those in
the experimental mindset,
Reishi is strong and bitter in
parentheses, like any great medicine.
So if the bitterness is too much,
I recommend trying it with honey end or
nut milk such as almond milk and quote.
So I'm going to say no,
you should suck it up and you should drink
the tea because it's not that bitter.
And maybe should take the advice of all
Chinese people when they're criticizing
younguns. When they say
Boone Ung. Sure. Cool.
Which means you're not able to eat
bitterness. Bitter is in many cases,
an indication of things that help
liver detoxification and so on.
Not saying that's the case here,
but I've tested this ratio
lecture on family members,
on friends. Everybody has liked it. It's
a little bit earthy. It's not that hard.
So I would just say suck it up and no,
don't put in honey or milk or any of
that shit. Just drink the goddamn tea.
It's delicious, I think. Right? If
you like poo air, that kind of stuff,
that type of tea, you're going
to dig it. So just try it. Okay.
Back to then my read. If you'd like
to naturally improve your sleep,
both onset and quality,
I think naturally you might just enjoy
this ratio lecture without any sweet
nurse. It has organic, Reishi
extract, organic fueled, mint extract,
organic rose hips extract, organic
Tulsi extract. And that's it.
No fancy stuff, no artificial watching
McCall at anything. So check it out.
Go to foursigmatic.com forward slash
and Ferris and get 20% off this special
batch. I don't know if they're gonna
be making much more of this, uh,
it since it was made specifically for
you guys to do me a favor and try it out
so that they continue to be
open to experimenting with
me to create products for
you guys. Specifically. Check it out.
Four sigmatic, that's Fou, R, s, I g,
m, a t, I c.com. Forward
Slash Ferris, F, e R, r, I s,
s and get 20% off the special batch.
And you must use the code a Ferris
to receive a discount. F. E. R,
R I s.
S.
So again going to foursigmatic.com forward
slash Ferris and then use code Ferris
for 20% off of this rare exclusive
limited run of Reishi mushroom elixir for
nighttime routines with
out any sweeteners. Enjoy.
This episode is brought to you
by fresh books, man. Oh Man.
Do a lot of listeners of this podcast
and readers of mine love fresh books to
the extent that I ended up meeting
with the CEO not very long ago.
Why are they so popular?
Well,
they are the number one cloud accounting
software designed exclusively for self
employed professionals.
That's many of you and used by
more than 10 million people.
You can send invoices, track your
time, and get paid very, very quickly,
which suits the needs of a
lot of freelancers, a lot
of [inaudible] and beyond.
You can't take pictures of receipts.
You can link your credit
card and debit card,
so all the things you buy automatically
appear in your fresh books in the right
category, so on and so forth. Makes
taxes easy, makes invoices easy,
it makes your life easier.
And also in fact I would recommend a pdf.
Uh, they didn't ask me to
read this part by the way.
They'd put the other pdf a while back
called breaking the time barrier subtitle,
how to unlock your true earning potential
so you can search for breaking the
time barrier.
A lot of people ask me,
how can I get a four hour work
week with a service business?
And the story in that Ebook, it's pdf is
the short answer is really, really good.
So I think you should also check that out.
So breaking the time error,
checking out,
but also why not test out freshbooks.
Claim your 30 day unrestricted free
trial@freshbooks.com forward slash Tim and
enter timferriss two rs and two ss in
the how did you hear about us section?
That sounds like we're going to get very
little tracking. That's a lot of work.
But just go to freshbooks.com forward
slash Tim and tried out because it is a
very good product and I think you
will find it simplifies your life.
Joy.
Hello boys and girls,
ladies and germs.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss Show where
it is my job every episode to
deconstruct world class performers,
people who are excellent, if not the
best at what they do in many, many,
many different fields.
And that scratchiness is Tim Ferriss
coming off of antibiotics because I had
some little gremlins inside me that
I brought back from the Amazon.
That's a separate story. In
any case, my job dot. De de,
De de, De, de construct, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah many fields.
And this particular episode
we have a wonderful guest,
Jack Kornfield.
Alice Walker Calls Jack Quote,
one of the greatest spiritual teachers
of our time and quit jack trained as a
Buddhist monk in the monasteries
of Thailand, India and
Burma. Shortly thereafter,
becoming one of the key teachers to
introduce Buddhist mindfulness practice to
the West.
He has taught meditation internationally
since 1974 that's before I was even a
glimmer in my papa die.
So it's been teaching for a very,
very long time and he has had a profound
and direct impact directly on my life.
So I'm thrilled to finally have him on
the podcast to share our shared history,
his incredible stories and the practical
tactics and very detailed techniques
that you can use and we
dig into all of that.
You can also say hi to him on the
Internet at Jack Kornfield on Twitter.
Check it out. Jack's history.
Just a little bit, won't
spend too much time on it.
Jack cofounded,
the insight meditation society in Barre,
Massachusetts with fellow meditation
teachers, Sharon Salzberg,
who's also been on this podcast and
Joseph Goldstein and the later the spirit
rock center in Woodacre, California, which
is where I did my first silent retreat.
And we talk about that.
He holds a phd in clinical psychology,
which is important to me and comes into
this conversation because he's a very,
very diverse toolkit for dealing
with many different types of personal
challenges, issues, questions and so on.
And as a father, husband and activist,
his books have been translated into 20
languages and sold more than a million
copies. He is prolific. His books include,
and I pulled some of you for
your favorites, a wise heart.
That's number one,
a lamp in the darkness,
a path with heart after the ecstasy,
the laundry,
one of my favorite book title of all time.
And his most recent book,
no time like the present subtitle,
finding freedom,
love and joy right where you are.
He is quite possibly the most purely
compassionate human being I've ever
interacted with. And compassion
isn't a word that I use very much,
but Jack is unique and I'm thrilled to
give you a window into his story and his
teachings.
Without further ado,
please enjoy this wide ranging
conversation with Jack Cornfield.
Jack, welcome to the show. Oh, thank
you Tim. And pleasure to reconnect.
I have
wanted to have you on the show for some
time now and you've had certainly a
tremendous impact on my life,
uh,
both through your writing and through
a firsthand in person interaction,
which I think we'll touch upon.
But first I wanted to ask you a
complete non sequitur from that,
which is something that our mutual friend,
Adam Gazzaley suggested I ask you about.
And Adam,
for people who don't know
him is an incredible, uh,
PhD MD neuroscientist based at UCF.
And he suggested that I
ask you about hang gliding.
And I have no idea why he suggested that,
but I'm going to start there.
And if it doesn't go anywhere,
we can, we can change direction.
But I figured we would just start with
that and then we're going to rewind the
clock. But why did he suggest
I ask you about hang gliding?
Well,
it started many years ago when I cross
country with a friend who had a hang
glider and we would stop periodically
and go off different hills.
Um,
and it was fantastic.
And then I wanted to do paragliding
and started to learn it.
Now because everything is developed
and paragliding slot, you know,
is a lot more official. You need
a license, which I don't have,
but one of my favorite things is to
tandem paraglide and go off the top of
places like Grindle walled in, uh, uh,
in Switzerland where you can take the
ski lift up to 9,000 feet and then jump
off and float silently.
Like you're a bird among the clouds.
The birds actually do come by sometimes
and like check out what's this big bird
flying up here? You can catch thermals
and go way up above the glaciers.
And um,
it's one of the most thrilling and
delicious experiences that I know.
That's incredible. So you've, you
first experienced that at what age?
Uh, probably in my late twenties. Um,
and did some and then
sort of put it aside. Uh,
and then I was traveling
and teaching in Europe. Um,
and I saw a sign for paragliding and I
said, oh gosh, I really want to do it.
Um,
and started and now each time I go where
there's high mountains and paragliding,
that's one of my things that I love
doing. You know, there's something about,
I've had most people have these dreams
once in a while. If you're lucky,
a dream of flying or maybe in your
meditation you have the sense of not being
limited to your body. Um, and,
and this is the closest thing that I
know cause it's absolutely silent and
you're floating there.
It's quite fantastic.
And this is something you still do it
and hope to do it and hope to do it next
summer when I'm back in the Alps.
And how, how old are you now? 72
72. Good man. Well,
we're going to then go back a bit in
chronology and ask about childhood.
I would love to hear you
describe your childhood.
What were you like as a child?
What was your upbringing like?
Well,
first thing to say is,
I remember when I got to
Dartmouth College in 1963,
um,
and I called my mom from the payphone
in the dorm sometime in that fall.
I didn't call very often, but you
know how it is. And I said, mom,
I said,
guess what?
There are a lot of other really
fucked up fat is the side.
So that's kind of where we,
where we, where we start. So, uh,
there, uh, yeah, I had three,
three brothers and my father was a mixture
of a tyrant and in a really abusive
person and a brilliant guy.
Um,
I was born on and on the Marine base in,
uh,
toward the end of World War Two.
And they didn't send him overseas to do,
they put him in the medical part of the
marines because he tested so high on
their tests that they, you know, okay,
we're gonna use them for something. Um,
so he was brilliant in certain
ways. He was a biophysicist who, uh,
help design some of the first
artificial hearts and lungs.
Worked on the space program,
but also did other kinds of weird
stuff like work for the army,
um, biological weapons, people
not making biological weapons.
We're trying to design things
that were kind of computer,
um, biological interfaces, all
kinds of creative stuff. But he was,
uh,
he was all,
he had mental problems and so we
didn't know when the car pulled in,
whether we were going to get Dr Jekyll
and Mr. Hyde. He would come in and,
you know, either he
could shout, be abusive.
Thrilled my mother down the stairs, rant,
Jace after us strive to hit us, whatever.
Or We'd get this
interesting creative person.
But we hardly ever had people come over
when he was around during the daytime is
a way we would, um, because you never
knew what you would get. And so, um,
our family life in my family
life in some way was also,
there were great parts of it cause I
had my brothers and we were like our own
gang. We moved all the time,
but we had each other. Um,
and because he was a
wacky as well as smart,
my father either quit or
got fired every year or two,
and then we would go from one place
to another. I went to, I dunno,
eight schools by the time
I finished high school. Um,
so my childhood, uh, partly it was,
there were the happy of rough
housing and being a boy with,
with three other boys,
um, uh, and adventures.
Um, and then in the basement, my father
had all kinds of scientific equipment.
He had all this stuff from World War II,
this huge radio from a battleship that
you could tune into a thousand different,
you know, shortwave stations
around the world. Um, and projects.
He was trying to design stuff.
And so we learned from him,
you could pretty much take or design
or do anything in the physical world.
Um, and at the same time, uh,
I felt like my whole childhood was also,
uh,
how to say it colored with the fear of
his violence and his unpredictability.
Um, so and I became kind of
a peacemaker in the family.
We all sort of had our roles and duck.
Now I do it as a profession, right?
I'm trying to kind of make it a little
smoother between my parents so they kill
each other. Um, and each of my
brothers had their own strategy.
My twin brother who was a lot
bigger, um, and much more outgoing,
um, who played football, which I certainly
didn't. I was skinnier and you know,
I was in the orchestra and he was
the football player. But anyway,
I remember when he first got in a
fist fight with my dad cause
my father was abusing, um,
our mom and,
um,
my twin brother had been as young men
sometimes do that was probably 13,
14. I mean, grew pretty big and it
was looking in the mirror, you know,
making muscles in the mirror to see how
strong he'd become. Anyway, he just,
you know, uh, got into a fist
fight with my father. Um,
and I was both thrilled and terrified.
Um,
and uh, but it worked in some
way because of the abuse, uh,
settled down quite a lot after that.
So that was his,
his strategy was just to get angry and
then later kind of to go his own way.
Somewhat moral though. We're all all
had been very close as brothers. Um,
so there was that at the same
time there was a lot of interest,
intellectual interest. So we read and
learned about all kinds of things.
Both my parents were, um, really
interested in the world around us.
And, um, uh,
so it was sort of this
mixed a thing of the,
you know,
the gift of being together
with my brothers and a mom
who was basically pretty
nurturing,
although she kept trying to leave
him and never got it together.
I think it was too scary in the 50s
to have four boys, you know, no job.
Um, and so we were in the middle of
this and the kind of healing that it,
it took a long time,
um,
to do the inner healing work from,
the pain of my family.
Um,
and I remember when I became a Buddhist
monk and I was sitting these first years
with my teacher,
Rajan Cha in the forest monasteries of
Thailand on the border of Thailand and
Laos.
Um,
and I've been sitting quietly and then
some of these memories are energy would
come where I remember one monk who
had a hot near mine and the forest did
something that annoyed me and
I just got enraged inside.
And I sat and then I went to the
teacher and I said, you know, um,
I'm really getting angry here.
And, uh, he smiled. He said, yeah,
we're, where do you think that comes from?
Or something like that. And I said, well,
I don't know. I said, I
thought it was a peaceful guy.
It wasn't never going to be like my
father. I won't, you know, be peaceful.
But it turned out I just
stuffed all that stuff.
And so when I told my teacher
about it, he said, good. He said,
go back in your heart.
It's the hot season.
You've got a little tin roof and close
the doors and windows and put all your
robes on. And if you're going to be angry,
do it right. Sit in the middle of that,
you know,
and sit in the middle of the fire and
don't be so afraid of it because you're
afraid of it. You're just going to keep
stuffing it. And on the other hand,
or if you're afraid of it,
it'll just explode. There's
another way to be with it.
Um, and so that was the
beginning of some healing,
just to realize that I could
actually tolerate the suffering. Um,
and the energy that was in my still
carried from trauma in my body and heart.
So we're going to absolutely come
back to [inaudible] cause I have many
questions on that chapter in your life,
but just,
just so that I can create the
proper visual in my own head.
So you sat there in your hut in the
sweltering heat with all of your robes on
when you were,
were you angry in silence?
Well, I was pretty much angry in silence.
And that's an interesting question.
Yeah. I, you know, in the
monastery, the culture was not,
was not much that you would yell,
you could go somewhere out in
the forest and yell, but it was,
it wasn't decorous or something. People
are with the Hell's wrong with that monk.
Um, so mostly, uh,
I was sitting in silence and then scenes
would come. Then I would realize, wow,
you know, I thought I was
peaceful. I carry every,
in every cell of my body.
I also carry both the pain and anger,
my childhood and my father,
and just the,
the anger that comes with being a
human being and human incarnation.
And I was never going to have that,
but of course there it was. Um,
and it lasted, you know, this was,
I had days of and, and actually,
um,
much longer weeks or months of waves of,
of this coming and learning how to,
you know,
be present it and not
get overwhelmed by it.
So I want to backtrack and
then connect those dots.
So between childhood and
ending up in Thailand,
you mentioned Dartmouth earlier
and from what I've read,
at least you were initially premed
and then ended up Asian Studies.
Could you describe that experience in
Dartmouth or how you went from premed to
Asian Studies?
Well,
you know,
we all get turned in these
mysterious ways in our life.
We think we're going one direction and
then something happens unexpectedly and a
gateway opens.
So I was coming from an organic chemistry
class to the class that I'd signed up
for out of interest on Asian Studies,
uh,
raise in philosophy or something.
And it was an old professor
and doctor winks it.
Chan who would come up from Harvard.
He was kind of emeritus there.
Um,
and he even said cross-legged,
sometimes, you know,
in the front of the room and would
talk about loud too. And that was him.
And they talk about Buddhist teachings
and how the Buddha taught suffering and
its causes and its end.
And that really all of a sudden I sat up,
I said, there's an end of suffering,
there's a way to do. And he said, oh,
there's all these teachings and practices
where you can transform your heart and
mind.
And I became thrilled about it and realize
that whatever impulse I had to go to
medical school,
um,
probably part of it came from
wanting to heal myself. Um,
and so I started taking more and
more courses and then it was,
it was the 60 [inaudible] and I
became a card carrying hippie.
I'm a card carrying LSD,
taking hippie as a matter of fact.
And um,
Eh, at the end of, in, yeah,
when I was getting ready to graduate,
there was still the draft and I thought,
well I'm definitely know we want to go
over and kill people in a war that I,
that I've been protesting
it protesting against. Um,
so I decided to go into the Peace Corps
instead and ask them to send me to a
Buddhist country where
maybe I could find it.
One of those old Zen masters
that you read about, um,
and got assigned to Thailand.
Um, and when I got there,
um,
people you could kind of request
where you went, they, and, and I said,
send me to the most remote place you can.
I wanted adventure.
But I also wanted to kind of
reading all those old zen stories.
I wanted to see if that,
that still existed. So, um,
you know,
and there were little detours like being
in Haight Ashbury in the summer of love
and things like that,
that definitely, um, they,
it changed my life also
in a very deep way, um,
because for at least for a time,
there was a window when people
were just giving things away.
There was such a sense that the
world could be transformed. Um,
some of it as we know, very, very
naive. One in the other hand,
it also felt like a greater sense of
brotherhood and sisterhood than I had ever
known. Um, um,
except with my own brothers who I love
a lot and we've done a lot of things
together and I started to feel like
there are other ways for me and for the
world to be and live. Um, and
that was, that was also very,
um,
wonderful.
You mentioned,
you mentioned a three letter acronym that
we're probably not going to spend too,
too much time on, but I, I, you and I,
you and I have had quite a number of
conversations where I've wanted to ask you
about some of your experiences,
uh, with psychedelics,
including LSD,
but we've never really gotten into it.
So I figure why not do it in front
of a few million people, uh, the,
the Lsd at that point,
your experiences with that,
did that inform your decisions at all to
then go into the peace corps and end up
in a remote area?
It did.
And I've written out a little bit about
it and in a couple of different of my
books and chapters in books I've
written because I'm the most,
oh, Buddhist teachers and
teachers of my generation, um,
also started with academics.
You know,
myself and almost all my
colleagues, um, you know,
in the spiritual industry that I'm in,
um, that was the beginning and for me,
um,
it showed an incredible possibility that
all is created out of consciousness.
Um, and the possibilities
of inner freedom and,
or basically I was able at the,
at the best of it to see
my body and my personality,
um,
and my history and realized that that's
not who I am to become much more the
conscious witness of it all.
To See yes,
birth and death and to go through
those kind of, um, uh, death,
rebirth experiences that can happen,
um,
at times in a deep session with Lsd or
death of ego or sense of self or removing
and realizing, wow, there's
a freedom and a life force.
It's what we're made of.
Um,
and that profoundly influenced my interest
in spirituality and also interest in
what the world can be. Now.
Um, just a few days ago,
I was on,
um,
loudly with my beloved wife Trudy.
Um,
and we were visiting
spending time with Ron Doss,
who for listeners that don't know,
was I'm the author of this bestseller
in the 60s called be here now and now,
easy 86 and in a wheelchair.
Um, but Ron Doss,
who had been at Harvard University and
was one of the early explorers of LSD
before he went to India and
became a spiritual teacher, um,
uh,
in the living room while we
were there two days ago. Um,
Roland Fischer,
who is one of the senior professors in
psychopharmacologists at Johns Hopkins
University Medical School over rolling,
rolling, rolling, rolling. Griffis rather,
and Roland, excuse me, Roland
Griffiths and Roland, um,
laid out all the research that's happening
now on the silicide and that he's
been doing and it's success for people,
terminal cancer patients,
all of losing a great deal of their,
the fears that they had. Um, uh,
working with people with
severe depression. Um,
and it was a beautiful session because
you could hear how these sacred
substances and these mind altering
substances when they're used in the right
context, can really
transform human beings. Um,
and Nyu Johns Hopkins,
there's a whole series of studies that
are happening now that are finally
bringing it back into the mainstream.
So I'd love to underscore just a few
things that you mentioned. Uh, number one,
uh, Ron Doss, for those people
who want to do additional reading,
formerly known as Richard Alpert,
if I'm getting that right,
also has a fascinating story coming
full circle with psychedelic research
beginning, I guess at Harvard in some
respects as it makes sense to me,
why Roland's research would
be so meaningful to him. Uh,
and a number of other, just,
just quick comments for people.
Number one is if you're interested in,
in looking into these sole Simon,
which is,
uh,
considered the active psychoactive
ingredient in magic mushrooms,
uh,
at Johns Hopkins and elsewhere,
I've actually been involved with
a crowdfunding and funding myself,
some of the research related to a
treatment resistant depression, uh,
at Johns Hopkins with Roland Griffiths
as the senior investigator. Uh,
and I'll be posting some updates to that.
But fascinating work
looking at everything from,
and this is also as you mentioned,
Nyu and at other very well
regarded universities,
uh,
alcohol addiction,
nicotine slash tobacco
addiction as you mentioned, uh,
end of life anxiety in cancer patients.
The implications are,
are really profound and the data very,
very promising.
And I wanted to also mention to folks who
are perhaps saying to themselves, well,
I'm interested in taking
cell psychedelics myself,
that there are people I know,
good friends of mine who do
not currently use psychedelics,
but had the ego dissolving,
a experience of a non ordinary reality
through psychedelics that then led them
to become, uh, or contributed to
them becoming very, very delicate,
diligent meditators.
S and, uh, Sam Harris,
who's a phd in neuroscience,
uh,
and thought of are very well
known as a and an atheist.
Uh,
or you know,
one of the four horsemen of the atheist
apocalypse along with Richard Dawkins
and others, uh, is a very close friend
and extremely diligent meditator.
And He's, he's written about
how his psychedelic experiences,
which were in some respects very,
some of them uncontrolled and you
really have a coin flip there. Uh,
it's in terms of which
direction you can go,
but showed him possibilities within
his own mind that then led to a very,
very, uh, I'm not going to call it devout,
although I should just a
bathroom diligent practice.
So I don't want to take
us too far off the rails,
but you go to Southeast Asia.
Oh, sure. We move on because
we are talking about this.
It turns out for those who were listening,
that set and setting an intention
are extremely important.
If one uses these psychedelics
like psilocybin or something
to set the intention
to learn, to open, to have a quiet,
it's not, not as a party experience,
absolutely makes,
you know,
brings your attention inward.
And then all the kinds of discoveries,
um,
become right in front of
your right in front of you.
Um,
the,
but the other thing is that whether it's
right for somebody to use psychedelics
or do you use meditation,
these are all, uh,
invitations to step back and
see the mystery of your life.
Because we tend to live in the,
you know,
daily Minutia and checking off our
list of tasks that we have to do and
completing them by work or,
or you know,
or eating or all the kind of things
that make up a day and we go on to
automatic.
Um,
and whether it's meditation and difference
or other spiritual disciplines or for
some people it also can just be that
they have what in Greek is called a Kata
Bossam below, you know, somebody
close to them gets cancer or,
or is dying or they have some accident
or something and all of a sudden you sit
back and you realize, whoa, life is an
uncertain the way I've been taking it.
It's not just checking off the list and
this is a mystery human incarnation and
what am I going to do with it? And Wow
at this, how did I get in this body?
Look at plants and trees. And, and, um,
language that air coming out of your
mouth that you shape it different ways in
it vibrates a little drum
and the ear of someone else.
And I can say Golden Gate
Bridge and they can envision it.
And you start to realize that all of
it is alive and made of consciousness.
And then the whole sense of who you
are and what matters begins to shift.
And you start to realize that life is
not just getting through the hoops,
but it actually also can be a celebration
of the heart of something that you
have to bring to the world that you come
out of life. And my friend melanoma.
So Mary, who's a west African
Shaman and medicine man,
also two PhDs are kind of remarkable guy.
Um,
he says with the dog or up people in
West Africa that he's from that um,
they say that every child
comes into the world, uh,
with a certain cargo.
Is there a metaphor like the cargo ships
that ply the rivers of West Africa and
that,
that they're given gifts to bring into
the world and that we have gifts to bring
to this mystery which
include opening to it.
And as we do love grows,
connection grows and in a whole different
way of being in the world happens that
we need, um, so much at this time.
So that's a little interlude there.
Before we move on to the net,
your next question,
I welcome as many interludes as you would
like to interject and I wanted to just
ask you to say one more time that it was,
I believe Greek word for caught them off,
which means a blow.
It's like something comes and it just
sets your life spinning an entirely
different direction. Right? Like a
catalyzing event and that the, exactly,
I've had a few of those recently that I'd
like to selfishly ask you about later,
but I can bookmark just so
I can bookmark this name,
uh, s uh, Stanislav Grof if
I'm saying that correctly.
That's correct.
When just when did you meet him?
Roughly what age or what date,
just so I can come back to it because
this is another thing I've been meaning to
ask you about for a long time and get
into. But I haven't had the chance.
So I had, there's two things to say. Um,
when I came back from the
monastery and now it's,
you know, I guess the year that I
connect with Stan was maybe 1973.
I made two really important connections,
right.
And came back and start
eight psychology in graduate
school. Um, I was in Boston. Um,
and first really important connection
happened when I went to a meeting of the
Massachusetts Psychological Association.
And there was this guy who looked like he,
he didn't look just like the straight
psychologists and it turned out he'd just
come back from India not long before
named Dan Goleman, who was it,
who was a graduate student at Harvard
and he had projected on the screen this
Tibetans wheel of birth and death that
you see in the Tibetan Tonka is that that
normally would be taken as
some kind of affirmative, um,
icon, iconic, uh, you know,
symbol. And he said, no,
no,
this is a psychological diagram.
The Buddha was actually
more than anything else. Um,
he was a scientist of the mind and a us,
a profound psychologists.
And here is how craving
turns into contentment,
and here's how aggression can be
transformed into powerful energy to heal
yourself and others.
And he were going through this diagram
and I went and I talked to him and he
said, Oh, you, you come back from
monastery, you've got to come over. Um,
and so he took me to David Mcclellan,
who had been the chairman of the social
science and Psychology Department at
Harvard at that time,
the one who hired Tim leary and Ram Das.
And then later had to fire
them for their LSD work. Um,
and his house, he and his
wife Mary, were Quakers.
His home was a kind of soiree,
um,
where Ron doss and Tibetan lamas like
Chogyam Trungpa and I think Krishna Murti
and various spiritual figures would come.
Um,
people were going to MBN
coming back. Um, and, and, um,
I connected with this whole group of
folks who have now been friends for 45
years. Um, Richie Davidson
was another that I met there,
who's now one of the preeminent
neuroscientists in the world on studying
contemplative neuroscience and an
affective emotional neuroscience.
It was a whole collective of people,
Dan Goleman who wrote
emotional intelligence that
sold 10 million copies and
many others.
And then I got a job working for a,
an Esselyn like growth center in Boston
at that time cause I was excited at all
the new gestalt bioenergetics what are
the things that are transformative here.
Um, and they asked me to help set
up programs and I thought, well,
who do I want to,
who do I want to meet?
So I set up a program with John Lilly
and I set up a program with Stan Grof who
was still at Johns Hopkins and married
at that time just married to Joan,
Halifax, Joan Groff. And we
became friends. And so we've,
Stan and I have now worked
together for 45 years.
I went out to join him at SLN for many,
many years,
spending many months together,
helping during his development of the
holotropic breath work that's at this
powerful breath transformation. And, um,
he has been a partner and a,
and a in a heart friend for exploration.
And we've traveled where we've
taught in Russia and in, you know,
places in Europe and various
places around the world.
So this is,
this is definitely a path that we're
going to come down and dig further into,
but I, I'm going to steer us to, uh,
[inaudible] I want to know how do you
land with the Peace Corps in ever more
remote?
Well,
what most people would consider a
remote corner of the world and ended up
finding a living master. How does
that, how does that actually happen?
I don't know. I, but I assume you
didn't speak Thai at the time.
I did actually did the Peace Corps.
Right.
And then I had to learn Lao.
I did because the Peace
Corps at that time,
it was a very early in the peace corps
had really good language training.
They borrowed it from the Monterey
Language Institute. So, you know,
initially I didn't speak that well,
but um,
because I'd also studied Chinese
at Dartmouth, he came more easily.
Um, and I was there working in these, um,
in the health rural health department,
on tropical medicine teams,
mostly malaria,
but also typhoid and teams going up
to different villages and taking,
drawing blood and um,
giving out medicine and things like that.
And then somebody said,
there's a,
there's a western bank in this
province we heard about, um,
do you want to meet her? I
said, of course I do. So I,
I went to this little mountain and
walked up to thousand steps to the old
Cambodian temple, ruined at the top.
And there was this very interesting guy,
um,
who had just finished a couple of
years before the first peace corps,
I think in Borneo.
And then got interested in Buddhism
and common ordained as a monk.
And I talk with him. He's now, he's
named Dot Johnson. Tomato is, is, um,
amongst name cause he's still a monk.
And he became quite famous and Thailand
and then became the abbot of a temple
in, in England. Um,
and I became friends with
him and he said, oh, I found,
I found a really fine teacher.
He said, you know, a lot of them,
they kind of take you, you're a Westerner
and they treat you special. He said,
this guy doesn't treat you any
differently than anyone else.
He just wants you to do that work,
you know, and learn that, learn,
learn the deepest way you can.
And he's in this forest jungle.
And I said, I'm going
there. So having heard that,
I went and I visited a Jen Cha and he
was a little bit like the Dalai Lama.
He was funny and wise
and very warmhearted,
but also very strict and very demanding.
But he did it in this loving way. Um, and
I thought, okay, this is the real deal.
This guy looks like, uh, like what was
reading about and all those in stories.
So I,
I read that he said to you,
and I'd love for you to tell
us when he said this to you,
I hope you're not afraid to
suffer. Uh, if that's true.
When did he say that in?
Why did he say that?
Hey,
I,
so I visited him a number of times and
told him I was going to become a monk and
then I ordained in the village where
I was living in the peace corps.
People wanted me to do that.
It was a beautiful ritual.
And then after some days,
um,
made my way down to his
temple and he said, that's,
that was his opening gambit. I'm walking
in and did the gate and I see him,
I vow as I'm here and he looks at me,
you know,
kind of leans back a little, a
little skeptical. He said, all right,
I hope you're not afraid to suffer.
Welcome. And it was, it was, uh,
it was like, you know, you didn't come
here just to kind of do some interesting,
cool anthropological experiment
or something like that.
If you're going to do it,
we're going to put you
through the training. Um,
and, and, and he did, but he,
you know, there was like this little
smile as he said it. Like, okay,
you are you up for it? All
right, dude. Come on in.
Well, and what did, what did the
training consist consist of? What were,
what were some of the first things
that you had to do and then what,
what was the suffering that he alluded to?
What were some of,
well, that'd be some examples.
Um, okay. So of course the,
the first training was just how to walk
around and not have my robe, you know,
fall on the ground and embarrass me
and everyone, a hose that comes to,
they all loved it. Oh yeah. All
right. Look at the western. He's,
he can't even wear his
robes, right. Or whatever.
So part of it was just the unfamiliarity
of it culturally and otherwise.
Um, uh, there were the,
there were the two kinds of suffering.
The big suffering of course,
was being alone with my own mind.
I mean, there you go, you know,
having to do hours of meditation,
um,
when I didn't know what
the hell I was doing. Um,
and then as I talked about with anger
or fear or confusion or, you know,
all those kinds of states,
um,
learning to deal in a very
conscious and mindful way.
And then more importantly
in a compassionate way,
in a kind and loving way with all the
energies that make up my humanity and our
humanity. Um, and that means that
when you sit and you get quiet,
anything unfinished in your heart will
also come up all the unfinished business.
So, you know, um,
relationships that I'd had that
ended badly in college or, or,
um,
certainly stuff from my childhood
and family dreams that I carried,
things will fill the, not all
of that up. It's, um, yeah,
my friend Danny,
the mot humorist and writer says,
my mind is like a bad neighborhood.
I try not to go there alone.
And there's some way in
which, um, in community,
sitting together with others in
meditation and then sitting in my hot, um,
it was really facing myself and
my full humanity. That was the,
that was probably the most difficult
thing because then you get insanely bored,
are insanely restless or, and then how
do you deal with all those energies?
Normally what we're restless or bored,
you know, what do we do? We, you know,
um,
open the refrigerator or you know,
go online or something because we can't
be with our own loneliness or fear.
Um,
so those are the inner,
and then there's the outer with bordering
the outer one or ones were things
like, uh, getting up.
The bell would ring at three 30 in the
morning and I'm not an early riser by
nature. I go, Oh God, here
we go. And we walked through.
It was actually very beautiful. Then
we'd walk through the forest at night,
either by moonlight or sometimes you'd
have a tiny little flashlight. Um,
and one of the forest monasteries
where there were a lot of cobras,
we'd have a little stick and you'd tap
the path so that the snakes would know
you would feel you coming and move out
of the way. We wouldn't step on them. Um,
and then we would sit silently for a
couple of hours and then do an hour of
chanting on a hard stone
floor. Mind you, when we,
everybody else seemed comfortable
in my body was killing me. Um,
and then at least once a week we would
sit up all night with the teacher and he
would sit there comfortably meditating,
maybe talking with another colleague that
it would come and we'd just be sitting
and meditating and he would kind of peak
over at us. Like, how are you doing? I go,
God, it's been four hours. When are we,
when is he going to let us go back
to sleep? And he didn't, you know,
so sitting up all night,
um,
it got very cold in the cold season,
and it got insanely hot and hot season.
Um,
and somehow learning to live extremely
simply where the set of sandals and a set
of robes and an alms bowl and then you
would eat what you got offered in the
village. And we would share it in
that monastery with others around us.
Um,
and sometimes you'd get nice food and a
lot of times in the dry season you get
really, really skimpy food and
there wasn't that much to eat. Um,
and so picture a day where you get up
at three 30 in the morning, you know,
um,
you sit for a couple of hours in
meditation and do long than an hour long
chanting on a stone floor. Then it's
getting dawn and you walk barefoot,
you know, three miles, five miles,
10 miles with the alms bowl and a handful
of other monks and get your food and
come back, whatever you've been offered
in. That's the food for the day. Um,
and then you go back to your meditation
or to the work of the monastery of
sewing robes or drawing water
from the well, um, and it's,
you know,
McGee and 105 degrees hot season.
Um,
and uh,
then you go back and you join in the
community for more meditation and then the
teacher smiles and say, how
are you doing? You know? Um,
and then other kinds of practices. For
example, we had a charnel ground there.
And so I've charnel ground,
which is where a cremation ground
where people bodies would be burned.
And so on occasion would go to a
cremation and then sit up all night.
And contemplate death, um, and you know,
look at the body and then watches it
burned and then do these meditations where
you would reflect on,
well,
this is going to happen to the body
that you're inhabiting as well.
Who Do you think you are? Do you think
you're this physical body made of,
you know, hamburgers or lettuce
or whatever you happen to eat?
Is that, are you hamburgers
and let us, you know, or Oh,
where are you?
Your feelings or your thoughts?
Who are he really born into this body?
Um,
like Koans. Um, so anyway,
and the alms bowls.
So you'd be,
did you eat whatever you gathered in
one meal? Was it spread throughout
one meal?
You eat one meal a day,
which makes you very easy
to make your life easy. Um,
and at the same at that monastery,
things were shared.
There was other monasteries I stayed in
where you would just eat what was put in
your own bowl. Um, uh, and, um,
you didn't have to eat
everything that was given to you.
There were some things that were,
you know,
in the dry poor season there would be
Curry's that were too hot for me to eat
cause they use the chili's to
kind of um, preserve, preserve,
preserve the food. But you know, when,
when it was a really poor
village or something, you know,
they would have to make curries out of um,
field bias or field new apps
or bat or bats or, you know,
I remember eating, there was a, um,
curry that was made out of basically
the grasshoppers that had come scrap
through and there was this whole
big, you know, insect wave of
insects that were kind of eating the
crops and they, they collected them all,
made curry out of it. So, you know, okay,
this is what you get for your food today,
dude. I think I might take
the grasshoppers over the,
over the bats I, but yeah.
Well yeah, but when it's highly spice, you
can't tell what is mystery. That's true.
We all had mystery meat and middle school.
Anyway,
this was like mystery meat on steroids,
exotic mystery mean.
What was the,
what was the longest period of time that
you spent in silence during that time
in Thailand?
Well,
then I went to a Burmese monastery
because I wanted to do this very intense
meditative training and
I spent about 500 days,
so less,
less than a year and a half in silence.
That with the exception that I
would talk to the teacher, um, uh,
every couple of days I'd have a little
10 minute conversation about what was
happening in my meditation and the rest.
I was just sitting and walking
18 hours a day when I could or,
or so sleeping a little
bit. Um, and I remember
at one point, uh, it
was relatively early on,
I've been sitting and walking and, and
pushing it as young men. Do, you know,
I'm going to get enlightened
and all of that and not moving,
sitting with a lot of pain,
which is also part of what happened that
at the forest monasteries sitting on a
stone floor for hours without moving.
Um,
he really had to learn how to
deal with your own physical pain.
And I was exhausted from sitting and
walking in my little hot that I had for
that long retreat. And after a couple
of months I thought, I'm really tired.
I got to lie down. But
then I thought, well,
but I'm not going to nap
for a very long cause I'm,
I'm on my way to enlightenment,
whatever. Um, I'm going to
do this. Right. So I said,
all right,
I'll lie down on the wooden floor rather
than on the little map that I had and
that way it won't sleep so
long and I'm lying there. Um,
and then I wake up and I get up and I
walked very slowly doing this mindful slow
walking to the end of the hot and look
out the window toward where some of the
other monks in the teachers live in some,
some way down,
some way down through the trees.
Um,
and then I turned around and I start
walking the other direction in this,
this meditation hut that I had.
Then you could walk probably
it was maybe 15, 18 feet long.
It was long and Arrow.
And I see this body lying on the
floor and all of a sudden I go,
oh,
that's me.
And then I realized that I'm
having out of body experience.
And what had happened is that I was so
intent, I'm not going to sleep long.
I'll get up very soon.
That intention was really strong,
but my body didn't want to get
up. So I got up, but it was,
it wasn't in my body.
And I've walked very slowly and I peered
down at my body and I turned around and
walked the other way and walk back.
And then the second time I walked back,
I got closer and then I fell into my
body and I woke up. I said, Oh wow,
that's interesting.
But what I saw out the window,
it wasn't just like a dream
because I was watching, you know,
my teacher and talking to these
other monks. And then I got up again.
And that's exactly what was happening.
And that was the first of a series of
all kinds of very interesting experiences
that happen.
And those
other examples of those
types of unusual experiences.
B and D,
Was it your time in Burma that found you
experiencing these for the first time?
Well,
first of all,
to first experiences, even though I
had experiment with meditation back in,
in a senior, in college and so forth, um,
worry experiences again that
came through psychedelics. Um,
and so I was familiar with
all kinds of weird and,
and powerful and mysterious or
mystical kind of experiences.
Um,
but they,
but there's something about learning
how to navigate it without taking a
substance and learning that your own
consciousness is the field that you can,
that you can learn to navigate first
all the personality and emotions and
history and so forth. But then you start
to realize that you're bigger than that.
That who you are is not just your
thoughts and feelings in your mind. Um,
and so whether it's out of body experience
or the experience of vastness of
becoming the sky,
um,
within which everything arises and passes
or the experience of profound silence,
we're of the void where you enter,
enter a stillness before experience even
arises or the experience of luminosity
where, um, uh, where my body
would dissolve into light, uh,
their time sitting.
As you get concentrated in somebody,
your concentration builds that your whole
body and mind open up. And you know,
first you get the elements,
your body can feel heavy like a stone,
the earth element or can fuel so
light that you have to peak your,
open your eyes and make sure you're
not floating cause it feels like you're
floating in the air or it can be filled
with fire and you feel like you're in
the middle of a raging fire
or can get icy cold, you know,
or all kinds of vibrations and
couldn't delete the energies.
And chakras start to open. And sometimes
it's pleasant, sometimes it's not.
You know, as deep energies
start to move through your body,
they also kind of push open.
The places that are held close so that
when your heart starts to open in deep
meditation, sometimes it feels
like you're having a heart attack.
They've physically
painful because all the,
all the things that you've held around
your heart to protect yourself start to
loosen. Or when the energy hits
your throat and it starts to open,
weird was come out,
you know,
and then you get to visions
that come and, uh, you know,
Brow Chakra,
you start to see all kinds of colors
and visions and hear things that all
possibilities of the play of
consciousness can start to open after,
um,
both period of silence,
but also really deeply training
attention and concentration,
these experiences just to put
them in or at least part of, uh,
what you said in context
for people listening. Uh,
there, there were a number
of things you mentioned,
but one in particular that opening in the
chest that I experienced in the 10 day
retreat, done it a spirit rock, uh, which,
which for which you are one of the, the
instructors or the lead instructor. Uh,
and I,
it was an incredibly powerful experience.
And listening to your description
of some of the feelings.
It makes me want to go to the jungle and
spend time doing this type of training.
However,
the 10 day retreat as you know from
firsthand observation and interacting with
me was incredibly difficult
for me and terrifying it.
A number of points where I felt like I
had crossed a boundary into maybe even
madness where I, I was fearful I
wouldn't be able to return from.
And so I'm curious to know during that
period of time in Thailand and Burma
could be afterwards as well,
but when you were in the,
in the jungle and doing
this very intense work,
were there any particular points when
you wanted to quit to go to go home?
Absolutely. I mean, I remember I,
I got what I think was malaria.
I would have a really high fever and I
was sick as a dog and I'm lying in the
bottom of my little hot there.
Um,
high fever and shivering and Odg and
chalk came to visit me and in allow
language and he was,
he was also funny and quite blunt.
And the allow language is a
very straightforward kind of,
the sentence structures are really simple.
So he looked at me and he said, sick,
Huh? I said, yeah. And he said,
hurts all over. Huh? I said,
it's your just, he said hot and
cold. Yeah. He said, you know,
makes you afraid. I nodded. He said, makes
you want to go home and see your mother,
doesn't it? And I'm not there. And then
he looked at me and he said, you know,
this is the jungle fever. This
is malaria. We've all had it. Um,
but now there's some good medicine.
I'll send the medicine monk over and
then a couple of days you'll be fine. Um,
um, and then he looked at me and he
said, you could do this. You know,
you can do this.
So I mean,
that was an example of wanting to go
home to my mother. What am I doing?
What gets me, what kept going? I mean,
I don't want to interrupt, but psych,
what kept you going for,
I'm imagining 500 days of silence.
I could barely handle 10
days. You know, Tim, I mean,
what's kept you going?
What keeps any of us going about things
that we care about? I had somehow,
I don't know, kind of a
wacky, but I think also, um,
important kind of passion to
say I want to understand or I,
I, you know, I've started down this
road and I want to see where it goes.
And I think all of us find at a
certain point in our life that there,
or if we're lucky that something really
matters and you've done it in your work
and your travel, you want to
explore what your human capacity is.
And I'd read, read these old
zen stories in this. I said,
I want to see if this is true. I want
to find out. And then as I, I started,
things started to happen like that,
out of the body experience and
rapture and changes in and openings.
Um, and I realized that there's
really something to learn here.
But there are a couple of other
things that I want to add to this. Um,
one of them that's the most important
is that it turns out that it wasn't,
and it isn't so much about
the actual experiences. So,
ah,
Jen Cha,
my teacher talked about how in his album
training for the first eight years in
the jungle,
um,
he had been a very ardent meditator and
had all kinds of insights and dissolving
and somebody in John Experiences
all kinds of, he is a weakened.
Yeah.
Or how would you try to found,
somebody has a lot of meanings as a word,
but it can mean profound states of
concentration in which the mind dissolves
into light or into joy or bliss or,
um,
becomes absorbed with anyone
of all kinds of states.
So we went to the most
famous teacher of that time,
another odd going on Jenman and told
them not all of these experiences in the
master looked back and Vince
said, Cha, you missed the point.
These are just experiences.
You know,
it's like gone to the movies and you
have a romantic comedy and you have a war
movie and you've a documentary,
you know, and uh, you know it.
Disney movies, they're just movies on the
screen. Some pleasants a month. I wasn't.
The only question is
to whom do they happen?
Turn your attention back and ask,
look to see who is the witness of these.
What is the consciousness that is
knowing these ever changing experiences?
This is where your liberation will come.
He said,
become his language.
If I translate it is the one who knows.
Become the knowing rather
than the experiences.
And then you can tolerate anything
and you can respond with love and
understanding because you rest
in the timeless consciousness,
which is your true nature.
So part of what I also learned
in meditation and teach
is that it's not so much
about the experiences, Oh, I want
to have this or that experience,
but it's this profound
turning back to ask who am I,
what is this consciousness itself?
And that was born into this
body that will leave it.
And we can talk about death
at some point if you want. Um,
what is this mysterious consciousness
itself? Um, so there was that.
Um, and then, um,
then I also had the opportunity of
being with a few other teachers.
And one of my,
uh,
one of the people that I
was very close to and, um,
inspired me profoundly was a Cambodian
monk named Maha goes and under who was
the Gandhi of Cambodia.
And what I met him,
we were living in training together
in a forest monastery in Thailand.
And it was during the time the
Khmer Rouge came to power and,
and eventually killed 2 million
Cambodians in a kind of genocide.
And he was,
he survived because he wasn't in country,
but all 19 of his family
members were killed.
His temple burned. Um,
you know, uh, all the,
all the Buddhist texts and
so forth were destroyed. Um,
and when he was able to,
he went to the refugee camps,
refugees were pouring out of Cambodia
by the hundreds of thousands,
and he went to the refugee camps on the
border of Thailand and Cambodia. And, um,
I was able to go with him
and at a certain point
and he decided to open a temple in the
middle of one of the biggest refugee
camps. Here's 50 or a hundred thousand
people, these tiny little bamboo huts,
um,
and got permission from the UN,
HCR High Commissioner of refugees,
uh,
and build a platform with a little
roof over it and put an altar with a
traditional Cambodian
Buddha on it and so forth.
But it was a camp with the Camaro
rouge underground, um, lots of them.
And so they put the word out that
if anyone went to be with this monk,
when they got out of the camp back
to Cambodia, they would all be shot.
So we wondered who would,
if anyone would come and,
uh,
went through the camp the day,
the opening day with a big kind of
Temple Gong ringing it and 25,000 people
poured into the central square around
this little 10 point God and he logos.
And the sat there and he was a scholar.
He spoke 15 languages
and he was, uh, you know,
extremely
kind hearted human being who
had suffered enormously, um,
and had transformed it into the kind of
compassion that we think are with the
dollar alarm or something like that.
In fact, they became friends and go,
Sonata became the head of
all of Cambodian boozing.
But there he was at this point,
sitting looking out at 25,000 people
who had suffered immense traumas.
And you could see there was a
grandmother and the only two surviving
grandchildren that she had,
or an uncle and one niece and their
faces were the faces of trauma,
um, and of survivors. And I thought, all
right, what is he going to say to them?
And he sat very quietly for a long time,
just in their presence.
And then he put his hands together
in this kind of modest way,
um,
and began to chant in the microphone,
yet it sound system in Cambodian
and in Sanskrit are Pali,
the Buddhist language. One of the
first verses from the Buddhist texts,
um,
they'd goes,
hatred never ceases by hatred,
but by love alone is healed.
This is the ancient and eternal law.
And he chanted it over and over
in Cambodian and in Sanskrit,
Pali.
And pretty soon the chant was
picked up and in a little while,
25,000 people were chanting
this averse with him.
And I looked out and they were weeping,
many of them,
cause they hadn't heard their
sacred chants for years. Um,
but also because he was offering them
a truth that was even bigger than their
sorrows.
That hatred never ends by hatred,
but by love alone is healed.
This is the ancient and eternal law.
And they were sitting in
the middle of the, the,
the healing energy of the Dharma,
of the teachings of the
heart that can liberate us.
Later on goes to Nanda,
who was nominated for the Nobel
peace prize a number of times.
Um,
spent 15 years walking through
the killing fields and the,
you know,
mind areas and so forth,
leading people on foot
back to their village.
And he said to the refugees,
you can't go back in a boss or the
back of a truck or something like that.
You have to reclaim your land with love.
And so he would lead a thousand people
and he'd be in the front with a bell and
a Gong and a few other monks and the
whole way back they would be chanting the
chance of lovingkindness so that by
the time they got to their village,
uh, whatever had been destroyed, there
was the sense that they were reclaiming
not just the land,
but they were reclaiming their own hearts.
That's a beautiful,
really beautiful story.
And it,
it prompts me to ask a question that
I struggle with answering myself.
Uh,
and,
and it's also a question
many of my friends have asked
themselves and I'll take
a stab at it.
Uh,
how do you decide when
to do deep inner work?
And take an extended period to do that
versus being in the world and trying to
impact others and the world.
And to just provide a little
bit of background on that.
I have friends who are building businesses
or building careers of some type or
families.
And I at this point do not have wife,
kids or company to build,
at least with a large organization.
And I've come back from
various experiments,
sojourns experiences over weeks or
months and shared these with them.
And they've,
they've expressed this longing,
this deep yearning to
do something similar.
And then they asked this question
like, how do I, how do I best decide
if and when to do the deep extended
work versus being in the world?
And I know it might be a false dichotomy.
You might not have to choose, but, um,
I'll talk a little bit more just just
to fill the space. But the, uh, I,
I had this experience personally not
long ago when I was in South America and
had someone telling me, uh,
in sec in Spanish, which was
not their native language.
Uh, this is an indigenous
tribe, but this, uh,
Upal this mayor effectively who
worked a lot with different, um,
plant medicines and he said that
he recommended one 15 month diet,
very, very strict, 15 month period
with many different restrictions,
uh, no sex, no alcohol, no pork, etcetera,
and to develop certain capacities
and to practice in effect,
I mean at certain types
of meditative practices.
So I struggle with this myself as well.
How do you,
how do you suggest someone think through,
so did you give up sex and pork?
I've done it for short periods of time.
I'm not a year and a half.
I've done it for weeks at a time,
but not for 15 months.
But what appealed to me about that,
definitely not the lack of sex and pork.
I like both of those things.
It was,
he said that's something you only have
to do once in your life and it opens
doors and it creates
opportunities that are difficult,
if not impossible to achieve otherwise.
So of course that's very tantalizing,
but 15 months is a really, really long
time to opt out of everything else. Um,
and I'm not saying it has to be 15
months for some people as you know,
setting aside even 10 days
to do silent treat as hard.
And I know there are things that
they can do on an ongoing basis,
like morning meditation and so on.
But for,
for those who are really drawn
to this extended deeper work,
how do you think about,
and that's why I go Sananda brought it
up for me because he'd spent so much time
outside of his country and then
went back and was really on the,
on the ground doing work with locals had.
How do you think about that or
suggest someone think about it?
Uh,
first my answer is yes
because all of the things that you say
are true that yes, there, you know,
most cultures, um, encourage
at some point human beings,
most wise culture as human beings to step
out of their ordinary roles and their
ordinary routine. Whether you go to the
mountains or the ocean, you know, or,
or a temple or a change in how you're
living so that you can open up to the
mystery.
Um,
and so that you also can open up to love
because what I saw with my teachers and
go sonata as well, nudge
in chat and other is, um,
that they were able to love no
matter what it was really, eh,
because they,
they inhabited consciousness in a very
different way than just a small sense of
self.
There was something much a possibility
that we could live with forgiveness and
love and be really effective in
the world at the same time. Um,
so they're not separate.
And that's sort of what your question is,
how do we live in the world? Um,
and at the same time, you know,
what trainings and how do we connect
with something deeper and part of it is
just intuitive. You know, Tim, um,
Eh, if you have new more than, you
know, or young children and so forth,
it's not the time to go on a long retreat.
Your kids are your practice.
And in fact,
you can't get as zen master who is
going to be more demanding then,
you know, an infant with
colic. Right. Or, you know,
or a teenage, you know, certain teenage
kids where you, but with the young ones,
you know,
years end master might say,
you've got to get up early
in the morning and you know,
once in a while you might roll over,
the kid is crying and sick.
You have to get up. Um, your family
needs tending and the, you know,
if you're even vaguely,
um,
a responsible and caring parent as you,
that becomes your practice.
And if you think, well,
if only I could be in the great zen
temple of Kyoto or an Ashram in India are
down in the Amazon with Tim,
you know,
taking Iowasca or whatever that
plant medicine they give, you know,
your kid is, can be like
Iowasca on steroids. Okay.
You want to, you want to face yourself
and your own limitations and your own,
you know,
you want to look at the smallest sense
self and find out how to live with it,
where the freer and bigger spirit here,
we just hired someone to live with you
and train you full time. So it's really,
you know, um, and that's an
important thing. But what,
what makes it work is that,
um,
you have that intention not
just to soldier through it,
but to say,
let this be a place where I awake and um,
graciousness and inner sense of freedom
and peace as things come and go where I
awaken the possibility of presence,
um,
in pleasure and pain and joy and sorrow
and gain and loss and all the changes
that I find, uh, uh, an invite, a more,
a timeless place of becoming
the loving witness of it all,
becoming the loving awareness that says,
yeah,
now I'm having a family experience and
this is the place to find freedom because
freedom is not in the
Himalayas or in the Amazon.
The only place it's found is in your
own heart exactly where you are.
And that's what goes to Nanda,
Todd. And when, what Jen Cha,
that's really what they wanted to
communicate. Now that being said,
if you have an opportunity and you're
drawn to it like somebody you might do,
you know Jack Dorsey? Jack. Yeah.
So Jack just did his first 10 day
meditation retreat and he tweeted about,
I wouldn't say it otherwise, but he
tweeted about it and it was, you know,
one of the top transformative
experiences of his life.
And it's not to say 10 day retreats
are the be all and end all. They are.
They're very powerful and
compelling. Um, but you,
even if you have a company
or even if you have a family,
there might be a period of a week or
some days where you can in fact get away,
um, and step out of those
roles and turn inward.
And that can be tremendously valuable.
So I think both are important.
You just have to listen what the,
when the time
it's right.
So there are so many things that this,
this brings up the,
the first though is just a housekeeping
for people who may not recognize the
named Jack Dorsey. Uh,
that's Jack at Jack,
I believe it is on Twitter of a,
you might add then wonder how did
he get that user handle? Well, uh,
he's,
he's one of the people behind Twitter.
So you use of Twitter and square fame
among many others. A fascinating,
fascinating guy. Uh, so
people can check him out. The,
uh,
the comment on the infant being the
full time trainer working with you, 24,
seven reminded me also since you
mentioned Ron doss earlier of a,
a quote of his that I like, and
I'm going to paraphrase, I'm sure,
but if you think you're enlightened,
go spend a week with your family.
Yeah,
yeah.
Which I think is a fantastic one. And
that's part of the reason, uh, and,
and you know, some of the
backstory, but, uh, we all have,
I would imagine we all have tough things
that happen to us. Experienced trauma,
traumatic experiences as children have
a lot of triggers related to family
members typically. And, uh, for me,
the forced to break takes a
number of different forms,
but that includes a trip every six months
and extended trip of two to four weeks
with my parents and my brother
when he can make it. Um,
so that's only after being
introduced to meditation,
something that I would even consider
as a practice. And, uh, the,
the last point I'll mention just out
of my personal experience is that a,
there's a piece of paper I have in my
wallet and I've had in my wallet for a few
years now.
It's getting a bit worn down.
It's a piece of construction paper and
an ex girlfriend gave it to me who,
who knew me very well. And it says, the
task that hinders your task is your task
beautiful.
And uh,
that's a good reminder for me.
I wanted to ask you two questions that,
uh, are personally important, uh, but,
but also may apply to other people.
The first is the question that I believe
you mentioned Adrienne Cha perhaps
others have indicated is
the question versus the,
the experiences or movies of these
say out of body experiences and so on.
To whom do they happen? Right? To
whom do they happen? Is this a Koan?
Like what does the sound
of one hand clapping where
there isn't really an answer?
You're are,
you're expected to arrive at is,
is the value in contemplating the
question more than any answer?
Yes. Both. Yes. Both. And no,
because, um, it is,
it's a profound contemplation for
us. One of the great, you know,
questions of human incarnation. Who
are we? How do we get into that?
How did you get into this body with the
wiggly things on the end of your limbs,
you know, little fits of a
clause that you have, you know,
his nails and this digital tail and that
whole at one end into which you stuffed
dead plants and animals and glug
them down through the tube. I mean,
the whole incarnation thing is
really pretty wild. So who are we?
And then what are, what, how
do we make meaning of it?
What this is that this is a lifetime
question and that way that it's a on,
but in another way,
it also actually does have an answer.
And the answer,
of course has to be found by each person.
The answer to point toward it.
Um,
it's very clear that you're not just your,
you know,
salad and vegetables and hamburger
body and you're not just your emotions.
I hope cause they're always changing
and your thoughts. Good God,
I hope you're not your thoughts. Um,
so you start to realize, all right,
why is there then,
what is this self?
Who am I in neuroscience?
You know,
there was a Time magazine issue on
modern neuroscience where it said
neuroscience to search throughout the
brain over many decades now and come to
the conclusion that they cannot find
the self located anywhere in the neural
mechanisms of the brain and
that it simply does not exist.
But what does exist is a sense of
self that's built out of a sense of
identification with our thoughts and
body and so forth. It's all wise,
inappropriate.
We should be,
but we also know that it's not the end
of the story and you know it from walking
in the high mountains or listening to an
extraordinary piece of music or making
love or taking some ex, some
sacred medicine, you know,
are sitting at the bedside
of someone when they die.
That mysterious moment when spirit
leaves the body or when a child is born.
We have these moments where we open to
mystery and realize that who we are is
not just our personal history
or our body and emotions,
that we become the consciousness itself,
the witnessing awareness,
that we are the loving awareness
that was born into this body.
And that becomes actually
a direct knowing,
a direct experience.
So there is a,
a way in which we also can come home
to ourselves and it brings a tremendous
sense of freedom and wellbeing,
um,
as all the movies of haver
changing life happened to us.
So that's why I said yes, yes
and no. And both. Um, and I,
there's just a little aside thinking
about you going back to your family as a
practicing twice a year as you're doing,
I just want to remind you
in the listeners that, um,
Buddha and Jesus both had a hard time
when they went back to their family.
So don't think that it, you know,
there's something wrong with you,
part of it. So that's why they call it
nuclear family. I think some, anyway,
uh, the, uh, there's another,
I guess it's a word more than a question
that I'd love to ask you to define and
that is compassion or compassionate. When
you use that word or those words, what,
what do you mean exactly? Or what
would you like it to me and for people?
Um,
I would like to distinguish
compassion from empathy.
Um,
and I'll use a simple illustration.
If you're on the playground and you
see a kid being bullied and you feel,
oh, that must feel terrible, that
hurts, right? That's an empathy.
And empathy can be useful.
It also can,
you can get overwhelmed by empathy
if you don't know what to do with it.
But there's some way in which you
start to feel resonating. You,
because we are not
limited to these bodies.
We are actually a and interconnected
system of consciousness.
And I'll talk about that
a little bit more. Um, uh,
in a minute.
Um,
but we all know whether it's mirror
neurons from neuroscience or the field of
presence as, as neuro, you know,
scientists like Dan Siegel talk about
extended presence that we can feel empathy
with one another. When someone's sadness,
someone's angry, um, someone's hurting.
Compassion is the next step.
You, you, you see or recognize,
you feel,
and then you care.
You care about it and you want to,
if you can do something that helps so
that you see the kid being bullied and you
realize, um, I want to tell
the teacher or the principal,
or I want to just walk over there and,
and say something or intervene to
help stop it. And so compassion,
it's called the quivering of the heart,
um,
when it wants to move to alleviate the
suffering of yourself because you can
have self compassion.
It's very important or those around you.
And it's born into,
and the earliest studies of infants,
um, you know, at Yale and various
places like that show that even very,
very, very small children have this
resonance and this kind of care.
Um,
and so it's not shut down in us.
We were a species that's interconnected
and we care for one another.
And this is your birthright,
this natural, natural compassion.
And through practice in meditation,
you can reawaken it, you can extend it,
um,
and it can become your way of
living and moving in the world.
Um, as a little aside, and I'll
just bookmark this one, um,
just got back from a conference
with our dear friend Adam Gozali,
our mutual friend,
Richie Davidson,
who is another of the most
famous neuroscientists,
especially in this area.
Um, and a number of other,
some contemplative lives
and neuroscientists and
some technologists from the
valley and VC talking about how to build
compassion into our interface with the
technological world, compassion tech. Um,
and in from starting from the
very simplest things of projects,
like can you build a
fitbit for compassion,
where instead of your body where you
can either no moments of care around you
are in yourself or be prompted
to care for yourself, you know,
or when you say to Siri or Alexa,
you know, I'm feeling lonely,
or you know, and so forth. Um,
what kind of response
do you get from them?
From the algorithms and
all of that because the UK,
England, uh, just, uh, uh,
pointed their first minister of loneliness
for the country and I think it was a
joke, but it's not like an old
Beatles song. All the lonely people,
there are 10 million
lonely people in England,
Dave estimated and this minister
has got cut and it's, you know,
it's for isolation and loss of capacity
and health and all kinds of reasons that
loneliness makes things way worse.
But there's some way in which
compassion is that which connects us.
And it's a beautiful thing. Even if you
walked on the street and you see someone,
you know who's struggling and so forth,
it doesn't mean you have to fix the
whole world. That's not your job.
That would be egotistical.
But you can reach your hand out in men,
the things that you can,
you can tend to things that you can
and you can do it not because, oh,
you pity them, those poor people,
but because they're your family,
you recognize that we're common humanity.
We're in this together.
I'd like to build on that and preface
it with a comment on the tech.
So you mentioned collaborating with Adam
and he's discussing the potential of
combining or utilizing technology to
help people to develop and harness
compassion. And some folks listening
might be like, oh, come on,
that's so pie in the sky.
But I'd like to point out that you've
already collaborated successfully with
Adam on software like meditrain,
uh, m, e, d, I, t, r, a,
I n,
which was one of the tools Adam has
used in his end of one or end of two
experiments in a rejuvenating
his mental capacity to,
I want to say in his twenties and
Adams Adams, one of those guys,
you can't tell if he's
28 or 45 and he's just a,
a silver Fox will always looks young. So
I don't know how old he is, but he's not,
he's not 22. Uh, but the Mediterranean
was one of the tools that he utilized.
And uh, I don't remember the name that
he used for this run of experiments.
You might know that the training that
he did neuro man or something like that
was very, very successful. Uh,
so you already have a track record
of collaborating successfully with
neuroscientists and technologists.
The on the,
the compassion front,
I'd love to use that as a
segue to loving kindness.
And by way of personal example,
I failed but failed as a strong word.
I quit,
I stopped meditating after many,
many attempts,
had very absurdly high number
of false starts over many years.
Uh, and it's, it,
it really stuck after a number
of experiments and experiences.
I had a doing three or four
day trainings with say,
transcendental meditation and
having the Social Accountability,
being accountable to someone else's.
Very helpful.
But another turning point
was experimenting with
loving kindness meditation.
And I think in part it's exceeded because
it took the focus off of me, me, me,
and allowed me to focus on others.
But I'd like to read a brief paragraph
from a profile of you in the New York.
New York Times is from 2014 and feel free
to correct anything that is incorrect,
but I'll, I'll give it a read
first. And I quote in the West,
Kornfield says,
quote,
we encounter a lot of intense striving
ambition and a lot of self criticism,
self judgment and self
hatred and quote concerned.
He initially turned to
the Dalai Lama for advice,
but self hatred was such a foreign
concept to the Tibetan Buddhist that he
wasn't able to offer any real insight.
Over time,
cornfield and his colleagues began to
believe that Americans needed particular
meditation closely.
I'm sorry,
practice closely linked to the concepts
of self forgiveness and loving kindness.
A training and the unconditional
acceptance of imperfection without such a
foundation says cornfield
meditation can easily become,
and this is the part that I underlined
and starred without this foundation says
cornfield meditation can easily become
yet another form of striving quote,
another thing you do to make yourself
better and quote instead of a path to true
contentment.
So could you please describe for folks,
uh,
what loving kindness meditation practice
looks like and elaborate in any way
that you feel might be,
might be useful or helpful for folks?
Yeah. Um, and, um, that meeting,
which was some decades ago
with the Dalai Lama, yeah.
He didn't understand when we talked
about south hatred, he couldn't eat.
There is no word for it back and forth
with his translator. What does this mean?
Fine. He looked up, he said, man, but this
is a mistake. Why would anyone do this?
But then he asked,
how many of you,
there was a group of us who were
teachers have experienced this and almost
everyone raised their hand.
So we see that when people begin in our
culture and in the west to meditate or
to try to in turn inward really, that, um,
it's very common to encounter
a lot of self criticism,
self judgment, or even self hatred. Um,
and you know,
they're all the causes from are,
these are all kind of conditioning
that we got from, from our childhood,
our education and so forth.
But what it means is that you're sitting
there saying, I'm not doing it right.
I'm no good.
You turn meditation into one other,
one of the things that you don't do
right cause you can't control your mind.
The truth is that you can't control your
mind easily. That's not the point. Um,
there's a different way of approaching
your mind which gives you tremendous
capacities, but it's not, oh
I have to stop my thinking.
I don't want to have these fields and
I hate having all these judgments.
I don't want to be so judgmental islands
thought I hate this judging mind.
What does it just more judgment.
So instead is you become first
able to become the loving witness,
the,
the mindful loving awareness that says,
oh this is the judging mind and
it's been trying to protect me.
Thank you for trying to protect me.
I don't need you now. Thank you. Um,
all of a sudden there's
a distance from the,
from the painful or destructive or,
or um,
self critical thoughts simply by
witnessing them with loving awareness and
acknowledging them.
This becomes the gateway to the
practice of lovingkindness and self.
Self compassion.
Um,
and very often people
can't do it for themselves.
They feel that's too much of a stretch.
Like why would I wish myself well,
it feels egotistical.
Um,
and so the way that this practice,
um, begins for, uh,
skillfully for,
for such folks is instead to think of
someone that you really care about a lot.
Um, and to picture them, remember them,
put them in your mind's eye and feel the
kind of well wishing you would want for
them.
You know,
may they be protected
and safe from difficulty.
May they be held in loving kindness,
may they be well, healthy, strong,
and you wish them that may they be happy.
And you do this for a time,
a kind of inner well-wishing.
Um,
and also maybe you feel as you think
of this person that you care about,
if you let yourself also tune in to
the measure of sorrows they have,
the struggles that every human being has,
you know,
and it tenderizes your heart as you think
of them because you don't want them to
suffer. You feel the kind of
rising of compassion and care.
So may they hold
themselves and compassion.
May they be safe and protected and well,
and you do that with water to people
that you care about for a time.
And then you can imagine
even as I'm describing this,
and you following your own heart,
you could imagine these two loved ones
looking back at you it with the same
kindness and saying,
just as you wish us protection and safety
and happiness and wellbeing and oh and
compassion,
they gaze at you and they say you too.
May you be safe and protected.
May you be filled with tender
compassion for yourself and kindness.
May you too be healthy and well,
may you be happy. They want
you to be happy. I think about,
and when I'm doing this,
I'm visualizing some loved ones
and I know that as I do it,
I can feel they want that for me.
And then finally,
as you feel that from these loved ones,
you can put your hand on your body
or your heart even if you like,
and take it in and,
and then begin to realize that
you can wish this for yourself.
May I hold all of the joys and sorrows
of my life with tenderness and kindness.
May I hold my struggles with compassion?
May I be filled with loving
kindness and loving awareness.
May I be safe and protected?
May I be well strong,
are healed.
And as you repeat these
simple interventions that
have been done for thousands
of years,
it's as if your cells are listening.
And this is the research of people like
Liz Blackburn and Alyssa Apple Hoo Hoo.
There's blackboard and got the Nobel
prize for discovering the telomerase and
the telomeres mirrors at the
end of the caps and the DNA. Um,
it turns out that your cells listen to
your heart and that to your intention,
that consciousness affects your body.
And little by little,
even though it can bring up its opposite,
I hate myself, I'm never be good enough.
And you see all those and you just say
thank you for trying to protect me.
I appreciate that. May I be well,
may I be safe, may I be held in love.
And little by little
like water on a stone,
it starts to soften the places that are
holding your lack of self forgiveness,
your lack of care and love and
kindness starts to grow in you.
And it's a very beautiful
practice. There's lots of
places you can find it on my,
in my work and teachers like
Sharon Salzberg and family
children and Tara Brock
and [inaudible] and so forth.
Are there any particular,
do you have any guided,
loving kindness meditations or audio
that you can recommend people listen to?
I do. Um, and uh, I don't know.
They could go on my website,
Jack kornfield.com. I think
they will be on there.
I do know for sure I have a whole series
of great programs with sounds true with
soundstrue.com that include,
um,
meditations on the mine vast as the sky
meditations on compassion and loving
kindness. Um, and I did a book, one
of the books I've done is called, um,
a lamp in the darkness and it contains,
uh,
I think eight or nine different,
um,
guided practices that you can
get either with it on the CD,
but you can get it as a
download basically. Um,
and sounds true also has that and has
a compassion practice and a grounding
practice in a kind of a vast sky
like mine practice and so forth.
So you, so you can look off,
look for all of those. Wonderful.
The beautiful thing is
that you can learn this.
And I was couple of years ago invited
to be part of the first White House
Buddhist leadership gathering.
Um,
there were 120 Buddhist leaders
from around the country,
from different communities. I don't think
that's going to happen again very soon,
but there it was. Um, and uh,
one good hope and um,
we talked most of the communities did
beautiful things that were involved in the
soup kitchens and tending the
homeless in projects, you know, um,
to support healing for
whether it was malaria.
Are there other diseases in different
other parts of the world and so forth.
All kinds of great stuff.
And certainly meditation.
And when I got to talk,
which was kind of a summary talk toward,
uh,
toward the end of it,
um,
I mentioned that in the historical record,
whether it's true or not,
that the techs and so forth describe the
Buddha meeting with kings and princes
and ministers and so forth.
And probably if the Buddha were or around
now would go to the White House if you
were invited. He certainly would have bet
with Obama and who knows. And now, um,
Eh, end, he had advice about why society,
which he would give to
leaders and you'd say,
if you can train your people to meet
one another with respect to listen,
with respect to differences and to come
together peacefully listening to one
another and then, then you're pro
society will prosper and not decline.
And if your society tends to
the vulnerable among them, the,
the young people, the old
people, those who are sick,
it will prosper and not decline.
And if your society tends to the
environment around it in a healthy way,
it will prosper and not decline.
And so these are,
these are principles of compassion and
why society that you could read perhaps
in a number of great traditions from
the Iroquois nation or from the Taoist
sages. But here's the beautiful
piece. Yes, these are,
these are good things,
meeting and harmony and discussing and
harmony and being respectful for one
another and so forth.
Um,
there are practices that you can teach
and learn that develop this capacity so
that in our elementary schools now,
you know,
through organizations like castle,
which is a consortium for social and
emotional learning that's worked in,
you know, 10,000 schools. Um,
kids learn social and emotional learning.
They learn compassion,
um, and it changes their lives.
They're better academically.
Um, and all these kids carry that,
you know, the troubles of our times.
They hear the news, they see the
trauma even in their own family. Um,
to teach you how to steward your own
hard, um, from when you're young.
And then these capacities are now
being incorporated as we know,
mindfulness based stress reduction in
clinics and hospitals in businesses in,
you know there's the mindfulness
teachers that for the,
when the Seattle Seahawks
won the championship or the
the Chicago Bulls in the
La Lakers when there were
championship teams, they had a,
they had a meditation coach, a
mindfulness coach, George Mumford,
a good friend that these capacities
can be learned wherever we are and they
transform our life.
It's not just by accident or that you
have this beautiful experience on the
mountains or making love,
but you can make that alive for you
through these trainings every day,
every part of your life.
Jack, there was a question I was
planning on asking at some point. Anyway,
and I think this is a good segue,
which is how can you get a busy person
hooked on my fullness practice and what
would be a first step or how to start
and since we're talking about loving
kindness, I would like to give a bit
of a hard sell for loving kindness.
Meditation is one option because I recall,
perhaps it was two years ago,
I was really beating myself up and for
people who don't know this about me,
I've spent the majority of
my life being, uh, the, the,
my own worst enemy in terms of inner
dialogue and be extremely brutal and
hypercritical and load
some of myself, uh, in,
in so many different respects.
And I was going through a particularly
intense and difficult time with that
inner critic, just ruthlessly,
uh, beating myself up.
And at that point, another
friend of mine, a shade Manc 10,
who created the search inside yourself,
classic Google.
He was a very early engineer,
which became w the most oversubscribed
class for employees at Google,
uh, recommended that I take a look
at lovingkindness meditation and,
and I didn't have any particularly
sophisticated approach to it,
but I decided with nothing to lose and
that I was having so much trouble during
that period,
sitting still and trying to focus on say,
the breath or anything like that,
that at night this was happened to
coincide with book deadline. Probably, uh,
not pure coincidence that
my beating myself up was
exacerbated during that time.
That was a few years ago
and I began at night, uh,
in my case in a, when I would take
a shower at night or sit in a sauna,
I ha I very often go to hotels to write,
which is something Maya Angelou and a few
others that convinced me it might be a
good idea, uh, that I
would consider to people.
Just like you had mentioned two people
I really cared for and wish them well,
that's all I did. And a shaded said to
me, Mang is usually what I would call him,
that at one point a woman in one of his
classes had done this for a one day at
work.
Every hour on the hour,
she would just look out of her office
and wish someone well that she could see
in our mind's eye for 60 seconds or so.
And she says,
she said it was her best
day of work in seven years.
And I found that unbelievable.
So I decided to try it myself.
And that week of just spending maybe two
to four minutes at night before going
to bed ended up being one
of the most blissful weeks,
uh, in memory. Certainly
at that point, uh,
in several years it was really profound
and I couldn't pick out any other
variable that had changed.
Uh, so for me, I just want to,
for people who are listening and saying,
ah, you know what, I'm type a driven,
super hyper competitor.
This doesn't apply to me that
it very well could apply to you.
And that by taking a little
bit of the harmful edge off,
you don't automatically remove your
competitive edge. Uh, and in fact,
I would argue just as you mentioned
that the bowls and so on used to have or
still do,
but you used to have a mindfulness coach
for competitive advantage that that it
can be another tool in your toolkit
and doesn't take you out of the game,
so to speak. It just makes you more
aware of the games that you're playing.
So that's a long sort of infomercial sales
pitch that I wanted to just make sure
I got in,
uh,
because I discounted a lot of these
practices for a very long time because I
thought it would at best be
a waste of time and at worse,
uh,
take away some of my skills or tendencies
that allowed me to get to where I am.
Um, so that, that, that is more
of a confessional than a question.
But I would love to hear your thoughts.
Any additional thoughts on,
on loving kindness meditation,
but also any additional thoughts on how,
if you wanted to get a, a busy, uh,
maybe even an impatient person
hooked on mindfulness practice,
what first steps or
approaches you might suggest?
Uh,
so a lot of different questions
sort of woven into what you said.
Um, and the first is that there's a kind
of misunderstanding in our culture that
love is a weakness and it's not,
there is a way in which,
um,
it's the force that can,
it probably the only force that can meet
the level of aggression or violence and
other such things that are happening.
And, um, you know, in the world, um,
it's the power that lets mothers
lift cars off their children,
or it'll let somebody like Dr.
Martin Luther King Stand. Um,
you know, after his church was bombed
and children were killed and say,
we will meet your
violence with soul force.
We will not harm you,
but we will love you so deeply that
we will not only transform ourselves,
but we will transform you in the process.
And so the notion that love
is somehow a weakness, um,
I think we do everything out of love. We
want to be loved even in our, you know,
ambition and our desire for,
for success underneath it,
um, is, you know, we want
to be well, we want to be,
find our happiness and that's
part of part of love. So it's,
it's actually a power. And
my colleague and friend, um,
west Nessc or when to interview
Gary Snyder a couple of years ago,
Gary is a pure literary
prize winning poet, um,
and environmentalist for 50 years when
writing about bio regionalism and one of
our great kind of elders in
this environmental movement,
he said, Gary, what do you have to
say to us now that oceans are rising,
the world climate is changing,
you know,
the hotter and hotter the
species extinction. And Gary
looked back and he said,
don't feel guilty if
you're going to save it.
Don't save it out of
guilt or anger or fear.
Those are the very things that are
actually making the world worse. Save it.
Cause he would love it because it's
part of you because it, and that's the,
that is the, is the power. Um,
whether you're starting a company but
also it's not just that you, you know,
some vision, okay, now I'm going to
become this wealthy playboy or whatever,
you know, a Zillionaire, um,
that what is your life mean for
you and what do you really want?
And when you listen, there is something
in you and it's part of your birthright,
um,
to both be able to give your gifts but
also to love and be loved in return.
And it's turns out that it's a power.
So then what you're talking about is that,
um, it doesn't take much to begin
the training and you're, you know,
two minutes or four minutes in the evening
or this woman at her work taking once
an hour,
you know,
30 seconds or a minute to look at somebody
there and offer a well-wishing can
transform everything.
Um,
for people who want the practical support
because it is hard to do on your own
if you go to sounds true.com and look up,
um,
the programs that I have first,
there's a 40 day program
called mindfulness daily,
which is 15 minutes a day or 12 minutes
a day depending on the segment that both
gives instructions in mindfulness, loving
awareness and loving kindness practice.
Um, and it's 12 or 15 minutes a day
and by the end of those 40 days,
you really have learned the inner
skills and then it builds up. There's,
and then a deeper training
called power of awareness.
And for those who are interested were
about to open an online teacher training
for people interested in mindful, um, in,
in passing along mindfulness and
loving kindness to others. Jack,
just to interject for one
second for people listening,
I will also link to all of these
resources in the show notes,
which you can find at tim.blog/podcast.
So you don't necessarily have
to remember all these things.
You can go to the URL and uh, we will
have direct links to these resources. Uh,
sorry to interrupt Jack just wanted to
mention that for people listening and
with it.
Then there is also of the programs there.
There's one called guided meditations.
That's, you know, a download.
It's like 10 bucks or something and
it has a loving kindness practice of
compassion, practice of
forgiveness practice. Um,
I think it may even have a joy practice,
uh, and and so forth. So you can,
and it's really helpful to have guided
meditations at first cause otherwise your
attention,
we have a very short attention
span in modern society.
Albert Einstein,
at least according to scientific American
said, if you can drive
safely while kissing a girl,
you're simply not giving the
kiss the attention it deserves.
And we are in this kind of multitasking
world with our devices and we've
forgotten how to tend to our own hearts.
We've forgotten how in some ways to
really be present for one another and more
importantly for our own life.
And so getting guided meditations
is tremendously helpful.
And doing these little mini practices
that you talk about one minute,
two minutes, several times a day, um,
can transform you now. Oh, I was
just going to mention to people also,
if you look at behavioral change,
if you look at Bj Fogg,
formerly of the persuasion laboratory
at Stanford, you look at Diet,
a dietary change, any
of these things, uh, do,
doing less than you think you're capable
of doing is a really good long term
strategy in terms of starting off rigging
the game so that you can win in the
beginning so that your pass fail
mark and your mind is a really,
really low hurdle. So I just wanted to
reiterate, guided, guided meditation.
Don't white knuckle in the beginning
I'd make it beautiful, easy as possible.
And that the same principle from
the, from the ancient, you know,
texts say that you start and
the easiest way for some people,
kindness for themselves seems impossible.
But then you pick a child you care about
or someone else or even when you do go
to yourself, you think of yourself
when you were an innocent child, um,
and wish yourself well.
The game is to do wear whatever
naturally opens the gateway.
Whatever's the easiest.
For some people it's their dog.
You'd come home and you know the,
the most nonjudgmental being in their
life wags its tail and loves you and it
doesn't care.
You know what's going on in your head.
So you take the avenue that most naturally
opens your heart and then you do this
just a little at a time as you said.
And it doesn't take long.
But the other thing that's important
is that sometimes as you do it,
it can actually display or show you
the hypercritical nature of your mind,
the shame that you
carry. Um, the, you know,
the self judgment or self loathing.
And so then you, then you say,
well what do you do then?
Or it brings,
it brings up its opposite is that's the
place that you just breathe and hold all
that stuff with kindness because this
is our humanity and we all have some of
that.
And the point isn't to get rid of it or
judge yourself for having it or try to
fix it. It's almost as if you put your
hand on your heart and you say, you know,
this is like mindful self
compassion of deep training.
This is part of the measure of
struggles that I've been given,
like every human being,
these things have tried to protect me
and now I can hold them with tenderness
and say, alright, you know, thank you,
but I don't need your help anymore.
I can be kind to myself. And, and, and,
and in that way you're not trying to
fix yourself or perfect yourself. Um,
if anything, you're trying to perfect
your love. This is Jack. I want to do, we
give you credit for help that you gave
me and also tactical advice that you gave
me during the 10 day silent retreat.
You give me a lot, but I want it,
I want to highlight one that's
related to what you just said.
I was going through a very,
very difficult time,
particularly a days seven,
eight,
nine and you,
you gave me the advice that you
just mentioned. And there's,
there's one component I want to
really underscore for people.
And that is when you're,
for instance,
trying to do loving kindness meditation
and instead you get the opposite or you
get this self ridicule,
uh, who are you to try it,
to meditate in this self indulgent way.
This is ridiculous.
Or this voice starts to pop up that is
angry or hateful, whatever it might be.
The process of not simply dismissing
it or fighting against it,
but recognizing it as a coping strategy
that helped you in the past in some way
that you developed. Because
in my case, you know,
the rage was a fuel that if I had without,
which I probably would never have left
long island where I had friends who later
overdosed on opiates and so on.
So it,
it was a gift in a way and the tool,
and as you said,
you can thank that response or that
part of yourself and then put it,
and I remember you
recommended even visualizing,
and please correct me if
I'm wrong or elaborate,
but visualize taking that part
of you that is a coping strategy,
thanking it and then putting
it say on a shelf, uh,
where you can use it later
if need be along with say,
other icons are figures who,
uh,
whether it's Buddha or other
that that you recognize as wise.
And then continuing with the meditation
so that thanking that part of yourself
for the function that it wants serve,
even if it is not serving you now,
was such a key insight for
me that then helped me to,
uh,
manage my internal states or,
or observe and appreciate my internal
states for the next several days where I
really felt like I was lost at that point.
So that was a really direct tool
that helped me tremendously.
Mostly.
Yeah.
Thank you for bringing it up because
it's so important for people when we come
to that hypercritical, shame.
Shame place. Um, we're,
we feel very vulnerable and we've
been identified with it. Um,
because you needed it. I needed
these things for survival. So,
and if you try to get rid of this stuff,
you just end up in a fruitless
battle against yourself.
And it's just more judgment.
So what you described with saying,
thank you for helping me survive.
I appreciate it.
Let me put it on the shelf or the altar.
I'll put it in the lap of the
Buddha or whoever, you know,
the goddess of infinite compassion.
You hold it for me. If I need it,
I'll pull it back. Um, and that
sense that this isn't who you are,
it doesn't describe who you are.
It isn't who you are. It was,
it was a strategy because we're
vulnerable beings and you were tender as a
child, you know, and you had to make sure
you could survive. Thank you for that.
And now I have a different capacity.
Um,
and let me just talk about that capacity
a little bit because the capacity for
presence,
um,
and the great heart of compassion
that's said to be your birthright, um,
is a really mysterious thing.
Talk about identity. Um,
and when my,
um,
youngest brother's wife
Esta was dying of cancer,
um,
and she was just a beautiful being and
I spent quite a bit of time with her and
with my brother. Um, I had gone
home, she was close to dying.
I'd gone home to sleep and I want to
get up early in hurry back cause it was
very close and I, uh, got my car,
I had to stop the drug store to pick up
a prescription, um, hurriedly running,
you know,
dashing through the aisles and so forth.
And I'm at the checkout counter and all
of a sudden my whole body relaxed and I
thought, oh, Hesta died.
And I got out to the car and I called my
brother. I said, how's it going? He said,
oh, as to died a few minutes ago.
And I said, I know, you know,
I'll be there shortly. Um, and
we've all had these experiences.
If I ask in a room,
how many have had this particular kind
of where you knew someone died when they
died, you know, a quarter of the
hands will go up. Why is this?
It's because who we are is not this body.
We are,
we are the consciousness itself.
And so with all of these practices,
what they allow us to do is to step out
of what's called the small sense of self
or the body of fear
and reconnect with the,
with a field of connection,
interdependence of compassion.
Um, and to take our history and to
honor it, but not be bound by it.
One of my favorite stories
is a rum dos.
Again,
this wonderful spiritual teacher in the
early years when he came back from being
with his guru in India, uh,
he was sitting up there and teaching,
um,
you know,
devotional practices and
meditation practices and he
had a beard and white robes
and uh,
and,
and beads and you sort of in the guru
outfit and a woman in the front row raised
their hand and say, rob does
around us. Aren't you Jewish?
What's with this Hindu stuff? And Rhonda,
I said, well, yes I am actually. Yeah,
it was bar Mitzvah'd is as I was too.
Um,
and there are many things I love
about the Jewish spiritual tradition,
the generosity of it, the, the
Kabbalah. All did great. You know,
teachings on the many stages
in states of consciousness.
The Hasidic masters who
were like Zen Masters.
And then he paused and
looked at and he said,
but remember I'm only
Jewish on my parents' side.
And there is something both Whiti,
which he was,
but also profound about it because we
are not just our parental history or,
or the historical circumstances of this
place and body that we were born into.
And something in us knows this
so that when you look at the,
there's a wonderful book
that came out last year,
the year before called the book of Joy,
which was a conversation between
the Dalai Lama and Archbishop Tutu.
And both of them have marvelous laughs.
I think people go to hear the Dalai
Lama by the tens of thousands,
not just for the Tibetan teaching,
some of which are actually
hard to understand. Um,
or even the fact that he's this
Nobel prize winning, you know,
world figure.
I think people go to hear him laugh
that somebody who's carried so much
suffering from the loss of his country
where he can't return and the burning of
temples and texts and all of those things,
and he and two had a week together
when they were asked and to,
and this created this book,
how can you be joyful?
How can you laugh like this when you've
lived through apartheid and the death of
so many people around you?
And Dalai Lama,
they banter back and forth and like
brothers. And the Dalai Lama says,
so much has been taken from me.
He know they've taken our sacred texts,
they've taken our ability to make
prayers in public. They've taken,
you know, um, so much of our culture,
why should I let them take my
happiness? And then two, two,
starts to laugh and giggle and say, you
know, I've been through so much, um,
but I am not going to let
myself live in that place.
I'm going to let myself live in
that which affirms life and in a,
in a kind of profound,
a joy that we made it
that were still alive,
that we can contribute, that we can
be here in this beautiful earth.
And this shift of consciousness
is what's needed for the world.
Um, because we look honestly, um,
no amount of technology alone is going
to save us nano technology and space
technology and biotechnology and
worldwide web, Internet, computer,
a super computer technology is going to
stop continuing warfare and racism and
tribalism and environmental destruction.
Those are happening based on
consciousness of the human heart.
And so we are now, you know, these have,
you've made these enormous developments
outwardly where you have the Great
Library of Alexandria and your smartphone
in your pocket along with it million
cat you tubes or whatever. But
there it is, it's all in there.
And then,
um,
what we need is,
collectively to develop a
transformation inwardly of,
of our inner life that is parallel to
this enormous outer transformation.
Um, and that's that, you know,
one of the chairman of the Joint
Chiefs of staff some years ago said,
we are a nation of nuclear
giants and ethical infants.
You know, you know how old, I don't
know how old humanity is, but it's time,
you know, um, it's time to
grow up. So, so that this,
this work that we're talking
about is both individual.
But as you learn to meet your own
life with greater understanding and
compassion,
um,
it empowers you to move through the world
in a different way and to help others
do the same.
And then you get the kind of joy of two,
two in the Dye Lama that you're
somehow part of an awakening.
That humanity now needs more than ever.
Jack,
I'd love to ask you,
these interviews are always
driven by some self interest.
I always have somebody issue or challenge
or problem that I'm trying to figure
out. So I reached out to someone
like you to help me do it.
But I record the conversation, uh, as,
as we chatted about before we hit
record, and you know, this already,
but the last several years have been very,
very important for me in terms
of addressing certain traumas.
In the last eight weeks in
have been transformative
and a lot of beautiful ways.
And the periods, the, the,
the duration of periods,
uh,
within which I don't berate or
attack myself have become longer.
But there are still times when
the wheels fly off the car.
And this last week has been one
such example. Uh, and I tend to,
when I make a mistake or feel like I'm
backsliding or relapsing to compound the
problem by beating myself up,
which then I start to,
then I beat myself up about beating
myself up. And you know where that goes.
So let me paint a picture.
So I,
I found out recently that
my Japanese host father,
and I've been in touch with this
family since I was 15. I'm very,
very close to them, 40 now. And I
found out that he just was admitted,
uh,
because of the host mother sent me an
email to the hospital with liver cancer.
And, and this there, they
don't have the details yet.
I just sent a followup email. They don't
know what the prognosis is exactly, but,
uh, needless to say, the
worst case scenarios are,
are certainly being conjured in my mind
or the potential of those and then,
uh,
simultaneously have been contending with.
And I believe you have some
experience with this, uh,
contending with a what should be a very
simple construction project of a cabin
up in the mountains. Uh, and it is,
it has been delayed and delayed and
delayed and there've been cost overruns in
cost over in cost overruns
and his promises made
promises, broken expectations,
set expectations missed.
And a friend of mine called with a whole
new slew of problems yesterday related
to this place. And I lost my shit, for
lack of a better term. I mean there,
there are many other things
going on simultaneously.
But I got really pissed and I was like,
you know what,
this extending the olive branch,
being understanding can't gambit is
not working with these people. Like I,
I need to,
I need to take out the baseball bat and
like pull old Tim off the shelf who was
just this like juggernaut
head through brick walls and
be like, listen, fuck face.
Like if you don't do a, B,
c, d and e here, these are
going to be the consequences.
And then I'm like, well wait,
I'm supposed to be compassionate,
but how do I not be a pushover?
And it turns into this big dramatic
play inside my head and then I wait,
then this is going to end soon.
I'm not going to keep going.
But what I then often do is
self medicate with caffeine.
And I think it's a way of
feeling productive without
actually being productive.
And it also creates so
much volume on the noise.
I think I use it to tune
out a lot of feelings. Uh,
so when someone relapses or
has this kind of experience,
what do you suggest to them?
I mean, is there, uh, is
there a particular pattern interrupt or
approach that you've found helpful for
regaining footing? Oh, so there's
a number of things to say.
Um, yeah. First of all, um,
you could call it relapsing or you could
just call it like, yeah. Is being human.
One of the Po,
the most most beloved poet in Japan
was a zen master named Rio Kahn.
And there's a two line verse that of
his that I particularly find fitting for
this where he wrote last year
of foolish monk this year.
No change.
You know,
and you can sort of feel the
humor and the tenderness. Um, and,
and there's a way in which you see
your personality, that point, you know,
you have a body and you
have this particular body
you're born with and you can
transform it in certain ways within the
limits of the body that you were given.
Um,
and similarly have a personality.
And anybody who has a number
of kids realizes that you
don't come in Tabula Rasa,
that you actually, this kid is born.
It has this kind of temperament.
So we have a personality and just like
you don't want to look too closely to the
Bot at the body. Sometimes you
don't want to look back closely.
The personality either. Um, you know,
it has its foibles and its fears
and you know, all of that. Um,
and so you start to kind
of look at it and say, oh,
now there's a really good example of how
neurotic I can get. Thank you. Thank you.
I'm pretty sure reminding me,
you know,
and then you get a little sort
of like the keeper of the zoo,
a little more tender with this,
those kinds of creatures. So that's,
that's it's bringing in the nonjudgment,
you know,
or loving kindness for the way that
you actually are and not your ideal.
Um, or bringing compassion,
you could say, yeah,
this is a tough one in this triggered,
I get triggered. So what? Um,
now the other thing is if I have the
same experience when we had a big remodel
of our house when I was some years ago,
um,
and raising my daughter and,
and in my first marriage and we were
supposed to go and teach and travel in
Europe and this guy who was a
good contractor, but you know,
everything of course gets
more expensive and you know,
news and it just kept getting
slowed down and I said,
you weren't going to get this done so
we could make these decision for went to
Europe and it's not happening.
You've got to hurry up.
I do that like three or four
different times and it doesn't happen.
Finally I go in, I get
pissed and I say, listen,
you know,
you said this in our contract,
it was going to be done by and if you
don't fucking get this done by the time of
day,
I'm going to haul your ass in court and
sue you because I need this done and I'm
not going to pay you that God damn money.
Oh. He looked at me and he said, Oh,
you really want this done, don't you? I
said, yes. Next day there's a huge crew.
It starts to compound
that. I realized, okay,
what I've been sort of talking
meditation speak Nice, get it done.
He was a fucking contractor
and I decided to keep,
I had to speak contractor ease,
get the God damn job done or I'll haul
your ass. Oh, okay. I got it. Yeah, I'll,
I'll send a team over.
And that's all it took.
So there's something playful about
that as well. It's not that you can't,
I've seen the Dalai Lama
get angry at people.
It's not that you can't use that
power and that understanding,
um,
you know,
when it's necessary to get to
the very strong or forceful, um,
uh, and you don't have to judge
yourself unless you hurt people.
And then of course, that's the
misuse of it. Um, but it's just,
it's part of being human.
Um,
is there, so you say to
yourself when, no, I think,
I don't know. You are, uh,
certainly in person and any,
with any contact I've had of you with you.
One of the most compassionate
people I've ever met. And I, I,
I've, I don't use that
word very much, but your,
your presence of listening and being
with someone is really incredible.
Uh, and I don't know how much of that
is an in intrinsic versus trained,
but for better or for worse,
you're coming out of the womb.
I've been very, uh,
impatient since day one,
so I worry about,
I can get my,
it seems like my default is the yell is,
is speaking contractor ease to,
uh,
more than just the
way the wayward contractor who's,
uh, who's putting off work.
Is there some,
when I feel that the sensations
of anger beginning to bubble up,
is there something that you would
suggest as self talk or just a temporary
pumping of the brakes to
make it an informed decision
versus just a lashing out?
Well, um, I could give you an answer,
but in a minute I'm going to guide you
in a little practice so that you can find
the, find the better answer.
First I just want to say that, um,
that anger, you know, yes, it's your
habit or maybe your temperament,
that's energy. And there's nothing
wrong with energy. You know, it's,
it's the power of that.
Let you do all the kinds of things you've,
you've done in your life that
are tremendously, you know,
creative or resourceful or daring
or whatever kinds of things.
So you want to respect, okay, I'm getting
filled with energy and you might be,
then you want to lash out. But first
you want to respect that energy. Wow,
let me feel this in my buddy who
anger, how big is it? Woo. Okay,
then your question is then your question
is, what can I do to modulate it?
I could give you, you know, okay,
take some breaths, ground yourself,
look at that other person
number, blah, blah, blah. But
instead, as we were talking,
um, let yourself, um,
picture a circumstance recently, it
might've been with your, you know,
the contractor is doing your cabin or
something else and you're, you know,
that uprising of,
um,
the injustice of it and how right you are,
you know,
and how you're going to get this
goddamn thing done. You know,
and how you have to have
to be hard and strong.
You feel all of that and feel
that energy in your body.
First thing is just remember what it
felt like. And now you're becoming the,
the kind of mindful loving
witness of it and saying, wow,
this is a lot of energy. Can you
feel that? And remember that?
Okay. Now, next step, um, is that,
um, the wisest, you know,
figure you can imagine,
maybe it's the Buddha or, or maybe
it's, I don't know. It doesn't,
it doesn't matter. Some great master
martial arts master, you know,
who's mastered themselves
as well as their are,
comes to you and let yourself imagine
somebody who's going to teach you how to
manage this powerful energy
and see who appears,
somebody appears to you.
Um,
and first they look at you and they smile
and then they say, yeah, this is really,
this is the big energy. Um, and they
appreciate you. So instead of saying, Oh,
you're a doofus, you know, they
say, Oh yeah, you actually,
you actually carry some powerful energy.
And they acknowledged that they bow to
you. Yeah, Tim, you got it all right.
And then you say, yeah, but how do
I manage this when it takes me over?
And so this zen master,
whoever comes,
reaches under their robe and
pulls out a gift for you,
which is a clear symbol of exactly what
you need in that moment to help you
regulate it so that you
can keep the energy,
but doing it in a way that doesn't
cause harm to you or another.
And this clear symbol you'll be able
to see, to adjust what you need.
So let yourself picture the gift that
they put in your hand and let yourself
imagine. See, envision,
picture what it, what it is.
And if you can't see it clearly hold it
up to the sunlight, you'll be able to,
and then let me know what
you get. You want me to tell
you what it is? Yeah, yeah.
All right. So the person who came to
mind for me, I went through a few,
was the creator of judo.
Fascinating guy named Gigo Takano.
Really smoke a small guy, uh, who
yes. Who could, who could
throw all the big guys and
smile at the same time. Right,
exactly. Changed a lot also in Japanese
government. Fascinating guy. The,
the symbol,
I don't know why this is to be honest,
but it's a
pyramid the size with,
with,
with straight edges about little
too big to holding your palm.
That is uh, uh, blue.
It's like a sort of, almost a, a
mixture of Scott pure sky blue,
like a blue bird blue with a bit of
electric blue mixed in and it's sort of a,
a smoky vapor that's floating
around inside this glass pyramid.
I don't, I have no idea why that's
the case, but that's what came up.
All right. So we'll stay with it. And
then there's one more little piece.
So he gives you this, this pyramid, um,
free associate a little bit on what it
might possibly mean cause the assembles
or like dream images and they have, they
come from a deep place in your psyche.
And this pyramid has a message for you.
This blue pyramid.
Just guess what it might be.
I think it's very, very stable. Uh,
it's an extremely stable structure.
And uh,
for me it also,
I could imagine it
representing power also.
It seems like a very powerful symbol in
many different cultures. Certainly. Yup.
Uh, the blue, the blue is
a little easier for me.
It's a very cooling,
soothing color where, uh,
certainly red is the,
the Colorado CCA with a fire with the,
the uh, hi, uh,
a resonance anger energy would
be more of a red fire element.
Uh,
so the blue would be a,
a cooling or countering
balancing force for that.
All right.
So now what I want you to do is
imagine taking this blue pyramid gift,
which represents a kind
of extreme stability, um,
and also a kind of power and cooling
that's given to you by Jugaad Oconto and
taking this into your body so that there
you are filled with this energy and
anger. You know, this huge wave of, um,
you let that be there and you take this
pyramid in and you let that energy be
inside this stable,
grounded place of power and feel what
it's like to be inside this blue pyramid
with this energy and feel how
it feel, how to, it affects it.
Just notice as if they're,
you're in that circumstance.
And now I'm remembering I am
the blue pyramid with the,
and what do you, you know,
what does it feel like
wife, the Ma, the most noticeable
thing. And uh, you know,
I wonder of course how
much of this is the,
the actual visualization versus the
timeout I permit myself to have,
but others,
there's very often a tightness
on the left side of my chest,
right by the sternum.
And I feel when I start
getting a wound up.
And that is absent when after taking
this gift and then visualizing it being
incorporated.
So that dissipates while you're
practicing and you know, and,
and you know this very well in
athletics, that yes, you practice things,
but other times you also practice
envisioning whether it's playing piano or
whether it's, you know, some,
some Olympic training that some
of the times you just do it, um,
in through visualization and it activates
a lot of the same neural circuitry.
So here you're starting to get the feeling
of what it's like to be in the middle
of this upwelling of anger and so forth.
And then taking a couple of breaths
and feeling the Blue Pyramid and the
connection with the earth and the
stability of it and the power then of that
presence that cools you and allows the
anger to be there but not in the same
uncontrolled way.
Now there's one more thing and
that is if you imagine again,
you got Oakano, I believe you
said his name is, he comes,
he comes up to you after
giving you this gift.
And he touches you kindly on the shoulder
and he has a few words of advice of
how to handle this powerful energy that
comes up in you because he knows all
about it.
And what does he whisper
into your ear constantly?
Well, he whispers this, this,
this came to mind immediately.
He, he says zen, you'll
cuisine y'all, which is,
uh, you know, I, I still
have this actually there too.
He has many famous quotes, but he, he has,
you might consider proverbs
short aphorisms that I,
I've actually carried with me
since I was 15, but they're packed.
They're packed away somewhere. I
have two of them are on cloth. Uh,
and the,
the firstest stomata but still made a
bot cannot have the thoughts though.
It's means basically if you, if
you work hard, you will achieve,
you will reach your, your target.
It's not the best translation,
but that's the idea. The other
one is then New York was in your,
which is effectively the
most efficient use of energy.
But it could also be the, the best
slash most benevolent use of energy.
And it's,
it's a principle of judo,
but it's something that he
applied to everything, uh,
includes including education.
So it would be that very
short bite sized aphorism,
which is a, and I'm sure some
scholars probably disagree with me,
but roughly translated
here at least as I take it,
is the maximum or most
efficient use of energy.
So take that in, take his, his
intention zones and Yoko's annual,
um, the benevolent and efficient use
of it. Feel that pyramid. And now,
um, you were assigned,
is that the next, um,
five times that this comes with your will,
maybe tomorrow or next week or so forth,
bringing in the blue pyramids, stable,
powerful cooling.
So the energy is still there.
And then you hear his voice ses and
you'll go [inaudible] and you go, oh yeah,
I can use this, but I can use
it in a benevolent way, um,
and try it five times and
then then, um, text me,
let me know what happened because of that.
We're closing the loop.
If you do it and see now you're,
now you're responsible.
If you've agreed that you're going
to do it, it's sort of goose.
It gooses the game a little bit.
You Go,
okay now I better do it cause I have
to let Jack know where we know what
happened and let me know what happened.
Well I'll be able to do,
be able to use it this week cause I'm
flying out to the site of this cabin to
meet with everybody and see what,
so I'll, I'll have at least
five opportunities to do that.
Have you have your zen training ahead?
I mean the other thing that it's great
and then that you can hear in this rather
than my giving you a cookie cutter answer
is that we actually have the wisdom
that we're seeking or that's available.
We have it in ourselves.
I mean you didn't have to fly to,
you know,
Kyoto and getting your time machine to
go back and see did you go to Ocado, um,
you know,
or whoever it happens to be the di La
or whoever happens to come to you. Um,
the booter or,
or some other great figure that actually
the goddess of compassion that we carry
that wisdom in our own heart.
And part of what these
contemplative trainings do is
they give us access just by
taking a little, little pause. It didn't
take you 30 seconds. Okay? He appears,
what do I do? Oh, here's how
my body would feel. What,
what perspective should I bring up?
Here's efficient and
benevolent use of energy. Okay?
Now I remember.
So these answers for the,
for the questions of the psyche in the
heart don't require going somewhere.
They ask us to quiet and begin to listen.
And as you do,
then you discover your own and your own
inherent wisdom and your own compassion
as well because the,
the benevolent use that he offers to you,
where does that live? It
lives in Tim. It lives in you.
S one of the,
one of the reasons I've,
I've wanted to have you on the
podcast for so long is that for me,
you represent a very
wide spectrum of tools.
So you have developed a toolkit that has
enabled you to work with everyone from
the, uh, the, the seekers
of say, the Buddhist, uh,
along the lines of the Buddhist traditions
to say adolescents who are cutters to
war vets with PTSD, missing limbs and
so on. You've worked with a very, uh,
diverse set of students
and a patients maybe even,
uh, in, that leads me to
my next question, which is,
after these experiences abroad,
why did you decide to pursue,
to come back?
Why did you decide to come
back to the U s period?
And then why did you decide to go back
to school and study clinical psychology?
So after the first five years in Asia,
um,
there were certain, there were a few
other westerners who would become monks.
It was a handful and some were going
to stay for the rest of their lives.
I've learned a lot. And so that was kind
of a choice. Am I just going to stay?
And I realized, no, I want
a family. I want a lover.
You know,
I was a young man after all.
And just the celibacy for those
years was actually pretty hard. Um,
I want,
um,
I want to see if what I have learned
really translates into the life back home.
I don't want to just leave it.
Um, and so I was some wrestling,
but it became very clear to me that,
uh,
that I wasn't fit for the
monastery for the rest of my life.
I had other, not only other
desires, but also and longings. Um,
but also we're real interest to say, does
this work elsewhere? Um, so I came back,
I thought, well, what can I do? I got
it, got a couple of jobs and right away,
and of course I knew how
to do is be a student,
but I was now a student of the mind
and the heart. And I thought, well,
how do I learn more about what
happened to me in the monastery? Oh,
I'll study western psychology.
And so that started me on that
particular path and I learned a lot of
complimentary things.
There are some very good trauma work in
the West that I've learned about that
really enhances the compassion
and loving kindness.
And mindfulness things that I
learned in, in the temple. Um,
and, uh, you know,
now I've done a lot of years of teaching
eastern or Western psychology together.
These principles that I've learned are
spreading so widely in western psychology.
I went to the largest therapy
conference in, in, um, the country,
um,
in December and down in Anaheim
and gave a talk and you know,
here's a room full of
3000 or 5,000 people.
And I ask how many of you have,
um,
some experience of meditation
or mindfulness practice?
And the majority of the hands went up and
that would not have happened, you know,
20 or 30 years ago. So, um,
the eastern psychology is now
becoming more invisibly woven into the
understandings of clinical
psychology and the West.
And it's beautiful. Now I want
to say something else. You know,
when you talk about working with
a variety of population, you know,
um, s yes. People in prisons. Yes,
that's our kids coming out
of gangs, but also, um, CEOs.
And there's a dialogue that
bill forward. And I did.
He was that that time the
chairman of Ford Motors. Um,
he was actually the CEO
perhaps before that, but,
and then it was as he's the chairman of
Ford Motors and he talks about it too.
It was in, um, 2008,
I guess when the auto industry
was just about to melt down.
Um, and uh, he called,
we'd had some contact and he's a
meditator and he said, you know,
I'm going to lose the,
my grandfather's company and maybe the
whole industry on my watch and it's hard
to sleep. What can I do? And we
did loving kindness practices and,
and, um, mindfulness practices
together and so forth.
Then I gave him some practices
that he could use. Um,
and it turns out that at
whatever level you're on,
whether you're incarcerated or whether
you're a CEO or whether you're a
returning,
that,
that these inner capacities that we
have to be present without getting lost,
to bring a, um, uh,
an understanding attention to these
energies just as you were doing with anger
in ourselves, um, are
really, really liberating.
And sometimes you know,
what's needed,
like for the vets are that the
people coming back from the war is,
I'm also a kind of forgiveness
practice in trauma work. Um,
and we'll come together and, you
know, they'll say things like,
um, I can't tell you what
I saw because in fact,
people don't want to hear the horrors
of war. They can't tell the story.
And if they do,
often they retraumatize themselves and
the people around them couldn't bear it.
But there's something
worse because they'll say,
I can't tell you what I had to do.
And so it's locked up in their hearts,
you know, and then what do they have?
They can drink or they can, you
know, um, distract themselves or, or,
or get in, you know,
blind rages periodically.
But if you get a room of returning
combat vets and hold it with,
um, a proper space of
understanding and compassion,
not only can they tell their stories,
which they've never told,
but they can listen to one another
and say, Oh yeah, I've been there,
and all of a sudden they're
not so alone anymore. And,
and that release of the
weight on their heart. Um,
so there's a social dimension to trauma
where we need to tell the story, um,
helps them release also what's carried
in their nervous system and in their,
and there's some,
some correlation between between those
two together that becomes very powerful
and we need that.
We need,
I do a lot of teaching of forgiveness
practice and self forgiveness and those
are also on those,
those guided meditations that I teach.
And for a lot of us self forgiveness,
like self compassion becomes a very,
very important way to liberate ourselves
from what we had to do to survive in
the past so that we're
actually be free in our life.
How do you set the stage, for
instance, with those, with those vets,
what do you say to them or what would
exercise might you do that opens a door
for them to share these stories?
So a couple of images.
One with gang kids and then one with that.
Um,
for,
for gang kids who come in are these kids
who are trying to get out of gangs and
might come with a mentor or something
like that to some events. We've had
any of these guys in
there, you know, ah, their,
their hoods are up in,
their hats are on backward and their
lean back and saying like, come on man,
you're gonna teach this meditation.
You're going to teach us,
give us some poem stories or bit listen,
we're out on the street.
People got nine millimeters,
you know,
you gotta give us something better
than that. So we try to make, uh,
a setting that honors who they
are from the very beginning.
We say,
well,
we can't talk yet about the real things
that we came here to do because there
are too many people in this room
who have not been acknowledged, um,
and not been respected.
So would you go out in the parking lot
and pick up a stone for every young
person you know who's been killed?
And we light one candle and put
it in the center of a table,
say bring it back in and say their name
and put their stone by this candle to
simple as possible ritual.
And these guys and sometimes gals will
come in and their hands are full of
stones. No young people should
know that many dead people. And,
and they'll say, this is for Tito and
this is for RJ and this is for home girl.
And pretty soon there's a mound of stones
and the names of people they've lost,
um, were, were put into the,
the fabric of the air of that room.
And their hoods are no longer over their
heads. They're sitting up like, okay,
this is the place where we can
talk about what's really going on.
So there's something about
making, whether it's through, um,
as the simplest ritual or making a
container in which people realize that,
that this is a safe place to talk about
what we've never done before with the
vets. One of the things that
Michael Meade, Luis Rodriguez,
these guys from Mosaic
Multicultural Foundation that
I've worked with for years,
a really wonderful, um, Michael,
who, who's in, you know,
a great drummer and a storyteller and
mythologist who's also been working in
prisons and with vets and gang
kids for years. And I'll say,
let me tell you an ancient
story of returning warriors.
And he has a handful of stories from
Africa to bat or the Mayan tradition about
warriors coming back, you know, with
their hands covered, with blood. Um,
and you know, their eyes,
uh, filled with, um,
the, the Mars with the Marshall
Energy that they would,
that they can't stop the violence
cause it's taken them over.
And here's a myth or a story that tells
about how ancient warriors were brought
back into their community.
Um,
I'll tell you the myth if you want
to hear one of them. Oh yes, please.
So here we are. You
know, and there's these,
there's these vets and already stories
of started to pour out about, um,
I can't tell you what I saw. I
can't tell you what I had to do. Um,
and Michael stood up and he said,
let me tell you an old Irish story of a,
um, an Irish warrior name, Coco Lane, or
I'm not sure how his name is pronounced,
something like that.
Um,
and he was the most fierce and
famous of all Irish warriors.
And the Irish warriors were, were mad
men, um, because they would go out,
they'd paint their bodies and
they'd go out and make it.
And sometimes you just see them coming
and you'd run the other way. But anyway,
there was some marauding king, King,
King and army that had come
to threaten their area.
And so coco lane went out and almost
single handedly chased them and defeated
them.
But then he was coming back
to his own town in a chariot,
covered with blood, uh,
and, um, his eyes blazing,
bearing down in his own town,
still possessed with the violence
of war with the god Mars.
Um, and they were all terrified he
would come and do violence there too.
And so they now look, can we
do, what can we do? Um, and, uh,
they went to ask the old wise woman in
the village and she said three things.
And so the first thing they lined up
all the women in the village who bared
their breasts and this slowed him down,
um,
as if it reminded him of his
mother's milk or something. Um,
and because he was slowed down and the
second thing they did was take a rope and
tie it around him and put him in
a huge cauldron of cold water,
which hist off his body.
And then they filled it three times
with cold water and find his body cooled
down.
And then the third thing they did is they
took him and still bound and they lay
him on a carpet in the
court of the local king. Um,
and they sang to him the stories and
myths and songs of warriors who had
protected the kingdom and then come back
and released the violence and the fears
that they carried and planted their
crops again and love their families.
Um,
and resumed living in harmony with
the community from which they came.
And they told the ancient stories and
sang the songs for three days and nights.
And when it was over cocoa
lane, eyes open, they let his,
they untied him and he was back
as a normal human being again.
And after Michael told
this story to that too,
had been telling terrible accounts
of things that happened in this room.
Um,
a hundred men stood up and we'd been
working with a simple African chant,
a song that was really an African
chant of a prayer, you know, um,
earth hold me for this.
Living is hard. Um,
we all sang to the vets,
um,
together for a long time as if we could
sing them back into their bodies from
this as if they were low lying there
and the, the court of the king. Um,
so this is, you asked
the question, how do you,
how do you make a setting that allows
people to truly feel that they can tell
their stories, um, and
be held in compassion?
Whether it's the grief of these gang kids,
that no one's really given them the
place to give voice to, you know,
or the vet who says,
I can't tell you what I had to do.
That's very powerful.
And it makes me also think back
to conversations I've had with uh,
Sebastian younger who was,
uh,
a wartime journalist as,
as,
as a co produced and shot a number
of really hiring a documentary films,
including Ristreppo,
uh,
and most recently wrote a book called
tribe that touches on some similar topic
area.
And leads me to ask you,
are there any rites of passages
or rituals that you feel
would be useful for every
man or woman to experience?
This is something that I've felt
a longing for and a lack of,
uh, since my teenage years
because I, I, I'm not Jewish,
did not have a bat mitzvah,
Bar Mitzvah.
I don't know if that
serves that purpose in the,
in the Jewish tradition necessarily.
But are there any,
any rituals or rites of passage that
you think we could use in, let's
just say the United States?
Uh,
that would be helpful too.
Whether it's a specific population,
specific group or uh,
anyone.
So while you're talking about is a
really big subject that's a subject of
initiation and unfortunately bar Mitzvahs,
at least when I was in there,
whereas it was a relatively
lightweight and meaningless thing.
You get up there and you recite your,
you know,
Hebrew portion of the Bible and now
you're a man and they give you a bunch of
presence and there wasn't a
lot of meaning in it. But the,
the problem that you raise is that of
the lack of initiation and what's true is
that it's been forgotten in our culture.
Um,
one of the few places you get
initiation is going into the military.
That's an initiation. Um, but a lot
of these gang kids, for example,
they're trying to initiate themselves,
which can't really happen.
You need elders and you needed in a
ritualized way, but they'll go on that,
you know, if you're in the Mussai, uh,
tradition in east Africa
and the Messiah people, um,
as everybody's heard, you know, a young
man at a certain age of 14 or something,
we'll go out and kill a lion,
um,
to prove that they're now an adult member
of the society and that they're brave.
And that's part of their initiation.
There were initiations for young women
as well. Um, and it's not just an Africa.
The Mayans had initiations.
And in Thailand,
when I lived there back starting
in the 1960s, at that point,
almost every young man
and many young women,
when they reached the age of 1920,
they became a monk for three months or
for a year and lived in an austere way.
And it was part of their initiation to
learn both the inner life of themselves
and also a kind of discipline. We
don't have it. And because of it,
you know, kids who are trying to initiate
themselves on the streets by, you know,
shooting somebody or doing something,
you know, that shows that they're brave,
but it's not a lion, it's
another person or it's, you know,
I'm trying to get the attention
of the others and say, prove how,
how powerful or strong they are.
So we desperately need these and we need
them built into our education and to
our psychology. Um, and I
can't give you a simple answer,
but one of the people who's has the
most intelligence about this is a man of
colleague of mine named Michael
Meade. Um, and if you look on mosaic,
multicultural foundation is the writings
on initiation and what's possible here
and the things he's led our very,
very inspiring.
Um, so that's a place that I would look,
that's a good starting point. Wonderful.
I will certainly find that. Well, Jack,
I think we could go for hours and hours
and hours and I always love chatting
with you and I'd love to
perhaps even consider doing
a part two sometime. But given that
we've already gone for two plus hours,
I want to ask just a few
more questions and uh,
I'll actually start with just
reading something very short,
which is from your 2017 year end message.
And uh, this is, I think this
is just to inject some more,
uh, optimism into our conversation,
which we've already had plenty of.
But, uh, this is, this is just a small
portion of your year end message.
A Martin Luther King Jr describes
our collective journey with hope.
The arc of the moral universe is long,
but it bends towards justice and quote
and Pablo Neruda Explains Further,
you can cut all the flowers,
but you cannot keep spring from coming.
Renewal is happening.
This is back to your voice.
Take quiet time to listen to your heart,
to meditate and to rest of
midst the great turnings.
Feel the renewal of spring that can be
born in you. Align yourself with goodness.
Let yourself blossom like a Lotus or
whatever unique flower you are shining in
the world, offering tiny seeds of love
amidst it all. Blessings to you in 2018,
Jack.
And I want this,
this note to then lead into,
uh,
in certainly you're
welcome to comment on that,
but which book you would recommend of
yours people start with or where they
start with all of the many materials,
recordings,
readings that you
produced because you're a,
a fantastic writer and a prolific writer.
Uh,
you have some of my favorite book
titles I've ever heard by the way,
including after the ecstasy, the
laundry, which maybe we could touch on,
but where would you suggest people start,
uh,
of the many things that
you've, that you've written
and shared with the world. Uh,
and, and if you have any comments
on that year end message,
you're welcome to share that as well.
Cool.
So from books, if you want
something simple, I have books like,
um, you know, an introduction
to meditation that sounds true.
Publishes or I have, um, um,
a little book called the art of
forgiveness, loving kindness and peace,
which is very simple
stories and practices. Um,
if you want something
that's richer and fuller,
then you could look at
one of my bigger books,
like a path with heart or the wise heart,
the guide to the two principals
of Buddhist psychology. Um,
and again,
I think lots of stuff
online and SoundsTrue's
particularly a good place to go
along with my website. Um, then,
and that 40 day mindfulness
mindfulness daily,
which is think it's like 30 bucks
or something. And you, you know, um,
is a really wonderful way to start.
Um,
in terms of what I had written,
uh, about the trusting heart,
one of the greatest zen techs from
thousand years ago says to be awakened or
enlightened is one with
trusting heart and mind.
And it doesn't mean that,
that we won't go through hard times.
We always have and we will again,
and we are now in many ways,
but that we also have born within us
the capacity to meet these difficulties
with, uh, understanding, um, and
with courage, with compassion,
and to transform them.
And in that way,
one of my favorite recent books is,
um,
called the better angels of our
nature by Steven pinker. Um,
and he's a remarkable professor
at Harvard anthropologist,
historian talking about,
um,
the growing consciousness of humanity in
spite of the kind of wars and conflict
and environmental things.
There are so many good things that have
happened that he charts over the last
few centuries of the development
of, um, you know, uh,
certain certain abilities for peacemaking.
There's actually less for than there
had been. Um, you know, respect for,
for women. Um, the reduction
in, uh, you know, child labor,
all kinds of things. And,
and in that same regard, um,
there's a wonderful book
called very the chains,
which is about the ending of
slavery in the British Empire,
starting with this handful of men,
um,
who met in a British tea shop or printing
shop and spent 30 years riding around
the country bringing ex
slaves who are well spoken to,
talk about the middle passage and the,
you know,
the horrors of slavery and so forth.
And even though the British Empire's
economic engine was built around slavery
and sugar by the end of their work,
um,
of 30 years, uh, the
British parliament, um,
outlawed slavery and the British Empire,
you know,
decades before it happened in the u s
and the Quakers were a big part of this.
And the Quakers famously wouldn't
take their hats off for the king.
But when, um, what is his name?
Thomas Clarkson,
who was the center of this group trying
to end slavery and going everywhere to
do it. When Thomas Clarkson died,
the goal, the Quakers of the England,
England took their hats off because he'd,
he's freed so many
spirits and so many lives.
So the possible we have these amazing
possibilities that human beings,
and we're just growing into them now
culturally. Um, and it's about time.
Um, but it's, it, they're the,
they are possible and we each have a,
have a contribution to make in it.
Jack, I'm going to ask you one more
question before we wrap up with, uh,
just,
uh,
letting people know where they can
find you on social media and elsewhere,
the website and so on. But last question
is, one I like to ask, and this is,
this is a metaphor,
but if you could a short
message on a billboard,
in other words, get them. I get a message
out to millions or billions of people.
It could be a few words, one
word, a phrase, a quote of yours,
a quote of someone else's. Uh, what
might you put on that billboard?
Yeah.
Um, well, two things come to mind.
One is a question that when I sit with
sat with people many times at the end of
their life that they,
that they then ask of themselves
silently or out loud is,
did I love well, because in the
end what matters is really, um,
the billboard would have a question
rather than a statement. Um,
and it would have a
question. Something like, um,
I don't know, how could I love myself
better or what, what, you know,
so that it actually, it's not that
I'm going to tell them something,
they already know this,
but I'm going to remind those who read
that there is something that's asking to
be awakened in them. How could I
love myself? And this world better.
And then you know, or what gets
and you know, then you'd go, well,
it gets in the way of that.
And how can I love that too?
How can I love myself in
this world better? Hmm.
Well, Jack, I want to of course,
thank you for your time today,
but, uh, beyond that, I want to
thank you and this is, this is very,
um,
very much from deep in my heart.
Thank you for helping me to learn to
love myself better and quite frankly,
to see something in the first
place that is worth loving.
That's not a where I've spent
most of my life. So it's,
it's turned into, uh, if not my,
I hesitate to say my top
priority because I'm,
I worry about sounding
it's self indulgent,
but it's become one of the most important
and fruitful tasks in my life is
asking that question,
how could I love myself better?
Or how could I learn to love
myself better? So thank you
very, very sincerely, uh,
for that. And that the words don't do
it justice, but, uh, uh, I'll, I'll,
that's all. That's the best I
can do right now, remotely is to,
is to put it into words.
So thank you for that.
Thank you Tim.
This was,
this was a pleasure to do and what I feel
and I know is it as you tend your own
heart,
I'm in a wise way,
then it makes you available
to bring the gifts,
the many gifts you have to the
world, you personally and others. Um,
but to do it in a way that's on the
carrier wave of connection and love and it
transforms everything. So
thank you to, Well Jack, I uh,
you know, I'm looking at it
texts one of ours and I'm feeling
the necklace around my neck,
which is really a thread,
a red thread that was used to
close the one of the elements,
the closing of the 10 day silent retreat.
And I shot you a text not too long ago
asking what the three nots meant because
I'd forgotten.
And this is what you wrote back first,
not equals refuge in whatever you hold
is most inspiring and sacred. Second,
commitment to compassion
for self and others. Third,
following your highest intention.
And the intention that I've said at the
end of that 10 day retreat was to learn
to love myself so I could
love others more fully. Uh,
but I've realized that maybe what it is
is learning to love myself so I can help
others learn to do the same.
And you've been an integral piece of that.
And uh,
I just love that I have the opportunity
to introduce you and your work and these
traditions to more people. And uh,
I will certainly be linking to,
uh,
where everyone can find you online,
but are there any particular
best places just to,
to reiterate where people can find you
and I'll link to these in the show notes.
Uh,
Jack kornfield.com and also look up Jack
Cornfield on soundstrue.com for those
programs that I talked about.
And then spirit rock.org,
which is our great
meditation center in the Bay,
San Francisco Bay area.
Absolutely stunning,
stunning,
beautiful location worth visiting
just to bathe in the scenery,
but many more reasons to visit as well.
Uh,
well Jack, thank you again and thank
you. Thank you Tim. It's a pleasure.
And to everybody listening,
you can find show notes,
links to all the resources, books, and
everything that we discussed at Tim. Dot.
Blog slash podcast. And until next
time, thank you so much for listening.
Hey guys, this is Tim again. Just a
few more things before you take off.
Number one,
this is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Fridays,
a very short email where
I share the coolest things
I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the, uh, the
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance.
And it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend.
So if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour work
week.com that's four hour work,
week.com all spelled out and just drop
in your email and you will get the very
next one. And if you sign
up, I hope you enjoy it.
This episode is brought to you
by fresh books, man. Oh Man.
Do a of listeners to this podcast and
readers in mind love fresh books to the
extent that I ended up meeting
with the CEO not very long ago.
Why are they so popular?
Well,
they are the number one cloud accounting
software designed exclusively for self
employed professionals.
That's many of you and use by more
than 10 million people and you can send
invoices, track your time and
get paid very, very quickly,
which suits the needs
of a lot of freelancers.
I'll have to onto my
friend Louis and beyond.
You can't take pictures of receipts.
You can link your credit
card and debit card,
so all the things you buy automatically
appear in your fresh books in the right
category, so on and so forth. Makes
taxes easy, makes invoices easy,
it makes your life easier.
And also in fact I recommend a pdf.
Uh, they didn't ask me to
read this part by the way.
They'd put the other pdf awhile back
called breaking the time barrier subtitle,
how to unlock your true earning potential
so you can search for breaking the
time barrier.
A lot of people ask me,
how can I get a four hour work
week with a service business?
And the story in that Ebook, it's pdf is
the short answer is really, really good.
So I think should also check that out.
So breaking the time error, check it out,
but also why not test out freshbooks.
Claim your 30 day unrestricted free
trial@freshbooks.com forward slash Tim and
Inter timferriss two rs and two ss in the,
how did you hear about us section?
That sounds like we're going to get
very little tracking, a lot of work,
but just go to freshbooks.com forward
slash Tim and try it out because it is a
very good product and I think you
will find it simplifies your life.
Enjoy.
This episode is brought
to you by four sigmatic.
You might remember four sigmatic
for their mushroom coffee,
which was created by those clever finished
founders and when I first mentioned
that coffee on this podcast,
the product sold out in less than a week.
It lights you up like a Christmas tree,
which can be really useful. However,
recently I've been testing the opposite
side of the spectrum of new product and
that is their Reishi mushroom elixir
to help me end my day to get to sleep.
As you guys may know,
longtime listeners,
at least I struggled with insomnia for
decades. I have a largely fixed that,
but still shutting off my monkey
brain has never been easy.
It still isn't easy very
often and I found Reishi,
which had been fascinated by for
a few years now has been very,
very effective and calming
their old formula. However,
four sigmatic old formula included
Stevia and I like to avoid sweeteners,
all sweeteners for a host of reasons
and I then just ping them and asked,
hey guys, I would love to experiment
with this and maybe actually suggested,
but I'd like a version without
sweeteners if you'd be open to it.
Too much of a headache,
don't worry.
And they are always game
for experimentation.
And so they created a special
custom version without the Stevia,
without sweeteners.
Now it is part of my nightly routine.
Their ratio looks or comes
in single serving packets,
which are perfect for travel.
And in fact,
I'm about to leave the country right
now and I have a packet in front of me
that's just going to sit in
the end of my carry on bag.
You only need hot water and it mixes very,
very easily.
Here's some recommended copies
that they put in the read,
so I'm going to read it and
I'll give you my take quote,
a warning for those in
the experimental mindset,
Reishi is strong and bitter in
parentheses, like any great medicine.
So if the bitterness is too much,
I recommend trying it with honey
end or nut milk such as almond milk.
And so I'm going to say,
no,
you should suck it up and you should drink
the tea because it's not that bitter.
And maybe should take the advice of all
Chinese people when they're criticizing
younguns when they say who and sure.
Cool,
which means you're not
able to eat bitterness.
Bitter is in many cases and indication
of things that help liver detoxification.
It's on,
not saying that's the case here,
but I've tested this ratio
lecture on family members,
on friends. Everybody has liked
it. It's a little bit, or if the,
it's not that hard,
so I would just say suck it up and no,
don't put in honey or milk or any of
that shit. Just drink the goddamn tea.
It's delicious. I think if you like to
air that kind of stuff, that type of tea,
you're going to dig it. So just
try it. Okay. Back to them by read.
If you'd like to naturally improve
your sleep, both onset and quality,
I think naturally you might just enjoy
this ratio lecture without any sweet
nurse. It has organic, Reishi
extract, organic fueled, mint extract,
organic rose hips extract, organic
Tulsi extract, and that's it.
No fancy stuff, no artificial watching
McCall at anything. So check it out.
Go to foursigmatic.com
forward slash Ferriss and get
20% off this special batch.
I don't know if they're gonna
be making much more of this, uh,
it since it was made specifically for
you guys to do me a favor and try it out
so that they continue to be
open to experimenting with
me to create products for
you guys. Specifically, check it out
for Sigmadek. That's Flur, s, I. G,
m, a, t, I, c. Dot com forward
slash and Ferris, F, e. R, r.
I. S. S. Get 20% off this special batch,
and you must use the code,
the Ferris to receive a discount.
F. E. R. R. I. S. S. So again,
go to foursigmatic.com
forward slash Ferris and then
use code Ferris for 20% off
of this rare,
exclusive,
limited run of Reishi mushroom elixir
for nighttime routines with out any
sweeteners.
Enjoy.
Okay.