Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism
boarding the sponsors of this show.
99 designs,
which is your one stop shop for
all things graphic design related.
Go to 99 designs.com forward slash Tim
to see the projects that I've put up,
including the mockups and drafts of
the book cover for the four hour body
Ex-officio Ex-officio and I go way back
ex-officio dot com forward slash Tim you
can see the clothing that I've used for
traveling through 20 plus countries,
including underwear.
By the way,
that's about half of my
underwear drawer right now,
ex-officio dot com forward slash Tim you
can also see the viral video that I put
out, which shows you how to travel
the world with 10 pounds or less.
As always,
you can subscribe to this podcast on
iTunes and you can find all of the links
and resources from this episode as well
as every other episode by going to four
hour workweek.com forward slash podcast
spell it all out or you can go to four
hour workweek.com and just click on
podcast feedback. If you have feedback,
I would love your thoughts. Anything at
all who you'd like to see on this show,
Ping me on Twitter at [inaudible]. That's
twitter.com forward slash t, F, e R R,
I s s or on facebook@facebook.com forward
slash Tim Ferriss with two r's and two
s's.
Good day.
This is Tim Ferriss.
I'm sitting in a park.
It's a beautiful park in San Francisco.
In the fall, weather is upon us.
The leaves are turning color and the
eucalyptus are still standing tall.
The foliage has not yet fallen.
It's a beautiful day.
For those of you who have not listened
to the Tim Ferriss show before.
This is where I tried to use all of
my contacts and research to dissect
excellence, to figure out whether
it's a billionaire investor,
a chess prodigy and actor, or in this
episode's case and actor and a comedian.
How do they do what they do?
What are the tools and tactics and
tricks that you can use? So we dig very,
very deep,
but I'll start off with a
bit of linguistic trivia
and I will ask apologies,
or rather not apologies,
that'd be a weird way to phrase it.
Forgiveness from the Turkish speakers.
I love the Turkish language.
It's a fascinating language,
fascinating culture,
a real collision of European
and Middle Eastern cultures.
And I also have found the similarity
between Turkish and Japanese.
Very,
very interesting.
But I'll give you an idea of how I
deconstruct languages just by memorizing
phrases. You can pick out patterns.
So for instance, if you say,
good day as translated into English
and Turkish. And I guess again,
I've read, not, not set it a
lot, but it's Egan, Eagan large.
Okay,
good evening is
[inaudible] [inaudible] and then the,
the way you would say child,
I believe it's choke Cho Cho took or choke
hook and then you have a choco color.
Okay. So you noticed the lot at the
end. So to churn child into children,
you have the Lord at the end and it
turns out that literally good day is good
days or good evenings in Turkish.
And so you can start to piece it
together without a dictionary,
without a gram reference
just by memorizing a handful,
even like a hundred words or
phrases. Anyway, I'm a nerd.
There you have it.
But we're gonna move on to Brian Kellen
who's the guest for this episode.
He is a prolific actor who has acted
in more shows than I can count,
certainly, but includes pretty
much all the shows at the,
at the top of the rankings, Frasier, uh,
Nyp de Bleu entourage law and order,
CSI sex and the city king of Queens.
It goes on and on and on.
He's also a worldclass comic who travels
the globe performing standup comedy for
sold out audiences all over the world.
He's also one of the best
read people I've ever met.
So we're going to dig into all sorts
of things. The craft of comedy,
how he boost his boost is
boosts his own creativity,
which sounds like I could stand to gain
from ideas for improving education,
both self education and institutional
education. Uh, many different, uh,
book recommendations,
influences of his.
We really dig into a lot of
details that I found fascinating.
Brian's one of my favorite people to
hang out with. So without further ado,
here's Brian, Callan.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Tim Ferriss and welcome
to the Tim Ferriss show.
But we also have 50% of this episode,
which is the Brian Collins show. Brian,
welcome to the show. Thank you sir.
I am excited to have you on
for many different reasons,
not the least of which, as
we were discussing before
we started recording, uh,
you are known as the best body and comedy,
if I'm not mistaken.
That's right. And so just think
about, you guys don't have any videos.
Just think of a, if you were to take
human skin and stretch it over a Cheetah,
I think that's why that's not me.
That's just what my critic,
the critics, that's what, that's, that's,
that's the worst they can come up with.
Well, my admirer say, but that's
just, that's just what the critic
and uh, you know, I'm
trying to piece together,
it's been a number of years now,
but how did we first meet,
what was the first
Neil Brennan who is the
creator of the Chappelle show,
knew I was in the fitness
and all that and he sent me,
I believe a Ted talk you had done
about a guy named Tim Ferriss. He said,
what do you think of this guy?
And I, I watched it and I,
and I was very taken with the way
you were explaining things and,
and how you use your body as a,
as a human Guinea pig. And I,
I think I texted him back. I
said, well, I know one thing.
I'm going to go out and get the
book, the four hour body. And, uh,
of course that sent me,
basically,
I started with the four hour body and
then I got into the four hour work week.
And then of course I listened to, uh, uh,
and then I read the four hour shifts. Um,
so I became sort of this, but what
I really, some of the concepts.