I will just do a sound check. What did
you have for breakfast this morning
for breakfast?
I had a cup of coffee with two shots
and heavy cream and actually uh,
an Americano with two shots of coffee
and heavy cream and I had a smoothie with
apple and yogurt and some shit and it,
well we, we will talk more about the
shit part. Uh, that, that's good.
It's going to be real
relevant to mold at this altitude.
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
No,
it just seem like
I'm a cybernetic organism
living this show metal go up.
This episode is brought to you by
Athletic Greens. I get asked all the time,
if you could only use one supplement,
what would it be?
And my answer is
inevitably Athletic Greens,
it is your all in one
nutritional insurance.
I recommended it in the four hour
body did not get paid for that.
And I travel with it
to avoid getting sick.
I take it in the mornings to
ensure optimal performance.
It just covers all my basis.
If I can't get what I need through whole
food meals throughout the rest of the
day, and you can get 50 oh my
gosh, 50% off. Yes, 50% off.
If you go to athleticgreens.com
forward slash Tim that's athletic,
greens.com forward slash Tim,
check it out. It's tasty,
but more important.
It will help you not screw up when
you're doing your nutritional planning.
For me, it just covers the
basis, takes a load off my mind,
puts a lot in my body and check it out.
athleticgreens.com forward slash Tim
this episode is brought
to you by Vimeo pro,
which is the ideal video hosting
platform for entrepreneurs and in fact,
a bunch of my startups already used
Vimeo pro including wealth front,
who uses it to explain how
Wealthfront works. Task Grab,
it uses it to tell the company story
and there are many other names you would
recognize among their customers, airbnb,
Etsy, et cetera. Why do they use it?
Well,
dimio pro provides enterprise level
video hosting for a fraction of the usual
cost. Features include gorgeous,
high quality playback with no ads,
up to 20 gigabytes of
video storage every week,
unlimited plays in views and a
fully customizable video player,
which can include your logo,
custom outro, et cetera.
You also get VIP support and you get
all of this for just one 99 per year.
That's $17 a month with no complicated
bandwidth calculations or hidden fees and
you can try it risk free for 30 days,
so check it out.
demio.com forward slash business that's
v I n e o.com forward slash business and
use Promo Code Tim to get 25% off. That's
a special discount just for you guys.
So check it out. vimeo.com forward
slash business promo code, Tim.
Yeah.
Hello my lazy kittens.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to another
episode of the Tim Ferriss show where
I attempt in each interview to deconstruct
world class performers to tease out
the things you can use,
not just act with integrity,
but what does that actually
mean on a daily basis?
What are your morning routines?
What are your habits?
What are your favorite books?
What are your influences,
what are your favorite documentaries,
so on and so forth.
I really want specific tactics that you
guys can apply toolkits that you can use
in your daily life and lives.
That's a plural for you guys and
this episode is no exception.
I'm very excited to have Sophia Amoruso
that's at Sophia underscore Emma Russo
on the show. She is founder and
executive chairman of Nasty Gal,
which is a global online destination
for both new and vintage clothing,
shoes and accessories
among many other things.
Founded in 2006 nasty gal was named
fastest growing retailer in 2012 by ink
magazine.
Thanks.
I suppose in part two it's
11200% three year growth rate.
It's a very big number.
Sophia has been called to quote fashions,
new phenom and quote by Forbes magazine
and she's become one of the most
prominent and iconic figures in retail.
She recently founded
Hashtag girlboss foundation,
which are words financial grants
to women in the world of design,
fashion and music.
Sophia's first book,
Hashtag girlboss check it out
is in New York Times bestseller,
published in 15 countries. And
we touch upon many, many things.
We talk about tactics testing,
the genesis story of Nasty Gal,
early successes, early mistakes, uh,
the last time she accidentally
crapped in her pants.
We really go all over the place and
there is a lot of personality in this
episode. There's a lot of fun and
there's also a lot that you can use.
So without further ado, please enjoy
this conversation with Sophia. Amoruso.
Sophia, welcome to the show.
Hi Tim, how are you? I am,
I'm fantastic and uh,
we've had such an adventure putting this
together and getting all the tech to
work, but I'm stoked to be chatting
with you. I've wanted to have a,
a, a jam session with you for so long
and I know we've met very briefly before,
but, uh, let's,
let's start with some basics for people
who may not be familiar with you and,
and I know your role has changed
in the last, uh, year or so,
but when people ask you, what do
you do, how do you answer that? Now.
And how did you answer that two years ago?
If I don't know them,
I just say like I have an online fashion
business and I try to leave it at that
and if they ask, it
depends on who it is. Um,
but I started a company called Nasty
Gal in 2006 as an Ebay store selling
vintage clothing and you know,
whatever,
like all a lot of entrepreneurs
just did everything myself.
Did what needed to happen.
Just ran a little ebay store but
it wasn't little for very long. Um,
left Ebay about a year and a half later
and launched nasty gal.com which is now
kind of a full on fashion ecommerce,
commerce,
a destination.
We carry brands,
we design our own product and
we still sell vintage. Um,
and I guess I'm an author,
so there's that too.
I wrote a book last year that
spent a bunch of time on the,
on the bestseller list and
it was called girl boss.
It's called Hashtag girl boss, but thing
Hashtag out loud. It's kind of weird.
I mean you're a multihyphenate,
you've done a lot to to put
some numbers or stats to it. Uh,
and I'm reading off of a, just the
reading that I've done, so I'd love for,
feel free to correct me,
but it sounds like company has
customers in more than 60 countries.
It was the fastest growing retailer
in 2012 according to ink magazine.
Uh,
and I guess at one point at
least it sounds like, and again,
I'm reading from online, so who
knows how verified this is. But, uh,
I guess in 2011 when it was
started in 2006 and by 2011,
revenue is like 24 million or so marking
I guess in 11,000 plus three year
growth rate. So very impressive
stuff. Uh, very impressive. Uh,
and the, uh, I have to,
I cannot resist asking about some of these
bullets before we get into that whole
story. I apologize in advance. So for,
for those who are wondering how
this podcast gets put together, uh,
I usually like to,
not not rehearsed,
but send some prompts for
guests are on the show.
So one of the sentences that I send out
is can you please send some bullets with
a handful of topics and are questions
that will lead to actionable tips, advice,
comma, funny stories, comma or
resource and how to recommendations.
So funny stories.
The first I just went straight for
funding. Oh No, it was awesome.
So I'm just going to read the first five
and then we're going to dig into one.
So bullet number one,
I once poop my pants in high school.
We're going to come back to that.
Number two.
I have three poodles that are all related.
Number three,
and I'm paraphrasing here,
I lived on a street called called orange
blossom twice in different parts of
California. I love Karaoke and
the then the, the last bill it,
I'll read it.
I'm a big supporter of reality TV because
it's cheaper and healthier than weed
or alcohol.
So people love the embarrassing stories.
I woke up this morning for the first time,
I just adopted a rescue puppy about
six weeks ago. She's five months old.
I woke up and she's never pooped
in the house and woke up and she,
she's been crate trained
and looking at the crate,
it looked like someone had taken a
handful of mud and throwing it into a
Cuisinart. She somehow managed
to diarrhea in every direction,
including on the top of the cage. I don't
know how this is possible. Yeah, yeah.
Unless you're like a Cirque de
Solei athlete who's had whatever,
a two I should drink. But in any case,
so this is on the mind, obviously,
it's all clean up. She's
fine. She's chilling. Molly's
good. But tell me about this,
this high school incident.
I, uh, I have to,
I have to ask since it was sent over.
Oh my God. Well, um, I
was at this guy's house.
I was like 16 years old.
I was at this guy's house who was like,
it's amazing basis. He played this thing
called a war guitar, which is base.
It's like a, it's like a
base with, I don't have a ton
of strings on it. And you,
it's, you basically just play
the fret board. And he was
just thinking, it's weird.
Like proggy musician and I thought
was super cool. Um, and he was like,
I don't know, maybe he was like 19.
I thought that was amazing. And, um,
I went to his house, he like lived with
his dad and got there like, I don't know,
after like 15 minutes and my
stomach was just like, uh, oh. Um,
I had eaten some,
some pepperoni pizza.
I think like the kind that has cheese
that you can almost drank, like not, um,
not the, not like, you know,
not like Boutiquey La Pizza or
whatever. It's like, it was like,
it was like gnarly pepperoni pizza, just
like mouthfuls of cheese. Anyway. Um,
I was like, oh no, I don't want
to use this guy's bathroom.
I'm not sure what's going on here,
but I should probably leave.
So after like 15 minutes at
his house, I, I left, um,
and I started driving down the
street. It wasn't like, oh Geeze,
well if I find a toilet then I'll
be happy about it. It was like, oh,
I really need it toilet.
Um,
and I stopped at this liquor store
and walked inside and I was like,
do you guys have a restroom I can
use? And they were like, no, sorry.
It's for employees only.
I thought age,
it would have been confusing if I had
like lied and said I was pregnant.
I've done that before. Um, oh,
you won an awful person. Oh.
Um, and then so I got
back in my car and drove,
I was in like 1991 Honda civic with
a little like, like a little like,
like a racing steering wheel.
It was pretty funny. Um,
and I drove it on the street and stopped
at a gas station and got out and it was
like step step, frankly, just like, oh,
I didn't even make it inside.
And it was just like, you know,
when something like that happens to you,
you wonder if you're going to spend
the rest of your life doing that like
uncontrollably because it's just
so, it's so shocking. Like it,
it just shouldn't happen. Um, and, and I,
I just like I had to get back in my
car and like finish, like finish.
And then I had to drive home and,
and you know, sitting in my, in my,
I'm sorry. That's, that's,
that's, that's my pitch.
I apologize for that.
But so you see
same story
and uh,
so I have number of friends
who swapped the stories.
Sorry, my dog's freaking
out guys. Ah, okay.
This is a podcast verite.
Uh, are you there?
Yeah. Okay. Coming back
to the topic at hand.
So I have a number of friends who are
athletes and I've been competitive
athletes and guys take all sorts of
disgusting preworkout products and so on.
And these guys trade stories
of what they call fouling out.
So what happened to you? They would
call fouling out and, Oh my God,
I'm not alone. People are out there.
No, you're not alone. And, um, so I'll,
I'll trade of just a really quick one
because I think that most guys who've
tried to gain muscle and taken a lot
of horrible supplements will somehow
identify with this. So I was on my
way driving on my way to Sfo, right?
Driving to the airport. And I had
had a bunch of creatine monohydrate,
a bunch of coffee,
and then I think what's called MCT oil,
which is the ultimate recipe for disaster
pants. I now realize in retrospect,
but got halfway to the airport,
I'm racing to the flight deck and had
the exact experience that you did like
just viciously shat myself.
And so I,
it's like throwing up,
it comes in waves.
Oh I was the worst. That's
like throwing up. It's so true.
So then I had to basically like
clean myself up with my own boxers,
like running to the airport,
get through security and
then go deal with myself.
But so for those people out there who've
had this experience, you're not alone.
And that what you said also like the
steps kind of like steps, step, Bang.
It made me think of like San Francisco
Doula midwifery and whatnot because
they're like, oh, when you're
trying to have a natural birth,
if you're doing it at home,
you can have a pregnant woman like
walk on a curb just like one foot on,
one foot off. And that's a one way to
like kind of pop the baby out. So wow.
You know, all kinds of stuff. Well, yeah,
for our baby before baby
sounds like a horrible tragedy.
Uh,
but uh,
how did the business start in yet?
And I think a lot of people know, they
know you, they know your photograph,
they've seen the book.
Uh,
they're very familiar with the company
as it exists now. But like what was the,
what was the moment in which you
decided to start selling clothing?
Yeah. Um, I'd never worked in a club
thing store and it wasn't, you know,
this is the, Ebay was definitely not
my way into the fashion industry.
That was not my intention.
I just was kind of flailing.
I want it to be a photographer,
but I figuring out how to like schmooze
in the art world or talk about my
photography and make stuff up about why
it was important or all of that stuff
just seemed like now,
right for me.
And not like people were
inviting me to do shows,
although I did have a show at Adobe
books before they went extinct.
Do you ever go there?
No, this is, this is here in the bay area.
Yeah. It was a super cool book
store in San, but I don't know,
I was like working at the Academy of Art
University in downtown San Francisco.
On how, how old were you at that
point? I was 22. Okay. Got It.
And I got that job because I
needed to have a hernia fixed.
I don't know how I got a hernia,
but I had no health insurance.
I had to get a job so I could get health
insurance so I could get my hernia
fixed.
And I had to work at this job for
three months to get health insurance.
So I did,
but I was working in the lobby just
like checking student ids and sometimes
worked like late at night
and was [inaudible] had time
to kill on the Internet.
Um, and was getting friend
requests on my space.
I'm not sure if anyone remembers.
I'm kidding.
Um, and so I was getting friend requests
on my space from Ebay sellers that were
promoting their businesses on my space
and I wore almost entirely vintage at the
time and I knew where to find it.
And I saw the prices that these vintage
pieces were fetching on Ebay and said,
hey, you know, I can find them for way
cheaper. Um, I know how to take a picture.
I'm pretty sure I know how to
use the Internet. Um, and Ebay,
Ebay was a great place to start.
You know,
there's a kind of like a
framework for you to sell online.
It's really easy today. But then building
a website like a web shop wasn't,
you know,
it wasn't as easy.
So I started with Ebay and you also
have a built in customer base there.
You put something and you can test,
you can test like what works
or if people like your taste,
your taste or what you
have to bring to the table.
So I bought on Ebay for dummies and uh,
had a friend model for free, you
know, and just found some vintage,
sold some of my stuff.
And it was very, you know,
you can get a read on
what people like really,
really quickly on Ebay because
they watch stuff. Right.
There's something called watching,
which is basically like you're,
you're like monitoring it.
Are you adding to your favorites?
You want to see what happens with the
auction over the course of the week or 10
days?
How did you know where
to find vintage clothing?
I, it was like all I wore,
so I just, I had spent,
I've just spent my youth in thrift stores,
like discovering,
just unearthing stuff
that no one else wanted,
that I thought it was really special
and I made a, made a career out of it.
Did you have a favorite thrift
store at the time? In the bay area?
Um, let me think. Uh,
at the time, I don't know. No,
none of them are just, none of them
are a real like gold mine anymore.
I like to state sales a lot because you
can encounter people who have no idea
what they have that's
becoming rarer and rarer.
And thrift stores are like onto
vintage being valuable. Um,
how would you find at the time,
how would you find the estate sales?
Just look in the newspaper or like a
craigslist. I'm nothing man. I'm chilling.
Yeah. Craigslist and the newspaper. Yeah.
And I like line up with all these
people that were, I don't know,
way older than me at like 6:00
AM to be the first people in.
And I just run straight for the closet
and hope whoever died had great style.
I saw the end. I didn't watch,
I didn't see the entire thing.
My girlfriend is watching it at the
end of this documentary about a,
I want to say a fashion icon named Iris
who's now or when it was recorded or
filmed in her nineties 93
and she has awesome style,
but I think it'll be hard to get to
her estate still. I, yeah. So you got,
you get Ebay for dummies,
you know where to find
the vintage clothing.
Um, take a picture. No,
I how to take a picture
and you're getting an indication of
what works or what people are at least
interested in. Right through
the watching. What was,
do you remember your first sale
or your first day of sales?
Yeah, it was like, well it was, uh,
it was, it was a week of auctions.
So I watched what happened over the
course of the week. And at the very end,
some stuff goes crazy because people swoop
in at the last minute trying to steal
it from whoever was in the lead. And,
you know, sometimes nothing happens,
but I learned really quickly what,
you know,
what was working and what wasn't
and tweak that, you know, every,
with every auction,
with everything I,
I bought and I watched my competitors
and I watched what they were doing and I
just, I tried to do a
better job and I don't know
what, what, uh,
what are some examples of maybe some
of the things that you noticed in those
initial tests and that
you could be better at?
Yeah.
Um,
well the thumbnails are the
thing that attract that Amy, you,
you evaluate everything
as you browse Ebay,
buy a thumbnail and the title of the item.
And those are two things that you can
optimize just to kind of infinity.
I mean there's a limited amount of space,
but I knew that using images that were
really bright where you could see the
silhouette of the item,
Ebay thumbnails had gotten a lot bigger,
but at the time they were
teeny tiny, teeny tiny. Um,
so making it really obvious what the,
what the item was and even showing,
you know, I had a, uh,
I would split the image in half and
have half of the thumbnail be a full,
like a full length shot of the item.
And then I'd have like a detail shot
like on the maybe the right hand side and
the description. So I mean,
the selling vintage is,
is such an incredible way
to learn perceived value
because unless you're selling
something that's like a designer,
like a Chanel jacket or whatever,
you're buying stuff that you're buying
it for the style and you're buying things
that have no inherent value,
that could be,
that are really are someone
else's throwaway and
exalting them to a level that
makes them worth more and,
and worth more. I mean,
Eva was the customer who
determined the price.
They started everything at
nine 99 and let them choose,
I'll let them fight over it,
but only they only thought over it
because I turned it into something really
special.
Um,
and I breathed new life into
these forgotten about things.
And what were, I mean,
as a, as a copywriter,
how did you accomplish that?
Um,
and maybe that's a nonspecific
question that's unhelpful.
I'm just first for instance. I
mean a lot of people bring up, uh,
I think it's influenced by Robert
Kel Deni and they talk about,
say you'd get a scarcity
time, restrictions, et Cetera,
eh, as sort of tools of persuasion that
can be used for, for good or ill means.
Um, but there, what did you, how did
you learn to write persuasive copy?
Um, I don't know. My mom
was a writer and write it.
Reading and writing was always, I
mean, it sounds like so, so basic,
but it was just something that she
always took a lot of pride in. And,
um, something that I really cared
about and I guess I had a voice.
I didn't realize that until
later on when I re, you know,
when I realized it was building a brand
because there were so many specific
things that were, had become
part of the nasty y'all DNA. Um,
but you can take something
that may be like an eighties,
like big ass, you know, coat
KP thing that, you know,
some, you know, overweight
lady might've bought. Um,
and turn it into like this,
like avant garde. I mean,
you can use a word like avant garde for
something that could be perceived as
like outdated and funky
on the wrong person,
like a lady with a perm or just like the
coolest thing on some like kid with a
weird haircut, you know, on the
sidewalk. So it's all about context,
right?
Yeah.
So a couple of things. Um, the,
the first is thumbnails. We're
doing this over Skype, uh,
for those people who always ask me,
I'm using he cam call recorder to record
this and the Audio Technica Atr 2100
Mike, which is about
60 bucks on Amazon. Uh,
but your thumbnail for Skype
is this rad looking chick.
I don't know who, she is a
hoot. It's a bunch of bikers,
naked female bikers and one of them has,
it looks like a tattoo of flowers and
something over one breast and she's
holding a knife. I can't really
tell exactly what's going on.
Yep.
That's pretty accurate.
Where is this from or how did you,
um, so I'm, I'm working on,
I'm working on my second book.
Um,
and I've been like pulling images.
There's all kinds of inspiration.
Some of it will be used in the book.
And this is actually an image from
a movie called girl boss, Girl boss,
gorilla
gorilla, g. U. E. R.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
So that was a film that I saw a long
time ago that was kind of the inspiration
for the name of girl boss.
And very few people know that
there's a whole genre of Japanese,
um,
like cinema called pinky
violence or just pinky films.
And it's pretty much like all female
revenge and like girl gangs and they're so
cool. Like they're super stylish and
Terentino's ripped a lot from them.
Um, and this, this one, this
is from girl boss gorilla,
I think battle royale,
I want to say is one of those comic books,
one of the most violent.
Uh Huh.
I've seen it.
Violent things you could possibly imagine,
which makes you then think of some of
say the fight scenes in like kill bill in
some capacity. But coming back
to the writing for a second,
let me start with a question that I
always ask and we'll go from there.
What is the book that you've
gifted most to other people?
So the book that I have gifted
most to other people is uh,
the richest man in Babylon,
which I talk about in girl boss and it's
was written like a hundred years ago
and it's written as though it was
written in biblical times or something.
A parable.
Oh yeah, it's a parable or, yeah, it'd
be a parable. It'd be like the alchemist.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's basically parable set in ancient
times describing someone who goes about
this guy who goes about,
I forget his name,
trying to find out how he can make money.
How can you,
you can make a life for himself and
his family and he encounters all these
different people and lessons along
the way. Um, and the advice is very,
there's some really simple advice like
save 10% of everything that you earn.
Don't take advice from the baker if
you want to be a cobbler, you know? Um,
and it's something that anyone can
read and understand. It's like a,
it's like a one hour or two hour read.
It's the tiniest little book and a hundred
years later all of the advice still
holds up, which I find really
great. Um, and it's like a, it's a,
it's a cheap book and I'm a cheap
giver, so I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
So it would be that, it would
be that in my book, I guess
the richest man in Babylon. And
what, uh, what other writers,
just from a writing perspective,
so you said your, uh,
you said your mother was
right or your father, my mom.
What type of writing did she do?
Well,
she sold houses for a long time and
then kind of quit doing that and started
writing about real estate.
And now she writes about all kinds of
stuff and she's working on her own book.
Um, but yeah. Wait, what was the question?
The question was, I was, I was stuttering
and stammering my way to the question,
which was what do you have any favorite
writers or writers that you admire have
influenced you?
Any of the above?
Yeah. So, uh, Rainer Maria Roca,
I think it's just such like, great.
Can you say that one more time please?
I think it's Maria Rilke. Oh
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Um,
so on love and other, what's
it called on loving other, um,
maybe it's just on love.
I don't know.
Everything I read almost like everything
that I learned from actually reading
things or,
um,
on earth thing culture happened before
I started the business because after,
basically, since I was 22, so
it's been almost a decade. Um,
I feel like my personal,
I dunno, my quest for,
for for knowledge was
fulfilled by all this shit,
all the challenges that come
with building a business.
And so things like books that I read for
fun and not books that I read to learn
stuff kind of went out the door.
Right. It's like all nonfiction.
The discretionary extracurricular
just kind of got consumed,
are displaced by the work
kind of.
Yeah.
It's like I only read things that I can
do something practical with now. Just,
I don't know, not, not, not something
that makes for a lot of relaxation, but
fun. So Rainer Maria,
Rilke, uh, if that's,
I'm sure I'm pronouncing that incorrectly,
but he's come up actually in my life
in the last 48 hours of a two separate
people recommend reading. And I
did read this long, long time ago,
but letters to a young
poet. Yes. From 1929. Uh,
so what did you do?
You said it's not relaxing and I
know we're hopping around a lot,
but what do you do to relax?
Let's just say,
looking back at some of the either tougher
periods or fastest growing periods in
your company, what did you
do to decompress? I mean,
when you felt overwhelmed or burned out,
what did you do?
How did you manage that?
God, sometimes you just kind of explode
and hopefully no one else is around.
Um, when I was like, I was
like crying last night. Uh,
also,
why were you crying last night?
I can't let that go.
Oh my God. I don't know. Just because,
because running a business is really hard.
Um, and what do you mean?
What do you do? I mean,
do you cry for like five
minutes and you're done?
Do you cry for longer than that?
Do you?
Yeah, I cried for like five minutes and
then I was done. She was kind of like,
this feels good, so I'm going to just
let it happen for a second. Yeah. Um,
yeah. It's just like, fuck it.
It was just one of those
was the long day. Um, yeah.
But right now,
the thing that relaxes me the most is to
tuning in and turning off with reality
TV. Hmm. Uh, I don't know.
I just finished watching the entire
season of the worst show. It's not,
the people are not even compelling.
They're like not funny. It's, it's,
it's so bad, but it, you can't stop
watching it. It's called dating naked,
eating naked. Oh my God. I've seen,
I remember I saw a few minutes of this
in like a waiting room at a doctor or
something. And I was like,
that is the most ridiculous
premise I've ever seen,
but I couldn't stop watching it.
So dumb. So, um, but I can't,
you can't stop watching it.
You're like, Ooh, they're buds. And you're
like, but I'm like watching this show.
I Dunno. Um, yeah. What else do I
do to relax? Hang out with my dogs?
They're cool.
Um,
these are, these are, these are
the three poodles that are related.
They're all siblings. Yeah.
And they're different ages.
They're like from different letters,
but their parents like, yeah,
their parents have been busy.
What are their,
what are their names?
Um,
Donna summer is the oldest one and she
was like three and the next one's cozy
dozer and cozies like,
I dunno,
maybe just over a year old.
And then there's one named Gino who was
named after my husband's grandfather.
Um, and he's like, I don't
know, maybe eight months.
That's that. Gino, I want to talk about
naming cause naming and titling is really,
I, I've, I've enjoyed reading about how
you've gone about it in a few cases.
So the girl boss gorilla,
I had no idea.
So that's new and I need to get that
made into a poster in my house cause it's
amazing. Uh, second. So Gina's,
after the grandfather would
have with the two other dogs,
how did you come up with those names?
Or how were the named,
I dunno. Donna was just like,
well it was kind of like,
can we name her Donna bummer. And then
it was like, but that's not very nice.
Caleb's name. They were Donna
summer. I Dunno. I Dunno why.
So it's like she's a cool
haircut and then a cozy,
it was just like super sleepy. And
you know, when we brought Donna home,
she was like screaming her head off,
just like don't take me away
from my parents. And we were
like, oh no, we're awful.
And then we brought cozy, homey and cozy,
just like kind of slapped. There's no,
it was just like, I'm cool and she's still
like that. So it was just like, let's,
let's name our cozy dozer
cause he does her now. Nasty
Gal. [inaudible] this is Pete.
A lot of folks don't know the origin.
Where's the name from?
So the name Nasty Gal.
Um,
so I used to work at a record store in
San Francisco that's no longer around, um,
and Noe valley called street light
records and spent a lot of time,
I think music was probably like
my first love way before fashion.
I'm not even sure if I'm in
love with fashion. Um, and this,
I'm not sure if it was
just reissued at that time,
but I somehow on covered this album
called a nasty out by a woman named Betty
Davis, who I think is becoming,
become more well known. But, um,
she is the ex wife of miles Davis and
she's just like super outspoken funk
singer with a really great band behind
her and just the Super Raunchy like
awesome lyrics and she just
doesn't give a fuck. Um,
so when I was choosing a name for my
Ebay store, which I never thought I'd be,
you know, I never thought I'd be
talking about it this much, you know,
nine later you just fine.
I still like the name. Um,
I thought I thought nasty gal would be
good because there were so many other
ebay sellers who,
whose business names were like lady
standing in the desk or you know, like,
or like lady in tall grass or like Boho,
just like so like Bohemian and kind
of like expected. And I was like,
I'm going to name it nasty
Gal. I Dunno. I'm just like,
I'm an m antagonistic and
I don't know I'm at work.
What uh, looking back at Nasty
Gal, I guess a couple of questions.
One is I've read in different places,
well different accounts of
this. Why Levy Vba? What uh,
what?
Yeah,
one second. Did I actually say that
she has an album called nasty gal?
Because I think I didn't,
cause I think I just talked
about this lady named Betty do.
Ah, all right, well that, that's
helpful to have that tidbit then.
So the album name is nasty
gal. Hence yes. Bang. Okay,
cool. Uh, the transition off of Ebay,
how did that have that happy? What's
the, what's the story behind that?
Well, it wasn't much of
a transition, you know,
I like to make promises that I'm not
sure I can keep and then figuring out how
to keep them.
It's happened a few times in my life,
um,
that we will come back to that.
Yeah,
it's good.
I think you can like will things into
happening by just like committing to them
sometimes. Um, and so I was started,
started to promote the idea of this, you
know, coming soon. Nasty Gal, Dotcom,
Nasty Gal, vintage.com was actually the
first URL I had to buy nasty gal. Dot.
Come from, you can guess who? Um, but I,
I had started to leave
feedback from my customers
second. All right. I actually
kick guess. I'm like, Bet Davis.
I can't imagine that's no.
Who did you have to buy from one of
the boring company? Yes. All right,
got it.
Can you do that through a broker?
Do you to reach out to
them directly or how did it
and did it through a broker.
Got It.
And where does someone find such a broker
to help them if they want to do that?
I don't remember. Someone introduced
me to this guy and it was like,
it was $8,000.
Nice. That's a good investment
right there. So sorry to
interrupt, but I had to,
my head was spinning with all
these incorrect answers so,
so you get the domain
you've put up coming soon.
But at the domain domain. Yeah, coming
soon, you know, nasty gal vintage.
And I had started to leave feedback
for my customers on Ebay saying like,
hey come come the coming soon as y'all
vantage.com. And I was like, Oh shit,
I better build a website. Better
actually do this. So I figured it out.
I launched the website, um, and
when I launched the website,
Ebay decided to suspend me at around the
same time. So it was not a transition.
It was literally like,
I'm going to try this website thing.
I hope I can go back to Ebay if it doesn't
work out. But it'd be, it was very,
it became apparent pretty quickly that
that wasn't going to be an option.
I got suspended for leaving a
URL in the feedback for yeah.
Ebay,
if it doesn't want to send,
they don't want you sending
traffic off their website.
Yeah.
[inaudible] on the stealing our
customers a from there. Yeah,
nay on the Ebay.
Right, exactly. Uh, so the,
so what the hell did you do?
I mean if,
if suddenly Bam,
that entire ecosystem is turned off.
What happened in the next kind of like 24,
48 hours?
Um, I had, well some people, some,
some editors had heard or seen on the my
space profile that I was going to watch
your website and they did a little
coverage. I bet when they, when it,
when it launched and it launched,
it was his kind of like,
there was a lot of pent up demand I had,
I didn't know I would have any traffic,
but the website sold out just instantly.
It was like an hour and there was maybe
150 items on the website when we launch,
but there's only one of each of those
things that are just one of a kind of,
you just 150 orders still seems like a
lot for your first day of doing business.
It was just like,
I had like Kelly Ripa stylist calling
me asking if I had another one of those
like extras though, isn't it like vintage
jacket and an extra small? It's like, no,
it's one of was crying and I don't know,
it was,
it was very serendipitous that it, that
it worked at all and that, you know, I,
I was able to not have to go back
to Ebay is even a sentence somehow.
No, I think we, I think we
can work without punctuation
in this conversation. Okay.
The, uh, especially since I've
had enough enough tea now, uh,
and uh,
butter and coconut oil two to
last me for like a Siberian trek,
but I'm digressing the Ebay transition
slash booting off of slash jumping,
jumping headfirst and growing
wings on the way down.
That was how long after
you started selling on Ebay
that was a oh gosh,
a year and a half.
And at the,
at the point that you launched your site,
what we did sales look like on
Ebay for you, if you recall?
Yeah, so the first year on Ebay
was like 75,000 in revenue,
which, you know, I wasn't paying
myself. I mean I didn't need stuff.
I lived in a pool house for $500 a month.
Like I drove an 87 Volvo. Like I didn't,
I hate Boston market and subway, you
know, like all the time. So it was,
that was like winning a lottery.
Yeah. Oh for sure. I think Boston
markets underrated. I used it kind of,
that's like trader Joe's
and Boston markets.
Like don't knock it until you try it.
Uh,
and then you start getting these
inquiries from say Kelly Ripa style.
She is extra small. Um, having
been on that show on, she is tiny,
such great shape. She
is an amazing shape. Uh,
how did you develop those
relationships with editors and so on?
Or was it all out of the blue? I mean,
did you ping them? No, it was sitting here
like totally inbound at that point and
there wasn't like a giant, you know,
there wasn't a ton of news
embryo. It was daily Candy, um,
you know, rest in peace and uh, who, what,
where and they just kind of, they
had, they followed me on my space,
they heard about the launch and they
decided to talk about it and the kind of
coverage I got with stuff that
brands like car, we'll pay, you know,
tens of thousands of dollars you know,
for. But when you're doing something cool,
people want to talk about it.
And I guess it was cool.
I mean I hate saying that I'm cool,
but
no, you can say it was cool
because if you were like,
let me tell you how I'm cool,
it would be one thing.
But you're talking about how the, how the,
the launch was cool. That's fair. Okay.
They liked it. So they talked about
it. If you have something great,
people will talk about it.
I think that's just kind of
like a rule of the Internet.
And if,
if someone were launching now,
not necessarily fashion or
anything like that, but they say,
I have this idea for x, let's just, let's,
we can think something up
like a vintage toy cars,
let's just say I'm sure it's been
done, but, and they say, you know,
I would like to figure out, I would
like to build a business based on this.
What,
uh,
what advice would you give them in terms
of kind of testing or de-risking or
testing the waters in any way?
Um,
or you can answer that in any
way really that you'd like,
but if you had that
conversation with someone,
and I'm sure you have had
probably ad Nauseum, these
types of conversations, but,
uh, assuming they're pretty smart,
they're willing to do the work,
they're detail oriented,
like what would you say to them?
I would say it's, it's really great
to test your product. Um, I'm,
my mom is like,
I'm going to talk about something before
I even launched it and make a big stink
about it. The thing that I'm not, you
know, who knows if it's gonna work out.
And that's just, just me being kind
of like short attention span, um,
instant gratification. But I really
think there's a lot of value and,
and being patient and testing things
with like a small group before you go out
there and tell the world today, you
know, here I am fully formed, you know,
buy into my style, you know,
buy into what I'm doing. Um,
I think there's just a lot of
resources for, I mean it's,
as far as selling online
goes, it's, I mean,
it's like having a lemonade
stand at this point.
So it's incredibly easy thing to do.
Your product should be
really differentiated and the
way you talk about it, um,
should be unique and really thoughtful
and regardless of whether you're selling,
you know, use diapers or
use toy cars, um, sorry,
um, you, you should, you
should, you should really,
really invest in presenting yourself well,
and there's websites like
Squarespace obviously, that,
that make that so easy now, um,
so much easier than it used to be.
Finding a graphic designer that can make
something look like what you can plug
into now for almost no money is,
is incredible.
Yeah. No, the, the infrastructure, I mean
the, the rentable infrastructure per se,
whether it's a Squarespace or a
wordpress or someone else. Uh,
I mean you can,
you can have a site up and running within
an hour or two and then you could use,
you'd, I've mentioned them
in the four hour work week,
but even the marketplaces that exist
now for things like designers, writers,
illustrators, like in 99 designs or
Fiverr or something like that. I mean,
I'm having no illustrations
done for a book right now. Um,
with the non Spec version of 99 designs,
these kind of one on one projects and
the quality is obscene. Lee High, I mean,
I've been very, very impressed.
So it is a lot easier. Uh,
in particularly with
things like Kickstarter,
I think you have also the ability to
see how strong your pitches right before
you buy inventory or manufacturer things.
Yeah,
yeah. No one cares. You
don't have a customer.
It's like you got to see if anyone cares.
Burst. Yeah, exactly. And if they're
willing to part ways with their dollars.
What were some books or resources that
helped you in the first few years or
overall build in building nasty gal
early? Um, I would say,
I would say in the dummies guides
or not. I mean, they're fine.
They're really fine. When I went to raise
venture capital, there's one called,
I think it's something like how to be
smarter than your venture capitalists,
like literary something like that.
And I I that and I was like, you know,
I've raised $70 million. So I
guess I figured that out. Um,
and there was a book called no man's
land that I thought was really good.
It was about just that period of time
or you're too small to be big and you're
too big to be small. And most
people, higher middle management,
but middle management
have never seen the top.
So then you hire more senior management.
And I've done that.
And even that's challenging. So,
I mean there's no silver bullet,
but reading other people,
reading about other people's experiences
of growing and struggling with scaling
a business always makes you feel better.
Is the book that you were thinking of
venture deals be smarter than your lawyer
and venture capitalists?
No.
It's,
maybe it's called like how to outsmart
your venture capitalist or something.
How to train your venture
capitalist. Yeah. Basically. Um,
how to be smarter than
your venture capitalists.
That's what it's called. At least that's
what's coming up in the search results.
Let me see how to be smarter than
your venture capitalist. No. Oh,
venture deals be smarter than your lawyer,
I guess. That's it. Yeah. Okay. All right,
cool.
Yeah.
Venture deals for people interested
in this world is a, is a great book.
That's Brad Feld and his partner.
Um, very, very good investors.
Uh,
what,
what were some of the biggest challenges
for scaling an ecommerce business?
What were some of the harder things that
you guys, that you had to contend with?
Let's just, let's just keep it focused
on, on you. But the company of course,
as it's growing,
um,
and I've spoken with people like Phil
Libin of Evernote on the podcast and he's
like, well, like this, you
know, Gent who runs Rakuten.
He's saying you should always plan on
like what if it's three times bigger?
What if it's 10 times bigger?
They're sort of these phase shifts where,
where systems have to be
completely redone. But for,
for you in growing the company,
what were some of the,
what were some of the
hardest periods for you?
Yeah, I would say I would,
scaling is really hard.
So I would say infrastructure,
so systems and we still don't have the
systems that we would like to have to be
able to plan our business and evaluate
our business and talk about it.
What would be some
examples of what systems?
I mean it's really kind of like
unglamorous stuff, like an Erp system,
like enterprise resource planning, which
basically connects the dots between, uh,
you know, different departments like
finance and, um, you know, merchandise,
whatever. Austin. Right now,
everything that we do is living in kind
of disparate systems that don't talk as
much as they could. Right. Um, so
that's, that's a struggle today. Um,
what else? I mean, I would say
people, I would say like, you know,
being,
having never really been a manager prior
to starting the business that has asked
to gal. Um, you know, my dream
scenario at one point was, you know,
it was not getting out of a bathroom and
eating Boston market, like, you know,
with my hands and then, you know, and
then, and then encountering, you know,
hundreds of, uh, you know, a team of
hundreds who are looking up at you.
That's like a really scary
thing. And they all assume, yeah,
I thought you meant your dream was walking
into the office of hundreds of people
in your bathroom. And it's like, that's
very wolf of Wall Street. Like, oh wow.
I kind of liked that visual,
like eating lobster tails while
you walk through the office.
I would totally, I would
do that, but I have, um,
should I start over
because I didn't make it?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. It
does make sense. I be how,
what did you view your, now
you are, you are no longer CEO.
Is that correct? No. Yes.
Correct. When you were Ceo,
what did you view as your job?
Like
as entrepreneurs to you?
It's really tough because there's so
many things that I've been a part of and
done over the course of the company's
history. And I'm also kind of the brand,
the brand cop. Um, and
the brand is my voice. Um,
and the vision has kind of grown
out of the, the beginnings,
the DNA of what was
nasty gal origin story.
So there's never been a point where
I could just be like the cut and dry.
I'm the CEO kind of person, you know,
I'm the cultural leader and the,
all of these things, it was so things,
um, so you know, when, when you're,
when you're growing a business,
it's really hard to say, no,
I'm not going to plug that hole.
I'm not going to edit the photos.
I'm not going to, you know, companies
spring leaks and when you have, when,
when you've done so many different things,
it's,
it's easy to sprout arms and
fingers and just start like,
you know,
over extending yourself by filling in
the gaps as they present themselves,
um, over the course of, you
know, so it was, it was not,
I don't think I got to choose my,
what I did as much as I
perhaps would have liked to.
And I'm even today,
I'm not,
I'm not sure if I have that privilege
because you kind of have to do what the
company needs you to do for it to
continue operating or to be its very best.
And nine years of that is
a really long time. Um,
and I th I think my greatest
strengths are with the brand and with,
with marketing the brand and
with the creative and um,
the things that in the
beginning built built nasty gal.
And that's what I'm hoping
I can focus on today.
How do you,
how do you keep,
try to keep the team on the same page
so that that sort of brand aesthetic and
spirit doesn't get fragmented and turn
it into some Frankenstein monster where
you've become brands that you loathe
or whatever you get there. How do you,
how do you try to do that?
You're going to really quickly become a
caricature of yourself. I'm like, yeah.
Um, uh, yeah,
like a spoof of like
what you've done best.
And I think it's a, it's a matter
of talent but it's also coaching.
But at the end of the day I think you
really need to have tools that everyone
can rally around and say, Hey, this is
what it is. This is what the brand is,
this is what we're all signing up to do.
Not this is my idea versus
your idea versus your idea.
Cause I think culture
like in a, um, in a, in a,
in a business that people really excited
or excited to work at culture can be
used as a weapon. I think the brand
can be used as a weapon. I think there,
you know,
there have been times where people who
are really cool and actually do get yet
what the brand is,
find themselves really frustrated because
not everybody gets it the way did they
do. And they start to say, well, Sophia,
Sophia said this or Sophia wouldn't like
that. And it's like, I don't want to be,
don't sling me around.
Like that's not cool. Um,
and so we've been
spending the last several,
several months actually working
on some what of a brand bible,
but also just filters for how we make
decisions about what the voices and how
we, how we take pictures and
you know, the, the world that,
that is a nasty gal world and what the,
you know,
what the guard rails are that
people can explore within.
We always want to leave room for people
to be creative, but it takes out a,
it takes out the, uh, the objectivity,
uh, or wait, yeah, the, all
the subjectivity. I'm like,
God, my brain's not working.
Basically it makes it not personal.
So it makes it makes it more
objective or depersonalized.
Yeah. So it's easy for it to be like, oh,
well that's not on brand because
I said so. It's like, Oh hey,
we're all trying to do the same thing.
Let's look at this thing that's just sits
outside of us and our tastes, our ego,
whatever. Let's talk about what it
is rather than what we think it is.
So you have to have those things defined
for people to have conversations about.
And that's something I'm
really excited to have.
There's a, there's a
really cool handbook. Um,
I think it's just called the handbook
for new employees for a company called
valve, which is a software company. Uh,
it's one of the coolest sort of employee
orientation handbooks that I've ever
seen.
I had a chance to meet because it was
Gabe Newell at one point in Seattle and I
was somebody else then recommended. I
see this handbook. It's really cool.
You should check it out.
I think he might enjoy it and people
listening might get something out of it.
You can find the free pdf if you just
search valve employee handbook is pretty
sweet.
I think I've seen that. It's
really beautiful. It's this
teeny little cool thing.
Yeah. Yeah. It's really well done.
Great illustrations. But, uh,
lays out the basic ground rules,
right.
For working within this
somewhat unusual culture, uh,
that you mentioned the,
before I derailed us with the wolf of
Wall Street analogy and you walking around
in a bathroom eating lobster tails,
which actually I have two
quick, uh, quick anecdote.
So when I was in college,
one of my buddies and I was in,
I was in New Jersey and one of my buddies
ends up calling us from Atlantic city
and he's like,
there are limos coming to get you.
You have to come to Atlantic city.
We show up and he's just been on a bender
and made like $200,000 blackjack and
proceeds to spend it all
in the next 48 hours.
And he was walking around the casino in
a bathrobe eating any ordered lobster
tails for everyone on the, on
the like blackjacks floor. Wow.
It sounds kind of imagining like
you could, you could be that person,
but with like a Martini glass,
I love absurd,
just doing absurd things like that can.
Uh,
so I was going to ask you about,
I was going to ask you about managing
and I will, but absurd things.
What are some absurd
things that you've done?
Oh my gosh,
I'm getting on a bus to call it that.
I'm calling a girlboss Hashtag girlboss
and well it's like later at the
end of this month and we're,
it's just the paperback.
It's the girl boss paperback and it
has a new introduction and it as the
introduction to the introduction,
I guess just talking about what's
happened over the last year a little bit.
And we're going to like 10 different
cities on this crazy tour bus.
It's like I'm a spice girl
or something and you know,
throwing events at different venues
and some bookstores and it's just like,
it's really absurd to be riding around
like Hillary Clinton and I'm like a
campaign bus basically.
But Penguin,
penguin wanted to do it and I thought
it was just like too good to pass up.
And it's, it's really funny to have your
face and the cover of your book. Like,
he likes, you know, slathered across
the side of like a giant were us.
Yeah. But I would imagine. What about um,
managing, let's talk about
that. So the managing of people,
you had no experience prior to nasty gal.
Now it's grown of course tremendously.
Um,
what were,
who were the mentors or what were the
things that helped you learn to manage to
the extent that you were able,
oh my God, I think I'm
still learning. Um, wait,
say that again.
Yeah, that was, but that was
a word salad question. Okay.
Who are the mentors or the,
the resources that helped you
learn to manage other people?
Because I think that's a
weakness of mine quite frankly.
I'm good at defining systems,
but I'm not always a,
for instance, I mean I was
raised by, are not raised by us.
That's weird.
I was coached by a lot of athletic
coaches who were always kind of very short
with praise. They would, they would
not, they didn't do a lot of head pats,
but heavy on criticism
and very meticulous.
And so I am often very bad at providing
praise when I probably should because I
don't feel like I was ever given it.
Therefore it's not really necessary.
Uh, I think I'm the same, but that
causes all sorts of problems. Right?
We don't feel appreciated. And it's like,
oh my God, I totally appreciate you.
But like I respect your intelligence
enough not to like be like,
I don't know.
Yeah, it's tough. I mean, because I've
always been told by the good stuff,
the good stuff.
I remember I had a VP of sales at one
point when my first job out of college and
he said, you know, I,
I would give him all the story and the
backs or tell him all this stuff about a
reclined. He's like, Tim, I don't need
the story. I just need to know next steps.
And second, I don't need to know the good
news cause that takes care of itself.
I need to know the bad news.
And I was like, oh, okay.
And so I've kind of adopted that.
But you end up in a position where
people can get very demoralized in,
in a culture where people
aren't getting uh, the,
or don't have the ability to
celebrate little wins and so on. Who,
who has helped you to become a better
CEO when you were a CEO or a better
manager?
I've had some executive
coaches along the way.
I think knowing the difference and then
actually living the difference are two
different things. And I think I'm
pretty aware of the things that I'm,
what my shortcomings are as a manager,
as a leader, as a fill in the blank.
Um, I'm not, you know,
I think I experienced the
same thing when you are,
especially if you're entrepreneurial,
which I think we like,
we can both like safely say we are.
No one's giving you,
no one's giving you
those pats on the back.
And when you find yourself in a position
to be doling those out, you don't,
you don't really relate because that's
not something that you ever required.
I'm an only child. I had a really
mean dad. I mean, he's often now,
but like it was criticism after criticism
and it makes you self aware enough to,
uh, to calibrate on your
own. And a lot of ways,
even though I'm totally open to, I
love, you know, criticism and I love,
but I think when you,
when you're like a solo act at any
point in your life and have to manifest
things without, without the team, without
the amazing team that we have today,
you become really good at being your own
critic and your own and also your own
pat on the back or you're motivated
maybe by different things.
And that's a hard thing to relate
to as an entrepreneur who's leading,
who's leading people. And I think that's
definitely been one of my shortcomings.
Um, but I've, I've,
I'm always like seeking advice and
I'm always seeking to better myself.
I think leadership management chops,
whatever you want to call it,
is something that comes over time.
A lot of things are just learned
over time with repetition.
And that's something that I
have, you know, I've been,
that's one part of the job that I've had
is managing people or leading people,
but there's been a million other things
that I've done, uh, over the course of,
you know, nasty Gal's trajectory
and having someone like Sherry,
our CEO who has a lifetime of those
chops behind her who wakes up every day
inspired,
not just inspired to lead people but
knows how to do it in a way that will work
is such a real,
it's such a cool thing to witness.
When you were in the CEO role,
who were the other CEO's out there alive
or dead that you admired and really
looked to as role models?
Hmm, good question. Um, I mean,
I've always admired Natalie Massenet
who founded net-a-porter. Um,
and she hasn't been the CEO
for a long time, but she's,
she's just like an incredible
woman. Um, why she incredible.
Um, she's, she's a mother of I to, uh,
she started a company a long,
you know,
like she started an ecommerce business
long before most of us had the idea to,
um, she's been told, you know, I mean,
I think people like Kinda scoffed
when she, you know, she said,
I'm going to sell a $30,000 handbag
on the internet or sell shoes on the
internet or these things that
have become really common place.
And she's also just a super duper down
down to Earth woman who's funny and sweet
and gives great advice and who's
seen a lot. And um, there's not,
there's not a ton of examples that
I think are, are similar to hers.
Mickey Drexler's also
an incredible like CEO
Mickey Drexler. Yeah. Do you know
who Mickey Drexler is? I don't,
I'm embarrassed to say, but
I shan't tell the lie. Okay.
He's the,
he's the CEO of j crew right now and he
used to be the CEO at gap and he's kind
of like a retail legend. Um, he's,
I think he's called like the merchant
prints or merchant king or something like
that. Cool. Cool. Nickname. I
know, right. I know he's just,
he's someone who's given
me advice along the way,
just really great advice and connected me
to people that I've ended up, you know,
great people be, get great
people. And you know,
it's just when you meet someone
awesome, you've eats off. It's, it's,
it's common that I find the people
that they surround themselves with,
the people that I also like. And that's,
it's just such a cool thing. It's like a,
I dunno. It's like you don't have
to, it's like, it's like going to,
nevermind.
No, no, no. I want you to
finish that thought. That was
good. That was interesting.
I was going to start babbling like
about Yelp reviews and it's like,
it's like a Yelp review for a person.
It seems like it wasn't that,
it was not an intelligent thought.
Yeah.
So I brought up, you know, I
should learn to do that more often.
I would embarrass myself a
lot less. Uh, what were, what,
what was some of the advice that,
uh, Mickey has given you that to,
that has stuck with you? It doesn't
have to be specifically business.
Could be anything.
I mean, his advice was to stay
CEO, which is really funny.
It's definitely stuck with me,
but I ignored it.
Um,
let me think.
Oh, I get, I can give you an escape
hatch for this. My memory blows.
We can, we can I get an a, I
can give you a whole slew of,
of pills and potions for that. Uh, but,
uh, we, we will do that separately. The,
have you met David Cho?
No. You haven't? Okay.
Somebody asked online what you,
what you learned from him? Yeah,
yeah, yeah. The, uh, the,
the graffiti artists
slash artist who ended up,
I guess worth 500 million after Facebook,
I believe I'm saying his last name.
Oh, cool. What did I learn from
him? No, I didn't. I, that's cool.
But you haven't met him.
What I learned about him was
everything that you just told me.
Okay. Okay. Got It. I've been hoping
to, I find his story fascinating,
so I'm hoping to connect
with him at some point.
Yeah.
He's just made some really fascinating
creative decisions that da I'd love to
love to dig into. But, uh, anyway,
that's a whole separate story.
Uh, the, uh, what,
what do you struggle with the
most and how do you deal with it?
I struggle with doing it all most.
I struggle with feeling like I don't
have time for everyone who I want to have
time for and who I,
I assume once my time,
um,
for,
for my friends and for my husband and
for my parents and for my team. Um,
it's just time is a really finite thing
and prioritizing it so that you can,
you know, so you can be your
best so that you can, you know,
have real solid time with people so you
can also find time to be alone or to
take a vacation. It's just,
there's not enough time. Um, so I,
I'm always feeling like I'm
letting someone down or I'm just,
you know,
it's like,
it's like my calendar is booked up for
the next month and a half now and it's
just, I, I, it's, it's
not always like that,
but to look out at the rest of the year,
it's kind of like,
it's over like the years, you know,
years over. That's, that's something,
I dunno if I, you know, I kind of hoped
that my life isn't always like that,
but there's gotta be great things if
you're planning that far out. I guess,
you know, I feel very lucky for that.
Any answer to your question really is,
is you're feeling like I
don't have all the time.
I wish I had to spend with all the people
that I wish I could spend it with and
how do I deal with that?
Yeah. How do you deal with it?
And let me ask, uh, just uh,
in combination with that,
and this is maybe a very silly question,
you obviously are very driven and that
is sometimes leads people to find it
difficult to hit the
pause button or downshift.
But you've stepped out of the CEO role
I would think as an outsider looking in,
uh, of course you're still
going to be very involved as,
as a chairman is chairman.
But why can't you create more time?
Why can't you block out time?
Cause the company still needs me for
my things and I still partner with my,
my CEO and still spend a lot
of time with her. You know,
I'm drumming up opportunities
for the business,
whether it's a collaboration or
um, you know, weighing in on,
on something creative. You know, I still
spend time there. Uh, you know, I've,
I've signed up for more things that then
I probably should have, but you know, I,
I, I, everyone should be.
So I don't know. I feel,
I feel like saying no is just,
it doesn't create opportunity.
So I'm throwing all that I can into
the air and just to see how much I can
actually handle. I think, I don't
know. I'm a glutton for punishment. Um,
so, you know, it's like I'm
launching a podcast next month.
I'm like promoting this paper
paperback. I'm Finna, you know,
I'm working on another book.
I'm like, who knows. I mean,
I want girl boss to become its own
thing. Girl boss should be, is,
is so much more than a book. It
should be a business. It should be,
it should be conferences.
It should be.
It shouldn't be so many things
beyond what it, what it is.
It's just a matter of of
doing it. Um, as of making,
making the time and finding
the team and Oh my God,
what am I going to start another business.
I'm not sure, you know, but just doing,
doing all I can with all that I have
and connecting things that shouldn't
connect is what really, really gets me
excited because that's where you would,
that's where invention happens and that's,
that's where I get,
that's where I just get like really,
really excited about things. So
what, what were some of the
key inflection points for,
uh,
for the company?
So if you look back over the
last 10 years or whatever it is,
um,
what were some of the key inflection
points that allowed nasty gal to become
what it is right there? Cause
I can think back, for instance,
with the four hour work week,
I can think very specifically to like the
day that Robert Scoble at the time put
something on his blog was
a clear inflection point
that was a clear inflection
point. The appearance on Doctor
Oz clear inflection point.
So a meeting certain people
getting advice from say, uh,
Michael Gerber who wrote
the e myth revisited.
And before I even wrote the
four hour work week, he said,
if you're gonna write a book,
write a fucking book.
Like don't half ass it because a mediocre
book is more of a liability than a
help and blah, blah, blah. Right. So,
so I can point to very clear
introductions, meetings.
What are some of those
four for you and nasty gal?
Yeah,
I would say it was launching,
I mean the first one would be
just launching the Ebay store.
The next one would be selling a Chanel
jacket that I bought for $8 for a over a
thousand.
Um,
so the next one would
probably be launching,
launching the website and having
it sell out just overnight.
And then pretty soon after that,
hiring my first employee, um,
after that it would be buying
things that weren't vintage.
So buying a small,
medium and large of something from a
trade show and bringing in new brands and
testing and seeing if our customer had
an appetite for more than just vintage,
um, which they did. And then it was like,
I think just didn't just, you know,
scale scaling isn't, that's not a,
that's an inflection point.
But what happened? We outgrew
our space and Venetia,
I mean,
we've moved so many times,
but I would say after that it was
raising $50 million from index ventures.
Um,
for me personally,
it was four pages in Forbes in 2012.
How did the four pages in Forbes happen?
Because there's often some
backstory, right? Not,
not all of them are just gifts from
heaven that get dropped in your lap.
And maybe this was, but how did that
come together? I mean, that's a,
that's a significant weight.
How did one drop in my lap? No,
how did it come together? I'm not saying
it did jump in your lap. Forbes. Yeah.
Um, oh my God. The way, the way
media works as well. It was, it was,
it was someone who I'd met through index,
her name was Julie Soopat.
And she was friends with
someone who wrote it,
Forbes and they were getting brunch. And
she mentioned me and this, the reporter,
um,
got interested.
And then I had no idea what I was
and never talked to the media before.
And then Julie, Julie used to run,
um, like PR at Youtube and she's,
she consults for,
for startups and she's kind of like a
master of all things, uh, publicity.
And she was like,
well,
now that you have someone writing
a profile on you in Forbes,
you,
you probably need my help.
So I don't know if she did
a great job and you know,
so I hired her and she helped me,
helped me, just coach me through it.
She was like, they're going to want
you to look like a billionaire. That's,
that's there.
You know,
we've had to reshoot other stuff that
I worked on with Forbes because they
didn't think that the entrepreneur and
his hood, he looked like a billionaire.
So it's so funny.
It's really funny just how all that works.
And so now I show up at photo shoots
and I'm like, what do you want me to be?
Okay, I'm bringing it, you know,
it's like so Dorky, but you know,
it's like whatever. He just tried to
do your best, you do your best. Um,
what was that, what was
that like? That was cool.
That was was, what were some other
pieces of advice that you got a,
or things you've learned
about interacting with media?
Um, God, I've learned so much.
I feel like I could do it.
Give one, always do fact check
corrections via email and not fun.
Yeah,
you need a paper trail of that stuff.
I've been missing misquoted so
many times. Really? Ah, yeah.
And then that will sneak its way
into Wikipedia and then it's a big,
big quagmire to fix.
Hey,
I mean,
I think it's just that like the media
always wants something to talk about and
um, they can, they can skew
things or their own, you know,
for their own fun. And it's, you know,
there was a time where I think I believed
a lot of what I read out there and I
still believe a lot of it,
but when there's controversy
it's often just to serve.
Um, you know, it's clicks and you
know, get, yeah. I don't know.
It's like I don't know what
I'm just kind of babbling,
but be careful with what you say.
Um,
and if you don't have anything to
say then just don't say anything.
I think it's okay to say no.
Yeah,
definitely. And also, I mean
one thing that I've learned,
cause see if you take
something out of context,
like one sentence out of a paragraph,
it can make you look like, you know,
a hero or a complete ass or a misogynist
or an asshole or any number of things
so that the context is so important.
You know,
what I've been doing for
the last couple of years,
if I send a response
via email to journalist,
I'll just say thank you for
using this in its entirety.
I do not give permission to slice and
dice this if it's going to be cut down.
I need to give you permission. And A,
not everybody responds well to that,
but usually the ones who
respond poorly to that,
if it's diplomatically worded or the
people who already had an agenda to slant
something and it really controvert
unnecessarily sort of, uh,
Cindy Arie waves
and even like the most,
you know, the best.
Some of the best
journalists I worked with,
they'll write a really positive
story and then their throat,
they'll throw in some shit just for
their own credibility to make sure they
don't sound like some big fan.
Yeah.
So there's always going to be some shit
that they like say that you're going to
be like grumpy about,
but it makes them credible and you just
kinda have to like stomach it. Yeah.
And you can actually, I mean,
you can help them. Also,
you can facilitate things by saying like,
here are two or three of my detractors,
but that'll, that can also give you, um,
as long as they're safe, factual
attackers. Does that make sense?
Yeah. One you walk like an ogre and heels
and it's like, no. Like, I'm like, go, go,
go dance in public in fucking heels.
I'm pretty sure I can. It was just like,
no, like, it's fine. But like of all
the things like I can walk in heels,
you know, like, um, just
like pick something, just,
there's plenty of things to criticize
Jesus. If you, if you catch me in like a,
you know, it's in the corner. I'm
probably picking my nose. Like, you know,
it's just like find something real fun.
Hey,
uh, when, when are you,
when are you happiest?
Oh, God. Um,
I'm happiest when I'm like running
down a trail in big Sur downhill,
a little, just a little
downhill, like any,
any jump and you feel like you fly,
like 20 feet is almost like a dream. Um,
I think that's the best feeling is being
like, I'm in a video game, but it's real.
Like this is real life.
And I'm like, yeah,
I think just like running down a trail
in the forest is like maybe the best
feeling ever.
That's such a good answer.
That's a cool, uh, do you,
side note,
if you come back to San Francisco and
I'm sure that'll happen at some point,
there's a place called house of air,
which is basically a humongous building
full of trampolines at different angles
and you can feel like you're in
the matrix. It's amazing. Uh,
do you struggle with depression
or anything like that
and you don't have to not
oh,
totally.
I just struggle with
depression my whole life.
I've been in an hour
therapy my whole life.
They tried to tell me I had add and give
me some stuff in high school and they
tried to give me the stuff for depression.
It's make me, made me feel super wired.
Um,
I,
I think when I got busy that went away.
Um,
more than anything.
I think I started with anxiety so I,
I can hit the ceiling by like 11:00 AM.
Um,
if something just doesn't go right, I
mean, I don't like yell or pound my fists.
I'm not like a person in the office
who throws things. But if I'm like,
if I'm not happy, ain't nobody
happy. Like in the room, basically.
It's just kind of like, it's not, so I
don't, I'm not good at hiding my feelings.
It's,
it's unfortunate.
And then there's people who value it
and I try to keep those people around.
Um, but um, yeah. Had Depression.
Depression's like a gnarly,
gnarly thing.
How do you, how do you
contend with that? Uh,
and I ask as someone who has similar ups
and downs and has for as long as I can
remember, but what, what are you,
what are your coping mechanisms?
Um, if it's, you know, I,
it's easy to point at things in your
life that are out of your own control.
Like I've pointed at who I got married
like three months ago, but I have,
there's been times where I pointed at
Joel and I was like, you're the problem.
It's like, no, you're just not,
you're not solving your own problems.
Like I think you can just look everywhere
outside of yourself to fix your
problems. And thank God
I'm not like, I don't know.
It's like addiction issues or anything.
Cause I'm totally, if that was,
if that was it that ran in my family,
I'd be a total mass. I think. Um,
um, I, I know that I've been, I'd taken
antidepressants at different times, um,
and some are better than
others. Um, but I just,
I generally like to stay pretty kind of,
I know alcohol,
alcohol can help. Yeah. Yeah.
Wow.
That's so,
yeah.
I'm not sorry,
alcohol reality. I'm
telling you I'm playing,
I'm playing not to lose
more now though, but, um,
I mean I can have one glass of wine
and I'm like the happiest, most like,
uh, like charismatic, like, you know,
just fun person when and if uses.
Yeah.
And when I'm not drinking, I'm like, you
don't want to walk up and talk to me.
Like I'm not friendly. Like I'm not
unfriendly, I'm just not open, you know,
I'm just Kinda like stuck in
my head, you know. I Dunno.
What, what's your go to
wine drink or your go to?
Yeah. Um, I, I like white
wine. A lot of bars don't have
white wine, but it would just
be like, uh, I don't know.
I started drinking chardonnays. I like
those. Oh, I got to go. Verts demeanor,
which is really good.
Right?
It's really good. Yeah. Good
one is the cliff family,
the cliff bar people.
I went to this thing in Napa and my God,
it's so,
I sound like so cool now, but
I took a, I I like went on a,
on a bike ride was basically my,
my investors have a retreat every year
and all of the entrepreneurs and they're
in the, in the, the, um,
the partners at their firm get together
and this is at the cow at cal state
grants, which is like a really beautiful
place in Napa. Gorgeous. Super.
Should be pretty schmancy. And then
they have these activities, you know,
so you don't hear people talk
and there's really cool people.
Like Jerry Yang spoke at
the last one and um, just,
it's really interesting. And then they
have this, you know, this, these, um,
activities. And one of
them was, um, you know,
road biking and road biking up to a
winery and then having a glass of wine.
I was like, yeah, I'm getting
in shape for my wedding.
Like I'm going to drink wine. I should
get on a bike first. And Oh my God,
these all these guys, they're all European
for one and they're like, you know,
they're like wealthy guys who like have
their own shoes and like all the clothes
and like
do this. They like to do
it as a thing. You know,
they're like those guys who've had the
cycling so that they're like $5,000 I
just thought it was,
I thought it was like,
I was just like going on a bike ride
for fun and I was just, Oh my God.
It was the only person
that didn't finish it.
I did get in the car and like get a
ride to the top of the hill anyway,
and the top of the, at the top of
the hill was cliff family winery.
I don't know why I'm like, I'm like, I
don't know them. I'm not, I'm trying,
I'm not trying to plug anything.
It was just like a,
I'd never heard of governor [inaudible]
and I bought a few bottles into and had
it shipped to my house. And um, yeah,
I guess, I guess a white crispy wine.
Yeah, super. That's super
tasty stuff. Uh, sons,
Sarah's pretty good go to
for a lot of folks. The uh,
I guess I usually do it a
gin tonics of Hendrickson,
Hendrickson soda is kind of my go
to if I don't want to have a nasty,
nasty headache or Tequila as you've seen
really,
you have to, you have to go with the
good stuff if you're going to do Tequila.
So the costs of that are going to,
is very expensive but very tasty with
that no head. I mean, you saw me,
I had a fair amount to drink,
but a no headache the next day.
No cognitive disfunction
felt just fine. Uh, the,
uh,
when you think of the word successful,
and I know that's a gnarly dicey word,
but who's the first person
who comes to mind for you?
Yeah,
successful.
The word success is really conflicted
for me because it sells people this idea
that there's like a destination.
I think there's people who can,
man may have manifested things in the
world that make more noise than other
people, but success can just be as being
a stay at home mom if that's your dream.
Success can be,
um,
having a small business and keeping
it that way and keeping in laying low
because that's what you want and
that's the life that you want. Um,
I really want, you know, and as someone
who's public, it's kind of like a,
it's a, it's a, it's a hairy thing
because I'm out there and I'm, I'm,
I have a book and you know, I have a
business and I sell things and whatever,
but it's,
I just really want people to remember
that they're capable of doing everything
that the people they admire or doing.
Maybe not everything,
but if your own don't be so impressed.
I guess that's where, you know where,
where my head goes is,
you know,
there's no reason that you can't have
the things that the people that you
admire,
that you admire have.
And so it like access just sells this
kind of like ultimate destination when
even though I've accomplished something
and you've accomplished something and
whatever, it's like you, I,
I told you I was crying last night and
it's not like we who like my, you know,
I'm done. I've, I've arrived
or anything like that.
If you have any amount of hustle and
any amount of humility, you know,
that it all can go away tomorrow and that
you should do everything you can with
what you have today.
Um,
so I guess it's a very philosophical way
of saying, when I hear the word success,
I don't know what Warren Buffett, I
don't, you know, it's like, I dunno.
Yeah,
it's tough on you.
You said don't ask the cobbler if
you're a brick layer or whatever. Yeah.
I was thinking of Warren Buffett when
you said that because he often says,
don't ask a barber if you need a
haircut. He's full of those. Totally.
Uh,
the,
let me ask you just a couple
of a rapid fire questions.
You don't have to have
rapid fire answers, but, uh,
just because I know that people will
ask me why I didn't ask them if I leave
them out. What is your
favorite documentary or movie?
My favorite movie might be
I phone called the color,
the color of pomegranates and that's by,
um,
this guy served Sergei Haragei snob.
I'm not even sure if I pronounce it
correctly. He was like a Georgian, um,
filmmaker and it's basically a moving
painting. It's just one of the most,
there's almost no dialogue.
It's just one of the most beautiful
songs I've ever seen. And um, I've been,
you know, I grew up Greek Orthodox and
I'm just still kind of enchanted with the,
with Eastern,
um,
the visuals of like Eastern Europe.
Um,
yeah.
Sounds, sounds gorgeous. Yeah.
I need to sort of fill up my roster
so I'll add that to the list. Uh,
what are you world class at that people
might not realize or what do your
friends know you're world class at that
the rest of world doesn't know about it.
Um, wait. Um, what, what
did I put on my thingy?
I Dunno, I didn't read it. So for
those people listening, I, um, I send,
I could look it up.
I,
I send some of these questions in
advance just so people don't get totally
stumped. Um, which happens, uh,
but I didn't look at the answers because
I want it to be fresh for conversation.
Uh, I could pick it up. I can
look it up. Uh, bear with me
a second. I'll pick it up.
Oh my God. I can use my brain. Hold on.
That's okay. That's okay.
It's a, so let's see.
We got a plane catch.
Oh my God. Yeah. Um, yeah,
I guess playing catch.
Yeah, no, I, I'm like, I,
I can have really good coordination
to the point of it like being freaky.
Like if I dropped something,
I can be like looking the other direction,
like scratching my arm pit
with one hand and then like,
like swooping and like cat,
like reflexes like that happens sometimes,
but it always even surprises me.
And also I'm good at playing catch.
Did you play athletics or
sports growing up or no?
Um, yeah I played soccer.
I mean I played basketball,
I played softball when I was like in third
grade and then I played soccer a lot.
Um, I snowboarded a lot.
It never hacky sack.
San Francisco awaits. Okay. We can have a,
if we can do some like Hula hooping
devils, teach me how to break down.
I could teach you, I can give some basics.
We can do six stepping next time you,
you've come along. Uh, what are the
most common misconceptions about you?
Um, oh, I think people,
well I met some people
yesterday who thought they were
like, I was like, what is,
what it's fun surprises. He mass.
We spent some time and they,
I showed them the office and talk to
them about my business and it was like,
well, you know, what do you,
what surprised you? And they
said, well, you're, you're,
you're not as egotistical as I
thought. You'd be like, wow. I mean,
that's not insulting you from any outside.
You know,
you put yourself on the cover of a book
with your hands on your hips and you
know, whatever. And, and maybe you
expect something different. But that was,
that was,
that was pleasant.
Yeah. It's better than the
other way round. Like, wow,
you're so much were mega maniacal. And
I couldn't, God get me away from you.
Uh, if you could have a billboard anywhere
with anything on it, what would it,
where would you,
I could have a billboard. I put
nothing on it and I put it everywhere.
Just an empty, you know,
I'm going to cheat here.
I'm going to go back and see if there's
anything else that you'd stop telling
women to smile.
Yeah. That's just like such a grumpy
billboard. The right teams. My mind,
I'd rather have nothing. You project
what you want them to their billboard.
But that's, that's, and
since I've given you this,
this imaginary billboard,
you're entitled to do that,
but I want to hear the backstory on
stop telling women to smile. What's the,
what's the, what's the
store? Baxter? Well,
it's something that I've said. I
mean, I've said just like, stop,
don't tell me to smile or like, I mean,
if you're a girl who's not, like who,
who a guy wants to talk to and you
intimidate them because you aren't like
giggling or whatever, they'll like take
a, it's like you're, you're there for,
you're there for your pleasure
or I don't know what it is,
but it's happened to me from as
early as I can remember. Just like,
you should smile more. Just like,
Oh, you look really pretty new smile.
And it's like, that's nice. Thanks. Um,
but there's something that's like,
you're,
you're here for me, so can you just smile
if I have to like look at you. You know,
cause you're making like a woman,
a woman evaluating me just makes me feel
like emasculated or something kind of,
you know, like they just like
don't know how to handle it.
And it's really frustrating
and honestly pretty insulting.
And then I found out that there's
a woman named, what is her name?
I mean she has like this,
she's an artist,
I think she's in Brooklyn and she started
something called stop telling women to
smile and someone's telling me about the
other day and her name is Tatiana Fuzz.
Lee's Foz La [inaudible].
Oh my God.
Foz Law leads a day. Yeah.
It's just real long name.
I'm, I'm embarrassed of
how I did that. But um,
she has like a like wheat paste posters
and like kind of like a campaign,
like stop telling women to smile. Like
I'm not your baby. That kind of shit.
Which is just, I wouldn't put, you know,
if I could put one thing on a billboard,
it would probably be nothing, maybe
nasty gal if it was free, you know?
Yeah. What was your, what was
your thinking process around,
um, stepping down? Stepping
out of the CEO role?
Yeah.
I just,
my the things that I find myself that I
think I'm good at or not the things that
a CEO wakes up everyday to do,
I'm running an executive team of
sea levels who have more experience,
you know, then I've been in, you know,
that I've been in business for or,
um, it's just, it's like
there's a, like I said earlier,
there's just a totally different
skillset that comes with leading,
leading people and um,
and giving praise and repeating what
you're there, what we're all here to do.
There's a lot of repetition actually,
and I'm the kind of person that's like,
what, you didn't hear me the
first time, which is not,
I'm not saying I'm proud of that. Um,
I just think that's kind of how I,
that's just how I roll and I,
you know, I, it, it's a whole,
if there's an art to leadership
and, um, yeah, I wanted,
I wanted to focus on the creative parts
of the business, you know, I want,
you know,
the book kind of had its own it be,
it kind of made me the face of
the company, which I wasn't prior.
And so there's things that come along with
that that, um, are good for nasty Gal,
but take my time and take
me out of your office.
And there's nothing worse
than feeling like your,
you've abandoned the people who are
reporting to you who need your time.
It's just a matter of choosing. Um, so I,
you know, I chosen, it was
something that had been,
that I've been thinking
about for a long time. Um,
what was,
what was the first day like or a night
after you made the decision and it was
okay,
you'd finally kind of made the call and
knew that you are no longer going to be
CEO.
I think it was just a lot of relief,
a lot of relief and just feeling
like I had done the right thing.
I was really happy for Sherry,
my CEO,
and it just seemed kind of
like a non event to our team.
I expected more of a reaction, but
they were like, what's the difference?
Sherry's in all of the all hands meetings
and she speaks and we don't know who
she is.
What's different?
That I don't think it was a huge
change for most of our team,
which felt good. Yes. Yeah. That's great.
Yeah.
I expected a lot more questions and I
was kind of bummed that people weren't,
they weren't like, they weren't like, they
were like freaked out and they're like,
okay, cool. Got It. We've
been waiting for you.
Don't let the door hit you on
the way. I'm just kidding. Uh,
what a $100 or less purchase has most
positively impacted your life in recent
memory?
Um,
I had a hamburger yesterday.
Amber,
what kind of have, what kind
of hamburger and we're, I mean,
was it a particularly early?
Huh?
Interesting hamburger or I no, no, I
mean the one thing, I mean I could, yeah,
let me, I can think harder on this, but I,
yeah, no, it's basically just inexpensive
stuff that you get a lot of value.
I'm looking at my,
I mean a manicure
manicures are like pretty,
they're good. They're like, they make you
feel better, but they cost like, you know,
I get Gel so I don't know, maybe
they're like 20 or 30 bucks. Then. Um,
you're, you don't hit your hands as
much. I don't know what else. Um,
under $100 not a lot is
under a hundred dollars.
It's like a hamburger or you know,
probably,
I mean probably a glass of lion.
Oh God,
that's the theme here.
That's a glass glass wine.
It's good.
I actually bought one of my favorite
bottles of wine I've ever had.
A I bought from trader Joe's.
They have great wine service that people
really know what they're talking about.
It's for $4 for a bottle of white wine.
And if you want to upgrade that,
you get the, um, I, I
really like Rombauer. Sure.
Oh yes.
Ron is good.
Yeah. 2004 I think I had,
which was amazing. Uh, and uh,
not that expensive. That was the first
white wine I ever bought a case of.
I thought I would never buy
a case of white wine ever.
I've always been a red wine guy and
Rombauer Chardonnay was the one that made
the difference. Um, what does,
what does the first 60
minutes of your day look like?
Now I'm going to ask that
a little retrospectively.
When you were CEO of the company,
uh,
on a, on a, on a, on a day where you
look back and you're like, fuck yeah.
Kicked ass today. What did the first
60 to 90 minutes of your day look like?
Or what were your morning routine?
Yeah, I mean I usually, and a day that
ends wells one that started with exercise,
that's for sure. Um, yeah, so cute. Um,
I usually eat, you know,
for breakfast, so I wake up.
What time, what time do you
wake up? I Dunno, like six 37.
Um, most people are like exercising at six
30 or seven, but I'm just, I don't know.
I stay up, I'm like, I keep,
I, I just keep weird hours. Um,
so I wake up,
I take my Invisalign out of my mouth
because I sleep with these braces in
basically.
And before that it was a mouth guard
cause they clench my teeth cause I'm a
freak.
But I recently botox my jaw so that
I can't clench my teeth as much.
Whoa, sweet. You injected fat.
Just something that basically makes your
muscle weaker so that you don't aren't
such a, I'm like, I'm like hulk smash.
Like I've clenched my teeth
like the fucking hawk.
Oh No. I, I sometimes
wake up with blow, my God,
why don't you call this way
looking at your face. That's
what I like really over developed
jaw muscles. Like a pitfall I do.
Let me look at, hold on, let
me look at, I'll just go.
Okay. Right now. No, but it does,
that's what happens. You know,
I have a jaw muscle that no,
you don't have a strong job,
but when you're a girl that is like a
kind of a masculine thing, whatever.
But yeah, I'd also just, you wake
up with a headache. So I did that.
That I think that's helping actually.
Um, yeah. And then I wake up, I probably,
I might pee. Um, I chug
water. I'll try a bunch.
I tried to check a bunch of
water but it don't always,
and then I drink coffee with
heavy cream in it. Um, yeah.
What to, how do you make your coffee?
We have a thing called a Jura,
like j u r a some company and it's
just like basically put the beans in.
It grinds them and it's
just a coffee maker I guess,
but it's like a fancy coffee maker
and it does it give you ra? Yeah. Um,
and, but I put, I put hot water
in the glass. I filled that,
filled the mug up about halfway with
hot water and then I put the shots of
costly. I guess it's
a suppressor. I Dunno.
Are coffee beans and espresso
beans the same thing?
Uh, they are often roasted
slightly differently. Um,
but my understanding is you're just using
kind of more beans for the volume in
the case of espresso.
But the darker the roast is,
my understanding is the lower the
caffeine is interestingly enough. But uh,
but yeah, you're making, you're
basically making an American,
we use David Lynch,
David Lynch, like are you serious?
He not,
he not only has trends,
it'll meditation foundation in
schools for at risk at risk youth.
He also has his own. Wow
Man. I'm really lisping now,
but he also has his own coffee.
Look up David Lynch copy. I
just did. It's pretty good. Um,
that's how my husband
found it. But um, and then
so how can I see, so you have your coffee
with h, why heavy cream? I don't know.
Someone,
I'm a big fan of him.
And now the whole thing is that like
fat's good for you? So I carry the last,
but I already knew that, so. Yep. Um,
and then I'll have, um,
one of maybe three things.
I have rolled oats with,
um,
a little bit of honey and a little bit
of milk and a little bit of salt was
raisins usually, um, just made
on the stove top and that,
or I will have, um, a pancake
that I make out of rolled oats.
So I crack four egg whites into a bowl
and then I put two cups of dry rolled
oats in,
and then I stirred around and the eggs
kind of help the oats congeal and then,
yeah. And then I shape it
into a pancake in a pan.
And then I cook,
I like heat it up a little bit,
and then I put it on a plate and I put
apple sauce on it and a little bit of
maple syrup and I eat it. And
it's really good. Um, I mean,
but it's two ingredients, which
is crazy. Um, and it's, it looks,
it doesn't look as good as it
tastes. It's pretty decent. It's, um,
yeah, I bet that'd be really
good with like some nuts.
Yeah. Or I eat, drink like a
white smoothie, which is like a,
has apple and Greek
yogurt and some cinnamon.
Um, and it's just like a pretty
simple, but so some of that stuff,
some of those recipes came from this
guy that I trained with named Harley
Pasternak.
Have you heard of him?
I have heard that name. Yeah, it isn't.
He trains with UFC fighters probably.
Probably.
He's like a celebrity trainer type and
he has people that work for him and I
mostly,
oh, you know what I'm thinking about? Mike
Dolce is okay. Instead of Harley. Yes,
yes, pastor. But pastor neck
Spock's and stuff, he's awesome. And I've
just gotten some cool recipes from him.
So those are his recipes. Um,
and then I'll, I don't know,
I guess I shower, you know, and then I'll,
I'll go work out, you know, depending,
sometimes I do, sometimes they
don't. And then start my day.
Sometimes I'll roll out of bed and have a
phone call and you know, I've, you know,
it's like we have a call, we're on a
kind of like a call now and it's like,
I haven't showered. I
don't know. I'm at home.
Sometimes I'll have calls for a
while before I go into the office.
Sometimes I won't go into the office
because I'm working on something that I
need to focus on.
And that's hard to do in the office.
And I remember every day is different,
but they all start pretty much the same.
When you work out,
what if you could only choose a couple
of exercises for the rest of your life?
What would they be?
And the reason I'm asking is I saw this
photograph on your Instagram account, um,
which,
uh,
which I thought was hilarious and it was,
it was you on this,
I'd want to say an elliptical.
And it said preparing the center for
her wedding day or something like that.
And because you have a very well,
a very well developed and pollutes,
uh, put it that way. Very,
no, this is purely anatomical speaking
as a, as an exercise physiologist. And
so those don't look like they came from
ellipticals or is that just a god given?
That's,
I like,
I can't cause when I think
now you're Greek, Greek,
Italian and Portuguese.
Oh, all right. That explains it. Okay. So
I, I, I knew only about the Greek part.
I'm like, not usually, like if it was
like, yes, I'm 80% Brazilian, I'd be like,
okay,
that makes
no, and people actually like get surgery
and make their butts. It's like, yeah,
if I wear a dress like the top fits,
but then the Bot,
I can't get the bottom over my hips or,
and then,
or if like at the hips fed and like the
top is too big and I'm not gonna like,
I don't know. I don't, I
don't, I don't want big boobs.
And then like if I wear pants,
it's just weird. It's not,
it's, it's like, it's,
it's weird that like our culture is like
into bots because I think they're kind
of gross, but, okay.
Well,
I mean I think you just have to watch
like discovery channel for 15 minutes and
see like presentation,
posture and all that stuff.
And mammals have that
fixation I think. But, uh,
the, uh, hmm. Not My
intention to go there,
but the exercises,
so if,
if you're exercising before
you get started with the
day and you could only pick
a couple of exercises,
I mean, you basically asked me why. I
have a big butt, like that's what it is.
That there's no, no, no, no, it's fine.
I'm not, it's funny. Um, no it's not.
It's not just you do,
what do you do? Well,
if you had to only choose a couple of
types of exercise, not just for the bud,
not having big, but is that like,
I can go to hell really fast.
So you have to, you kind of
have to exercise. Um, uh,
I do deadlifts for my bat or just in
general. I do dead lifts, dead lifts or,
um,
I do a lot of lunges.
I do some walking lunges and like some,
I dunno,
we just go out sometimes. Um, I'll um,
like resistance training. Um, well, no.
When you do dead lifts, are you doing
sumo stance with your legs wide?
Are Your legs closer together?
Kind of like,
um, there are a little beyond
shoulder width and like slightly bent.
Right.
Indeed.
If you had to choose three types of extra
says just for the combination of like
enjoyment and benefits for you overall,
what would you choose?
Um,
probably like squat jumps,
box jumps and um,
let's see, like shoulder presses. I Dunno.
It seems like you could get a lot.
He's like a lot of different things
happen with those three exercises.
Right. And then you have the mountain,
you have the trail running at a slight,
if I'm in big Sur for the flying effect,
uh,
well I only want to ask a couple more
questions then I will let you get back to
your day. But this is, this
has been very fun. What did,
what advice would you give
your 30 year old self?
MMM,
it
doesn't get easier. Uh,
I need, tell me more.
Oh, I don't know. I mean, I think, I
think when you're, you're like, yeah,
I'm like onto something. My business
was grinding and I, this is so cool.
I can't wait for a time when you
know, I can just like, you know,
let go or a time where I can,
oh man,
this is just going to be running itself
someday or I'm going to, I dunno. Like,
or just you think, you know, as you
get older, I mean, yeah, you know more.
You can handle things better, but it's
the same. It's the same, you know,
it's just, it's, it's just
different stuff I guess.
And the challenges are bigger
with bigger things. Um,
and you know,
I think,
I think if it's easier to sell yourself
or for maybe other people to sell you
that it's just like one vacation after
the next and hey, I have a great life.
I really appreciate everything that
happened. I've taken some great vacations,
but just that, like the, the,
the hustle never ends, you know,
that it was just a year ago
is 30 a year ago. So, hmm.
It would be like hi.
I don't know.
That's right. I keep forgetting that
you're, you're such a young age. Uh,
what, um, what are you most looking
forward to in the next 12 months?
So far
in the next 12 months? I'm looking
forward to going to Tokyo. Um, yeah,
we're going to Tokyo,
my husband and I for like a week and I
haven't been since I was in high school
and it's just,
I know it's a cool place and
I have some memory of it,
but things are so different when you're
an adult and I'm excited to to check it
out and eat food. Now I eat
Sushi. I didn't mean Sushi
when I was in high school.
Weird.
Oh yeah. Now that opens up
all sorts of doors. The uh,
well if you ever want to chat about
that. Oh yeah. Just feel free to ping me.
Gimme gimme a call.
I've spent a lot of time
there and actually have a
two part article on Tokyo on
the blog that goes through some of the,
the smaller spots that I love,
but that is exciting. Oh yeah, we can,
Tokyo is something I
think everyone should do.
It's one of those completely alien places
for English speakers where you can get
completely lost,
completely confused,
even in the middle of the night and not
really be in any danger whatsoever. Yeah.
Yeah. We can leave your purse, you know,
on like you can like give it to a bomb
and it's probably safe for an hour,
you know,
you're right. Perse check.
It's just a fascinating,
fascinating country.
Yeah.
It forces you to question a lot of your
own sort of social norms and behaviors,
which I think is really helpful.
So that's a, that is exciting.
I'm super stoked for it. I'm going to
be headed to Korea for the first time.
I've only been in the,
some of the hoping to,
hoping to head to Seoul and within
the next month or two. But, uh,
what, uh, do you have any ask
or requests for my audience?
And, um, we'll, we'll,
the question after this is going to be
where they can find you online and learn
more about you and so on.
But just in general,
any like recommendation
or request of my audience,
any action they should take or
things they should think about
that's for their own good.
Uh, yeah, sure. Let's do that.
Um,
I dunno if you compliment someone today.
I don't know.
Say something nice to someone.
Yeah, it'd be nice. Be
Nice. Uh, awesome. Well,
I would love people to check
out what you're up to. Um,
you've done such, you've done so
much for such a young man. Uh,
yeah.
Well that,
that of course is a, uh, a sort of high
praise in mind in my world. But yeah,
the, of course they have. You have to,
but where can people learn more about
you? Uh, find out what you're up.
Cool. Um, well nasty gal.com
that's like, you know,
my reason for existing. And then, uh,
you can follow me on Instagram
and Twitter and snapchat.
It's Sophia Underscore Amoruso
and I'm launching a podcast.
Uh, I dunno, launching a podcast
next month called girlboss radio.
And you can read my book. It's
called girl boss. No ma'am.
Cool. Yeah. And uh, people will be
listening to this for quite awhile.
So look for girlboss radio guys.
And uh,
the book has a 835 reviews on Amazon.
Four and a half stars,
more than I want to say.
I'm looking right here.
More than 70% are five stars.
So the book has had a
fantastic reception and uh,
I appreciate you taking the time.
Thanks. Really, really fun. Of course,
this episode is brought
to you by Vineo pro,
which is the ideal video hosting
platform for entrepreneurs. And in fact,
a bunch of my startups already use
Vimeo pro including wealth front,
who uses it to explain how
wealth front works task grab,
it uses it to tell the company story
and there are many other names you would
recognize among their customers, airbnb,
Etsy, et cetera. Why do they use it?
Well,
dimio pro provides enterprise level
video hosting for a fraction of the usual
cost.
Features include gorgeous high quality
playback with no ads up to 20 gigabytes
of video storage every week.
Unlimited plays in views and they
fully customizable video player,
which can include your logo,
custom outro, et cetera.
You also get VIP support and you get
all of this for just one 99 per year.
That's $17 a month with no complicated
bandwidth calculations or hidden fees.
And you can try it risk free for 30 days.
So check it out.
demio.com forward slash business.
That's v I n e o.com forward slash
business and use Promo Code Tim to get 25%
off. That's a special discount
just for you guys, so check it out.
vimeo.com forward slash
business promo code. Tim,
this episode is brought to you by
Athletic Greens. I get asked all the time,
if you could only use one supplement,
what would it be?
My answer is inevitably athletic Greens.
It is your all in one
nutritional insurance.
I recommended it in the four hour body,
did not get paid for that and I
travel with it to avoid getting sick.
I take it in the mornings to
ensure optimal performance.
It just covers all my basis.
If I can't get what I need through whole
food meals throughout the rest of the
day, and you can get 50 oh my
gosh, 50% off. Yes, 50% off.
If you go to athleticgreens.com forward
slash Tim that's athleticgreens.com
forward slash Tim, check it out.
It's tasty, but more important.
It will help you not screw up when
you're doing your nutritional plannings.
For me, it just covers the basis, takes a
load off my mind, puts a lot in my body,
and check it out. athleticgreens.com
forward slash. Tim and until next time,
thank you for listening,
okay.
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.