Optimal at this altitude,
I can run flat out for a half mile
before my hands start shaking.
I'm a cybernetic organism living.
Whoa.
This episode is brought to you by
wordpress.com I love wordpress.
I have used it for so many years.
It's my goto platform for
blogging and creating websites.
I use wordpress.com for
everything every day. My site,
tim.blog is built on it. The websites
for my books, including tools of titans,
tribe of mentors. It's all
in wordpress.com and the
founder Matt Mullenweg.
One of my close friends has
appeared on this show many times.
Just search Matt Mullenweg,
Tequila Ferris for quite an exciting time.
Whether you're looking to create a
personal blog, a business site, or both,
you can make a really big impact
right out of the box when you build on
wordpress.com and you'll be
in good company. It's used
by the New Yorker, Jay Z,
Beyonce, five 38 tech crunch, Ted, CNN,
and time just to name a handful,
and one
of my
friends@googlewhoshallremainnamelesshastoldmethatwordpress.com
offers the best out of the
box SEO imaginable and quote,
and it's one of the many reasons that
nearly 30% of the Internet is run on
wordpress.
You do not need experience or to hire
someone that's perhaps the best part.
wordpress.com guide you
through the entire experience.
They have hundreds of
designs and templates that
you can use and it's easy to
get started. There's no need to
worry about security upgrades,
hosting any of that there for 24
seven support, and they're very,
very responsive. If you have
questions, they get right back to you.
And this allows you to create the
highest quality with the least amount of
headache and friction. So if
you're building a website, period.
When my friends come to me and ask
what I use, what I recommend they use,
the answer is wordpress.com
so check it out.
If you want to get started today,
learn more with a 15%
discount off any new plan.
Go to wordpress.com forward slash Tim
to create your website and find the plan
that's right for you to learn more,
take a look,
wordpress.com forward slash Tim
for 15% off a brand new website.
Check it out.
This episode is brought
to you by legal zoom,
which more than 2 million Americans have
used to help start their businesses.
Past guests even such as well,
wordpress lead developer,
CEO of Automattic, Matt Mullenweg now
valued it more than a billion dollars,
have used legal zoom to help
with their business needs,
specifically in his case
to form his company,
but legal zoom isn't just
for launching your business.
Their services include everything from
helping you to manage changing tax laws,
reviewing contracts,
NDAs,
nondisclosure agreements,
important stuff,
handling lease agreements and assisting
with really any other legal challenge,
hurdle, inconvenience that typically takes
time and effort away from running your
business.
The best part is that you
won't get charged by the
hour because legal zoom isn't
a law firms so they won't be running the
clock up and spinning circles just to
raise your bill.
Instead they just ask you to pay one low
upfront price for whatever it is that
you're looking to get all the card style,
so visit legal zoom.com and check out
their business section for all of their
services and if you want special savings,
that's the terminology and
the copy that they suggest.
I don't know what the special savings
is folks, but it's titillating.
If you want special savings,
enter Promo Code Tim Tim at
checkout capital t, lowercase.
I am again,
take a peek legal zoom.com
and enter Promo Code Tim.
Hello boys and girls.
This is Tim Ferriss and welcome to
another episode of the Tim Ferriss show.
He saw,
she booted on there every episode.
It is my job to deconstruct world class
performers of different types and that
term world class is going to come up
again in this episode so you can pay
attention to the context.
And this particular conversation I have
with me and Mira Co who has been called
quote the most powerful woman in startups
and quote by Forbes and is a lecturer
in entrepreneurship at Stanford,
the child of a rocket scientist at NASA
that's a literal rocket scientists and
is a Palo Alto native and has been steeped
in technology startups since she was
a teenager.
Prior to cofounding floodgate,
she worked at Charles River
ventures and Mckinsey and company.
Some of her investments include Lyft. I
Yazdi, I'm gonna screw this up. I know it.
Xamarin refinery 29 joy run taskrabbit
and mod cloth given the success of her
many investments,
she was on the 2017 midas list of top
100 venture capitalists and I just found
out today back on 2018 elbowing her way
to the top to steal the crown from her
partner, Mike Maples, Jr.
It's all good spirited Mike and
is known for so many other things.
I'm going to skip some of them because
we're going to touch on the seeds of her.
Many, many accomplishments in perhaps
some of the first few minutes of the
conversation.
Uh,
she has a Yeahi hope I'm getting that
right from Yale and a phd from Stanford
and math modeling of computer security.
She lives with her husband,
three kids age 10,
eight and six very well spaced
and one spoiled the hog.
And welcome to the show.
Thanks for having me.
So there's so many places we could start.
And I was,
I was hoping to humanize the ever
intimidating and Miraco, which I,
I may only partially succeed at doing.
But could we start with explaining
why your brother used to introduce you
or how he used to introduce you on stage?
Yeah, so I, I had this brother,
an older brother by exactly two years,
were born on the same day,
and he was one of these
guys was so confident.
He knew that he wanted to stay cars and
airplanes from the time that I could,
I could remember him existing. Um, and,
and he was always confident with friends
and he was also confident on stage.
And so as any good Asian child would do,
we played musical instruments.
I played the piano,
he played the violin,
and we would always have to perform.
And I was painfully,
painfully shy.
And so I would get up on stage
and I would refuse to speak.
And My mother and knowing this
wouldn't let this get in the way of our
performing,
she would send my brother up on stage
to help announce whatever I was playing.
And I have this real clear memory of
being in junior high and having this
happen. Uh, my brother got up
on stage and said, you know,
this is an Mira. She's going to
be playing a Chopin Nocturne,
um,
and go and,
and I looked over and I
remember thinking to myself,
you know,
like they think the mental dialogue
that's happening in a teenagers mind,
this is totally ridiculous.
And because I'm sitting there in front
of a room full of people and I felt fine
playing the piano,
but I felt petrified speaking.
And that's one of like the clearest
memories that I have of my brother and me
and the difference that we
had between the two of us.
Why are you so shy or
nervous about speaking?
You know, I, I've always
been an introvert,
so I think it comes
probably directly from that.
Um, but I was also sort
of, I was a strange child.
I have to admit, I, I had a
lot of different interests,
but I love to do things
by myself. Um, and,
and so I just didn't, I wasn't really that
interested in talking to other people.
Um,
like one of the first thing my mom
actually discovered about me when I was a
little kid when I was two,
I only spoke Japanese. Um,
and we were living in Michigan and I used
to be this very hostile little child.
And I would walk by anyone
speaking in English.
And in Japanese I would say,
I wish you would leave. So,
you know, like, I can't even for mom,
my poor mom. And so she was like, oh,
we really should socialize. And, um,
with people who speak English
and were living in Michigan.
So there's no shortage of these people.
Do you, do you still speak Japanese?
I do.
So I speak Japanese to my parents.
How do you say,
I wish you,
I wish you would leave just for people
who want to monitor that to people in the
park or wherever they might
be as do you recall or how,
how might you have said that as a kid?
Do you have any idea?
I think I might've said,
let me think about it.
At [inaudible]
that is aggressive.
That's really aggressive.
You're not welcome in this house.
Oh my God.
Gory. It was like, it was, I think
probably more likely it was Ooda cy. Nah.
Right, right. Oh Wow.
That's even worse. Right.
And so I know,
I was like something that like
a drunk dad says, yeah. Yeah.
It's kind of like shut up. Yeah, you're
really loud. You're really irritating.
But like,
like a little intransigent,
two year old saying that to a grown
up speaking English in her home.
Okay. I don't want to take us
too far off the rails, but we,
we may come back to that.
Okay.
So we were talking about you being
introverted and shy and weird. Yeah.
And it was,
um,
one of these things that I think
it really held me back and I knew,
I knew actually it was holding me back.
Um,
the strange part though was my mom was
recently talking to me about this in a
few years prior to that experience where
I'm in junior high, my, I'm on stage.
I had actually done this
other thing, which was, um,
we had this summer school program where I,
uh,
I would go to local community college.
It was foothill college and all
these schools around the area.
And when they let out for summer,
uh,
the students would go to this community
college to take math classes and writing
classes and whatnot.
So a lot of elementary school students
to high school students would be at
Foothill College. And,
um, and so my mom said,
you have to pick two classes.
And one class was a math class obviously.
Um, and she said you could pick
your second class. And, uh,
my brother picked a normal junior high
school writing class and I was in fifth
grade at the time,
so 10 years old.
And I picked a negotiations class and
it was not in the summer school program.
It was an adult class. Why
did you pick that? And um,
I picked it because I remember
the book was getting to yes.
And my mom looked at me and she said,
why did you pick this class?
And I said, it's because they're
teaching you how to get to. Yeah.
And I want to know how to get to yes.
And I have this incredible experience,
this Co,
this community college of
having, um, a class with,
I imagine they were probably 30 to 50
year old adults taking this class and they
were probably the most patient,
wonderful people. And you know,
we had this,
uh,
this experience where you had certain
supplies that you were given on pieces of
paper and then you had to negotiate,
you're on Mars and you had to negotiate
supply lines and whatnot and create a
real society.
Um,
in the simulation they're taking seriously
a 10 year old kid who's negotiating
for supplies.
And I,
I remember taking that
experience and feeling like,
you know,
I was taken seriously in that environment,
but it was a great experience
because it was a small class,
it was like 20 people.
And in that setting I
felt okay speaking up,
but then on stage I didn't still and,
and so it was sort of these small steps
that felt like I was getting closer and
closer to realizing, oh, I need
to actually be able to speak up.
I need to be able to say things
in front of a large audience.
And so there was this
desire to face my fears.
What was the next step after that?
How did you go about facing
the fear of speaking on stage?
So in,
in high school I get to high school and
as every high school freshmen is doing,
they're looking for different
activities to, to participate in.
And I decided to dive into a speech
and debate and speech and debate.
At this time at Palo Alto high
school was not a very big activity.
There were probably about
20 students on the team.
And uh, I, I found that I,
I really enjoyed it and it was a
really great group of students,
um, and then not only from
Palo Alto high school,
but from the local community.
And I just fell in love with the idea
that you could really seriously get up in
front of an audience and,
and talk about really important
issues even as a high school student.
And so,
uh,
I dove into that activity and
it was frankly terrible at it.
I think freshman, sophomore year,
I didn't win any tournaments,
didn't even come close. Uh, and that was,
that was sort of the way though
I decided I could face that fear.
What did you, what kept you going? I
mean, there's the, the answer that,
or perhaps potential answer
you gave just a moment ago,
which is you really enjoyed it and you
loved it, but what did you love about it?
What,
what did you enjoy so much?
They were able to persist through
failures over those first two years.
The first thing is just the people.
Yeah.
I reflect actually on the people that
I met in speech and debate and they're
doing incredible things. We
have just in my, my year or low,
not in my team, but in my local
community, uh, professors,
you know,
one's at Harvard and government ones
and Philosophy University of Colorado,
a one woman is now, um, on,
on the the morning show on NPR.
Um,
we have several venture capitalists.
It was just a really interesting
group of people, um, all in,
all in the same age group,
uh,
who wanted to talk about
really interesting things. Um,
I also found that the actual
activity itself was something,
it challenged me in a way that
I hadn't been challenged before.
So I was really good at math and science
and those things really came naturally
to me.
But getting up on stage and speaking was
not something that was natural to me.
But the piece that I did love that
came very naturally was competition.
And I'm,
I've always been this way.
No, I'm just checking.
Yeah, I can agree with that.
Right. I love, I love competition. You,
you put in points on
anything and I want more.
I want to, I want more
than the next person. And,
and I remember the coaches that
we had, we, we didn't have, um,
teachers at our school
who were able to coach.
And so we had to go across the street
to Stanford and find students who are
willing to coach. And these,
these kids were, you know,
18 to 21 years old.
So they would pump us up by saying,
Hey,
if phew can get someone to
cry in cross examination,
I'll buy you a slice of
pizza. And so, you know,
things like that were
extraordinarily motivating you,
like logic and arguments
could get you a step further.
It was just something that even though
I wasn't good at it at the time,
I just loved it. And I felt like if
I could just do one more tournament,
I become even better at it. And you
would see that. Right. And so that's,
that's the thing that I love.
So do you have any memory of,
this seems like a very,
very specific example that you
gave the crying in the pizza.
Did that actually happen?
Did you succeed at making someone crying
cross examination for a slice of pizza
or is it, was that just
something that can, can you
please describe that?
Yeah,
I feel like I'm not succeeding and my
desire to humanize me and make myself seem
like a less of a dragon lady but
there, but this, I want to hit
here, I want to hear this story.
Several stories.
So there were points in time or I
remember people would cry in the,
they would crumble in the middle of
cross examination and run out of the room
crying.
And my coach would see that and proudly
bring me a slice of pizza after this
happened multiple times. This wasn't
a single tournament. It was an,
and there were moments where I got,
they had courtesy points too.
So it wasn't just about winning.
It was also whether you were
courteous during that. And there were,
there were rounds where I
got zero courtesy points and,
and my coaches,
you know,
they would say they would ask why we
got zero courtesy points just to really
understand if we were just being mean.
But a lot of times it was just
because we were, you know,
and I was particularly tenacious
in cross examination and,
and even at the point where I had the
person stumped, I would just keep going.
I would keep going, keep going
at it. Um, and so it was,
I remember at least,
you know,
four or five occasions where
where someone cried and,
and left the room before the round
it was over.
So this,
this was like the Cobra Kai
of debating the bad team.
My, uh, my, my six year old at one
point right before kindergarten said,
hey mama,
I can make people cry just with my words.
Say it was like a really proud
moment for me. And then I had to,
I had to course correct and, and, and talk
to him about that. But no,
for someone knew who it was,
is wondering what I omitted from
the bio that I had in front of me.
You had two years of not doing well.
And then in the bio we have,
she placed first in the
National Tournament of champions
and second in the state
of California in high school.
And it goes on and I'll,
I'll mention one more thing.
And it was part of a five person team
at Yale that competed in the Robo Cup
competition in Paris, France. All
right, but let's focus on the debating.
So how did you go from
sort of miss flub with not succeeding
and debating to getting good at debating?
Yeah,
this is where I think
it's the love of the game.
Has To,
were your parents supportive
through all of these, the,
these early trials and tribulations?
No. So you have to, you
have to remember, you know,
I come from very traditional Japanese
parents who really want me to get into a
great university.
And my mom at one right after sophomore
year looks at my record and my parents
were incredibly supportive.
They would go and judge these
tournaments every single weekend,
spent so much time doing it,
driving us all over the state. And,
and my, my parents pulled me aside and
said, you know, this isn't working.
You have a losing record in this activity
that you're doing and you appear to be
doubling down on your
time with respect to this.
And if you want to get into
a good college, you have to,
you have to perform well in whatever
you're doing. You know, just,
it's not just about effort,
you have to have results.
And I remember my mom said to me,
I've heard fencing is a great way
to get into an ivy league college.
And I remember looking at
her and I was like, how,
how is it possible that she's my mother?
She clearly does not know anything
about my athletic abilities if she's
suggesting that I move into
fencing at this moment. Um,
and so I said to them,
point taken,
give me the summer and I'm going to,
to just work on it. I'm going to, and
this was back before the Internet,
so I working on it men,
I was at Stanford Green Library reading
philosophy books and reading articles
about the,
I think they have 12 topics,
12 possible topics that they're
going to pull from for the next year.
And I just studied those topics.
I lived in the library and then I,
um,
emerged that year to start competing.
And when they announced that first topic,
I knew that topic cold and then I
could write my cases really quickly.
I had already done all this research
and I remember going into my very,
very first round, uh, and,
and had this deal with my parents.
If I didn't win one of my first
two tournaments or at least place,
then I would quit.
And I have this distinct impression
walking into my very first round of debate
that fall and feeling as I looked across
at my opponent that there was no way
that they could have out prepared me.
And so I knew that whatever they said
I would have five arguments against.
And it was this incredible knowledge
that that it's not that you can be lucky
and turn your luck around,
you actually make your own luck.
And for me that was a profound lesson
because I placed in that tournament and I
placed in the next tournament
and it was like that.
It just never stopped after that.
And I had a losing record all
through my freshmen sophomore year.
And it's like I turned it around
junior year very suddenly.
And the main difference was that I
was willing to outwork and outdo every
competitor who walked
in through that door.
For people who don't know the format.
And I'll be honest,
I've been surrounded by it and not
surrounded by but certainly in the same
universities and so on
where debate teams existed.
But I've never seen a
debate competition what,
what is,
what is the format?
So it's, it's a bunch of
nerdy kids dressed in suits,
holding briefcases and
then maybe that's changed,
but that's what it was back then.
And then you have a resolution
that's been announced nationwide.
And that resolution is generally
has some philosophical elements to,
this is also Lincoln Douglas
style of debate. And you have,
um, so, so it's one
person against one person.
So it's individual and it's value
based and so you're really debating
philosophy. So, um,
an example of one debate that we did,
the principle of majority rule ought
to be valued above the principle of
minority rights or resolved that
education is a privilege and not a right.
So, so all of these debates
are really surrounding,
not a specific policy,
but it has some application in the real
world and what you're trying to debate
is a philosophical underpinning
behind that statement.
And what I loved about debate was you
are actually forced to debate both sides.
So you had to have cases ready for
both the affirmative and the negative.
So pro the resolution and against
the resolution and the format is the
affirmative goes up and talks about
this resolution and says all the reasons
that that they support it.
And then there's a short cross
examination where the negative then cross
examines the affirmative,
asks questions of the affirmative.
Then the negative gets up and talks about
all the reasons that they're against
the resolution and then goes point by
point against all of the arguments that
the affirmative made and
talks about why they're wrong.
And then there's another cross
examination of the affirmative against the
negative and then the
affirmative gets up for rebuttal.
Negative gets up for a rebuttal.
And then the affirmative Dez closing
arguments sort of shorter and shorter
speeches towards the end.
How is the outcome determined?
What are the, the parameters?
Yeah. So, so it really
depends on the, yeah,
aside from courtesy,
courtesy points, it's
all about courtesy. Um,
there's two different types of tournaments
actually when, when I was debating,
one was where you had parent judges
and that I would say really the,
the style of speaking,
um,
your flare really would come into
play. Your sense of humor. It was,
it really just a line by line arguments.
There was also a places where you would
go where college students were the
judges or experienced
coaches where the judges,
and that's where really the line by line
logic becomes much more important than
just the style of your debate.
Um,
so it really depends on your audience and
you had to read the audience correctly.
And did they just then say,
I I choose a or B or do they have to rank
like the sort of Olympic style one to
10 in some fashion?
So you only have two debaters that you're,
you're judging and you
vote for one of them. And,
and in some of the rounds you have just
a single judge. And then in another,
Anne, in the, the breakout
rounds and semifinals you,
you might have a panel of judges
and they can't confer. They're just
sort of voting individually on who wins.
So you,
you may be at a point now with debate
and argument that you've reached the,
the,
uh,
it's an unconscious competency phase
in the sense that in skill acquisition,
one framework that one could use to think
about skill acquisition as you go from
unconscious incompetence
to conscious incompetence,
to conscious competence,
then unconscious competence.
So I don't know if this question is
going to be a good one, but I'll,
I'll try it anyway.
For people who want to get better at
debating and structuring arguments and so
on, are there any books or
approaches or resources, anything,
exercises that you would suggest?
Well, getting to yes, I
thought was always really good.
Uh, I actually found
the philosophical, uh,
texts to be extraordinarily informative.
So anything where you have
that Socratic method in a book,
I found really,
uh,
a great way of learning how people
debate the greatest philosophers,
Aristotle and Socrates. Even, you know,
when you get into more modern,
um, literature around justice,
you have people like John Rawls writing,
uh,
that is actually a dialogue
and a real logical debate.
And I always found those examples to be
really great to read how people argue
philosophical constructs. Um,
you know, presidential debates,
to be honest in politics aren't real
debates because it's two ships passing in
the night and you don't have
real conflict between people.
Um, I've also found like the
British parliamentary system,
if you've ever had the
chance to see that on,
I think sometimes it's on c span at,
that's actually an interesting
observation of a real world debate as well
because they will actually
engage in dialogue around
policy and it's not just ad
hominem attacks.
Um,
though I find those sort of real world
examples much more powerful than someone
going sort of point by point
in teaching you how to debate.
Because I think the how is much more
around how do you engage in the idea?
How do you read and research both sides
of an argument and what do you believe
on both sides. Um, and so, you know,
one way to do that would actually do take
a fairly controversial topic and then
actually read,
read a lot of literature on both sides
of the argument and then understand where
actually the conflict happens.
You know,
are there definitions that
people don't agree on? Are there,
uh, are there nuances that, that
people haven't thought about? Uh,
are they,
are they real?
Is there a real conflict or are they
two ships passing in the night? Um,
I think you could do that with
even the gun control debate,
or you could do that with immigration
or you could do that with abortion and
really understand, uh, both sides
of an argument and that that's,
that's the way to engage in the
process of debate, I believe.
And if we're,
if we're reflecting back on your Cobra
Kai training for slices of Pizza,
uh,
I'd be really curious to know if
there are any particular approaches or
questions or playbooks that you find
very useful in a heated argument.
And I'll give you some
hypotheticals, right? Look, let's,
let's say that you are on stage at an
event and you are doing a Q and a with the
audience and you have someone who ends
up being really hostile attacks you or it
could be on someone on stage.
You're just having a
contentious debate of some time.
I find it fascinating to see how people,
even with no real logical
advantage shutdown opponents,
and I'm not saying that's you
in this case, but for instance,
whatever people may of our,
of our
dear current president
of the United States,
I do find it fascinating how
effective he has been at saying,
check your facts right? And, and,
and it just throws enough imbalance
into the dynamic where someone's like,
wait a second,
maybe I did miss one piece
of due diligence that
they're on their heels and it
opens up a window and creates sort of a,
uh,
an illusion of them being stymied that is
really advantageous. And I'm like, wow.
I mean it's, it's kind of
gross on one level, but it's
also kind of brilliant. Uh,
and I also have a lot of lawyers in my
family. And so one thing that they'll do,
uh, not to say they all love arguing,
but a lot of them do. And you'll,
you'll say something and they will go,
so let me just get this straight.
You're so I understand you're,
you're saying that acts and they'll
kind of take your argument and like inch
inch it a little closer to absurdity,
but just subtly enough that you'll say,
yeah, that's about right. And they'll say,
okay, so really what you mean is x. Right?
And they start to edge you over before
they even counter with an argument to
make you contradict yourself
or kind of seem ridiculous.
And then it's, they just have
to kind of finish you off. Uh,
but I've never taken, I've
never taken debate. Uh, and,
but I do find this really
practical and really interesting.
So it's a long winded way of enjoying.
But yeah, like, so what are your,
what are your thoughts on any of that?
It's funny, my, my husband
has said to me in the past,
and this is a lesson that I continue
to try to learn and relearn,
is that life is not a debate.
Right?
And, and you know what he's saying? And
it's funny, he was a debater as well,
um,
in college and in high school.
And we joke that I would still have beaten
him in high school if we had actually
gone head to head.
But,
but I think it's a really important
point that life isn't about winning the
argument. And, um,
and he's also said to me in
the past, you know, it's not,
it's not about being right.
And I think that's so true.
And it's something that I'm always
trying to really practice in life.
And I think it's the debate or
in me, um, makes it really hard.
The,
the things that you're pointing out are,
what's important about it is that
people have a tendency to have an inner
dialogue where they're there,
right?
And instead of really
listening to the other person,
they're coming up with the next
argument that proves that person wrong.
And so,
so if you go back to what I really loved
about debate and what I felt like I got
out of it, it was actually this ability
to see both sides of an argument,
to really delve into a topic
and understand why the,
the side that I actually naturally
believed could actually be flipped on its
head.
And,
and that was a really
important skill to develop.
And I think that was so much
more important to develop
then the skill to argue
for my side.
Because I think in the world today,
what we don't see enough of his empathy
for people you might even disagree with
and we get stock in our version
of truth and what is right.
And we aren't truth seekers anymore.
As a result,
we're truth of winners.
And true. Yeah, very true.
And that, that's the piece that
really makes me sad is that, you know,
when people are like,
oh,
this debate skill is so great to have
because now you can like Ram people with
your ideas and,
and I've never seen a situation where
you shouted people down and convince them
you are right.
And I,
I've seen situations where by developing
true empathy for the other side,
you actually create bridges and you create
commonality and you create situations
where you can actually
work together. And, um,
and I think that's the piece I would
take away from my debate experience.
I would say actually making the person
crying cross examination probably is not
the skill that I should be using in real
life. Although maybe sometimes I do.
I do.
Just when you're teaching your years,
your son the black magic,
I, I should point out just so people
don't think I'm completely, uh,
uh, sort of drinking the Koolaid
of the blood lust of this,
of this potential sport. Although I
do find it very, very fascinating,
uh, as an insight into
some parts of human nature.
But the book you mentioned getting to yes,
just part a or a B byproduct of the
Harvard negotiation project as I recall.
Yeah.
Is Not a book about proving you're right,
it's a book about getting outcomes.
Yes.
And there is another book which I believe
was coauthored by one of the coauthors
of getting to yes. Called getting
past no. Which I also really,
really like and it is about a,
well both of these books,
any book really under negotiation is
about achieving a very particular outcome
or arriving at a a desired result as
opposed to proving that you're right.
So I just want to underscore that,
uh,
B because there is a very real world
differences you already noted between say
debate and negotiation.
I mean the tool kits are very
similar perhaps in some respects,
but in, in debate you're not
going to have to think about,
I wouldn't imagine something like the
Batna that they talk about in getting to,
yes, you're your best alternative
to negotiated agreement, right?
Like do you like walk away
power or what your options are?
You don't necessarily have to
go through that thought process,
but when you step into the real world
and you're not just trying to prove that
you're right,
you're trying to get someone to concede
something and agree to a certain set of
terms or price or whatever it might be
a or amicably trying to break up with
someone or get together with someone or
have a divorce or whatever it might be.
Uh, you're really trying to
manifest some type of outcome, uh,
or damage control. It's really, really
different from being a truth winter.
Uh, and, um, the,
the worldclass term that I mentioned in
the intro and use used a little bit of
foreshadowing saying that I suspected
it might come up a little bit later.
So in doing,
in doing homework for this conversation,
uh, I read, and I don't think this
is a misquote, but that your dad,
even when I think you were going to be
photocopying and the Dean's office would
remind you to be world class
and you would ask you if you
turn it into calculus assignment.
Is that a worldclass effort? Yeah. Uh,
could you talk a little bit
more about this? And, uh, uh,
that's not that,
that wasn't my experience growing up.
My parents certainly encouraged
me to do a good job, but, uh,
tell us a little bit more about your
dad in this particular case and how that
was used.
Yeah, so my, my dad grew up in Tokyo,
um,
right at the tail end of World War II.
And so one of his earliest memories
actually is just a plane's coming across
Tokyo and the fire bombs and
he escaped to the countryside.
Um, and, and then came back
to Tokyo for high school. Um,
his father passed away when
he was in college and he, um,
literally tutored kids. Uh, one,
one guy was like the prime
minister's son until he,
so that he could make enough
cash to support his family. Uh,
he had three other siblings,
um,
and he was one of these
incredible academics.
And so he was at the top of his class
in one of the famous high schools in
Tokyo. Went to Tokyo University. Um,
was also then went to Toshiba,
which at the time was one of
these great companies to work for.
And then he ran into a friend
who, um, who told him he was,
he was also a friend who was one of the
top at his high school who said, hey,
there's great opportunities in
America. And this, this person had,
uh,
gone off to Princeton and gotten his
phd and was at that time working in,
uh,
one of the great labs and Ibm and
was also becoming a professor. And,
and my dad decided that he also wanted
to go to the u s and he was the eldest
son.
And so having a mother who's
a widow and three siblings,
uh, he had to take care of them
until he had saved up enough.
All of his siblings were married
and his mom had the courage to say,
you know what,
you can go,
you can go to the u s so this is sort
of the backdrop for who my dad is. He,
he comes to the United States
without speaking very much English,
gets a phd in mechanical engineering,
Aerospace Engineering,
um,
and then is in a la ultimately as a
postdoc and an associate professor.
Um,
my mom comes to marry him and they are
the only family members living in the
United States. So really no support. Um,
so my dad eventually makes his
way out to NASA at Moffett field.
And, and I, my memories of him,
he was very engaged on the academics,
but he would wake up at five in the
morning and go to work and he'd bring back
reams of paper and would continue
working late into the night. Uh,
he loved what he did.
And so when he turned to me on anything
I ever did from the time I was a small,
small child, um, I would
be writing something.
And if the handwriting wasn't
neat enough, he would say, hey,
is this world class? And I remember
thinking to myself, you know,
four or five year old,
yeah this is world class.
But he would always push.
He would always say is this really,
you know,
the best that a five year
old could ever do. Um,
and it was a constant message and the,
the story you're pointing to is one,
when I was in, in college, um,
after living through a lifetime of
this is this world class question,
I had a um,
a moment where I was starting my,
my financial aid package included,
you know,
10 hours of work study
and I the opportunity to,
to work in the office of
the dean of Engineering.
And what was really funny to me at the
time it since I'm leaving to go to my
first day of work,
I called my parents and my dad
gets on the phone. He said,
make sure you do a world costs job.
And I thought,
my dad thought I was like really doing
something important in the office.
And in fact I was just photocopying. And
I said to my dad, I'm photocopying and,
and filing, there's no such thing as
world class there. And he said, well,
I'd still think about it.
And so I get to the office and I am
actually just photocopying and filing.
And I remember standing in front of
this photocopy machine with a stack of
papers thinking to myself,
what is world class in this situation?
And I decided it was really crisp copies
where you couldn't tell that it was a
photocopy.
And so I remember really trying to make,
you know,
the,
the color match and
everything was straight.
Um,
and I spent a lot of time on the
details and when I was filing things,
I didn't just handwrite it.
I got a label writer and I'm,
I made sure it was printed out on labels.
Um,
and I really tried to do everything as,
as well as I possibly could.
And I remember I was getting donuts
and I would like make sure I got the,
the fresh doughnuts instead of the
ones that had been standing out.
I'm in the basket for awhile.
So every step of the way,
it was what can I do to
make this experience for the
dean or for his executive
assistant?
A delight moment.
And it was a real lesson for me because
it was a case of real ownership.
I felt so much ownership
of the job I was doing,
even though from the outside,
I think most people would have thought
it was just sort of a grunt job. Um,
and I think that's sort of,
again, when I come back to you,
don't just get luck.
You, you make, can you,
you create these opportunities
for yourself. Um, to me was,
was a real well real learning experience,
right? I mean, you're, you're,
you're looking at the potential
precursors of luck and trying to set the
conditions, even though they
might not always produce luck.
The you can increase the
likelihood of it happening,
which I think is a perfect segue to
a discussion about spring breaks.
Don't worry, this isn't going anywhere
tricky. This isn't going anywhere tricky.
Uh, this relates to shadowing. I'll just,
that'll be my cue, which
might bring you back. So,
all right, we're, we're
to lead into this. Uh,
you were giving a man a tour around Yale.
Yeah.
Who is this man? Why were you
giving them a tour? What happened?
And I actually don't know all the
detail. I just, I found two lines in
a past interview and I was like,
you know what?
I don't want to dig into this because
I don't, there's more to this story.
I know it.
Uh,
yeah.
So I'm like,
I'm a junior at the time at
Yale and doing this office work.
And the dean of engineering was
this, this, this older gentleman, um,
Alan Brom blame.
And he had no idea who I was.
And I'd been working in this
office for I think two years,
but he barely knew my name, but he
was, he was just like this great.
He'd worked under George Bush, Sr. He was,
he was a legendary physicist.
Um,
and I really look up to this man.
And so one day he,
he pokes his head out of the office and
the executive assistant was out and he
said, who are you? And I said,
I'm an Mira. I'm your, I'm your student
assistant in this office. And he said, Oh,
I've heard of you.
I need you to go and give this,
this friend of mine a tour of
the engineering facilities.
And he's like, I know you'll do a good
job. Sarah has told me, you're great.
And so I take this gentlemen and I take
him on a fairly thorough tour of the
engineering facilities and we just
had a great conversation and he,
it started off with, you know, where,
where are you from? And I said,
I was from Palo Alto and it turns out,
this is also from Palo Alto and we're
just sort of talking about Palo Alto and
in the buildings that are around us.
And my growing up back in Palo Alto
and in the middle of it he said, hey,
you know,
what are you doing for spring break?
And it just so happened I was going
to go back home and visit my family.
And he said, well,
that's great because, uh,
I'm wondering if you want to come and
shadow me and see what I do for a living.
And in my complete self centered,
uh,
moment of being a, you know, Jr, uh,
I hadn't asked this guy what he did
for a living. And so I said, well,
what do you do for a living? And he
said, I'm the CEO of Hewlett Packard.
And I remember thinking to myself,
I'm such a moron. And, and I said,
I think that would be amazing to be
able to shadow you for a couple of weeks
during spring break. And
so this man, Lou plot,
um,
invites me to just shadow him
in 1997 and I am going around,
literally, he, you know, he, he
didn't have a driver. He was, is,
this was really just the,
the Hewlett and Packard error of CEOs.
He drove himself around in a Ford
Focus. I remember this. We'd go,
go to different meetings and he took
me around and one of the days actually,
uh, Bill Gates came to make
an announcement about.net,
um,
with Hewlett Packard.
And so it was an incredible
event that happened.
I got to sit back stage and see
everything that was happening.
And Lou Platt that invited
the photographer to come
in and actually take a
picture of me talking to Lou and
I didn't really think about it.
But after the fact,
I get back to my dorm and Lou Platt
has sent me a thank you letter.
Thank thanks for coming to visit.
I thought you would enjoy
these photographs and there's
two photographs in there.
I framed them in my office.
Now one is a picture of me sitting on a,
on a seat talking to Lou.
And then the second picture is bill
gates sitting exactly in that spot that I
was sitting in talking to Lou Platt.
And you know,
to me like mentorship means
so many different things.
I've had so many different
examples of mentors,
but to a junior in college who,
who literally is a no body,
um,
he was such an incredible
example of mentorship.
He never asked for my resume.
He never asked for my GPA.
He just sort of took this girl and said,
you know what,
you have,
you have something and I,
I see it and I'm going to show
you something even greater.
And, um, to me that is such,
it was such a gift.
It was so incredible because I hadn't
even thought about my own personal
potential ever.
No one had ever described anything to me.
And I came back from that
with my mind completely blown.
I met Anne Livermore who was an executive
and I never seen a female executive in
my entire life. And here's
someone who I could look at and,
and see and I can see that
people around her respect her.
Um, it was just a, it's a,
it's a life changing moment
and it comes from that first.
Okay. You know, comment from,
um, Dean Bromley who says,
I've heard of you, I heard
you do a great job. Um,
and that's where the
opportunities opened up.
You're the,
you're the woman responsible for my
fresh doughnuts and crisp photocopies.
I've heard good things.
Exactly. It's a little things,
steps, filing labels. No,
I should note where you don't
have to go too deep into this,
but in a way you were perfectly
primed for doing a good job with your
photocopying and labeling
after spending. Was it summers in
Kanazawa in the stationary store?
Am I making that up?
Yeah, no, my first job
was literally helping my,
my uncle and grandmother sell office
supplies in Kanisawa Japan at our store.
Taichii doll
pikey though. Oh Man.
[inaudible] is just such,
I'd never been to Kanazawa for
those people who don't know.
I used to live in Japan long time.
My first time out of the U S was a
year in Japan as an exchange student,
which is a whole separate story,
but never made it to Kennesaw until
a few years ago. It's gorgeous.
And it's not that far away
from Tokyo at all, but such a,
it's such a cute spot with,
uh, so much to offer. Uh,
what did you, I'm sorry, go ahead.
Yeah,
it's,
it's actually incredible because it's
one of the few cities in Japan that was
protected by historians.
The US,
it did not get bombed in World War II
because of some of the historic elements
of the city.
So it's almost like a smaller version
of Kyoto and it has a historic,
a Japanese garden called Kevin Oakwyn.
Yeah, it was unbelievable. Unbelievable.
Believable. So it's,
it's like an eye summers.
I would spend maybe like two
blocks away from Kevyn Aucoin. Wow.
So it was an incredible
set of summers. But yes, I,
I used to man the cashier register at the,
the office supply store.
So I know my pens and notebooks and
in stamps like nobody's business.
Do you have any favorite Goto?
Don't worry,
I'm not going to spend
too much time on this,
but do you have any favorite notebooks
or pens or items of those types that you
use today?
Yeah, yeah, totally. So I'm on pens.
I love the juice up.
Oh four how do you spell giussep juice up.
Oh,
juice up. Okay. Yeah. Juice up oh
four. You can get them on Amazon.
They're super thin pens. Oh four that's
at the 0.4 millimeter or something? Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah. And then, um,
for notebooks it's the Nuna,
it's n u u n a,
some European brand,
but,
but I like any notebook that
has the dot matrix on it.
Um, and those, the, the paper
quality is really great.
I see. Dot Matrix. Just not, it's not,
it's not like graph paper, but there is,
there are perpendicular lines
that are dotted. Yes, yes.
I'm very particular. They
could go on and on. Oh,
it appeals to the dungeons
and dragons nerd in me.
Anything that resembles craft papers to
the juice, apoe four and the Nuna. Yeah,
definitely. Anything European
sounding with the repeating val,
I'll pay 40% more for, um, maybe, maybe,
maybe 100%. Okay. Maybe a hundred percent.
You mentioned that you have these
photographs in your office. I'm curious,
you're sitting in your right now.
Yeah. All right. So what else,
I'm sure you have photographs,
you were family,
but outside of kind of the usual suspects,
is there,
what are other items that you have in
your office that are important to you?
Uh,
let's see.
I have the original lift pink mustache
that used to go in the front of the cars,
um, which I love. I have,
I'm also a picture and a set of
laser etched metal plates that,
uh, students gave to me, um,
that have sort of a word graph of
all of the words that they thought,
uh, they could, they, they ascribed to me
students. Of what, what,
what was the context for these students
interacting with you and what are some
of the words?
Yeah, so I had, um, I teach at Stanford.
So after my phd,
what I realized was I loved
teaching more than anything else.
And so I stayed in contact with,
uh,
Tina Seelig and Tom Byers over at
Stanford who run the Stanford Technology
ventures program.
And they've given me the opportunity
to teach a few different classes.
But the one that I got these metal
plates and the photograph from was,
uh,
the class of 2013 may field fellows
group and they have words like a thunder
lizard,
bad ass inspiring,
um,
mother.
So, um, you know,
it's just really fun to see
sort of what words they thought.
What were you, what were you
teaching these Mayfield fellows?
Uh,
so we were teaching them basic concepts
behind leadership and entrepreneurship
and it's sort of the first exposure that
they get as juniors and seniors into
really, you know, startup ecosystem.
What does venture capital
do within that ecosystem?
What are the tough choices that you have
to make as a leader within these types
of organizations?
What does growth look like in
these types of organizations?
So it's just sort of a startup one oh
one but what I love about it is it's only
12 students and it goes for nine months.
Wow.
So if you get to be involved in it,
you get to really know
some of the students.
And I've been mentoring students and
sometimes teaching some of these classes
since 2008 and you get this whole arc
of the career path of young people and,
and I really love it. I think it's
just sort of you get, see, you know,
students who start off as seniors
and then they start their career,
they might go to Grad School, um,
then they go back and get a job.
Then they have, uh, they get married.
And then I think one is now
about to have a kid. Uh,
so you just sort of see this whole arc.
Um,
and it's just about 10 years, 20 years
behind where I was. And so I get,
I get to see this incredible progress
that the students make over time.
So it's,
it's something that I love
and Miraco Mother of Thunder Lizards,
Aka mother of dragons. We're gonna,
we're gonna,
we're gonna come back to thunder lizard
because there's a whole lot wrapped
around that. But, uh,
I'm going to try to keep,
my brain's somewhat focused here.
Is there a reading list for that class or,
uh,
do you recall anything that was on a
recommended or required reading list for
that class?
Yeah, so we actually teach a, I'm
starting a class today at Stanford,
um, for the new spring
quarter. And in this class,
what we're teaching is what I
would call intelligent growth.
It's a little bit different than may
field fellows. Um, but my hypothesis,
my belief is that just
like fake news in politics,
there's actually something that we would
call fake growth. And we've, we've,
we've worshiped at the alter of
growth for about five to 10 years now.
And what I've seen is that specifically
specifically within startups,
there's so much that we
see that it's fake and,
and no one has ascribed actual
adjectives to growth until now.
And so the class that I'm teaching to
engineering students at Stanford is around
what is actually intelligent growth.
And so you asked about the reading for it.
It's all around some of these
case studies that we've seen. Um,
a great example of that
to me is Qualtrics.
We're going to have Ryan Smith who is
the sea of Qualtrics come in and speak.
And I think he's a great example
because I think he was at $50 million in
revenues before he raised a
dime of venture capital money.
And so as a result,
he's going to own an incredible piece of
this company when it exits and it will.
Uh, and so I love the capital efficiency
with which he built his business.
I also think, you know,
one of my companies,
Lyft is a great example of having
that kind of discipline early on.
And not just not just wasting venture
capital dollars in the early days,
they didn't have product market fit.
So they spent two and a half years
working on this platform called Zimride,
knowing that they had to get
to density and writers. Um,
and Zimride was just a,
it was a platform where you could find
carpooling arrangements and it was being
sold to universities and companies,
but we couldn't get enough density to
get transactions really moving fast.
And it was two and a half years
before they launched Lyft.
And in the first six weeks you could start
to see that there was a real traction
there.
And it was only after they,
they knew what they were doing with Lyft
that they went and raised large round
with founders fund and then
an even larger round with, um,
Andreessen Horowitz and, and
that, that story of really,
really hacking value before you go out.
And Hack growth is something
that I don't see often enough in,
in silicon valley.
So it's something that I'm,
I'm continuing to seek and
I love to see companies,
especially outside of Silicon
Valley, that, that do that.
And that's when we come back
to hunting for thunder lizards.
That's what I'm looking for.
When you mentioned the case studies,
do you have written case studies
that you using it much like a,
I don't know if Stanford uses these,
but much like the Harvard
Business School case studies,
which are these kind of three ring binder?
Yeah.
A five to 10 page cases that
are published. You use those?
Yeah, we use, uh, so the,
the ones that we focused on,
there's a Harvard business
case on flood gate,
uh, that you can purchase
off of the Harvard Business
Review website. All right.
So just
so anyone can purchase these, you don't
have to be a student. And I, and I just,
yeah, I don't want to interrupt but keep
going because the format of these case
studies is really interesting to me.
In as an undergrad senior when I
took ed showers class in high tech
entrepreneurship,
which is how I met Mike Maples Junior,
who's going to be a recurring
character shortly. Uh,
I remember how useful they were. So
that's, uh, that's the only interjection.
Sorry to interrupt.
No, exactly. So we,
we use that case study for Qualtrics.
There is one on flood gate, so if you
go to the Harvard Business Review Site,
you can actually just search for flood
gate or Qualtrics and it'll come up in
there somewhere between,
you know, five and $15.
They're pretty easy to buy and download.
Um,
but I think those two in
particular are quite valuable.
We have then also,
uh,
just people coming in and speaking about
some of the things that they've learned
in how to grow that business from
zero to one and then one to ax and,
uh, people like, uh,
Michael Siebel who is now a partner
at y Combinator but also was part of,
uh, Justin TV. Um, and social cam.
We have a Stephanie Schatz who,
who was the fearless leader
on the sales side for Xamarin.
She had 18 straight quarters
of beating the stretch target.
Uh, so you can only imagine how
incredible she is as a sales leader,
taking a company from zero to
$50 million in revenues. Um,
so we have a lot of
different types of people,
whether they're CEOs or c Aros or venture
investors coming in to talk about the,
the kinds of trade offs
they had to make and,
and how they decipher growth,
uh, to make sure that they're,
they have the real kind and not
just kind that they're buying.
Right. It, just to elaborate on that,
for people who may not be in the
startup world, if, if for instance,
you're sitting in on an incubator,
a investor day,
and you see 12,
12 companies in a row that have 20%
month on month growth with very similar
looking charts,
there is some possibility that they
have been inflating or manufacturing the
numbers with paid acquisition to raise
funding or do any number of things.
And it's really easy to, uh, it's,
it's relatively easy to spot once you
know the symptoms, but there are an end,
then there are, I suppose, you know,
Richard Fiman would say the physicist,
you must be sure not to trick yourself
or fool yourself and you're the easiest
person to fool.
You can also get very caught up with
what you might consider vanity metrics.
But let me take a step back and
just ask. Well, before I ask people,
definitely take a look at the case
studies for both Harvard and if you search
Stanford GSB,
which is the business school case studies,
you'll also find a website with these uh,
profiles of companies
and not just companies,
but decisions they had to face generally
where you can determine for yourself
what you would do in a given situation.
Then read about what they did,
whether it's Mongo DB,
I'm looking at this Stanford GSB
site in the case studies right now,
so nose and so on. Uh, how did you
go to investing?
How did you first be he become exposed
to save venture capital and what did you
think you were going to do in college
when you were in college junior year?
What do you think? What did you expect
you're going to do when you grew up?
Yeah,
I actually had multiple different paths.
I started off when we were talking about
my brother describing this kid who knew
he wanted to work with cars or airplanes,
uh,
from the get go.
And guess what he's doing right now,
he's in Germany working with
race cars. So, you know,
and I was the complete opposite.
I think when I was four I wanted to be
a farmer and then somewhere along the
lines I really wanted
to be a doctor and I,
I want it to be a doctor for
a fairly long period of time.
Where in you freshman year?
Summer I took organic chemistry.
It was in this premed track. Um,
I think sophomore year,
summer you take the m cats if you're
pretty sure you want to go to medical
school.
And that summer I was with my best
friend who also really wanted to go to
medical school and she is right now,
uh,
studying leukemia. She's a
doctor, uh, at UCF. So she's,
she's clearly gone down that
path and double down on it. Uh,
but I remember going to study
for the mcats with her and I,
I turned to the side and I looked at
her and I had the sudden realization,
which was that then, this is two days
before we're taking the amp cats.
I said, hey, Kathy, I hate hospitals.
Um, I don't like actually
being around sick people.
I also don't love it when people
are always complaining to me.
And, and I think that might get
in the way of me being a doctor.
And she looked at me like I was an alien.
And she said,
why are you saying this right now?
We're about to take me.
I'm cats and we need to go study
for it at Kaplan. And, but,
you know,
I was just constantly observing her and
she's just this incredible human being.
And she continues to be. Um,
but this realization of wow,
like the actual job of being a Dr. May
not be something that I actually enjoy,
was really a hard realization when
you've been all in for this long.
And so, but it was, it was a
realization that I really had to face.
And I knew,
I knew my gut that I was doing it
because it was a really great path.
It was a path where I knew
what the next step was.
I knew what next class I had to take,
I knew the next exam I had to take.
Then there was applications,
then there was school,
and then there was residency and
fellowship and it just felt like a really
predictable thing to do.
But the actual work at the end of the
day was not something that was going to
love or enjoy.
And that was really disturbing to me.
And so I really screeched
off of that path and I had,
and it was hard because I had actually
taken all of the requirements except for
biology and the premed requirements
did not actually overlap very much with
electrical engineering.
So I've taken a lot of extra
classes to make it a possibility,
but realize also it wasn't for me and
that's where I was sort of in this state
of not knowing what I wanted to be.
And that's okay
for one second.
Yeah.
What you just described illustrates a,
a degree of self awareness,
but also decision making that I think is,
is rather uncommon in the sense that I
know a lot of people who have gone on to
become doctors or lawyers or fill in
the blank that has a lot of prerequisite
training and schooling because of say
succumbing to this sunk cost fallacy.
Like, Ugh, God, I've put in so much time,
even though I have this intuitive feeling,
I'm not going to like it.
I really should do it.
And what was the conversation or the
background that allowed you to step off of
that path? And not to beat the
like Asian kid drum too hard, but,
but let's be real. Right? I mean you're
also, I mean that's, that would be a very,
uh, admirable, well-respected,
happy to share at a dinner party with
friends type of path for your parents,
I would assume.
So all the more uncommon that
you would step off of that track.
So how has that, how has that the case,
why, why or why were you different?
So I think it goes back to actually
the moment in debate where I,
I, my mom is telling me, um, you should,
you should do fencing instead of debate.
There was this realization
of my parents really love me,
but they don't know me and they,
they don't actually,
no one really knows me in terms of my
capabilities and what I feel like I can
get done. No one knows that
better than I do. And, um,
and it was a,
it was an important lesson for me because
one other fact that I didn't mention
is that in as a kid,
there was no sign that I was
special except for, you know,
these weird characteristics where
I would go learn negotiations. Um,
but I failed the Iq test multiple times
and the school district insisted I was
not gifted or talented.
My mom had to fight for me to be part
of this gifted and talented program.
Um,
as a two year old after I,
I was a really hostile to
people who spoke English.
My Mom's stuck me in, tried to put
me into preschool to socialize me,
but I, um, ended up biting the
person who was interviewing me
for, for a preschool slot and
they put me in special education.
And, um, and I was,
I was one of those kids who got picked
up in a short yellow bus from our house
and take into a state run program for,
for,
for special children. And,
and I think for a long time,
my mom wasn't really sure what I was,
but she just decided to be all in on
the fact that I was gifted and talented,
even if I wasn't.
And she really worried that I was,
I was one of these special
children. And, and,
and so I had sort of an environment around
me way before Yale where I knew what
I was capable of, even if the
test scores showed that I wasn't.
Hmm. And I knew that I
knew what I was capable of,
even if my parents didn't see it in me.
And I think there's sort of this,
this moment in time that
people need to have where,
where you realize that there's
no test for human potential,
there's no recognition for that.
It's something that you have
to find inside of yourself.
And I think for me, you know, that,
that one of those tests was
actually going back to, am I,
am I going to be a great doctor?
And if I revisit this question
that my dad had always asked me,
can you be world class?
I knew I couldn't cause I looked at
Kathy and she was going to be world class
cause she loved,
she loved helping people and she
loved helping people from that kind of
caretaking perspective,
which is not where I was
going to be world class.
But I felt like there was something in
me where I could be great at something
that just wasn't it.
And how did you have the, you've all
this technical training by this point?
Many have the chemistry, but you certainly
also have the, uh, let's see here.
At that point, the electrical
engineering probably. Yeah. Uh,
how does finance and
investing or startups,
I don't know which came
first enter the picture?
Yes.
So having grown up in Palo Alto,
I was actually exposed to a lot of
startups as a, even as a kid. My,
I used to Babysit for a
serial entrepreneur, um,
and he was always tinkering
around in his garage.
And I remember thinking to myself, oh,
he, he works for himself, which is very,
very cool. I also, I'm
on my debate team. Um,
was Lisa Brennan jobs who I didn't really
realize she was the daughter of Steve
Jobs until I was in her house. Um, and
we were, we were talking about debate.
I was,
I was a senior at the time and I was
helping her through learning the ropes of
speech and debate. And Steve jobs
sort of appeared out of nowhere.
And I remember thinking to myself, what
a Steve Jobs doing in this house? Um,
and so, you know, it was just
sort of, it was all around and,
and so venture capital was something that
actually a friend of mine had brought
up when I was still struggling with
this notion of what should I be.
And he was a real finance guy
and he said, you know, you are,
you're really good at technology and
you're now in business because of this
exposure to loop plot. You know, have
you ever thought of venture capital?
And I remember kind of reading about it
and having heard a little bit about it
growing up, um, looking into it and
realizing, oh, you have like all,
all this work experience you need to have.
I talked to a couple of former Yalies
who were venture capitalist and,
and sort of had that in my,
in the back of my head. Um,
and so,
you know,
I went off to work at Mckinsey as a
consultant for three years and then in the
process of trying to
figure out what to do next,
I met a venture capitalist by
the name of Ted Denture Smith.
And in that interview with him,
we spoke about not about technology,
not about the research I'd
done or my work experience,
but he wanted to know what books I
was reading. He wanted to know, uh,
about the music that I loved.
And in that period I was really
into modern American literature.
So I was really into El
Doctorow. And uh, there,
there are a few books that
I just absolutely loved and
we talked about that for
a little while. And then when we
turned to music, I've played piano,
classical piano since I was four and he,
he and I talked about the,
the classical musicians that I really
loved and he happened to be an English lit
major along with being a physics major.
So he,
he loved books as much as I did,
maybe even more.
And then he was an opera nut.
And so we had all these things that we
could talk about and two hours into that
conversation,
never having touched upon technology.
He then basically said,
how would you like to come work with me?
And, um, I was living out
in Palo Alto at the time.
This is an opportunity in Boston.
And I remember not,
not even hesitating knowing that I
wanted to work with this, this person,
this human beings sitting
across the table from me, uh,
jumped at that opportunity.
And it wasn't,
it wasn't the fact that
was in venture capital,
but rather I really wanted the chance
to be working around someone like Ted
Dinner Smith at that time.
Let's talk about that
interview for a second.
So that I think would strike some people
as a very unusual interviewing style.
Do you think in retrospect,
and maybe you know,
that he had already decided you
were fully capable of doing the job,
therefore didn't have to check that box
and just wanted to make sure that he
could work with you and
spend time with you.
Was it that he was using the interview
to sell you so that when he made the
offer you would say yes. What do you
think was going through his mind before,
during, or after our, I suppose
before and during that conversation?
You know,
I think Ted is a very unique
human being in that when I,
I used to have this perception that
networking was work in a room and like you
shake a lot of hands and hold a lot of
babies and you learn a few names and you
move on.
I learned from Ted that networking is
actually a deep curiosity about the human
being who's sitting
across the table from you.
So I don't think he necessarily
had that kind of purpose in mind,
but that he was just really interested
in what I was interested in.
And we happened to find commonality and
he was trying to understand how my mind
worked in what I was interested in.
And I,
I've taken that as a real lesson
because I love the way he would network.
He,
he learned so much about
people in that process and um,
and,
and that's how he ministered
to his entrepreneurs.
He also,
um,
was capable of providing advice at the
right time because he really knew those
people. Uh, and so, so for me,
I felt like it was a
really unique interview.
It's stood out from all the
interviews I've ever had,
but I think he was learning more about
me than most other technical interviews
could have gotten to.
And then you know,
his other partners I think ease our mini
gave me sort of more of a case study
and could dive into that.
But Ted always had a deep curiosity
about the human being and not necessarily
just the skills.
Okay.
What else did you learn from
him or in that position in that,
in that job?
I thought that Ted was also an incredible
first principles thinker. So this,
my second day of work at
CRV was nine 11 and so,
so it was, you went from kind of
a bad economy to a horrible, um,
black whole economy and,
and so it was a really terrible time for
venture and they had just raised this
one point $4 billion fund.
And so that's,
I mean for venture,
that's a huge amount of money and it's a
huge accomplishment to convince so many
investors to invest in your venture
capital firm at that amount.
But then Ted took the time to actually
start to do analysis with me on how much
capital had gone into venture
capital at that moment.
And then the exits had stopped.
There are no more IPOs,
no one was acquiring companies at the
economy just came to a screeching halt and
he decided along with the other partners
in this firm to give back most of the
money.
So they reduced their fund from one
point $2 billion to $450 million.
And the reason why that's so interesting
and impressive is that the way a
venture capital firm makes money,
the way you have any salary or on the
operating money that you have for the firm
is a direct percentage of
the fund that you raise.
And so by shrinking the size of the fund,
you're shrinking the size of the
management fees that you get pretty
dramatically.
Oh, for sure. Very dramatically.
I mean for people who don't know,
I mean you hear very often,
it's not always the case,
but in venture capital two and 22 and 20
and that means 2% management fee based
on the sort of assets under management,
meaning that particular fund and then
20% of the upside for people who don't
know.
And so, so they, they decided to
give back those management fees. And,
and to me that was really,
really impressive cause you're,
you're facing now in a really terrible
economy and not only are you shrinking
the size of your fund to reflect that
you're also shrinking the size of your
management fees and you're,
you're taking that blow. Um,
and so, so things like that I learned,
I learned also, you know, how to,
how to shepherd companies through that
kind of difficult time and how to be a
true partner to an entrepreneur.
Um, and so, you know,
I think it was a really important lesson
to learn because I would argue most
people haven't seen real cycles.
People seem to think 2008 was a
real significant dip in the economy.
But anyone who lived through 2001 knows
that 2008 was a blip compared to a real
downturn. And because
we've had a, you know,
raging bull market for such a long time
that that memory and that knowledge of,
of having survived,
you know,
2001 as a crisis period is something
that I hold with me really my war chest.
I know how to get through
that kind of time period.
And I don't think a lot of people do.
Yeah.
It makes me think of a lot of what I
heard in Silicon Valley still here.
I know before moving to Austin,
uh, which, which makes me think of,
I'm going to paraphrase this,
but it's a quote from Sir
John Templeton I think it is,
which is the most expensive words in
investing are this time it's different.
And uh,
it has been quite the bull run.
You mentioned first principles
thinking, uh, what, what are I want,
I want to tie that into something
you mentioned related to your class.
Tough choices for leaders.
What are some of the
toughest choices for leaders?
I suppose in this context,
CEO is or high level exacts
cofounders of companies, what does,
what are some of the,
the toughest decisions that nonetheless
seem to come up fairly commonly?
The most difficult thing
for a startup founders,
CEO leader is that especially when you're,
you, you witnessed multiple
phase changes in a business.
And so if you imagine you're going
from absolutely nothing to something,
that's what I call the zero to one phase.
You're searching for product market fit,
you're trying to find the best customers,
you're trying to find where your
tenex advantage is truly valued.
That's a very different business
process and truth seeking.
Then when you're going from one to acs,
which is now that I know what my value
proposition is, I'm going to add to that,
but I'm also going to pull on
some of these growth levers. The,
the fundamental job of a VP of marketing
who is in that zero to one phase
changes dramatically one to x.
It changes dramatically for the
salesperson in zero to one to one to x.
Um,
and you go through this incredible Bermuda
Triangle where you have to navigate
that change. And so, so what,
what I see challenging for,
for startup founders is actually being
comfortable with your fundamental job
shifting from every three months.
You would have a massive shift in what
you need to focus on and how you need to
develop. And I think, you know, a,
an accompany is a
multidimensional thing in,
in, in Silicon Valley we spent so much
time thinking about product and product
market fit that we forget that there's
this huge emphasis you might want to
place on the fact that a
company is also an organization.
A company is also a category
that you're building.
A company is also a business model,
you know, companies also a team.
And so it's,
it's,
it's the skill set actually to balance
all of those things and knowing when
you've, you, you fundamentally need
to change out the talent in your team,
uh, the knowing when you actually
need to let go of a product.
Um, and knowing, actually to me
this is probably the hardest piece.
Knowing the difference between a winning
strategy versus a strategy not to lose.
Could you elaborate on
that please? Yeah. So
to me a strategy not to lose this
is a lot of different things.
It's to not to lose to a competitor,
not to lose talent.
Uh,
a strategy not to lose out on revenue.
So it's all these fears that you
have of captured ground or uh,
the fact that you might have someone
take over something that you're,
you want to do a competitor
who's breathing down your
neck versus a strategy for
winning is about where
do you double down on,
what do you do to capture
ground, to be aggressive, uh,
to play off offense and not defense.
To me,
that as a huge difference between that
strategy of I'm going to win in this
market versus I'm not going to lose and
not losing often invest in involves a
lot of hedging.
And when you feel that urge to hedge,
you need to focus. We,
you need to be offensive.
What, what, in what ways
might that hedging manifest?
What would be examples you've seen or
hypothetical's of the symptoms of a
defensive strategy in the form of hedging?
Great question.
It might manifest itself in,
I am going to go after two very
different customer segments.
One is large enterprises.
There is small medium businesses and the
reason why that's really hedging is you
have two completely different ways of
selling to those organizations and you're
afraid to pick one because maybe
you have some revenue in both.
Right?
But in that situation,
by not choosing to focus
on one group or the other,
you're probably a short changing your
team because you don't have a specialized
team to go after that opportunity.
You're short changing your business
model because you aren't pricing your
product correctly and you're shortchanging
the opportunity because probably your
product isn't optimized for that customer.
Set your,
your customer services and optimize
for that product set and your team is
ultimately confused because you're
heading in two completely different
conditions and directions. And
so I believe that, you know,
that's one of the most common ways that
I see people involved in a strategy of
not losing instead of
we're here to win it. Yeah.
Yeah.
All of those things you mentioned also
contribute to lighting money on fire.
Right? I mean that's tests, that's
split focus. Just the bottom
fire,
the bonfire
of funding, uh, or cashflow
depending on where it comes from.
Uh, the, this is really important and you
know this, but I want to underscore it.
People listening
and give a few other examples that might
be worth people might enjoy exploring.
So this winning versus not losing
distinction seems really subtle up,
but you can get an in to, to feel
for it in a few different ways. Uh,
one is,
there's actually a,
I think it's a three part mini series
podcast called the making of Oprah and it
talks about the rise of Oprah.
I know this seems like an odd segue.
Oprah impresses the hell out of
me on a million different ways.
And after you listen to this, you'll
understand exactly why that's the case.
But she would constantly tell her team,
many of whom wanted to
respond to say Donahue,
who is the 800 pound gorilla at the time.
Like we need to raise our own race in the
sense that if you're on a thoroughbred
horse and you're in a race,
you need to focus on your race.
You can't be looking side to side
at the, the, the, the competitors,
the razors next year you get yourself
into a lot of trouble or you get really
injured. And the second is
if people want to Google, uh,
Dan Gable on aggression,
uh,
there's a short video I put on my
blog that hits this point exactly.
And I'm giving examples from
different disciplines because it is
crossdisciplinary. It's not just
investing in startups. Dan Gable is the,
the most legendary wrestling coach,
certainly of the last,
I would say a hundred years in
the United States. Uh, also, uh,
won a gold medal in the 1,972 Munich
Olympics without having a single point
scored on him. That just does
not happen. And uh, this video,
we'll show you a lecture that he's giving
one of his athletes after his athlete
tied and he said, you lost to him twice
before you just didn't want to lose.
He said, you never win that
way. You got to tie. And that's,
that's exactly why you got to tie and uh,
the differences is just so
powerful and it's, it's worth,
I just thought taking a
second to, to underscore it
because I think that uh, it's,
it's, it's really a critical
distinction that you brought up.
Like I think about it,
I love to ski and I had this instructor
once I was complaining about going
through powder and I was, I was saying
how it really hurt my, my thighs.
He was like, my thighs are burning
and he looks at me and he said,
it's because you're not
leaning forward and,
and like the minute you lean forward,
suddenly you're just gliding.
And it's scary in that moment when you
lean forward because you feel like you're
gonna fall and yet it gives you so much
more control and it gives you so much.
It's so much less effort
counter intuitively.
And that to me is like
the perfect example of,
oh like you have to actually have a
little bit of aggressiveness in order to
have the win.
I think you are, are well
suited in that respect. Uh,
how did, how did you meet the, uh,
how did you meet the man who
so famously tries to trick,
not trick that sounds too strong. Who so
commonly will say something like, well,
I'm just a southern boy.
Maybe you could slow down and explain
that one more time. Which by the way,
if you ever hear anything like that,
like really stop and pay attention because
you're, you are about to be tricked or
directed. I've actually borrowed that
and I use that for long, Long Island.
A lot of them like, you know, I'm just
a slow long island boy. Take a second.
Maybe you can explain that to me again.
How did you meet Mike Maples Jr?
Yeah,
so this actually happened in one of the
classes that I was teaching at Stanford.
He was, uh, he was one of the
mentors for a bunch of teams.
So we had all these teams who
are creating business plans for,
for their own version
of a startup company.
And we had incredible mentors
to each of these teams. We had,
I think someone who was the
former CEO of verisign, we had,
I think Diane Greene might've
been a mentor to one of the teams
can we had Mike Maples and green
is for those who don't know,
Diane Greene is now the
head of Google cloud.
She was also the CEO of Vm ware.
Big Deal, a big, big deal, big deal,
big deal. Um, and what we,
what we did was we would team up some
of these entrepreneurs or people in
Silicon Valley with a student
team and Mike was one of them.
And for people who know Mike,
he's just this charming guy,
boy from Oklahoma.
He calls himself sometimes
a washed up enterprise, uh,
VC and are washed up
enterprise entrepreneur,
but he's not.
And uh,
so he came to our class and
he was mentoring this team,
but he was actually being too nice.
And so this team was having
like all sorts of weird issues.
They were fighting and they came to my
office hours and one of them started to
cry and
spotting a theme here within proximity of
right. I did not make this
teeth number cry. It was,
they were making each other cry.
And so I was just kind of,
I was really,
I was kind of mad at Mike
because part of the, the,
the role of the mentor is to help
shepherd them through this tough points.
And he was just kind of checked out
on that front. And, and I emailed him,
he said, Oh yeah, my team's doing great.
And I said, well, I kind of beg to differ.
Uh,
they were just in my office and one of
them started crying and they're fighting
and right now if they
don't pull it together,
they're really gonna fail the class. And
he wrote me this message that said, well,
I think they're going to get an a plus.
And so I said, well, so
far, not tracking. And,
and so we just sort of have this friendly
banter and actually the team does turn
it around and they ended up getting
an a plus in the class. And, um,
or did he just throw some turtle shells
on a desk and like divine his way to
that outcome?
I,
I'm not really sure,
but I actually take full credit for the
turnaround because had I not pointed it
out to Mike, then the team
would have just imploded and,
and so, um, so based on that interaction,
you know,
a few years later I was starting to
get to a point in my phd where I was
thinking of starting my own company
and I had started my phd in computer
security exactly because I knew that
it didn't matter when I graduated there
would be a computer security
problem out there and I would be,
I wouldn't be at risk of market timing.
And it was sort of a perfect opportunity
because just as I was going through my
research,
it was from 2003 to 2007 at this point,
we had transformed from this world of
where security used to be a bunch of
vandalism problems to now there are
companies involved in like real money was
being involved.
And so real crime was being created here.
And then towards the end there was really
like nation state warfare starting to
happen.
And so my,
my research was really in risk management
of computer security and I knew that
this was becoming a huge issue.
And so I started to think
I'm going to make a company.
And so at that moment I turned to some
of my advisors and my advisors were nice
enough to say, hey, um, if you're
thinking about starting company,
you've been in the ivory towers
for literally four years,
so you should get out of the classroom
and go check out some angel investors.
And then Mike was one of the first people
I turn to and I asked him if I could
see his deal flow and he was
nice enough to say, sure,
why don't you just come in and take
a look at my deal flow on Wednesdays?
And so we would sit next to each
other and look at companies and
I mean, you get the, the,
the sort of top of the funnel companies
that he's considering potentially
investing in,
right? They would come in and pitch
for between 30 minutes and an hour.
And then at the end of that, I,
um, I think it was, you know,
March of 2008 he calls me is I'm
actually going up to Tahoe to ski.
He calls me to say, Hey, and
um, I have this great idea.
I just raised my first fund.
It's $35 million and I think that you
should drop out of your phd program and
join me.
And it's not the venture back startup
that you've been thinking about,
but it's now a backed venture startup.
Let's go. I like that. That's really good.
Now was that an immediate yes.
Or is it a let me sleep on it.
I actually thought he was
crazy because first of all,
you know, I was literally, again, I was
a nobody. I, I'm, I'm a phd candidate.
I didn't even have my degree at Stanford.
So there's like all these business
school students, there's great, you know,
Angel investors milling around the,
the major question was like,
why does this guy think that I
would actually be a good investor?
And then the second piece
was there weren't a ton of
venture capital firms that
were being started up. So even when I
went back to people who were my mentors,
some of them said,
why would you go to a no name VC?
Why won't chew go and be an associate
at Kleiner Perkins or excel or you know,
sequoia. Yeah. And I didn't
really have a good answer.
Um, just to set the stage
for folks who don't know,
maybe the recent history in Silicon
Valley at the time that Mike had proposed
this to you,
sort of microcap venture capital
was barely a thing, right?
I mean it's,
it's there,
there are a lot of funds of all
sorts of different sizes now,
but at the time this was very unusual.
Yeah. And so it was, you know,
this point and when you get to
2018 there's probably, you know,
30 funds being pitched a week to a limited
partner who invest into these venture
capital firms. But back then
there was very, very few.
And so it was really a question
of is this the smart thing to do?
And I think this is sort of where, you
know, when you turned to an entrepreneur,
this is the feeling that
they get. Um, what I,
what I sensed was there was actually
a major change of foot. I'll,
all of the students around me at Stanford
didn't need $5 million to start a
company. And that's what venture
capital was offering to startups.
At that point they would say, I will
buy 50% of your company for $5 million.
Right? Is predicated on the entry costs
being very high. And some are very,
very high.
And like at that point,
you know,
we suddenly have open source software.
We really have what starting
to look like cloud computing,
we have all the shared resources.
So even though I was helping to run
servers and the closet at my Grad in our
lab, that was starting to become
something that we didn't need.
There was actually,
you know,
services that you can use
where you could rent services.
And so to me,
uh,
there was a dramatic
change that was happening.
And so you had to change
the financing environment.
And so I felt like I could see
something that everyone else didn't see,
that Mike was also seeing. And he used
to save 100,000 is the new 5 million.
And,
and,
and then the second piece
for me was this guy,
Mike maples had a skillset
I had never seen before.
I made maybe in like one or two
other people in my entire lifetime,
but he was this incredible marketer
and I used to believe you either build
things or you sold things.
Everything else just seemed like
an extraneous skillset to have.
Mike was incredible at
storytelling and positioning and,
and,
and strategy,
like real strategy for how do you create
a new category and how do you build
that category and how do you
create the king of that category.
And as an engineer,
I had a thought about what you
do after you build the product.
And so this magic of category creation
to me was something that almost felt like
magic.
And so I looked at Mike and I thought,
I really need to learn from this person.
And,
and not only is it a great skill
set that I'm learning from,
he is also genuinely one of
the best human beings that,
that I've ever encountered.
And so it was just sort of this magical
combination of someone whose values
really aligned with me and how I wanted
to build a firm and the things that I
wanted to do with that and how I wanted
to treat entrepreneurs and in a person
who was a mad genius. And so that
combination to me was irresistible.
And so a couple of months
into it, I said, sign me up
a couple of months. All right.
So question number one, just for,
for people who are wondering,
and I know a lot of people,
you seem very good at avoiding the sunk
cost fallacy and this is so, so, so key,
this cognitive bias.
Uh,
when you were looking at the
quitting of the PHD program,
did you, I don't know how it
works at Stanford, but did,
did you realize you could kind of,
you didn't have to quit?
I did not quit.
So,
so that first year and a half of my life
within at floodgate was crazy because
at that point I joined floodgate
and I have an 18 month old child,
my daughter Abby. And then I, you know,
I think it four or five months into it,
I am pregnant with my second child.
I've promised my mother as any good Asian
daughter would that I will finish this
phd if it's the last thing I do.
So I'm waking up at like four o'clock
in the morning doing research until,
you know,
seven when she went,
my daughter wakes up and then taking her
to daycare and then working from like
eight 30 to six 30 at floodgate and
then coming back doing dinner and then
working on my phd again,
Rinse and repeat.
And then I got pregnant with my second
child a few months into that and then,
um,
decided I was going to defend my phd.
They set the date for six weeks
after I gave birth to my son.
And so, you know, I,
I not only did my first
set of investments,
but also had gave birth to a child,
cared for another one and managed to
stay married and finish this phd all
between 2008 and 2009. And so, you know,
to me like that's like the most creative
and probably productive period of my
life ever and probably will be,
but,
but also showed me that I can actually
do a lot of things that everyone around
me was like, why would you do all
of those things at the same time?
How does, how does this seem like a non
sequitur? Kind of is, but uh, how does,
how does your mom say your name? Because
Anne is sort of an unusual first name.
Oh, no, but that's what my first
name, my first name is Nicole
nickel.
Yeah. So how does my
mom say she was like, no
Vaco Dayco chances going there.
I can barely, that's another word.
Everybody should look up and learn.
Shug I sequoia and uh,
that just means sort of awesome,
impressive,
whole all sort of things because I can
barely manage to brush my teeth and
shower on a daily basis.
And yet you're doing all
these things simultaneously.
I have to pause at this point
just to try to fill out the,
the,
some of the,
the colors of who [inaudible] is.
What have you struggled with? Like
have you had any dark, really,
d doesn't have to be dark,
but difficult times,
dark times that you could
tell us about and where you,
where you really struggled or is that
not part of your sort of lexicon?
No, I think we, we all
have struggles, right?
So I think even in this moment of like
the Phd and caring for my kids and caring
for myself and my,
and my family and all,
and trying to do a good job at
work, like things slip, right?
And, and I, I,
I struggle with this still today and this
is where the darkness comes in is like,
am I doing anything? Well, like,
am I a good mother? Am I, you know,
I, I didn't, I wasn't today, my,
my six year old is on a
field trip and he asked me,
why is it that you never
get to come on a field trip?
Like those are all these
moments where you wonder like,
am I failing at being a
parent or you know, Aye I,
Aye not able to get to the dishes.
And My, I had a moment where my,
my front door neighbor is actually a
Japanese woman, a nosy Japanese woman.
She went up, she went up to my
mother and she said, you know,
your family is so strange.
I always see the husband doing
the dishes but never the wife,
never the wife
that is the most nosy Japanese
neighbor thing to say ever.
Like I spent two days like in,
in that,
in that front window doing dishes. And
at some point I was like, oh, screw this.
Um,
but,
but it's like all it is this constant
battle of how do I figure out what my
priority is so that I
have like minimum viable,
you know, progress on some fronts. And
then the thing that really matters,
I'm going to make massive
progress on. And so, so that,
that's where the darkness creeps
in. I think, you know, for me, my,
my really loser moments
have been things like,
you know,
early on I just described to you early
how there were tests that always said
like, I wasn't that smart.
There were, you know,
lots of examples where I wasn't good
at a lot of different things that other
people found very normal.
Like I was horrible at standardized tests
only until I got to like senior year
or junior year in high school.
Did I finally figure it out?
Like there's so many places where so
many people said distinctly average,
maybe not even that smart.
And,
and I think for me it's been learning to
tune out the naysayers and knowing that
there are certainly a lot of
things I'm not going to be good at,
but there are things that I
can actually be great at. Um,
a really good example of
that actually is my phd.
I remember when I got to my phd
at Stanford and I'm starting,
first of all,
like I took a math class and there were
high school or college freshmen in this
class and it felt like the math teacher
was speaking Greek and the freshmen are
flying through this material because
they're like little kid geniuses.
And I remember thinking to myself,
well,
clearly I should not be
getting a phd in math.
And thank goodness this
is an operations research.
Then I had this second
experience where the professor,
a new professor came in across the hall
from me. His name is Ramesh Johari.
And uh,
he was my age because I had taken
five years off to start my phd.
He was literally my age
and he was incredible.
He could remember things about different
papers and theorems and how they were
proved from like years past,
compare and contrast them.
He just knew things that
I struggled to remember.
And I remember looking at him and being
in one of his seminars and thinking to
myself, that is world class
as an academic. And I'm,
I'm okay at it. But I would have
moments where I was like, I'm,
I'm actually not even good at it.
And then I would go to a
conference and like when you,
when you compare yourself against the
world of Phd students and obvious,
then you start to develop a
little bit more confidence.
Then you go back to Sanford and
you see what world classes and,
and I was thinking to myself,
this isn't the path and there's a,
there's a place where I actually can
use the skill sets that I do have,
where I can be really good at the
things that I'm doing. And so if, if I,
if I, I'm sitting here
saying, you know, oh,
I was always good at everything
that I did. It's just not true.
There are so many moments where I
realized it's like being a doctor.
I said I would not be
good at being a doctor.
I would not be great at being an academic.
I would not be great at a
lot of different things.
Just knowing and having the self awareness
of where I would double down is I
think what, what I was good at. And so,
so it makes the,
this emergent life where I was
going from one track to another,
I was going to be a doctor and then I
went to Mckinsey and then I went to VC and
then I went to get a phd
and then it went back to VC.
This is all self discovery rather than
a stated path that I had career plan for
a long time.
Well it strikes me also that,
and maybe I'm trying to create narrative
where there isn't one or connection,
but it seems reasonable that Mike's
superpower or one of his abilities to help
create categories and then sort of
mint kings within a given category is
actually a different species of
something that you're also good at,
which is kind of a Jack Welch,
Ian in a sense. And that is you're looking
at the different paths you could take.
And if you can't be saying number
one or number two in that thing,
it just gets rolled out and you're
asking this world class question over and
over again.
And one way is to find something where
you can dominate and really be world
class.
And the other is to create an
entirely new category in a sense.
So it seems like you and Mike are very
complimentary in that way and have that
shared programming. Uh, I've,
I've heard people describe you as an
investor when your strengths is being
technical, which I suppose seems
self evident given your background,
but how would your colleagues,
how would,
how would Mike,
let's say describe your,
if I asked him what her aunt
superpowers is an investor,
there are a lot of investors out there.
What is,
what is ends superpower set of
super powers? What would he say?
I think for me,
the super powers I have or a few folds.
So one is because of the,
the technical capabilities that I have
when someone is describing particularly
anything that has to do with math.
And Luckily for me right now,
math is having this incredible resurgence
in artificial intelligence and in
cryptocurrency, I, I can get that piece.
I can get that piece better than I would
say probably 99% of the investors out
there.
And so if I get a math paper,
that's something that I love to dig into.
And that technical insight is something
that I think I'm better at than most
other investors out there.
And then from there I can also start to
piece together what that company will
look like around that technology.
And so it's not just I'm looking
for great r and d projects,
but ones that are ripe to
be big D and little r and,
and I think that's a super power,
especially at the very early stage.
So one of the companies that I
invested in back in 2010, uh, Yosty,
they've gone over a hundred million
dollars in financing at this point.
And I found them when they were,
they didn't even have a business plan.
They had four math papers
that they sent to me. And,
and so to me that, that's something
that I, I doubled down on and it's a,
it's a part of the types of
investments that I like to do. Um,
that's very different from,
you know, the task grab.
It's refinery 29 and lift that
I've done in the past as well.
I think the other superpower that is a
little bit less, seven is more of an,
as I'm working with people is I feel like
I have a pretty good sixth sense about
the dynamics within an organization.
So I can tell when there's
actually in fighting happening.
I can sense when a executive
is starting to disengage.
Um,
and those are things that,
that I work on with a lot of
the CEOs that I work with.
Um,
and then the,
the last piece that I think I really
love to engage in is the fundamental data
behind the business. And so, um,
I love looking at the cohort
analysis and really engaging on data,
uh,
because that's,
that's a piece of the puzzle that I
feel like I'm also good at encoding
uninviting.
What are you looking for now?
And water thunder lizards.
We mentioned hunting thunder
lizards earlier and I
promised I would come back to
it.
So maybe we define that first and perhaps
you could tell us what you're looking
for at the moment.
Yeah, so, so a thunder
lizard is inspired, um,
by Godzilla. It's a term that Mike, my
partner used to always tell this story,
which is that we are inspired by
entrepreneurs who are like Godzilla.
And so what is Godzilla like?
He's born from radioactive atomic eggs.
So the DNA of that entrepreneurs
already fundamentally different.
And then he swims across the Pacific
Ocean and depending on if you're Mike or
me,
he lands in either the bay area or
Tokyo and starts to wreak havoc and eats
trains and automobiles and buildings
and then proceeds to crush that,
that industry and creates disruption
and then build something out of that.
And,
and so you know that that idea
of disruption is something that,
that I always liked that imagery of like
the journey across the Pacific Ocean,
born from something fundamentally
different and then really starting to turn
things over. Um, and so,
so when we say, okay,
what are we looking for right now in
terms of where do we think the new thunder
lizards will exist?
There's sort of two different areas
that comes back to the math that I,
that I'm really interested in.
One is I do think that artificial
intelligence is about to disrupt a lot of
different types of enterprise software.
Um,
I think that enterprise
software is still socks.
And if we're going to be able
to really transform the way,
um, uh, an, uh, business
has actually operated.
We have to take these,
the software that just basically records
data and spits it back out to you into
something that's actually
more intelligent,
that tells you something
that you didn't know,
that gives you superpowers.
And,
and I think that we're going to see
more and more of that in the industry.
And so as an example,
like baseline examples,
why do we spend millions of dollars on
oracle or net suite when the CFO is still
has to make a budget for next year?
Why does it that financial planning just
automatically automagically generate
itself based on all the
history that it knows,
plus all the data from the external world.
So I think things like that we're going
to start to see happen more and more.
I also think, you know, fundamentally
the scientific method may also be dead.
Like we list used to have the scientific
method is developed in a time where we
didn't have enough data and data was
actually the fundamental bottleneck in
scientific research.
Well that's just not the case anymore.
And so why is it that we form a hypothesis
then look at the data and then come
to a conclusion. We should have
all of the data then have, uh,
an analysis of that that leads us to a
hypothesis or a belief system that we
fundamentally test further.
Um,
so I think these massive
changes are coming and,
and you see it even in,
in cryptocurrency. Um,
there's also really
philosophical, interesting
debates happening around, well,
you have this massive pull towards
centralization, whether it's an AI and ml.
We have to have all of that data in
one place in order to really train
MLP machine learning,
machine learning, um,
or in cloud computing.
You're also putting it up into the
data and to more in data centers.
Um, in crypto currency, uh,
we believe that there's going to
be more decentralized software.
And so how do you reconcile
those two types of systems?
I think there's lots of really interesting
themes that are just at the start of
being discovered. Um, I'm
really excited about what,
what's going to happen with autonomous
vehicles and the technology that it's
going to be required to
make that a reality. Uh,
and so all of those areas I
think are just fascinating.
And so it feels like,
uh,
the period of real intellectual abundance
and that we're headed into a period of
real great creative energy
end up at a time where a lot of your
philosophical training and reading will be
put into practice in the real
world, right? Where we have,
yeah, if you look at the,
uh, people can look up the
trolley scenario or that is
typically thought of as a
thought exercise, but if you're
programming, not take too
off on a tangent,
but if you're programming for autonomous
vehicles and there's some type of act
of God off hailstorm,
a huge boulder falls in the middle of
the street and the car has to swerve left
and hit to school kids or swerve
right and hit five geriatrics.
And how does it make the decision?
What is the logic embedded
into that machine? It's,
it's uh,
really bring,
it takes a lot of these philosophy,
one o one thought exercises and translates
them very directly into the real
world with real consequences and is,
it is a fascinating time
and how much, it's also like how much do
you want to know? Right? So deep learning,
it's actually very difficult to know
what's happened inside of this black box.
And,
and so there's more of a demand for,
let's know what is actually happening.
This inside of this black box,
especially if lives that are risk or have
billions of dollars are at risk and we
need to be able to audit these, these
algorithms. I think there's real,
real interest in new technologies now
that we can actually audit and know what's
going on inside the box so that, you
know, if the, the trolley example happens,
we actually know how the machines
will make their decisions.
And so I think there's a lot of work
to be done, a lot of opportunity,
but also a lot of thought that needs to
go into how we want to regulate all of
this.
Tricky. Tricky, tricky. Yeah.
Well it's going to be
going to be exciting. Very,
very interested to see how all
these things coalesce. Right?
Also you're looking at these
gigantic companies, the
Facebooks googles, the fangs,
right?
That are more and more so
converging onto the same territory.
To see how that resolves if it does
in some fashion is also really,
really exciting to me.
Or how something like y Combinator just
to do a little bit of inside baseball
can say we are interested in this type
of company or this particular aspect of
engineering or fill in the blank and
it's kind of steer the attention of
thousands or tens of thousands of would
be entrepreneurs into a particular
sector or type of project is also just
really interesting to think about from
the the ramifications five years
down the line. Right. But anyway,
maybe
we have,
I mean like I think we have
so many incredible societal
problems that need to be
solved and I believe that the private
sector is most capable of solving these
problems,
right?
Whether it's energy or health or you know,
the fact that we have so much trash.
How do we solve that?
How do we get clean water to people?
Um,
it's not just about the next social
network and how do we deliver a better
advertising to people. But
you know, the, the beauty of,
of this type of entrepreneurship is that
there are huge societal problems that
still need to be solved.
That I think, you know, is,
is a really exciting opportunity also
to build great businesses around.
Uh,
and so I think that's,
that's also what gets me up in the morning
and makes me believe that that what
we're doing is important work.
Yeah,
it is important work.
I don't think that sort of collective
interest in self interest have to be
misaligned, right? They're not
mutually exclusive. You can,
you can solve and there's a long history
of solving public problems with private
sector technologies and companies.
Uh,
and let me just ask a new,
we, uh, we've gone a little
bit longer than expected, uh,
which I should have expected.
Let me ask you just a few more questions
and then we'll wrap up with where
people can find you and learn more about
what you're up to. Besides getting to,
yes.
Are there any books that you've given a
lot as gifts or re-read a lot yourself?
Oh Gosh. For me, you know,
right now there is,
there's a couple books that I think
are, are super interesting. So,
um, my, the,
my mentor Ted Denture Smith just wrote
a book called what school could be,
and this goes back to sort of education
as a critical societal question.
Um,
how do we fix education?
And what he did was he
went on a 50 state tour,
um,
to look at schools and discover that the
answers are actually already there and
are incredible school teachers throughout
our country are already finding
solutions to teaching our kids the most
important skills they need to have.
And I think reading that book
has not only given me hope,
but also a desire to see real change
in the public school education system.
Um,
but I think that's a really important
problem for all of us to actually engage
in. And so that's one book that I
would really push on to other people.
Um,
the other one that has completely
on the opposite end of the spectrum,
but it is a fiction book. It is, uh,
by Khaled Hosseini, um,
who also wrote kite runner.
He wrote this book called a
thousand Splendid Suns and, uh,
probably one of the most beautiful books
that I've read in a long time in terms
of fiction writing.
And I would encourage people to read
it because it gives you sense of,
uh, Afghanistan's incredible history, um,
and the role women have played
within that history. And I,
I just loved that book because it just
was eyeopening to me in a very different
way. Um, so two very
different types of books.
None of them like straight
forward business books,
but ones that I think are meaningful
for our society to read today.
What school could be in
1000 splendid suns. Yeah.
Is there any purchase of $100 or
less? It's kind of arbitrary, right?
But just not a Bugatti or something that
has most positively impacted your life
or positively impacted
your life in recent memory.
Okay.
$100 or laugh.
Yeah, it could be. I mean, look, if it's,
if it's like a foldable Kayak that
you've got for 400 that's fine too.
But it could be, could be anything,
could be $2, could be free.
It could be any recent
addition to your life
that
it's actually a foldable chair.
So I go to my daughter's
soccer tournaments a lot
and there's this incredible
foldable chair. I don't know what
it's called. You can get it on Amazon,
but it has this flip over
sunshade that goes over your head.
And for any parent who has been
at a swim tournament or anything,
this is life changing because oftentimes
I'm just baking in the hot sun and you
can be anywhere and you have your own
personal tent that like folds over your
head. It's been, it's like
saved me on multiple weekends.
My husband bought two of them.
I love it.
Can you send me a link to that and
I'll put it in the show notes if, uh,
if you can track it down. So
for people wondering, I'll,
I'll put that in the show notes at Tim
Dot. Blog slash podcast and you can,
you can find this miraculous
foldable chair, uh,
if you could have a giant billboard
anywhere with anything on it.
So metaphorically speaking, getting up
a word, a quote, a message, a question,
anything out to millions or billions
of people can't be an advertisement.
What might you put on that billboard?
Wow.
Hmm.
I wonder if it's like not
losing does not equal winning.
So one of my, one of my themes
these days, I like that. Yeah.
And I think actually finding
your world class life,
it's probably the other one
that I would think about.
We'll give you find your
work worldclass life.
And I think the reason for that is to me,
everyone is capable of that.
And I think oftentimes we forget it.
And uh,
and it, for every person it's different.
That's the beauty of humanity. So
what do the characters for vehicle mean?
Oh my gosh.
So it means it's a small round bell.
And the reason for my parents named me
that was they were originally going to
name me something more like,
you know,
really beautiful child or you know,
genius child.
And my mom, my mom took one look at
me when I was born and she's like, no,
none of those.
She said,
your face was so perfectly
round when you were born.
It reminded me of this
bike perfectly round bell.
And I'm like,
mom,
like all these other friends that I have,
especially Chinese friends
are like super intelligent,
like world class dominating
dictator for life.
CEO, child, you know,
and I'm like small bell.
Hi.
Are they coachable?
Uh,
and where can people find you online?
Say Hello.
Learn more about what you are up to.
I think professionally the best
place is to see my Twitter,
which is an a maniac, a n n, n, I, m.
A, n. I.
A C or a on Instagram.
It's a m.
I you are a,
you'll see more of my life there.
Amy Muda. Yes. Three bays.
Is that what that means?
Muda something like that
maybe. Yeah. So Twitter,
Twitter,
and a maniac.
Instagram a Muda m I you
are a and best website,
floodgate,
floodgate.com.
[inaudible] dot Com why flood gate?
What is a flood gate?
Why, why is it called the floodgate? Yeah.
Yeah. Cause we think we're
at the forefront of like the,
the headwaters of, of
innovation and so, and,
and, and it sounded, I don't know,
kind of big and audacious
good enough reason.
A audacious,
audacious, yes. Uh, audacious,
aggressive but still the mother of
dragons, there is a nurturing mother.
Like there is den mother quality to him,
the Mama Bear, you know,
I'll, I'm very protective,
but also I'm going to push my kids and
the people around me to be the best they
can be.
Just don't get in. Don't get in
between the mother and the cub.
Good guideline. And I will say
for anybody who's wondering,
what would it be like to just go sort
of motto Amano with an I would say,
you know,
you're one of the few people I would
put Sam Harris in this category where if
you, if you are willing to
engage in at like eight,
eight public debate with either of you,
you just have to make sure that you have
practice defending it against having
your face ripped off and like the most
logical complimentary way possible.
Uh, I've just very impressed
by you and, and I've,
I've really wanted to have you on the
show for a long time and I'm thrilled that
you were willing to carve out a few hours
to spend chatting and it's always fun
chatting.
It's always fun. Tim, you, you've been
there from the very get go. You were,
you were the person behind my very
first investment in task rabbit,
so I have a lot to thank
you for it as well.
Well, the, the adventure shall
continue and I will certainly, I'm not,
I'm not as involved as I
used to be in the tech scene,
but I'll be cheering from the sidelines.
Is there anything else that you'd
like to say or suggest or mention?
Any parting words before we wrap up?
No, I hope the, the, your audience, uh,
enjoyed this and if they got
anything out of it that they,
if they want to contact me,
I'm always open to more conversations
and a hope that some of my story shows
that even if people tell you you
can't do something that, that you can,
Ken indeed just got to spend the
summer reading up on those 12 topics.
That's right. You would can't
always out talent everyone,
but if you out prepare them, you might
as well have out talented them. Maybe
the billboard sign,
his effort matters effort really does.
It does. Uh, well Ann, thank
you so much again. This is a,
this has been such a treat and a,
and a gift and I look forward to
hearing what people have to say on the,
on the interwebs. And perhaps we'll
do a round two in person, uh, during,
during one of, what was the name of the,
uh, was it the Tim Ferris wine hour?
What was, what was the true, yeah,
they call it Ferris time.
That's a Mike calls it Ferris time,
which was the, uh, yeah,
the little little wine,
a pair of TIF to smooth out the
edges that we could describe it.
He just grabs, he just grabbed the glass
and it's like, I think it's fair sour.
I'll take it. I will take it. Uh, and uh,
and I will talk to you
soon. See you soon. I hope.
And to everybody listening,
you can find links to everything
we discussed, the books,
the foldout chair and much more getting
to yes and so on in the show notes as
you can with all episodes at Tim
dot. Blog forward slash, podcast.
And until next time, thank
you for listening. Hey guys,
this is again,
just a few more
things before you take off. Number
one. This is five bullet Friday.
Do you want to get a short email from me?
Would you enjoy getting a short email
from me every Friday that provides a
little more soul of fun before the
weekend and five bullet Friday is a very
short email where I share the coolest
things I've found or that I've been
pondering over the week.
That could include favorite new
albums that I've discovered.
It could include Gizmos and gadgets
and all sorts of weird shit that I've
somehow dug up in the other
world of the esoteric as I do.
It could include favorite articles that
I've read and that I've shared with my
close friends, for instance,
and it's very short.
It's just a little tiny bite of goodness
before you head off for the weekend,
so if you want to receive that,
check it out.
Just go to four hour workweek.com that's
four hour work week.com all spelled out
and just drop in your email and you will
get the very next one if you sign up.
I hope you enjoyed, this episode
is brought to you by legal zoom,
which more than 2 million Americans have
used to help start their businesses.
Past guests, even such as,
well. Wordpress lead developer,
CEO of Automattic, Matt Mullen leg, now
valued at more than a billion dollars,
have used legal zoom to help
with their business leads,
specifically in his case
to form his company,
but legal zoom isn't just
for launching your business.
Their services include everything from
helping you to manage changing tax laws,
reviewing contracts, creating Ndas,
nondisclosure agreements, important stuff,
handling lease agreements and assisting
with really any other legal challenge,
hurdle, inconvenience that typically takes
time and effort away from running your
business.
The best part is that you
won't get charged by the
hour because legal zoom isn't
a law firm,
so they won't be running the clock up
and spinning circles just to raise your
bill.
Instead,
they just ask you to pay one low upfront
price for whatever it is that you're
looking to get all the card style.
So visit legal zoom.com and check out
their business section for all of their
services.
And if you want special savings,
that's the terminology in
the copy that they suggest.
I don't know what the special savings
is folks, but it's titillating.
If you want special savings,
enter Promo Code Tim Tim at
checkout and capital t, lowercase.
I am again,
take a peek legal zoom.com
and enter Promo Code Tim.
This episode is brought to you
by wordpress.com I love work.
Thus I have used it for so many years.
It's my goto platform for
blogging and creating websites.
I use wordpress.com for everything every
day on my site to not blog is built on
it. The website's form
books, tools of titans,
tribe of mentors all on wordpress.com
and the founder Matt Mullen leg or my
close friends has appeared on the show
many times. Just search Matt Mullenweg,
Tequila Ferris for quite an exciting time.
Whether you're looking to create a
personal blog, a business site, or both,
you can make a really big impact
right out of the box when you build on
wordpress.com and do be in good company.
It's used by the New Yorker,
Jay Z.
Y'all say five 38 tech crunch,
Ted CNN time just to name a handful,
and
one
of my
friends@googleshallremainnamelesshastoldmethatwordpress.com
offers
the best out of the box
SEO imaginable foot,
and it's one of the many reasons that
nearly 30% of the Internet is run on
wordpress.
You do not need experience or to hire
someone that's perhaps the best part or
best.com guide you through
the entire experience.
They hundreds of designs and templates
that you can use and easy to get started.
There's no need to worry about
security upgrades, posting any of that,
that for 24 seven support and they're
very, very responsive. You have questions,
they get right back to you,
and this allows you to create the
highest quality with the least amount of
headache and frictions of
you're building a website,
Harriet and my friend's company and ask
what I use, what I recommend they use.
The answer is wordpress.com
so check it out.
If you want to get started today and
learn more with a 15% discount off any new
plan,
go to wordpress.com/tim
create your website to find
the friends right for you to
learn more. Take a look.
wordpress.com four slash 10 and
for 50% off a brand. Do you check it out.