What are, what are the top, say,
two or three books that you
either discovered or delved
into while researching?
I was told us away. I mean, if you had to
pick your top two to three, you're like,
all right, if you want to maximally
gain in whatever way, I'll let,
I'll leave it open to, to you read
these two or three bucks. Like,
if these are the only two or three
books you read this year, you'll be,
you'll be better off
for having, okay. Well,
I'm looking at the bibliography right
now and some that jumped out at me that
were total favorites.
Ron Chernow's biography of John
D Rockefeller, which is Titan,
though the life of John d Rockefeller
was like a total game changer to me.
It was an amazing biography. Um,
I like Sarah Bakewell, his book,
how to live.
It's like a series of essays about
Montana who invented the essay. Yeah.
Um, he's really
fascinating. Sarah Bakewell.
Hmm,
cool. Um, I like, uh, let's
see. Oh, I read this book.
Um, the, uh, the fish that ate the whale,
the life and times of America's
banana king. He was this, uh,
a totally fascinating but relatively
unknown historical figure who started,
he started a fruit company
buying spoiling like the,
the day old, not daily, but
the, about to expire bananas.
Um, that would be important in
like late 18 hundreds, America.
And he would sell them, um, like
he would sell them by train car.
He ends up,
he ends up buying United fruit.
He starts a small fruit company that it
grows to be so big that it buys United
Fruit company, which is the biggest
fruit company in the world. Um,
so that's why he's known as
the fish that ate the whale.
He's this sort of fascinating,
a Jewish businessman. Um,
I read a really good biography
of Edison by Matthew,
uh,
Josephson called Edison a biography.
Okay.
Got It. And if there was any
others, I'm trying to think.
Yeah, those were some, oh,
and I read a really good biography of
Ulysses s grant called Ulysses s grant,
triumph over adversity that I loved a lot.